[Music]
[Laughter]
okay so can you please take your seats
so this is the call backing group i'm
karsten bowman this is from reminisce
yeah this one is a bit low
so this is an IDF meeting we are on a
Monday so I probably showed you do a
little bit on this there are some idea
rules that we are working under so if
you talk about technology and know about
a patent claim affecting the technology
you have to tell us or you can decide to
just not talk about the technology and
yeah the whole point is about making
progress on drafts where we hope most
people have read those and they're weird
views here are because Apple has
destroyed the you know to a little bit
so I had to convert the slides to
PowerPoint and back to Kino to be able
to show them so the brew sheets are
going around good and we do have scribes
so those people who ascribe can they
raise the hand take notes nobody take
notes but yes does Alex does Marco does
okay good thank you so so the note well
applies I think I already said what's on
them let's talk about the agenda we have
two meetings one now and one tomorrow at
the same time so today we will hover
around work new blast calls are the ones
that have already been done or once that
will happen soon and at the end we will
have a quick look at payment over
cuerpos Adrian here thank you and
tomorrow
we will have another one of those that
are done with work new class called
another one that maybe is up to forward
new brass code and then we will wander
into less charted territory any comments
on the agenda anything which are clicks
okay so let's go right into the first
item new which is called over TCP now
this has been a neverending story we
completed work last call she can March
or something like that and we had a lot
of brouhaha about the URI schemes so we
reached an agreement finally how to
handle the URI scheme problem and the
current draft reflects that and also
should be clearing all IES three
discusses can you have a quick look
where the major th well okay okay so
maybe somebody else can can ever look
whether yes she discusses are gone on
that draft so a B approval assuming we
will be in the RFC editor queue soon
Omega hasn't cleared us yet okay maybe
mock tomorrow there is also a dependency
on a small housekeeping document hi bye
WebSockets
we're known because this document is
assuming that the slash start well-known
mechanism is defined for WebSockets but
it wasn't so this document defines that
and we will see we are aware that
housekeeping document goes but forth
over TCP itself we are pretty much done
and we also
spend a little bit of time on Saturday
getting a few implementations together
there is a pretty well cooked
implementation now in lip co-op so that
that was a little bit our reference
implementation on Saturday and there are
two implementations that are in the
process of being created one from Jim
and one from me and we managed to go to
the place where we could do a get on
slash that went on at call which because
of the fact that there are a few things
mandatory you have to really foil you
can get a get over TCP a connection is
already quite some achievement so Jim
wrote up the issues that we found there
there is one example that isn't quite
right I think - is missing on an option
name and I think the only place where we
probably want to think about it a little
bit is what does it mean to send a
request after you have sent release
income over TCP we have an explicit
release mechanism so one side can shut
down the connection without disrupting
things that the other side is trying to
do at this point in time and we didn't
really say very much about what it means
to have sent that release and we might
be more explicit about the idea that
after having sent release you are not
supposed to continue to use the
connection as it was so that that's
maybe something that the author's took
for granted that is kind of obvious but
it could be made explicit and also the
text could be made a little bit clearer
on the situation where you do a ping
pong
and you have a custody option in the
ping but the the other side doesn't want
to do a custody option in the return and
there is currently no language that
discusses this case and the point here
is of course that the delay language
that is there for the case where the
custody option is present doesn't apply
to this case so this is the level of
issues that we have had at the hackathon
we probably could address this in in a -
11 and of course the we are still
waiting for the discusses to clear and
Alexei has to do with evaluation whether
we did the end of the comments right so
maybe there are a few more small
editorial things but apart from that I
think we are done with it and at the
start of this segment I should have said
that I'm changing hats because I'm not
saying this as a chair because I'm a
co-author on this document sorry for not
pointing this out so whether this is the
original chair on this side okay any
questions on discussion items on
poverty's of you Tim Kari Nokia I just
got a question on this I'm trying to get
an understanding of just timeframes
right are we talking about this do we
think that this is going to go into the
editors queue this year yes so there is
an interesting gauge that we should be
working to which is the Consumer
Electronics Show in Las Vegas and by
that time it should be in the RFC editor
queue or we get some problems so that's
really the ultimate deadline and we want
to have it in the queue we follow and
that's what February right for what we
know it's January in January okay all
right thanks so it should it should be
the Christmas tree okay next item okay
good afternoon everyone
my name is Carlos Gomez and I'm going to
present the last update of the draft
entitled coop simple congestion control
advanced also known as cocoa next please
so first of all let's take a look at the
status of the document so the last
revision is 0-2 and the motivation for
this last version is that a few months
ago highness and heads up on 0-1 before
initiating a working group last call so
the the word the heads up was sent to
the core and eCPM working groups and
also to the ICC research group so after
that we received two reviews one by
three
oh you're right
just continue talking okay
yeah so version two so the last update
of the draft is actually aimed at
addressing the comments that we received
in those couple of reviews and so yeah
so also we expect 0-2 to be the version
that would possibly be intended for
working group last call so let's go
through the updates in this last
revision so we have one technical update
which is that the impact of strong and
weak estimators is now tunable that's
the impact of these two estimators on
the computation of the RTO as a result
and it is that in the previous version
of the document we we used some fixed
constant weights for the contribution of
the weak and strong estimators as you
can see those weights were 0.25 and 0.5
however in the new revision we have two
neural parameters for those weights
which are the ones highlighted in red W
weak and W strong which by the way have
0.25 and 0.5 as default values
next please so we also have quite a
number of material updates actually most
of the work in this last revision has
been editorial so first of all we have
extended the abstract in order to
explicitly indicate that the core of
this specification is an RTO algorithm
then in section 1 now we have a proper
introduction whereas in the previous
version the section was almost empty
then section 3 describes the area of
applicability of the document and now we
explained we have added that the
algorithm define being adaptive is
actually
intended for a wide range of network
conditions in terms of different aspects
such as network topology traffic load
different link technologies and so on so
related with that in section 4 which
focuses on RTO estimation now we
explained that we expect this algorithm
to run in in different conditions and we
expect a wide spectrum of our titties
ranging from few orders of magnitude
below the default RTO estimating go up
which is between 2 & 3 seconds and
greater values than that then also in
the same section we have added some some
content to the discussion we had on our
TT variability so previously we
explained that in coop we have
application processing times that
contribute to the coop party T which in
addition may be variable with different
distributions and we explained in
version 0 1 that this is something that
doesn't happen in TCP however now we
have also added that if TCP is using the
latest knowledge means there's also some
contribution in that case to the RTT
which also may be variable with
additional delays that may be up to 200
milliseconds typically or in theory up
to 500 milliseconds then another update
is in the subsection that needs a
discussion when we describe the measure
RTO estimate that's for the 2.2 and in
order to better motivate the need for
the weak estimator which is quite
unusual in the IDF we now explicitly
explain that the weak estimator
allows to update the RTO estimator when
our T DS are mostly weak so recall that
we carta T's are those for which the
sender has run into the transmissions so
this may happen for example when we have
really low ceilings or when there is
some congestion event that induces
losses as well
and we also explained that in the latter
if losses are due to congestion then the
the week estimator allows to update the
RTO actually increase the RTO as well
and this helps avoiding spears time outs
reducing the rate of retries and
decreasing congestion so we have also
added references to the base co-op
specification this is intended for
readers that might not be so familiar
with co-op and we have provided pointers
to specific sections and also to
specific parameters in several cases and
on the other hand we have also extended
section 7 which is it provides the
security considerations and we now
explain that an attack that manages to
prevent packet delivery will lead to an
RTO increase which may lead to a
performance decrease however well this
attack is not specific for cocoa or even
for co-op but anyway this might be
mitigated by means of network access
control and if the attack is performed
by means of radio jamming we are that
recovery from that situation can happen
in reasonable time when cocoa is used
because the the week estimator increases
the chances of obtaining RTD samples
even when there may be a large amount of
losses leading to almost only allowing
to get weak RTDs finally we have also
quite a number of updates regarding
appendices so first of all the old
appendix which was entitled aggregate
congestion control has been removed from
the document this was suggested by the
two reviewers mentioned at the beginning
of the presentation and this also
matches the actual intention of the
authors so this has been removed and
however we have added three new
appendices and this is b c and d the
first one appendix b provides pseudocode
on how the RTO estimator date works
also on how the RTO aging mechanism
works and also for the variable back off
factor on another appendix we have added
some examples where we provide numbers
on the calculations for the week our
titties
for the variable back of factor for
aging and we also provide some
explanations which try to clarify a
little bit the properties of these
mechanisms and finally we have added the
last appendix which provides some
analysis on which may be the difference
of the values the difference between the
values with the strong and the weak
estimator well so that's all for this
presentation any comments or questions
I did this honest thanks for the update
was really useful one question that
wasn't answered from my review is when
as a developer if I care about so the
reason why I would want to take your
document into consideration is because I
don't want to have this stop-and-wait
behavior that co-op over TCP provides me
with the in star equal to one so Biff
the advanced congestion control
mechanism I can actually change that and
have a value higher than one is that is
that correct so customer and the
congestion control doesn't take away the
stop and wait behavior so it's you still
have lockstep so in the request get a
response and request get a response can
I now have more than one an outstanding
request
re-imagining response no this document
doesn't modify and start for example so
what this document does is instead of
having the static setting for the RTO in
the base co-op which is between two and
three seconds now we compute the RTO on
the basis of RTD samples okay so um that
leads to my real question is I think it
would be nice to indicate on at what
point a developer shoe should actually
move away from co-op plus that type of
extension took over UDP to a model a
co-op over TCP like co-op over DCP was
motivated by a fired rubber or firewall
traversal but there may be other
motivations as well that relate to the
congestion control or specifically to
this behavior of sending multiple
requests which is sometimes also
annoying just does that make sense what
I'm saying actually you you have written
the text for that so the introduction
for Cordova TCP ya know provides
information to this question
it provides background for the coop of a
DCP but it yes provide the information
on at what point should I consider not
going for this document but then for
something more like I don't understand
what the complexity differences
neither the albick document on DCP
implementation guidance nor this
document nor any other document provides
me that type of judgment I think the
complexity in the complex city versus
the benefits isn't an too obvious to me
and maybe not to developers either
maybe it's obvious to you but yeah so I
don't remember the details but I think
we put some text in the Coco draft that
discusses what what the incremental
complexity is with respect to the base
congestion control but this is the
coatrack yes
yeah and I've read the Coco draft and it
wasn't India but maybe we got stripped
out let's check that okay and the next
question is when do you actually go
through TCP which is a bigger step and
that of course depends on on the
complexity that your specific platform
needs to run TCP it also depends on your
application whether that actually
benefits from an aggressive transport
protocol so in some sense or
environments it's actually a benefit to
not have an aggressive transport
protocol yeah fully understand that but
and that big TCP guidance document gives
me the impression that TCP is also
highly tuneable and there's there's a
lower pond as a higher bar and so I
don't see what the overlap is between
what is going on here - what is going on
in the elevator with returns terms of
users of a transport for the call and I
think there could be some additional
clarification of it specifically if
you're not like working full-time in a
transport area
and I maybe you have that information
written down somewhere already it would
be good to add it we happen to have the
author of the Eric physically document
very close so maybe that's actually
useful thing to add yeah yeah maybe it
needs to be added there I don't know
what the best place is but it would be
nice to have the information somewhere
yeah sounds good
now what what we don't have is numbers
where we can say by the way implementing
TCP takes you this amount of ROM space
and so on oh yeah there's only at the
moment ideal week document we have those
numbers but however only for a subset of
the implementations we are considering
so let's hope we can complete the
information at some point so the advice
that should be in the cocoa document is
that that if you have space to keep two
or three variables per year plus
vary where two or three formulas for
every packet to send appear then you
should do cocoa and not the basic
congestion control help then no takers
have that and we will consider now so
the next step of course is doing the
working class call so I managed to
decide when when to do that and the idea
is to make sure that's working last call
is done in a way that the the transport
working groups that have indicated
interest and also the convention control
resource a research group is in the loop
of that working across coil and I think
Alexei has something to say about how
his end wants to handle the history
process
you mean my idea of asking another ID
yeah I tend to ask birria to as you know
person more familiar with this stuff to
be the responsible lady and she did ask
recently what the status of the document
it was expired I said well it will be
renewed and so I'll talk to her again
thank you
okay so barring any other comments I
think we should check the the
conversation we just had with Sunnis and
then go forward in Glasgow
okay so next one is resource directory
and we have a remote presenter for that
you just have to hello do you hear me
yes we do thank you um my name is
Christina Moses and I'd like to present
the current status of the resource
directory document and the associated
resource directory DNS SD linking parts
I go I'll go through the through the
recent changes briefly and use them as a
set up of to show where we are with the
document and to ask some questions about
how we can proceed there there will be a
part about DNS St 2 which will be after
the actual rd text a slide please
one change we did since version 11 was
to introduce the introduced a number of
statements about what we think the RT
should do which basically amounts to
storing statement and storing links with
the same semantics they have when they
are when they are retrieved from
well-known core documents and allow
clients to fetch those links and query
those queries that information was the
same mechanisms they use when they are
doing regular multicast or well-known
core-based discovery an RD can also come
into play when when multicast is
unavailable or when there are other
reasons why you don't want to get that
information directly from the node dns
SD is not directly here in the
motivation because I'll show later that
we can do everything we need for
exporting to DNS st from what an RT can
do if it is designed without particular
consideration for our DD n SSD next
slide please so what is an inner
resource directory and
we flashed out how this looks textually
now as well the ERT contains links and
the top line shows how they look like in
an unco file they have a link target at
the left which is evaluated to a full
URI they have a link link source which
is usually the the well-known core
document or the the device itself and in
most Katyn most common cases it's
implied and has a relation or some other
link attributes and attributes that
describe the target so for example
resource type we transfer we take those
links up in the resource directory and
Express and replicate them semantically
which means that the serialization might
look a little different for example the
anchor as in the bottom line needs to be
explicitly stated because the document
comes from somewhere where this is not
obvious but some of some things like the
rail relate like the rel equals hosts
can still be implied by default so
Christie that they quickly mentioned
because the predictor is not very sure
oh great well this is great here and so
these are default values of the target
attribute so the actual well-known core
entry would just say this part here and
this is default it's on the with link
relation hosts and the empty anchor
those are the default they use and at
the point that Christian is trying to
make is that this can stay at its
default value but the anchor where you
actually has to change because in this
case it's the when on call environment
that provides the device itself but in
this case it's the resource directory so
this has to provide the other end of the
link the place where the link emanates
from all right Thank You cousin if you
go to the next slide please
there are some other entities in the
resource directory which is endpoints
and groups and points is mainly what
using to manage that a particular device
registered there and can have some
additional properties that are available
for querying and groups which are
aggregates of endpoints that typically
share a multicast address the next slide
please all these entities can be used in
queries across the resource directories
so you can look for as in the first
example query look for groups which
contain a particular node and then you
get a link to that group resource to the
place where the group is registered with
some additional data about the group
like what is its multicast address what
is it is its group name is it in a
particular domain you can so this is a
in this image this is a this users
information this queries down the the
stack you can also query APIs in the
next example where we are looking for
and for all endpoints that are in the
rooms group so this again gives us a
link to one registration resource which
is not particularly useful as well as a
link to a courier but contains
additional information in the metadata
for example this has an endpoint type or
what is the where is this registered
from from and most importantly it
contains the links which can be queried
not only by querying their their
attributes so for example you could have
a lookup slash rest query RT is temp and
get all temperature resources but you
can also query all resources that reside
on say n pound endpoints that are
wall-mounted as in this example next
slide please we we did some more changes
to I won't go through every single of
them but some are particularly
noteworthy we've added an information
model that that kind of provides the
whole set up we as I've shown on on the
first slide we've
nailed down how the resolution of your
eyes work so what is what is result what
does need to be resolved when how our
relative references are evaluated and we
removed sections about how those
registrations can be changed because we
don't have suitable content formats for
that yet
so we can't we can't specify how this
works anyway and we prefer to specify
how the general thing works and if
account if and when a content format
gets along that allows simple
modification or observation of
collections of links which everything in
the resource directory basically is then
this can be added to the resource
directory without further changes on the
of the information model and lookup and
next slide please so what are what are
the the next steps we've published
version 12 document a few weeks ago next
slide please
we do have some changes we know about
that we'd like to have in a version 13
document for example registering a
multicast address and fixing something
about that you can actually go up and
down and the in the image I have shown
before in the queries but there are also
slightly from some open questions
especially about how next slide please
especially about whether a group an
endpoint registration can be included in
a group even if it is not registered on
the same end on the same resource
directory which is really kind of doing
the icing because resource directory is
not originally specified to be federated
but it looks like it can be without
doing much on the specification side and
we'd also like to have some idea of how
this how the specification or how this
interface can evolve
without breaking older implementations
we invite you to join us on the issue
tracker all the those open issues and
also the pending ones are described
there and it would be very good to have
input from the working group on on those
and next slide please
we've really received comprehensive
reviews from Jim shot and Hannah's about
the 11 document thanks for that but I
think given that we'd like to go for
working group last foursome um it would
be good to have more reviews and also to
get input from people who are actually
implementing the resource directory so
as to expound on that now is a good time
to implement this stuff because we have
really cleaned up the document a lot and
at least for me as a co-author the
situation has started that they
understand what the resource directory
is about and how it works so I that
implement dusts can now be in the same
situation and of course there are
partial implementations in various
environments for instance like radium
terrarium uses the resource directory
but only a certain subset and doing the
the whole thing now seems possible and
it would be nice to get more feedback
honest I have a question on on the slide
on a changes like there was one note
about removed all methods that modify
links in existing registration and I was
following but this also means that if I
do an initial registration if I do it in
a registration would that prevent me
from changing the links there or is did
I misread you know you can you can do a
link registration and re registration
and this is currently the only way to do
it and the read registration is
semantically almost equivalent to
dropping your registration and
registering in you and this is what you
can do even without explicitly dropping
your registration so you can just pull
to the to the directory resource again
as you would do for example after a
reboot when you've forgotten that you're
registered and then the Rd will accept
that registration and now have an
updated set of set of links and this Lea
registration would that require me to
resend everything again
with the modified words so if I want to
remove one link would have to resend
everything or what I indicate that one
thing yes you will have to run resend
everything in that region re
registration because we don't have the
content formats yet that would allow you
to say this is a this is a patch on that
on that linked list and please remove
that particular link okay so that's
maybe it's something that we may need to
look into a little bit because in
unlikely there them at least
registration interface we were hoping
that we don't have to send everything
again when we do every registration when
the when the life time expires oh no you
don't wanna live time expires um you can
you can always keep your registration
alive so you can just post to the to the
registration resource you've obtained
but it will need to be an empty post and
it can't change the links can't it can't
change the links now but you can
register a new with a new set of links
so the important observation is that
right now we don't have a media type to
fetch a registration so we can hold a
replace it yeah we can refresh the
registration registration yeah but we
cannot say change the third star on the
top I was hoping that in earlier
versions of the document that might be
presented at that time patch wasn't
available so my hope was that once the
patch was available never actually do
different versions in their brief and
without patch that we would once patches
available would actually switch over to
pageant allow that patch to be used also
for a registration interface that
sounded like obvious to me but maybe
it's not so the decision was to define
that patch media-type in a separate
document because we don't have to hold
up this for defining that media type
okay I miss and and we had a pretty
interesting discussion at the OCF
meeting on Friday how to do that because
the the the current March page document
is geared up for having maps of things
and and you essentially replace things
in there by giving their keys but those
links it's on our maps they're arrays so
we we need a variation of merge patch
that that grabs into an array finds an
element of the array based on one of the
keys in the map that is the element of
the and replaces that and we have to
write that that must have been a
discussion after a ocf meeting it was at
the gym shot I vaguely thought I
actually saw that that that the map
stuff existed but I wasn't paying that
much attention at the time because I was
having a hard time fitting either a
patch but that's not actually why I
stood out there one of the things that
really worries me and I'm not too sure I
want to see the are deep actually
progress until we figure out how it's
supposed to interact with the new URL
schemes so that we because I'm not too
sure you want to you if something is
reachable by multiple schemes I don't
know that means you end up with multiple
endpoints and so forth and what that
means in terms of anchors um if if
you're registered um the current idea is
that if you're registering with multiple
your a schemes you will still have only
one registration and the pending
protocol negotiation document will
describe how you how you add your
alternative transports and how you can
query them in the resource look up so
that you finally get a resolved link
based on your preferred transport when
you're querying the resource directory
is that gonna make mi gonna have to
heavily modify my resource directory
implementation when that gets done or
pretty um you will need some
modification because you will need to
interpret the information that is now
provided in in whatever attributes that
came along but the changes should be
very minor they favor
what's the current state of the protocol
negotiation document no there was how
close is it to being done because I what
I hear Jim saying is that you have to
treat them together and that if you
haven't reviewed them both at the same
time then you're skeptical that this one
came whereas before that one right I
think that's what you're saying Jim and
so the real question is is the other one
also ready for working request call here
Jim are youing to put him through at the
same time as I'm not arguing for or
against but it's how I understand you
it's coming yeah so we know how ocf does
this we have an existence proof edit
can't be done but it still has to be
done
so maybe we can copy as much as possible
from from the ocf solution of the ER
that would be my personal preference but
that discussion needs needs to be here
yes and I take from the input that
that's really a blocking point for
finishing Rd because we need to
understand that now there are two kinds
of alternative transport situations
there are situations where you have
transports that are mostly equivalent in
most of their technical parameters so
one may go through a firewall the other
one may not but but once it works it
doesn't really make a big difference
which one you use and we have other
situations where we for instance combine
UDP access with SMS access
that's a very different situation and I
think we have to make sure that we
actually address both cases it might
name is empty so then I go back to you
to your reviews slide and yeah
I think we could just proceed to the to
the next slide which is which starts the
part about our ddns SD before we do that
a quick question who has an
implementation of a resource directory
at this point I mean yes
I mean it's partial but it's does
something so who has such an
implementation kind of kind of so we
have two implementations that do
something in the same space and
californium does have one Jim has one I
have an old one
a student that probably needs to be
fixed and I have a current one and
Christian has a current one so yeah so
did what I get from this is that we have
enough substance here that we actually
could start doing some intro plus
testing we didn't get this into place in
time for this hackathon but we might
want to use the time between now and the
next ITF to actually do a little bit of
virtual interrupt testing between our
implementations so how we do that we
have to find out but I think it would be
a good thing to start with that now okay
just yes yes um so I promised that we
would
that I chose that DNS SD works from vrd
what what what exports to DNS SD
unconditional needs is some support from
from the origin server so from the from
the endpoint that is providing the
resources to say that it wants to be
exported and to provide instance names
because they can't be derived from
anything that is that is present in the
resource directory otherwise the current
document that is that that should be
published about today describes this as
happening from a resource directory but
actually it can equivalently work from
the well-known core data as well so
while an exporting agent would typically
piggyback on an RD it can could just as
well do multicast discovery and export
whatever it finds from there to DNS st
how this works has not really changed
since DNS st was a part of the resource
directory I'm showing next slide please
I'm showing here on the top a typical
example of what it could what a resource
look look up could look like in the in
the Rd and the bottom half represents
that information in Indian SSD so our
next slide please
leave the information gets gets moved
around a bit but what is what is in the
in the DNS SD record is you DNS SD type
that is derived from the resource type
it is registered in the domain which is
shown in green it uses the instance from
from the from the link form a document
as an instance name if there is a if
there's a sub type to the resource type
that can also be exported to the to the
to DNS SD which is the proper part
this is the first on half of the day of
the dynasty continent the second is the
mapping to the actual address which
happens in a server and a text record to
form the complete URL again if the if
the link is not formed from from a DNS
name as the authority which is shown in
red here it could also be derived from
data in the resource directory but then
again could be derived in in any other
way just as well because there just
needs to be a or quad a record for the
thing that the server record points to
next slide please
before we go so a question on the part
in blue which is the Sto and so this
example uses an RT value with only one
dot in it there exist plenty of RT
values that are registered with IANA
that I have two or even three dots in
them so the question is when going to
DNS is there any problem because you
have the underscore sto mm-hmm is there
a problem if that has dots in the middle
of it funny fun thing is it isn't
because the way T and s SD works is it
doesn't work on the on the serialization
of the DNS record which usually uses a
dot to separate the segment but it works
on the on the actual DNS messages which
have fields that are not dots delimited
so there can be a dot for example in the
instance name or the resource type so it
sounds like no there's not a problem it
can work when there's when multiple dots
in the RT that comes whatever here's all
right yes sounds brittle to you um
I don't personally I don't like it very
much but given that there already can be
thoughts in the in the instance names
and implementations largely support that
but there is and this now brings us to
the next slide
still the open question of how those
things should
be mapped exactly because um what the
issue we are having here is that for
resource types there is a registry so
you could register the sto dot anything
resource type and there is a registry
for DNS as these service types which is
not the same registry and which is not
coordinated and most entries or many
entries will not need to be in both so
the question question yeah I realize I
may have phrased my question slightly
differently than I should have but you
probably answered the question I was
asking what I should have said was there
exist RT values with multiple dots and
here it into a sto plus a temp piece and
I should have asked how do you know
which dot discipline just boils down to
the same thing we have an open issue
about that one proposal is to say that
can you go to the previous slide please
if resource.type is unknown to the dns
SD exporter it should not be split by
any dot but it should be exported as
some type coop UDP with the whole
resource type of the subtype and
particular as a particular s do so
whoever registers a resource type can
say can also register a DNS SD type and
their sub types and along with those
registrations provide a pattern in which
by which those resource types can be
converted to DNS SD types so then the
DNS SD converter needs to be aware that
this RT scheme is handled like this
Indian Indian SSD but this information
needs to come from somewhere and
providing a simple pattern with the
registration would be one way of
handling that so Dave knowledge several
times three thank you said okay I'm Vic
for the question slide um yeah so if
we're expecting a server to know the
instance name and we're trying to have
the exporter make assumptions on how to
derive the service name why wouldn't we
just expect the server to be able to
drive or state what the service name
should be since we already expect it to
state what the instance name would be um
that's a viable suggestion and would be
an alternative to having that registry I
figured this might look like having not
an X but an X in s with the particular
service name could be done I think and
might be a better option so the the
objective when this was designed was to
have the the expansion's attributes kind
of generic so the the node that exports
these attributes doesn't really have to
think in DNS SD terms they might be
other lookup schemes that I use that
generality is not needed so I think
that's a good discussion Trevor yeah
because it sounds like you know your
resource types particularly as they
start getting you know hierarchical you
know sto dot whatever you may be your
exporters might not know that but your
server should if they if they
particularly if they have to know the
instance name we know that there is a
strong argument that the evolution of
the various parts of the system can go
on and in parallel so if the device
already knows about the resource drive
that the exporter doesn't know about
that should work the device should be
forced into a weird situation there so
there I think that's a good idea
okay
nobody else is running to the microphone
so let me just as an author comment on
the pace in which this document has gone
on for a long time we have had
essentially a little bit of progress at
each eye each EF but nothing in between
and if you look at the commits that on
the github repository now it really has
taken off and we have significant
progress and we want to keep up that
pace and and finish this work so again
comments like like those from from
tamiya that's really useful input and
that would be good if you could provide
us with that input so timeline to
preempt a question that Jim is perfect
to have not another Christmas tree but
we shouldn't go on with this much longer
than the London ITF I think ok thank you
thank you Christian you on the engine
room screen you have this really weird
look because your glasses reflect the
light and you have these blue glowing
[Music]
presentation from outer space okay Thank
You Kristin so we had a video and I'm
sure the comic people will squander that
thanks and now for a presentation down
to earth let's say that we'll take a
little bit more time
so we are going to be talking about
carmine and so I'm going to be giving a
couple of updates since the last time so
on a very macro level you can see the
main drafts that are part of this
package here it's a little bit offset so
basically so here we have the tree main
draft documents that are the yang to see
bro mapping this draft and come by
itself so we had some actions from the
last time which were riveted drafts
perform interrupts deployed asset
registry like down to the straight to
the point so on the update and on the
review of The Drifter different drafts
the yang to seaboard draft hasn't moved
because one of the things that we said
is these three drafts basically they're
moving in as a package right the moment
that we have some inter up and and that
we see that everything is working weld
and we do the working group last call
for all the three of them so basically
here we are ready for working group my
last call since IGF 97 which was not
three years ago unfortunately or
fortunately then we have the courseid
that is stable for two IDF's now and the
comma which is the one that is mostly
evolving for the moment so and then
there are some new drafts that that have
been added that are allow the whole
system to be working very nicely but
these are like just some extras so where
are we and this is the point that we
actually start talking this one works
okay thanks this way I'm not going to be
able to I don't need to turn around
always so we have existing
implementations as I said since the last
time we had some and right now we are
really improving our implementations so
we have two implementations that are
proprietary implementations one is go
line when you see
we have two partial implementations that
we had some knowledge from the last IDF
and one of the goals was for this IDF to
have an interrupt with at least two
implementations of them and to have a
hackathon so in order to produce an
open-source implementation or at least
put the basis of an open-source
implementation because it always goes
through the open source so we needed to
scale back a little bit on our initial
expectations because some of most of the
key people that are were not able to
come here to Singapore
and so we needed to scale back on this
but we did our best so I'm here to
present what is our best at this point
well after several changes and many many
discussions we actually managed to do a
virtual Interop over the internet
between two implementations so the first
point here is that one of the
implementations actually manages to run
a full calm eye with a subset of the
functions that are fetch patch and post
for our pcs running on ipv6 the other
one is full but you know can
interoperate with itself so it's not
much enough interoperability between two
different implementations so the point
that we really did was to say okay we
need to have at least these
implementations to be able to show that
they are running so we have fetch which
is the basic of everything where you can
go and can really retrieve information
from the server so here the client and
you can retrieve information from the
server so the type of request that was
so we needed to have a use case a test
case so we was using the module ITF
system and more specifically we were
just trying to get the system date right
what is the current time so we have the
seat file that is generated for this
with the seed allocation that allows you
to actually build the whole kamae system
up
and through this these are the the first
results that we have so we are able to
okay do this so I we are able to fetch
single values fetch a container fetch
two values in one single request that
are announced two separate values
whenever we try so we found some issues
with some of the implementation so we
are now it's like minor bugs we are
fixing this and with this we actually
managed to validate the yang to see bor
string mapping derive types container
representations and we have also
validated the delta encoding and having
Delta euro like Delta compared to the
URI that is given in the fetch request
so this is a first result of a first
interoperability like an a basic use
case that is out there from two
implementations independently mutations
and that is pretty good given the time
that we had to you know to do this since
the last IGF we are quite happy about
this of course our goal is to go and to
do much more until the next idea next
point so yeah but before I go to this I
would like to share some of the lessons
learned through this through this
interrupt so the first thing is that ITF
system may may not may not be the may
not be the easiest module to use as an
interoperability basis and one of the
things is basically you know we want to
test everything we want to say okay is
there this is an integer this is a
string this is slow this is you know we
want to be able to have like a basics
all the things that can be presented
present in a yang module we want to be
able to but to go there and do like
fetches and patches and and have all
these nice stuff that we can have with
them and gets and puts so and just so
that we have like this unitary tests and
that we can do one against the other
so one of the things that we are
starting to do and this is starting
again right now so we are ramping up we
had so to give you a short idea of the
timeline that we had until the past IGF
we had be weekly meetings so we were
managed to advance pretty well from
since the last IDF to this one it was
like summer and all these kind of
different issues that that happened so
we were less we didn't manage to have
this beautiful virtuous meetings and
right now we are restarting them again
so we are restarting two weeks from now
in order to define this interoperability
suit and to be able to have it ready for
the hackathon in ITF 101 so that's the
first issue that we would like to
address is to have this basic young
modules in order to test this
functionality on the protocol level and
here this is a question also to have
maybe net mod have already established
such a baseline yang modules for testing
I'm not aware but now I see Eric saying
no so no so maybe it is something that
we could contribute also to the network
community so that's the first point the
second point is that you know these
famous Delta encodings that are super
efficient and are really really nice and
we really do like them and one of the
things is that and with Andy we were he
was also saying this in the past it
could be a little bit tedious when we
are trying to debug complex requests and
complex queries that have different you
know you have several sub trees and and
you could get a little bit lost in case
you you're just so lonely watching that
watching the payload and of course with
with the right tools this is not a
problem but we are not there yet
having the full tools that we have all
the you know the burgers that keep
everything in place so one of the things
is that we are really would like to
propose is to have this option in the
server and or the client that can say
okay well you know I would like to
disable for this session this the Delta
encodings and then we go and tag the
sits with seaport actor 39 that has been
allocated it's an identifier and it's to
just to indicate hey this is the sit it
is not the Delta said it is it is
directly to sit and the same the
simplest thing in this is that you know
you in your code you just need to
whenever the code is parsing it you know
they don't need to do anything special
they are just doing Delta Delta oh
that's not a delta so I'll just take the
value as it is and I continue so it is a
pretty straightforward solution
it helps debugging and you know you run
your server in advance in the bug
environment you debug and then whenever
you decide that it's good well it is
able it by reaction to this is you can
do that but don't kill anyone I mean you
really should fix up your to it store
handle this it's not that hard and I
think doing this this take 39 heck is
about the same amount of work as fixing
up those two is so why don't just fix up
those two it's and do the right thing so
I think one of the things is good when
we want to have an interrupt is to I
mean we can say okay we're going to do
this dirty hack but if you can have it
on your interrupts that would be really
cool so please everyone hack you're good
and then you know just the hack it so
yeah somehow III agree with this but
it's it is a very neat solution I don't
see any back and any any any problem
with it like you a long-term problem
that could appear but the long-term
problem is that this stuff is in
production systems don't do that okay
even if it appears in production system
it C it is going to waste - let's say
bandwidth from although it's going to
jeopardize interoperability because I
will never implement it I mean it's way
too easy to fix that words to show the
right values I mean you don't really
want to
see the city anyway you want to see the
actual identifier so you need to have a
tool to do that anyway so I think that
that's yeah you you're trying to run a
marathon on crutches and and that that's
not going to work very well I honest
probably agrees with me
so Peter meet the famous I won't be
very original I support Carson's remark
fully I don't think he should add
complexity to reduce complexity sorry ok
so that's a point point taken that's
improved so another point that we had
from this first interrupt was that
actually we have this minimal set that
is pretty straight forward and that
allows us to have the full functionality
of comma and the one of the points that
we'd like to do to just state there is
that it is possible to have coming
minimal plus comma extended and let's
say call my minimum is fetch patch and
post for the are pieces and then we can
have a very simplified document and you
have a second document or like two
sections where the second section builds
up upon on the first one and then we say
okay you know if you want to do a get
put post in all these nice operations
then you know this gets transferred to
patch this or fetch this so this way we
can like really go with that with comma
minimal
come I extend it and you know we
basically it boils down to this like we
have these implementations and we will
be very happy to have other people
having different implementations but
until we have this is the only thing
that we'll be able to interrupt
so that's about the implementation part
and the lessons taken now on the
hackathon well on the hackathon we do we
did start an implementation so we
started with with a specific specific
module in mind because we wanted to have
a specific use case so in this case we
started with the shake context
compression so we expressed shake in
yang and then we started you know like
building the whole the whole system
around it I can declare partial success
so yeah we started it we have the yang
module and everything is working and
then a partial failure because actually
I made some maybe not the best choices
in the use of the in the choice of the
Python tools that were out there and so
we reached or yeah we reach to some
point where we understood that the the
choices of the basic libraries that we
chose for Yang actually makes it super
difficult to make the Seabourn encoding
well so I need to go back a step
this was after discussion with the
medmont team and basically rebase the
development of the of this part with ydk
which is the yang development kit which
based on your yang file produces Python
code so this is the only thing that
needs to be done so I was really hoping
that we'll be able today to come and say
hey we have this working baseline
implementation it needs you know it's
interrupts with these other parts but I
think that we should like step back a
little bit and prepare for for the next
for the official hackathon that will
take place at the ITF 101 and where most
of the people that are actually quite
active and which and who are working a
lot at in come on come I will be there
so then will be will be
really around the table and really
really be able to advance with this so
that's about the hackathon and so as I
said next steps be weekly meetings from
now on that will ensure that we have the
full interrupts in London with the
fetchin patch so something like as I
said to call my minimum and have the
hackathon also and prepared the
open-source implementation from their
own so these are the next steps and on
the yang to see board documents I get
the feeling that we will not be
introducing the option 39 it looks so
cool it's off some problems and the
option worst was there so okay so that
one is done and on the Kamiya documents
what we could what we propose to do so
this is like an option and this is
something I would like to hear the
working group if you have any opinion on
this would you like to see how my
minimal and come I extended if this will
give come I minimal like it's just going
to be like removing a lot of text of the
current document simplifying some stuff
and having three basic operations and
then having like maybe a second section
that does this or a second document that
that does the firt that that you is the
first the current document proudly shows
all those best verbs that we have get
until e8 and post and in my chest it
shows how to to use them with comai so
this is all wonderful but it's a lot of
complexity I don't know how many media
types we are generating there and it's
not really solving a big problem so
maybe this minimal form is a good thing
but maybe another way to look at this is
it might make sense to edge catch as as
a third message that we want to support
but that's it so we don't really want to
do the other things if you want to
modify something it's not really a very
onerous to do a batch and only if you
just want to get at a single item may be
supporting get as the third message
might make sense and we wouldn't have
two different versions two different he
said which was always an apology so I
really yeah that that's something that
we really looked at it and we discussed
about it and the thing is that in get
you have a URI so if it's simply having
a gear to sit so you can forget and you
want to get one item that is identified
by one sit it's super easy there's no
problem with this the question is if you
want to do a get on an item that is part
of a list okay but then what's I mean
the then the problem is that your get is
super partial like you can only get some
some items like a super subset of the
thing so you need to say okay did part
of the things in my yang module I can do
it I can obtain I can get through a get
and parts I cannot maybe it could make
sense if you want to say okay you know I
can only get like the first level of the
things like if I have a first level
element like if it's a container I can
do a get and I'll get the whole stuff if
it's an item I can get a single leaf I
can get this leaf but if I want to get
like the first item of a container maybe
now this one I could get also but you
know if I have a list then I cannot I
will do a get and I will get the whole
list I cannot say okay I want this item
of this list the examples actually they
get so I just wanted to throw this in
the room that maybe we don't want to do
a minimal and an extended but we won't
simply do the right thing and that may
be exactly fetch and match odd may be
fetching fetch plus
more method like hmm but looks let's
look through the examples and see what
actually makes sense we don't have to
support all of risk just because it's
there okay sounds reasonable I try to do
this to do the to do the exercise to
provide how would it look like without
the other methods and if we only have
the get method some I mean we have it
working even now so first it's a it's a
question of text editing so that's on
Carmi and now on Sid so cities the
identifiers that are used income I and
here just a short reminder so ass it is
simply a 64-bit number that's of course
it is a 64-bit but in because it's
expressed in C bar it can be on one byte
to buy it's four bytes and and so forth
so it's pretty dynamic it is a file so
you have like a young schema that
represents the reason that that map's
the reason or C bar if you want and then
you have the lifecycle of a model and
you have allocation policies so you have
a two-tire allocation policy that you
have the first one is managed by Ayana
it's called the mega range registry and
you know Ayana allocates chunks of 1
million sits and then we have a second
level registry that people go and you
know can much more actively allocate
range sub-ranges so since the last time
we have these three that are solved and
this one that was somehow you know we
were not here is it really solved are
there any problems so we discussed again
and again with with I Anna we discussed
also it so many people and I said ok you
know we should not be just keeping the
working group last call for this these
are things that could be solved when it
comes to Ayana and then we say ok well
there is this detail or this detail that
should be will be changed but generally
the document is good so
that's that it's good we have not have
not changed anything so right now the
next thing is okay so what about it yeah
Peter the founder stock a very simple
question bomb of the sheet generation
tool for the moment it's difficult to
know where it is will be part of the ITF
useful tools really help yes thank you
Peter so that's actually an excellent
question
so you know so whenever you have a yank
file you have a tool to generate the
seed files of the correspondence it's a
tool that's like a plugin for PN so it's
like it's the super standard thing that
people use for yang and it's just like a
plugin it is not yet in the main branch
but it has been stable for a long time
now so what we did was basically we put
it we made a web interface to around it
we wrapped it up and it works and since
this weekend so this was like the
partial hackathon that we had around
some several virtual places we have also
set up the seed registry so this is the
first seed registry that is that is out
there that is in some kind of a minimum
value of MVP Mode minimum well protected
so we will start operating it a little
bit illegally
just to see how it goes right in the
second million of the of the sit
registry because there is for the moment
there is no megasuck mega range its
registry
Ayana has not created this so we cannot
legally obtain like 1 million blocks to
start to play with so what we are going
to do is we are going to say hey we
pretend as if we have this thing by the
time the last were the working group
last call passes and Ayana goes all
through the whole process and the mega
range registry is created but in the
meantime we will get the feeling and
people will start using it and hopefully
you know it will just get translated at
the moment everything is in place we
will just say ok yeah it's there so we
have this too
but the single context that's the normal
thing to do when you write a document in
creating our in a registry you provide
an initial population of that registry
so in this case you would say the the 1
M 2 to M range is taking up by this okay
yeah so so doesn't know what's going to
do and so this is the DCT interface so
we have so this is the best the basic
the login page so this was this has been
existing for like a couple of months now
so you can come and then you can click
on login all this stuff so you come in
you register so you fill in some
information about yourself like from
which country and so forth we have a
super secure way of actually the
thinking is your computer or not so
we're using reCAPTCHA and then once you
have signed up you can log in and then
if when you have logged in you can see
all the modules that are available on
the system yeah there was a question
yeah yeah there's a comment by Michael
is up just a second I don't if he happen
he thinks that the minimum is a select
merge format where the select user links
attribute values of merge works under I
think he's going to make a proposal on
the select merge but I think it was also
finish line so sorry
ok ok so you have this welcome page and
here if you if you go to and you see so
this could be sensors Peters question
here you have the tools right away you
have seat file generation sit validate
and sit consistency check so if you
click on these links you don't need to
go on to login to do this you just
provide your rank file on a web
interface and then it produces you to
sit visit so what you need to do is you
need to login request a seat range so
for example your the 10 C user you go
there and use the 10th company and
you'll get the range from 1 million ten
thousand to 1 million 11
so these are your 1000 seats and then
you go here on this file generation you
click and you say okay I have these
thousand seats this is my yang file and
then the tool populates the produces the
seat file that corresponds to it and
puts the correct seat files and then you
can go up and upload the seat file to
the to the to the to the registry and
then it gets fixed and locked in this is
my tears for the minutes so where did
you set this up sorry where did you set
this up so I see these nice screenshots
but how do I get there okay so so
actually actually so yeah so you see so
these are all the nice the nice things
here so you have to hear the when you
when you log in you have the the seat
ranges that are there so your account
the cedar ages that are mapped to
different idea to different link from
ways so there is a big there is a small
problem here but I tried it no it's not
working now no it was it was working
yesterday even so I think that we had
some update program during the night you
know people working in some other time
zones were updating stuff and right now
it's not working but it will be working
by the in the next two or three days
like you can we can just go and and and
and lock it and you can just go and log
in and try it and as I said so this one
this one these two these three points
were actually addressed by what Carson
said so this is like the first place
that we'll be testing the whole thing
the most important thing is also to get
feedback on the the behavior of how
things are behaving like people can say
hey this is really not working for me
I would like you to see the the process
in this way around this way it's not the
important part like this we can change
this process the most important part is
that we have the registry that people
register there sits and that we have
this nice process where we avoid land
grabbing and you know we and we flee
defy this this process so and we we
don't overburden Ayana with every small
module someone can want to register
somewhere around the world so these are
the design
these are the the design constraints
that we put to ourselves so right now
the question is do we do a skull on it
or do we wait more we would like to see
some cross validation with net mod and
you know that that we started getting
all these discussions but what is the
right time to do what is right thing to
do as a next step so the last IDF we
said document is pretty much ready for a
group but we wanted to see an interim so
maybe you can actually continue what you
started at this weekend
couple more days and write up a little
bit of report about that and then send a
message to the palest explaining what
you did and what your experiences were
and of course you should do this in a
way that other people who want to
participate in that so I think that's
what we said last time you want to have
that interrupt and we are halfway
through I think that's the the yangtze
border cured and maybe the yangtze
border human also is the first one we
actually want to Lascaux because this is
one where we need very close
coordination with net mod and so that's
something that you really need to look
at the the other documents are more core
specific and I think we don't have such
a high coordination requirement there so
we can do our normal two week working
last part so we can probably do those a
little bit later and use the time to
continue on the intro okay so I agree
on this point on the go with you at this
point about the sit so draft course it
will actually you use a yang file to our
yang module to define the structure of
the file or I mean the structure of the
CID file so the the way this the way
these information is stored for all the
citizens oh sorry the way this
information is stored is actually
described as a yang file it's a young
schema and moreover we are basically
saying okay well they are so these are
some useful things to know about about a
yang module so we have this basic M
module and then we have these like
correspondence when we say they did well
there is this link there is this URI and
this is the city that is allocated so
it's some kind of a meta information
about the it's superlight meta
information about the initial yang
module so the question is maybe you guys
from that mod would like to at least
take a look at it and say well you know
well I mean we started talking to them
and they say okay that's pretty
interesting we'll we'll review it but
just just saying that at some point you
know we may also try to to to offer
their opinion okay I'm going I'm going
to take this in this one I think it's
better and so with this I have finished
Alex yeah Michael Richards means asking
if you can use comai to allocate seat
ranges to use command to allocate see
what's it ranges that's an excellent
idea
I think that I will invite him on the
next Interop to come and decode the the
part into the citric history code but
yes that could be really cool that would
be yeah it's possible and so now I'm
going to pass the word but before
passing the word to the mic to to Hank
who on hankies okay so during this
hackathon there was something really
interesting that happened and that was
that people on the next table were
really really busy bringing this new
great feature to the world of yeah
that is push so yank push that is used
for telemetry and that's that what's
really interesting is that this is
actually a cross working group work so
you have sockem net conf and core that
are working on this and you have a very
interesting way to to see how you you
have like a whole process so basically
for the moment it's using XMPP you have
a process to to see how a collector or
something that is observing like like an
observer can go and can discover devices
can see what is happening in real time
can hack and have update streaming
events from what's happening from the
configuration and operational data and
so this thing okay so it will each one
the best cross working group of
collaboration work and what is really
important is that for the moment it is
using so there is this new technology
that's called yank push and it is based
on that content Resco for the moment and
right now it's actually the moment to go
and and go to deeper into the car my
world into the world of IOT into the
world of very efficient
tallip telemetry and Hank and Eric in a
couple of other people have actually
wrote and they have written draft on
this that is the problem statement and
now Hank is going to to say in much
better way what it's all about
thank you yeah hi I'm Hank um next slide
so yeah young pushes build and designed
in Netcom for group leading parties are
for example co-authors of this problem
statement about the there a lot more
people involved in that it's called the
yang push design team essentially
written with a Z I think that's a
tradition so we created a problem
statement that basically tried to
actually effectively identifying gaps in
the co-op realm and the Kumaran in order
to create Akamai datastore that would
support the same push operations that
are already be able to be conducted via
net conf and rest conf so the natural
order of things would be to now make
this happen
komai first of all telemetry means in
this context that the data store
contains state and that state is a kind
of subscription to change its
configuration operational data so in
essence if you think back a few 10s of
years SNMP traps we're doing the same
thing and they're now reached yang so to
speak and our faciliate hid in extra
quota calls that a net conf
and restaurants so the streaming of
continuous changes happens on the device
without further interaction coming from
the client we have a lot of things to do
here
for example we sometimes want to have a
subset of things from the module we do
not want to subscribe to everything like
as a thousand leaves in the module so we
have a filter expression in this
subscription which is for example
differentiating it from the pub sub that
is already existing in coop and in the
end it will enable data motion that is
way more safe descriptive than it is now
using standard modules I think about 800
in audio is already defined in the IDF
and therefore the principle of not
reinventing the wheel is being applied
here also using coop and the binary
representation via of course in the
future enable
far better scalability I mean this is an
overused term but it effectively really
will enable a lot of more telemetry on
the wire especially if composite devices
start to have their own data stores
inside them so a device might be a set
of multiple data stores so how are we
planning to do this um fetch is not only
able to do then observe operation to
basically establish a subscription but
also is able to convey a filter
expression due to its capability of
containing a body so we are creating
media types that will be enabling
XPath expression for example all as we
just heard a specific get on a subtree
to get everything from that set down if
it's a leaf it's just one value copy or
container so you can also do subtree
subscriptions with the gates basically
without the filter expression I think
all right so I have to think about this
is what's coming up just before my
report here so we're going to do right
at least two drafts
I'm not highlighting here that there's
something called call home I'm just
mentioning that now so the data store
sometimes wants to yeah find a suitable
client that it's supposed to subscribe
to it and this can be triggered by just
initiating the ETS or DTS connection and
then say peer allowed to send and then
the rules change the client then starts
the dynamic subscription for example and
then we go into the realm of it on
whirring bootstrapping and such result
that might be a little bit complicated
for today we're starting with the fetch
and get operations with the observe to
get the subscriptions on Akamai ah data
store the one thing here is that um
komai is not really very visible in that
confer group so we are trying to
remediate that situation by bringing all
more net conf people looking into a
specific
this new draft it would be the
subscription to the kamae datastore and
my rough educated guesses that will be
about 45 fine 7% experts from coal mine
and a little bit more experts from I
come very to make this a feasible
document and a feasible approach so I
think this is my little report yes it is
and the first questions from Hannah's
Hank
when you say XPath do you really mean X
bar is it kind of my staff is that it's
a very powerful mechanism and maybe
maybe that's intentional or maybe I'm
not sure in what the functionality that
is very true so we have the sub-tree
concept which is basically done by
getting a specific city and everything
below it this is also this is the other
alternative that is existing in yang 1.1
RFC and Eric has a I think sophisticated
answer to the rest of the XPath question
yeah basically we intentionally with the
egg push did not limit the XPath
elements that can be used we leave not
to implementation and anybody at this
point can choose what subset they want
to support because it's very difficult
to choose which subsets you want that we
certainly didn't want to do it
generically across all kind of
technologies so we're a lot of the the
standard allows XPath implementations
will choose which things are why that
probably doesn't work like from an intra
bility point of view you can because
it's almost like a scripting language
XPath is it so you can't just send at
the end and assume but what is the what
is the anticipated interoperability then
like it's a minimum set that you need to
abort and if you provide something else
then you bounce back and say error we
formulate your question or
English has a RPC mechanism where if
something's not supported it provides
back a look and a pointer to what is the
current error with the or the current
non-supported element so we do have a
great response mechanism in the RPCs for
the filter so let me have it before the
next question comes in that we are
targeting two sides of the same coin
here first of all we are targeting less
volume on the wire and more self
descriptiveness of today basically raw
values that are pushed around so that's
supporting unsolicited push those
informations and we actually know what's
happening what's pushed to you this is
not a IOT this is just another and one
at enhancement and natural progression
of how to make better use of your
resources then on the other hand we have
constrained devices and they might not
really like the complexity of XPath
expressions and answering our pcs all
the time so you can fall back of course
to the most simple way to do just a
sub-tree subscription this is to be CDs
hider this is will be stuff we have to
discuss when we divide the drop in
progress or offer now Eric has a comment
yeah to follow up on the other answer
because this is related the yang push
does allow filters and we have transport
drafts for Netcom HP to comité so it's
possible to put for transport what
specific filters or what elements you
want to support so there's no reason you
cannot apply additional constraints by
transport if that's the way you choose
to do in limit what's there while the
overall mechanism is in place so there
are definitely by transport additional
technology selections which are allowed
as we expand past the base
implementation that we used in the
hackathon which was Netcom true so Tim
carry no key idea but question as I was
trying to figure this out because you
know I won for look telemetry when we
look at you know normal notes not IOT
constrained notes I mean it does a very
nice job of giving a general framework
for
for pushing data right limitary in in an
IOT rolled with with constrain devices
you know originally we had this thing
called observe that kind of did that
right so I'm trying to understand how
we're going to get this if you ever look
at the push framework it's a well it's a
rather heavy framework when you compare
it to something that's constrained and
so I'm trying to figure out exactly what
this means to constrain devices that you
know observed was was all they really
needed and and then what what does push
really look like in that context I I'm
very concerned that you know as we start
bringing the stuff over from net mod and
net conf and we get all the things that
go around you know more expectations
that you would have on on routers then
you would I have on on IOT device that
you know this this framework working
really working a it might work on a
constrained Network but it would be
difficult to justify in a constrained
node and I'm just trying to understand
you know what you guys are thinking
about in terms of observe vs. push in
telemetry this is this is touching the
topic of a call home or finding a home
to call home to if your boot strapping
or if your drop ship or if you're
imprinted or if you enrolled at some
point you want to send out data as an
Alex II device a lot of mechanisms how
to bring the things into the field and
this here allows for a very slim down
semantics well-defined output that is
interoperable with everything else it's
already out there which is a big benefit
if you have a lot of other devices that
are already data stores a lot of post
processing infrastructure that can
handle all that information it is kind
of practical if the things it's just
appear in your domain and
then push information to you can be
processed and just like the exactly same
way there is a homogeneity to the
complete process that in simplified
interoperability drastically also what
you are getting it is it is a hazard
huge overhead so but an IOT device can
have some hard-coded someone I wish the
video would see that one other item
there is a parallel structure you might
guys might have heard of DDS service the
same mechanisms are shown to work on IOT
devices there's our proof points that if
you don't require deep filtering there
are implementations which do similar
stuff except it's not using yang it's
using you know whatever the language is
there so customer the underlying
question here is is yang good for you
and I think that that's a complex
question and not everybody will answer
this question with yes but for those
areas where where yang is actually
useful technology to work with the next
question is can we make that scalable
and scalable not upwards but as we are
always interested in downwards so okay
can we define a version of this this
yang push environment that actually
makes sense on a limited device that is
probably not going to be your light
switch it's probably going to be a
little bit more powerful device so I
don't think we are targeting class one
devices here but still can can we make
this work in a way that it's not
dominating the the actual application
that is running on the node but it's
available for making these event streams
available for for telemetry purposes and
right now I wouldn't say yes sure
we're trip still trying to do that but
I'm pretty optimistic yet to add to that
comment that's that's what the problem
statement which is published has really
highlighted the first section most of
the building blocks are there and
they're actually quite feasible to build
something way more static then the
typical data store if you're required to
do so if you do not have the resources
to react in a RPC interactive error
detecting way and now I - Hank I was
waiting to hear the answer to Tim's
question about how does this relate to
observed mechanism is it it is using the
observed mechanism that's how it related
it it is a fetch observe the body there
is a filter expression or okay because
maybe you have an example in the in the
problem statement document which I
didn't need to look at but my
understanding of the observe was and
some of the other work that was done
they were filters separately defined for
observe and then you use the observe
mechanism to send the notifications but
what we heard earlier I believe I heard
was you use a different filter
expression mechanism and maybe the
answer that you get is also different so
maybe maybe just an example in in the
slides or in there in the document
withheld through the document understand
the unfortunately the this is this is
bad conduct I think the problem
statement has a lot of approaches as for
suggestions to make it better
understandable so it's not only a
problem statement but it's also a set of
proposed solutions unfortunately which
is bad conduct we should have done this
in two documents but the bias now are
the problem statement by providing for
every solution area a set of proposals
how to solve this and we already in this
it is already outdated so we had a few
days to talk about this and we already
advanced
those but there are examples in there
yes so I asked for this presentation
mainly so that the group has the heads
up that that this stuff is happening
again I'm I don't think we're in a
situation yet where we can say oh this
has been proven to work it's obvious
that we want to go there there still is
a need for for additional work but then
it's good for the working group to know
that this work is going on and and some
people may want to take part in that so
I'm not I don't think we are asking the
working group to take on this work today
yeah please do not adopt a problem
statement
this is Mattias I try to make sense out
of this for the minutes so in the
beginning I saw there is this push
framework using XMPP and you use XPath
and so on okay when so so what I
understood is that you said hey this
overall mechanism could be good also for
constrained environments so you're
looking for the equivalent over what
whom I does already in this space is
that's kind of a good summary ignore the
slide there's nothing to do with core
fact is that yes core and core can be
used here and that's it
ignore the slide this slide shows how
pushed information can be post processed
in a security automation domain that a
second and can be used to create apology
pictures by unchanged subscriptions for
neighborhoods discovery between devices
and or whatever if your USB serial
connector just was connected and your
switches now many really locally
configured these are change events in
operational State that can be pushed to
a second collector and then be further
distributed in security automation
domain that is able to detect anomalies
does machine learning or something else
so this is basically a application of
young push and we want this to be
bolder than that conformist community we
see a lot of applications that are
already trying to create multiple data
stores per device and the number of
telemetry streams will increase
drastically if this process of this
trend continuous so please ignore this
light in the context of cohab it's quite
appstats here these are just the results
from decathlon okay but you're still
looking for something that kind of fits
the overall ecosystem using yang using
the push mechanism and so on but you're
looking for this blue part that was at
the bottom going to the devices it
should use kind of the same how we model
data how you transmit it but you're
using for a good transport that uses
coop the coop observe and some some
optimized futures and not the experiment
and heavyweight stuff we are still on
not unsure how to deal with a very
complicated XPath stuff I think they
have to be a bit compromises this is the
interest most interesting thing that's
not been discussed yet it's about the
media types of emissions we have to do
but in general you're correct
there as the fact is there's so many
yang modules out there and and most of
them are actually kinda useful I mean
despite the 800 done by ITF that about I
think 2000 then in total by the industry
so there's a lot of good stuff out there
and and not making use of that it's
kinda redundant and probably not the
best idea so that that's that's one of
the more drivers for using yang again I
know people are kind of fed up with that
term at some point I know and some other
stos use something else entirely which
is not necessarily better other ways to
express models and this is just another
way to ensure long-lasting
interoperability and reducing redundancy
and defining models for data that has
been transported for years already
again I'm waved from the square thank
you
so as I come he has managed to time
advantage completely and we will move
the pub/sub part two to a Tuesday so we
have a chance to get Adrian who is only
here today to quickly talk about a
payment of our couette and thank you for
other questions and so this was a
last-minute decision to come to this
session based on interactions I had last
week at w3c TPACK with wave of things
working group and and some people there
so I chair the payments working group at
WC and there's a note there's a number
of API is rolling into browsers today
for payments the way they work is that
the website constructs a payment request
which it submits to the API and in that
request is a set of accepted payment
methods so the API itself and the data
model is quite generic and you could put
anything in there what has emerged as a
desire from part of that working group
as well as the web things working group
to look for ways to bind that same data
model to alternative transport so not a
browser API but the the initial proposal
was HTTP the the people I spoke with in
San Francisco interested in exploring if
bindings would also be with digging into
so the the expected interaction would be
some thing makes a request and instead
of getting a response to that request it
gets a request to pay the payments made
some other way and then the request is
retried so it's it's it's likely the
work will continue within a w3c group
for some time but making you aware of it
in case you're interested in getting
involved they double through see I've
created a mailing list so if you are
interested just join that
Public IOT palest and the work will
probably get moving in the next few
weeks and that's it yeah so if you look
at the way this payment required the
stuff works that that is really
reminiscent of the way ace handles the
case where you access a resource server
and and are not authorized to do it yet
so probably the the right group to
present this in would have been the ACE
group but there is only happening
tomorrow here today so I think that
that's a useful thing to keep in mind
there there is a payment infrastructure
being defined and that will need some
ways to reach down to constrained
devices and my present example is is
always a coffeemaker I want to be able
to instruct the coffeemaker to make a
career for me but if that coffeemaker
requires payment how do I do this with
co-op today and so probably the ACE
framework is actually already quite
useful for doing that
so it probably makes sense to bring
these things together in some form and
it may be interesting to look at so the
way their data model works is it's quite
possible that the response can be very
static so your coffeemaker could be
pre-configured or have a very static so
it could work very well in a very
constrained device as well it doesn't
need to do any payment processing itself
it would need to be able to do something
like produce the payment request
information which could be very static
and then validate maybe a token later
that proves payment happened somewhere
else so it's I think the model would be
applicable in constrained space then
constrained devices but I'm yeah leave
that to the experts out of my wheelhouse
a little bit this one is I just open the
document scanned true but it doesn't it
sounds like related to the AIDS
framework but it does
actually use the x-ray book it doesn't
use access token he doesn't use OS in at
least from a quick glance so you seem to
be defining something that is somewhat
similar but if your own header format
and everything else it may be ace is the
right way to do it in card like I say
I'm out of my wheelhouse in that curve
sort of world so I would in my
participation from anyone who's
interested in this yeah arrow scroller
what are you assuming the client for
this activity is what what am i assuming
the client to be yes no assumption is
the payment today the current API
binding is is divined for browsers of
the client but the the data model makes
no assumption the data model is somebody
says give me a set of payment methods
that you support I'm familiar with other
word limits API works but my question is
like what said of what's interactions
between the device and the arm and the
client depends on what you see they keep
those the client or if you think evils
the client are basically generic web
browsers and one sort of idiom is
appropriate if you assume it is a
something we know the standardized
protocol another should it be is really
sure and so given that given that the it
the interaction from um I mean so in the
in the web browser puns this problem by
basically paying a JavaScript API and
having stuff behind the covers and so if
you're on
given that the pay actual payment
operation here is a miracle occurs
behind the scenes it's important
understand what you think the
capabilities that device are of the
client may get a request and then and
subsequently initiating the payment yes
I think it's very determined by the
payment methods that are used so some
payment methods could be an exchange of
tokens that are understood to be valid
for a prepaid arrangement that that
could be perfectly valid or or it can be
much more sophisticated that the client
actually has to go online to a payment
service and execute upon human tissue
the the purpose here is to try any
couple those two
no I again I'm not asking the question
of what the payment mechanism is I'm
asking the question if we think the
device is that is doing this work I'm
failing to see why that's irrelevant
because the capabilities that
device-dependent dictate what kind of
API or interaction mechanism is
appropriate again if the device is not
capable of doing a sophisticated payment
method then it would it would not be
able to interact with it with a a server
that requests that payment method
there's a it's an agreement between the
two devices or payment methods that they
can both do so your misalliance is
understanding me but I don't actually I
am yeah everything is with you right
nothing
so we will meet again tomorrow H wanted