[Music]
ah yes good morning welcome to debt net
gonna get started I'm Lou burger this is
Pat Taylor our Secretary yoni is remote
our agenda and slides are in the normal
place please feel free to go download
them and watch them as we go through we
saw it all start all of our sessions
with the note well we're late in the
week you should be familiar with it at
this point basically anything you say
here will be part of our permanent
record and subject to our IPR rules as
usual we are streaming audio and video
if someone would mind jumping on jabber
that would be great yeah no one does
I'll jump on in a moment we usually do
our joint minute taking sort of
crowd-sourced minute taking the link is
off you can see here or it's easier to
get off the tools page go to tools
working group minutes you'll also find a
link to the etherpad they're my Bettis
if you google you'll find it all so
please jump on and contribute our agenda
is has not been changed from what has
been published we're gonna go through a
number of our working group documents
and then talk about a some work that
we're looking to adopt and then some
other consideration pieces the last two
documents are our presentation slots
are really more informative than work
that we're going to be necessarily
taking on at least immediately they're
the norms documents talks a lot about
what's going on TSN and how TSN
mechanisms queuing might be applied to
debt net whether that ends up coming in
as a working group document or not it's
very useful work either way the last
piece is we're gonna hear on network
calculus which could help inform how we
model some of the parameters both in
what's happening inside the network so
things that would support path
computation as well as parameters that
could be used for describing our
services so this is really going towards
the helping to inform the piece of work
that we haven't really gotten to and
I'll talk about that in a second oh and
of course always please discuss things
on the mail list the I per hour process
I think everyone's there with me on it
spend too much time on that where are we
with our documents with respect to
deliverables and milestones the we have
three documents that are pretty mature
we want to last call them the
interesting thing is is by keeping these
alive we actually keep finding little
pieces that we think we understand and
we probably do but as new people come in
and read the documents we find they
don't understand what we meant it to say
and in fact the documents really don't
say what we think so by keeping them
alive it's actually been good because we
can go and fine-tune these documents so
there really is a trade-off of
publishing because it's nice to have
RFC's and the work is done and we can
move on there's a trade-off between that
and making sure we've documented things
not only so everyone in this room
understands it but more importantly so
the people that come along next
understand it so we should be thinking
about that as we go through the last
call on the agenda we have a couple of
our documents the data plane solution
one
is going to be a really good and
important discussion we had a lively
debate on this document at the last
meeting before adoption and we have a
lot of open issues and we have a good
block of time of our agenda spent
allocated to going through some of those
issues and hopefully we can make some
good progress here which of course will
confirm on the Working Group list so I
was mentioning that the last
presentation is helpful in informing
some of our thinking part of the reason
why we as chairs wanted to have it have
that slot when it was offered is that we
don't have any proposals right now for
our yang models and that's the last
piece of deliverable that we have is we
need we need something to describe what
is happening on inside our a debt net
node and then also how to provision
those a debt net service so the one of
our motivations for having a talk that
is not on a draft but is providing
background is to help getting the work
group thinking so we can get some
contributions in this area area I remind
folks there's company for contribution
driven if you want to participate in the
working group you want some new space to
add value here's a good place to do it I
guess that's my last slide so with that
we'll jump into use-cases I'm Ethan
Grossman from Dolby Laboratories and
this is the update for the dead net
use-cases draft we'll go over the goals
plans status the common themes which is
something that I wanted to just review
briefly because it informs a lot of
other things in the debt net and we have
three new use cases which we'll cover
very briefly so the overall view of why
do we have a use cases document what is
it
it provides the industry context for
debt net goals what are the use cases
how are they addressed today what do we
want to do differently in the future and
what are we asking the networking group
and the ATF to provide in order to
enable these things the use case is
organized by industry but in addition
we've broken down the different use
cases into a sort of set of common
factors which we refer to as the debt
net common themes so these are the
commonalities between use cases and as I
sell review those very briefly the use
case draft functions as a yardstick for
the functionality of any proposed
designs for example it provides a way to
look at you know what is the requirement
and then what is our solution for
example architecture and so on what is
it proposing and does it will it satisfy
the use cases the use case draft
explicitly does not state specific
requirements for debt net nor does it
specify design architecture or protocols
we made as a working group a conscious
decision not to have a requirements
document for debt net we're going from
use cases to architecture and design and
one quality of that alluding to what Lou
was saying a second ago was that there
are ways in which as the design evolves
it may need to inform the use cases and
say well you know
we've got a solution that really looks
about right but it doesn't quite satisfy
this one particular thing so maybe we'd
have to go back and actually amend the
use case to say this to say well no
that's not quite it so there there is
been that but so far there haven't in
recent years in the recent years since
the last update there hasn't been any
such correction required so that's
that's been stable so the plans for the
use case draft as Lewis saying or we
feel the draft is pretty mature and
we're looking at last call but again
there is that quality that if something
changes in the architecture that we
would want to possibly modify the use
case draft but so far again that hasn't
been necessary so we have three new use
cases which were introduced in the last
few months these are the private
blockchain the mining as in mining for
or not as in data mining and network
slicing and again it's not a complete
solution for Network slicing but it
provides some useful technologies for
developing network slicing
infrastructure so I just wanted to look
over the common themes I'm not gonna
literally read over all these to you
these are all pretty much the the
bread-and-butter of debt net at this
point what we're trying to do and what
the basic premise is but they're
interesting to keep in mind that these
this list exists and that these are
discussed in the use case Draft this is
page one or two there is another page
but the idea is that these this list
also serves to inform the security draft
because one of the things that we've
done in the security draft is to look at
each of these particular sort of
properties that this kind of network
would have and what sorts of security
issues are there organized against these
individual properties in addition to
what are the security issues that might
be associated with a given use case by
industry so this is a good overview of
just a different way to to organize the
way the goals of debt net so the mining
use case again I'm gonna go only very
briefly through these use cases I'm not
really doing them justice but just
to have a brief overview of what they
are so for the mining is case if you
imagine a sort of a large open like a
pit mine we've got a huge area filled
with large machines digging ground and
moving earth around and putting up big
piles of stuff it's a very dangerous
place and the trend in recent years has
been to automate all of this so that the
people are actually remote and they
operate all this equipment you know via
video links that you know show what's
going on from the view of a piece of
machinery and then they operate the
machinery with levers from a distance so
there's a lot of real-time wired and
wireless communications going on between
these machines and in addition to all
that going on there's a lot of sensors
distributed throughout the area to
determine for example if a given pile of
something-or-other is likely to be
moving or becoming unstable you want to
know that so a lot of these sensors are
using this lp1
type stuff to to move those there's also
voice communications among various you
know people along the different stations
or monitoring all this so the idea would
be it would be nice to put all this into
net and particularly if you have
wireless parts of dead net that would be
awesome
so it's an important use case blockchain
if you don't know what blockchain is I'm
not going to be able to explain it to
you in 30 seconds but if you do know
what it is you probably know more about
it than I do but the point is that it's
a process that can be done on a
corporate network not just the the
Bitcoin blockchain that's on the open
Internet it's specific applications of
which there are actually quite a number
that in which you can facilitate the
process of what they call consensus
where the computers systems have to talk
to each other and move information very
rapidly and reliably between them it's
usually not a ton of information but the
latency is important and the packet let
negligible packet loss is important so
all of these these things contribute to
useful to be useful in blockchain so for
network slicing again debt net isn't
it's not exactly a pure application of
it but if you look from the bottom of
the pyramid of requirements going up you
find that the requirements and developed
network slicing infrastructure include
being able to have guaranteed bandwidth
low latency lopat packet loss all these
would be very useful in implementing
these kinds of isolated network slices
because it enables functional
performance and security isolation
between the slices and in the end it's
very desirable that the behavior of one
slice not affect the behavior of any
other slice a question from growl I
think Greg murska ET I I agree that yes
network slicing has one use case or okay
one area of use cases that referred as
ultra-low latency and jitter because for
example new mobile backhaul doesn't
really have strict latency packet loss
requirements it's just bigger pipe and
for example massive il T might not have
very strict requirements industrial IOT
which falls into the first low latency
jitter scenario yes
so basically out of three scenarios that
identified by 3gpp one definitely fits
deadline
I agree with that but we might be more
specific when we talk about net slices
to refer to this scenario rather than
say that all net slices require
guaranteed yes that makes that makes
good sense that's Greg if you have any
suggestions that could help clarify that
in the document that'd be great
you know it's proposed some changes on
the list and we can get it into the dock
I'll be glad thank you thank you
Toula sacred I am so to me it's it's
very simple right if somebody wants to
have dead net services and a service
provider needs to provide them in a you
know virtualized environment and slicing
is the new password how to define you
know virtualized environments that can
provide let's say hop-by-hop guarantees
right but
to me it's it's not quite clear if it's
a new use case by itself right it's just
a virtualization of a dead net service
if all the services people want to have
from slices are not dead definite
services but any other services like
even you know low latency whatever you
know guarantees that somebody wouldn't
called Aetna today then you know they
could also in my opinion be provided you
know through a slicing architecture that
doesn't rely on dead net underneath so I
think that that is my claim I'm not
hundred percent sure right so the
question is if all the services required
by slicing are non dead net services if
you would implement them natively would
you still be able to make a case that in
the slicing environment you need
underneath more dead net that would be
making it a real use case otherwise it's
just a virtualization you know way of
whatever dead net service you have in
before well that's a good point and I
think one way that they was phrased was
that dead net is a candidate technology
for use in the infrastructure of network
slicing and so I think in that case yes
it's not a not a pure use case if people
feel that it's not appropriate to have
that in your please let us know on the
list and you know we can we can discuss
it discuss it further so I have one more
slide that briefly discusses network
slicing but I'm not I'm not really going
to go into it but the point is it
provides the technology for providing
isolation between slices in that sense
functional performance security again
and perhaps the ways that debt net
enables you to specify a number of
redundant paths and so on could help
with with reliability and so on so
that's a matter of implementation I
guess anyway that's what I have I was
just going to reinforce the point that I
do think that there's an extremely good
match between what I've heard of the
network slicing five-year requirements
and the work of that net and wishes
easier news story Emma Stewart to take
this use case out of the document
if you whoever speaks at the mic please
really lean into the mic if you don't
lean in we can't hear you you have to
get very close to the microphone we
couldn't really hear you I think was the
point Stuart if you could please repeat
so the point I was making was that you
were asking about whether this should be
in the document having looked at the
problem for quite some time I think
absolutely it needs to be in the
document it's a perfect match for
something that we know that 5g is asking
for and it will be a real mistake if we
took this out thank you sir
okay so my name is tal Mizrahi I'm from
Marvel this draft is about security
considerations in debt net it's a
collaboration between a group of people
led by Ethan Grossman and the group also
includes Andrew Sabir John and Rick
Kevin and norm this is the outline of
the draft we've presented this a couple
of times in the past ITF meetings and
these are the main sections in the draft
or the main themes in the draft security
threats basically what are the possible
attacks on deterministic networks
impacts of these security attacks which
means what happens if there's a
successful attack mitigations which
means what what we can do to try to
mitigate or to prevent some of these
attacks and finally there is a section
which associates each of the attacks
with use case themes so the use case
themes are basically based on the use
case document we saw on the previous
presentation so this draft has been
around for a few months we presented it
in ITF 98 in 1999 there was quite a bit
of feedback it was recently adopted by
the working group so right now we're
it's draft zero one of the working group
document the main differences between
the previous version and the current
version so there are two main
differences first of all in the impact
section significant changes were made in
this section first of all a lot of
clarifications and also we revised the
impact to use case mapping we'll talk
about that in a minute another section
that was significantly revised is the
section which associates attacks to use
cases we'll also talk about that in a
minute
okay so like we said impact means what
happens if there is a successful
security attack so basically one of the
things we see in the impact section is a
mapping between impacts and use case
industries so in each column of this
table you will see a different use case
industry and then each row kind of shows
a different type of impact so for
example if we look at the first row we
see the criticality so we can see for
each industry whether the criticality of
a successful security attack on that net
whether it's medium high or low and on
the second row we see the financial
impact and so on so it's this kind of
shows you know mapping of what are the
impacts of each type of industry so this
is something that was significantly
revised in the current version another
aspect is the section that map's the
attacks to use cases so we kind of have
a sub section about each use case theme
and what we had in the previous version
was that for each use case theme we had
kind of an outline of what are the
topics that we plan to discuss it was
phrased in the form of a set of
questions so in the current version in
this text was significantly revised we
have more detailed text which maps for
each of the use case themes it describes
what are the main security aspects which
are related specifically to that theme
so at this point looking forward the
next steps we we were thinking about we
would like to discuss with the working
group first of all so far the format
we've been working on is kind of a
design team it's not formally a design
team but it's a group of people who met
periodically and worked on the document
and now that they're working of now that
it's a working group document were kind
of reconsidering this format we're in
urging people who are interested in this
work to join us to contribute so that's
one aspect another thing is that we
would like to encourage a lot of reviews
okay we'd like people to read the
document to try to see what's missing to
try to see what's wrong so as many
reviews at this point it would be best
it would improve the document and this
is a good time for anyone who hasn't
read the document yet this is a good
time to read it and also another aspect
that we need to look into in the near
future is what the data plane design
team has been working on we need to look
at it from a security perspective to try
to see the possible threats and the
possible security aspects that need to
be addressed in this document okay so
this would be a good time for questions
and comments thank you greg Mirsky City
I just want to ask you what you think of
they were a threat or importance on
attack on OAM because om will be used
for SLA assurance in a dead net and if
somebody skews your measurement that
will trigger false negative okay so do
you think that it because again I
understand this is a generic problem
it's not the problem specific to that
net but is it reasonable at least to
mention that om can be vector of attack
to destabilize that net environment okay
it's a good point do you think that
there is something here which is
different in that net then conventional
networks I think well again that's
depends on how important the performance
measurement is for the environment
because SLA and SLA assurance for that
net is important then
ah it might be really used to base their
boys because in some networks they do
performance measurement only for the
billing right here the performance
measurement I can envision that will be
determined
you have to reroute which you know
disturbing to the network any change in
in a topology that you have to force and
switching paths are may result in packet
loss because not it's not instantaneous
so you might have some packet loss
result of false unnecessary switchover
okay it's a good point good point to
consider this is the kind of feedback
we're looking for you're missing this
stuff in the document it's not just
packet loss you're going to get as a
result of an inadvertent switchover
you're going to get J delay jitter
changes as well and in fact actually
that I don't remember seeing you there
but we may want to look at some of the
conversions control technologies in the
underlay in order to preserve those
characteristics in the network
absolutely agree yes protection methods
and restoration that again I agree
that's subject of itself because there
could be absolutely legitimate service
the gradation or metrics the gradations
and even tailors detected in the network
but that might be induced as a result of
attack on om skewing the measurement
because you can easily imagine that not
just injecting packets but just
intercepting packets holding them for
longer and thus producing wrong
measurement results okay thank you in
terms of formats there's nothing wrong
with holding meetings of people who are
working on the document authors now that
we've switched to a design team sorry
away from the design team format into
the working group document it would be
good if you publish when you're gonna
have those meetings and open them up to
the working group if you don't just
remember that any decision taken by a
set of authors is not a decision by the
working group and you need to if you
come to some agreement on a position you
should take it to bring that to the
working group present the proposed
changes and see what the if there's any
feedback on the list so that's really
important but there's nothing wrong with
with having authors meetings so don't
feel like you should stop that
particularly if it helps progress the
document in terms of terms of your
comment on soliciting a wider input I
think that's just right one of the
things I'd like to ask the working group
as well as the author's to when they're
reading the document for the first time
or reading it again is to look very
carefully of what is being discussed if
it's in scope or out of scope of what
we're doing here for example we're not
doing control plane yet that's out of
scope where we are right now but we
might do it in the future so maybe
that's something that belongs in an
appendix but not the core of the
document so we don't want to lose good
material but we want to make sure that
the core of the document is focused on
the work we're doing right now okay
thank you
so now we're going to go remote Leone
yoni please queue up yeah yeah
here you but we don't see you okay you
want to see me okay
of course we want to see you yeah all
right there you go all right look going
quick very early morning okay
all right so you have this line shop
okay good
do and we're ready to go when you're
what you want us to go to the next line
okay okay so hello everybody
remote again so the only current working
nowadays for the Nordic semiconductor
and so this is about the data plane the
recently adopted solution document and
the next slide please
there's a delay in you seeing as so so
we got a very thorough review from
Stuart so thank you so I recorded down
some 30 40 plus comments in the document
so those who up in reading this also
document can find those comments
embedded in the current 0 0 version of
the draft and then there's been some
what we'll be discussing on the email
list so this presentation is is mainly
concentrating on tier data plane so the
transport part and some of the things
that the services that we actually
provide for the service layer so next
slide let's just want to remind you
about the deadhead services and these
are extracted from the architecture
trust so we have the two low consistent
loss pounded ladies interior and the
high delivery ratio and the
X like this one comment I'd like to make
here is in and this was it privately to
me is that we the objective of debt net
is is the delivery ratio how we achieve
it is mechanisms that we decide to
define it define in the working group
and it's okay for us to have multiple
definitions the particular question was
related to whether or not network coding
was in scope or out of scope and the
answer is that is it in scope we don't
expect to be working on it for a while
but if there's a proposal for it after
thing other things have stabilized that
could come in to satisfy that last
service alright I'm on the next slide
okay thank you sorry we have someone at
the mic basically well net recording is
mentioned in the architecture it doesn't
mean that we have to implement it what
we have in the architecture is very
interesting for positioning functions
whether we implement them or not but I
think it's it's good and we need to keep
the network coding positioned inside the
architecture so if people think about it
they need to know where it is and what
it does okay so again borrowing stuff
onto the architecture document so
reminding you about layering what we
have so so VM and and and where we are
now with this document we have the
transport layer and and speaking into
the service layer because we have a
couple of functions in the service layer
that for example norm is going to talk
about this but even it comes to a tacit
sequencing and application and
elimination and the T stuff is somewhere
in between so in the solution document
we be currently describe two solutions
so we had the RPGs encapsulation and
then we have the transport solution that
this is based on a suit existing pseudo
wires
and the if you read the document and how
it starts the ipv6 interpolation is
mostly intended for the M native I
pivoted end-to-end it in service cases
where the end system are dead net over
an input and output am didn't service
flows Italy using the ipv6 traffic and
then we have this other wire
encapsulation that the one of the use
cases that we address here is the year
the emulated decent service saw the
island interplan but it doesn't exclude
that you could actually talk the
insistence would natively talk pseudo
wire based encapsulations okay then the
next one so what what this presentation
is mostly about and the thesis and
discuss some points they circles around
two topics so the so as I said we have
the ipv6 and we have in the pseudo wire
into a pseudo wire based sources in the
document and the how the service layers
is expressed in those encapsulations we
need to discuss and decide whether we
aim them to be unified or whether we let
them to kind of go different ways and
then the the other kind of Peaks
question is about the what kind of
solution we want to have our PSN it
current is modeled after the pseudo
wires all right next slide
sorry about the em universe service
layer so for the current solution
document so they are not really aligned
anymore how they look on wire so if you
tend tinder party how you would actually
make chips and and the pipe on logic you
need to have two different paths if you
want to super both a transport types so
the DDM the the first question that I
have for the working group kind of going
forward on how to model the document in
the future is like a suit the data plane
solution aim for a unified on wire
format for the service layer so for ipv6
and then the something else that is is
23 cents or MPLS based so should we
looked at how we package them in the
same way or let them diverts and have
their own encapsulations for for example
for CBS numbering and how they identify
the flaws as long as functions are the
same so this is the first question
I look for an answer so I think part of
the part of the answer lies in are the
only two trades they work yes I did say
right in here that's right that
part of the answer lies in whether these
are the only two that we need to support
so if it turns out that there's some
industrial format that we also need to
support or plain old-fashioned v4 needs
to be supported that tends to push you
in one direction if these are the only
two that you need to support then doing
an optimized one for each one prob
possibly makes sense it depends how many
others that we might need okay and
that's a fair point
so the handle for example regarding the
ipv4 part we had a kind of agreement
that we are not going to look into a pv4
solution if someone goes for not vv4
that's their problem
so well that if someone did v4 over TSN
and that we would were interconnected
TSN domain yeah now they need to make
sure that that that kind of intertwine
solution works but describing a solution
especially for ipv4 as as for example
transport solution I don't think that we
should be doing it um so she Stewart
again I take the view that if customers
need v4 and in a lot of legacy worlds
they might I suppose we should support
it I don't think we should use this as
an excuse not to service customer need I
don't know whether they do but we really
need to be clear on whether it's needed
yes the question is to me is whether we
support it as an end-to-end debt net
service
or as a yet another TSN service that's
being carried over debt that and I think
we've taken to position the latter
position I'm not saying it's the right
position base I think that that's the
direction we've been headed down if we
want to do something different that's a
good thing to raise well what will the
use cases tell us the use cases don't go
to that level of detail there are
high-level applications that says we
need to support industrial mining as we
heard earlier whether that the miners
don't care whether their v4 v6 they just
don't want a piece of machinery to you
know run into them so what one of the
points that was made I can't remember if
this was on list or privately is the
whole discussion about whether we should
be continuing to you
talking about pseudo wires or should we
just be talking about what is it that
the data plane looks like and not being
worried about being tied to the all the
seed of pseudo wire references and I
think it would be good to hear from the
group on that and I'm not sure if you're
gonna get to that yoni later or if this
is what you were thinking of also
covering in this path is oh so I have
some some clones later on apart so then
other let's defer to the conversation
that yeah so but as I said I try to kind
of go into that that direction so I
rather interesting in the on wire format
and I'm at least the kind of semantics
on certain thing that I can extract from
the flow so given some technologies I
don't really I don't think that we
should actually care that much how how
packet cut into some point as but it
came over the MPLS or whether it came
over IP or something so if we can unify
the step further that that our did not
specific for for certain time processing
on the service layer that that would be
great because then then you can actually
have reuse some of the logic that you
have faster processing and that that's
basically also think that what what led
to this question so whether we want to
stick with the kind of universe format
how you encode stuff into the packet or
whether we let them go as towards head
optimized for a certain specific
transport and the it's just because this
is this is a one one big question in the
whole document how you're going to split
and how you're going to do that in the
future so I can only do you view that
what we have now is unified or separate
it's a separate it so we started to go
on the path that that we defined for
ipv6 we started using the extension
headers and and we use some of the ipv6
fee
for certain a service layer and
functional so that that's a clear
indication into solution rough currently
that it's going to separate place to
confirm it'll be continued on that one
you only one second okay so I respect to
this specific question of whether or not
it you're asking just that I want to
make sure we're all clear where you're
asking for feedback on whether we should
stick with the current approach or try
to go back to the original idea of
having a single unified on wire format I
haven't had a lot of comments in the
room but no one is objecting the current
definition of using different formats on
the wire as long as it matches the the
dead net service
so I'll just correct me if I'm wrong you
need is that that did I paraphrase
correctly yep that's correct
does anyone want to come to the mic and
object to the path that the document
currently has where we're currently
headed where it is okay to have
different on wire formats and right now
for vv6 and for MPLS environments and
maybe in the future it'll be another one
but we're not there yet
norm is coming to the mic hopefully not
object norm fin I think it's great to
have both formats and there's I think
there's a legitimate question whether it
should be split into two drafts but for
sure so I think we should consider this
point closed at least in the room I
think that when we send out summary
notes you get the next version of this
removed this question and that are it
closed okay go with which allows
different formats the question was
what's the answer
okay Greg Mirsky GT I think it
our work much more easier and documents
more readable if we extract that net
layer definition in one document and
then we might have that net over
different technologies as separate
documents it's it's very similar to
what's done in other groups like let's
take I don't know segment routing there
is segment rounding MPLS and there are
segment routing ipv6 the question to you
would what you're saying let's go a
separate document yes ok does anyone
object to separating out that peat
receive no objections in the room always
changes neatly confirmed otherwise ok
so basically we go with with the route
that the aura choice and let the a
different different types have their
claims have in codings
right and also to sit great to sort of
start breaking this document apart yeah
that's actually next question that that
that the so the question number two is
not really valid for this one so if you
go to the next slide so this is actually
to the bigger question now so like
currently we have ipv6 and the MPLS
based and same document so following
what Greg said so this is another
question question number tree so should
we split that into two troughs so what
we have currently so basically saying
that every time we have a different type
of transport data plane solution we just
spin out a new document that describes
the details how you encode that
information and so what I heard what I
heard was yes we should split it out
into separate documents and I didn't
hear any objections to splitting it
in two separate documents I think I
heard the suggestion that it should
actually be three documents kind of with
a I guess an overview document one for
each encapsulation I don't know I'm not
sure whether we need that because we
already have like architectural and
other things I'm myself in favor of two
documents because we have all the
architects the documents and so on that
we know actually won't be aiming for we
just need to kind of okay the discussion
on T is for example the elimination so
to pref part that norm is going to have
their own that that might change your
name yeah I
Unferth the comment here I'm also in
favor of name please Lou Anderson I'm
also in favor of splitting but I would
actually like to keep the document one
more version where we actually sort out
all the issues before we do in the split
yeah that seems reasonable I think the
author should be allowed little
flexibility as to when they do the exact
split you know this is not we're not
like about the last call it so it's if
you think it makes sense to do one two
or three versions and then do the split
that's great yeah but I'd asked start
noting at least put in a comment that
this document is gonna be split and
noting where that where things are gonna
end up okay let's get you need you you
mentioned in question to a split between
the lower layer functionality and your
parallel functionality likes service
commands etcetera and I think that's
that's back to the discussion of having
layers and and what belongs which layer
this particular document is addressing
as long as you you talk about frame
encapsulation and in formats I agree
these are those two documents we want to
do and I'm competing with that we jump
in your head of what Nam whisk is going
to talk to about and what I'm going to
talk about there are all your services
that I don't think they belong to either
of those documents but that those other
work
which is taking place above it belongs
to the traditionally earthly or three
which we are doing here
and some of it belongs to a barriers and
and they happen I'll be somewhere else
we don't have to put all this yet you
have a Pascal has a document on
transport services sort of thing about
that's rides above debt net so yeah
absolutely not we're not gonna make one
document that covers all layers of the
network right and you were in this room
when we say transport services we think
like ITU we think don't they in the
forwarding plane the rest of the HF and
some other area when you took it we
pronounced transport you think that's
something very very very different so
that's part of my priming document right
the routing area tends to talk about
transport as Network transport services
not transport protocols which the
transport area and application area
right so my document is about the other
thing right not transport services as
you just said which people here so
you're in the minority in this room but
you're in the majority that's okay okay
all right
can we go for I still have three flights
Saudi next one okay so then the about
the the thing that we had in in the
source current solution document that
this was what I would offer the en as
pseudo virus so uh so along to discuss
analyze value writing the a solution
document we kind of found out the three
best describe what what the es who the
water-based solution could be and so
saying that the drivers behind why we
actually went for through the wild based
solution the first place they were quite
practical so we found a transport thing
was two tasks a controller a sequence
number and existing standards for that
and we have a clear description how the
sequencing works it even describes the
reordering and the applicator
elimination
not that it has been successful with
that has been pointed out multiple times
that it's not really deployed but it's
still great to find a reference in a
documentation that someone has been
thinking this before and then we had the
from t death net we had the relay
concept and we kind of found a close fit
that from the movie segments with a
wireless model that after that and the
we could find a lot of similarities so
that that was the reason why we went for
this who the water-based solution in the
first place
we were not like in the kind of in love
with the text positive otherwise so the
the current ways of describing the
solution take would be DM the the way
that is current in the solution
documents of based on the multi second
pseudo wires it has been brought in to
attend attention multiple times that we
could explore so model the transfer
based on the EVP ends and nowadays that
you can actually also had the a control
bird it's recommended in India a 2-14
and or that if we could come up with
something new that that mom gave a name
as a tenant wire so on and this seems to
be a sticky point so we need to kind of
make a decision which way we go in the
future
so next slide and if you keep mind the
layering and the services that the data
plan is to provide for the connected
service layer so one of the key
functions that we need is going to be
the sequence number so that we had the
possibility of finding splitting flaws
and finding it obligates so good that's
about the why we keep up pushing this
the Seekers numbering and do that
Netflix it was pointed out that the that
the current soulsand document assumes
that the secret number is a flat numbers
base that says like consumes the whole
numbers
so like if it's a 16-bit has default
64,000 numbers you support but in our
attempt to reuse existing of four four
four eight just pointed out rightfully
that the zero is a reset number this
kind of we missed so and if we in a
future want to inter work in any way
with the existing a layer two
technologies that already deploy TEDMED
services and the public eight
elimination things like that they all
are seem to follow a single sample space
so if we end up using a technology that
has reserved numbers like 0 interworking
with those is going to be very very
challenging
so the question number for that I have
relates to this this how we encode to
see this numbering to get not close is
like a so that that and this is
specifically in the in the context of
MPLS based solution and and reusing the
existing standard that we have for for
EVP ends and the pseudo wires which is
basically RFC four four four eight is
that is that actually usable so if we
need to define a use one from word type
solution that would fit for example into
so the wires or EVP and whatever we
chose for should we go there and and
just define our ol let's say control
type of solution and the if we go that
route will that be an issue
when we look into modeling this solution
over to the wires or a VPN so basically
do we try to reduce extinct standard on
this record or just go for and design
something of our own
Thurston
or for question and the then depending
on the answer we go for a new
controversial custom five will that
implicitly mean that net what we have
come to define is not sort of war it's
not evpn but it's something different
and are we fine with that and if you
want to peek in the the next question is
going to be what is the actual
technology so should we call for the S
or number six would pity that we go for
it pseudo wires over the Rico for evpn
or something else okay
so question for first we actually have
someone at the mic I'm not sure if he's
wants to ask a question
okay four five or six or something
completely different
no I was I mean I thought we were
dealing with these slide by slide so
it's just you it again
um so a question first question I got to
ask you is do you think you need to put
anything other than Ethernet over this
service because if you think that we
might have to carry some other legacy
service then there'd be a lot to be said
for staying with the pseudo wire format
at least the format as emitted by the by
the TPE
because both silicon can already do
those sorts of things the issue of skip
zero is irritating but it's not
catastrophic right there are it you can
do it you just have to recognize that
you've got zero and you've got one less
than 64,000 in your room
in your sequence number and the thing
just you know skips it on the one side
and interprets it differently ever sees
one
so I don't think that's catastrophic in
terms of continuing to use four four
four eight in terms of using the evpn
system you have to remember that there
is nothing even remotely analogous to
the SP e so I'm not sure
what is driving you to that but
certainly is nothing analogous to the
SPE but really the SPE is the wrong
concept I think we need to think about
replicators and eliminators put in the
the network and I think that that would
be a better a better approach to
introduce a different object Stuart a
clarifying question it sounds like
you're advocating or saying that pseudo
wire constructs really arms providing us
a lot of value here and in fact maybe
wrong you're saying that sorry my turn
not to lean it to the mic you're saying
that pseudo wires aren't providing a lot
of value number one and number two maybe
even the wrong construct certainly SPE s
are the wrong construct which is the
whole reason we went with rice but
whether T Pease of the right construct I
don't know and the net will detent that
will depend on whether you want to carry
other wire types
besides Ethernet across this service
with these reliability characteristics
and I don't know the answer to that
question if you do there'd be a lot to
be said for staying with the t PE design
and just having a different different
object in the network that's not an SPE
maybe you want to respond or should we
go to the next question
so we will look into Ethernet as a
payload type and and the IPS or a packet
as a payload type so for the existing
pseudo wires fee for the latter we will
conclude out of say six six five eight
that that he's asked that possibility of
carrying any packet over the M pseudo
wires so that was kind of the for that
one regarding the the the super SPE
discuss on the desert that's basically
the question number seven and and and I
think that norm is going to have a lot
to say about the earth
the key functions that we had call it is
PE when it comes to a replication
elimination so that that's part most
part of the next discussion skipping
reusing the 4 4 4 8 and 0 not being part
of it and that's not being catastrophic
I myself kind of agree on that the issue
really is around the what happens with
inter working with the existing
technologies so so sorry
again existing stuff would work nicely
would knit with 4 for all right you
could take an existing a TPA and it
would emit packets that would go into
your net so that that's not about the
reusing so the thickness they have the
sequence number already embedded in
those payloads and if we want to keep
the the replication emanation working on
we actually the TP would take the cps
number and use that seekest number
somewhere in the payload so kind of
touches that point so but I let I like
known to say around that if he is on a
mic so pet that they were so so Stewart
I
the point is it's on the slide but
basically if you're using this to carry
the layer to the layer 2 technologies
then if you don't skip 0 you can carry
the same you can use the same serial
number at layer 2 and if the in the
pseudo wire encapsulation but if you
skip it then then that will diverge
because the underlying layer 2 isn't
skipping 0 yeah this is norm Finn let me
say something about the skipping 0 if it
can be an issue if the result is that
every 64k packet gets delivered twice
that may or may not be a disaster it
depends on the application if the result
is that every 61 every 64,000 packets
you drop a packet and it doesn't get
delivered that's way way WAY worse than
our goal for that that would be terrible
okay so it has to be dealt with somehow
we have to figure out what it's going to
do okay I would be reluctant to deliver
them twice because that's for some
applications that's not going to be you
know that if if the packet is flipped
the switch and they need this
reliability because they have a really
stupid protocol that says flip the
switch and said have said it too on or
set it to off and that can be a disaster
so it we got to deal with it okay and it
doesn't matter to me a whole lot
whether we're we're reusing that whether
the point is being able to reuse
documents or being able to reuse some
gates I think it's great if we can reuse
some gates I think it's nice if we can
reuse documents but you get a set we
should figure out what the right
technical solution is and then and then
have our documents back it up not not be
driven by because of be artificially
constrained by documents before getting
to the do I just want to ask you Ani you
have do the authors have a position on
this question so okay so this doesn't 3%
the whole team so this represents me so
I don't have an issue defining and using
so that that so really using documents
is okay but the what norms ends about
reusing the gates and antiques
dissolution so having them counter to
the implementation not to skip zero
might be actually an easier solution at
the end would you not be a point of
yourself yeah
norm Finn this is this is obviously a
rathole because it's so easy to
understand everybody's kind of opinion I
believe that one of the really things
that we really need to do is there that
there are a lot of deployed applique
there we want to capture those
applications and move them to bigger
better networks and to capture those
applications zero is just as good as
serial numbers anything else it does not
mean don't do replicated don't do thing
well you're you're just to be clear
you're saying we should allow for zero
buys and change it it's just another
sequence number eight Thank You Pascal
we have a clearly delineated
architecture where we've got a device
somewhere at the edge of the network
awesome we do point in a network that
does the sequencing and that the UI
Stokes layoffs today or to a device that
elimination that's very clear in the
architecture and putting any semantics
for the lower layer about what those two
guys say when they set up a sequence
number is a layer violation if that's
why we're hitting all those prongs we
should leave those two guys put whatever
they want and like we said it depends on
the semantics and even if they want to
put it as a non sequential number I mean
for defeat against whenever they should
have their home place where they can put
this sequence and the rest of the world
should see that as a no bug that just
blindly transport it we should not be
talking about the authority of semantics
in this room yeah we're just to be clear
that the point is is if we if we don't
skip if we allow zero we might be able
to send less bits on the wire and that
if we have to skip zero means we we
definitely have to add some bits on the
wire so this is an optimization question
whether or not we're restricting what
the user of that net and carrying her
consent all right you can if you can
transport a note back all the way with
our young coded with zeros or not not
zeros it's it's okay but it has to be a
note back for the lower layers otherwise
we'll hit problems in the malleus
speaking as pals co-chair there's no
reason in the world why we cannot define
a new debt net pseudo wire with the
behavior that zero is included in the
sequence base
okay okay so I think we have direction
yes we go to resolve here the first is
are we we want to be constrained with
the this thing semantics of the pseudo
wire definition that requires skipping
of zero since I'm getting from the
discussion is that we don't want to be
constrained to skip 0 and that 0 should
be treated at just another value yep
okay I'd like to see if anyone disagrees
so I don't hums don't work for my ears
so I'm gonna ask people to raise hands
this is get it a feel for the room do
does anyone object to that path of of
allowing 0 using 0 as a valid value the
implication is we're doing something a
little different than what's what is out
there right now no objection okay could
do it if you Mike I can't hear them no
one can't go in the record the Stewart's
coming right Stewart yes just to find
another pseudo wire and it will work you
want to think about whether you want to
pick up all the other characteristics of
the design but yes that will just work
see so now we get to the next question
which is we care if we model this as a
pseudo wire as a evpn or as something
else
can I just go back a bit though alright
just slightly sooner wires use 16-bit
sequence numbers all right well that's
the current term design people were
talking about the sequence numbers
needed by the underlying service isn't
that possibly a different sort of number
space I mean it could be eight bits or
it could be 32 bits so I don't think
perhaps we shouldn't get the too muddled
up agree let's go again the semantics of
what this sequencer and the Eliminator
use and that could be multiple
implications and doing very different
things one could jump everywhere
it's one could encode it in somewhat
fashion to to protects against attacks
the lower layers should not depend on
what the upper layer - what number of
bits skipping 0 whatever that is that
should not that should be copied ly
layered differentiated we are getting we
all agree on that I'm gonna cut the line
on that discussion you have a lot of
other questions to go through and we
want to leave some time for more yes so
it would be good to get to this question
the number six is ECM the big one it's
kind of going to shape a lot of what
what happens in the in next revisions of
the document so basically whether we
keep up with the suitable base approach
that we have today or we kind of start
keeping EVPs in your mind or then we
just go different route and so I just
want to kind of point out that the kind
of discussion between pseudo wires and
evpn and when you look in the actual
encoding or wire for the pipeline point
of view they look the same so the N sure
yes yes VP VPNs
use pseudo wires to carry that they paid
out I think this is the point that you
know is just making is is well the wire
formats the same the documentation is
quite different well yeah this is a
documentation and modeling question more
than a wire format discussion let's move
on
is anyone else want to comment on this
topic norm Europe and norm fin III I
tend to go towards wanting to do just at
net wire and define what that is and
one was the control word that we just
settled the other is that if I look at
what does TSN want from debt net okay
which is one important consideration not
the only one certainly we do not all TSN
does not always want an Ethernet
connection thank you very much
okay we want a routed connection okay
one of our problems is that you can't
make a bridged Network big enough so
giving us on giving us a pseudo wire
that provides an Ethernet connection
that connects these two clouds is not
necessarily what we want okay we don't
want to expand the volume of the
broadcast space okay though the pseudo
wire the thing after the connect the
control word I believe I'd like to I I
think I'd like to see it is not
necessarily 12 bytes of of MAC address
being the next thing at the control word
on the third option that you only
mentioned which defining what the plane
is not worried about anyone elses
terminology of pseudo wire or Evie and
those are just ways of describing the
same thing on the wire we should be
worried about focus on the wire it yeah
it's a way to attract other people's
baggage other people's arguments yeah if
we go that way I wouldn't call it a debt
that wire I would just call it the debt
that data plane and because just to be
clear that we're focusing on the data
plane not a new pseudo wire not at the
end it's just so shoo it yes I agree
with you
EVP ends don't have any in network
construct which you need so you're going
to be modifying EVP NS anyway Greg and I
are having a semantic argument over
whether the end you to do eyes or not
but that's a different matter fact is
that it's still not a perfect fit
because EVP ends don't have the other
constructs you need which is in network
replication and elimination though I
think that the right thing to do is to
define the right
structure to carry things may be used
you know the OEM stuff that we already
have and make it easy to use those sorts
of things but decide to just design the
right thing for the job we're not
talking about a new data plane here
we're talking about reusing the existing
data play and it's just how we describe
it so the sense of the conversation at
least I'm taking away is that that there
is agreement among those who have speak
it spoken excuse me more coffee please
spoken is that we shouldn't worry about
modeling we should just focus on the the
data playing and describe just the data
plane and whatever makes sense to bring
into the document we into the document
but not be constrained by a pseudo wire
construct or even an EVP n construct are
there any objections to that reading of
the room though there appear to be no
objection okay so I think this could be
a told we should document that way is
the resolution the notes will be bat and
so okay
number seven question I will skip that
because we will figure out that later on
oh yeah so I mean there's a quite a bit
long road to ghastly folk for modeling
with the real ice and stuff so I'll I
rather see some documents evolving
before you go for this all okay so for
my part I I got a very good clear
guidance where to go next so thank you
yone on on number seven as part of once
you have the document cleaned up makes
sense to propose something they are
context things up please do so obviously
use the list yes thank you
let's give a uni I'll come back to your
question seven in my presentation
great all right thank you I'll switch
off this one Norman wait oh I wasn't
counting on doing my slides in addition
to you knees is it these are these are
mostly bp's solutions stuff these are
the slides we received from you I had
these aren't the sides for the data
plane for the bounded latency later
that's later yes
oh okay that's fine I can do this I
thought I thought we were doing uni
slides instead I'll be glad to do this
and it I'll be quick yes we've taken
care of that we've taken care oh I had a
question because it's been brought up in
the group about load sharing let's go to
the diagram where did I have my diagram
here we are
imagine that between
it says reppin the limb the two dotted
lines I'm going to use the diagram from
it from another slide imagine from the
between rep and limb we have to slow
links so I have to 100 megabit links and
I have a 150 megabit flow okay we have
these convenient serial numbers on them
we could split that flow into two and
send it on the two wires and use two
debt net flows and recombine them at the
other side and manage to get a a single
flow over to slow wires or five slow
wires or whatever and we have the serial
numbers in the in the packet so that
wouldn't be too hard to do and do we
want to add that and make that part of
debt net and it's architecture so that
is normal I have a question let's look
at what our solution is then ask this
question again that's fine with me
that's fine with me
okay ready okay remember to bring that
up once we have a prep solution okay we
did this aggregation encapsulation
techniques and this is one of the
reasons why I argued for let's do the
debt net thing which is now a debt net
data plane not necessarily grabbing on
to pseudo wires for scalability we need
to aggregate know okay for scalability
we need to aggregate flows okay we can't
have the backbone knowing about every
single flow we want to put a bunch of
flows into a bigger flow imagine that
we've aggregated all those flows on the
left so that they can be delivered on
the right as separate flows again
layering is going to be part of our
solution of course so what are something
different here that you're talking about
only that I'm talking about that you may
have a control word on the outside and
another control word inside of that
because I'm doing two layers of of
replication and elimination if that's a
given when we were tied to pseudo wires
that's kind of awkward if we're not tied
to pseudo wires and that's understood
that's all I wanted to hear I think I
can't remember which document it was
that talked about being able to run
layers of that net for aggregation
purposes
I believe the architecture does
explicitly we explicitly had that in
there from a scaling stamp fantastic
it's also
suggested that we don't need
intermediate nodes that do replication
and elimination do the replication and
elimination only at the ends okay don't
do them in the middle I wanted to give
the basic use case for why replication
and elimination in the middle is a nice
thing to have uh this diagram was shown
to me by a person who does industrial
networks in industry as well as service
providers you can have a big ring with
little rings attached to it there are
times when you need to break the main
ring to modify the topology you want to
add some little rings or delete some
things okay and you need to have planned
outages in a large network like this the
fact that you're doing planned outages
means that having two failures is not
unusual and in particular if I need to
break the main ring where the big blue
bar is I have to be sure that there is
no little ring broken for example the
red bar in the upper right I have to
make sure that all of those networks are
clean before I make my main break and I
have to hope that nothing in my small
ring will break while I've got the main
ring broken okay this is a very
practical situation they can't shut down
the whole plant in order to make changes
to the network that's just not an option
for them if you have the intermediate
replication points at each point where
the Rings join the little rings join the
main ring then you can have two failures
in the network you can in fact you can
have multiple failures you can have a
failure in any small ring you can have a
failure in the main ring and you can
still get the data through so that's I
think a requirement so I think that's
why we
the intermediate replication and
elimination points low Anderson I take
your point though question on this
picture if there is a break in the small
ring to the upper right wouldn't that
ring turn the traffic around the other
way so instead of doing what I've shown
here is to end-to-end paths I'm not
talking remember debt net does not
respond to a failure by creating a new
path I simply have the two paths and I
see the packets and I throw away the
extras in a ring technology would
actually turn the traffic around I'm
drawing a ring topology not a ring I'm
not talking about a ring protocol that
heals rings and turns things around and
reverses stuff in the sense of rmr or
shattering protection so it's just a
topology okay yes norm as a heads up
you're talking to a group that's dealt
with transport rings and transport
protection for a long long time yes you
may be triggering responses and thoughts
that you don't anticipate because of
these words really really familiar with
lots of ring protection solutions in in
for those people he wants to do 1+1
end-to-end protection not ring
protection so even though you're saying
you're doing
you got rings you're not doing ring
protection in the parlance of those
who've been doing transport exactly
right Thank You cutie compiler yeah so
is the suggestion that you're making
that when the traffic on the red path
enters the small ring to the top right
it's replicated both up and down so that
when you have that red cut it will be is
that is that the goal not where you're
going yeah actually actually the source
is down at the lower left sure it goes
both ways around the ring the two
squares each rough
replicate the packets in both directions
okay it one of which gets eliminated as
they crisscross those get eliminated
then they go around the big ring all the
way around and crisscross again one of
them gets eliminated they go around the
little ring yeah yeah really what we
want to do here we've been talking about
end-to-end protection not a multi ring
I've not been talking about infinite
protection I've had the ladder diagram
in the architecture from day one the
ladder has been in the with the
intermediate elimination has been in the
architecture from day one and talked
about in the architecture there's
actually anything new here well that's
what be peace all has been doing yeah
yeah let's get to I thought we just said
let's define what that net is and then
we'll see that net over foo right so
this is perfect we define something
which does that and then we do it over
food well we were talking about the how
we documented from a data playing
standpoint it was pretty much the same
thing but let's see let's see where we
end up you just said this right we see
what we want and and we and this is what
we want one of those things we do want
and then if we can optimize you know
something like the sequence control this
on this particular layer to lorelei as
technology will do it if we can't we'd
have a header for us it's a little hard
to define a technology from a slide so
we really have to get into the documents
and understand what's really there well
let me make it clear that's what's in
there now that's what's in all of the
documents right now this isn't a novelty
the funny thing is I barely heard you
so the point the Creedy made was that we
have to really eat the mic so sorry
about that
so there is one other question that's
been pointed out this is an example of a
note on a ring that has an attached end
station out there attached coast and I
want to rep I want to immolate eliminate
the duplicates and this is a ring so I'm
gonna have packets coming in from both
directions okay I want to pass the
packets in both directions
let them still go on around the ring but
I want to only deliver one to the end
station it's really easy in a one chip
router where one thing processes every
packet to tell which one came in first
and past the first one that came in out
the end without the port it has been
pointed out by people that if I have a
federated router with a bunch of line
cards and the way I built this router is
that absolutely all decisions are made
in the ingress line card and the egress
line cards are completely stupid and
just queue up packets for output that I
can't really do this okay well and
therefore we need
to get rid of this thing okay ah so this
is fairly simple there are ways there
are ways around this yes we could say
I'm not able to do that you can only do
elimination on input so we'll go ahead
and pass the packets on to the next guy
and let him do the elimination I don't
think that's great for bandwidth there
are cases where you get at least three
copies on a wire which is not which is
not a good idea so a number of potential
solutions are possible I would suggest
that you know a right solution would
that would be at most put a note in
there that said you know make sure if
you care that to watch out for this
problem
purity compeller I think we should put
down what we want the box to do and not
how it's architected and if the box is
stupid don't use it I perfectly that
sounds good to me
and actually do it it's Lou norm that's
actually really the point I was getting
at is is that we've the the function
you're talking about from a box
standpoint really is unaware that you're
talking over a ring that's right really
it really is Jo and I'm blanking on the
term I wrote the document but I just
blanking on a term of what we've called
it in the past but we have the in
whether you're doing your modeling it as
an end-to-end recovery
LSP recovery or a segment recovery you
have a point that does the the
replication and and a point that brings
that does the recovery and from a box
standpoint whether that's over a ring
topology or a mesh topology or tree
topology you know who cares of course I
wouldn't have net and I completely agree
you can have these nested one within the
other so you can have one replication
point going to another point in the
network that has another replication
point and then I'm all being merged back
together I understand this the the where
this came from where this came from
is that people who are doing elimination
today typically think of a thing in the
center of the box that if it sees the
second copy it throws away
and then it does the forwarding the
document that we have is very explicit
that you do your forwarding and then you
do the elimination just before out put
that vial that's not the way a lot of
people do this similar things today and
they find that a shock and I have had
two people at this meeting and several
at very and many people over the the
last three years come and say oh wait a
minute this is screwed up I have to I
have to wait and yes you it's more if
you do it in one thing in the center of
your box you have to think about things
and you have to emulate that behavior
and that's not trivial so if we make it
clear what we want to do I'm cool with
that clear you're saying what you want
to do on a box level not an interface
level yeah and if someone chooses to
implement it in the center of the box
great if they choose to men and an
engineer face that's right but what we
specify is the behavior we need right
which will not be in the in the context
of a box right exactly right so Stuart
so I think the first thing is we should
separate replicators and eliminators
their separate animals that do separate
things
sometimes it's useful to have both in a
box sometimes it's useful to have just
one in a box correct so we should
architectural split them out and talk
the set took them as separate things the
control plane will need to know about
them a separate thing it is they may be
right that's the first thing so there's
been some confusion then in the in the
discussion about whether they're
separate or not and certainly it didn't
come out in the solutions document to me
that they were separate objects so the
second thing is that it seems
intrinsically that a replicator is an
ingress function and an Eliminator is an
egress function if you have to choose to
execute it some other way inside your
implementation fine but essentially the
right place to do elimination is on
egress the right place to do replication
ours on ingress inside your box you may
have some extra packets but hey that's
just inside your box that may burn up a
little bit of back brain bandwidth
that's so what
Stuart I think we just took the decision
to not describe the internal behavior
and that it is it's a button we're going
to describe it as a box function and
it's on the box to decide how they want
to implement it and all sorts of things
to get these things to work I couldn't
hear you
Stuart Luke IIIi have to take a little
exception to that okay the easiest way
to describe the behavior is to draw the
elimination function on the output okay
if you draw if you describe it in terms
of the box you wind up with 17 times
more text so it's very confusing so I
would describe it with the functions
there and say however you do it this is
the result you want so if the normative
text describes the behavior in a box
that's fine and then the informative the
non normative part uses a example that
cover that that describes it as in a
particular instantiation right that's
fine but we have to make sure our
normative text is on the device and the
informative can you can describe it any
way you'd like we absolutely must not
require you to put the functions in this
place in your box exactly absolutely
right
Tana Secord so let me take both sides of
the argument I fully agree with you know
Stuart that will not be able to
troubleshoot and do anything without you
know more specifically lean in a little
bit more I'm sorry oh sorry no it's it's
it's it's really hard with these
microphone so you know I'm coming from
from from a multi-car side and I haven't
seen a single yang model or anything
else that actually goes into you know
the details like ingress and egress and
especially you know we've built this new
really crazy cool forwarding plane
called beer and you know internal
behavior of the box was never exposed
anywhere and I'm just waiting for you
know these these to become problems in
operations but from the perspective of
how have we done this in other groups
how can we avoid talking about that from
stuff I think you're completely on the
right track are you on the right track
of getting something successfully easy
deployed that's a totally different
question yeah I would suggest you take a
look at branch nodes and PLR
a local repair in FRR and in segment
recovery and intend recovery because
that's really what we're modeling so the
the existing technology we're looking at
isn't IP multicast but more about the
MPLS protection and recovery mechanisms
that have been that are widely deployed
well i pfr doesn't have this concept
sure IP FR doesn't have that concept is
this a one of the techniques you're
using in limit there's no eliminate
there's no elimination normally applied
in a you have PL RS they don't operate
packet by packet so we but that from a
concept standpoint we have pieces that
have that have modeled this before that
were patterning patterning after I think
this is a longer conversation that we
got time for here but right this remote
right there's MPLS out there and there's
gmpls out there and we're gonna build on
those maybe one way is really to start
proposing text and you know I think that
there are certainly for the elimination
a lot of you know not in prior knowledge
from both technologies that norm was
mentioning like ADA 2 CB and an also
application layer um redundancy removal
and if you simply start from the
perspective of what are the Diagnostics
that operators want to have express them
through a yang model then you're already
implying certain forwarding plane
functionalities that you need to support
okay unfortunately you don't have any
proposals yet on such yang models and it
would be great to start seeing some
proposals and if you want to leverage
some of the background that you have got
in a huge hell yeah um well I had one
totally related but different question
how about the just insertion of sequence
numbers are we and and all just assuming
they already perfectly exist or is that
another forwarding plane function that's
part of the encapsulation function that
Jana was talking about we're gonna
insert them unless there's a technology
that we can piggyback on so that that
would never be decoupled that should
always be only done in the end
capsulation side
only done in the encapsulation side that
it's an integral part of the
encapsulation and not come later
you can do layering so these can be
nested thanks
we actually are ridiculously over time
yes so let us discuss you let me I'd
like to take if like David's yeah this
is probably not the right side as we go
back one or two in essence a question I
want to ask is trying to understand this
from a requirements perspective what's
up here looks like trying to design
about three different fermentations on
loss in the weeds so simple question
suppose I replicate and I failed
eliminate and both both packets go
forward what what happens then you
violated the specification okay that's a
must
that goes in the doc this is all
possible device implementers about how
they might meet that must but the your
nord of text says you must eliminate and
if you can't do it
sorry go play something else's game I
apologize for making this more
complicated than it needed to be I think
we've got adamant agreement here that we
specify what we need to do and that's
fine right in particular with respect to
the prior discussion or essentially said
is that at the egress interface
duplicates must not yes absolutely so it
sounds like seven is just fine state the
requirement and
mr. go ahead Ameen it right and it's
perfectly okay to have narrative that
describes a specific implementation if
it helps make it easier for others to
implement thank you so I'd like to ask
the next three presenters to shorten
their time by five minutes and that will
put us back on schedule so ten minutes
please 11:15 sorry okay my name is
balázs Varga I will speak about the
information model and data Motel updates
this presentation is about the
discussion we had since the last IDF
meeting in Prague it will show very
shortly but updates we have made in the
drafts and will also highlight the next
steps so in the in the last idea of
meeting in Prague we had just one
information model and it was the flow
information model during that meeting
and also afterwards there were
discussion about service model and
configuration body related stuff to to
be included in the variable documents
and we had quite lengthy discussion with
outdoors of this draft and also the
other draft you will see very shortly
and in order to define what type of data
models we need for death net we have
just looked some idea of specification
regarding information model and data
model they are destroyed in 34:44 and
information models describe in a
high-level and pretty much
implementation and protocol agnostic the
management objects however data models
provide a much lower level of details
and they are also protocol specific and
pointing exactly how to configure stuff
other definition we have used is
regarding the service models I think
these are very essential part and this
is a very specific type of data model
because it is practically describing in
an independent way and technology
independent but services provided for
the customers there are two type the
customer service model this is something
that is shared between the customer and
network operator and it is just having a
high-level description of the service
and that is what is used by the service
providers in order to create the service
delivery model which consists all the
details about the service had to
implement it on the network elements and
of course we have also looked the young
definitions in order to find out what
explicit does that have to be done that
and the
discussion we have concluded that there
are requirement for three type of data
mother's a service model a flow model
and a configuration data model the flow
information model and the service
information model is something but is
shared between the customer and the
network operator to define the service
and the flow characteristics and the
configuration data model is something
that is between the management and
control plane entities and the network
elements to define the configuration of
those devices in detail so that staff
has put in two different drafts one is
dealing with the service and the flow
information model this is what we have
also updated to this meeting and there
was also a new draft created by our
colleagues about the configuration model
which also includes some young specific
staff just to very shortly highlight the
update in the flow information model
draft we had already for the flow
information three group of attributes
defined the source the destination and
the flow status and now that we have
added to the draft are some placeholders
for the service information model and
there we have for group of information
attributes one is related to the ingress
one is related to the egress one for the
definite domain itself and of course
there is also status for the service but
is provided and the plans
practically to update those droughts the
configuration of the draft is version
zero draft so there are also some part
where we intend to update and also in
the flow information model the service
model specific stuff is something what
we intend to update in the in the coming
months
that's it any questions comments
questions comments ok the last meeting
we talked about that whether or not to
adopt this document at this point we'd
like to get people's feedback on whether
it's time how many people have read the
document that's a ok number not great
not bad how many people think that this
document is a reasonable starting point
for work in the working group on this
activity in this area should we adopt
it's about I'd say it's about the same
so it's an ok number actually they're
more in the back then so I think we
actually got more people saying we
should adopt than read that's always an
interesting outcome thank you for the
feedback we'll confirm on the list
[Music]
vesko you have 10 minutes
okay 25 years ago I was working with IBM
on a transport layer for ISO name which
was 90 percent of the networks at that
time and this extra new thing which was
called IP and so what's interesting his
job is that a good number of lessons
that you could learn at this time still
apply today and for example one of the
big lessons while I was writing to an Nu
6.2 which was the Ethernet interface was
very very complex where has writing to
the IP circuit was kind of easy several
years later I mean yesterday was dead
and IP was there if we want our
technologies here to be very successful
we need to provide a very simple API to
do parallel applications which mean we
need to define a transport that takes
all the complexity of going over a dead
net link as supposed to push all this
complexity to them to to the upper layer
to the application at the moment the big
hassle we have in the field to move
industrial applications the audio/video
application etc onto Ethernet it's
because those applications have to
rewrite everything that we normally
would place in the network such as
jitter elimination in order delivery etc
and so some some very big applications
they could migrate to Ethernet but most
of the industry automotive and all sort
of things applications still stick to
serial cables point-to-point not
Mercer's because writing to a debt net
wire or something is just easier net
wire is so complex you have to do all
those functions which should not belong
to the application and because they
don't exist anywhere else they have to
be pushed to the application so what
what this document is looking at first
is how can we provide a transport layer
which gives to the application a simple
API so as to use the deterministic
network and then we'll see that this
transport and it's another lesser-known
for those times at those times the
transport I was talking about that net
transport was frame relay was what I was
writing a frame relay transport
terminal equipment and transport trying
to transport normal transport layer 4
transport like TCP and UDP was a huge
fader and the reason is those frame rail
networks implemented a function called
Cir committed information rate and the
committee deformation rate is pretty
much like the shapers we are talking
about in that net they will cut extra
traffic so what's gonna happen on this
network what did happen on these
networks with TCP is TCP was growing the
window at some point the CIA would just
see too much robot and would cut the
data and then the window would go down
and and traffic would look like a sea so
now if you put TCP on the shippers that
we are describing here you'll get the
exact same results because they are
pretty much the same behavior or Syria
now if you want to put UDP on this kind
of networks depending on what the
throughput of the application is I'm
giving you few bytes by few bytes by few
bytes each one encapsulated in a big UDP
Datagram or I'm giving you like 10 KS
and you have to slice them up in in
fragments the other whole bytes that are
going to be sent on the network will
vary dramatically for the same
applications report meaning that I have
a deterministic network but they have a
completely and deterministic feed into
this network which gives me a
non-deterministic result right so at
some point of your ok I can not use the
usual layer 4 transport that I'm used to
on this deterministic network I have to
provide something which simplifies the
application writing and makes the best
use of the deterministic underlying
topology and that's basically what this
document is it's talking about providing
a 90f sense transport so as to use
properly the underneath that net
transport services right and you see
that part of what you have to do in this
transporter your feets actually into
what this group calls the service layer
and the rest is in the document if I
don't have more time but I think it's
very good to highlight any changes you
think we should be viewing and here just
so people are following right who may
not have followed what you just said the
transport protocol like think TC
P UDP that layer we're not going to do
in this in this working group that
belongs in the TSV working group what
we'll do here is if there's any
requirements that percolate down we want
to make sure that we have them
appropriately covered and so if anything
if you could focus on those aspects this
is yes exactly that's what my
presentation is all about the one thing
I'll say and this is more as a
contributor there's been some really
good work about talking about I think
was actually done at Google of taking
TCP and replacing its flow control with
allocation based flow control they have
a paper that's accredit on credits and
they referenced earlier work where it
was just straight allocation and that
that work shouldn't suffer from what
you're talking about but yes this type
of discussion is while it's really
interesting to those of us who are
working on debt net it actually belongs
in TSP working group yes exactly and one
outcome is a discussion to basically
split what basically present what we
wanted to achieve and then work with TSV
to make this separation what happens
well that's what I'm getting at but I
also would really have the separation
just we're not doing the transport
protocols here . if you can we have this
quite being transport layer
functionality in our documents today so
so well maybe that's that's what we want
to determine david black as speaking
stage vwg chair i think there's still a
little bit of separation to be done
because i see some things being labeled
transport i'm not sure are in particular
i see some link level flow control
between the host and the first hop
switch router which does not sound like
transport to me happy take congestion
control but a link based flow control is
is something else I think we agree I'm
not sure about that necessarily agree
with what's written in the document but
I think you and I agree
okay so okay cool and so I'm standing up
here in part because a Pascal petition
at the Regina title and so that it was
sent over a TV gene we looked at it and
couldn't quite figure what's going on I
said at the very least um there is link
level flow control in this doc that that
almost certainly stays here the high
level transport protocol which is okay
figuring out what the how the
application thinks about the fact that
that this network is ticking and at
every tick you can send you can send it
most 5k that that's starting to sound
like more of a transport protocol where
where where where we can have direct
discussion about where and how to work
on it the one area that I think might be
confusing is something like pref and
whether that is that something you do
and and at the transport protocol like
you do with TCP retransmits or is it
something that gets in them what I
thought I heard about 15 minutes ago was
that your routers do that and if the
router gets it wrong the routers broke
try again and that's that's not a track
that's not a transport function that's
the moral equivalent of the class of
ring protection mechanism you find in
you you you you find in some of these in
in some of these interconnects yeah
agreed but the problem is in routing
area we call that transport yeah well
I'm sorry we can't we I'm sorry we don't
have enough we're enough words in the
English language in fact you call it
transport does not make it my problem by
definition the point of it is we have
layout stuff and this is yeah okay so
we're down the weeds what I'd like to
see is some teasing out of what would be
transport as the IETF uses that term for
transport area and what needs to be
solved here because it's fundamentally
lashed to the components that make up a
debt net Network be that the big be that
the links or the some of some of the
fancy function and then those like craft
wait by the way David the the the
replication and elimination that can be
in routers or nn-no it's but I agree
that it's regardless of which it's being
done at for debt net it's at layer 3 or
TSV TSN does it layer 2 as well so yeah
that way yes a question to David so I
mean we've done tunneling across flow
controlled stuff right so and I'm just
trying to understand your logic about
you know it sounded as if you know if
it's not end-to-end flow control
reliability it's out of TSV but that's
not true for the technologies we've done
right
like you know tunnels that that that
have flow control okay so we're gonna
need to get that have the presenter
present what he thinks impacts this
group he really is out of time but so
we'll ask him to go as quickly as
possible right so so the initial first
thing I would like people to read the
draft and make the whole mind but the
bigger the thing which definitely
impacts this group is that we have to
have an architecture which covers the
things we are talking about cheer and
then once we agree on the architecture
then we can always decide oh there we
have because we have this layered
architecture and basically going down
those sub layers of the service thing we
have to decide where the transport is
and where these repairs so I will
basically go into three slides or four
slides I've here where I'm suggesting a
tiny Delta as to the current
architecture document left is the
current and right here's the the new
thing so well this the first thing I
want to mention here is mostly the
introduction of float sharing like which
which is pretty much it going what gnome
was saying we're probably I think we
need to express better and position
better how what load sharing is I'm not
saying that every protocol that that net
is producing us to do load sharing right
but we still need to position it in the
architecture yeah again be careful to
rather than inventing new terms please
use terms that are used in the area so
we have ecmp bundles lags things like
that yes I mean let's work with the
working group on how we go things right
so I have this Delta and we can tune it
or just I would like this group today to
accept some deltas into the architecture
so as to enable the feature that rather
than go through the details when we if
you haven't already proposed one less
proposal on list and we should discuss
it there okay okay the layering a little
bit there are two slides you know this
is the drawing that that suni has been
presenting and part of the discussion is
is which layers do we really have and
are we missing some in the architecture
do we discuss that's here because we're
really out of time oh so so so okay so
this is a heads up that this discussions
coming to the list so basically what if
she goes through the slide actually I'm
gonna bring up something that Deborah
suggested and we were gonna bring it up
at the end she suggested that it might
be makes sense to think about a an
interim meeting maybe January mid
January somewhere around there I was
thinking that that would just cover data
plane so we'd look for an update of the
data plane document and then plan for an
interim to discuss that but perhaps this
is an additional topic to add into that
is to make sure that some of see if we
can cover any issues we have in the
architecture and wrap that up so that
would be a two topic interim that we
should be considering and discussing on
the list but Pascal please don't wait
for that please bring the issues up on
the list and drive the discussion there
norm now you're back
I'm going to be very I'm gonna be very
quick because I want to hear from shel
Nev I'll skip over this the last two
lines are important we've not talked
we've not spent nearly as much time
because the 1+1 redundancy is requires
fiddling around with the encapsulations
and data plane we've done an awful lot
of thought on that we haven't talked
much about the main feature which is the
bounded latency and zero congestion loss
and how to do that we have to be able to
get accurate not approximate computation
of the worst case latency and how much
buffer space you need to go along with
that to ensure zero congestion loss
without accurate numbers it doesn't work
so people are implementing this stuff
people are shipping a lot of product
right now not a lot but some to the TSN
specifications the 802 dot one TSN
specifications almost every box that
implements this stuff is also a router
they aren't just switches just bridges
they are routers and they're
implementing this stuff so it would be
nice for
an RFC to be able to call out and say
yes you can do this this is one of the
cueing techniques that are suitable for
that for debt net it would be nice to be
able to say here's the yang model that
includes as several choices among your
choices are the debt net excuse me are
the TSN queuing stuff right now that's
practically impossible to do so I'm
telling you that there's a project that
has passed its first its first hurdle
for for becoming a project it still got
a long ways to go to provide a document
that gives a reference point so that you
can say I want that I want to I want you
to use that particular queueing
technology so that's coming
I wrote a draft the original purpose of
this draft was to be able to reference
that so we could do that I'm going to
speak the unspeakable word intserv we've
done this we've done this before it's
called in serve it really is we need to
be able to take make use of that stuff
I would hope this draft would be come
with some other with maybe if somebody
else needs to be the lead on this
this draft would become the document
that says the way you get the zero
congestion loss is that you use one of
the following technologies to do your
cueing and these are the issues you have
to deal with here is a common language
so that you can talk about these
different techniques so that you can do
the network calculus and figure out what
you need to get the goals that we want
to do and so I consider this now an
introduction to Johnny thank you we
really would need a need from the
working group is a docudrama
says here's the yang model to configure
a debt net service and that debt net
service gives some abstract service
parameters and then we could have this
document says here's how you can go
implement those abstract service
parameters yeah
but we're chartered to deliver a yang
model to describe a debt net service we
don't have any drafts yet so hopefully
take a look at this document think about
it think about that during the next slot
next presentation and send some text
please just one comment there is a
version zero draft on the young mother
just recently before this meeting
announced by or who are guys so high
like that send it into the list again
and think about presenting that at our
next meeting thanks norm for getting us
back on schedule so today I'll give a
short introduction to a theory that was
developed 15-20 years ago in what four
things that today we would call
deterministic networking the
to give essentially to running crews who
pioneered this and other authors who
have evangelized and added stuff it has
been developed for deterministic
networking called in serve and diff sir
it has been used by people I were caring
for in serve and by an attorney for deep
serve and it uses a language that's a
bit different that then from what we
read in the dead net documents or
thought it was a good idea today to
bring that language into this audience I
was asked by Lou to explicitly say where
it could be used so based on my
knowledge at that time which was before
I came here this is what I wrote I think
that the major interest would be to to
have an abstract definition of nodes
that would not preclude not prescribe an
implementation when we do a young model
we have to export of the internals of a
node and if we do that too much we are
sort of saying that any node would be a
certain schedule area done by a certain
company that's certainly not what we
want so one of the things we can hope to
get out of network calculus is a
description that is a bit more general
than simply saying a node has a maximum
latency of so much so let's dive into as
some of the technical components the
first concept that is used is the
requirements to limits of the flows that
go into a network if you want to have
zero congestion laws the mathematical
one mathematical way of doing that is to
express an arrival curve and the arrival
curve is a function of time called alpha
here that means that over any time
interval of duration T the amount of
data units bits bytes or packets if your
packets are fixed size that you can
observe in any interval of that duration
is bounded by the value of that function
and this has been typically used in the
in servant diffserv settings by has been
associated to leaky bucket or token but
constraints that correspond to one a
fine curve if you have a simple leaky
bucket shown here on the Left I think
you have a question I don't know if you
want to wait to the end you wait to the
end in the
sure I could read that the essentially
the constraints we put on the flow our
maximum number of packets and maximum
size of packets which could be Dirac
which could be used to derive a
constraint over the type over a time
interval T which is there at the time of
which we observe things in the debt net
setting which gives that kind of curve
right so that kind of curve is in fact
what you obtain when you impose that the
curve you have is called sub additive
which is a required property so that's
the first element then once you put
limits on the flows that go through a
network you also want to capture what
your network nodes are doing to a flow
in in the inner of context and the port
nodes were inspired by generalized
processor sharing and packet
approximations of generalized processor
sharing so you can view this as an
attempt to put all those schedulers
there were tens or perhaps hundreds of
purple schedulers that have similar
properties in terms of latency and
buffering but different properties in
terms of implementation complexity so
that's one attempt to generalize all
these schedules so that's that's the key
the key concept of network accuracy I
would say in this context so we say that
a network element it can be a router or
it can be an entire cloud offers a
service curve if the following equation
is true if you count the accumulation of
data units D of T at time T it must be
lower bounded by the formula that is
given here now that looks like a very
abstract formula how is it decline for
for various examples in the in serve and
diffserv context practically always the
the type of functions that were used for
service curves are the one shown in blue
on this on this figure they are called
rate latency service curves so they are
piecewise linear based have a latency of
T and a rate of are so many
doulas are can be modeled as having this
property
practically all schedulers you find in
linux implementation today are of this
type and in all the schedulers that were
defined there's a bug here it's not RFC
7000 it would be too young for such an
RFC it's RFC 20 to 12 and that has
defined that a specific model used in in
serve and it explicitly makes reference
to something that can today be
interpreted as this rate latency service
curve so it's one way to model for
example the service received by a high
priority flow when there's no preemption
that's the easiest way to understand it
so a packet of this type of this in such
a scheduler might be subject to a delay
T which is the max Priya delay due to
low priority traffic and once it's
served they serve at a minimum rate on
but I insist today this is a very simple
way to think of such a rate latency
service curve but the interest of this
is that many more sophisticated
schedulers such as deficit round robin
that gives that give a number of quanta
to to every flow have a similar property
of course such schedulers have the
property that they isolate flows with
deficit round robin and with all the
weight attracting schedulers you are
able to isolate a flow from an excess of
traffic coming from another flow which
of course you would not have a priority
schedule another interesting thing is
that if anything you know about you'll
notice your note is too complex to be
modeled in detail for example perhaps
for some TSM nodes the only thing you
know is a worst case delay so if you
know something about the worst case
delay that's also a special case of a
service curve now admittedly not very
interesting but the interest is that it
fits in a general framework and I will
say in a minute what what that framework
leads to but before getting there the
very first things we can do when we have
service curve an arrival curve is three
pounds the first bound is on backlog and
nor mentioned the need to to quantify
backlog and delay so this is
once you have those curves you take the
horizontal deviation to obtain the bound
and delay so you draw a straight line at
any at any place and you take the max of
what you get that's what we can call the
horizontal deviation between the arrival
curve and the service curve and that's a
bound on the on the delay now depending
on whether your arrival curve and
service curve properties are tight if
they are this is a tight bound
similarly for backlog in the vertical
axis and also it gives you a tight bound
on the arrival curve at the output so
one of the well-known problems we have
when we do deterministic networking is
that even if we constrain a flow at it
inputs to have some maximum burstiness
or maximum number of packets per time
interval as soon as it is if it is
asynchronous and it is sharing buffer
with other flows then this is no longer
guaranteed at the output of any note
shall be increasing burstiness can be
obtained by the formula not shown here
for example that's a computation that
was very frequently used in the past if
you assume the arrival curve you have is
derived from a leaky bucket and the
service curve is given by rate latency
service curve then you have those
explicit formulas we find for example
that the worst case delay bound is a
function of the latency term of the
scheduler plus a term that depends
inversely on the burstiness of the of
the flow which is one of the parameters
of the arrival curve and inversely of
the rate of the schedule it can also be
used to quantify the increased in
burstiness that you have when a flow is
served in such a schedule now the
perhaps the main interesting result in
the context of insurv was this one it is
the concatenation property this applies
whenever you concatenate several service
elements of nodes or even clouds and you
assume that you do per flow guarantee so
you assume that each of the service
elements is giving a service curve
property to a flow that does not apply
if you do pre-class guarantees or
aggregate
guarantees but if you duper flow if the
first service curve if the first network
element offers a service curve Padawan
and the second that r2 then you can
forget about the details of that of the
this concatenation and model the whole
thing has one network element that
offers a service curve data which is
given by this formula here that can be
easily computed this formula is called
the mean plus convolution of the two
service curves for up Tory function it
might be
it's an optimization problem to compute
it before piecewise linear function it's
fairly simple for example for rate
latency service curves if you do the
mean class convolution of two rate
latency service curves you simply add up
the latency Xion you take the minimum of
the rate this translates into the
following results that was well known by
insurv and explicitly used in the
computations that are done in RSVP it's
called pay bursts only once I'm assuming
here that I have a flow that is served
by two Network elements the first one in
gives a per flow guarantee better one
service curve better one the second one
similarly with beta 2 and I can do two
things I can compute bounded latency by
summing up the two bounds I will have a
first formula and is formula we see two
things we think that the first
parameters are affected by a factor 2 so
in the worst case you can have a delay
at the first node and at the second node
that is proportional to the burstiness
of your flow you also have an additional
term that comes from the fact that the
arrival curve into the second node is
worse than it was in the first but
because we know the concatenation result
we can abstract the entire sequence of
elements by its mean plus convolution
and then we obtain a second bound which
now is tight and this bound has the
magical property and the first parameter
is affected by a factor 1 so that's why
it's called a
only once it is not possible to have
both the worst case delay in the first
note and in the second note because if
you have the first if you have it in the
first note and their scheduler I will
not be able to produce the worst case
burstiness at the output so this means
this will have implication I will
discuss in a second we also very
frequently use the word shapers this is
used in different contexts with
different meanings in network calculus a
shaper is a device that forces a flow to
have an arrival curve constraint so if
you have a flow generated by an
application it may not have the arrival
constraint so functions like Linux DC
will offer you the possibility to make
sure that the output sent on the network
will be satisfying the arrival curve
constraint and one very famous way that
was described by Renny cruises for
example leaky bucket shapers and it was
also developed in in other contexts that
delays the data until it's able to be
controlled by this leaky bucket shapers
are also very well understood in in
network oculist so if we a shaper has
this mathematical property which is also
expressed by min plus convolution which
in particular implies that if we view a
shaper itself as a network or service
element it delays data so it has also a
service graph property of course is
doing much more than delaying the data
it's also shaping it but if we were
interested in and delay introduced by
shaper then we can simply use this
formula to say that the shaper also is a
service curve element with a service
curve equal to 2 the curve that it's
shaping to another properties of shapers
that was well-known in the context of
insurv is this sort of miraculous
transparency of reshaping a very often
in network nodes in order to
control backlogs and delay and buffers
not delays if you're interested in
controlling delays we can ignore what
happens in the intermediate nodes but if
I want to size the buffer that is
required at the second node on this
figure then I know that the worst case
arrival the pattern for this flow is
worse that at the there at the origin of
the sauce so what is frequently done is
to impose reshaping and I believe this
is done in many TSM implementations now
one legitimate question is if you
reshape are you making the end-to-end
delay bound worse are you potentially
you are because if some traffic is if if
person is has been increased at the
output of the first node you delay
things and but it turns out that if you
do per flow shaping per flow scheduling
everywhere this is not happening
so reshaping is for free and we cannot
resist
no it's our ITF non compliant but I
cannot resist the mass that is given
here you have the mathematical
explanation and the last the last line
of the formula here on the left you have
the horizontal deviation between the
arrival curve and service curve of the
interest and stuff which is in plus
conversion of the three functions now
min plus convolution is like a standard
convolution it commutes you can change
the order which means the delay bound
your 10 is the same if the shaper is put
as the very first element now if you
have a source that is conforming with
your constraint you shape it and the
shaper is transparent that's one of the
result there are other bells and
whistles that may need to be to be
considered in particularly if you would
like to apply this in a definite setting
in particular that we need we may need
to separate variable and fixed delays
now what are the implications on things
like bad in latency path computation
well one of them is a whether we could
do better than characterizing
intermediate nodes or intermediate
clouds by simply their worst case
latency which is a natural thing to do
but we know that by the papers only
wants phenomenon by doing that we might
be largely suboptimal so an alternative
which is exactly what is done in RSVP of
interv mathematical constructions are
exactly the ones that are done is to
characterize an intermediate node not by
its worst case delay but by the
parameters of its service curve for
example in insurv a rate latency service
curve so if this is what I export then
the entering concatenation can be
characterized as a service curve that
has the minimum of the rate and the sum
of the latencies and then the delay I
will obtain here will have the birth
paid only once so the improvement will
be equal to n minus 1 time the delay due
to the burstiness of the initial flow
now these burstiness cannot be avoided
has to do with packet size it also has
to do with maximum number of micro flows
that were aggregating if in a dead net
setting we are aggregating multiple
flows which were very likely to do I
know that net is not concerned with any
change to the control plane so here so
this is not a change to the control
plane this would be one way to compute
an end-to-end bound using an existing
control plane of our ICT for example
here then it would simply if we are able
to export some dead net nodes as a rate
latency service curve then we can simply
accumulate the minimum of the rates that
are allocated along a path and sum up
the latencies of so this is described
here for unicast flows in the RSVP
setting is explaining exactly how this
can be done also for multicast flows it
works the same there's no fundamental
difference
here if you have a note about which the
only thing you know is a bounded latency
you don't know a rates latency service
curve well this is a special case of a
rate latency service code with infinite
rates so for such a note you will be
also able to export the right things to
this has been also studied by a number
of people in centralized path
computation if you do a centralized path
computation you can do better things you
can improve it some papers are explained
how to cast such a problem as a mixed
integer and convex programming and
giving a reference here on how this
could be computed
you
thank you so this was not a time
it was just a battery of the microphone
being dead so I think that's where
calculus can help understand some
phenomenon right a burst only once that
may have an impact on the design of an
end-to-end service like we're doing in
in detonate it can use to to to provide
perhaps resource models that are more
general and because of being more
general they don't prescribe specific
implementation so for example I think
and interests could be very interesting
to add to the death net documents how we
would use existing schedulers
which is what some networks I know are
doing where we use linear surrenders
that offer already a large variety of
schedulers so we pick one of them and
then we can do that net deterministic
networking with such things so that
exists today there's a requirement to be
able to support it so it'd be
interesting to see how to fit this in
the in the existing document it's also
interesting it's been overlooked here in
that net but it's very important in
other fields like aerospace industry the
ability to prove formally end to end
delay bound it's very difficult in
general to unless you use abstract
construction like network carriers you
have to try to find out what are all the
worst-case scenarios but you're never
really sure whether you have in your
mind all the worst case scenario so it's
possible to formally prove this I give a
reference at the end of this slide show
on how the aerospace industry used this
to certify some Ethernet AF DXi
networking which are very similar to
what we're doing here
well I think
thank you for your attention okay
questions the front mic might be dead we
seem to have all our batteries seem to
be dying at the same moment their their
batteries in the back or come on up here
if you want to use the mic so we have
two faders at the same time but um it's
very interesting and thanks for bringing
it up couple notes I would welcome your
to look at work that we presented at SMC
working group on applicability of
alternate marking method and there was
update to the idea of measuring
residence time in elements and we refer
them as a note residence time and sub
know though because residence time is
the variable element of propagation that
contributes to jitter in the service
chain and actually there is an idea of
how to do proactive residence time
measurement in a domain so that
residence time can be used as a metrics
for calculating constraint paths the
past constrained with latency and jitter
will be interesting to see how this work
presented that you present can be
correlated with their experimental
measurements in the wife Network erasure
a norm
the reason I cut mine short was to make
sure we saw this the the
characterization of the various queueing
methods is the critical part here I
think right now the biggest problem with
some of the TSN stuff is that it's not
clearly characterized in a way that we
can make use of and I think this is
going to improve everything thank you
okay thank you I think I'd like to
insist also that for for debt net it
would be perhaps not optimal to to
specify what the schedulers are okay I
mean so say no yeah do you have any
hypotheses on the floor arrival process
it's like jinny run no there is the the
hypothesis you're making is that in
order to provide in to and latency
bounds and backward bounds that you are
able to enforce an arrival constraint
that's the only thing but you're not
assuming it's I don't know stationary
process or place or whatever of course
there's nothing about time to follow on
this Lu to follow on what I think Norma
saying without the problems mics the
while we don't do control plane here we
do look at how to characterize the nodal
behavior as well as characterize the
service behavior and if we can if we
have the challenge of developing generic
semantics that are not specific to a
particular queueing technology and so if
this can help us that that's really
useful so I know you noticed you
commented we don't do control plane here
that's okay because what we really need
are the parameters that would be passed
around by the control plane anyway and
that that we do here so any insight you
have we would from this work would be
very helpful we do sort of work by
by text so if you want to put this
extract what you think is applicable and
put it into a document that's great if
you want to take pieces then contribute
it on to the working group list and say
it probably belongs in this document
then you don't have to have the burden
of doing the whole mechanical editing
process but whichever way works for you
we would just like to benefit from the
insights you've gained here I think we
have time for another comment we're glad
to work with you to get some text out of
this and get get it get a draft or
whatever okay if I can avoid and roll
from thank you were you coming to the
mic okay so with that we're we're pretty
close to being out of time
we have there was one good topic that we
didn't fully explore pascal's impact on
architecture I'd like to suggest that
there people here in the room who are
interested in working on that get
together if possible over the next day
that we still have left and see if you
can work through that so I guess I'm
really looking at norm if you guys might
might have some good time to sort of
work through that and then bring the
results to the list and I'd like to just
remind people that we probably we're
going to look at an interim sometime
early next year we have to get in sync
with the data plain authors to make sure
that we have a sufficient update to the
document that captures the discussion
that we've had today before we have an
interim that then would just repeat the
discussion so we want to make sure that
it would be worthwhile for people to
either travel or participate remotely I
think it would be good to see a show of
hands of how many people would be
interested and I'm gonna ask first you
know in a virtual interim and then
willingness for a physical interim to
discuss the data playing open open
issues and see if we can resolve those
so how many would be interested in a
virtual interim working on data plane
and sigh that seems like our
some good numbers what about physical is
there some willingness and I know we
have to figure out where that would be
and maybe like at a hub location
somewhere hands if so we had both a
reasonable number and a volunteer of a
host
so that's appreciate it thank you with
that we are exactly on time really
appreciate all the good discussion and
contribution we might think about having
a second session the next time to allow
for more discussion very much
appreciated see you in London