we get started I asked them a couple of
things I asked them what's the best
thing that has stayed the same about the
IETF since the beginning what's the best
thing that has changed and I asked for
some anecdotes to be able to share so I
wanted to tell people a little bit about
what I learned in this process the first
thing I learned is that this isn't
actually IETF 100 its IETF 99 according
to some people who were there from the
beginning this is the front page of the
proceedings from what what is known as
IETF 1 and you'll note that the title of
the meeting is not that doesn't have the
word IGF in it it was actually the
gateway algorithms and data structured
task force that was meeting and it
didn't become an IETF meeting until
halfway through the first day so and and
and you'll see you'll note that actually
if you if you look closely at this which
you maybe can't see on the slide it's
like this piece of something is taped
over that says first idea so this little
trickery of labeling going on there and
you know the lesson we learned from this
is that we don't actually know how to
count
so thanks thanks to Bob Hindon for
pointing this up so that was lesson
number one the next thing that I learned
was about friendship one person told me
that the IETF has helped him to make
35-year friends and that person is
pictured on this slide and might be here
in the audience
Mike st. John's another person told me
that some of his best friends are people
that he has met in the ITF so I want
people to really think about that for a
second if this is your first IETF
meeting anyway this is their first IETF
meeting oh yeah bunch of people
so you can look to your left and look to
your right and think these are gonna be
my best friends in 35 years and if
you've been participating since the 80s
and you already have those 35 year
friends you can think to yourself those
friendships have lasted twice as long as
the average marriage already this is
this is what the IETF inspires some
people right
it's amazing but we must be doing
something right if we're bringing people
together who you know remain friends for
that long we use this term community a
lot in our in our daily life probably
you probably heard it you know a couple
dozen times today while you were sitting
in working group meetings talking about
consensus decisions and so forth but we
rarely actually stop to consider the
sort of fellowship that it that it
implies and that really came through in
in the chats that I had with with folks
who have been participating a long time
the last thing that I learned was about
the sort of spirit that permeates the
halls of these meetings I asked people
what was the best thing that hasn't
changed and there was a just remarkable
consistency to the answers here so one
person told me that talked about people
working together towards a common goal
another person said there's a general
feeling of collaboration for the greater
good essential people doing the right
thing I mean listen to this stuff right
like think about which other sdo do you
go to and this is what they they tell
you it's about the commitment of its
people to help the Internet grow there's
really a sense here that people come
together not necessarily because they
are you know motivated by their employer
or even personally motivated but
motivated to give something back to
contribute to something larger than just
their own project but to but to come and
collaborate to create something larger
than themselves
and I think that's as true today as a
problem that as it seems that it was at
IETF one so I would invite people to
raise that glass that you have in your
hand and toast to 100 or maybe 99
meetings worth of friendship and
collaboration and service of the greater
good Cheers
so now we get to go to the boring part
here's our agenda for today we're going
to hear a few words from the host of
this meeting then we'll do brief updates
on hot topics from me from the
administrative side Leslie and Portia
and from the NomCom Peter ghee a quick
preview of ITF 101 then we'll have a
recognition of some individuals who are
stepping away from the ITF we'll have
the presentation of the Postell award
from my sock and then we'll have the
technical plenary portion which is doing
a forward look at social political and
technical perspectives of what the
internet is going to look like in the
future
and then we'll end with open mics as
usual so first big thanks to our hosts
for this meeting Cisco
the meetings really wouldn't be the same
if we didn't have the support of our
sponsors so we're really thankful for
that and I will invite Dave Ward to come
on up and give us a few words
hello everyone
thanks for coming to the hundredth IETF
I'm Dave Ward from Cisco many folks have
heard of Cisco before so I'm gonna skip
the marketing speech if you're not
familiar with you if you're not familiar
with us our rapid sales seemingly after
you shortly but there are a couple
people that I want to call out
specifically one many of you met as not
only did she hand you your cool and
awesome circuit Singaporean lion logo
t-shirt
she also single-handedly arranged the
social event last night at the aquarium
that I thought was just simply fantastic
at an outstanding venue and Kwan Fong
took the day off today well deserved but
when you see her around tomorrow or the
next day
please say thank adore she did all of
that work single-handedly
and second Charles Eckel who has taken
upon himself over the last several years
to be the lead of the ITF hackathon and
he volunteers all of his time for that
and organizes the whole thing and it is
the fastest growing part of the IHF
community over the last several years so
thanks
third shameless self plug I'll save all
my comments for tomorrow I speak at the
lunch slot tomorrow afternoon so hope to
see you there and thank you all very
much for coming
all right so moving on to IETF /i HG hot
topics we've covered a bunch of these
topics in a written report that was sent
to the IHF mailing list last week so
there's a lot more detail they're just
going to cover the highlights in the
interests of brevity so talk a little
bit about the participant statistics for
this meeting we have a few requests out
to the community that I wanted to
highlight for people talk a little bit
about the side meetings experiment and
the code lounge at this meeting
hopefully people have made use of those
is a 2.0 near and dear to my heart and
the ITF website revamp so the
participant statistics we have 1011
people on site and 142 first-time
attendees so a participant profile
pretty similar to the meeting we had
last year at this time and Sol you can
see the distribution of folks from
different countries 55 countries
represented pretty typical for for the
meetings these days the iesg has a
couple of requests out to the community
right now where we're looking for
volunteers and feedback the first is
that this is the year when the isg
selects a one person to serve on the IAO
see the administrative committee of the
IETF all you need to do is send name
email and qualifications to the IAS G
alias and those nominations close at the
end of this week so if you know of
somebody who you think wants to jump
into the administrative side of the ITF
please send us a note we also have a
note out from Spencer seeking people's
input about our expression of our
expectations for bringing new work into
the IETF the very short summary is that
we're hoping to have earlier notice when
people want to bring new work in and
more attention to the specific work
items in the proposals for new work
there's a somewhat lengthy thread on the
IETF mailing list about this so I
encourage you to check it out and send
send us your thoughts if you have them
there's also a couple of requests out
from the IAB to the community the IAB is
not giving a presentation up here but I
wanted to flag those for people as well
we're looking for volunteers for the
ican technical liaison group again you
can send email to the IAB chair and the
executive director if you're interested
in serving in this capacity and the
deadline for that is November 29th and
then just yesterday we also announced
that we are seeking candidates to join
the I saw cord of Trustees there's kind
of a staggered a nomination or
appointment process that goes on for
that board so this year we're nominating
we need to select two people so please
send your nominations to the executive
director of the IAB and those close on
january 9th side meetings and the code
lounge so we started this experiment
back at IETF 99 with side meetings
having an online signup process and
we've adjusted it somewhat at this
meeting based on the community feedback
from that meeting so this time we had
both a larger room and a smaller room
that were booked Abul in advance
they both had projectors and the sign up
for the meal slots we transitioned to
being only on site because they they
became very contended so didn't really
work out that well last time we also
have included now in the sign on the
signup page and then the emails a
reminder about the IETF meeting rooms
policy there was some concern that the
side meeting room signup was being used
to circumvent the meeting rooms policy
which describes which kinds of
organizations can use the space for for
free and which need to pay so folks
should keep that in mind when you're
signing up for side meetings but
hopefully people have had a chance to
make use of the side means room and we'd
appreciate continued feedback about how
we how people think that experiment is
going we also had the code lounge for
the first time at this ITF so this was a
portion of the ITF lounge that was set
aside for working group chairs to be
able to reserve time for coding sessions
amongst their participants
and again definitely looking for
feedback I don't we didn't get a lot of
signups ahead of time but would be
interested to know how people ended up
using the space I asked a two-dose so
this has been a recurring topic that
you've seen presented in the plenary and
in the in the written reports and some
of you are participating on the mailing
list already a discussion that started
towards the end of last year about
potentially refactoring our
administrative arrangements that we used
to support the IETF those arrangements
are more than 10 years old so it seemed
like a good time to revisit there's a
design team that was set up a couple of
months ago to start exploring some
options for this and they have a very
nice document that I encourage people to
go take a look at they've put a lot of
effort into fleshing out the problem
statement what the requirements are for
the future and exploring some 3 3
specific options we had a buff yesterday
on this topic where the community gave
further consideration to the work of the
design team and the result of that was
that we narrowed the list of these
structural options that are discussed in
the design team document down from from
3 to 3 to arranged between the other two
and essentially identified some areas
that need to be further fleshed out both
from the IETF side but also in in
partnership with I sock to try and
figure out what the right next step is
here so I encourage people to join the
mailing list this is not something that
happens you know every every year and
the IETF it's it's a fairly infrequent
thing but should have hopefully some
positive impact on our administrative
structure once we once we get it done
we've also had ongoing and the IETF
website revamp again a project that was
started some time ago to redo the look
and feel and some of the functionality
of the IETF website there's a scope of
work that was written down a couple of
years ago that you can go check out to
try and understand the
parameters of the project the phase that
we're in now is really a fine-tuning
phase so we've had many rounds of
feedback from focus groups and then from
the broader community over the last
several months we're hoping to move it
to production after IETF 100 so you can
take a look at it it's at beta IETF data
work and continue to provide feedback
some folks are providing feedback on the
IETF mailing list which is great
you can also file issues in github or
send email directly to webmaster at IETF
Torg there's Greg wood where's Greg wood
he's also has who's who's been managing
this project has a table at near ITF
registration where you can go provide
feedback as well another couple of
announcements from the IAB and that the
IAB wanted me to relay they've done two
appointments recently the first one is
for the independent series editor so
after many years of service Neville
Brownlee will be ending his term as IOC
and the IAB has appointed Adrian Farrell
to take on the helm in February we also
recently reappointed Heather Flanagan as
the RFC series editor that's one of the
important duties of the IAB so thank you
both to Neville and Adrian and Heather
for your willingness to continue
so there's a bunch more in the written
report online as I said a little bit
more about experiments note about
Appeals there have been none since i HAF
99 status update on the project to help
remediate some of the Demark issues on
the ITF mailing lists and lots of other
reports from from the other bodies you
can also always check out the ITF blog
where we try to keep fresh content
coming all the time about what's going
on in the ITF and with that I would
invite Leslie and push up or
administrative hot topics
oh come on I don't usually do this
yeah
I'm not likely to figure this out
anytime soon
thank you
I don't generally play the slideshow on
my own computer so great Thanks so my
name is Lhasa Daigle and I'm the IOC
chair and as a first
oh dear thank you this is gonna be fun
[Applause]
thank you I'll get there would you like
me to come down and watch what you're
doing all right and I'll be checking all
your computing as we go along through
the evening all right so my name is
still Leslie Daigle I'm chair of the IOC
and as a first hot topic from from our
end it is my pleasure to to introduce
you to you all know that we've hired an
interim IAD since you all read your
email right so it is my pleasure to
introduce to you Portia when Stanley who
is our interim IAD and she will take the
first part of our presentation
[Applause]
thank you thank you and thank you for
the champagne to calm my nerves and so
it is my pleasure to have the
opportunity to thank the sponsors of ITF
104 sets assisting us with your much
appreciated gifts our global hosts Cisco
thank you very much we also have hosts
for our gold sponsors silver and bronze
gold china internet Network Information
Center
our silver I can bronze sponsor Infocom
Media Development Authority and we have
connectivity sponsors StarHub view quest
NTT communications and merit window
broadband company our Thursday break
sponsor is wall Wade and our we also
like to have think our volunteers for
our code sprint and they have worked
diligently during this meeting to
enhance the IEF IETF data tracker and
developing tools for the community thank
you again to Cisco for sponsoring the
hackathon and support also provided by
Cisco and we also would like to
acknowledge our volunteers for in their
not team and our line speed is our
contractor for the network and which is
led by Rick Alfred and the NOC is also
led by Jim
Martin and a host of volunteers that are
listed there on the slide and we also
have meet echo who is a contractor
responsible for seamlessly connecting
remote participants in the meeting to
the meeting thank you to all them thank
you and then last but not least I'd like
to continue and encourage you to attend
Thursday tech talk with Dave Ward from
Cisco Thank You Leslie great thank you
so um a few IOC updates particularly the
much long-awaited privacy policy update
and the second one the document
authentication policy if that doesn't
sound familiar it may have been you may
have heard it referred to as a subpoena
policy they are updated since our last
meeting and available online we do have
a detailed report as Alissa noted and
you can find that on the ISC website I
did want to highlight one particular
area I mentioned I think of the last
plenary and have outlined in the in the
report that we're looking at attendance
we're looking at meeting revenues and
sponsorship support and while we had
about 10 years where we were able to
accurately predict meeting attendance
and thus build our budgets accordingly
the last couple years have thrown us
something of a curveball and as you can
see from the Prague meeting financial
summary we have not been so successful
in we've under we've overestimated how
many people we would have at a given
meeting and so overall between that and
our sponsorship revenues we are looking
at we are we are under budget on
revenues so if we look at the Singapore
meeting so far and these numbers are
slightly different
than the ones that ELISA presented in
part because they were collected I think
a couple of days earlier but still even
at the slightly north of 1000 number
that ELISA had on her slide were a
couple hundred attendees short of where
we thought we were going to be for this
meeting we do have quite a number of
registered remote participants and a
number of people had visas had visas
issued so that they come could come and
participate in this meeting so the
Singapore meeting will have more data
when the dust settles of course but I
think we're beginning to see something
of a I won't say concerning trend but
from a financial perspective it's a
concerning trend so for the budget
perspective we have put together a
budget which will be part of the eye
socket that is review reviewed this
weekend at the I saw chord meeting so
that's why all of these are proposed
items for the 2018 proposed expense
budget we've capped expenses level at 7
around 7 million we have budgeted less
ret we've predicted less revenue we
budgeted for less revenue by a million
dollars reflecting the impact that we've
seen in the decline of participation on
site and attend sponsorships we have not
for the 2018 budget put in any
expectation of a meeting fee increase
however we have proposed a $900,000
increase in indirect Internet Society
support for 2018 and predicted projected
a registration fee increase of a fairly
significant 10% for 2019 and possibly
33% in 2020 and and onwards all of these
things are our current projection of the
future you know our crystal ball is well
informed by data but otherwise no better
than anybody else's crystal ball and so
between the is a 2.0 work where you know
we're looking at possible structural
changes and the fact that you know we
know that we need to have a look
the overall financial model of the ietf
where do we lean to get financial
support for the work of the IETF and and
how can we you know find more of it
and/or better support ourselves all of
these things may change so I just wanted
to make sure that everybody is clear on
sort of the trend lines that we've got
and to expect sadly more discussions
about this in the coming years there is
no specific plan in hand today and as I
said there is not currently meeting
registration fee increase planned for
but we have to figure out we can't
continue we live on on a negative
incline and we'll have to have some hard
discussions in the coming months so not
to end on a downer but thank you so next
we have Peter he NomCom update
thank you this is your 2017-2018 NomCom
and importantly a couple of email
addresses there that allow you to reach
us either the chair or position or the
hall of the NomCom on that second alias
and this is this is gonna come into play
when we get to the third slide these are
the positions we're working to fill
right now as you can see one position at
the IAO see we have six members of the
IAB who are up and then various members
of the iesg the stars next to the names
indicate people who are not reopen their
positions now at this meeting we are
entering phase two of our efforts up to
this state you know we've been looking
for nominees we've been soliciting
feedback we continue to solicit feedback
we are also doing our nominee nominee
interviews here at the meeting the
deadline for feedback is next Friday the
24th and of course for those of you who
have holidays next week maybe this week
would be a really good time to get that
feedback in if you wish to send feedback
on individual candidates you can do so
through the NomCom website there down at
the bottom you can send e-mail if you
want to just cover you know the general
topic of an area that you want to send
input on and if you wanted to send
anonymous input you can send that to the
chair alias and I can enter that either
anonymously into the data tracker or
share it without attribution to the rest
of the NomCom so our plans then are to
continue working through the nomination
nominee interviews and we hope to have
decisions taken by January and then
submitted to the confirming bodies thank
you
[Applause]
Thank You Peter and thank you to the
NomCom for all your hard work
so just a quick note about our next
meeting ITF 101 which will be in London
co-hosted by Google and I can so
everybody hopefully is planning to
attend that one and big thanks to Google
on I can for for agreeing to host
typically we have a little preview of
the next meeting but they both thought
we could better use the time charging
forth on the plenary agenda so thank you
for that and now's the time when we get
to recognize a few a few special folks
here so I will ask Leslie to come on
back up to do the first recognition
this time I brought paper so as many of
you know ray Pelletier became our first
IETF administrative director in 2005 and
double bonus points for those of you who
are reading your email you know that he
retired from that position on October
31st so in 2005 the IETF had met only
for about 60 odd meetings and we know
they're pretty odd meetings it was
supported by the contributed efforts of
a few organizations integrated
administer of machine and so there's
just one more thing to say and that's
Thank You ray Pelletier
I'm supposed to take this back
[Applause]
and I usually stood up here as usually
make thank yous and well I change
anything I do when I make some thank
yous I did prepare about 15 slides but
it was suggested that perhaps I
shouldn't do that I do want to say that
you know the IAD position is just one
part of the IETF support organization
I've been here 12 and a half years and
I've worked with a numerous people on
the IOC all the IETF IOC committees that
we have all the volunteers like in the
NOC and the code sprint all the
contractors the Secretariat the RFC
editor veralyn line speed all those and
me deco my Italian friends all the
sponsors global hosts and all the other
hosts and connectivity sponsors I sock
has contributed close to 20 million
dollars over this period of time in
support as well as providing some
accounting legal and financial support
thank you very much and of course the
community I had a lot of guidance and
support yeah
and I appreciate it I learned an awful
lot by doing this so any success that
we've had frankly is the success of the
entire team not just the IAD I just
happened to be in the middle of doing a
lot of things and often referred to
myself as a single point of failure or
spot and indeed occasionally it was my
motivation in accepting this job was
frankly to support the very important
contributions of the IETF with IETF was
making to the world it meant a lot to me
to be doing something that meant a lot
to to others and I'm very happy to have
tributed in a small way to the work that
you had done and over these 12 years
it's been four thousand plus RFC's that
were developed i didn't write one of
them nor could i I couldn't possibly do
your job and I have a tremendous respect
and admiration for all of you so it's
really been an honor and a privilege to
have supported your efforts in the in
the small in the small way that I could
possibly do that so in every meeting
that I always get one question and it's
not about the cookies and the question
is something that come up to me after a
16 or 17 weeks in which we've been apart
and they'll shake my hand and look over
my shoulder and say where's ro and so
for every meeting my wife has been with
me my brilliant smart talented rock star
beautiful Italian wife has been with me
and she's here tonight and I thank you
very much where are you where's ro ro is
back here back there
thank you
if I started naming names I couldn't
leave so I will I will defer that and
send out notes individually but really
has been a privilege to have served you
in the small capacity that I could thank
you all very much
Cheers it's my turn so I get to say
thank you for for 20 years we've had one
counsel for the IETF and then for the
IETF trust and Georg Contreras has been
that counsel and he's been the person to
who I have turned to and - we have
turned to throughout these many years
having to do with intellectual property
and subpoenas and documents and
affidavits etc it's just trademarks it's
a tremendous amount of work George where
are you you're supposed to be here we
told you to be here you here come up
here come on okay
[Applause]
of course is a plaque right of course
the black yet Jorge Contreras IETF
council and I PR guru 1998 to 2017
[Applause]
alright alright so so hey thank thanks
very much so
20 years is a really long time and for
any lawyer to represent a client that
doesn't actually exist it's an amazing
and amazing accomplishment
so you know to prove it to prove that
this happened I actually dug out my tee
shirt for my first IETF meeting which is
ITF 46 in Washington DC which is where I
spend most of my practice and my mom was
appalled that for this auspicious
occasion where I get this plaque wearing
a 19 year old t-shirt but still actually
looks pretty good I don't that good in
it but the t-shirts good
so I started representing ITF under the
administration of Fred Baker and then
served through the administration's of
Harold Alvis Ron Brian carpenter Russ
Housley er ER CO and now briefly ELISA
Cooper and you know by DC standards
that's pretty good that's pretty good
record so when I when Harold became ITF
chair he came to Washington to meet and
our offices were at the the Willard
office building Pennsylvania Avenue two
blocks from the White House and we set
up on this roof terrace and had this
conversation and he asked me in that you
know Norwegian charming Norwegian accent
I was like what do you do and I don't
know I didn't know how they I still
don't know what the answer is but you
know we've done it for a long time so
thanks a lot ray you know has been a
stalwart and a great supporter over all
these years he's also a lawyer believe
it or not that he will not admit it
I have it on good authority that he's a
lawyer too but he's he's been great as
have so many other people at I ATF and I
do want to thank especially Scott
Brandner who I know is not here in
Singapore but he really is the one who
is behind the spirit of the IPR policies
and many of the policies that we have at
IETF ITF is different than every other
standards organization in the world that
I know of and in this case I think the
difference actually makes it better so
thanks to everyone
I really appreciate it's been a great
run
next is Heather and Ted you could come
on up
just Heather Heather and not Ted
we should actually say Heather and
Neville where is Neville Neville come
here
you didn't think you were gonna go ahead
away that easily did you he's gonna kill
me later but very nicely he's very
polite about it okay so Neville was
appointed as independent submissions
editor in 2010 now that was in the midst
of a fairly tumultuous time for the RFC
editor in particular because that's when
we were transitioning from ISI to ms we
worked through a couple of RFC series
editor transitional acting and current
and we spent some quality time figuring
out what we needed to do next and as
with many of the positions in and around
the ietf Neville's appointment as is II
was as much him stepping up to the plate
as it was him not running fast enough
when Brian Carpenter and others
approached him for applying for the
position so Neville is a editor of many
talents he plays a piano unless there's
a sign on it saying don't touch it he
practices yoga and the skills he brings
as a professor and a grandfather no
doubt served him quite well in dealing
with authors um and let's not forget the
phrase you know if I need help I'll ask
for it
a phrase he used quite often with the
iesg enough that they gave him a t-shirt
which I believe he was wearing earlier
today so I'd like to offer thanks on
behalf of the RFC editor team and many
others for all the sanity that you
brought to the role and all the help
you've been to us over the last seven
years and I hope you remember the fun
times because there were some fun times
and the fun times sort of come in the
form of this book of all the April first
RFC's that have been published
since 1978
so this book there's a lot of colorful
sticky notes in it and those those
sticky notes are actually well they were
blank pages they're now filled with well
wishes to you so I hope you enjoy
reminding yourself of the RFC's and
enjoying the well wishes from the
community
[Applause]
I feel a bit overwhelmed by all this and
it's very unexpected but at the time I
started that was the point where Bob
Braden was in the process of stepping
down so I had two days at ISI when I
found out all about how the IRF C's were
produced and then Rob Brydon gave me a
list of what he had as independent
upstream contributions and said here it
is off you go and so over the years it's
been a long learning experience from
there and as Heather said well it took
us a couple of years to work out exactly
what we wanted in our editor series
editor and then we went out and found
Heather which is wonderful and in the
years since then I've had a steady flow
of independent submissions I've
published what I think a fairly long
list of worthwhile RFC's and I've had a
lot of fun looking at the April first
RFC's which are very special because of
course they don't exist there are no
internet drafts for them beforehand and
along the way I've certainly met a lot
of people whom I would not otherwise
have met and I've really enjoyed working
with them and helping them so thank you
very much for all this
[Applause]
okay next we have the mouth and B
Postell award Cathy
hello everyone it seems very special
that where we are awarding this year's
John pastel award on the hundredth
meeting of the IETF
we know that John was the first of many
had the first of many jobs at the IETF
and so it's quite inspiring when you
think about what one man accomplished in
too short a time on our 25th anniversary
of eyesockets also quite warming to
remember and know that he was the first
member of the internet society so we
think of him today as we honor yet
another one of our outstanding
colleagues so the Jonathan be Postell
award was established by the internet
society to honor individuals or
organizations that like John have made
outstanding contributions in service to
the data communications community the
award is focused on sustained and
substantial technical contributions
service to the community and leadership
the award the awardees of the Postell
award are here and amongst them you know
are some of our most distinguished
colleagues they and a committee of this
group are the the selection committee
for the next year's award so this is 19
is my great pleasure to announce this
year the award of the 2017
Bella was cakey
so they see you're not going to get the
award just now my name is Olaf Coleman
chief internet technology officer from
the internet society let me share with
you I am so happy and proud that I am
allowed to hand over the award to Casey
Casey lates Kara not Qaeda
I was just explained that that is the
wrong way to pronounce it the center of
a plight internet data analysis
kaida is a unique place it's one of
these places where scientific rigor
applied measurements open data and the
Internet come together on the science
since its inception in 1997 the group
has published over 350 papers in the
majority of them in peer-reviewed
journals and they've done so on a broad
set of table of topics Qaeda also makes
it data available which means that over
1,100 papers have been published based
on that data
that's an enormous contribution to the
body of public knowledge Jana has also
become the go-to place to get inside on
the large-scale topology of the internet
the place to get neutral data that will
inform both engineers and policy makers
in their world and if you want to have a
map of the Internet topology know more
about spoofed addresses IP reputations
large scale outages etc etc you go to
Kayla it is that body of work that forms
the basis for evidence based work both
in the technical and the policy domain
and that's not all
Casey has always promoted sharing of
data the core of scientific work is that
data that experiments are reproducible
and when data is hard to gather which on
the internet that this is it is very
important to make it available to the
rest of the community in the interest of
science in Casey has always made that a
commitment that commitment the
cornerstone of her work
finally Cassie is one of these leaders
with a vision that gets things funded
and done sometimes facing bureaucratic
challenges and almost always in
environments where those that are being
measured would prefer not to thank you
case
[Applause]
Kathy said this morning and I should
speak for three to five minutes and my
husband said wow you're gonna have to
come up with 30 minutes of material for
that but I promised I was gonna talk
slow Oh too late right this is I think
it's fair to say been the most
surprising and positive total honor
surprising honor
total shock I haven't been to one of
these meetings in 15 years many of you
were coming up to me and saying what are
you doing here Casey it's been great to
see you all and some of you haven't yet
connected with and please find me before
I leave I'm here till Saturday so you
know my email address is Casey it's
something and the other reason is that
I'm tend to focus more on what we
haven't accomplished yet rather than
what we have I had no idea we had that
many papers published oh that's really
cool I don't do that measurement enough
but also because I my initial reaction
was what those are the guys inventing
the thing that we're studying all we're
doing is trying to measure it although
it is hard but I couldn't do it without
you all always helping me helping us but
k2 folks validate our inferences the
biggest problem in internet science
second biggest reproducibility and I
also couldn't do what I do without my
family my husband and son who are over
there and their first IETF newcomers did
the idea and again if you spent time
with me you can know what a challenge it
must be to be married to me at dinner my
husband will say something and I'll say
how was that measured
it's totally irritating but he manages
so I want to just say one quote that
follows on
from the Postell quote we all know which
is kind of a biblical tenants if you ask
me be liberal in what you liberal or not
you accept conservative more what you
sin if you go to RFC 1122 I like to go
to the source material is what
researchers you and right after that
quote which is quoted from an earlier
RFC Bob Brayden then the editor of this
document the host requirements document
says the following software should be
written to deal with every conceivable
error no matter how unlikely sooner or
later a packet will come in with that
particular combination of errors and
attributes and unless the software is
prepared chaos can ensue 1989 in general
it is best to assume that the network is
filled with malevolent entities that
will send in packets designed to have
the worst possible effect no IOT back
then 1989 next he gets a little more
optimistic this assumption will lead to
suitable protective design although the
most serious problem in the Internet
have been mysterious problems have been
caused by uninvited mechanisms triggered
by low probability invents mere human
malice would never have taken so obvious
of course exclamation point 30 years ago
that is and that was twenty years after
the ARPANET DARPA in 1969 so we're 50
years into this people we are old we are
like the Bell heads that we used to call
the old people thirty years ago and then
we were they were just building a
network they didn't well in 1989 even in
1989 they knew the promise and perils of
the of the Internet and of course even
John knew we have to do something to
prevent the chaos there needs to be a
bureau of Internet numbers and and he
became it today the promise and the
perils are much stronger and much harder
to measure they go up many layers and
there's going to be a lot more needed in
the next twenty years than in the last
twenty so this award really did make me
take stock of where we've been although
I didn't count papers and we are going
into writing our programs and quedas
program planned for
the next four years and came in a really
profound time for us so just to give you
an idea one of the things we're going to
try to do in the next four years the
fantastic group there was a slide of all
the people at kata that are doing the
real work so I feel bad taking credit
for all the real work happens back there
as you know if you lead a group one of
the things we're gonna do in the next
few years is tie together a bunch of the
measuring projects that exist at kata
that are a little bit siloed and don't
have a unified interface and try to
create a bit of it make it easier to get
access to some of this data then I know
people use but I know it could be easier
to use so in that line I'm gonna do one
plug for a kata project and then get off
the stage and watch people on the panel
talk about how to measure the future of
the internet maybe which is quite a few
things about the Internet you can
measure from anywhere like ipv6 whether
if something is supporting ipv6 or DNS
SEC and you might get really depressed
if you do try to measure it which I have
in the past however there's one thing
and it's also a 35 year old problem
internet called ingress filtering or pcp
38 that you it's very hard to measure
from anywhere on the internet so it's
very hard for researchers to do it the
only real way to measure it now this is
not quite true but I'll oversimplify for
right now is to get inside each network
and measure it so what is it it's
preventing spoofed packets who
apparently can put any malicious thing
they want in the packet it's preventing
packets from fake source with fake
source addresses from leaving the
network from leaving your network
classic incentive misaligned
configuration that you would have to put
into your routers in order to protect
the rest of the internet from somebody
in your network sending traffic that
maybe a tagged traffic that has a fake
address and you can't then easily trace
back to the source of the problem so
group akkada good for folks akkada have
built a tool called spoofer a org and I
guarantee you well I propose there is
nothing else you can do in 60 seconds
that will have an impact on Internet
security like this will you can download
this tool install it on your laptop and
what you do is it goes around you go
around the world it's really good for
people who travel a lot to meetings and
go to strange networks you go around the
world and it will test that weather
that Network can spoof by sending
various types of speed packets back to
trusted servers akkada and then we
analyze which networks can and can't
spoof and you can see all of the data
you can opt out to having it be
published on anonymized and then we
share aggregated versions of this data
for with we share aggregated versions
publicly we share a nun anonymized
versions with remediation authorities to
help clean up this 35 year old problem
so we're still going with the protocol
where you can put a fake source address
in the packet guys I'm a little worried
about that but as long as we still have
that be the protocol we better get
better measurement of it so that's one
of the small pieces that we're working
on and I will end on that note and give
you a business card to deploy it if you
want thank you very much guys thank you
so much
[Applause]
Thanks so next up we have the technical
plenary I would invite Brian Trammell
and our plenary panelists to come up to
the stage while we do that
Casey's remarks actually reminded me of
one other tidbit from my collection of
anecdotes from folks who were been
participating in the ITF for a long time
one of them explained that and the early
days of the IETF it felt so liberating
to just have no process it was like I
just made it up as we went along and
it's compared to like this this isoh
stuff that people have been doing it
just it felt like like so liberating and
he ended the paragraph with we may have
become our parents after 30 years it's
like both on the technical side and the
process side
I could evening I'm Brian Trammell as
you may have noticed this is ITF 100
from the champagne and whatnot we've
done some looking back and often the
tech plenary we look forward we look at
things that are happening right now or
happening you know in the coming year or
two years things that we think are short
upcoming developments we're going to do
something a little different tonight we
have we're gonna look a little bit
further ahead at this milestone so we've
had 100 meetings as we've heard in a
couple of speeches before the Internet
has changed a lot during that time in
some ways it's changed a little less a
lot of that is in part to what we do
here so the question that we want to ask
is what will the internet look like at
the time of IETF 200 so we've asked a
panel of people some some of whom many
of us know the talk was tonight about
this question for variety of different
perspectives so we have first jr. I he's
the founder of the wide project
professor at Keio University with a
focus on global computer networking and
communication he's known as the father
of Japan's internet or the internet
samurai we have hitting children a chair
of the department of computer science at
Columbia University in New York and
juanique Moreau president and co-founder
of the human internet humanized internet
sorry a nonprofit organization focused
on providing digital identity for those
individuals most underserved so first
I'd like to invite Jun to come up to the
stage yeah yeah
it's light will yes yes I know how to
use a Mac
okay good evening everybody this is Jim
Wright and from from wide project K
University and the eyes I put my total
internet civilization but you know it
means that any of the space of the life
on this planet then I know it's a it's a
no no no place without the internet no
activities no life no industry without
the internet when we think about the 200
ITF time right and so we already
understand that kind of a situation
already so therefore I called it
internet civilization but anyway I
myself have been in a participating on
the ITF long time ago like I feel gross
time and then I've been participating on
a developing the technology and then
they know when we are working as a part
of the university activities and then
they know around connecting with the
universities around the world and the
dad was academic network and then they
know that we didn't understand the
national boundary at all so that's how
we developed the internet and that
therefore there it's a very interesting
space so we have been you know
developing the internet bridging the the
other space beyond the border about
Nations and then we didn't even think
about the nation's border and probably
that's one of the reason I was sitting
here and discussing with many of the
people because I'm the other side of the
Pacific Ocean and then many people
sitting in the know this place is there
my site I'm sorry
when I first participated in the United
States you know that's the time but
anyway so after that then you know
Internet is a
not only by used by the university
people but also by the many of the other
industries therefore there any kind of
particles connected by internet which is
changing the world drastically and that
so then they know when the data is a
share on the Internet then they know
that's a lot of beyond the data beyond
the silo be under particles bridging
impacts it's happening and they're there
for the that impact of the Internet and
the Internet State in the single
internet around the world in the global
space that kind of a concept and a
principle is a very much you know
creating the any possibility on the
human being that the collaborations are
beyond the borders in the den I know
also a service platform is a created on
top of it and probably the data
necessary be IOT but you know the
digital data is a transmitted and
exchanged over the Internet and then a
service platform like you know people
can utilizing their creativity and the
wisdom to on the platform of the first
platform like you know web architecture
and the other thing therefore the a lot
of new things happening and then ideas
can be implemented on the common
platform that standardization by
technology but when we think about the
standardization with technology then IDF
is concentrating on in a bottom of the
idea an internet part only in the 10 a
knows that as we all know that web
architecture html5 standard HTML
standard is a split into the w3c so as
the many of the service platform
application area is a creating the
different type of their standard so
that's one of the concern we are now
facing at that the internet Committee
here is a thinking about the internet
layer in the de Nino but we
a long time ago we worked we worked on
you know many of the application area as
well and then I sometimes it's written
into the various technologies so that's
my concern is you know again they're
splitting into the various pieces of the
areas of the segment and then they know
they started to create the new type of a
death standard on the digital in the
communication way for example I'm
working on recent Briana in a medical
device standard which is basically
worked in their ISO and IEC and I looked
at the other specs and then there's no
specification about network
there's no specification about the time
stamp even and they're on the data
therefore there no no specification
about how to connect the medical devices
in your hospitals operation system so in
a patient room so you know I'm started
to worry about those segments of the
industry started to utilize a digital
communication thing but not not
necessarily be working with us winging
that you know running from us so but
that's a probably one of the concern
that we should we might be a you know
thinking for the future that that it's a
very important that necessary
collaboration should be established and
then so that you know be on the side
silo wall and we can we can decide off
everything so that that's one message
and then they know this side is you know
I recently used for the many of the
cases and then you know when the society
is reviewing the internet space then
they you know take call it whatever the
thing the Internet I mean ITF definition
of the Internet is pretty specific but
not for the everybody but everybody is
now utilizing the Internet therefore the
you know what we are working on is not
sometimes they recognized in the global
society who are really depend on the
internet therefore that as I said
different type of a technical standard
you know going on which is the part what
I'm worried about
so the you know beyond the surface of
their was beneath the surface of the
ocean then there is a lot of work going
on but the people not always noticing
that our our in the den I know a lot of
services applications and you know the
business is on top of it is always at
their concern but it's a really
important that they should recognize the
work on the beneath of the surface of
the ocean so that's a you know the
definition of the Internet today so
that's basically the thing then the one
more thing is that the this is since
this is a year than the last century
then in the u.s. internet operation was
very large and then in Asia was small in
the den they know the this is a 2015 16
17 and therefore now we are entire world
and then beyond the finally beyond the
fifty percent of the population is a
utilizing accessing the Internet and
then they're there for the next IDF I
mean IDF 200 then I you know it's a
certainly they almost a hundred percent
of the population is a you trading the
internet and then I you know what is the
impact of the technology standard so
that's base that's another thing so let
me well this is a digital fabrication
thing gender is just changing the
manufacturing and the fabrication
factory and you know that can be
industry very much but it's also on the
internet and then we're working on a you
know digital scan and the sending the
digital data beyond the border of
anything in the denardi producing by a
3d printer like like fabric digital
fabrication things and then we don't
need that transportation system delivery
system and the
packs and packs at the border of the
nations it's a it's going to be a very
difficult but anyway so that kind of
things happening everywhere so internet
is for everyone is a kind of a motto of
the I sock mid-90s I believe we worked
on the phrase but then they know this
committee is working for everyone now
and by the IOT devices and everything
then everything and everyone but we are
so the technology have to be concerned
about the new technology coming with the
new devices new area of industries I
really need think that the internet
communities should consider about the
each of the areas so no area of life
without internet can be considered in
next 30 years of the internet store
history so the technical challenges is
always interesting and then we've been
working on that and then they know so
this planet is a date-time planet but
one of my friend two times master owners
observing the us from the spaceship or
mr. Morrison
in the den they know he was talking
about the date-time planet in the night
time planet nighttime planet is alight
therefore it's a technology is the
environment this is environment this is
the environment so now technology is
imbibed we are all working for the
environment for this planet and that so
that was a very encouraging message I
received from him so the last message is
you know some of my friend it's too late
to say in the IDF and rwan to say don't
politicize the internet thank you very
much
[Applause]
okay I have tried to do my homework
assignment I pretty sure pretty
miserably failed but I'll have the
advantage in 30 years or so I'm hoping
that I won't be at the meeting if I'm
allowed so let me do kind of four kinds
of predictions I illustrate I think
different perspectives for IAT f200
which would be around 20 47 or so the
first one which actually give the
largest chance of being roughly correct
is probably released exciting in some
way namely that we collectively as the
Internet
will really be the third or major
utility that we have namely water and
electricity
hopefully gas won't exist at that point
anymore kind of a natural gas type of
stuff that we will be moving Tina of one
of a-kor civilizational infrastructures
that most people outside just will not
know just like most of us probably have
no idea who standardized ism it must be
organizations for that electricity
delivery waterworks and all of those
type of things the next possibility
which is not contradictory to that is we
will see new applications as Jim was
mentioning that a roughly linear
extensions of what we've already seen
autonomous vehicles and things of that
nature the challenge there is to get
those new communities to actually find
us in that they can indeed know that we
are can contribute to their project most
of them don't seem to see the need at
the moment medical community was a good
one mentioned this a third and fourth
one are a bit different
namely 30 years is long enough that we
might actually see fundamental
transformations of key parts of the
internet namely both transmit
and into action transmission kind of a
quantum transmission protocol type of
thing and that might happen I and that
requires a fundamentally different set
of skills than certainly than I have you
know and is that something we will be
able to handle at that point and and
obviously been kind of brain computer
interface type of model where we into
action model that it's largely visual
and audio which has dominated so much of
our work here is no longer relevant or
as well event you know I think those are
kind of disruptive forces less likely
but that might occur on the other hand I
we shouldn't be even in 30 years
projects too far of a difference between
what we have now or not it's instructive
to look at our in kind of little legacy
networks like we own what we like to
call them and not and we probably a high
point of a legacy network was the 5 ESS
telephone switch at least in North
America for that it was designed and I
bought into service in 1982 it still
carries for vast majority of voice
traffic mobile voice traffic in the
world even today
and indeed as particularly in Japan
Japan and the u.s. medical community
knows the fax machine still cannot be
replaced so technologies tend to last
quite a bit longer than we think they
will so I'm pretty confident that we
will still probably both telephone
numbers and ipv4 addresses around in
2047 I try to look back to kind of see
if I can do a little bit of
extrapolation
gonna be early but not quite the ietf
one days simply because the transition
that happened kind of in the first 20 I
ATF's was much larger than we can
reasonably expect for a relatively
mature technology and these are pages
from we still printed versions online as
well I mean a PDF version that will
laborious ly put together as we
on i-80 f25 which was roughly kind of
when I got involved on a little bit idea
of what was going on and well clearly
but working group titles have changed
about DHC vis me one surviving member of
that working group family the basic
ideas structures of a OU's even kind of
a topics divisions don't look all that
unfamiliar kind of a time-traveler going
back would find themselves relatively
comfortable in a I 80 F 25 environment
and conversely somebody to try and
travel from ITF 25 to 100 probably
wouldn't get to loss besides recognizing
the cookies so let's look at instead of
looking at technologies what drives new
development and fundamentally for the
Internet I believe it is the economics
that drive it besides a little bit and
talk about that the politics and the
regulatory side and the transformation
that I think we have observed in the
past 100 is when we started it was very
much about hardware limitations
arguments about variable length
addresses versus fixed addresses
advertisers memory time sizes of command
words and FTP so that they would fit
into 32 bits all of these things were
largely driven by hardware limitations
that slowly faded we're having fewer
arguments as to whether CPUs can I
handle text or binary encoding I mean
all of our favorite discussion topics so
but it has now morphed and we bait out
IETF side kind of illustrates that a
little bit I was noticing is a topic
that's number one listed there is no
longer a software related topic is
really about Network automation and if
we Sdn were mentioned just a minute ago
which is largely not about the software
part but of optimizing human resources
also we've had we like to think pride
ourselves
justifiably that we introduce novelty
and new ideas into the internet but in
reality like good engineers the
requirements are brought to us from the
outside so you could argue in 1970s the
whole idea of the internet became really
relevant because we are moving from a
voice centric telecom environment to
trying to connect computers that needed
interoperable communication in 1995 type
of one with mobility issues started to
emerge and with two thousands people
outside for North American language
realm and British language realm needed
the internet wanted the internet leading
to internationalization in the 2010s
because of consumer internet obviously
became much more of an issue and I
believe in being more immediate
foreseeable future the notions of shared
infrastructure and autonomous and kind
of self-running Network simply because
of cost concerns will become much bigger
and then and I think we saw that already
is most increasingly people will look at
much higher level abstractions than
simply a packet delivery mechanism this
is why I think partially the blockchain
and things I got matter beyond just kind
of a speculative hype
another thing to consider is that what
we work on at least traditionally in the
lower layers is has become a really
small part of what carriers actually
spend money on roughly speaking only 15%
of what you pay for services goes into
hardware capital investment routing the
embedded software that in that 70% of
VAT is actually a civil engineering not
electrical engineering and computer
science so what we do is roughly 4% of a
total an important four percent but it
is only a small fraction of what
carriers worry about and that's why I
think the notion of automation networks
will become much
more important topic so the other one
which we probably don't like is that
many carriers have essentially become
like Airlines they buy equipment that
they did not design in some cases may
barely understand they largely a
marketing organization that slap their
colors onto my services and equipment
designed by others and what matters a
price and reliability not so much
novelty and engineering feats that is a
different environment in what we are
used to in the previous kind of IETF 100
type of model the other one is that the
economic base is unfortunately shrinking
it came up orbit earlier in a different
context indirectly the IETF has
benefited tremendously from the shift of
voice revenues to data revenues that has
largely funded set aside our operation
because money was available that
traditionally went into by PSS switches
now that money was available on Wow go
to Cisco in other ways just to mention a
name I well also I believe technically
see kind of a discussion going back and
forth over those 30 years as to the
centralization versus decentralization
I'll actually posit that we'll instead
of having an argument as to whether
we'll have a centralized internet or a
decentralized internet kind of a
pendulum back from the cloud environment
back to a peer-to-peer environment that
was fashionable a few years ago I'd like
to think of it as a quantum pendulum it
will always exist in both states at the
same time and we observe our determines
as to which state you see so those
arguments I think a largely unproductive
we also seem to exist in three tribes
namely in the tribe that is used to be
called a kind of enterprise network
nobody uses that term anymore now
probably better called the data center
network we access network and the
backbone network
I suspect most of us are kind of more
familiar and spend a lifetime in what we
think of the Internet backbone then we
do about enterprise and data center
network but economically speaking the
backbone part is becoming increasingly
small part of it it is already a tiny
fraction of the other two in the US and
I believe this is true elsewhere as well
the environment economic environment is
changing we're seeing a strong
consolidation of carriers and to some
extent also equipment vendors in doubt
that has consequences we are in some
sense at least if you extrapolate by
2047 we'll be right back where in the
u.s. we started in 1984 there will be
one network operator left after all the
mergers from a second driver namely the
policy perspective we've had a pretty
simple network or in simple pretty
simple architecture namely where are our
divisions our layering kind of our
working groups and areas actually mapped
quite well to a political realm and I
take the US version just a because I
know it and be because it's somewhat
matches pretty well is that we actually
had organizations that even if they had
never heard of layers and working groups
and areas map pretty well to boast
namely we have kind of a Federal Trade
Commission law enforcement side in it
below Leo's the Federal Communication
Commission for example in the US and
equivalents elsewhere so that model was
relatively simple it was clear who was
responsible for what who could govern
what and who would stay out of certain
areas as importantly and it was the
notion was pretty much a global one
while we all recognize that some
countries weren't quite there that was
always seen as a temporary aberration
they'll just get with the program
eventually it's just not quite there yet
but it's a temporary trend of transition
kind of unfortunately kind of like the
ipv6 transition in terms of duration
and I believe and this is the challenge
part we've had it a little bit too easy
it used to be that when you worked on
the internet you pretty much didn't have
to explain your value wasn't like when
you were an automotive engineer and you
had to account for sprawl or accidents
or pollution it was and I'm siting here
a kind of not too dated 2004 type of one
where the internet was simply a tool of
empowerment and economic I'm no economic
engine no ifs and buts now we are in a
much more ambiguous circumstance I
posted the I'm one resistor we first to
not kind of classical or alia IETF
company but we are certainly working on
the internet isn't seen as completely
just a good thing stop easy we are kind
of saving humanity type of thing all of
these things are now much more
complicated than they used to be I'll
make one point running out of time is
economics went through a similar
transition some of you might have heard
about this year's Nobel Prize in
Economics which was something called
behavioral economics namely men the
transition from looking at a mechanical
model largely mathematically driven but
we're simple equations about lying
completely rational human actors that
maximize utility to a much more complex
and somewhat fallible notion of humans
as real human beings with all their
foibles and limitations I suspect in the
next thirty years will be largely
dealing with that transition where we
can no longer ignore human limitations
and we're obviously seeing that already
we may not like Pedroni fluent and next
thirty years it will be much more
complicated than that I what we have
increasing concerns about content it
won't not just be China and North Korea
anymore that are suddenly worrying about
content they don't like and maybe
that we don't like I will have national
but not on regulation and policies that
have international impact
piracy is one of those speech
restrictions and and think this is
already starting to happen that people
worry more about the ability to restrict
communication as opposed to simply
enable it you can see that in apps you
can see it in the transition from the
open web to lying to more closed
environments from phone I an email to
closed environments simply because
people don't want to deal with the bad
stuff out there so what's our role we no
longer get to claim just be easy and
good stuff we're doing kind of
humanities work here and many of us are
no longer kind of a junior level that we
can just simply say this is somebody
else's problem that we need to deal with
we collectively know how powerful the
stuff is that we develop the
technologies how much it can be used for
not just the good things that we all
value but for also for spreading hate
I'm for enabling repressive societies
for not bringing people together but
driving them apart so we are also beyond
just IETF members all of us our citizens
we vote hopefully we are shareholders
and corporations we're parents
okay season I wish our neighbors and we
are drivers of cars that might get us
distracted thus we have to think much
more broadly about human perspective and
particularly humans that are not like
engineers that have other values that
have other limitations and other goals
and we do so I would argue that we
should at least mentally extend the
motto of the IETF namely not just to
make the internet work better in and of
itself as an engineering artifact but
make it work better for people thank you
[Applause]
okay so it's very fine to be here
amongst great friends and and colleagues
and so when looking at my homework
we were looking I was looking sort of
way way in the future and one of this
are more posing questions about where
our internet is going and whether or not
it will be relevant so let me frame it
up the conversation because there are
some patterns and there's some thoughts
and questions that we need to think
about one of the notions is that we are
confronted by parallel worlds and that
which we recite today and that which is
developing in front of us and whilst
technologies one you know an enabler of
the Internet there has been sort of
there are patterns that may challenge
it's very consistence and some of them
implied a little bit by henning which is
you know controlled by the few and there
is a growing trust deficit or should we
ask ourselves whether or not there is a
growing trust deficit hence the sort of
this new development of what I'll call
what we have often called the flow of
value so we may have me thinking about
the enhanced brain and we have humans as
software and then there is the tension
between weapons of mass empowerment and
those of mass destruction with all the
human enhancing tools that are at our
disposal including personalized home
robots the ability to heal ourselves we
can eventually detect that we could be
the miscreant actors ourselves could we
imagine perhaps this is the frame-up
stalemate as the risks are so high
towards the community-driven
mass let's say destruction so some
observations as I said is that there are
there is this central tending and this
is a question that we need to ask
ourselves if there is consolidation by
organization is are we tending to have
fewer large organizations there's whilst
there's also this wonderful appetite of
societal experimentation some of which
have been alluded to by by June in terms
of the Internet as an enabler for health
the internet is enabler for education
but how does complexity if at all enable
the individual and so that is another
question that we need to ask ourselves
this slide this is very interesting
because it was produced in 2014 but it
it's already happening when we think
about the hundred years and that we can
have and now have live transact life
translation of languages that people
were talking about autonomous cars and
so on and so now we're thinking about
other kinds of realities that are
starting to develop the brain as the
interface is is interesting in itself
because now we have to look at what our
if we are looking at this dial now I
want to I don't want to call it a
dialectic so much as a polarity we no
longer want to swipe you know where we
no longer swipe devices I mean there's
one hand there's that which is good but
what could actually what could we think
about if we're reading someone's
thoughts and if there is this key to
actually think about controlling the
brain as an interface to the Internet
the creepy factor will set in pretty
quickly and that is where we will
require perhaps I do not share
capability controlled by the mind on the
other hand we are living we're thinking
about you know what is this whole notion
of cyber warfare what is it bot how do
we define it bot when does about to
become a bot there are higher levels of
control there's this friction between
individual and community rights you know
attended free of recently an algorithm
decision-making workshop and human
rights so it goes to governments or
responses to security itself and its
challenges and do we do we actually have
a threat of future increase if you will
of regulation at regulation it by the of
the
Genet that may fragment the internet
itself along nation state boundaries and
this is a very challenge to the threat
that we have to for multi stakeholders
and multi stakeholder is an approach
that has been so fundamental by which we
the internet have assumed policy making
decisions and what about something that
we often hear about is sort of the risk
to to human rights what is the place of
privacy in our world can we or should we
be thinking about designing oversight
systems well will be the red lines of
and now the future if you think about
what is happening today we look at
facial recognition and profiling
capabilities that really risk and are
risking eroding this notion of trust
that we have the trust which we define
not only by rely ability as a definition
but do not harm do not harm you
and with that we have also the
capability today that along the lines of
your own you know threat of profiling is
around you being profiled itself you can
be really put in the bucket of you are
desired or you are undesirable and there
may be also this polarity between the
haves and the have-nots and this is from
apply magic sauce calm heading has
actually alluded to general data
protection and regulation privacy these
are this is privacy by design and if
you're not ready may 25th 2018 is coming
upon us so this is a very interesting
interpretation of privacy because it's
very restrict and so that is something
that we are you know that we have to
think about this polarity if you will
and of course now we see this emergence
of compliance or DDP our compliance as a
service so the consent will be much more
difficult when we're talking about
individual much more stricter and we see
that and so I'm gonna leave you with
this because it's really important when
I talk about when we think about these
buckets that are happening in the future
is for the next 100 for the next 30
years or so let's not lose sight of the
individual let's integrate ethics and
governance now and in the future for the
sake of our humanity thank you thank you
very much for a panelists the mic lines
are open for discussion if you'd like to
ask the panel any questions so okay then
I have a couple so I noticed something
is sort of a theme in all of these talks
is that these are all sort of
externalities right so there there are
forces that are kind of being imposed on
the internet from above which is not new
but it's it's maybe accelerating a bit
these days and I'd like to ask each of
the panelists to sort of look at it sort
of one of the externalities or one of
these forces in a talk from another
panelists that they found the most sort
of interesting or compelling or
something to watch out for June okay
yeah first of all the you know a lot of
a new technology coming in and then as I
mentioned during my speech and then I
know the new industries coming me and
the which has never been actually a part
of the community like in a medical area
hospital area agriculture area in the
you know the agriculture machine
actually is very similar to the
automobile industry itself I mean
machine itself and then the turning out
to be a robot but because of the
different type of industries there for
the regulation application and the
things are totally different than the
creativeness idols so but then they
probably they gonna use the common in
technology like an internet but then
they know in different ways so that kind
of a segment is gonna be you know what
we are worrying about ended and then you
from the you know the the application
and the other usage is gonna be you know
very much expanded but then they know
they are not always a connected in terms
of the technological development and the
you know we really want to see the
harmonies between the you know those
area new areas and then existing
internet space some one thing I found I
that you said it might be wanted to
emphasize it a little bit is I heard a
little bit of a tension between two
modes we've always had this kind of a
notion that we do this bottom-up not
just in terms of engineering but also in
terms of kind of multi stakeholder
discussions and you didn't mention the
term but that's the notion largely of a
set of equals at least in theory who
would often driven by NGOs as opposed to
governments and certainly not the ITU
model or not the UN model of one country
one vote in that and I think indirectly
what I would you refer to that I found
interesting and it may be worth digging
into it a little bit more that model is
under strain in debt namely why we still
have these organizations and we always
Internet policy to happened in
governance type of things in our space
the willingness of countries to
participate and actually implement or
zoo what's happening or even pay
attention to is diminished I don't have
to mention countries well that's the
case even countries that are when
traditionally more have been more
responsive to that are no longer at
responsive and in Dutch not just the
u.s. it's a lot of other countries
in Europe in to some extent Asia where
that's similarly the case so dr. Mia is
one of a challenges we have the
assumption that the IAT F model largely
bottom of a organised in governance type
of models will continue to be as if not
necessarily love but at least respected
by others that may or may not be the
case and it may not happen all by itself
[Music]
so for me I think the I think June's
call-out don't put politicize the
internet could have been done several
internet meetings I'll go probably at
the beginning because we see the
dynamics that are happening and although
one one goes by the sort of mantra that
we are not political there's this
swimming dynamics that are suggesting
that you cannot avoid it or you are
politicized and I think that
politicization as a verb is very very
important you and to your point having
yes multi-stakeholder is actually being
very stretched today but then you
probably we probably want to understand
what does that mean if we are not
working together because governments are
involved is there a threat of
over-regulation or fragmentation of the
Internet in terms of a policy
perspective is really the question thank
you very much well things have a lot to
do all the speakers my name is Juan
Carlos when you get excellent
presentations I also want to follow up
follow up on the what is the message
that I'm getting and starting actually
from ELISA I think this is both
reflection and inspiration because we
can reflect on what has happened up
until now Lisa pointed out it's great
what I eat EF has done but it's very
interesting to hear and I share the
views that you guys are giving on what's
coming and that's when I think that the
big shift is going to happen where we
are moving from we've done great
technical job to now we have to be more
responsible and ethical not only doing
great technical job but thinking about
what exactly this technology can be used
for and what are the consequences so I
think that you guys have given a great
view very different but very
interestingly similar views on let's not
be political let's think about exactly
what this technology can be used for in
the next 100 years or 100 IETF us what
you want to measure it but if you wanted
to give a message and money you
mentioned that privacy by design is a
good example security by design I think
those are great things to keep in mind
what else do you think we should and
this is a question for all of you what
weather also you think we should keep in
mind if we want to make sure that this
technology works for the best people
take a stand on the ethics I think is
really or at least the defining the
intentionality of the technology that it
that you are developing is going to be
very important that has a direct
relationship with governance if you will
but this notion of ethics is I think
going to be more important in now and
then future that makes sense I'll just
maybe take a slightly different tack
Emily we've often had a notion that we
could just engineer ethics into a
networked privacy whatever you whatever
values you have in that I am somewhat
doubtful about data namely I think we've
discovered that just about any
technology that we've developed includes
and that others kind of in our orbit web
technologies wireless technologies
whatever you want to do I I've yet to
find a technology that despite the best
intentions every engineers in a sense
and none of them presumably wanted to
engineer technologies that could get
people killed while driving I not even
probably wanted to engineer technologies
basically uh ever more sophisticated ad
delivery mechanisms primarily so on I
but I it's not obvious to me certainly
that we could have done collectively
anything dramatically different so what
I would actually argue for is that
instead of simply saying there is
another status code or there is another
protocol or another X consideration
sections that we can add to the back of
the internet draft is that it is
important for us to see our role as
professionals as Internet technology
professionals that goes beyond kind of
our own closed environment where we're
comfortable talking to each other that
all speak roughly the same language
maybe not human language but the same
kind of cultural language many wise
technical cultural language is to go out
and be part of a broader discussion and
that includes not being shy that we can
often and we should be able to
anticipate some of things that could
happen and that we can't by protocol
design can't prevent i but we can win by
governance by political choices we make
collectively and by the advocacy at
least be aware that we're not just
become shields for technology and just
ignore that there risks involved yeah
actually yeah I wanna add the one thing
that you know the multi-stakeholder and
then in a lot of application you know
application coming in and there is a
requirements for the basic sub the
internet and then Minnesota but you know
it's a very difficult for the engineer
to
you know engineering ethics and
engineering privacy I understand that
you know that's gonna be very difficult
but it's not engineer engineers not only
being you know receptive to the other
requirements from the various
applications but also we can be more
proactive for the you know the what the
design of the you know those areas
application area including the privacy
and the ethics you know from the
engineering point of view which is very
important that the new technology coming
in and then understand the new
technology and the proactive to you know
speak up for the you know what's gonna
be the usage of the technology it's
gonna be very important thank you so
basically we cannot longer claim we
didn't know this technology was going to
be used for a different purpose and
thank you very much for your answers
hi Bob Hinton and thank you for the good
talks so I mean we both did a pretty
amazing thing
you know in the last hundred IETF
meetings I think certainly it's going
farther than at least when I started
this and I like to think mostly you know
it's a good thing and we've done a good
thing for the world but I I admit being
more concerned as we see it being used
for things which are not good and you
know we've certainly built something
that allows gives people who want to do
bad things a very easy way to multiply
their work a lot and they could be far
away from the thing they're doing it to
or the people they're doing it to or
trying to get money from you know we
know all of these things and I fear this
is gonna only get worse and I don't I
mean I want to keep thinking this was a
good thing
for everyone and you know the people who
aren't connected yet and it clearly has
been but there's this sort of dark side
that I you know I don't know what I
don't know what you know we do point
solutions around this but I don't know
what we should be doing about this that
because it it could get a lot worse so
I'd like to hear what you guys think and
I'll take it I mean maybe for the best
wow I I'll take two stabs at it the only
one is it definitely a set of things we
are I I think most everybody except any
perpetrators believe that this is about
Congress is for coming out or decide or
things that you will indirectly I think
we've heard too I'm a destructive part
we're just plain I'm antisocial part
where I think there are good engineering
and technical solution that are not just
design solutions but also ones we a week
and think can do more in thinking about
how we can make those solutions
deployable by people who are different
than us when I think we experiences with
TLS experience were secure email among
many other in security realm in
particular should by now have taught us
that simply designing good technology
doesn't mean it will get deployed it
will work wow it will be manageable all
that but much harder challenge and is
this way of we all indirectly talked
about kind of a human a computer brain
interface we tend to think of it as the
brain controlling of a computer I will
be much more about the reverse direction
i we already have essentially engineered
not we probably others who are somewhat
at higher layers systems that play to
you
and you can call them weaknesses but
maybe are just human characteristics I
died even the tool set that you
mentioned that we I don't think I
anticipated certainly not how powerful
that can be when we see it when we have
kids on how addictive it can be how
displacing that can be we see it
obviously at the higher political levels
as well that to me is much harder
challenge doesn't mean we shouldn't do
the first thing but I admit I'm at a
loss of a little bit how better protocol
engineering can basically make our
technology less addictive and less
tempting for people who want to want to
essentially render the fabric of society
so one comment one comment Bob that I'd
like to make here is that yes it's for
good but there are there is always this
tension of polarity between miscreant
characters and that you're never going
to get away from that I think that's one
one thing in terms of abuse of the
internet however it's more cognizant
being more cognizant of of that fact and
yes the stakes are higher I think that's
really an allusion to your question so I
don't have a direct answer for that but
I think it's more being aware if I may
just one quick aside can't think we've
often been all mentioned just one
example in that way I think we as
citizens type of thing is have often
been not as strong an advocate of what
we could do and I'll do two things
namely media and education well I think
knowing what it can do the best remedies
that I think I've heard from for those
type of more non-criminal kind of a
divisive parts of it is we teach
students kids earlier and we provide a
healthy media landscape namely where
journalists can do their work they can
get paid for their work they can add
facts to the environment we've often not
been we've indirectly not us
individually but by the technology
undermined those things as opposed to
sir I am bill foundation for
I think that's something we can tweet
there just a closer to what we can do
well here's just a simple are the
horizontal divide right in the demo
chariot and then you know society area
divided clearly then they know it's not
good then then you probably something to
a bridge in the designing the internet
based society that's what we have to do
all right so I'm gonna go ahead and
close the mic line and let the queue
drain because we'd like to get to the
open mics so please I what has been said
around building an Internet that's
better for people so you all mention
different examples of what could
potentially be done so ethics perhaps
not just focusing on devising more
considerations at the end of documents
but I was wondering if all of you could
speak a little bit more to what that
would look like especially because there
seems to be some one of the tension
between on the one hand say we need to
start engaging with these things as they
come up more and more and on the other
hand saying we don't want to politicize
the Internet
so now great question I you know again
it's it's it's more awareness than
anything else I think it's I think the
do not politicize the Internet is is
something that should probably occurred
some time ago and I think this is the
cognizant of it is as being aware of
that now I know you're working on human
rights protocol and cell biology for
that work the the only thing that I can
say is that defining intentionality of
use and being more declarative about it
of what it is you develop is perhaps
something I know you do it but I think
even more so stronger today than ever
before being varied this is the
intentionality this is what this is for
used for anything beyond that point you
know you're not responsible cool
that makes them I'll just I'll made
subtly disagree is I think the notion of
saying don't politicize me Internet is
that's not our choice I mean I think the
in a good sense it is on my politics is
nothing but when the origin of the word
is after the Polish name only the
community that we'd like to emphasize
namely governance all the terms that we
use so in a good and why the Internet
should be part of a political discussion
it doesn't mean that it is in itself
becomes a tool of that discussion I
think this is the politicization point
I'm sorry so I appreciate very much that
subtle subtle distinction thank you then
then I say don't for it to set the
internet too much actually your question
Brian's sort of confused me I don't know
exactly how you phrased it but you set
something like powers from above the
internet from outside from external by
which if you're asking for clarification
I mean sort of be layers that you know
sort of under that line that they tuned
drew that we are more comfortable in yes
there is not that clear distinction
between the internet and society there
is not the Internet is so strongly
intermingled with society that that in
that that that that distinction is hard
to make so my question is comments on
that so so my comment is the originator
of the question is thank you for the
correction Olaf
no I mean yeah that's actually it's a
much better way to look at it so one
call out by the way congratulations I
saw con 25 years one call out is that
report that was written as an excellent
report it really poses a lot of
questions if people haven't read it I
think this is influenced didn't exist I
tried to show that a little bit by
example is that we have not always been
good about recognizing that these
influences exist and probably pretended
more often than was warranted that we
just did this out of our own kind of
volition just like when we pretend often
it things if we weld it I may be a
little bit more reactive and would like
to give ourselves query then we'd like
to give credit for and so I think it's
more realization much of what we do and
this is good I mean that's what
engineers are supposed to do we're not
just kind of when some a debating
society that's when doing science
fiction here why not no we're not doing
we singularity here so we are respecting
and reacting to external demands we just
have to be cognizant of what they are
and where they come from and who's
driving Bo's to get to your point
Hey
Nalini Elkins I'm really really glad
that can you hear yeah okay no eeny
Elkins I'm really glad you brought up
this topic and we're talking about it
this is a conversation that I've had
four different times already at this
IETF and every single time that I've
brought up something that actually Bob
hinden brought up about the dark side of
the internet you know everybody a lot of
people said to me don't talk about that
don't bring that up there's a lot of
things I think in this context in at the
ITF that we don't talk about and there
appear to be rules about certain things
that you talk about certain things you
don't talk about and and so I'm really
glad we're having this conversation
because I think we need to really think
about the unintended consequences of
what we're doing and and look at it in
the context in the full context of
everything and not just one side or the
other and and it does appear to me that
you know it when you have rules like you
can't mention certain things that's very
very dysfunctional and we have a great
deal of power we have and we probably
understand things in a way that most
policy organizations do not understand
and people who are setting policy for
example encryption policy they actually
don't understand what they're doing
whereas we do but that's a lot of what
comes up here is we're not a policy
making organizations we can't talk about
that so and I don't know and I'm not
saying we should I'm not saying we
should I'm just saying that we do need
to talk about the dark side and the
possibly unintended consequences of what
we're doing so thank you
yeah yeah that's what I meant by the you
know the kind of proactive to the the
any areas as much as possible by the
some of the people from this Community
to you know to the other areas and you
know the other stakeholders policy
people you know the government and the
other things I mean so because as you
mentioned then that they don't
understand then they don't understand it
you know they don't understand therefore
we are not communicating it's not the
way we should take so you know the
proactive meaning that the the people
who understand the Internet should
communicate with them and then they know
then I try to convince them make them
understand you know that's very
important activity I mean I'll just add
one thing which I think is one of the
values that we hate ATF has had namely
that we participate as individuals not
as representatives as organizations
involved wouldn't be a for travel and
make sure that we still have a paycheck
next month or all of that and my sense
and I didn't mention it but that was
relatively in most cases relatively easy
in the past thirty years they're just a
the organization's tended to be when
plumbing organizations in many cases if
you like internet plumbing organizations
the organization's tended to be
involuntarily non influential in terms
of policy non influential in terms of
just public perceptions as in most of
the organization we work for nobody had
ever heard of outside of a relatively
small community except maybe a carrier
that you might work for that was a
consumer facing one I think that will be
hard oh well many of us now work for
organizations particularly in commercial
space that are dominating in many ways
certain areas of economy or influencing
I mentioned the media influencing those
other areas often in not-so-great wise
and we conflict between what we believe
citizens individuals as engineer
and what our employer believes or larger
ecosystems of sponsors and others
believe that's going to be harder to
reconcile and that's just gonna be tough
so nothing to add but thank you for the
comment
so thanks I'm sorry I closed the lines
awhile ago
oh he was oh okay I'm sorry I didn't see
you okay were you there before Andrew
who's okay flip a coin go thank you for
this beautiful girl email free of
presentations that was very nice thank
you
what what struck me as the thing your
presentations had in common is maybe
that if you take the intent principle
that with Judy and entity is perhaps not
so much the phone or the computer but
the human being yeah I just wanted to
note that
you drew thanks my name is Andrew
Sullivan thank you for this discussion
i-i-i think i want to ask a slightly
nasty question and and that is well one
of my favorite twentieth-century
aphorisms is we reshape our tools and
thereafter they shape us and and it
seems to me that the discussion so far
has concentrated on the distinction
between the humans and this technology
that they have invented and are
deploying but it seems to me that you
know we're cyborgs right and and we have
become now these these creatures that
are internet 'add and so I wonder
whether there is this problem that in
fact we've lost the ability really to to
make the kinds of decisions or to have
the sorts of intentions about what the
technology can do that we may be once
upon a time could have had I don't know
and so I wonder if that's the case can
we really have the program that we've
discussed here where we think about like
the next 100 because the next 100 is
going to shape us instead so I thought I
would ask you whether that's a problem
that we are so interesting yes of course
the analogy of cyborgs because you're
walking you know you're walking
technology bits um yeah I think the
thing of it is is when you become the
cyborg is understanding what you were
doing you know and its implications you
know it's it's like people when you have
a pack of cigarettes it could cause
cancer or something and you you
understand that I think understanding
the implications are are clearly
important some people believe also that
privacy will be lost in all of that so
it's it's it's it's it's having and and
it's being able to communicate what that
means you know when you have that power
when you are that power what that means
to you as an individual I think it's
just being cognizant of it
okay um the yet two things are obvious
in this committee the development and
developing the technology in their
operating the technology but that led
into that comment and the questions I
think it's really important for the
future that the designing the
technologies in the you know designing
the Internet are or Internet space to
society that basically include
everything but that really the important
thinking about the design of the future
oh and I think we have one advantage and
I think this discussion whenever you
particularly go microphone contributions
I indicated that and it we are not the
first engineering discipline that has
had large effects on the environment
probably you could argue others mainly
mechanical engineers if you blame them
so to say for the internal combustion
engine and other machinery
I might have probably at least as large
an effect on our human environment but I
mean I think we've had one advantage
maybe because it happened faster maybe
because it in some sense more obvious
and just gases in the atmosphere is that
we can see it earlier and so that gives
us I think maybe a little bit of more
lead time in a little bit more of a
opportunity to react to it again in my
others this is not the first engineering
discipline which has fundamentally we
shaped not how humans live a miracle
none of us can imagine going back before
individualized transportation just to
take out whatever form it takes none of
us can imagine going back when there was
no electricity none of us can imagine
going back to an environment where we
didn't have many of the other
engineering contributions where they are
sometimes not so great impacts as well
so I don't think we're unique but I
think we have
I think it's come son more suddenly and
probably I mean others way batsmen
people have talked about global warming
since the late 19th century I in one way
or another so I think for us it is a
more sudden awakening as opposed to just
being necessarily different thank you
very much so um we are actually I would
like to have this morning haven't have
had it have us had more than five
minutes for the open mic I apologize for
letting this run long but I think this
was a really really interesting
discussion I'd like to thank the
panelists again and one of the open mics
is up but I'm not sure what it is
because I'm a cyborg now and my internet
is down and Ted tells me I'm supposed to
stay here so I'll do that
that means it's the IAB open mic unless
something has happened in the 30 minutes
of that talk so I apologize Brian you
let it run long so now you're on the IOC
no actually the IAB is up first so if
you're on the IAB we invite you to join
us here on stage if you're not currently
on the IAB and you'd like to be
nominations committee would like to talk
to you
[Laughter]
so Martin would you begin by introducing
yourself you have to press the button to
introduce you
Oh Martin Thompson mark Nottingham Jesus
this is animals don't amigo that's not
who you are
Justin - it Ted Hardy Brian Trammell i
uz Joey brand
Lee Howard Yatta Yatta Eric not Mike
so the mic lines are open and we are
ready to take your question about the
internet architecture the internet
architecture board or the work they're
up
all right hearing none I'd like to thank
Cisco very sponsoring us tonight and ask
the IOC to join me on stage and thank
you for the absence of questions
all right if you wanna start I'm John
Levine blueburger cover a range crack
still SV natal Alisa Cooper said Rd to
buy a scone room Kathy Brown Porsche win
Stanley
all right questions for the IOC please
heading towards last call so look for
that soon in your mailboxes and my
suggestion is that you read it like the
idea which places who might go for many
fine lunches and dinners and wait thank
you for the PSA and thank you to the
group for putting that together the mic
I'm sorry eat the mic Oh
but it's Indy number I wonder if you
collectively have tried to analyze as to
why that difference between projection
and we allottee exists is it something
systemic is it something temporary yes
so that's that's frankly the analysis
that we have to do now more we have been
doing some when we have to do more of
for any individual meeting you can come
come up with a reason for why the
numbers might be down what's the
industry doing you know we had a period
of four meetings where no matter where
you started in the world the for meeting
stretch was going to be expensive so I
think it is need a combination of having
a look at what's going on in the
industry what's you know what can we see
about attendance and what not
maybe a quick comment so I have looked
at some statistics of delegation sizes
and they have shifted in the last one
and a half years and I encourage you to
look at the statistics I like I only
have seen this personally but not as an
IOC body so we don't actually publish
the statistics because I feel we don't
do any sort of normalization around
affiliation like you can sign up under
whatever affiliation you want so we've
kind of done it in an ad hoc manner but
it's not something that we publish to
the community but interestingly if you
look at the if you if you do some of
that and you try to clean up the data a
little bit based on your own intuition
there's trends in both directions so
some companies sending more people at
the at the end of the spectrum of
corporations that send lots of people
some of them going up some going down I
haven't looked at the lower end I've
only looked at the at the upper end
Andrew hi I'm Andrew Sullivan so I guess
this is on the same topic as I guess you
might have imagined it would be I it
seems to me that for the last couple of
years anyway you know we've been
pointing out that there are a number of
trends that that could push the this
this number a little bit lower and and
we've sort of been setting the stage for
the idea that this this could happen and
I guess the question that I have now is
whether there's a plan for a plan to to
do with it assuming that it's a long
term thing I mean who knows whether it
is but just suppose that it were is
there a plan for a plan for doing that
or is that something that is in
development or is it something that
nobody's thought of I don't think a lot
of time right so I think as I trying to
articulate earlier in part it's a
question of revising the budget to
understand you know we're expecting
fewer people which has trickle-down
impacts in terms of our now that we have
our hotels lined up for your sin advance
you know we are expecting expecting
meetings of certain sizes beyond that I
think it's a question of understanding
yeah I think that there's work for the
isg to do in terms of understanding how
this relates to the work that needs to
get done and there's further work to do
in terms of figuring out well do we then
just jack up the meeting attendance fee
and you know make make the five people
who still come pay a lot or or or is
there a better balance for for funding
the work that needs to get done in order
to continue to have open standards for
the internet so again it's it that's
just saying a lot of words say there's
there's there now is a time to start
digging into it and trying to understand
how much is us is it us is you you know
and and how do we cope with that so
maybe
about this but you know there's there's
there's two sides to the budget right
and one side of course is the is the
income but the other side is the
expenditure and we we haven't been very
good about controlling that and in
particular for for good and proper
reasons we have been extending more and
more the efforts in in remote
participation which of course is one of
the potential contributions here and I
wonder if that's a discussion that the
community sort of more generally needs
to have but whether that's something
that we're prepared to continue in that
direction
or whether we need to find some way to
recover some of those costs or what all
right so that's that's part of why I put
this slide up this was this is the extra
slide in my deck from earlier so there's
costs associated with providing really
excellent remote participation and
there's the possibility that you know
maybe everyone's saying well heck I hate
Airlines anyway they're just a little
you know tin cans of germs so why don't
I say home and you know deal with it
remotely certainly there's some of that
going on I'm sure we all anecdotally
have friends who didn't make the trip
this time but it's also a question of
it's part of our reality now and being
able to have such excellent excellent
remote participation means that we can
tap into resources that would no longer
be available to us if we only had
on-site participation which also I think
leads to I think what you were getting
at which is do we start charging for
remote participation and and that's a
possibility but I think we don't
understand the answer to that question
until we have the further work that we
talked about earlier which is what what
is the right financial model for how we
float this boat anybody else
John yep beyond that my impression is
that many of there many of the remote
participants are from parts of the world
where it is unlikely that they would
come to a physical meeting which is good
you know and so would you know and it
also means that if we charge and meaning
we charge a meaningful amount for remote
participation we're likely to exclude
them and I think that there's there's a
there's a you know there's a related
issue that you know the average age of
people here
is high and you know and I'm like yeah I
have this great beard and you know and
and an adult adult child that means I'm
sort of a sort of a median age here and
many of these remote participants from
developing countries are young which is
good you know and they're doing
interesting work so I think there's
there's a there's a whole bunch of
interacting issues you know it's like
you know we need to we need to do that
you know we have this work to do you
know we may well it may well be the
model is that that you know we can't we
can't expect to get as much money from
part from the participants as we have in
the past and we look at we look at other
places you know and wearing my eye sock
hat this is certainly an issue that I I
sock is thinking about and I sock has
always been thinking about development
you know and I sock is not exactly poor
so you know so the you know this isn't I
wouldn't say it's a can of worms but I
would certainly you know it's it's it's
a it's a challenging opportunity you
know that we all need to think more
about because because our future is not
necessarily assured you know and we need
to figure out where the people are gonna
come from they're gonna they're gonna do
the work and what's the model that's
gonna actually allow them to do it so
I'll observe that some of the squares on
the table actually say no data and
that's in part because we actually only
started requiring instead of we started
with offering the opportunity to
register for remote participation but we
only started requiring registration for
remote participation relatively recently
and it's all part of a hand wringing
exercise of you know how should we
approach this beast and you know do we
ask people for their information for
remote participation and as a result we
actually don't have we have intuitions
in some sense of who's participating
remotely but we don't yet even have that
information so we had thought about
possibly attaching a survey to the
opportunity to fill in the survey as
part of remote registration for this
meeting it didn't see in the right time
or the right place but I think that
that's one one way that we may have to
look at getting more concrete data about
who's using this and why
so what your first question Andrew you
used the phrase dealing with it and I I
think it's important to recognize
there's the budget impact but then
there's also just the impact on the work
that is done in the ITF I think people
sort of seem to assume that there's this
like ideal number of people who shows up
at a particular meeting and for seven
years it was 1200 but it wasn't always
1200 right I'm sure people remember when
it was 2000 and other people remember
when it was 50 so you know it might be
that the new normal is a thousand people
showing up in a meeting and then we can
we also have to think not just like okay
well we lost $700 ahead on those 200
people but is a thousand people coming
here to do work that needs to be done
and are there people who are missing
maybe maybe it's the right thousand
people maybe we are all the anointed
ones I don't know but I think it's
important to to not only focus on this
question from a budget perspective but
also from a perspective of are we
attracting the the set of people who
need to come to the work here not
necessarily the right number of people
all right so there's a weird dance going
over on this mic and I wasn't sure
whether it was Stuart or urn next but
but Ali's jumped in front so I'm going
to assume that leah is has something
topical on this point and then I'll go
to Erin oh yeah sure so I mean this
trend is concerning and I really
strongly agree with Alyssa that the
strength of the IETF is in our
intellectual capital is in the multi
stakeholder perspective that we have
across the network and the concern on
reducing the diversity and participation
and ability of folks to actively
participate remotely in will hurt us I
mean that's that's really my concern the
other part is you know there's a reason
I'm working on IETF outreach instead of
fun routing algorithms
and it's not because I don't prefer the
funny routing algorithms it's because we
need to work on pulling in from the
right industries for our colleagues in
the area not just those who come here
but participating locally on the mailing
list we've got much higher mailing list
attendants but we need to be working on
this because yeah I mean look around the
room there's a lot of gray hairs and we
keep having people retire and that's not
going to change so please think about
this a lot sorry it's not a question to
the IOC but okay Aaron Aaron Faulk so I
was fairly apprehensive about making
this trip there was a lot of discussion
about it as we got closer and I was
watching the attendees 100 list I got
even more apprehensive I will admit that
I broke several rules on the way here
chewing gum may or may not have been
involved but I have to say that I've
been uniformly impressed and pleased by
the venue the a/v support at the hotel
the food especially this is I think a
great place to have a meeting and I'd
like to thank the IOC the secretary ray
and everybody involved for making it
happen I think that as meetings go just
sort of organizationally this has been
actually one of the better organized
meetings so thank you thanks for that
Stuart and you are Stuart Bryan sorry
yeah you have budget stureplan but so do
we this time next year we don't even
know which continent we're going to be
on let alone not true it's posted as
Asia alright I'll check that after it
should be indeed a fair point so so yeah
so to respond substantively to your
point about we don't know where we
haven't published where we're going a
year from now it's certainly imported
deep concern for us it's certainly been
something that we've been talking that
fact that this is late an announcement
has been something we've been talking
about for quite a while but we do
struggle in finding locations that fit
us that have the the right balance of
our hotel requirements our meeting venue
requirements and availability and some
manner of affordability and you know
this is clearly us and hopefully we're
getting a little better at it but the
long and the short of it is we have been
we had been struggling to find a
location for next years we we believe we
have one in hand but we don't announce
before we have the details finalized
because that would undermine our ability
to close a reasonable set of contracts
so again I can only apologize it's
taking this long
it's not because we're insensitive to
the fact that everybody needs to make
their plans it's just that we're working
hard at getting better at figuring out
how to get ourselves to good locations
in Asia and this took longer
hi Justin Richard I just wanted to thank
you guys for providing the rooms the
explicit rooms for side meetings one of
the groups that I'm involved in here we
actually had a much more productive side
meeting than actual working group
meeting like like 20 times more
productive it was kind of amazing and
having the space to be able to sit down
around a table and do that kind of thing
because we didn't know that we were
going to need that extra bit until we
got here and the working group meeting
didn't quite go as smoothly as we would
have liked but having that space to be
able to do that that was a little bit
more formal than just piling everybody
into you know the hotel lobby or
something like that was incredibly
helpful for us I think it will probably
continue to be helpful for groups like
us and others going forward so I would
encourage you guys to keep doing that if
that continues to be an option in venues
going forward so thank you for that sir
and to be to be fair the IOC can take
the credit for having the hotel space
for doing it but you really should be
thanking ELISA and the isg for thinking
of doing it not seeing anybody else at
the mic Kathy you wanted to say
something yep very quick announcement so
just so you know Computer History Museum
in California is has it started
archiving all of the RFC's and I'm just
announcing it all of the work has done
by header or from our lovely RFC editor
team
I'm just announcing because it went
through ITF trusts but from first RFC
till the current one and it will
continue being archived from now on so
hopefully ITF 1000 now its proper
archive also its proper museum grade or
kovalev of of the service so your work
is being okay all right thank you very
much
so next up is the iesg
[Music]
alright shall we start at your end Terry
Terry Madison in tarea Debra Berg
routing Adamo chart road Ben Campbell
art Kathleen Moriarty security oh yeah
this routing benoît close-ups yeah I
could have been transport Alissa Cooper
general area
Spenser Dawkins transport jet Rd
ex-officio IAB Warren Kumari ops there's
Corolla security Sodus Krishna Internet
Alexei Melnikov application in real time
ok mics are open
mr. black
David black so we we had an interesting
time in transport on Monday and I
thought I'd come share there's been a
couple of attempts in transport over the
past few years to do something in
anticipation of encrypted protocol
headers these were gone by the
interesting names like spud or spoot if
you like that or plus and to
oversimplify they've gone not much of
anywhere because the privacy concerns
have been have been obvious and
forefront and they've been dealing with
something that isn't broken because none
of our transport headers are encrypted
now that's about to change and rather
quickly we have a protocol called quick
coming at us coming at us it's going to
encrypt the transport headers we right
now don't really seem to have a
mechanism to work beyond that to deal
with middleboxes
well I understand the classic IETF you
have middleboxes is that they're evil
remind folks that people people don't
spend money middleboxes because they
have nothing nothing better to do
they're higher middleboxes to do jobs
and if you put this if we fire those
middleboxes they'll find ways to do
those jobs that we're going to like even
less just a heads up this needs some
attention and fairly quickly pun
intended
Thanks so it should also mean for some
of the time she's spending in the
wilderness trying to anticipate some of
this so I would say we are paying
attention to it through many many
efforts some of which you mentioned and
so if if the point was to raise our
attention to it I think is the IHG
nobody up here would disagree with me
that we are paying a lot of close
attention to this if people have
suggestions about what more we could do
that that would be helpful but it's
certainly been I would say a dominant
topic of discussion in the IAS G lately
Kathleen thank you so I've been thinking
about it a little bit more in term
of next steps so we're just at a phase
of documenting right now and for the
draft that Al and I have been working on
getting beaten up wet for and whatnot
it's in last call right now and it's a
collection of monitoring network and
security monitoring that's somehow
impacted by encryption right and it's
meant to be a starter for conversation
so anyone not aware of this draft how
can we make progress in in these
discussions and so it's trying not to
take any any position but if we don't
tackle the problems our protocols won't
get deployed is one of my concerns which
is why you know been working on this
particular draft this is just
documenting the problems is just the
first step
once we do get a little bit further in
the document or get the documentation
published you know I'm sure there's gaps
in this so if you have operational
experience and can take a look at the
draft that'd be helpful or if you have
colleagues that you think should take a
look at it to make sure we're getting as
much documented as we can that would be
helpful I think so we have to think of a
bit more about what are our next steps
it might be per protocol that we go back
and look at this and we expand you know
sections to figure out what
considerations might be necessary
I would like to figure out if if we
could have a more structured plan around
it you know do we run a workshop you
know how the IAB run a workshop on next
steps is it around one protocol is it
around multiple protocols how do we
advance this conversation between the
end user and the network and it's not
just about privacy privacy's what you
hear about in the arguments it's about
control right so who's controlling the
metadata
at the endpoints or is it the network
and there's lots of money in that so I
think it adds contention to this
discussion and that's I think a really
important going to consider as as we're
working on this right because the
motivations are if you think of it in
that way are pretty clear but there's a
lot of work to be done because it's such
a point of contention and I think we
need to figure out how we go forward so
I I have in my queue up here Spencer
Warren Benoit Illya and then Ted you you
might want to keep it brief so Spencer
Dawkins the responsible area director
for quick and Davis group tsp WG and the
sponsor for the spud buff and the
sponsor for the Accord Bob and the
co-sponsor for the plus buff you're
trying to remember through were any
others so this is far my radar the thing
that I would like to see happening first
and quickly is for us to get a good
understanding what is Kathleen's draft
is is headed that direction there's
another word on in TSP whe I've been
talking with David about specifically on
encrypted transport headers and
basically what the impact of that is and
things like that I think that if we're
going to do engineering we've got to be
able to do we got to be able to describe
reality first so that we know what so
that we know what problems were what way
to try to solve I think that the IETF
can do what needs to be done and I've
been telling the people that all week
it's not like nobody's working on it
I've had probably 15 hours of
conversations on this specific topic
outside working group meetings this week
so
they say I would I would encourage
everyone who is touching this space to
to help us move move forward yeah I'm
just gonna say if people have read
earlier versions of Kathleen's draft
please reread it it's substantially
different both in terms of tone and
content so I fully agree with your
analysis and I would extend that not
only to transport but also to ops
obviously right because there is an
impact on ops whenever in the
pervasiveness ring RFC we added a small
sentence that encryption is good and
privacy is good but we have to do need
to have a balance with the way to
monitor networks and so yes I agree with
you I'm very concerned about the future
of the internet if on your couple of
people could innovate so I'd like to
turn the question around from asking the
isg to pay attention because we manage
the work that you come up with and bring
to it and this is an area where we need
research and we need people thinking we
can document the problems we can see the
technology change needing to happen for
other reasons but this is one of those
places where we have an opportunity both
to change or tilt the field as David
Clarke talked about at a previous
plenary to think about the ethics and
the implications of what we're doing
here and more to the point and equally
critical or Professions a board appoint
equally critical to make sure the
internet keeps working so think about
what you could do what kind of research
what kind of problems are you going to
see in your enterprise networks because
we all have them in your customer
networks what kind of changes would
I for the vendors what kind of new
technology could we use to do better
network management and operations
obviously I would like you to think
about what impact it will have in a
routing potentially as a result of those
things - but the key point is we need
you to be thinking about it and bringing
the work to the IETF to get done and
standardized Thank You Ted Hardy maybe
you remember may remember us from Coby
we're the thing you associated with it
that's not the beef so the role of the
IAB anymore is not to tell the ITF what
to or we do try and think about issues
like this and we have been thinking
about this one for a very long time we
ran the Marnie workshop we contributed a
great number of people to both the
effort around spud and Plus and we
continued to work on this in fact we
suggested yet another workshop on this
and we're asked to delay it because
there were such active contention around
the topic and tell us that it would look
like the IB was trying to step in I
think that what we've been trying to
articulate through the couple of years
we've been working on the problem has
essentially boiled down to this the the
messages which carry state mechanics
between endpoints and the messages which
carry signals to the path have divorced
and we do not intend to marry them again
that means that the messages which carry
path signals now need a whole new type
of creation and analysis than we've seen
in the past inside the quick working
group there was a design team looking
and analyzing the impact of a single
spin bit this is one bit worth of signal
to the path and over several months we
got a whole bunch of academic
information and a whole bunch of
practical experience that told us yeah
from a geolocation threat analysis this
isn't actually a big deal what it can
actually provide the operators isn't
actually any data that we can't get any
other place else but it may be more
convenient for that than other
that's the level of analysis that we're
gonna have to do bit by bit
as we put these things onto the path
because from now on we have to realize
that we're responsible for these path
signals they're not going to be
accidental inferences of the state
mechanics we're sending across the
network they're our responsibility and I
think we have to do it very carefully
but we absolutely have to do the
analysis Spencer again I just wanted to
add one more thing first I would I would
think that at least the IB semi workshop
was also relevant to this space so
basically we we've gotten to the point
on this with leadership to where the IAB
can't chair can't remember all the stuff
that they're doing trying to help
sure and the way the way the IEP and isg
do annual retreats is this past year the
IB met for two days we met jointly for a
day and the ISG met for two days I don't
know what the IAB did a lot but I know
that we talked about this on our joint
day and we talked about on Thursday we
talked about a Friday and if we were
still there we would probably still be
talking about it so please understand
that you have the interest and backing
of your leadership as you are doing
these investigations and helping us -
helping us all to understand what we
need to understand in order to move
forward okay good yeah tell us Eckerd
what work product is planned to document
what will break moving from TCP to quick
and can be recovered or cannot be
recovered in a language that is
understandable but you know operators
and not protocol geeks
so we have the manageability statement
which is only there to explain to the
network what the bits mean how you can
use them and what you can use do with
them and the audience is really not like
between us the audience is the outside
the operators the people that install
the stuff and I still actually learn how
to pray sit and like feedback I got this
for example I don't read RFC's so it's
really hard if we want to document this
in an RFC but we're on it so if it's on
the level of that a normal operator
understands like which are features of
middleboxes like you know
application-aware firewall or TCP
acceleration or what-have-you is that
the language for which work product is
being planned so we explained in very
detail how you can use the information
that's available you have probably to do
some some own work to map it to the
mechanisms you have right now because in
future the emissions might might be
different so is that a yes or no the
answer is it's not only one document
yeah and I mean also it's not only us
who generates these sort of documents
right there are discussions happening
and network operator communities about
the specific
set of stuff that's changing so it's not
only us who generates this this is you
know I brought up a thread and I use G
just a few weeks ago about I guess the
best way to phrase it is the relevancy
of the IETF
and how to bring users here with real
requirements and the things I've heard
in the industry is we're arrogant
we don't listen people other people's
solutions are broken we you know better
and we just seem to be a one-way filter
and the problem is is I think these
people would come here if they felt
welcome and I don't think they feel
welcome they feel very intimidated and I
can see a lot of reasons why it's
because when they come they say they
if they come they ask for solution X and
we're engineers where we want to know
the problem when they're standing first
before we provide solutions I always use
the SD when market as an example we've
been doing overlays and tunnels for so
long in the IETF and there's a you know
50 million dollars worth of VC funding
at least in two dozen Sdn vendors that
are implementing all these proprietary
things why aren't they coming to the
standards group and using this
technology that we have now they say
they want to do their own intellectual
property and I think a lot of vendors
can make a lot of money to do a lot of
cool stuff by taking our protocols and
creating good features and good products
and services around it but they feel
like they have the need that they have
to build it themselves it's kind of
scary what why are we being pushed into
your relevancy I think we need to go to
these groups of people and we have to
really show them that we're not arrogant
that we're really going to listen to
them and we're going to work together
they do need help and they they want to
build better solutions so I don't have a
question but I just want a reaction or
any comment from any of you I do you
know so I mean we have and continue to
try to reach out into operator
communities I know that Warren and
Alvaro for instance are talking about
possibilities at Nanog as well as others
one of the challenges as time frames one
of the challenges is that people come to
communities to organizations to do work
where they feel comfortable and that
they will be listened to and we have a
different culture and different
timeframes we also suffer from the fact
that the IETF is made of volunteers and
going to going out has its own
challenges it really takes the part of
individuals who decide to be ambassadors
between the organizations
to help do that one of the things I mean
I trying to start ITF outreach pieces is
it's a start right
but it can't just be me and it can't
just be a few plate you know one or two
places I'm trying to get parts there one
of those pieces is to have smaller
groups with more friendly conversations
on different technologies where you
start building up the professional
connections with other folks so that
they feel they can come in to the IETF
and be introduced the folks who will
also be able to help and care and guide
and mentor and bring in the necessary
work one of the challenges is also like
in the sd1 case figuring out and seeing
early markets and industries where there
will be a benefit from having an
interoperable standard and where that
benefit can be articulated and
communicated back but doing all of those
things is not our business as usual for
the working groups and we're volunteers
and we need to have people volunteering
to help decide I mean I'm happy to
brainstorm about it and I have been but
I can't do it all myself right we all
need to it's how do we pull more people
in how can we have folks be interested I
would love very much to see more
operators and to see these types of
things coming into the IETF and I
gleefully jump at each relatively
practical new technology that does come
in it's a hard problem but we can at
least keep making head rotor on it so we
know we know that these people we know
that standards groups are important or
people want to build standards because
there's you know the Emmy C there's all
these consortiums not really
international standards groups that do
stuff so we know that there's a need
there but one particular user group
that's interesting is this ona the open
network user group it's started in New
York with the financials and these are
guys that first came out and said we're
going to
build working groups to figure out
problems in the enterprise and how to do
things and they're actually turned into
building solutions and they're really
kind of inferior solutions and they know
about it but they don't want to come
here I mean we want to encourage them to
come here and talk and talk to us why
don't we just invite these people all of
us can do it anybody in the audience
could and we just create a gender time
so they can come and talk but we have to
make them feel welcome we got to remove
this intimidation factor so we need to
asking them to come short but we need to
be listening absolutely and that may be
part of that it ain't we have people at
the IETF who go to nog and participate
there one of the ways that we all of our
liaisons regardless of whether or not we
have a formal liaison work by having
overlapping communities we have that
overlap what we need to do is figure out
how to grow it and to do the
encouragement so they have agreed to
come here and I told them I would help
them to get people from here to go there
and we're gonna get agenda slots at the
next meeting so if anybody wants to talk
there's just some rough areas they want
us to focus on security routing some
application level stuff so we should do
this
so anybody interested I'm sure we can
find some folks who are interested yes I
mean a couple of years ago Chris
Grundmann from I sock did a whole bunch
of sort of surveys of the industry
operators etc found a bunch of really
useful info as you said we often come
off as arrogant some of that is people
who are well known in the operator
community could sort of arrive here and
we don't know who they are and so
there's sort of a disconnect on us not
listening we did have a bunch of
momentum at the time like we had a
couple of tables at some operator groups
to get feedback etc we lost that
momentum you know some of that is my
fault some of that is just we ran out of
steam we were planning on doing it again
alvaro myself Ignace presented to some
of the russian-speaking logs etc so
we're planning on doing it again the big
issue is
we need to actually listen to people
like operators or other communities when
they come along and speak and they're
sometimes were intimidated by our style
as well I think in this context that I'm
speaking of its IT yeah I want to just
say say two things real quickly one one
is that as long as I've been coming to
the IETF we've been talking about trying
to figure out how to get input from
operators and that's a that's a that's a
good and beautiful thing for us to be
thinking about you mentioning the
enterprise network guys that's something
that we have really not spent a huge
amount of time on because I don't know
how the heck you find them and we were
talking in the IB stack evolution
program meeting this morning about that
so again this is not you know thank you
for saying it out loud
it is something that some people here
are aware of and thinking about and we
welcome help the next time somebody
tells you that people at the ITF are
arrogant
tell them that elastic planaria you were
at one of the members of leadership was
wearing a t-shirt that said I smile
because I have no idea what's going on
so just just two quick things based on a
couple things you said you know one is
please don't wait until the next meeting
like we do we can do the work on the
mailing list and that actually helps a
lot I think to kind of prepare in
advance before you you know try to get
people up on the front of a stage so the
the work in the background I think is
extremely important but the other thing
is that and maybe this is like a little
bit of a contrast from what some people
have said here the the ITF is a two-way
street right what the it's an extremely
open organization
I cannot prevent anybody else from
coming and criticizing your thing if
you're going to bring it here
and pardon there's an education piece to
that that's different from you going off
into a consortium with two of your
friends and and building a protocol that
suits the three of you that's not what
we do here and so I think if to the
extent that people are used to operating
in that kind of environment it does take
a while to realize that it's not the
same here but you know it's it's
extremely difficult to prevent people
from from being critical of other
people's work in the ITF right like
that's just that's a different issue but
yeah all right Adrian oh I just I mean
we can do things on tone setting you
know I know as an area director I pull
people aside and and you know helped to
try to correct any tone problems but if
something is getting you know personal
as opposed to technology focus which is
I think what alyssa was hitting on not
not these other pieces then you know we
and working group chairs need to be
addressing that and keep the tone
appropriate Adrian I have a new topic
I'm willing to yield if people at the
mics are continuing this topic in the
back I'm Paul Barrett from Netscape just
on the Onaga point I just wanted to say
I'm one of the oh no vendor co-chairs
for the monitoring and analytics group
I'm here all week as they say so if
anybody wants to track me down and talk
about what we're doing an owner around
monitoring analytics we're particularly
looking at the challenges of cloud and
multi-cloud very happy to sit down with
you by the way I'm also also a network
enterprise guy so you know happy to talk
about that as well thank you thank you
Andrew are you following up on this
topic
sorry I do have a suggestion as to how
to find the enterprise people as we've
just seen there are some here but many
of us work for large enterprises
our workplaces support contacts in our
own vendors are the people who know who
the enterprise-d working people are
similarly when those of us who actually
work for vendors like I no longer do our
top support people who you talk to to
find the people you want to talk to
they're follow the people thank you
Thank You Adrian Adrian Farrell yeah I'm
aware that I'm between me and my own
dinner thank you guys for your service
you have an i ESG statement on I think
it's called on support documents and
these are the information or documents
that part of them get produced for
requirements or use cases or frameworks
and that that statement wisely suggests
that working groups consider other forms
of publication including wikis are you
aware that when you make comments
discusses or abstains ons that type of
document that has come through working
group consensus often as a working group
charter item has come through IETF
consensus when when you put in comments
that basically say I think that this
document is entirely pointless and has
no value you are best being a little bit
insulting towards the community that has
brought the document forward maybe you
might like to consider revising your own
history statement to more precisely say
what it is you actually think about this
type of work or revising charters to
take those items out or backing off the
language that you use in your
ballot positions you wanna stir I agree
with you on the fact that one of her
document arrived at the iesg it's my
personal view it's too late to say that
your work is pointless which was one of
the reason why we did that statement in
the in the view of new charter creation
so telling people up front if you're
doing new work maybe you want to think
carefully if you want to spend six
months doing program statement
requirements architecture in sequence
now whenever they come to the is G I
believe it's just too late and impolite
to just say I think your work is
irrelevant so I at least from my own
ballots but also I can't remember any of
the other members on the ihd they
actually said it's pointless I think
most often it's like we don't see
they're capable value of it which means
we as the maintainer of the stream
figure out you know what do we want to
maintain industry we very well see this
these documents have served a purpose
within the working group to find
consensus in the working group to be
clear about what people are talking
about in the working group but does they
have value for somebody outside of the
working group that's a question you
should be raised so yeah I fully get
where you're coming from I think I
should say sometimes we don't word
things quite as well as we could you
know if I have done that I apologize
sometimes we get busy and rushed and
there are lots of documents and you know
we could do a better job of wording
things so the IMG is split on our views
on these documents I personally see the
value and the archival value in these
documents in some cases working groups
that I work with are interested in their
larger community because they have a few
people here and a much larger community
who consumed these and they expect to
read those documents so I think this is
something that will shift over time
depending on the membership of the iesg
in terms of the view and I've seen that
over my three and a half years so I
certainly agree that at ballot time is a
time to show appreciation for what the
author's the work the authors have put
in and the working group has put in and
not to disregard that work I think that
part of the reason many of the charters
leave those types of documents up to the
working group is because sometimes they
can be extremely valuable to the wider
community in explaining how our
technology is intended to be used and
setting up the framework that we do a
very poor job of saying this is how you
can connect these different pieces of
systems together the applicability of
particular protocols and so sometimes
they are incredibly valuable and sadly
sometimes they're a document that's been
sitting there for five years and has
some outdated stuff and it's being
rushed through so giving the working
group a choice on how to handle it and
so on and then respecting what the
working group in the community the IHF
community has thought about the
documents is why is important and I
think that's why the statement is
balanced I certainly would be sad to see
that balance shifted and I actually
don't recall either the way actually was
so strong on what we what we commented
but I see that message that we put out
it wasn't about informational and
documents it was that informational
documents are often delay that any
solution works being done right the day
that when people just spin and spend and
spend these requirements and use cases
and there's no solution work you can
wonder then the interest to do solution
work
and also just put a huge delay that we
do have solutions so that that was the
message that we were trying to get
across that let's not delay solution
work to be doing hundred page use cases
or requirements and the only time
actually I recall that we commented on
something negatively on this was that
that document came through after already
solution work had been published and the
use cases that were being there our
requirements was outdated even towards
what the solutions that already had been
published as or RFC's so that the main
messages don't be hung up for years
trying to do use cases and requirements
I think there there may be have been
some other instances yep yes where there
was not solution work published first
and and the group felt strongly on it
and it hit the working groups real hard
so I I supported what the working groups
had done yeah so just to build on those
last three things that were said I think
the IHG statement reflect we reflect the
consensus of the IHG but I think taking
it further there's a diversity of
opinions on the IHG which is why you get
some ballots that that come down harder
and some ballots that are you know more
open to those kinds of documents and
that's why we haven't we haven't revised
the statement because when we what we
have captured the consensus and we
couldn't really take it any further
yeah I guess there's one kind of sake
you know sometimes you've read a couple
of hundred pages of documents and when
you're balloting it's fairly easy to
sort of forget that there's been a huge
chunk of work put into this and when you
write your comment you know you're doing
it in a Russian sometimes we worried
things list diplomatic ly then we could
[Music]
all right
hi I'm Steve vinter I do sniffer
analysis in a large enterprise network
and part of our analysis of application
and network problems is looking at all
the fields of the TCP header we look at
sequence numbers ACK numbers option
fields windows sizes we typically move
sniffers around to different locations
and see what the transport header looks
like at different locations we need to
see what those headers look like when
packets come in at the Internet so we
can know if it's our problem or the
carrier's problem and we can't do this
kind of analysis on a load balancer that
might terminate a protocol with an
encrypted header because load balancers
don't have the robustness to run a full
packet capture so I can't picture doing
this kind of work with a layer 4 header
that's encrypted it seems like we would
just have problems that we can't solve
ok we'll take that and seek comment I
guess I mean obviously this is part of
the larger conversation that we were
having earlier that David black raised
yes sorry I'm vertically challenged I
would agree with two comments that were
made you know being relatively new to
IETF three of them so far but I've been
in standards work for a very long time I
am and can you give us your name
Bret Jordan thank you for a long time I
am an enterprise you know large scale
network engineer very large scale and so
I do feel the pain that people have when
they come and they bring up ideas or
they bring up concerns and they're shot
down I have pretty thick skin so I'm
willing to fight but I know a lot of
people aren't and so there is a
consensus view that the IETF doesn't
care about what the enterprise needs or
the telco space needs and that's
something we need to fix so you need to
listen and we need to not be shot down
and you asked us to come and give us our
use cases and the things that we have
problems with you need to pay attention
you know we're not you know we spend a
thousands of dollars to come here
to say you know what these things are
gonna break now quick I'm really excited
about but I'm also completely terrified
with for the points that were just made
you're basically going to say that the
end point user the end user or the
application support person are the only
two people that can help you and we know
that the application developers don't
have a clue how the network works so
you're basically saying that all of the
network engineers that are called on on
a regular basis to say hey this
application is running slow this
application is sluggish it's broken
something's wrong help and so we need to
make sure that you know when I come or
when other people come that our
enterprise you know managers and and
have lots of experience doing this you
know I'm not just here to complain I'm
here to make this better
so thanks thanks for all you do thank
you for coming so I I wanted to say
thank you very much for coming in for
your comment and I think one thing
that's been sort of a disconnect here is
the scale of change that happened when
we decided to recommend that the that
the network be by default encrypted
because as you know for a long time they
were always encrypted flows on the
network and we've been recommending for
a generation that encryption be
available what changed really was we
recommended that it be to default and
the best parallel I think I've heard
this week with somebody saying it's like
having a wireline Network and somebody
turning on 802 11 suddenly the stuff is
going through the air you can't see it
at all anything you put on your network
to see what's happening can't be
measured and can't be seen and with AC
who was here before as our example
you realize we really do care about that
but what we haven't gotten across to you
or to other enterprises is that this
changes is real but the the shift from
default unencrypted to default encrypted
is the same kind of see change we had in
our networks when we went from wireline
networks to a mix up wireline
more wireless networks and that we're
gonna have to do the same things as an
industry that we did then which has
developed new techniques for looking at
how things traverse the network in these
new ways and if there's some way in
which that seems like we haven't been
listening to you I truly apologize but
if there's some other way that we can
try and indicate the scale of change
we're trying to foster here I'd love to
talk to you and find out how better to
express that and and as a responsible ad
for Kathleen and Elle's
mm WG or mm what effect encrypt document
how could you use this as a sales pitch
keys read the document it really
discusses sort of the things that are
going to change in a world of pervasive
encryption and things that operators
should be aware of it doesn't say that
we shouldn't be doing encryption it just
tries to make people aware you know both
on the operator and protocol design
aside so that we can make sure that you
know encryption will actually be
deployed and it won't be blocked which
might otherwise happen I have no issue
with encryption and privacy I I'm a big
proponent of that my concern is when
your application breaks and you can no
longer talk to your you know SPSS you
know or Oracle server and you can't do
your expense report and you need to call
the network team to say hey can you
troubleshoot this and figure out why
we're gonna say sorry can't help you
finally agreement and I just wanted to
say I used to I used to do the network
monitoring thing looking at clear text
payloads for a living for at least a
couple of years so I know what that
looks like I know what that you know I
know what that looks like I understand
so I guess the other piece I would say
is we are listening and one of the
things that as ATS we do is help with
the conversations and the introductions
and adding sometimes that little bit of
no really this person is here and you
need to pay attention to the kind of
problems that they're talking about and
the use cases and I'm very happy to see
large enterprise and enterprise
operators coming and trying to
participate it's really necessary and we
do I mean in writing we tend to focus a
lot on the large service providers
because they're the ones who have been
here and I really just delighted to see
you both and thank you for coming no any
elegans you know I wanted to we have
things to work out in TLS I mean of
course yes
and and I really appreciate a lot of the
support people are giving us but I
wanted to you know kind of tell you - is
that two different working groups v6 ops
and the whole routing area I have
reached out to us and made us feel
completely welcomed opened up a forum
for us and you know meet with us like v6
ops they that you know they meet with us
every two weeks to figure out what we're
doing and to go forth and help us so I
really and there's so many people in the
community that have you know really
tried to help so I wanted to say that -
it's a two-way street and it's it's not
easy you know it's not easy to do the
translation but but I didn't want this
to be like a one-way thing that there's
no question that there's been a lot of
very unfortunate misunderstandings of
everybody's statements and motivations
in some working groups and I'm really
sorry that that's happening and we're
really trying to fix that so thank you
thank you guys for everybody helping so
Malini I did try to help on the TLS
front and I hope that there's some
progress I wrote a blog but between the
last meeting in this meeting and I think
it got pretty wide coverage and got
picked up by a couple of other ripe and
aap Nick republished it but the purpose
was to run through your use case and
make it cluster crystal clear as to what
that use case is so a broader community
could see it and I basically threw
spaghetti on the wall with a solution
expecting other people to read it and
hopefully come with with brainstorming
ideas on that specific use case so you
know so there was outreach and there's a
side meeting that's happening with
somewhat related you know I don't know
what's gonna happen out of this but you
know as an area director I did try to
bring attention to to that use case yeah
yeah yeah I know totally Kathleen I know
I really appreciate yeah yeah I know you
guys have really tried it's I think part
of it too
I mean I you know I'm I'm we we have
work to do to on our side is I think
that one of the things we've been trying
to really make clear is our environment
our use cases and and try to do a
translation mechanism and I really
appreciate the effort you've done I am
gonna say though that I mean we I don't
need to tell you guys you know I I hate
to see things you know so I hate to see
so there's just a lot of
misunderstandings and I feel bad for
everybody on both sides and I and so
that's that's all I have to say
thanks Steve yeah to me the encryption
issue is like protecting financial data
we all want our financial data protected
and yet when we go to the loan officer
to apply for a mortgage we give them all
our financial data because they can't do
their job without it and I think the
encryption question is the same kind of
thing there are people like me that have
to see the layer four headers that have
to see the packet payload in order to do
our job of fixing problems and if we
don't get that visibility we're not
going to be able to do our job there are
problems that will not be solved by
logging there are problems that will not
be solved by endpoint analysis only or
they're gonna take an unacceptably long
time to solve if that's the only
visibility we have I don't think this is
blowing you up yet yet because these
protocols are not in all the enterprise
data centers yet we have already seen
perfect forward secrecy in our data
center and we've had problems that we
couldn't solve in a timely manner this
is do you know could help with some
experience I had doing this crypto I
with the security guys helped me quite a
bit or helped Brian and I quite a bit to
do this and it was great but it was kind
of funny there was this economy they
said oh you don't need to do encryption
over tunnels because the end systems are
going to do it to end and we're gonna
have this wonderful world and then other
people said oh no we need to look at the
packet so there it needs to be clear
text at some point along the way right
so you should you should do it right so
some people said well make the tunnel go
all the way at the endpoints and you
have your end ended security and then
when you need the visibility you bring
the tunnels like this and you have clear
texts on this side so you could just
move this thing and have this sort of
flexibility and I mean people
it sounds pretty flexible then people
say no or it's pretty weak on the links
well he needs the weakness where he
needs it and he needs the strength where
he needs it so so I mean this being ITF
100 I think it's it's probably
interesting to think for a second if you
go all the way back in the history like
what did people think that they needed
and not an order that they didn't need
right
and how much has that probably changed
over time I think that's one of the
interesting things about when you come
to the IETF is that how much that
perception can change and I think
there's probably going to be some of
that that is going to happen on on all
sides here right like but the things
that you believe and then that you feel
so strongly that absolutely it cannot be
any other way it turns out like if you
went back 10 years and you look at what
those things are like none of them are
true anymore right
so I hope that the the kind of spirit of
collaboration that word I think the ihd
is trying to foster around this topic
you know leads to some of those kind of
paradigm shifting thoughts for everybody
thanks good discussion
[Applause]