okay well during the five minutes when
we're waiting for the connector past the
blue sheets and maybe I can ask you to
come forward more because this room is
very hard to hear in and I want to make
sure that although we will try to be
really close to the mics that you can
actually hear us and see our slides so
feel free to come further down we do
have a riveting program so I know you're
not going to want to escape out the back
door the forces of research have Victo
are victorious today it's actually hard
to have the mic close enough the way all
the other things are cluttered on here
but I will try so if you can't hear me
signal quickly because I I might not
actually be able to keep the discipline
to use the mic as close as it needs to
be this the sound here is difficult okay
so welcome to the IETF 99s IRT F open
we were told last night this is really
IETF 99 and that we lost track of one or
we went one ahead so there's a showing
of the note well that's been adapted for
the IRT F because we actually do follow
by consensus we follow the IETF s-- IPR
policies
unless you've seen in all the other
meeting so so it's not theirs
nothing surprising here in addition I
wanted to add since we have the ability
to add to process more readily than the
ITF does that we follow the
anti-harassment policies and this is
just a pointer to them since there
wasn't actually a mention of that last
night in the plenary either that we have
them and that there's an Ombuds
I actually happen to also be one of the
Ombuds team so as you have a concern
about something in our Gees there's two
other people on that team so you can
certainly consult Linda Klee forth or
Pete if you need if you have a concern
and we're we're especially interested in
just having everybody have a voice and
speak up it turns out we have one so
thank you so much I apologize for your
run somebody kindly ran ran for another
connector okay
and next is that there is going to be a
good bit of photography during the set
this session because of the prizes and
if you have a concern to not be
photographed we have a policy that you
can inform the photographer please don't
include me in a photograph so that's one
of the things that I wanted to also
mention here okay so that's all the
policy and I'm going to give a little
bit more extended update because with
the long plat panel and so on I
volunteered not to give an update during
the plenary last night in case you're
wondering it's not that we don't exist
or that we were dissolute it's that we
actually tried to give some time back
and there we can have a little open mic
session if you have some questions about
the IRT F as well before we start the
prizes and then at the end one of the
discussion topics that the current idea
is the idea of having some sort of
lightning talk session that would be
like the kinds of lightning talks or or
these some numbers of other names that
that take place at research meetings and
it would be actually IETF
and I RTF lightning talks mixed up
together possibly in an evening if we
don't get bits and bytes back so be
thinking about that you can always
comment on that in the ITF discuss list
but we are interested in your opinion on
that topic I'll introduce the a and RP
speakers when we get to them but we have
very good speakers this is the last of
the 2017 awardees this time okay so in
overview as you as you know because
you're here
the IRT every focuses on the kinds of
tasks that are not standards engineering
basically but that seem important to the
IETF and to the Internet community to be
tackled by people we tend to work on
Applied Research we wouldn't we're not
so likely to have a theoretical program
here although I suppose we could
we're organized into para a parallel to
the working groups called research
groups as you know and there is an
internet research steering group which
is all of the research group chairs and
some at-large members and I'll introduce
them but that's the basic picture of the
IRT F and it's been around as long as
the IETF has been around with different
organizational relationships our current
relationship is a close tie to the IAB
actually so I thought people might be
curious about some of the differences
because many of you go to our G's but
may not have really thought about the
way in our G is organized differently
the most important thing is that where
we have freedom to be very creative and
how the work is done so the goal is to
have extremely impactful work
potentially work that will eventually
solve a hard problem that we'd like a
standard for or solve a hard problem
that standards folks need help with but
there's no requirement to have a strict
process so we can the groups can meet
they happen to meet at ITF quite a lot
but they can have meetings co-located
with other other organizations they can
have the lengths of meetings they need
we have had in the past had closed
research groups we have none now I would
have to think really hard before we
would charter a closed research group
but soon and since all the research
groups are open the one caveat about
meeting anywhere wherever is that there
help to the same process as the ITF of
announcing where those meetings will be
with enough time for people to
participate if they want to similarly
the output of of working groups is RFC's
but the group where the working groups
does not a research group does not have
to be RFC's it could just be code it
could be a hackathon it could be a
series of publications in a journal it
could be an agenda that's used for for
another body you know for a scholarly
body it could be a project of other
sorts and all of that is cool so if you
come to a research group meeting and
they look like they're doing kind of
IETF process they don't have to be and
feel free to suggest if you have a good
idea for how to pursue their mission
well some other methods where we're very
cool with experimenting being creative
we want to get a great mix of people and
a great mix of activity and we don't
need to be bound by publishing RFC's um
and then definitively research groups do
not produce standards track documents so
that is one of the agreements that we
have that we are parallel body that does
not produce standards some groups aim to
to do their work well enough to solve
some hard problems and then transition
to creating a working group
most recently disruption tolerant
networking has done that and this is
this is certainly one of the modes that
we like but we would not be publishing
standards track through the publishing
informational experimental or open
source or whatever up to the time that
there's a transition to IETF and then
the other thing is that some groups do
perform roles there are of service to
the standards track so that one of the
key examples of that is that the cipher
G produces those crypto reviews
that are sometimes extremely important
and normatively required for documents
in the ITF and that is done with with
very close ad sponsorship so that is
another model and if anyone has a
question as we're going along I'm also
happy to answer questions okay so it
would be nice for people to get as a to
get very involved we're very open we
have a discussed list that's quiet and
an announced list the analysis is very
quiet you can subscribe to it and just
get information about new groups and
reviews of new charters and and the
prizes the research mailing lists and
all the wiki links can be found on IRT F
dot org and we are restructuring that
page you'll see some changes my email
officially I RTF chair IR s G is
available I didn't get enough time to
put in the picture where the cats are
not just looking at the TV they're
actually typing because that's actually
what we're looking for but you can start
out by reading the way they are
those are my cats they're they're
at-large members of the IRS G in a
spirit yeah oh so many out this was
where the picture of the Taiping cats
will be later so how do you how do
research groups originate you may wonder
about that too and some of them have
been around a long time so their origins
are lost in time perhaps I'm going to
start requiring research group chairs to
know who all where the chair is going
back to the beginning because we some
groups have really different feelings
and structures now but but it would be
good for them to actually have a sense
of their past as well as their future um
but the main thing about research groups
is that they originate more more freely
than the ITF groups do we are very
interested in
making sure we don't block something new
that could be important that perhaps we
don't appreciate well not by we I mean
me and the IRS G but it also you so so
it turns out that you can propose a
group and with some tweaking to make
sure that it has a sensible charter and
that the that it has a mission and it
has some you know vision of what it
should be doing it can run for three
meetings in a status of proposed
research group before being considered
for for a more long-term gig and we have
two of those right now so the and the
way that we do the evaluation is they
get to three meetings and then the chair
has a kind of review with the with with
the chairs of those groups to talk about
how things have gone but also we will
start to have some more some more
requests for a review by the community
and by the IRS J there so here's the
celebri of research groups and I'm happy
to tell you that last meeting everybody
met this meeting everybody but the
decentralized internet group met and
they met informally so I they're
actually not yet counting as having had
one of their meetings but we won't we
don't do that for too long and you can
see what they are they have a wide range
of topics I'm actually quite interested
in soliciting a privacy research group
and if you have an interest in that you
should talk to me
we still have human several of these
groups still have to meet ahead of us
and I don't have the schedule right in
my head but if any of the chairs would
like to pitch their working group at the
mic for the rest of the meeting I beat
you could you certainly can do that h h
RPC every would you like to come up and
say word their meeting Friday morning
who else is still to me they apologize
for not memorizing okay so pan RG maybe
you'd like to mention pan proposed
research group maybe you'd like to
mention your your plans as well
is that one more still to me um okay
this is totally embarrassing but at the
HR PC I'll be giving an analysis of
treatment of law policy and politics in
the history of the RFC's with a special
emphasis on the first decade when there
was a great deal of discussion about
these issues and that and you want to
say your name does Sandra Bremen yes so
that should be a really great session an
hour you want to say a little more about
HIPC I'm Avril Dori I'm one of the
co-chairs of the group that Sandra's
going to speak at so she already said
the good stuff but you know another
thing though about the group is we just
got one RFC out and it's going to be
time to sort of look at okay we've got
some other things that are in the works
but how do we continue so it's a great
time to get involved in terms of how we
continue okay good good Matt yeah Matt
Ford just had a question about the
dinner gee I was kind of looking forward
to going to their meeting on Monday
morning it seems like it's been quite an
active group while it's been meeting
informally before can you say anything
about why that that meeting was canceled
because I I think I heard something
about the presenters were remote but
that doesn't seem like a strong reason
to cancel a meeting so Melinda do you
want to say something about that we have
one of the chairs here Linda co-chair
with Kuchar yeah we actually did did
have a problem with attendance by people
who were doing active work we're still
serving in start-up mode and we just
were having problems getting enough
active participation so I so so yeah we
are going to be we're talking about
doing an interim in conjunction with nd
SS and of course we'll be meeting in
London but we thought it was a better
idea to not meet rather than have a bad
meeting okay and um we have had very
good meetings of the group so far and I
will put out a report with my
observations about the groups on the
discuss list that's something that I
need to gather by their cadence for
Brian will say something about the pan
that proposed research group as well
path aware networking we're gonna have
our second meeting of the path or
networking repro post research group
right after lunch actually I think we
might be in here I'm not sure so the 30
second elevator pitch is we're looking
at it's it's kind of a it's kind of a
fuzzy sort of architecture sort of thing
it's like what what could we do in a
world in which the end points have a
more active participation in this
election that has that their traffic
takes and this came out of an
observation about a lot of sort of
disconnected work that's happening in
this space in the IETF sort of things
like IP views excitement routing things
like peas multipath transport protocols
work on these how do all of these fit
together and what can we do with this
stuff so we're trying to figure out
we're drawing a box around what it is we
want to do and we're still trying to
figure out about interest in the room in
this community is this correct is
entirety of research group is there are
there other things that we should be
doing in this space we're doing a
partial review of sort of the whole
story early in the group because we had
an unfortunate conflict with the ideas
both in Prague or first-time Syrians
like okay for those of you who didn't
come to the first meeting here's what
we're trying to do and a few
presentations we're sort of diving deep
on what we see is research into
mechanisms for realizing paths awareness
in the internet so some of these are
things that people know about work
that's been done in the IETF already
such as Alto so getting path properties
down to down to endpoints and some of
this is sort of blue sky stuff so please
come by that'll be the other first
afternoon slot Thanks
thank you yes do go by to attend so I
want to also say something since we have
a good number of research groups I do
participate in these scheduling rounds
for the meeting it's difficult to
completely deconflict
anything at the ITF these days and we
want to work on that one
thing that I hope to do is move this
slot into a lunchtime so that we can
make sure that since we always have some
a lot of interest in the in the prize
when their presentations we actually
have some ability to not conflict with
people for that and in general I think
we're just at the same mercy of of time
like everybody else but the the groups
cover you know span from there I don't
wanna call other things out too much but
but there's lots going on we also have
recently talked about having documents
which are in two different groups
because network coding and IC and RG
have interesting interaction between
between their work where they can
support each other so we may have
parallel work going on that is is really
co-sponsored by two groups and we don't
need to have it owned by one group we
actually have the freedom to do that as
well so if you have any questions about
other things I'm happy to entertain them
okay you could see the membership so the
chairs are our members of the IRS G if
you go if you write to the IRS G mailing
list you'll get all these people and
then we have some at-large members as
well who especially helped to tie us
back to for example the transport area
Spencer is one of our at large because
transport and an IRC have a lot of
relationship okay so people we're going
to have the 2a and our P meetings and I
thought I'd make sure that we know as a
group presentations what those are
essentially it's a best paper prize for
all possible published papers and
applied networking and I like to say
security too because we have an interest
in security applied security topics and
you'll see we have had a number lots so
they are four previously published
papers we're not very strict about the
deadline but it should be the last
couple of years and somebody numb or
either nominates their own paper and
themselves or a paper and the
speaker and the speaker is specifically
nominated in order to come and give a
presentation we select six awardees for
the year at the beginning before the
year but we announced them two at a time
and the prize winners receive some money
which has gone up for next year and also
a trip to speak here and we actually
have the resources to offer if they
request it to come back for a follow-up
if they've made lots of good ties and
would like to follow up and spend more
time at the ITF and I RTF and the origin
story is that Loras had the stroke of
genius and created this and it's a very
good way for us to connect I believe
that's right era and it was Lars and it
is um it's a very good way for us to
connect between the larger research
community and the IR TF and bring people
that are not always here to the to talk
with us the Internet Society funds it
primarily but there are some sponsors as
well and you might be a sponsor if you
think you could it's not a large amount
but we certainly would love that you can
talk to AIESEC about that um and thank
you to Comcast for being a current
sponsor as well as thank you to Isaac
the process starts with a yearly call
for papers I hope you all saw it
because I tried we tried to get it
everywhere and if we didn't we need to
do better and it completed on November
5th we actually got our largest number
ever almost 60 submissions and very good
ones to boot which in my estimation I'm
not the only reviewer obviously we have
a peer reviewing committee that is from
academics and from industry and you can
check on the link there if you want to
see more about the call for papers the
original call who's on the program
committee things like that and then
before the end of the year we will be
actually before the middle of December
we will be selecting all six and then
start to announce the ones for 2018 so
that is how that actually happens that's
where they come from
that's where Roland and Paul came from
from last year's group
so there's also the confusion because we
have to A&R things and people sometimes
say well did you mean the W or the P
what is the difference between those so
it seemed reasonable to deconflict that
for you today they both have an annual
call a and RP calls for nominees a and
our W calls for papers and our W gives a
prize for an already published paper I
sorry piece yeah I'm doing it myself
wrong and ANR W gathers new papers new
submissions air workshop submissions the
prize there's two presentations at each
ITF the workshop does presentations at a
workshop co-located with the summer ITF
we've chosen the program chairs for the
a and RW there's a steering committee
for that including Lars and and Colin
Perkins and myself and Sharon Goldberg
who many of you know and they've Chavez
who you may not know are the the
co-chairs of the PC and there will be
more information soon about the rest of
that okay so hopefully you're no longer
confused and you might want to follow us
at at in Retta fo which is our twitter
handle and we also have a facebook page
and you will notice that roland is in
this picture because he has been an
awardee before but it was a great sort
of triumphant picture to attract
people's attention and I tribute to this
picture the large increase in the
submissions so thank you to the people
in that picture and thank you too Olaf
for taking such a good picture okay so
if there are any other questions we're
in a quick open mic for IRT ephra or RG
questions hi Aaron Falk so some of you
may recognize me as the host of the
Pecha Kucha which is actually tonight
and I but I'm here because there's an
idea under discussion to take the the
lightning talk idea that has
Pecha Kucha has been kind of a fun thing
and trying to actually make it available
for people to present new ideas so more
of a serious lightening talk session so
I'm sort of at the center of a small
group that's doing some brainstorming on
this so just to be clear we're talking
about doing a lightning talk session at
the IETF sometime during the week that's
not going to conflict with working
groups or research groups and if you
have ideas as or opinions as to whether
you think that's a good idea or not or
if it's something that you've got some
ideas on people who might be interested
in participating part of the goal of
this is to do things like advertise barb
offs advertise interesting research
that's going on but you know this is
sort of like a zero to two slide slot so
it's intended to be very fast the kind
of thing that they're doing in dispatch
but to a broader more general audience
so I would love to see researchers come
and throw up a couple of slides on stuff
that they think that they're doing and
so I think this is kind of a natural fit
to the a and our PA and our W discussion
and hopefully some stuff that will come
out of this will lead to new research
groups
thank you yeah and so um Aaron and
Aliyah are two of the key players there
and the IR s G will take an interest in
this as well so so definitely we're
going we're supporting this idea we
think it's a good one okay so I'm going
to introduce our first an RP Prize
winner although not I'll introduce you
briefly because you introduce yourself
and your slides as well but Paul
Emmerich is from the Technische
universität münchen in Germany and
he's going to present moongeun which is
a really interesting high speed packet
generator and I will hand you the dongle
now let's see you need just the this one
and you'll have to stand in the pink box
[Music]
okay great
let's please welcome pop okay yeah thank
you for the introduction and yeah I'm
here to talk about my package generic
emulsion
and I will just start this rough
introduction Who I am where I come from
and then I will go over a few aspects of
Mugen I won't bore you with any details
about the implementation or performance
evaluation or how we built it I will
instead just show a few key points and
show an example about how you can use it
because in the end this was about
applied networking research which often
somehow includes a packet generator and
what I really want to show how to use it
and how it's different from what you
might be used to when you are used to
different package innovators beat'em
hardware or software so me I'm a PhD
student at Technical University of
Munich and it's at the German name on
the side before because when we wrote
that paper we had the company policy
that university-wide policy that we were
not allowed to translate the name to
English which leads to these awkward
moments people trying to translate it to
just pronounce that name and we luckily
changed that I think two years ago and
since then I'm allowed to say Technical
University of Munich which is so much
easier to pronounce for others and while
I've been there since 2014 and my start
as a PhD student and I'm hopefully
finishing soon ish I have to like write
a thesis and so on and this yeah I plan
to finish next year sometime I said that
last year as well but yeah and my thesis
will be about testing different network
devices where our network devices can
refer to a typical classical
two black box you send in packets out
that does something you get packets back
but doesn't divide seeing how fast it is
this is kind of boring compared to a
complex software system that can
investigate a lot of different effects
in depth and where the performance is
not always clear where the bottlenecks
are and so on and to do this i well I
kind of started this work on moongeun or
the idea when I did my master's thesis
where I had a deeper look at performance
of open V switch and virtual switches
and cloud environments and I just
realized there wasn't a really good
software package generator that you
could just use and that did all the
things I wanted to and in the end I
always ended up modifying some code of
some software package generator to get
it to do the things I wanted to was kind
of annoying and so I've addressed this
idea of building a Pecha generator to
start to really get even to really be
able to do what I wanted to do I had to
build this first and now it seems to
have consumed almost everything about
the teasers and it's mostly about the
package generator now so where do I work
at what was the context that this work
is being done in this is the networking
group at the thematics faculty Technical
University of Munich we are a relatively
large group of about 20 people plus some
external guys and we do a broad range of
network research topics that ranges from
everything from your usual traffic
measurement and analysis where we look
at look at traffic you look at we have a
mirror port our internet uplink where we
look for animalist here we do internet
byte scans we do everything we have our
own autonomous system for just for
research stuff and for doing internet
scans then we do of course all your
hotbar things from software-defined
networking and yeah Internet of Things
and the usual we do a lot of security
and privacy research as well and
peer-to-peer networks and of course the
performance analysis and modeling part
where I'm at this is this is really the
subgroup that
working in and what are we doing there
it's well the the main research question
or the main question that we have is
that packet processing becomes more and
more complex networks become more and
more complex it's no longer just a few
simple boxes that switch all out your
packets there are more software
components India there's the important
passwords from software-defined network
to network function virtualization and
even even when this is done in hardware
it often a software component to it and
it's often even done in software
nowadays instead of in hardware just
just last year we had a project in the
5g area where we worked was a big
company who were interested in in doing
some performance research of software
components in the 5g back and where a
lot of stuff is being virtualized their
virtualized network functions doesn't
need to be chained together it's quite
unclear how the how it impacts the
performance if you have different things
competing for the same resources if you
have different configurations that then
run in software that can compete for
hardware sources from bandwidth to cache
to memory to whatever and so the
research questions are from the
assembler thing what are the important
performance metrics sure performance
metrics you can just go to let's say of
C 2544 defines measure these things on
your box but it doesn't really work well
for a for a software device compared to
a hardware wise yeah it's 20 years old
and was designed for hardware devices
there of course new standard things and
the benchmarking methodology working
group is also meeting today that will be
an interesting session yeah then how do
you measure things in a realistic
scenario what is even a realistic
scenario do you just send some packets
what packets do you send it's
particularly interesting when you
benchmark stuff like firewalls where you
might want to simulate some complex
denial of service attack or anything it
can quickly get very very complicated
and another big topic that we are
working on is how do you make a
measurement reproducible if you if you
run this one thing once with your home
built package generator on
and you are testing your own homebrew
solution this really and how do you
ensure that someone else can reproduce
ourselves or even the you yourself can
reproduce your sites in one year because
you might not have that server that
hardware any longer or not that specific
software version which might not want
any longer because you upgraded a system
how do you keep that stuff manageable
and of course how can you predict
performances modules how do you can can
if you are planning a network and you
want to know how much harder how much
softer to buy what hardware to buy how
can you do that how can you kind of get
a model for the for the behavior for the
performance and kind of predict what you
need to buy what you need to plan
instead of just adjusting after the fact
so and this is what unblocking lists we
are lucky to have this big rack of test
service which has a lot of 10g port and
the some 43 ports at stripe diverse
hardware from low end power saving 4
core CPUs to big Numa nodes with 40
cores and so on from small portable
service that we can direct somewhere to
show off in a demo to these big boxes
and they also as the NHIN Sdn router and
one one key thing here that really makes
work work easier is that it's fully
automated test workflow that means if I
want to run a network experiment on and
benchmark something I really write a
script that defines everything that
starts starts from I want to use this
this and that server I want to configure
the switch that way or I know that they
are directly connected and then there's
a management note that allocates the
service exclusively for me so I'm sure
that only I'm using it and only my tests
is currently running on it and then the
test script completely boots the server
from scratch this means there's no fixed
installed operating system that might
break and Mike might challenge our
producer bility because you don't get
the same system again and that we do a
pixie boot of a network and just deploy
the notes as we need them and we can get
the same operating system again and
again
can just reproduce the exact same
software setup again and again and then
collect some data and aggregate the data
and already has some basic stuff puts
them in a Drupada notebook and so we can
start running analysis of the data on
top of that this is really nice
especially with the knife Buddha have a
big collection of operating systems and
kernel versions so if I want to run a
test how to see how the front kernel
versions evolved and then I want to
maybe afterwards I think oh this might
be another good metric then I can just
boot the whole thing again and run the
test and the whole thing again instead
of having to cope with downgrading an
operating system or anything so let's
get to the the main part of the talk
really is lost just a longer
introduction is this about packet
generators so this is a big packet
generator but you might have seen or
anything there are a few problems with
these big harder boxes first of all they
are big second they are quite expensive
and as I've heard some the nice guy from
into explains it like this so the
problem is them shipping around extra
boxes doesn't scale this is I think true
because often if you have multiple labs
and you don't have a package generator
for each of them then or you might want
some hardware features that are not
available and the end people often go
back to this fancy commodity hardware
here a few normal network cards they are
quite cheap comparatively they are
readily available you can just plug them
in your server and use them but then you
run into a lot of problems because of
course there's a reason why these big
Hardware generators are so expensive and
they are very reliable and precise at
what they do
whereas if you use a software package
generator it's typically it might be
slow it might be imprecise it might be
unreliable it might just give a
different society every time you run it
and this is the problem that I'm really
trying to solve here I'm trying to
combine the advantages of both software
and package on our software and hardware
packet generators that is software
typically cheap and flexible and
hardware typically very precise and
accurate and so the five main design
goals that I had
first of all it had to be fast obviously
so and this is building on top of the
DPD cave framework which was nowadays a
Linux Foundation project which was just
a set or a collection of drivers
optimized to Ibis current by past
drivers - for network cards and some
utility stuff for whatever you typically
need when building a network app and
then on top of this I built an nice API
to build packet generators and
everything I built about as was always
explicitly this multicart motive setting
in mind every we if you will show a few
examples of how our typical moonshine
script looks like it's always its core
it's always an explicit multi-threading
and explicit multi-core because that is
really the only way to scale to higher
speeds sure a single 10g link you can
fill that up those minimum size packets
meaning about 50 million packets per
second those are single CPU call it's
not too hard as long as you're not doing
too complicated things but as soon as
you go beyond that you need to be able
to run multiple multiple threads at the
same time luckily modern network cards
make this really easy because they offer
this multi queue interface and they are
natively doing doing a multi-layered
approach in hardware so the software on
top of it really fits quite nicely with
the hardware then I wanted to be
flexible because from my experience when
I used packet generators I always in the
end I always ended up modifying
modifying the code at some place and
doing doing something because I wanted
this view at protocol and then it didn't
support this real protocol or just just
one simple example I had this
requirement I wanted to generate
different flows only at layer 2 level
meaning I wanted to modify just the MAC
addresses and the package owner we were
using at the time didn't support it so
the source code and changed it and
patched it and so on and the change
denied it was okay
I had to modify the source code of for
package generators now so this doesn't
see all these configuration languages
they didn't seem to scale really so what
I did was I for Monday I give full
control of the main application to the
user meaning that if you use moon gender
idea is really that you write the code
for the main transmit loop yourself
meaning every single packet you sent out
goes through your code and gets executed
in real time for that packet and for
that we are using the scripting language
Lua which is has a very very nice
just-in-time compiler and that allows us
to really run custom script code for
each and every single packet because it
really come it really integrates very
well with lower other things and you can
get direct access to the packet memory
without pesky things like bound checks
or anything but just be careful when you
write your test then another another
thing that was traditionally very very
challenging for software package
generators is time stamping meaning that
you want to maybe do maybe people often
only evaluate their a few if you read
some academic papers about that great
new whatever out or whatever switch they
often only give you ok this is the
number and throughput that man uses this
million packets per second or even
though us disband versus typically the
software devices I was tricked by
packets per second and not by banthas
but you rarely see latency because it
was just so hard to measure as a
software package generator and
especially in academia people really
have these big expensive hardware boxes
so I really wanted to change that and of
course turns out time stamping doing it
precisely in software is a challenging
problem but if you read the data sheets
of your typical commodity mix carefully
you can find some tricks how you can
convince the heart that two times ten
packets basically the the the hardware
often has support for the PTP time
synchronization protocol which needs to
support hardware time stamping in order
to work properly and if you then craft
packets and trick the hardware a little
bit actually drive a little bit then you
can get the hardware to time stamp
almost arbitrarily packets and this gets
really nice result and really nice
insights into software or hardware boxes
that just weren't possible with software
time stamping another thing that is
quite quite the interesting thing and
was more more important than I initially
thought was doing rate control meaning
controlling the traffic
that assented that is to get between
packets like if you want to send one
million packets per second there I can
send a thousand packets sleep for some
time for like a millisecond sent another
thousand packets sleep for one more
millisecond and then you get at the
million packets per second but I can
also sleep between each packet for one
microsecond or I can do a fancy Poisson
process or any more complex pattern and
this turned out to be hugely important
than investigating software systems and
an aspect that's unfortunately often
ignored and then of course I wanted to
make it open source because what's the
point if only I'm using it I wanted to
make it really easy to use and freely
available you can check it out on github
and what I'm now going to show you is
just just only only a few well
measurements and and a few sites
basically and I don't want to bore you
with the details you can go to the paper
citations down there if you want the NGO
implemented details but I really want to
show some some well examples of how to
use it how the user is and why a few
things are important and this is the
static patterns this is really a point
that I really like because it was just
so much more important than I initially
thought and it's so often just ignore
what people just send a burst of packets
and say oh the average is fine let's
call it a day okay so this is kind of
kind of big confusing graph but it's
actually really easy this is a really
simple test set up what I did here was I
took two servers connected them as two
10g links and one mooned run on one of
them and different package generators
but that sort of on paper and open
research on the other one and just
forward packages open twist which no
fancy packet modification nothing no
fancy open V switch configuration just
sent take packets from one part and send
him out on the other using the normal
open V switch kernel module I think okay
there's a really boring test but if you
dig down into even such a simple
software software forward in case it
really shows you what kind of complexity
is hidden behind the seemingly simple
example so this graph shows the x-axis
is
overload meaning I'm increasing load in
this case was restricted to one flow the
forwarding device was restricted to one
CPU core because if you go motocross
Numa then this opens and you can so the
simplest possible thing and I configured
moongeun
to use different different sizes the
default I just generated constant bit
rate traffic meaning a constant gap
between the packets and this is the
baseline of this measurement meaning a
hundred percent and the measured thing
here is the latency relative to that
case so what you would expect if you run
your packet generators a few times on
the same case you would expect the
device under test to show the same
latency response because why would it be
different and especially you would
expect to get the the same latency
result if using different packet
generators if you don't change your
device and a test but what we did in the
past we had different package owner
doesn't get completely different results
for the latency of this the same device
and a test to be investigated estrada
and this graph is what i'm varying here
was the different graphs in that diagram
here is just the burst size meaning the
baseline one packet sleep for some time
one packet and so on and then four
packet sixteen packets are the two
packets and so on and see how the
latency relatively to the base case
changes and as you can see even with
something as a burst size of four or 16
you can quickly get a relative latency
that differs by a hundred percent or so
so you just get a completely different
asides just by changing how the packets
are spaced on the wire without even
going into anything from the content of
the packets just just changing the this
one thing and the the problem is why I'm
showing this is that people often send
bursts as the default case because it
turns out package after package
generators are only really fast in if
you have a naive implementation if you
send out bursts because all these
frameworks are always optimized to do
the last packet processing or batching
or vector or whatever you want to call
it all of it is optimized for this and
so the typical default burst sizes are
between 16 and 256 for software package
generators as you can see here this is a
really bad idea if you do latency or if
you want latency measurements
it doesn't matter so much for the
maximum achievable support that was
around 2 million packets for all these
configurations and now it's it was
really tricky to get different package
inheritance we have another paper on
this where we compared a lot of
different software package generators on
how reliable you can generate what we
configure them to do at first it turned
out to be very hard to even get them to
send didn't try to send CBR traffic some
claimed to send CBR traffic but then
have some optimizing oh sorry thank you
and can people hear well enough ok this
quiz will have sound from the other room
so yeah ok I just talked about Oh or
closer to the microphone so it was
really annoying you can get these
package owner like us to do what we
wanted then and even then there were
some optimization module sometimes in
there sometimes had a kernel component
and that then fetch them together well
to make it faster but it was not very
helpful and then they lied to you and
even even when we managed to configure
it it they still send out bursts because
it turns out it's only hard to send an
individual packet to a network cut it's
just not what they are designed to do
and in mundo and this is better but
there's not a detail I'm going to bore
you about a 12 page paper about it what
that one word you are just caught this
incredibly boring to get through but I
guess it's important so thank you for
that
ok why is this even different well one
reason is the CBR traffic is not a good
case so typically it's not a realistic
case the Internet traffic is not CBR
traffic but like people people passed
the CBR traffic because if you look at
for example the old RC 25:44 it calls
for a CBR traffic by default and people
just follow that 90 I mean the RC even
says you can test other traffic pattern
afterwards
but their default the CBR and people are
just like oh well let's just do CBR and
it's good enough and so this graph shows
the same measurement SD SD was had
before it's basically the baseline with
collecting the latency here for the CBR
case and it looks really weird at first
it's okay it seems to be increasing and
there's one we had spiked the Spikers
completely reproducible across different
systems different things and right
before overloads it drops completely
latency latency gets better
this is also completely reproducible
consider more measurement points in
there because when I first saw this I
was like well as can't be - I need to
measure maybe destroy study different
but it just reliably drops there I also
have a paper about that but it's also
another deep dive into the details of
how the Linux kernel and the driver
works basically there are two things
that are trying to well one is trying to
prevent the system from locking up and
from interrupted terms that's the Linux
poly mode Nappi which just switches to
some fancy poly mode and just poison at
work out and disable interrupts and then
guess the interrupting rate which is
typically found in all these drivers
that tries to save power and then you
and goes into power steering that's a
whole other can of worms to open so and
basically you're going to say here I was
having kind of okay kind of works also
hard to measure because by default the
UNIX can you find in most distributions
doesn't report the CPU time consumed per
interrupter can be at 100% CPU load but
edge drop reports you are at 10% because
it doesn't account enter up time
properly unless you sit there acute time
accounting selector compiling economy or
directly with the CPU performance
counters and this is completely
different piped off so now this kind of
looks weird and they're the reason why
it looks weird is really that the that
these algorithms that try to estimate
rate and so on they don't play well with
CBR traffic they kind of get confused
and there are a few state machines if
you get them unready it keeps switching
between two states all the time because
they get surgery confused by the CBR
traffic then I don't know exactly what
happens but you get these motor sites so
let's use APIs or process instead and
there
just looks much smoother and the site is
much more what you would expect and the
only thing I'm changing between these
two measurements is again their time
between packets in this case from CBR to
Prasad and much more reasonable result
and if you look at real world traffic
it's of course you all know that really
old sitcom paper about how you shouldn't
model your Internet traffic proposal
process but that's only really true for
larger timescales if you're running your
test of a few minutes or whatever then
you can use a Poisson process to
reasonably approximate what real traffic
looks like and then you get these nice
nice smooth suicides and more in more
realistic scenario which is also what
this is about
so what does the latency measurement of
look like if you want to if you know
installed Mundra and you want to drill
down into an - really one measurement
you get these nice histograms which are
just some way to represent how the
latency is distributed and typically for
many cases you want to see the F instead
but a histogram is well easier to see
visually so what you can see here these
are just measurements of a few systems
the first one is a software for water
running directly on the machine you can
clearly see there's some interrupt
sorting going on so you get this uniform
distribution kind of neat and the second
one there's a virtual machine and the
virtual switch and everything involved
then we get this long tail distribution
and I actually cut it off yet it's
actually long tail and there are some of
those cases there's also an interesting
thing to measure
they are just just if you work until
99.99% I love some latency measurement
and then you see some horrible results
there if you if you are benchmarking a
virtual machine or anything this can
also be a big problem and it's also
another thing where you can get probably
a whole PhD on how this happens why it
happens how to measure it and a hacker
box this is just something to show how
precise this really is because if you
note the x-axis it's and microseconds
and only goes up to 3.5 microseconds
typically saying the position of the
Mundra and hardware time stamping
approach it's typically plus minus and
plus minus subscribe nanoseconds that is
quite good for most things that
typically
typically agencies of the hardware box
its new range of a microsecond or maybe
500 nanoseconds to a few microseconds a
software box around ten microseconds if
it's good and a hundred efforts during
some parts having stuff and you can see
here is a nice bimodal distribution and
this is who's just an example where if
you want to break it down to one way or
your latency or anything it doesn't
really work because what's the average
of this what's the meaning of the
average of this is really nothing
so really meaning of the median of this
it has two clearly distinct paths in the
hardware in this case it was it was an
output part that was used by multiple
input parts and they are just two cases
either it goes to the cut through pass
if there's no packet being queued from
the other port or there's a packet being
Cureton so it gets queued for a short
time then goes to the other one also
have a full paper about that stuff and
then I want to show you how to use it
and there's just the only boring
architectures like basically Mundra and
sits on top of DP d k + TB DK is it's on
top of the network card and the network
card offers multiple queues and at the
top you have your users what we call a
user script that is your user controlled
you a script you write the whole script
and yes there's a lot of boilerplate and
the idea is kind of you copy/paste one
of the example scripts modified to suit
your needs
documentation might suck at some parts
but it's just your typical open source
project if you look at the example
scripts and if you look at your basic
assembly script that generates different
UDP flows and to report sir sites you
should quickly get an idea of how to
modify it for your needs or how to act
multiplayer things and the way we do
multi-threading is respond completely
independent virtual virtual machines
virtual machines in the sense of a
language implementation virtual machine
for the just-in-time compiler and that
is really they are really completely
independent and there are nice api's
that allow you to talk between these
these independent sets but their main
ideas are shared nothing approach
because in the end what you want to
generate as multiple flows and they are
often independent from each other or you
can break them down into a few
independent chunks
and that makes it really really high
performance and we have to look at the
examples to get an idea of what I mean
by this so and I don't know
so a quick except I don't know how much
time I've left there's no clock how much
time I got left continue for another ten
minutes okay great this seems perfect so
okay I'm gonna show this example and in
this case and this example is based on
our the excellent example this is also
something we wanted to test the exam and
then the package you know that is almost
VX and I don't know that's protocol and
well but for you and so there the first
thing that you can do is you can
dynamically general design a a complex
take of headers and really these are
just ahead us moon drain is still a
low-level package generator not a
traffic generator meaning there's no
protocol logic behind that you're just
sending out packets and the protocol
logic is like absolute minimum like we
implement up and NACP and whatever you
you expect for basic functionality and
there's like the hashing algorithm to
get the source port of the expand and so
on and to check some check some stuff
and check some of loading but it's not
the traffic generator can't build a tcp
stream from it you just can build
packets but it's meant to benchmark some
devices on there on the lowest level and
what you can do here is you can stack
together arbitrary had us and like in
this case it's me extra and running over
ipv4 and the VX plan there's a VLAN tag
is enough remembers another ipv4 header
and UDP oh by the way everything we have
is also a p v6 capable because the guy
who wrote the body the protocols tech
stuff he really likes ipv6 and so all
the examples also do ipv6 yeah and once
you have that thing it gets just-in-time
compiled and the next thing you do is
you create a memory pool with a packet
archetype meaning this is just some some
basic packet this is quite memory pool
this is just Maps if you know duplicate
then you will see how this maps to the
PDK stuff and then you fill each of your
packets with the archetype this means
you
- AVX dance Texas initially an empty
packet you tell it okay I wanted to be a
the exam tech packet and then you can
call this magic filler method which is
very slow but you only do this once and
this has nice nice setters basically for
all the headers you have in your stack
with the names that you defined before
and you can do stuff like lookup and MAC
address here and you can basically set
settings and then you can tell it to
calculate the checksums and the
scheduler checksum is again a magic
message that goes through the whole
stack and knows that okay there is this
checksum and to calculate that or adjust
either example just does it for one
thing but there's also another method
that does it for all the things in your
header because I think I'm using or
flirting here um okay
now this is basically the initialization
I defined my stack I defined what I
wanted to look like and then there are
some boilerplate code like commands and
argument handling and and whatever and
and then the next thing is you write the
actual transmit loop meaning you write
the the core of the of your transmit
loop of your package generate a test
script and this is this is so completely
different from other package generators
because in the end it's it's not really
a package generator pose it's a it's a
framework for writing package generators
and you write your own one based on one
of the examples and a lot of boilerplate
code so what you do here you allocate
some buffer array in this case it's
default back size and yes this example
sends out bursts unless we configure
that's right after I can't go into the
details about how the right control
works and then you at the actual main
loop that just checks is the process
they're learning meaning that someone
press control sees and sick term or did
another task stop it and we tell it okay
nice we want some packets on our memory
pool and we just get the packets with
the packet archetype that we previously
filled we iterate over these packets and
again cast them to the to detect that
post period compared this castle
operation is a completely free operation
there's no circus behind you it's just
the equivalent of a see cast and it
doesn't do anything besides
tell the compiler okay I want to use
these offsets for my packets and then I
can just access these packets
as you write offsets that gets compiled
down to a few assembly instructions and
I can do fancy things like in this case
I want to randomize my destination port
I can just call it mastered random or
whatever here whatever arbitrarily
complex processing you need for your
thing and you can of course access other
fields here and then you set some
offroading flex and you sent a queue to
tell you to send out the bots and this
is the whole main loop and this is also
runs typically on an independent thing
and you could start multiple threads
running this and if you look at the
examples that is really what they are
doing now let's say you don't want to
write a script because there's this
recent development that we are working
on is to really provide an actual packet
generator for our packet generator
meaning a set of predefined scripts that
have extensive command-line arguments
and a sense of config files because it
turns out not everyone likes likes
writing script but everyone likes
writing scripts in the newer a scripting
language there are I've talked to two
people from some companies they're like
basically oh but our at least engineers
they are not programmers they can just
click on the X jeogori and click the
start button we can't use this okay so
let's make it somewhat easier and in
this case at a config file to it there's
some new work the work-in-progress might
be completely buggy but completely buggy
but might contain bugs and so and in
this config file we just define defined
flows to give the flow a name and we
tell that the packet type a few
predefined packet types otherwise you
can use the magic magic protocol it's
taxing again and then this is basically
the same syntax just with a few
syntactic sugar things you need to tell
it if it's a MAC address you need to
tell it if it's nappy address and then
you can define things like ranges or
random Rangers which then get basically
well not compiled to code but they
basically it's efficient in the end it
works for us a lot of anonymous
functions and magic in this case this is
your typical simplest example please
don't copy paste and run it because that
ipv6 others as one of my first service
and then once you have key
he's pretty of these flows you can
purify flosser can define your own one
then you can under moonshine simple
interface that in start and the name of
your flow on which device to send on
which device you want to receive if you
want to just see counters for how much
stuff is getting back and then you can
set a few parameters like the packet
rate like if you want to use per so for
control if you want to use whatever how
many shots you want to use bypassing the
same device multiple times you can
combine different flows you can set time
limits for individual flows and so on
and you get then per flow packet
counters and yeah what you also can do
here which is it's often quite annoying
to be back something like this because
in the end you want to know what it's
actually sending out and then you might
end up using TCP dump on your
destination device or dumping message
here's like I simply debugging interface
that can show you okay giving this
config file in this configuration the
packets that I'm going to send out would
look like this here's an example of five
packets and these are the fields that
are being randomized or modified and
this is still work in progress in
particular I know that I just recently
broke the Poisson process for the
traffic generation so yeah I'm working
on this we got it fixed by next week
somehow work on outright a duplicate
no idea okay and one last thing I want
to show us how others using using
moongeun
just so that you might get an idea what
you have other successfully done with it
and how this might be useful for for you
or how this might work and a few things
I want to pick out across the high
profile applications and in particular I
want to point out the the DNS DDoS
resilience tests and was just recently
presented 1274 and they contributed some
DNS logic to moongeun is of course not a
full genus implementation but some
boilerplate code to get DNS queries and
to randomize DNS queries in an efficient
and relatively simple way I said I
couldn't share the actual code for the
for the DDoS attacks for legal reasons
which apparently something about hacker
tools and France or so
but they contributed in escort and it
should be relatively simple to build
some in SD dos testing device based on
top of that so this is interesting
because it uses the complex protocol six
and then the last thing I want to point
out this is really interesting because
they actually used Mundra how it was
intended to be used most people just use
my standard example script which sends
out randomized to DP packets and say
okay it gets me the number of flows I
type in there and it gets me latency
that's good enough and they maybe change
one line in the code but these guys and
we open a few project they really build
a nice test harness around moon drain
but they actually use much support
multiple different package innovators
munis one of them was one of the first
and I really like this because they
actually use their API the way it's
meant to be and they built this complex
test harness and this is a nice thing to
look at if you want to automate more
complex test setup also Big Shot off to
the first pair piscis before software
switch because they contributed the
hardware time stamping code for the
engineer 40 gigabit mix that was kind of
annoying work and I haven't done it I
was just about to get into it and they
sent me a polar has all great thank you
and yeah so I hope you found this kind
of tutorial style lesson useful I hope
maybe to find a few new users for some
things that has a broad range of
applications as you can see here and
hope you enjoyed it and I believe there
are a few minutes for questions left and
if anyone really scans a QR code ever
you can scan it here I can just type
moon run into Google and you will find
it on github hi Dan Bogdanovich
actually very nice work and I'm
pleasantly surprised in package
generation the package iteration so far
has been an issue and domain of the
expensive guys and seeing an
implementation using VP DK you know
solves many of the problems especially
up to a 10 gig space so thank you for
the work thank you
so I'll ask a question will it make
sense to come to one of our hackathons
and generate test traffic on the fly for
various people doing testing of their
that's actually yeah yeah II understand
I'm the second ITF and I was not really
aware what's going on at these
hackathons London yeah okay good good
another question yes thank you
hi Paul great talk as always al Morton
you might have to get closer closer like
yeah how's that you mentioned the
comparisons between packet generators
and the sensitivities of the devices
that are being tested like OVS and VPP
and so forth we've seen some of that in
in OPN fe testing anyway what would you
say to a specification that calibrated
the generators in other words like
policing kind of like policing the
police would would I mean I'm beginning
to think because of the sensitivities
we've we've seen and you've seen that
that might be a valuable spec to pursue
what's your thoughts that's an
interesting idea as I've said I have and
I believe I have a few graphs here and
like this just for me in packets per
second and a few software package a
notice and how they even even wind and
then configure to use poor software
doesn't try to hit this target which is
12 50 nanoseconds and but some
significant diverse and package on
duplicates not not visible here but
they're huge outliers and they're
because the printer statistics in the
same settings are really bad idea
I'm just such a specification might look
like it's unfortunately one half user so
it doesn't include Cisco TX package
generator which would have been a really
interesting addition and this what looks
like those are different generator at
the firmware control method so what we
did was used an FPGA for that
- just really precisely measure how to
how how they interpret actually behaves
and that for us it was quite challenging
so any thoughts on how you would specify
that again I mean some metric you would
look for how you can break it down to a
single number I mean what the is the
mean squared error but it's I believe
not a very good metric because yeah well
I mean if you have a target and it's as
stark as comparing those two slides they
may be just looking at the distributions
says all but the but I think the bottom
line is we need to learn from really
everyone's work that CBR streams aren't
really realistic yes we should we should
have different specifications yes in the
benchmarking that we're going to do and
then we need to ask the question across
different generators how accurately are
they producing the streams that we
desire so we have a template and it ends
up being the thing that we compare
against so it's actually easier to
generate because these are just scale up
to process new processor process and CBR
try to motivate thatit's can't do it
can't do it reasonably so I hope to see
you this afternoon
Thanks yes thank you very much and it
sounds like a very good hallway further
conversation in the hallway we have our
next speaker momentarily we're just
switch shifting so thank you Paula and
I'll see you at the next IDF here's your
machine back okay so the yeah ok I mean
introduce you so mm-hmm okay so our
second speaker is no is rollin round
race fake day from u-20 Fanta and surf
net he'll say it better but and he has
been as a speaker here before and thank
you for being here and I think you'll
enjoy this talk - Thank You Alison so
it's actually pronounced lowland fungi
swag day but I'm not going to torture
people and force them to do that so my
talk today is going to be about the use
of elliptic curve cryptography in DNS
SEC which is what the paper that was
that gautier NRP was actually about and
I'm going to go into a little bit more
detail about some follow up work that we
did after writing that paper and also
going to go into some detail about the
doctrine of these cryptographic
algorithms in the in a sec and since
Paul did a really nice introduction of
himself I decided to add one slide about
myself because I made that step and
actually wrote the thesis and if and
defended it on June 28 this year and
this is a thank you
this is me surrounded by my committee
you may recognize some of the people in
that committee some of them are here in
the room so no pressure no pressure
but I'm gonna go into the meat of the
presentation now and I'm not going to
repeat all of the earlier research we
did there are some pointers on the
slices slicer actually up on the
material site for this this meeting and
at the end there is a set of references
to all the papers I'm referring to so if
you want to look those up you can look
us up offline so in earlier research we
looked at issues with DNS X specifically
and there are two things that we focused
on which were technical issues and
first was that if you start deploying
the in a sec you may encounter packet
fragmentation and this can cause issues
and in earlier work we actually saw that
up to 10% of resolvers on the internet
have issues receiving fragmented
responses which causes delays or in a
worst case scenario actually causes them
to be unable to resolve certain domain
names that are domestic signed the other
issue of course is that because packets
are a lot larger the NSA can easily be
abused for denial of service attacks and
it in the past few years it has actually
been abused for that purpose and there
have been reports about that in the
media now all of these issues are linked
to the fact that DNS egg makes your
response size a lot bigger because it
includes signatures and keys in the DNS
packets and in an earlier paper we
actually argued that the root cause of
all of these problems might be that RSA
was chosen as default cipher for DNS SEC
because if you think about it if you use
RSA 1024 a bit or 2048 bit and every
signature adds hundreds of bytes to your
packet and and that quickly inflates
packet sizes so this made us wonder it
can't be do anything better can we use
for instance ECC so elliptic curve
cryptography tow achieves the same goals
as RSA so it's a public key cryptography
you can do signatures with it but the
nice thing about ECC is that the both
the keys and the signatures are much
smaller than they are for RSA while they
offer greater cryptographic strength and
to give you an example a typical case is
used for elliptic curve cryptography is
using a tour in 56 bit group that gives
you a 512 bit key and signature in Indi
in a second that's four times smaller
than for instance RSA 2048 so that's
attractive because it makes your package
much smaller so why wouldn't we switch
to ECC immediately for the in a sec well
to quote our essays RFC 605 which is the
RFC that actually standardizes the use
of the elliptic curve digital signature
algorithm in DNS SEC validating RSA
signatures is significantly faster than
validating ECDSA signatures about
five times faster in some
implementations it's kind of a weird way
of saying ECDSA is slower and this
potentially means that if we switch all
of our signing for DNS SEC over to ECC
that we're pushing problems to the edge
of the network right because validators
are the machines that do all this nasty
work for you of doing a full dns
resolution and they'll have to validate
these signatures and we might be
increasing their load significantly if
we start using these cryptographic
algorithms and actually this is five
times faster which you should actually
read as five times slower is a bit
optimistic so we did some benchmarking
and it's it's way worse than this so the
goal of the study in this paper was if
we switch DNS sick from using RSA to
using ECC how does that impact
validating DNS resolvers right so rather
than recommend to everyone well these
easy say ECC signatures are much smaller
it's really nice to switch to them let's
work out if we're not introducing a new
problem by giving this recommendation
and that was the purpose of this study
so how do we go about doing this we
decided to do a measurement study and
some modeling for this and our method
I'm gonna describe our methodology in
the next couple of slides and we started
out from the premise that we want that
we had this intuition that if we knew
the number of outgoing queries from
resolver so that's not incoming crash or
clients that's the queries the resolver
sends to authoritative name servers on
the internet that we might be able to
predict the number of signatures
validations that it has to perform given
that load right and that was our premise
and I'm gonna get I'm gonna talk you to
four factors that influence the number
of signature validations that a resolver
will have to perform now the first
factor is that for every query that a
dns resolver sends to an authoritative
nameserver
on the internet it will not always get a
response right so the number of
responses that come back are somehow a
factor in this the second thing is that
because dns a is far from universally
deployed
not every response that you get back
from an authoritative nameserver oaken
contains signatures right so you won't
have to validate signatures for every
response that you get back the third
factor is the number of signatures in
the response that contain signatures
right because while you might expect a
response to contain a single signature
for the record that you requested
actually we observed that on average
every response that contains signatures
has somewhere in the order of between
2.4 and 2.5 signatures per response that
has signatures that's because there are
signatures in the additional section
there might be extra records in there
that require signatures so this
intuition doesn't hold there are more
signatures in a response than just for
the record that you requested
finally your resolver may not have to
validate each in every signature in that
response either because it's already
validated one and it's cached it or
because it's in the authority or
additional section and it decides not to
validate those right it doesn't have to
validate those and another reason for
why it might not validate signatures is
because it doesn't have a full chain of
trust all the way up to the root so it
might not be able to validate that
particular signature and it's not going
to bother to spend the CPU cycles on it
right and to remind you again we do not
measure the number of queries from
clients because that very strongly
between resolvers we wanted to build a
model that we can apply to any resolver
regardless of its client population and
if I'm not gonna go into detail in the
presentation but in the paper you will
see that the model is actually a little
bit less accurate for resolvers that
have a small client population but those
are the resolver that we really don't
have to worry about as much because they
will be validating far fewer signatures
because they're processing far fewer
queries right
so how did we measure this this picture
shows you our measurement setup and on
the left hand side you see clients which
is typically you with your laptop unless
you're an idiot like me to run servers
over on their laptop and then what we
did was we captured traffic that was
going to production DNS
resolvers and then we forward this
traffic to an instrumented DNS resolver
so we're sending a copy of the exact
query traffic that goes to a production
resolver to one that we instrument and
then we measure certain factors on that
so to make sure that our instrument the
resolver is actually performing in a
normal way we measure the number of
queries from clients in the number of
responses sent back to clients which you
see on the left hand side marked as QC
and RC and compare that to the
production resolver right just to make
sure that we're observing the same thing
right because if we instrument resolver
when we break it and it and it doesn't
respond to clients as it should that
would be a mess right and there's some
some stuff in the paper about the ethics
of this because of course we're sending
people's traffic to an instrument to
resolve Reni we don't want to violate
their privacy so he took some measures
for that on the instrument instrumental
resolver we measure on the outgoing link
towards the internet so where the
resolver talks to a third date of name
service the number of queries it sends
all of these factors that I talked about
in the previous set of slides and the
numbers of signatures that it validates
and for that we actually had to alter
the code of the resolver right because
this is not something that most resolver
implementations typically keep
statistics for so in this case we modify
bind and unbound to record this number
of validated signatures if we then look
at all of these four factors that I
described in the methodology slide and
you plot those as a scatter plot and
then you see from top left to bottom
right all of the four factors so a shows
you the number of queries on the x-axis
number of responses that come back on
the y-axis B shows you the number of
responses on X versus number of
responses containing signatures on Y C
shows you number of response a number of
signatures per response and D is a
number of signatures that are actually
validated or fractional signatures
that's actually getting validated now if
you look at these graphs then your
intuition might be that you could model
this with a linear model although
especially graph B has a lot of noise in
it but as it turns out graph B is not
the one that we want to worry about
which is the number of
responses that contain signatures
because we're actually going to use that
later on in the model so there the
accuracy is not an issue for the other
ones we tried if we can approximate this
with a linear model and it turns out
that we can so I'm not going to talk you
through all of this but we came the
details are in the paper but we created
a simple set of linear equations that
you can then combine to make a model for
a validating resolver and it has four
important parameters so the first one is
the average number of responses per
query and this is something that you
need to measure on an operating resolver
to actually populate the model so these
are parameters that you would need to
measure the fraction of responses with
signatures and the average number of
signatures per response and a fraction
of signatures that is validated Oh
is the mic broken again okay I'll try to
eat the mic as somebody suggested
yesterday okay so of course if you make
such a model you need to validate if it
works so we validate or we said as we
set out for criteria that we use to
validate this model and the first one is
that we wanted to make sure that the
model works for a different DNS resolver
implementation so we tested it for
unbound and bind and actually I had a
student do some tests with all readiness
as well which at the time they were
implementing validation in the resolver
unfortunately wasn't stable enough and
the same is true for not resolver which
was then still under development but in
principle you could apply to those two
and we get some tests with it now the
second thing we wanted to validate is
whether the model has stable properties
over time and actually like I said only
alpha s which is the number of the
diffraction of responding responses that
contain signatures can vary
significantly over time because we vary
this parameter to do to make predictions
right so we don't really care if that's
stable over time but the other factor
should be more or less stable over time
so we measured over a five month period
and didn't see major changes in in these
two in the rest of the parameters of the
model
we also wanted to make sure that this
model works for different client
populations so we use traffic from four
sources to test the model we used so I
work for certain international research
in education network in the Netherlands
so we used traffic to three of our
production resolvers but we also use
traffic to one of the resolvers for my
University and in addition to this
because we realize that we may not have
typical resolvers because we have
certain client populations we also did
some worst case estimations that are in
the paper where we take sort of worst
case estimates for all of the parameters
of the model and finally we checked if
the model is actually a good predictor
of imparity observed data so what we did
was we populated the model made
predictions of what we thought the
number of signatures that we need to
validate what's going to be and then
compare that to what we saw in actual
practice and again the details forever
in the paper but we did some statistical
goodness of fit tests for that now the
next thing that we have to do is now
that we are we have a model for
predicting the number of signature
validations that are required we of
course need to know how ECC performs
right and although there are some
benchmarks publicly available that we
used in in in an earlier paper we wanted
to make sure that we had up-to-date
benchmarks so we took five
implementations of elliptic curve
cryptography and benchmark those on them
on a modern CPU
we took three versions of OpenSSL one
that we consider a legacy so you'll see
that in older distributions one that we
considered long term support because
it's in in all of the long term support
versions of for instance the major Linux
distributions and one that we considered
at the time to be new and optimized and
it's actually moving into long term
support now and that had optimized
implementations of ECDSA P 256 so that
is the algorithm that we expect will be
used the most in DNS ech at this point
in time
and actually there's now OpenSSL 1.1 or
0 which was not performed that
differently from 102 so this is actually
still a good set of benchmarks to use
today then we looked at the newer
elliptic curve algorithms 82 four five
one nine and eighty four four eight
which have only recently been
standardized for use in DNS SEC and
there again we took optimized
implementation of these two algorithms
because the the reference implementation
of those don't perform very well
so we took optimized versions there and
then what we did was we did a hundred
tests of running the algorithm for ten
seconds and then measuring how many
signature validations it would perform
in that period and the details of the
benchmarks rendered paper to give you
some idea so easy do you say P 256 is an
order of magnitude slower than RSA 1024
and why is that a good comparison
because we're you could argue that we're
comparing apples and oranges right
because ECD is AP two five six
cryptographically is much stronger than
RSA 1024 but I would argue that you need
to make this comparison because most of
the signatures that you see in the NSTIC
today are signatures with zone signing
keys that are 1024 bits where did that
make sense in terms of security or not
you can debate but that's the case and
then if you take ECDSA P 384 which is
greater perfectly even stronger you
compare that to something like RSA 2048
you see again that there is an order of
magnitude performance difference so this
is way more than the five times that is
quoted in the RFC even 8255 for nine
which is way faster than the ECDSA
algorithms in terms of implementation
that is still almost up to an order of
magnitude slower than RSA 1024 and only
four if you compare to RSA 2048 do we
get into the same sort of order of
magnitude as is quoted in the RFC right
so some key benchmarks because you're
going to see these in the graphs that
I'll be showing you
a little bit further along in the
presentation you see five
implementations on the left-hand side
the specific elliptic curves that we did
the test for and then the performance in
the number in terms of the number of
signatures validations that you can
perform with that algorithm per second
on the CPU sides at the bottom right
this is not the top-end CPU but it would
be a common CPU that you would encounter
in server architecture so this is
typically something that people have in
their data center right we have data
centers full of these stuff unless
you're really rich in your Google you
have these and why did we pick these
particular benchmarks because you're
going to see them in the graphs that
I'll be showing you in the in the next
couple of slides so we picked ECDSA p3
therefore because this was a worst case
scenario right this is the the slowest
of all of the algorithms that we
benchmarked and it is the strongest
broadly supported cipher and what do I
mean by that you could say that 84 4 4 8
at the bottom of the slide is stronger
in terms of cryptography but it's not
widely available in implementations so
few people are going to use it so that's
why we took P 384 as sort of a benchmark
to compare against then P 256 on
openness l1a1 we took that for as long
term support version of the most likely
use sulfur the one or two implementation
of P 256 as you can see that is almost
three times as fast because of the
optimizations in there and this is to
show you what an optimized version of
ECC can do
and then finally newer algorithms which
outperform the older ones by yd250 509
is is again another more than a half
times faster than the most optimized
version of B 2 5 6
although I've actually seen a paper
recently that claims that they can make
P 2 5 6 almost as fast as 82 for 509
right
so let's go back to our original
question which was what is the impact on
validating the US resolves right because
that's why we started this so we use our
model to evaluate or to estimate future
performance right and we took a look at
two scenarios so the first scenario is
what if we take currently in a sick
deployment and we switch all of those
domains over to ECC overnight so
everything that's now signed with RCA or
DSA or whatever you use will switch that
to ECC is that an issue well based on
the measurements that we did on our
resolvers we argued that you need about
150 signature validations per second for
a busy result where this was a result
for processing around 20,000 queries
from clients per second so this was a
busy resolver and that's not a problem
and even if we take the model and we put
in the worst case numbers we still don't
go above the worst case scenario which
is using p 384 so that's not an issue
but what if everybody deployed the NSTIC
and if they used ECC right so right now
the NSTIC deployment is roughly three
three and a half percent of all domains
on the internet what if a hundred
percent of those were to deploy it in a
sec and they all use ECC to sign what
does that do to your resolve
so the second scenario that we evaluated
is a popular domains first growth to a
hundred percent domestic deployment and
everyone uses ECC now what do I mean by
popular by popular I mean that the
domains for we for which the resolver
sense to most queries to the internet if
that switch is to ECC first right and so
here I plot the query popularity for
queries that the resolver sends to
authoritative nameservers and and this
shows you this is a classic so you can
see the the axes are low cloak and this
is a classic internet distribution it's
commonly referred to as ship for
long-tailed or Plato or 80/20 doesn't
really matter but basically what it
means is that the
most popular query and is by far
responsible for the highest number of
queries sent out to the Internet
so let's look at some results so these
are the really nice graphs that my
student cooked up he's a MATLAB wizard
and what you can see in this graph on
this axis and we can debate what you
call that axis but I would say it's the
y axis you see the intersect deployment
and as you may remember I said that we
will be varying the average number of
responses with signatures to simulate
the intersect deployment right so what
we did was calculate based on the
distribution for popularity we modeled
what if we go from left to right in that
distribution how many queries with how
many responses with signatures would
that result in and that's what we model
on that axis so from 0 to 100% in a sec
deployment on the x axis you see the
number of outgoing queries and actually
the maximum number of outgoing queries
we observe observed on the busiest
resolver was some 1,800 queries per
second and then you see a grey playing
in in the graph which is the maximum
number of signatures that we can
validate for ECDSA p 384 on a single CPU
core the takeaway from this is that
there is ample room for growth in the
NSTIC deployment and outgoing query load
right so we can go up to 100% DNS SEC
deployment using ECD DSA P 384 and the
number of outgoing queries from that
resolver could still double and Unbound
would still be able to validate those
signatures on a single CPU core right
and so this is a conservative estimate
if you run a really busy resolver you're
working at an ISP you typically don't
have a single core assigned to that
resolver so this is something that is
easily within the realm of the possible
so that's a great result we can we can
take the worst case algorithm and
unmount we'll still be able to cope with
it
so what does this picture look like for
bind um I apologize because the title of
the slide has somehow gone but this is
bind and for bind we observe something a
little bit different there might be a
potential problem for P 384 because as
it turns out bind validates up to two
and a half times the number of
signatures for the same query load that
unbound us and okay
[Music]
there are there's been suggestions for
reasons why that might be because blank
might be trying to chase if it gets
negative responses it might be trying to
chase more chase up other authoritative
nameservers it really tries very hard to
get the response and it might be
validating more signatures because of
that but we actually didn't investigate
in detail why this was the case we just
we just took this as a given but what
you can then see is if we look at the
the the situation for the ECAC ECDSA p25
six long-term support version which is
actually the one that we expect people
to use if they sign then you see that
even though buying has ample room for
growth or the green line that intersects
the red slope intersects it way beyond
the number of queries that we would need
to be able to validate signatures for on
our busiest resolver today and the same
is true if if for instance you want to
go for something really strongly you
don't even go for p 384-bit you go for
the newer curve 84 for 8 that
outperforms even the long term support
version of P 256 so to take away from
this is in most cases binary code but
there are slight words for P 384 now
answer the original paper we did some
additional benchmarks because you could
argue that we did our benchmark on into
x86 some of the optimizations that have
been implemented are only available for
x86 architectures so what about other
architectures what if I have a home
router and I want to do dns
accreditation on that how is it going to
cope
so we did a stupor chicken actually had
two students working on this where we
did benchmarks on arm CPUs and on MIPS
CPUs because we would think that these
are representative of what you would
find in the typical home router now the
key I'm not going to go through all the
details of those benchmarks but the the
key takeaways there is that the
performance is low but it is more than
sufficient for home scenarios and that
interestingly ECDSA may sometimes be
faster than EDSA because there are
already some optimized versions of ECDSA
available for for instance arm CPUs that
outperform the stock EDSA
implementations that are available for
that we did an N equals 1 home router
experiment so this is take with heap of
salt right this is not representative
but it's an interesting experiment to
run and one of my students really wanted
to do this and and I mean he got extra
bonus points for the fact that he got
informed consent from his roommates
before he did the experiment right so
and I didn't even have to enclose that
because he it turned out he had an
ethics course going on at the same time
so and there are two takeaways for this
shows you 24 others of course to the
resolver that they run in their student
dorm which he equipped with the unbound
and then instrumented and they're
measured and the there are two takeaways
from this and the first one is a little
bit serious in the sense that with them
concurrent user so he did this during a
party so there were lots of people in
the house and with them concurrent users
to query loud peaked at around 60
queries per second from clients right
now he also measured cache performance
on on his resolver and the cache
performance was atrocious right because
there are too few users to make good use
of the cache so actually only about 10
20 % of his queries could be received
responses from the cache so I said well
let's go for the worst case the couch
doesn't do anything and the resolver has
to validate everything and then you see
that if you
if you would run this on a mich CPU and
we take some of the benchmarks that they
perform that the resolver would actually
start to struggle because these home
devices typically have only a single CPU
core and that CPU core would be swamped
with signature validations at point load
so there's maybe some work there but
this is actually only if we have a
hundred percent domestic deployment
which today we don't have so I believe
we can safely assume that by the time if
ever we reach one hundred percent the
NSTIC deployment these devices will be
fast enough and there will be optimized
implementations of elliptic curve
algorithms Oh in a second takeaway from
this is that stood apart e's are not
what they used to be because it observe
the observant viewer will see that the
party stopped at 1:00 a.m. oh there's a
question is this a is this a
representative student party where
people are browsing the web instead of
getting drunk yes these are Millennials
so they're checking Facebook the whole
time posting selfies I mean yeah yeah
yeah my my XE my student was we told him
not to look at the queries and of course
he did
and and then he thought I don't want to
notice about my room Hanson and he gave
up on it so I want to end with some
insight into adoption right because I've
written a couple of papers on on use of
ECC in in DNS SEC but until 2015 there
was virtually no adoption of ECDSA
signing schemes that are standardized in
RFC six 605 and RFC six 605 dates back
to 2012 so and actually the first
implementation in environment unbound is
a little bit older than that right
because about the records one of the
authors of the RFC is also one of the
developers that implements Unbound so
there was supporting unbound actually
before the RFC came up so in late 2015
CloudFlare actually was the first DNS
operator to adopt ECDSA signing at skill
right they rolled out their DNS ik as a
service thing and they said we're going
to Oliver Guth Monson said we're going
to be signing with
ECDSA so we want to know how is it
option developed since then these graphs
refer that continental org and what they
show you is the period from the first of
March 2015 until somewhere last week
before I got on a plane and what you can
see against the legend is little bit
hard to read but I'm gonna be pointing
out some things such as the fact that
the majority of signed domains income
net and org still use RSA sha-1 that
should change sha-1 is not considered
secure anymore for signature algorithms
[Laughter]
this is the point in time where
CloudFlare announces its Universal DNS
accusing ECDSA P 2 O 5 6 and as you as I
hope you can see there is an uptake of
ECDSA that starts from that point onward
right the the pink area at the at the
top of the graph starts growing slowly
but actually ECDSA adoption is now
driven completely by other operators
that are adopting is our mas and and so
of I think the beginning of this month
ECDSA is the second signing algorithm
after RSA sha-1 please people change
that replacing our say sha-256 as second
popular signing algorithm so that's
actually a good news this is getting
adopted pretty quickly in combat and org
if we look at them to the 2t of these
that have the largest number of sign
domains which is Tata now under 2 C and
the picture is a little bit different
and as you can see that adoption of
ECDSA
Peter 5:6 is still quite low it's only a
fraction of the total number of sign
domains but one takeaway here is that
especially the C is doing really well
right no RSA sha-1 it's all our sha-256
so kudos that it actually makes way more
sense and they're actually going to
switch to signature algorithm for their
TLD to our sha-256 as well and at the
end of this month
in the Danelle also for a lesser session
one then in common an org but also only
a little bit of ECDSA so a take away is
the early large-scale adopters of DNS
SEC take longer to get a significant
share of SEC signed domains it's not
surprising but it also means that
replacing signature algorithms will take
time also because replacing signature
algorithm is actually difficult if we
look at the Alexa top 1 million
completely different graph also quite
interesting here you can see again that
there's quite a bit of adoption of ACDs
AP 2 5 6 22% of the electorate of 1
million signed domains in about 1.7
percent of them are signed use ECDSA and
61 percent of those use cloud fair so
there's actually also quite a
significant number that are not using
cloud thread for lists are using another
operator that's interesting right so I
get to my conclusions the first main
takeaway from the paper and from this
talk is that ECC is sufficiently
performant for use in DNA SEC right
we can easily validate the number of
signatures that we would need to
validate if everybody deployed the
intersect with ECC on a single CPU core
and still have room to spare so my
recommendation is going to be that
operator should switch to ECDSA for
signing if you haven't deployed the in a
sec yet
don't bother deploying RSA please go for
ECC algorithms straight away because it
gives you all of the benefits of ACC
which is smaller than a speck eights
which means no fragmentation we show
that in an earlier paper fragmentation
is fully gone and much less
amplification and if you combine that
with some of the newer ways to tackle
amplification attacks then switching the
combination of switching to ECC and
deploying those countermeasures will
actually make your domain unattractive
to abuse in amplification attacks
finally resolver operators may want to
look at deploying newer optimized crypto
libraries to have some CPU to spare you
can do this even with long term support
versions of the software but if you want
to
save on CPU cycles you might want to
deploy newer libraries and finally as I
showed you in the last couple of slides
adoption is slowly taking off and with
that I get to the end I would like to
thank my students who who helped me with
this
so it's Kasper Hagerman who just started
his PhD in at the albergue in Denmark
Bruce and JJ who helped with the ARMA
mips benchmarks and the data for the
adoption was supplied by the open Intel
project have a look at the URL if you're
interested and the references to the
papers as I said are included in a PDF
of the full slide deck thank you for
your time so any questions
[Music]
I'm freedom from NIST so we we have been
working on PGP sec implementations which
also uses ECDSA P 256 and listed
together with a SBIR contract the
company's name is a antara
technique so we have as together we have
developed a high-performance
implementation of PGP SEC and in that we
we did I mean it was mainly our SBIR
contractor anchor a technique and his
name is mammoth it earlier so excellent
work you should look at that we we
presented that paper at Nanak 69 in
February this year it will say BGP SEC a
high-performance PGP SEC implementation
but it has a lot of measurement details
about ECDSA performance and we use DAC
we compared it with the OpenSSL 1.1 dot
0 and significant I mean several several
I mean significant multiplication factor
improvement of this high-performance
implementation compared to open SSL 1.1
dot 0 so I'll be happy to give you the
pointer to that paper ok thanks
but that was actually the paper I was
referring to when I said that there
might be an even faster implementation
of p2 five six but thank you and it's
great work thank you thank you for that
and thanks to least for sponsoring that
West heard Icarus I thinks this is a
really good measurement work and I
enjoyed seeing the results quite a bit
you know the this sad thing so two
things first off the sad thing is that
you know you are providing guidance to
signers but it's but it's really the
resolvers don't have a choice right so
so if there is like a sudden uptake of
DNS SEC usage and you know that could
eventually blow through the roof and if
everybody used to looked at curve you
could still imagine that you know
although you you stayed at the end that
everything's okay right now based on the
current growth of DNS SEC you could you
can imagine the case where it actually
might be a problem down in the future
you know based on the fact that they're
they're still significantly slower and
that actually brings me to my next point
which is it would actually be
interesting to look at you know what
DNS SEC adoption rate might combined
with you know the CPU increase in speed
and and have this early warning system
of we're headed for danger because all
of a sudden the resolvers are not gonna
get it you know if all of a sudden some
major you know GoDaddy or something you
know started signing everything I don't
know I wouldn't I would HIGHLY encourage
go date to do that and stop judging
people money for for using Venus ik so
there's actually some discussion about
that in the paper and in the paper we
argue that even if you go for a
worst-case scenario so we're we we take
away all of the measurements and we just
model we assume that the model is is
accurate enough to put in worst case
parameters you it's arguable whether or
everybody has the CPUs that can deal
with this right but that that's an
assumption and that's an assumption that
we cannot not prove or disprove but even
if you put in worst case data then with
the way the DNS currently looks
I am confident enough to say that every
resolvers would be able to handle the
signature validations however if
suddenly the new gTLD has become wildly
popular and we see a fragmentation in
the namespace then this picture might
change because that might blow up the
number of cache misses which might blow
up the number of signature validations
and then we are in unknown territory but
it doesn't seem like the new g2u these
are that wildly popular so I'm not too
worried about that yet but there are and
these are actually discussed in the
paper so there are some situations where
our assertion that we can deal with
these signature validations where they
might not hold and this is one of those
situations the other one which is also
discussed in the paper is about what did
it do not how can I just reopen that oh
yeah okay there we go one of the other
things that we discussed in the paper is
a denial of service attack where you try
to cause cpu starvation by forcing
signature validations and this is
actually something that was that Polaris
man who was then still at Comcast
brought up and we actually verified this
so that's also in the paper and what we
did was we forced resolvers to do lots
of ECDSA signature validations by making
them verify signatures for cloud layers
sort of black life thing that gives you
a fresh signature for every NX domain
that can kill bind easily unbound
survives so there is an issue there but
we also sketch an idea of how you could
solve this in resolve or implementations
by doing some form of rate limiting and
and I know I've discussed this with
router from an outlet labs who thought
it might be feasible to do that I don't
know whether he has had time to
implement it yet does that answer your
question okay
dear defendant congratulations with your
work I still want to reflect on some of
your results well you made some analysis
of the you made some analysis of the
number of signatures validations done by
unbound and and and and bind can you
also continue this kind of work or
reflect on this work and say something
about what is the ideal if I could build
a platonic or ideal resolver what are
the number of signatures I have to fill
a date to come up with an answer okay
it's not the measurements actually but
it's more than theoretical approach and
that can give maybe some guidance to
this operative oh yeah learned opponent
thank you for your kind words an
interesting question this idea of
designing a platonic resolver I like
that I really like the term so I'm gonna
have to steal that from you and use it
somewhere that's actually interesting
because as the paper states there's a
huge difference between bind and unbound
but there are many factors that play a
role in that right a platonic reserve or
resolver what would you need to specify
requirements what that does does that
give you does that work the hardest to
get you an answer
does that find some middle ground
between spending time finding something
and then deciding it can be found those
are questions that would need to be
answered but I think that's interesting
research and so we have a PhD student in
our lab who's working on resolver things
and this is yet another idea to put in
his head we can make explicit decisions
ya know and I think I agree
so there's actually in my opinion far
too little research on what is
optimal resolver and for instance we can
talk about caching strategies we can
talk about time spent finding responses
I think that yes I agree with you there
is interesting research to be done there
thank you thank you very much
bilham tulip internet loves so very nice
work in very interesting definitely
quality work and it's very important to
find the right measurement metric so I
think it's very nice that you identified
those factors but however there are some
factors which are under exposed in now a
current scientific world and you know
there's this single factor which is of
paramount importance and I think you
know what I'm talking about and you know
it has driven many scientists to do
madness it's it's a difficult beast to
capture I recognized it so I don't
expect that you did attempt but have you
looked into the jelly Maori Factory and
so that's that's a really good question
and and and yes it did nearly drive me
insane but I have a backup slide on that
so we actually we actually measured the
legality you can see in the graph here
we measured the Galle more free factor
and I'll talk you through what you see
in the in the graph here so what we did
was we measured the callee more free
factor in micro more freeze for queries
per second leading to ECC validation
well I think that William already said
this everybody knows this factor so we
you see the initial ramp down right
which is what you would expect to see
typically in a galley more free
distribution and then some normal noise
but then there is this weird peak
an unexpected rise around 425 queries
per second which we can't explain right
so and and that has puzzled us for for
for the past year and a half and if you
know what causes that I I would I would
like to I would like to know right so
and we see this for unbound and for bind
and and there's also the suspicious
absence of noise beyond 450 queries per
second so help us so quantum factors
actually that influence the micro
murphy's a second sure it's actually a
different measurement unit every time
right sir it could be electrical
variation from satellite deborah's or
the static from nylon and we're but I
suspect that this will be the micro
mischeif assignments okay but anyway I'm
very impressed impressed that you
managed to capture this so it's
definitely it surprised me that that
someone would win twice the network
research applied into a research price
but now I understand violence because
you know thank you i concerned that the
audience is wondering if they've gone
out of their minds about this so we
should explain that Willam has been
challenged and now he's taken rolling
into a challenge to to use the word
galimov free at three mic lines and this
is a very successful version of that as
well as a you know a deep enlightenment
of an important scientific factor it's
good and micro factor and and and i
think i am our our play to surprise you
so let's go back to the serious
questions in this case unless matter
once you ask me a question about the
galley most refactor map
not with in on that labs can we go back
to your ECC adoption slide yeah
which one keep going that one no yeah
maybe it was the one you said yeah why
not
so anyway that'll do ash sorry yeah I'm
trying to understand this because it
looks like there was a lot of growth
around this time last year and then it's
been actually been pretty flat in terms
of ECC adoption since then do you have
any reflections on yes I do so let me
see if the pointer on this works what
you're referring to is is here where
there is especially not org it's very
steep this is very actually in look at
that in detail what happened there and
this is one Operator in particular who
who was using RSA sha-256 before and
they decided on their own and to switch
to ac/dc ECDSA p25 six for all the right
reasons because they wanted to reduce
their packet sizes they wanted to
increase the security of their signature
algorithms I think I I'm trying to
struggle onto him remember the name I
was domain names show up it's a
Norwegian company and I can mention
their name because I had some email
communication with them and they they
did this it's actually not been flat
it's kind of hard to see in the in the
graphs here if you if you look at the
slice you can zoom in a little so there
is still some adoption and and it's
still increasing slowly but the the
large peak was when this one
organization decided to switch and then
later on there's a smaller bump that you
see if you zoom a little bit into the in
on the graph there's another small bump
which is another algorithm rollover and
actually I brought these people because
I monitored their Okrand rollover they
did it completely correctly right so
those of you familiar with the NSX will
know that this is difficult to give a
little bit of idea to the people that
are less familiar an algorithm rollover
requires you to take those specific
steps which is to introduce new
signatures first before you introduce
new key because the NSA actually has a
provision that if something is signed
with a certain algorithm so if
key for a certain algorithm exists
signatures for that algorithm must also
exist because otherwise you'd be able to
perform downgrade attacks and most
resolver implementations take that quite
strictly so if you don't follow those
steps in an algorithm all over your
domain goes into goes bogus and
resolvers will actually refuse to
validate it so they did this correctly
and I think that was the first example
at scale of switching to a different
algorithm that was done successfully
because we've seen algorithm rollovers
for two days and CCT of these in the
past and almost all of them had some
hitch where they for instance introduced
the key at the wrong time or made
another mistake introduced at the yes at
the wrong time so this really is
something that needs attention and to
finish off with that there's sort of as
I said the Swedish registry is going to
switch from using our session 1 to our
sha-256 4.2 C and we'll actually be
measuring that I started this other
project called root canary which we
presented at the Mapuche meeting earlier
this week and this the suite actually
came to us and said can you measure our
algorithm below for because we're kind
of scared that something might go wrong
so we're actually gonna measure that and
see how that works in practice so we get
a much more detailed measurement and we
have for this particular instance where
we only have a granularity of one day
intervals well thank you very much this
is great work and congratulations on
winning this prize the second time I
should say that blow lands now been
invited to join the selection committee
for the AARP so no good deed goes
unpunished thank you
any other questions ok thank you for
your time
thanks everybody I think we should end
on this high note and so you know please
feel free to cluster up here and ask any
questions or get involved further and oh
I wanted to show you the cat who was
working so let me quickly do that and
then well and on that note this does
anyone else have any questions of a
general nature before we go do you when
you're trying to do things you can't
alright okay so go out and write papers
the way this cat owl does and and send
them here and participate in IRT F thank
you so we'll give everybody back some
time I think we have to do a
presentation of certificates which we
don't have to do in front of everybody
all up do we have certificates to
present to oh we oh sorry yes so we we
were going to actually if you want to
stay and work in here you can see the
the honor the presentation of the prize
certificates and the photographing of
same but thanks very much for for being
with us we're really very good session
[Music]
[Laughter]
okay