yeah okay um so this is now the lamps
working group and Shawn has decided that
he wants to volunteer those eight
minutes for me this this is probably
like going to be the easiest meeting to
take minutes in a bit more than five
vineland be surprised okay so this is
this is the lamps working group the note
well which everybody at this point and
here probably have seen at least once
[Laughter]
there's the agenda so we've got many
should do to take care of the need the
first half anyone who wants to to
subtract remove change things in the
agenda a now is the unspeak up you can
read the agenda it's off it's on one
slide it's still here I haven't seen her
so there's presentation
Oh actually that's me nevermind this new
stuff so issues the 18 in update
basically it's ready to go to I think
it's still stuck with ekor and these
it's just question giving it to the ietf
at this point i yes you at this point
[Music]
the two s/mime updates are currently
stuck on me I need to finish dealing
with the AV review comments
with any luck um I need to get that done
by the end of this week and then we can
then the Necker can sit on it for a
while and and then send it to iesg for
review with the two of us been
alternating not managing to not get to
this document to finish it so so I mean
so I tuned in actually has been proof of
iesg and it's just um we're waiting for
the food announcement to be sent okay
right so I'm excused for not actually
knowing that was in the cabinet so
neither of the authors of the I ate team
draft are actually here they've done
some changes they've done a few edits to
deal with things and as you've said if
this this was now ready for publishing
stuff okay
so yeah you're up next
sorry
just for clarification the ien document
on the t28 --red --red has been approved
the eai document i put on the telecom
for like right one from now sure why not
okay well let's skip this until he
manages to come back and get some place
so he's trying to get through okay
we're not exactly overloaded for mm-hmm
me being tires
yeah
okay so let's just skip over so okay
hi-yah so if it's useful I can give us
some money issue welfare lips trying to
connect so I've been pretty involved in
it too and I have a draft out some of
the issues published which I hope to see
adopted as the beginning of a working
document for the working group what
happened at the sea a browser forum
which is the self regulating body for
the CIA industry is we went to mandate
CAA and discovered some ambiguities and
in Felicity's in it in particular
there's this tree climbing thing we do
where we go up you know from the first
label the parent label to the parent
label looking for CIA records the way it
was specified said that we should
additionally we should do some
additional processing on see names and D
names and be that same tree climbing for
those see names of the lives the
downside of that is it creates a really
huge number of lookups and it creates
these really that ambiguity in terms of
which CAA record you want to use so the
C Bowser forum wound up adopting on
inner Atum so currently there's an
erratum on CAA and says this process
seems normally don't do that special
processing and so you have a fixed
member of whatever if there are three
labels in the domain name you're gonna
do three lookups modular the cname
processing which is handled by either
the cursive resolver so this is a sort
of awkward situation right now where the
see a browser form has adopted this RFC
bossanova bottom that's held for
document update so one of the big things
would like to do is actually do a
document update that fixes that issue
what I have done in the ancient draft is
rewrite how that's specified
part of it is that the specification you
know try to get into the
see name resolution when that's already
handled by RFC 1034 so instead it kind
of shells out okay - RFC 1034
do you know more thing say three times
if you have three labels and use the
results for those I'm not sure what else
Philip I wanted to address in his slides
here if he's ready he can jump on I
wanted to flag one other thing which the
see a browser forum wound up kind of
patching in which is error handling so
right now the what's specified in the
baseline of elements is that if you get
an error during lookup you can treat
that as permission to issue so long as
it wasn't a DNS that base yeah I'm
paraphrasing it so it would also be
useful for us to specify error handling
and the idea specification and it's all
see the screen now so fellow can go
Bannen the slides
thanks for me okay soon
okay for now okay it's you getting sound
yes okay so the basic problem with said
you go to the slide to the basic reason
that we have to do all this bizarre
discovery thing is some DNS records are
not are private and this isn't something
that we can debate they just are and CA
is regularly issued for city hit cuts
that can't be seen on the Public DNS and
so that's why there is the tree-climbing
algorithm NCAA the first problem in the
first place and the problem is that the
CIA records are intended to be
communication for the domain name hold
at the CX so this is like three
unfortunately DNS records are published
by domain name holders so that might be
directly or through a third party
and so cname is used to map a set intent
names onto a single target it's also now
used widely to delegate domain name
holder to a third party service provider
so this is what is done by MX + srv4
well behaved protocols
unfortunately HTTP is not well behaved
because it was invented before SRB and
there's no MX record for it so the prop
basic problem of the discovery is you
don't have the distinction in the DNS
record telling you why that cname is
that so I'm go to slide 4 the big
complication is that D names aren't
really DNS records there's something
else they're really a sort of
placeholder that goes in the zone file
that is used to generate cname records
on demand only the reason that it now
appears in on the wire is because of DNS
SEC and you need to be able to say why
you synthesized
a cname as Saudi name appears on the
wall on the wire so ca ca a client
should be processing thee names as part
of the seat name validation but only
really in terms of their DNS SEC
validation so if you've got an N SEC 3
record that says that you should have
had a seat D name then you've got to
understand that in your CAA code if
you've got a DNS if you've got a DNA
record that says that the cname should
have been synthesized you've got to
understand that and you've got your
understand if the C name retro turn is
valid and then the C name returned is
invalid so those are all things that
your code has to understand about when
you do the CAA record processing with
DNS SEC but really you're just working
off the C names I'll come back to this
in a moment okay so one of the big
problems that we're working around is
use of C name is restricted because the
idea is that you are so this is slide
number 5 the idea is that you're
delegating the entire zone so you're not
allowed to have anything else in a see
name in the DNS so that means that you
aren't allowed to have a phone that has
a cname and the CA a record and that's
the thing that gets us in trouble
because we have those administrative C
names that are used for internal
delegations and then you've got those CD
MD names that are used for external
delegations and you don't know which are
which and if you've run the CDN case
well you can't put your CAA record at
your zone any so that was what led to
the requirement that the CARF clients
follows C name so I've got a couple of
use cases in 3rd slide 6 so these use
cases are showing to see names in series
so first of all web example.com is going
to be
name - WWE example calm and that's a
ministry of internal redirect and then
we have example.com so www.example.com
going off to see the end of example net
and so that's the third party redirect
so if you look at the original algorithm
this is in slide 7 this is assuming that
cname mappings are administrative and so
you have a discovery path it starts up
great dot example.com ghost of WWE ample
comm then goes off to see the end of it
and that's really not something that you
would like to do the first two were fine
that's what you want the next one
example dotnet that is really bad duck
net mutts are bad but irrelevant and
then you'll go back to example.com and
then com
so CDN have made the RFC eight six eight
four four algorithm bogus so now slide
eight which shows what happens when you
have the errata and basically this cuts
out some but not all of the bogosity if
you have web block example.com WWI
example comm you still go off to the CDN
got example dotnet we then don't chase
the tree up any further then example.com
and then com
so that's what is in production today
because cab form requires us to do the
errata and then we go to slide nine the
solution that had been proposed is to
use a prefix record and just ignore the
cname issue completely so instead of the
algorithm chasing see names at all we
don't do any of that and instead the
discovery path will be web example.com
underscore prefix web not example calm
then WWE example comm prefix the same
example.com prefix of the same and so on
so that means that you don't
end up doing any bogus records the only
disadvantage is that you're doing
slightly more rip-rip lookups but you
know this is ca work this is validation
this is really not something that is a
huge deal so if we go to slide 10 which
is the final month I have the remaining
problem we then have is D name and D
name throws a spanner in the works in
that the stick system I just described
is not compatible with DNA and there
really is no way that you can make it
compatible and well the solute the only
solution that I can think of is you just
tell people not to do DNA the problem
with D name is that you're not like any
records underneath number one and number
two the specification says to weed out
any records that are there so there's a
lot of infrastructure there that is
going to ignore any labels under D names
so you can't use the prefix in that so
[Music]
talking to D and s people it sounds like
D name doesn't work anyway for anything
useful so maybe we can just forget about
and that's it okay um so Jacob C in the
queue after you so I'm going to run over
to him
but so to add a little context on dname
at let's encrypt we did a scan of all
the domain names of issued to and we
found that out of about 40 million
domain names only 40 of them used D name
at all so I think you know if we find a
solution that you know doesn't work with
DNA that's okay
in terms of adding the prefix records
there's two things I wanted to discuss
you know one Phillip suggested that you
know if we implemented this prefix
algorithm we wouldn't actually do rap MC
names I think that's the wrong approach
to take I think the problem with RFC
6844 is it tried to reinvent the basics
you name semantics for self and pressed
by different processing
I think whatever result we want should
you know follow normalcy name semantics
so in other words if you look at web
example.com using your recursive
resolver you're gonna get back a result
that includes following the cname chain
and you should process that in the
normal way so in other words one of the
records you'd get back would be from the
CDN or you know whatever this cnam
target is and I think that's not a
missed feature I think that's a what you
want in that the target of the cname is
you know that's the canonical name of
that domain and does have some say in
what's authorized I think there are some
interesting questions here about CD ends
setting hostile records with regards to
their customers but I think that does
come down to the relationship between EC
the ends and their customers at a higher
level I think you know there's this
question of you know okay we we took
four years to finally implement CAA and
production you know we got agreement
among CAS it's actually out there and
it's live for about two months now as of
September it's mandatory for all CA so
we're just now starting to see some of
the real world implementation so I think
it would be a mistake to fundamentally
change
discovery algorithm at this time I think
one approach we should probably take is
revise the RFC such that you know we fix
the bugs we found and it clarifies how
to interpret the errata manners and that
way the cab format can refer to a
specific standard stock that fixes those
and then independently pursue a more
radical change that's likely to take
more time to get adopted
go ahead Phil um my first question would
be what is it you want to do with this
current document yeah I'm not going to
problem with what he said people have a
use for cname I got no problem with that
I was merely replying to precisely the
set of requirements that I had seen and
I hadn't seen somebody saying that they
wanted to see name as well so yeah
following the cname for 1/2 seems
reasonable to me so I'm ok with that as
far as the document is concerned how
much processing we do only depends upon
what the algorithm we choose is so what
I wanted was the choice of algorithm
fillers and then write it up the other
choice the other proposal that Jacobs
made is use txt instead of the CAA
record I don't object to that at all but
I think there are people who might so as
far as the spec is concerned I can write
stuff up I need to know what to write do
you expect this group or the cab forum
to be the ones who are actually making
the decision of what to do I do not want
the lawyers telling ok ok I'm gonna
switch over back to Jacob
yeah so I'm the text record thing I
think somebody else may propose that I'm
actually in favor of keeping the CA a
resource record type it was a little bit
of a pain at first because some networks
reject it but support has actually been
pretty good so I think there isn't a
need to switch the text records for the
main discovery but I think there was
some discussion around doing it for that
underscore pretext in terms of like I
mentioned I actually have a draft and
I'm going to participate and actually
authorship there I think the next formal
step IETF process wise is to get that
adopted as a working group document and
we can collaboratively iterate on it and
I'll definitely agree with something
Phil said a cab forum doesn't want to be
involved in specifying this it's not
standard-setting body it's the body that
adopts these things I've been separately
involved in encouraging cab forum
members to participate or the IETF in
this process so they can have that input
and I think that was it I think there's
something else develop said I wanted to
respond to you but I forgot there
yeah I'll just +1 what Jacob said then
so if we take off so we can I've got no
problem doing the joint or the chip
thing
so we'll just meet offline and merge our
drafts or whatever okay
any input from the room hi this is Shaun
Turner um I think we shouldn't stand on
process if they're gonna implement it
and they found bugs and they wrote up a
way that they were they're doing it now
we should document it to fix what we did
wrong it would seem silly that we
wouldn't if we have this this way and
the authors seem like they're actually
agreeing with each other so all we have
to do is identify people that read it
and kid-like
agree to it in the IETF right so we have
to find like one friendly DNS person in
their mafia that will read this and tell
us that they like are kind of okay with
it right because that's the one hurdle
we're gonna have to get through but it
sounds like once they merge the thing we
should just adopt it yeah one of the
things that I screwed up when we did the
transition was I didn't think about the
transition to the errata so far very
upset with me should we go to
documenting what we want to move to or
should we also document the errata
version
I don't know that I have an opinion on
that and there's anybody else care about
documenting the errata version instead
of just saying this is what we should be
doing now just do it as a supersedes
rich sauce
Jacob yeah so my position is that we
should document the errata version
essentially not literally with the
errata text because there were some in
Felicity's in that as well
the simplification doc I have proposed
implements the errata algorithm from the
one that's actually in production but
uses much simpler language with fewer
ambiguities basically by pulling out the
the parts that try to we specify cname
so I believe pretty strongly we should
document what's in production making RFC
for that that supersedes the old one and
then move on to something that would
fundamentally change the discovery
process but it you know I think anything
that's going to fundamentally change the
discovery process should be motivated
primarily by seeing how things have
played out in production and for
instance if people say you know this
algorithm that we all know that isn't
serving me correctly I can't express
this policy that's really important for
me to express and then we'll be able to
decide okay is it worth the ecosystem
disruption to fundamentally change the
process again and then we'll have you
know a long period of transition but for
now I think we really want to lay in an
RFC that supersedes the old one
specifies the erotica hey they're in a
really clear way and maybe clears up
some questions about how to handle
errors so JEP are you basically saying
you don't see an immediate need to go to
the proposed algorithm from Phil
yeah that's correct I think you know
there have been some hypothetical cases
postpone of policies that would be hard
to express under the current proposal
but I'd like to see more real-world
usage of people trying to work with the
current system and finding ways that it
doesn't work for them I'm not the actual
chair so I can't make any sort of actual
final decisions from a peer process
point of view we actually can't reach
arter until we get one document in and
through the iesg we've got a document
there now so and it is actually through
because you push the publish so we can
actually start that recharter process
okay so this is Sean Turner um I guess I
can get them you know so I I like the
idea of a supersedes but I'm not really
super strongly and like one way or the
other if somebody has a really strong
opinion let's just go with that one and
do it like get the errata out it ought
to be pretty straightforward
pretty simple to do it shouldn't take
years to get get that version out the
door let's just do it bill do you have a
super strong opinion about this or not
okay so I think that's what I'm hearing
is we should get the new RC published
with the errata version and then
potentially start working on a draft for
fixing problems with that if if we
actually find any other is wrong do I
want to hum on that okay so that's
question number one do people understand
what we've been talking about yes
No okay there's at least one person who
thinks he does
it is there anyone who has a who
believes that the okay the solution of
we published the errata art rata version
as a new RFC which supersedes the
current one and then look at doing a
second draft do you want to proceed that
way
yes no okay so that sounds like a very
weak opinion that yes we should be doing
that sounds like most people don't care
about the problem itself okay thank you
so next thing up is shape
hello at the last meeting we adopted
their new work items and one of them was
to specify shake for pickax so here are
the two Hadees NIST has specified for
the two shakes the shakes they do have
variable output lengths
however for this purpose we we just need
to fix the output lens to 256 or 512 for
for the two shakes so that would make
thing you know symbol and conforming
with what we have been doing would be
kicks for you know what a decade or so
and currently we are we're describing Oh
Eddie's for DSA is see they say and and
of course I say and here is the the IDSA
the exact numbers will be specified by
this later that it would be a very easy
work for me to do so right now I just we
just put symbols X&Y for now and those
will be updated later and Oh Eddie is in
the same category of the signature
algorithms in the NIST sock
and this is for ECDSA and very similarly
the pacific values will be specified
later and the or information about ECDSA
specification is in the s 962 Oh
the format's and keys identifiers will
be provided in our draft and our
document later for now we just put a
placeholder in the draft
and this is something I don't know
should we specify oh I DS for both I'll
say standards or just only one of them
in some of the previous documents I saw
we specify both for PSS and because she
has one by five but that we all know the
one by five is one people are actually
using for pickets so so I don't know
what what our group want to do and any
suggestions and comments to improve our
draft please send us emails or speak to
the mic now or at any point hi she's non
Turner again um can we seriously drop
the DSA stuff I don't know anybody's
implemented the last time we went and
tried to find out if anybody said that
they used it nobody said anything I
understand it was documented and it's
like kind of in baggage that we've been
carrying around do you know of people
that really said that they needed it and
would they ever get to a microphone or
send any message to the ITF left and say
yeah I generated 10 certs with D si
signs I mean there might be people that
did it but if they didn't can we just
drop it
Eric or squirrel no hat yes please like
let us not have DSA any longer
Jim no hat yes I agree yeah but again
most of the the content actually from
from ASEAN's
at raf earlier so we did copy I just
copied it and fix the syntax
it included to be complete so it's all
listed there and then we can reevaluate
and say do we really need to include
them yeah I think the answer really
should be no so that we can make it
easier on everyone and then people won't
do silly things like use Ayana
registries to measure you know
implementations and how well they
conform to all the things listed in the
standard because people don't do them at
least that I'm aware of
hi-yah here can you go back to slide
number 4 that's the one with the BSA and
yeah so it says here that ID BSA with
shake is number 3 and can you go back
forward one slide so here it says it is
the ECDSA is also three so what they say
well they same identifier no no the why
the x and a y well sure the excellent
white tell you are different number but
is is both DSA and VCDs a number three
[Music]
because we have like that we put all the
signature in the same branch okay so the
so they're actually the same the same
prefix yeah so basically so basically
the four numbers will be with our
different numbers so what Y Z and Y
prime Z prime something like that yeah
and
Jim Shh
nohow I'm an asked a really stupid
question
since shake is a variable-length thing
is there any reason other than we don't
like doing parameters not to more
closely match the output of shake to the
length of the he that we're using we
could do parameter for the shakes but
this is an option to go consistent with
what we have done in the past but the
group want to do with the parameter lens
then it would be fine as well yeah in
that case then we have a variable length
output
so either way would be fine and what we
put here is to be consistent with what
we have done so far and that we thought
was the group wanted to do but I would
be happy to switch back to to put the
lens indicator in there and would that
will be just fine
I guess when in deshaun trainer
employing new algorithms we should go
first like this the kiss approach right
but let's just pick the ones that we
know people would want if they were
gonna drop them in if their variable
length like has anybody actually asked
for them to be variable length we fair
enough
but I mean like before we would just go
off and specify like $20 value of values
or whatever for the length of them we
probably should have somebody say that
they wanted it for us so I think that
like the the idea was that these are
going to be drop-ins okay and so closely
matched the key size so you fill it all
the way up if you're using like 128 with
a 256 bit cute so I guess maybe I lost
track of it but this only applies if
you're doing DSA right so if we just
follow up showing suggestion previously
we can nerd listen to our discussion
right we see DSA keys are fixed size so
you could just require that the that the
keys be expanded in the same size right
so um as a participant not know I'm not
an ad I propose we jettison DSA and
hence is identifiers that answer this
question and and require the pre CDSA
they'd be meant to be you know they'd be
same length but no so so there could be
could be some case when people use a
large curve and I want a faster hash and
that's why variable ends would could
could be useful in that case do uh I'm
not following
for example you use like curve like two
of 200-220 or 521 for example yeah and
you shake one one candidate wow I'm not
a jerk no I'm just saying yes but then
you should make then you then just why
not simply use shake up to the size of
the other I mean why just keep applying
it multiple times
yeah I know that that note okay - a two
visits would be best and and would be
better used
but I'm just in theory somebody you know
wants something strange like that no I I
guess what I'm suggesting I mean maybe I
just like lost track of how the heads
working these days but like otherwise
not bound to the curves no they are not
bound to the curve well I said I could
see poor unfortunate um that was the
idea but it's okay III think I think
they're bound in a hash algorithm but
not I think I think fixed land would be
just fine and but the the whole idea of
the shape variable and originally was
you know for to building the whole
symmetric crypto core in one thing
because in any case if you run a system
you need a random memo generation right
anyone that want to be efficient and in
different applications you want my one
different sizes so that's why did the
reason to design something with variable
our lands because it could be used for
many different things that does a beauty
of it but in order to utilize all those
beauties we need to have we have need to
define a new application new scenario
something big something are you know
something new in order to use that but
we are using the the popular standards
right now so is any more questions on
this presentation
one question Jim so some I understand is
that you requested me to drop this say
in the next version right that would be
my yes okay but I just check what's we
confirm okay
so the next graph is the same as syntax
and using the shake function with
signatures and Mac so right now in this
graph there's nobody's there and you
know I used the Russ houseless graph and
I just changed to the shake instead of
shell 3 and right now we have the key CS
number 1 1 by 5 and we have
ECDSA and NK Mac which is a matte
function using the shakes so the same
is for the sheiks we just explained in
the previous talk so that's a big ETS
number one version 1 by 5 and the same
thing F and Y will be provided later
and the same with is easy they say and
then for the shake instead of the H Mac
we'll just use a normal shake would have
in this specification we have a fix a
boot lens for for for the TAC and we use
the the the the shape specify in our in
the NIST FIPS 185 and it's very simple
and is efficient and that is way how to
do macking with shakes so I my
understand is that the first item will
not be there and any questions comments
and help me to make a draft better and
more useful for everybody
okay Sean Leonard so despite I guess
what the room said I think adding TSA to
shakes is okay so I'm just skeptical
that it shouldn't be there that's all I
wanted to say that it's not unanimous
that it should be out oh okay because he
here oka met he said something different
so I don't know what you would like me
to do or what a group decided would like
me to do they got into a dad thing the
essays days yes the essay goes I think
that's a pretty conclusive opinion
all right room I mean my recommendation
would be take it out now people can
always object on the list if they want
it back okay so we are going to update
it drops and from now if people have
more comments for us just send us emails
and we we would we will try to make a
draft for better
wrap up so we should be starting a
charter discussion relatively soon there
is a candidate charter which I have not
read as in my mailbox but it's not clear
exactly how soon that's going to start
Russ is going into surgery tomorrow and
he has an expected five to six week
recovery period after that so I'm not
too sure how much he's going to be
active between now and Christmas so
we'll see what happens in terms of that
but we will definitely try to get the
current documents done that should not
take any additional cycles from him as
they have all been basically pushed out
of the working group and on to the
authors and the ABS and then we'll see
what and then we'll see where we go from
there so there's any other business any
questions anyone I must ask thank you
for your time if you haven't signed blue
sheets it's complete
[Music]
so yeah
you