hey pops 8:30
everybody welcome to NBC
sorry well testing okay welcome to net
BC so first off note well should
everybody should be familiar with this
but for this particular working group
please make absolutely sure you're
familiar with it because the goal this
working group is to produce royalty free
video codec so we definitely need
everyone to pay very close attention to
the IPR rules in the note well start
blue sheets around I think we'll need
one so I'm not gonna bother with
what always takes the majority of the
ten minutes of chair time note taker we
need a note-taker volunteer very tourist
notes it doesn't have to be a every
detail just major decision points
volunteers
anyone uh on the media Co want to
volunteer for taking notes in jabber
room volunteer for taking notes we're
have to impose on someone now
Oh Nathan did thank you very much Nathan
took excellent notes last time or the
time before appreciate that we have a
jabber scribe volunteer that's much
easier just relay the room do you want
to do it since we're up here anyway and
now we have our guest co-chair thank you
very much man
all right so quick agenda Bash just
gonna spend a few minutes probably not
ten on on the status of the current
documents and then Thomas is going to
give us an update on the test document
and Steiner will give us an update on
Thor and 81 progress and comparisons
followed by Tim giving an update on
dalla 81 transforms and then Luke is
going to give us the latest chromo
prediction from luma as it's being used
in 81 any changes people want to make to
the agenda any other items to bring up
if not let's go on so quick recap of
where we are on our milestones we have a
milestone for the requirements document
that that was a workgroup last called
but um because it's being used by some
other standards body or some other
industry consortium
there may be some substantive changes to
it that we foresee coming up pretty soon
so we're holding off on the Shepherd's
right up for now
and we're waiting to see if there's
gonna be some substantive changes before
we progress it on to the is G hopefully
that'll conclude within with in November
so we're gonna update the milestone 2 to
November I hope to get that done before
the end of this month and the testing
document we're gonna update that
milestone as well because it's a not
going to be concluded anytime soon we
decided to keep it alive as a living
document while while the codec
candidates are progressing because we
expect the test methodology is going to
keep evolving so we don't want to freeze
the document pretty much early so once
we have a candidate we're comfortable
with and a testing methodology we're
comfortable with as being pretty stable
then we'll we'll move it on the chain
for the actual codec candidates we want
a single merged codec and we lack that
right now so we do not have a candidate
yet for the milestone for either the
codec spec or the reference
implementation so we lack a merged
candidate or merged codebase so you see
Tim and stun are presenting different
tidbits but not one consolidated
codebase or standard so that's that's
the glaring issue we need to deal with
his workgroup and try to bring out the
closure and Austin's going to get pushed
out to July so hopefully by then we'll
have more clarity on on how to come up
with a converged candidate and then
finally there's the milestone for
carrying this codec inside of containers
storage formats so we'll push that out
to end of 2018 because that work hasn't
even started yet
any comments on the milestones or the
proposed changes to them alright so
let's go on to first item on our agenda
Thomas so you're gonna stop us on the
muñeco yes he is can you come on over
to the queue
all right can you all hear me no here NC
this is I'm Thomas steady from Missoula
this is the idea that VC testing craft
version six was is there something
explicitly on this there's a just two
toys yeah so the testing draft has had
very few changes between this version
and the last version there's really only
two things one of the small failing
changes and changed it's almost your
little faint K is there any microphone
pick up that you can get ramped up you
one second is that better much better
thanks
okay um there's a small command-line
changes and intestine arrows so next
slide so the first one is CLI parameters
we've made some small changes to the
codecs that we test one is that we
removed a constraint for our leg and
frames from olymic died we previously
had divorced this 225 but it turned out
that was less than ideal value it
basically buffered way more frames and
we technically needed to on the encoder
so we decided to drop that out of the
command line as you can see that command
line is pasted on the bottom there we
just leave it up to the encoder to pick
the maximum reasonable value which i
think is nineteen in the current encoder
but the general idea is with the command
lines we want as many me you know as few
possible constraint we will not impose
just a minimum constraints possible at
encoder big the rest so that's in the
right direction so is that supposed to
be crossed through the lagging frames
equals 25 yes that Gesser do they do
that should be removed from the command
line
yep I pasted okay I'm in there is to
show that it was there but yes delete
that that's all
ideally I'd like to actually drop the
auto ultra studying as well
and that should be automatic but didn't
change the code basis to do that yet so
that's all second slide
slide number for a dollar problem is
that person we basically only allowed
two very slowest encoder notes to be
used for a dollar
this was the default or and for I think
two where we had a text file
configuration and for a one that killed
a CPU used equals zero and this became
increasingly problematic as you know and
I think in particular got much much
slower over time was their current
objective one vast suite of videos
that's in this testing document that
take that took who was taking upwards of
eight days to run the clips that became
impractical for testing so obviously
added an exception that allowed us to
run faster test settings under limited
so those circumstances basically if you
only compare an element to a limit and
you were just comparing a code change
that to change as a single feature
you're allowed to turn off a couple of
searches and figure the searches for
exportation and exportation types that
speeds up a lot and as long as you
specify I did this then it's a
reasonable usage this is not certainly
ideal I'm working on a better solution
for this I think a better solution will
actually involve custom you know speed
parameters to the encoder that are
better tuned to match a real usage the
one bad thing is that we by searching
less partition types and sizes we kind
of bias towards smaller partitions and
not the rectangular partitions which is
could could affect some tools in the
negative way so we're trying to find
something better but this is a stopgap
for now
and that is basically the only two
changes I've made to the document I've
not had to change the test set or to any
of the videos at all those have stayed
pretty much the same so this is Moe
virtually from the floor mic and be lazy
since there's no queue just stay up here
the the testing methodology itself
though not the infrastructure with the
testing methodology itself still
specifies that the testing should be on
the maximum compression not not any
other slower mode yeah so the there's
basically a section at the end at a
testing draft that basically says you
know different things you can test write
it so you could do like subjective tests
and you can do across codec comparisons
and there's like objective tests for
tools and that one is the one that we
allow into not used a very slow mode
basically by turning off the exportation
search oh but if you're doing like
across codec comparison you obviously
don't want to do that I mean I think I
understand why it needs to be done for
practical reasons in the infrastructure
but I I wouldn't think we want the spec
to say this is how we test ideally we
didn't have an infrastructure problem we
would test for max compression right
yeah and that's certainly a issue with
that doing this is a very highly codec
specific and implementation specific
setting so it's possible that which she
does does not belong in the testing
document and that could be a valuable
feedback okay I mean all codecs will
have knobs to adjust the compression
speed trade-off I think the it's
important for the testing document to
state that the objective comparisons
will be done at max compression
otherwise it's a pretty hard it's
another dimension another layer of curve
another dimension of curves that we have
to look at to evaluate performance
I know we've presented some of those and
they're useful Steiners
a lot of the speed complexity trade-offs
before but I think it's difficult to put
those in the testing document as
something that the candidates will be
evaluated on right at the same time so
the the one for thing is I don't want to
evaluate if I specify this I don't want
to evaluate the candidates in terms of
you know meeting the requirements
criteria on this this is purely for like
individual tools and drafts particularly
I do want to know like people I think
people later will probably present with
CPU used settings with arts ro and I
would like a way to normalize this so
that people people use the same CPU use
settings and stuff if they need it for
speed reasons but yeah this what we
could do is we could just say you know
they are not specified this in the draft
maybe say that you know you may you may
use faster speed settings as long as
you're justified it like external to the
draft basically try to be consistent
that's also a reasonable way to take it
if that's what people would prefer I can
change it
Jonathan Linux I mean it seems like with
any codec you know you know you can go
your code can go to absurdly slow right
I mean this is doing I've heard the
phrase frames per day as the speed I
mean anything could do exhaustive search
every possible bit stream to see which
one best matches you know in the extreme
keep your video in the extreme case and
that's just you can't say will use
whatever the invitation chooses to make
the slowest possible encoding and I
think there has to be some threshold of
this is just absurd we're not going to
test this because it has no practical
use okay what other people think um I'll
just know that that that absurd max
compression is what's traditionally used
in other other codec groups but uh I'm
happy to entertain more practical things
in our testing draft
[Music]
and the other strong opinions one away
to other I mean based on a current
feedback that sounds like I'd like to
specify this but made only for the a
women testing and maybe not too explicit
the exact parameters and so if anyone
but well I'll change it basically so it
allows us to do this but it doesn't
specify two parameters and seems like
the middle ground I hear three ownage x2
that let me know otherwise I'll do that
like you have no objections go ahead
okay that's what I'll do for the next
draft version that's all I have to
present so any other comments or we can
be done with this and I think we're good
thank you
all right next up ah
[Music]
okay hello everybody I have to have it
closed I think I have some please what I
have are some updates on on the Thor
College and also have some updated
charts on the performance and
compression trade-offs so this time the
for github has actually been updated it
hasn't been updated for a while so I
guess that's about time the main change
is that I've added the support for the
CDF filter through which was which has
been adopted in everyone what was I hope
did in everyone was the seen in past
version which I presented the last time
so this is what have implemented for
Thor another change is that I'm working
on faster and simpler audio proceedeth
in in authorities much faster than 81 so
when I first tried to use the audio from
from 81 the speed of Thor was roughly
haft just for the future but I think the
audio can be improved and it's much more
easy to experiment with the audio in
Thor because Thor is faster and I get
the feedback much faster and whatever I
do in Thor could be back ported into
every one as well and last time I
mentioned that I would like to get
support for the dollar entropy colder in
horror but there has been no progress on
that so just see that but that's the
first step towards emerged codec next
like this since the last meeting there
have been a few minor changes to see the
this is due to a face-to-face meeting we
had in the IOM group since the last time
there's a new skip block test what we
had before it was that we didn't signal
Anna strength for a future block if all
the coding blocks within that filter
block were skipped but the trouble with
that is that you have to de call the
entire filter block in order to know
whether all the blocks are escaped and
the Harvard people don't like that they
want to start a filtering as soon as I
can turn our coding book as soon as
possible not wait and it until the end
because they don't like the Bur for
anything so it was agreed to change that
so now the there's no signaling for the
filter block if the coding block size is
64 by 64 meaning that there's no
petitioning of that block and the
calling block is skipped that makes it
possible to signal the filter strength
just after the Skip flag for that block
that adds a slight coding overhead
because it means that there will be more
signaling and also possibly a slight
complexity increased because it also
leads to more blocks being fusion but
objectively the loss is less than 0.1
percent and subjectively I don't think
there is a great change
it could even perhaps even gain an
improvement because we get to doing more
filtering next like this and also
recently everyone has adopted support
for 128 by 128 super blocks so that also
influences how we do the Skip test CDF
still needs the signal at 64 + 64
resolution during the development of
sealed F
which was merged with the dollar-driven
to form seeded I tried different block
sizes and 64 by 64 was by far the best
size so we don't want to change that so
for a large super block 128 by once 22
single up to four presets in order to
keep the the same field the block size
the details haven't been what I decided
yet how to do this we need to still need
to investigate possible compression
impacts but the most simple thing would
be just to expand the instead of testing
for 64 over 64 blocks without
partitioning and whether it's Kip or not
just to check for 128 by 128 without
partitioning next slide so running see
deaf instead of C of F in for does give
object against just as it did in every
one I see gains around 1% or a half a
percent 2.2 percent I'll show the
results on a separate slide shortly we
see quite large gains for chroma of the
4% I'm not quite sure why we didn't see
again that high in in everyone so I
think I'll investigate that see that
does add more complexity or we will see
a path though it's it's more processing
but that's not unexpected I also tried
running CF on top of C death that gives
not much gain which is not surprising
since CDF is basically a superset of C
of F but I noted that if I greatly
simplified the CDF I do see a def just
give gains and actually it turns out
that
see a deaf Regan's almost all of the
loss if I simplify the audio but having
to an extra an extra pass or filtering I
think that adds a risk of over filtering
and also it adds buffer requirements so
it's sealed s still attractive for a
fast real-time encoder currently it's a
good way to speed up for what I I think
that it's much better I'd rather to do
work on the sea deaf audio I think it
might be hard to make it as fast as to
see a deaf are they all but it should be
possible to come close without you to
big losses next like this another change
since the last meeting is in a VA one we
have three filters applied in cascades D
blocking see death and then loop
restoration and that adds a lot of
buffer requirements and again hardware
people don't like that so there was a
new proposal from arm to an Android
contribution until Google and Mozilla to
reduce the buffer requirements without
stat there's an either a minimum of 30
lines of banned buffers but with this
new proposal it's possible to reduce
that choose 16 lines next slide please
so the basic idea is to some normative
changes and non normative changes and
non normatively
possible to do some shifting of the CDL
or filtering but the main normative
change is that when loop restoration
looks outside the super block that was
produced by C death it will roll it will
really deep blocked output instead
the CDF outfit and that breaks the
dependency between CDF and Luke
restoration so the changes that has that
have been proposed requires no normative
changes to see that it's mostly in loot
restoration and the changes have no
impact on the other compressed yets
results and it makes the buff line
buffer requirements for everyone the
same as for VP 916 lines even though we
have more filled filters in every one
and this is moving towards adoption
along with new restoration
it hasn't formally be adopted yet but it
will next slide so a bit more on the
encoder complexity on see death as I
mentioned I was working on simplifying
the audio and I think that can be
improved even more just as a test how
far I could get I try to restrict the 50
to do no block level singling and when I
do that I still get gains objective gain
similar to see lbf but I think in that
case the subjective gains are still much
better than sealed F because we will get
the the directional part of C death so
in that case the encoder will just have
to select the optimal strength for the
entire frame but that's a quite small
search space so and some other
simplifications that I have tried which
work well is to select the damping used
in the filter core based on the frame QP
and I've also tried to decide the number
of bits to use per block based on the
frame QP and sorry based on the bitrate
and friend pipe and I think that it
still many ways to improve the CDF audio
the the reason why I think it's
important to have a good are the oval
see that is that in a practical and
coders Edith can probably replace some
of the more complex tools in particular
in a the warm maybe not replace but just
help yeah well not replacements Tannen
but if you want to do every time encoder
you you probably wants you can't use all
the tools it's simply too complex next
slide please
so these are the results that I got for
adding see death in for heron comparing
just doing D blocking and with the deep
locking plus C death and in the low
complexity case is now a 6.2 percent and
the chrome app is not even better if I
look at the see ie de number it's
actually ten point three percent which
is I think it's quite impressive even in
the harder the compression is it's a six
point three and in the high efficiency
it's still five point two percent and
three point one percent in the low that
I and highly lay configurations so
that's that's not bad I think next slide
please
and if we compare this with Z of the F
so the these are the gains that we get
from replacing C of F with C death this
ee i ee number is 2.2 percent in the low
complexity low today configuration
manager ops 21.1% in the high efficiency
a high delay configuration so it's not a
huge difference but the main reason to
add C that is to improve the actual
visual quality and and in every one we
did some subjective tests
comparing see a path with Edith and even
though the change was less than 1% in in
every one people could still tell the
difference so that probably points
towards a real difference of at least
five percent next slide this mo from for
Mike again virtual for Mike a question
on the the the the gains for chroma look
like about three to four times the gains
over all right clue I as I'm serious
what I would like to investigate here is
whether there could be an impose in the
encoder it could be probably not
normative things that would have to be
fixed but it could be some kind of bug
that see that is able to partially
correct but I don't really know it's an
interesting results what we could always
hope it is that bug and and it will get
further gains Morgan Morgan for for mark
again
so before you finish on CDF I want to
raise one issue related to the
requirements document that we expect
some substantive changes in I think one
of them may be related to support of
four to two chroma format video and I
believe CDF is one of the barriers to
that because the direction search does
not support rectangular blocks is there
any plan to address that in any way so
how it currently works is that in the
case of 42 we'd still do the filtering
as normal for the luma plane but the
filtering is disabled for chroma label
all filtering or disable Direction
search only
it's completely disabled I think so
there are ways to address that like
skipping the directional part and
basically doing cell death at him as a
comment yeah Terry vary from forearm the
the directional search has only ever
done on luma so what normally happens is
the chroma uses the direction that luma
found when it to orient its filters and
since there isn't a direct
correspondence between the directions we
have a luma and the directions we have
in chroma when you squeeze the chroma
blocks into a rectangle then we disable
the filter sorry Tim your little fan at
the end so what do you do for karma
blocks then just disable the filter
disable the directions are should
totally simple the filter completely the
whole filter completely because you
can't disable the direction searches
that's only ever done on Loula what you
could do is just assume a fixed
direction which is what Steiner was
saying and and just always filter with
that direction and that would be
essentially like Co PF yeah also lucious
but currently I don't think in those
solutions any of those solutions are
going to into a v1 and it might be might
be because people don't care I'm sure
how important it is to have good
performance for 42 well I mean like I
said I think there there may be some
there may be some changes to the
requirements to make 42 more prominently
supported okay now well it is order but
the compression will surface lightly
okay
last time I had some graphs showing the
compression and complexity trade-offs so
if you want and I have updated those I
also had some graphs showing comparison
between the different codecs and I
haven't opted those since the difference
in Thor and isn't that big it's just 1%
so what I'm going to show are the
compression speed relationships using
our compressed yet with the objective 1
post test set and since ITF 99 there's
an improvement in every one of about 5%
and the encoder runs at roughly half the
speed I've been using the loaded a
configuration and the BDR anchor is a
the one as it was in July last year
which is roughly equivalent to vp9 and
next slide please so starting in July
last year at zero of the compression the
be dynamic goes down which is good so at
the last meeting we had the VBR gain of
about 20 percent and that is now about
25 cents and the graph has been steadily
dropping with the additions of new tools
in every one and there are still some
tools left not yet enabled so I expect
this to drop slightly more so we'll see
next slide please
and this is the complexity history note
here that the y axis is logarithmic and
the y axis is the frames per minute not
they not seconds but minutes it's it
started at around 15 last year in July
and is now round one frame a minute
so there's a change of the factor of 15
and it seems to be flattening somewhat
but again this is a logarithmic scale on
the y-axis I think this shows that the
compression gains that we haven't seen
in anyone don't come for free it has a
big cost so if we compare vp9 with
everyone I think currently everyone is
basically a continuation of vp9
if you plot it with difference
complexity settings so you have a big
toolbox and as you add more tools to the
codec you get compression gains but you
also get that speed penalty and the
question remains whether that 2 vols box
is a better tool box not just a larger
so we could replace tools in Li benign
whether simply better tools and get
better performance with the same
complexity I'm not sure but if if
everyone gets set opted and used as a
[Music]
standard people will work on this for
years and and it will probably eat at
night but we can't prove that yet ok
this is what I had just give a quick
thumb in the air of what the complexity
is absolutely right now relative history
but absolutely the vp9 roughly ah
certainly more than 100 times I guess
yeah so I guess it's a crystalline so it
will probably it hasn't been a great
focus to speed up everyone so that will
probably get more focused as the actual
tools are finalized but yeah right
the reference and gallery isn't that
practical yeah we can't simply I think
the the specification says that we're
supposed to run 4k sequences and bit but
we can't practically do that now so
nobody has been presenting the test
results according to the specs actually
because it's simply too slow and so just
to know that the those numbers were for
the encoder and were roughly what the
decoders yeah
the decoder speed is roughly 1/4 since
July 2016 it's about 4 X's complex is
vp9 four times the complexity I think
it's closer to 16 times but I think the
main reason for that is there's still
some simsim de optimizations lacking in
vp9 so I think four times is a more
accurate number thank you thank you
[Music]
all right stand in the pink box
I'm Tim Terry berry I'd be presenting
work on the dollar transform design this
is joint work with Nathan eggy and Monty
so although I got this stuff started a
few years ago those two have really been
doing the bulk of the work lately so I
think most of the credit of the recent
developments goes to them next slide um
I'm going to talk a little bit about
what our goals were in designing
transforms for dello one should be
pretty non-controversial as we wanted an
exact integer implementation it's just
the way that video codecs have worked
ever since 264 there's lots of iterative
prediction with unstable filters so you
want an exact specified implementation
so that all all decoders agree and
there's no drift um we also wanted to be
able to support many different
variations of the transforms so low bit
depth hide the depth both square and
rectangular discrete cosine transforms
discrete sine transforms etc we also
wanted high accuracy so this is this is
2017 as you just heard we can have lots
of complexity so in times past people
were afraid of having multiplies and
while we'd like as few multiplies as
possible we can have some multiplies in
there if it gives us more accurate
transforms that said we want to keep
software complexity as low as possible
in particular paying attention to how
things would be implemented in Cindy and
at the same time we want to have
reasonable hardware complexity which
means we need low latency for small
transform sizes and for all these
variations we want to keep transform
reuse and embedded designs in mind so
that stuff will come I'll come along as
you go through some of the slides here
next slide um so just just to start us
off this is the the four point discrete
cosine transform for each
sixty-four it is very low complexity so
you can implement this with 8 ads and
two shifts it has a few drawbacks one of
them is that that it is a non-uniform
scale transform so the coefficients that
you get out even though the discrete
cosine is this unit very transform where
all the basis functions have the same
magnitude of 1.0 this gives you out
coefficients that have different skills
that you then have to multiply by and
that usually gets absorbed into the the
quantization step so you know say oh
we're saving one multiply but in reality
in in the way encoders are designed
today we do rate distortion optimization
with several different possible
quantization levels for all the
different coefficients so you actually
need to do several multiplies in there
in order to get a consistent estimate of
distortion that backs out this scaling
factor and that those extra multiplies
get multiplied by the number of
different options that you search in the
encoder which is we just saw you know
this can be quite a lot one other thing
is is that when you start having larger
and larger transforms so this is only a
four point transform you know you start
going up to say 64 point transforms you
actually need a very large table of
constants for all these these scale
factors so we added the new goal that we
wanted to have uniform scaling for all
of our transforms and you know that that
will cost you four multiplies in this
design but as we go to larger and larger
sizes it turns out you can achieve this
with much less than one multiply for
coefficient all right next slide so this
is the vp9
four-point discrete cosine transform and
I may pick on vp9 a little bit today
just it's not because I think the vp9
design is bad but it's actually a fairly
standard textbook design for transforms
but I think we can do a little bit
better and so I want to talk about some
of the improvements we've made relative
to vp9
just because vp9 transforms are the ones
that I know the best so this is the
4-point DCT it actually has six
multiplies they are full 32-bit products
so if you look at the bottom there we
were actually taking two of these
products and adding them together so we
need the full 32-bit result in order to
do that and then it additionally has
eight adds two of those happen at 32
bits and then four shifts all right next
slide so there are a few avenues for
improvement
one is is simplifying the multiplies so
if you looked at the 264 design like we
could just scale the outputs of those
that transform then it would only cost
four multiplies instead of six
but the 264 design is not a real DCT
it's only an approximation to a DCT so
it would be a little bit less accurate
but we're going to see in a bit we can
actually do just as well with an
accurate transform so the other approach
for improving things is has to do with
scaling so the vp9 DCT adds this factor
of a square root of 2 relative to a
unitary transform um and in fact it
turns out as you make the transform
larger and larger each time you double
the size of the transform it adds an
additional factor of of the square root
of 2 so this is this is sort of okay if
you take the log of the width on the low
that the height and that comes out to be
even then you can just correct the thing
with a shift but now we want to use
rectangular transforms like an 8 by 4
transform or something along that and
now this scale factor becomes odd and so
we can't correct it with a shift we
actually have to correct it by doing one
multiply for coefficient in order to get
something that matches the same same
scale as all of our quantizers all right
slide so where does this scaling
actually come from structurally next
slide
um this is sort of the the textbook
factorization of a type two discrete
cosine transform so it starts out with
this stage here on the left
we're basically computing sums and
differences of pairs of pixels sometimes
called plus 1 minus 1 butterflies or
something to that effect and then after
that you can split the thing into a
smaller discrete cosine transform and a
smaller discrete sine transform alright
slide so these butterflies here at the
beginning are our nonunitary like if you
you compute equivalent basis functions
for that and say what's the magnitude of
the basis function it's 1 squared plus 1
squared is is square root of that is the
square root of 2 right so that's where
that factor comes from next slide and
because this is recursive there's
another one inside there and as you as
you expand the transform by a factor of
2 each time you get an additional one of
these these factors of a square root of
2 and you also wind up having to do
something in the discrete sine transform
that would is also expansion area like
this um if you want the scales to be
uniform all right next slide so we'd
like to get rid of this extra scaling so
that we don't have all these extra
multiplies in our rectangular transforms
so one way we can do that is we can use
multiplies and in fact if you go back
and look at vp9 s for point DCT they
actually already do this so I don't if
you flip back to the slide 4 so this
step up here um is actually would be the
same thing as a plus 1 minus 1 butterfly
but then it has scaled the outputs out
after that so that they match the
discrete sine transform at the bottom
there so that's that's one way to
correct this going
but that only got rid of it out of one
stage and we're getting a set of these
on at every stage so that winds up being
kind of expensive so another approach is
we can restrict ourselves to only using
shifts and ads and use asymmetric
scaling I'll describe what I mean by
that in the next few slides so we have
there are basically two different
options the the construct at the top
there computes a sum and difference
where the the output of the second
component is have compared to what you
would normally get and then the next one
computes a sum and difference where the
output of the first the first output is
half - compared to normally get and as
you see you can do this with with just
by adding one shift in between the the
two the two additions or subtractions so
what happens is instead of instead of
doing an addition and subtraction and
having both of the scales increased by a
factor of square root of two what we're
actually doing is increasing one by a
square root of two and decreasing the
other by a factor of square root of two
so they become asymmetric but overall
you know the scaling is unity so like
the determinant of this this transform
as a whole is still 1 and then we can
cancel out this asymmetry in subsequent
steps so next slide and you do that we
use constructs like this so the first
one there computes a sum and difference
where it halves the second input and
then the second one does the same thing
except it has the first input so these
these kinds of constructs can can cancel
out the asymmetry from the previous
steps so next slide we'd also like as I
said to simplify the multiplies so all
of these multiplies come from plane
rotations between two variables so
basically in all of our transform
factorizations we've decomposed it into
a series of these plane rotations where
we're taking two values and we are
rotating them by some amount so we can
actually
you know instead of doing that as as a
matrix multiply here we have four
multiplies in two additions we can get
rid of one multiply and instead add an
addition by using a construct like that
at the bottom here all right next slide
so we can actually also arbitrarily
scale the inputs and outputs of these
rotations so just multiplying through um
you can instead derive a series of steps
which which looks like this and the
important thing to note is that that all
of the all of the complex stuff there is
basically just reduces down to a
constant and so it's it's x0 minus a
constant times x1 x1 minus a constant
times p0 and then p0 minus a constant
times y1 so this becomes very simple and
and can let us absorb scalings in the
multiplies as well all right next slide
so the advantages of doing this we get
25% fewer multiplies in general
multiplies are much more expensive than
additions in in software as well as
hardware they all have this structure of
X plus a constant times y so when we do
that in fixed point it's going to be X
plus a constant times y plus a rounding
offset and then then we're going to
shift off that you know shifted to the
rights and only take the high part of
that multiplier output so the advantage
of doing this is that all of our 16 bits
in D stays in 16 bits so we don't
actually need to compute full 32-bit
products we only need the top half so if
we actually had to go compute a full
32-bit product we could only do that in
with half the throughput in a fixed size
Sindhi register so ssse3 and neon
actually both have instructions for
doing exactly this kind of multiply so
it's a single instruction that will do
the multiply add the rounding offset and
shift the product over to the right
and so none of that has to has to expand
out to a full 32 bits so that whole
thing fits in in 16 bits next slide
so putting all those things together we
get a transform like this so we start
off instead of having plus 1 minus 1
butterflies we have these these
asymmetric scaling steps we use both
types so that we get scaled outputs of
in different directions that we then
cancel in the next step and then we have
us our rotation down there at the bottom
gets replaced by one of these scaled
rotations using only 3 multiplies so we
have one more addition and three more
multiplies than then the the h.264
transform but we have uniform scale all
right next slide the other thing if you
counted very carefully there are 3-1
halves on the board our unless on the
slide but I only say two shifts at the
top and that's because two of them are
actually the same value so as you as you
get larger and larger transforms you'll
also be able to share more and more of
these shifts between the stages like
this and that's just because of the way
that we arrange them all right next
slide um
so expanding that out we can do an
8-point DCT next slide or 16-point DCT
and that keeps going up to 64 points I
yeah it probably would have taken a few
hours to make the drawings for that so I
didn't do that but took a few hours to
make that one for these but the other
other point to make is these things do
have embedded structure so both the
endpoint DCT and the endpoint discrete
Coast are discrete sine transform are
embedded inside a discrete cosine
transform that is 4 times larger so that
embedding actually skips a
because of the asymmetries so if you
only go up one level then then we're
actually taking asymmetric inputs and so
it's not exactly the transform you need
basically need two sets of right yes
yeah you need everything from there yeah
you even set in an odd set essentially
all right next slide so a few notes on
accuracy so all of these these right
shifts and multiplies introduce rounding
errors we want to keep those as small as
possible so we can the the way we go
about this is that we shift up the input
by some number of bits before we do any
of the transform and then we do the full
four transform quantize code D quantize
inverse transform and then on the other
end when we finally get down to pixels
we ship down the output again so how
much do you shift while we found
diminishing returns at about four bits
and that was enough to make all of the
discrete cosine transforms match a
double precision floating point
implementation after rounding to the
nearest pixel value so with just a four
bit up shift we get the error down below
one half of a pixel step for 8-bit input
all right is that open for Micah is that
compared to a the same approximation or
compared to a full full DCT implemented
in double floating-point that's that's a
full you know bog standard DCT you know
not any much straight from the formula
giant matrix multiply implementation
that's good
what about what um so the error winds up
being the same for higher improvements
and go to the next slide
I'll talk about that and something
uncouple sides yeah that's it basically
the the accuracy is less important for
higher bit depths because what you
actually care about is accuracy relative
to your quantizer and so higher bit
depths use higher quantizers to get
similar bit rates so we shift up less
for higher bit depths on basically 10
bits is a two bit shift in twelve bits
we have no that shifts so it injects a
little bit more noise but it doesn't
matter but as a result we can use the
same transforms for all bit depths all
right you know from the floor again so I
think that also means you can use the
same Sindhi one right for all the input
that's that's that's correct you can use
the exact same implementation that's
nice alright go back yeah next slide so
how does this compare with vp9 so vp9
also shifts up the inputs but by not as
many as four bits and then it shifts
down the outputs by more than four bits
and actually has to do it sometimes in
between row and column transforms too
and that's because they have this extra
factor of a square root of two that that
they grow by every every transform size
so what's actually happening is is the
scale these vp9 coefficients grows as
the transform progresses so any rounding
errors that you introduced early in the
process get magnified as that scaling
increases
whereas in dala all the stages have the
same scale so all of the rounding errors
are injected at the same level and they
do accumulate but we don't magnify them
all right next slide that's the one we
just did
so another important point to talk about
is the difference between scaling and
dynamic range so everything here has has
orthonormal or unitary scaling right so
the magnitude of the basis functions is
1.0 but the dynamic range of the output
still increases so the dynamic range
here I mean the minimum or maximum
output values you can actually have so
all of your unitary transforms are
essentially n dimensional rotations and
you can think of the input as a big
n-dimensional box and the length of the
diagonal of that box is going to be
longer than the length of any of the
edges so as you rotate it you can get
larger values than you started with um
in fact it's by a factor of square root
of 2 every time and doubles which you
know is in addition to the scaling that
vp9 does and in it they're not the same
scaling so we still have this factor of
square root of 2 and the size of our
coefficients but that's okay because the
l2 norm is still preserved by the
transform so the question you might ask
is how big can the outputs actually be
next slide so with a 4-bit upshift all
the transforms with 64 pixels or less
fit in 16 bits so that's a 9 bit
residual 4 bit up shift and then 3 bits
of dynamic range expansion which is half
a bit for each of the powers of 2 and 64
so that includes your four by four or
four eight eight by four eight by eight
four by sixteen and sixteen by for all
of the column transforms all the way up
to 64 point also fit in sixteen bits so
that means that that 16 bits is the
maximum size that you need for a
hardware transpose buffer so in between
row and column stages the hardware has
to buffer the coefficients so it can
transpose them which is a fairly
significant gate cost so being able to
keep that small as nice um it also means
that when you're writing Cindy you can
write a Cindy for the row transforms and
it used to be simply for the column
transforms and it all fits in 16 bits
and for all sizes and then you can have
a separate version once things start
going large at the 16 bits
so comparing to vp9 they have larger
intermediaries in the transforms but
they always shift their final
coefficients down to fit in 16bits so we
think this is a Miss optimization it's
it's actually just as easy to do this
shift down and pack while you're doing
quantization so we we have not tried to
do this extra shift at the end
it also helps avoid double rounding and
and simplifies rate distortion
optimizations is you don't have to have
any special cases for different scale
factors depending on your block size all
right slide a quick question move from
floor mic again so you don't you don't
have a fixed shift between the row and
column stages you you accumulate a
certain number of pixels total pixels
first before you do your shift um so we
don't have a shift between the row and
column stages at all who would if you
have bigger than than a 64 pixel so if
you have bigger than 64 pixel then we
start going to wider Cindy once once you
once the values start exceeding 60
minutes so you just go bigger than
16-bit intermediates yeah well I would
never shift down we never shift down
okay I mean you can shift down after you
quantize right because when you quantize
you're gonna have the same values you
would have had regardless of what your
shift was but yeah I mean that the point
is you're gonna have to go you're gonna
have to go up to 32 bits in the
transforms at some stage um because
we've eliminated this extra scaling we
do that at a later stage than vp9 does
and also because we don't do extra of
shifting for high bit depth we do it at
a later stage in the vp9 dose um so we
can keep you in 16 bits longer um but
yeah I mean at some point you do have to
go to go up to 32 bits and that's true
both in vp9 in and in us you know for
the larger transforms alright so a few
notes on reversibility so when you have
steps of this general form where you
take a variable and you add to that
variable sum function on all the
variables except the one you're adding
to um that's called a lifting step there
can be an
whirring like that that function could
be arbitrary it doesn't have to be
linear like as has no special properties
at all but because the function is not a
very is not a function of the variable
you're modifying it's exactly reversible
right so on on the the decoder side you
can just subtract off that function and
get exactly the value that you started
with what that means is we can make
inverse transform by just reversing all
the steps of our forward transform and
so it turns out that all of the steps
that I have described so far that we use
to build our transforms happen to be
lifting steps all right so so why is
this good why would you want to do this
so we really wanted reversibility in
dala because we used lapping instead of
a deblocking filter so do blocking
filters have this nice property that
they're low-pass on so they tend to blur
out details over consecutive frames um
whereas on the other hand forward and
inverse lapping are matched so any any
details that you have um do not get
blurred out by by applying the the
lapping filter they instead just get
shifted around and when you apply the
opposite of the lapping filter then they
get restored so if those two are not
exactly matched then you'll build up
these rounding errors over multiple
frames and this is the same problem of
you know we essentially have an unstable
filter so because we have an exact
integer specification of our transforms
on you know there you would never get
encode or decode or mismatch but it
would cost bits to correct these
rounding errors in the encoder so that
was bad all right
next slide um do we actually need
perfect reversibility um so it seems to
help
compared to transforms that don't have
it we've seen some small coding gain
improvements but it's probably not
required but we get it basically for
free from from the structure of our
design we don't actually have it in dal
anymore so when you do this 4-bit up
shift and then do the transform and into
the 4-bit down shift that down shift is
not
reversible so that breaks it you can
restore it by using twelve that
references even if you have eight put
input data basically just avoiding the
down shift down to two by four bits at
the end and there's a nice blog post
there by Monty that that goes through
and shows you what the this error
buildup looks like and what happens when
you switch to twelve the references and
it essentially goes away but it turned
out also that just using CL PF from Thor
or the da lady ringing filter solves the
problem by adding essentially one of
these low-pass filters back that that we
didn't have an art deblocking filter um
so that prevents these errors from
building up right next slide Moses from
the for Mike again so this is the
implementation in dala that is not
reversible because they downshift what
about a v1 um so so a v1 also has the
this four bit up shift in four bit down
shifts so it's also not exactly
reversible so all if you use twelve
internal bit-depth will you get the
invertibility right so and also to be
clear I'm talking about invertibility
between going from coefficients to
pixels back to coefficients right which
is the step we needed for the laughing
filter on so you still have
invertibility in the sense of going from
pixels to coefficients back to pixels
right yeah so where I was going with it
is if you had a skipping skipping the
quantizers then you could do lossless
coding with the real transform instead
of a instead of the current four point
right transform so that first gains
that's actually something we tried back
in vp9 with an early version of these
transforms um and I think just replacing
the the four point Walsh Hadamard
transform that they use with a four
point DCT was about 25% worse in terms
of the lossless bitrate so I don't know
if if you allowed using larger transform
sizes if you you know instead of just
fixing everything down an adaptive are
do over write that the transform size
you may be able to do slightly better
than that but but just doing a straight
swap of four point oct.4 we saw we saw
the same thing with h.264 high profile
somebody
finally implemented high profile and
switched everything to 8x8 you see loss
but if they intelligently switch between
four by four and eight by eight there's
usually considerable gain so maybe some
adding some heuristics to optimize that
may end up with a pretty good lossless
codec yeah alright Exide so the other
other nice feature of reversibility is
the effect it has on dynamic range right
so as we said the transform coefficient
values are larger than your pixel values
because your forward transform expands
the dynamic range your inverse transform
is also an n-dimensional rotation so how
do we know that it doesn't expand
dynamic range right like if I have two
coefficients X 0 and X 1 and they both
just barely fit in 16 bits how do I know
that X 0 plus X 1 won't overflow and the
answer is is because the transform is
reversible so all the values that I
compute in my inverse are going to be
the same as in my forward transform you
know plus or minus any quantization
error I've introduced so this means that
I'm only guaranteed to avoid overflows
if the coefficients come as the result
of transforming pixels so if I decode
random garbage I might get random
overflows um but we can just define that
that you know those cases aren't our
undefined behavior right we don't I
don't think anybody actually cares about
the quality of decoding random garbage
that's that's the same approach 264 took
so one note about discrete sine
transforms there are two types that we
care about type 4 and type 7 so for
inter predictions residuals the the
prediction error you get is asymmetric
so the error close to the edges you're
predicting from is much smaller than the
error far away from those edges which
means you want an asymmetric transform
to code them then if you say ok what's
the optimal transform to use it winds up
being this type 7 DST and get that by
taking the a linearly increasing
correlation metrics
and and taking the limit as the
correlation approaches one and solving
the eigen system and say what do you get
the type seven DST pops out
so type seven DST factorizations are
much nastier than the type fours which
are the ones that we have embedded
inside of our DCT so the type 4 is there
at the top and the type 7 is this thing
down here and the real problem is this n
plus 1/2 thing inside your trig
functions which means what this actually
is is is a trig transform embedded
inside of a 2n plus 1 sighs fast Fourier
transform and so pulling that out of
there and still retaining a fast
algorithm is a bit Messier since it's
not a power of two so next slide type
four transforms turned out to be almost
as good in there are already embedded
inside of all of our DC T's but our
current approach is that we use type
sevens for the very small ones currently
only four point eight eight fight and
then use the embedded type force for all
of the larger D STS so the small ones
are the factorizations don't get that
bad and it turns out to be where you can
get at least some gains by using the
correct DSD side so comparing overall
complexity the first three columns there
are dollar TX on the next three columns
our TX mg which is sort of the the AV 1
extension of the vp9 transforms to
handle all these things like rectangular
transforms in and unify hide the depth
and load that depth etc so we generally
have a few more ads but not that many
more ads you can see like for the 32
point DCT it's 6.2 versus 6.0 but we
have far fewer multiplies per
coefficient right again for that DCT 2.7
versus 4.1 so we actually can wind up
with with 39 percent fewer
applause I think for the 32-point DST we
actually implemented the the Cindy for
the eight-point DCT and directly
compared that to the existing Cindy for
for the Avon transforms and it was
benchmarked at 26.2 percent faster and
that's mostly result of using using
fewer multiplies and using cheaper
multiplies right so none of our
multiplies have to go up to a full
32-bit product and we don't have to do
any 32-bit editions so we're able to get
higher Cindy throughput you know say
just a small note for the discrete sine
transform we're using the type 7 while
txm G's is there's only using a type 4 @
for the 8 point discrete sine transform
which is why ours is a bit more complex
on particularly on the additions and
that's just a result of the type 7
factorization is is not as good alright
so a few hardware considerations inter
prediction requires reconstructed pixels
from your neighboring blocks so you
think about it this serializes the
reconstruction of those blocks including
the inverse transform part of that
reconstruction which is a particular
problem for encoders and the decoders
you can sort of start the transforms
early and it only serializes adding the
residuals but on the encoder side you
need to know what pixels to transform so
that that part becomes completely serial
unfortunately when we do our 3 multiply
rotations we those multiplies are all
changed consecutively like each one
depends on the output of the previous
one which winds up being a bottleneck
for small transform sizes for hardware
alright next slide so just for the
4-point DCT and DST we've replaced them
with transforms that are not perfectly
reversible and not lifting based but we
basically replace the three block three
multiply block with a four multiplier
it's just like the matrix multiply so
all the multiplies proceed in parallel
but we still only use the top half of
that
multiply output so we still get full
Sindhi throughput and then for the DST
we use a custom factorization that uses
two five parallel multiplies so I said
these are not exactly reversible but
they do solve the hardware latency
problem Exide so additional
consideration most hardware is already
multi standard and includes vp9 in all
the vp9 transforms and so they dedicate
a lot of gates to having lots of
parallel multiplies so we can replace a
bunch of the serial multiplies in our
rotations with these parallel multiplies
without introducing any additional
multiplies and so anything that anything
that's of the form you know x0 plus a
times X 1 u 0 plus B times u 0 and then
y1 plus a times x1 ruies have this ABA
structure for the constants we can
replace with this little more gnarly
looking thing on the right but if you
reduce it down it's 1 addition 3
multiplies that all happen in parallel
and then 2 more additions so it's the
same number of operations but the
multiplies can happen in parallel so
this is again no longer exactly
reversible so we're still experimenting
to see what impact that has on accuracy
and making sure it doesn't introduce any
new potential overflows that would
prevent us from from keeping our 17 16
bits so that's the everything on the the
design of our transforms I guess anybody
have any questions they can through most
of Mo's during the presentation so Moses
and Florida had one more final question
kind of a broad one so these look like
they compare these transforms look quite
they compare very favorably to vp9 and
av1 have you looked at Thor which is
basically a chibi see if you look the
comparisons to the Thor transforms so
the HTPC transforms um so so we haven't
done direct comparisons at least in
terms of for example coding performance
um in terms of complexity like I
they if I understand correctly the Thor
Tramp storms are basically giant matrix
multiplies um and and so you know that
you can get away with that for very
small transforms but as they get much
larger I think that this will wind up
being significantly faster
right okay about 15 minutes behind Luke
you can use the rest of the time if you
want because I think we technically have
the room until 11:30 but if you want to
speed up 11 that was 11:30 the next
session starts alright so Luke I got a
five minutes if you can I suspect you
can actually go to about 11:15 because
the new chairs won't need a whole
half-hour to set up so okay thank you so
so look just try to go quick on whatever
you can there can you hear me again
alright so you have the slides up for my
presentation can you see them no I can't
see them almost slide one okay I can see
them though so yeah I'm gonna present an
update to the CFL Draft for VC so if we
go to the first slide chroma from luma
is essentially an intra prediction tool
so it has no dependencies on other
frames it is only available to chroma
planes and it basically works by
predicting chroma pixels using
coincident reconstructed luma pixels so
let's go to the next slide to see the
difference from what we proposed before
so prior proposal was on a dowel
implementation so now we've changed that
to reflect what was proposed for a v1
most significant changes that we no
longer rely on pvq so prediction is now
done in the spatial domain we consider
the only the AC contribution of
reconstructed pixels I'll talk about
that a bit later but that is similar to
what was happening before in the pvq
version of CFL we use the existing DC
pred so DC prediction for the chroma DC
contribution this is already available
in a v1 there's already fast
implementations
it requires no signaling and it is more
precise than what is always used before
so that's also very interesting so going
on to the next slide so the differences
we can talk about maybe Dola
and Thor which are you know codecs that
people know here I already said before
we went away from frequency and we're
now going for the spatial domain for
prediction the Thor implementation is
implied in the signaling the doubt
implementation use the pvq gain and the
sign bit to send the information we send
the information explicitly using joint
signs and an index value the activation
mechanism was a threshold for Thor it
was also signaled in doubt we have a
special UV only mode in a v1 so anyone
has separate prediction modes for intra
and intra luma and intra chroma so we
take advantage of that to have this UV
only mode called CFL pred we do encoder
instead of doing encoder model fitting
we will do a rate constraint search and
we do know a decoder model fitting since
the information in signal in the bits
tree moving on to the flow of the
operations we see that if subsampling is
used as though if chroma subsampling is
used well the luma surface will not be
the same as the chroma surface so we
must do a luma subsampling that is
equivalent to the chroma subsampling
that's being done we subtract away the
average this gives us the AC
contribution in the spatial domain and
this is usually on a chroma transform
size block then we'll decode the signals
scaling factors from the bit stream and
we'll multiply that these are in q3
precision but then once we multiply that
goes down to q0 and we add in the DC
pred the chroma DC pred to that value
and that gives us our final prediction
so if we look at the codebook that we
end up with on the next slide oh okay
nevermind oh that's good okay
so alright so basically why do we go
with the chroma DC pred is that when we
use the AC contribution this each
contribution is zero mean which means
that it sums to zero
and doing so simplifies the linear
regression equation for beta which makes
it the average of the Karma reference
pixels and the DC pred is a very good
predictor of that as it tries to predict
it using the neighboring pixels that are
adjacent to the above and left borders
of the block and it requires no
signaling so we don't have to signal the
beta value so alpha will be signaled but
beta won't moving on to the next slide
we have the scaling code book so
basically this shows you when we do the
search what happens so we start in the
middle of this grid and we can change
the scaling factor for chroma correction
with a chroma CR and chroma C B and we
move from negative to positive and you
can see all the different tones that you
can get this of course is only a subset
of the codebook we have it is goes from
minus 2 to 2 in q3 so that it goes up in
steps of 1 8 0 0 is not allowed as it is
DC pred we pick our value using a rate
constraint search as I said before since
we are signalling the Alpha value the
when we do we can't use a liner
regression because that value won't be
our D optimal so what we do instead is
we do the same thing as any other
parameter in the encoder that requires
rate is that we take the weighted rate
and add that to the distortion value and
pick the the parameter that minimizes
that and that gets signal to do decoder
the next slide will explain how we go
about signaling lists so we will join
both times so there's gonna be 2 scaling
parameters one for CRN one for CB so we
joined them together a sign can either
be 0 negative or positive and since 0 0
isn't allowed because that's DC pred we
have eight values which we sent to our
multi symbol encoder as an eight value
symbol now for each non zero scaling
factor we will send a value excluding
zero but all the way to 2 inclusively
and this again with a step of 1/8 this
gives us 16 values for our multi symbol
and this actually maxes out what
Multi symbol entropy coding can give us
which is a 16 value CDF going on to the
next slide we can see results from our
analyzer there's a link you can click
there sadly it got moved behind the
image you can see the distribution of
how many times modes get used so these
are UV modes that in a v1 we can see
that there's about 44% of the time DC
prêt will get picked but a CFL comes in
at about 17% we observe it between 15
and 20% in different sequences for a v1
as you can see the other contender modes
or best motors still slightly below so
we see that actually performs other
chroma modes that are available in the
encoder and you can actually see this
live in the analyzer in real time moving
on to the results for subset one we can
see that there is a minus 4.65 CIE de
2010 tidge it is the bt right so it
gives us a rate decrease with the same
level of quality we use the CIE P D
value because it is the only one that
considers both luma and chroma and does
so in a perceptually uniform white if
you click on the links below you can see
the full breakdown with all the values
so subset one are still images and
objective one fast our video sequences
as you can see in that point we are
giving about an on average two point
forty one percent reduction this is for
a single tool CFL overall of 81 so
that's pretty interesting
there is also psnr games these are
illumise and our gains the reason for
that is since we have better predictions
we actually reduce the amount of bits so
and that gives us this metric actually
gives better gains because it has same
level quality but it'll have fewer bits
to do so and since this is the area
between a rate difference and quality
that I'll give you a negative value so
that's very good if we move on to the
next slide we see that it is actually
very good for screen content coding
so here we we have on average about 5%
reduction for the screen for the gaming
twitch data set which is on slide 11 yes
so notable mentions here are the
minecraft sequence so CFL alone gives a
minus 20% reduction on both minecraft
sequences that are in that test sets and
we see also good results for GTA and
star graph at about 5% each first tiede
2000 and you know still some significant
gains for psnr luma only so you know
we're really impressed with the results
from this tool and that's why we're
proposing it as an update for the CFL
proposal for a net VC I did I do that in
good timing perfect thank you very much
thanks for coming when sitting for a Tim
to time usurper any other questions for
for Luke on the chroma formula tool any
other final items off the agenda all
right so make sure that I get the blue
sheets signed if you came in late anyone
still here from net VC is make sure to
get them where is the blue sheet by the
way anybody needs it right please raise
your hand we'll get it to you otherwise
thank you very much
I'll see you 101
thanks Matt for standing in for our
co-chair
[Music]
summarizes
you