don't know it's the very proud have to
zoom bad
[Laughter]
we're gonna repair the microphone good
afternoon everyone this is the second
meeting of the path aware networking
proposed research group we're waiting a
couple of minutes for people to fall
back from lunch sending the blue sheets
around
I'm Brian Trammell co-chair in courtship
and okay so this is a kind of right
focus this is an IRT F research group
the IRT F intellectual property rules
parallel those of the IETF
anything you say here is essentially an
IETF contribution you should be aware of
rules about disclosure of IPR that may
apply to anything you say here so our
agenda today we're gonna do a little bit
of actually you know what we're gonna do
a little bit of setting up my computer
so I can do mirroring because I can't
actually see anything from the chair
here we are going to do a little bit of
review of how you set up a display on a
Macintosh
and we are going to go to arrangement
and we are going to do that and life
will get much better for everyone
whoo we're gonna do a little bit of a
review of sort of what the concept is
what are the questions that we're trying
to ask and answer here and then we have
a set of invited presentations from
Chris Pappas talking about methods for
path dissemination and path aware
networks and from Laurel and choix
talking about interfaces for path
selection to the first is okay so you
have a network that knows something
about its pounds it's going to take
information about those paths and put
them down to the endpoints they can do
something with them this is sort of
mechanisms a discussion and then once
the endpoints have this information what
can they do with it and that's more
about their all's going to be talking
about as we pointed out one of the
reasons that we're as a 'print I'm one
of the reasons that we're interested in
this area and research is that there's a
lot of work going on sort of in and
around the IETF that begins to give us
the ability to see a future where we
have endpoints that are aware of their
paths and one of those bits of
technology is provisioning domains so
Eric thinker will be talking about that
and then we have a C being around en
masse talking about Alto tingrong Zhao
I'm messing up all of these names I
apologize talking about a particular
application of path awareness
specifically to congestion control um
since this is a proposed research group
we have a lot of time at the end for
sort of like general discussion one of
the things that we're looking for here
is interest in this topic sort of at the
interface between research and the IETF
sort of what of what should we be
looking at as chairs for the agenda for
next time is there interest in working
on you know any documents talking about
frameworks or looking at things they've
already been done within the research
groups are gonna have a relatively
hopefully a relatively long an
interesting discussion about that so I
think we still need
to meet you notes taker and jabber
scribes oh sorry for interrupting but
you're looking for volunteers please
subscribe thank you Alison and minute
taker
have I seen Tommy yeah Ken can I get you
to do that for me thank you very much
see if you get good at it people keep
asking you to do it that's the problem I
owe him like three or four beers anyway
so it's good so we've identified a
common theme this list of working groups
boss and so us and so on is not meant to
be exhaustive so if we missed out on
yours please don't feel bad of sort of
path awareness and a lot of research
sort of going on around the edges the
IETF that the obvious one here is NP TCP
as I understand it there was just a
lunch meeting of people trying to figure
out how to do rebinding in a multipath
friendly way for quick so that's not
what quic is working on multipath
they're not working on multipath right
now but that is a future development
hybrid access approaches path control
approaches dynamic interface and
transport selection and then path
signaling works so the fact that there's
a lot of this work and nothing like an
architecture or a framework around how
you would put it together um you know
architectures and frameworks not really
what the IETF does but this did seem
like a theme that a new research group
should explore so for those of you who
have no idea what I'm talking about
because you were over in ideas the last
time we had that that was an unfortunate
conflict I as I understand we have an
unfortunate conflict this time with a
routing working group so at some point
we're gonna have to actually get the
routing people in here um is this is
sort of what the internet looks like
right now you have you know an endpoint
and that's not working at all
and another endpoint and you send a
packet to the to one of the gateway
router and that knows how to afford it
based on some control plan information
um that is you know distributed or
centralized usually distributed and but
you can think of it you can abstract it
away is just sort of the control plane
tells the 14 plane what to do in the
Ford and does it the endpoints don't
have really any control here about where
the packet goes based on anything other
than the destination address in a path
where internet you have the control
plane in some way is pushed all the way
to the to the edges you have endpoints
with transport protocol stocks that are
path aware at each end of the network
and can cooperate with the routers in
order to select path so here you see you
have path aware stacks on the colors
don't look great there so you have a
path or stack on either side of that and
they can select multiple paths through
the network that are joint or disjointed
various points they have enough
information about those paths to be able
to make informed choices about which
path they want to send stuff down um so
yeah again what's interesting about path
aware networking obviously the routers
are aware of the paths that the traffic
is taking this is I mean this we solved
this it's BGP right well not really um
we're interested in extending this to
the edge so discovery of has explicit
Association of properties to pass by
endpoints and endpoint selection of
paths since we noticed this is happening
anyway and things like MP TCP and other
multiple interface work we figured that
we should be explicit about it this
research group has one document that I
wrote craft Trammell panna RG questions
this is essentially just a list of open
questions um this is not anything from
the chair this is just I'm interested in
this topic and this is what I think the
open questions on that are please have a
look at it and let us know on the pan RG
list if the questions there aligned with
what you think the questions in this
space are so we also intend that kind of
as an introductory document to this work
for people coming in from outside the
research group so if you are coming in
from outside the research group and you
try to read that document and you are
completely confused and have no idea
what I'm talking about there that's also
useful feedback we had one suggestion in
Prague
because we're talking a lot about
especially with oliviers presentation a
lot about prior work in this space that
was especially focused on the transport
layer and how it tended not to work it
might be useful to have a catalog of
failed transport layer signaling
approaches just a you know a quick
document that says don't do this that
didn't work don't do this that didn't
work but also with some information
about like don't do this that didn't
work and here's why
right like not just complaining about
stuff I understand like to complain a
lot me IETF but sort of looking at ways
for it like constraining the space for
path aware approaches so that we can
make a little bit of progress here one
question that I'd like to ask in the in
the discussion phase today is if there
are any other documents that people have
either energy to write or think that
other people should have energy to write
and we'll try to find as jurors will try
to find you know match ideas and authors
to to things that we can do here we are
considering proposing a workshop on path
aware networking for sigcomm 2018 in
budapest if this were accepted this
would replace our fall 2018 to fall 2018
panarchy meeting but fall 2018 meeting I
think right now is tentatively scheduled
for Asia I hope we'll narrow that down
at some point before we have to buy
plane tickets so this would would
essentially replace that meeting and
we'd have it in in Budapest instead so
the call for papers for this would be
derived from the proposed research group
charter there's actually a draft of that
if you're interested in serving on the
TPC for that please Thank You Erin for
your interest in serving on the TPC
Thank You Spencer for your service in
City Aaron Falk I'm just wondering - in
long time since I've been this income do
they have promote participation at
workshops because I don't know I won't
be in Budapest so I'm just wondering
what we get the opportunity from a lot
of dissipation not as I unders they have
no support for that right we can stick
people on a on a Skype note in the
corner and your experience will suck
okay you answered my question leader of
Ramon presentations they are me Decca
wit sitcom now Oh in the workshops okay
good you know cool okay so thank you so
yeah let the minute show that Lars um
corrected me because they don't know
what I'm talking about
well uh sector does a treasurer for the
sick if you put in the rupture proposal
and in the requirements that you want
from the venue you put that in that they
will budget for it if they can get it I
mean they might say that it's not
possible on - and then you will need to
decide whether you still want to hold a
meeting but if you put it in the you
need to put it in a proposal because
otherwise it won't be in the budget and
rain won't happen yeah thank you very
much I'll go edit the proposal then
Spencer yeah Spencer Dawkins uh I'm
actually got up and walked slowly as the
mic so this is about the previous slider
to back that where you were talking
about what yeah the catalog of failed
transport layer signaling approaches
that seemed like there that seemed like
a really useful thing to do and if it is
helpful for me to collect those
experiences I can do you know I can do
two or three of them from my own
experience but just to start collecting
that and let other people send me email
and do it on list or me personally
either one I'd be happy to do that if
that's okay with the chairs please do so
we expect a draft Dawkins pan orgy
please don't do this please - don't -
this yes excellent thanks yes thank you
and I think that's all I have for my
chair slides so yeah so if you're
interested in helping out with the
workshop we are even just looking for
people who are interested in the area
who would be willing to review papers in
this space one of the things that you
need for a good workshop proposal is a
read of a list of people for the TPC so
please do send that to I guess pan orgy
chairs at IRT F dot org should work
Alison do you know if we have chair
aliases in the data cracker yeah we have
here at clearly yeah oh yeah okay we've
used that okay good
yeah nevermind for good um so yeah
please send up an orgy chairs at IRT org
interest in serving there so thank you
um next up is Chris Papas and I will
switch you over to keynote and thank you
for coming okay it's good afternoon
everyone and thank you for coming to my
presentation about dissemination of
paths in path aware networking so I will
start by the motivation of the part of
our networking research group and
stealing from the energy agenda slides
from ITF 99 one of the questions that is
Richard she wants to answer is how does
our awareness extent to the edge and by
edge meaning the endpoints so in order
to answer this question there are many
other sub questions to be answered for
example how do endpoints discover paths
and more specifically how do endpoints
discover paths in a scalable manner and
how do they react in case of a failure
in the network another question to be
answered is how do endpoints discover
path properties and how do they
associate this properties to the paths
and this has to do with dynamic
properties meaning that they change
often such as congestion or utilization
stages of some links on the paths and
more static properties such as
capacitive links on the path or derived
properties about a set of paths at
source path disjointness
one more problem is how to endpoint
select paths and how then do they inform
the network about the paths that they
want to use so in this presentation I
will cover some aspects that are
to the first and the third sub questions
so the focus of this research group is
the endpoint and how to give more path
control to the endpoints meaning more
path information and more path choice
but in order to talk about how path
control looks at the endpoints we will
have to talk about how the network
assists the endpoints in realizing this
higher level of path control so by the
term path dissemination I will refer to
through three things or three steps the
first one the first one is part
construction and this includes the steps
of exploring the topology and then
creating paths on top of that apology
and this step can be performed by the
network alone or by the network and the
endpoints together the second step is
that the endpoint will have to select or
choose among these constructed paths and
in the end the networks will have to
inform them at the endpoints will have
been formed the network about which
parts to use something that I will refer
to a spot representation so in the
remaining presentation I will talk about
design choices about path dissemination
focusing on science which is a security
oriented eight-part aware internet
architecture and then I will talk about
the design choices made or in other
prominent research proposals in the area
namely mirror and public routing so to
give you an overview about how about
dissemination looks inside the first
step is path creation and this falls
down to topology exploration which is
done through a process called beaconing
and then we have path segment
construction namely creating up segments
and down segments which I will explain
soon assume how they work then this path
segments are registered and this whole
process in science is performed by the
network so what the endpoints do is that
they start by looking up this path
segments and then they will combine
these path segments into end-to-end
paths and then select among them and in
the end they will just inform the
network about which parts they want to
use so going to the first step
the poet exploration happens through the
process called beckoning and this
process the beginning process starts at
core a SS and that term choruses is not
really well defined but intuitively
consider this that this Ras is that
exists high in the era T of the
interconnection market so they have
mostly peering relationships and
customers so these beacons will then
traverse the hierarchy from top to
bottom from the core towards the edge
and one important thing to note is that
each a s will receive multiple beacons
something that will translate into
native multiple supports and path
diversity so one interesting aspect is
that this process of beckoning can be
used as a transport medium in order to
disseminate path properties and it is
more appropriate for disseminating more
static path properties so in this beacon
messages each a s on a path can input
some information such as MTU capacities
of links on the paths some partial path
policy supported services and supported
crypto protocols then we have the path
segment construction process and this
beacons as they have traversed the
topology they now contain some path
segments that can be used by autonomous
systems in order to reach the quarry
ASIS that started this beginning process
so there are up segments which are spot
segments that can be used by non quarry
Isis to reach quarry axis for example
the yellow path segments can be used as
an app segment to reach a SK from ASR
and there are down segments which can be
used from Korea seas to reach another
AAS and encore areas for example the
orange pad segment can be used as a down
segment to reach ISS from ASL now the
next step is to register this path
segment because eventually an end-to-end
path will consist of an up segment a
down segment and potentially a core
segment which is a short path segment
that may be used in order to breach the
up and down segments and I will show an
example shortly
so this up-and-down segments will be
registered and looked up and more
specifically a enas will select a subset
of these path segments to be used by the
local endpoints to reach the core and
another subset will be selected so that
other endpoints can reach the a s now
this path segments will be registered
with a special lookup service that is
operated by path servers and there are
two types of this service first we have
path servers operated by choruses and
this is where these down segments are
initially registered with and they will
serve these down segments to remote end
points then there are path servers that
are running at non-core aassists and
they serve a dual purpose first they
serve up segments to local endpoints and
then they resolve and cast responses of
how to reach other remote end points so
then we come to the second step which is
to combine the paths in order to create
a full end-to-end paths and then select
among them and here we have the lookup
of path segments and at this step we
have two translations that take place
the first installation is that the end
point will contact a name server with
with a name in order to obtain the AES
in which that server resides in after
this translation the second translation
is that the end point will contact a
local path server and for that
destination in yes it will obtain path
segments that can be used in order that
can be combined in order to reach that
destination a yes then this path segment
will be combined and to give you an
example an end to end path can consist
of an up segment the down segment and
the core segment you can see in the core
to bridge between the up and down
segments or alternately for example if
an up segment and the down segment
advertise or contain the same peering
link a shorter end-to-end path can be
constructed in the end there will be
multiple end-to-end paths and the end
point can select one or more of them for
its communication this
two part representation and how the
endpoint will inform the network about
the selected path so in Sion this
happens through packet carried
forwarding information and more
specifically this forwarding information
consists of interface level instructions
and the consequence of this is that it
no lookups are required at the data
plane at least for the basic packet
forwarding in the figure you can see an
example of how an alias can allocate
interface identifiers locally so this is
only a local process and now this
information this interface level
information is embedded into the beacons
during the beginning process and this is
how the endpoints will eventually learn
this information through the registered
up and down segments now talking about
some other related research proposals in
ehre
the politics relation and construction
is similar to tsiyon in that endpoints
will discover their up graph which is a
set of paths that lead from themselves
to the core a difference is that in
Neera the endpoints are part of this
path vector component that is used to
discover the up graph now part of these
paths will be selected and then they
will registered with our name to route
lookup service so that other endpoints
can look them up in order to construct
end-to-end paths about path selection
the sender will choose a path from its
up graph and then it will combine that
up path with looked up paths in order to
construct this final end-to-end path and
Pat representation in ear is different
in that it is implemented through source
destination addresses for example ipv6
addresses and this addresses so the
source address will encode an app path
and the destination address will encode
the down path and allocation of others
is in error strictly follows the
business relationships as the others are
allocated from providers to customers
each others at each other outer is
associated with some forwarding state
which is looked up during packet
forwarding similar to how it happens
today
so padlet routing is a more generic
routing architecture and it defines two
basic concepts the first one is V notes
or virtual notes which are created by na
s and V notes represent routing
structure in the network of an AAS for
example there could be one we note per
outer or one we note per outer interface
then a palette is a sequence of such V
notes along which na s is willing to
forward packets so with respect to the
apologi exploration and construction the
routers will announce their v nodes to
their neighbors and then the neighbors
can combine these v nodes in arbitrary
sequences and they can also combine
paths let's and stitching together in
order to create longer paths let's part
vector is then used in order to
disseminate these putlitz and v notes to
the neighbors but the spot vector
component in path with routing does not
enforce any policy so multiple of these
pallets can be announced to the
neighbors
but selection is not really specified in
palette routing because as a generic
routing architecture it is not defined
whether the endpoints participates or
not for pattern presentation you can
think of MPLS so putlitz are associated
with flat identifiers and these are put
into the pockets and each identifiers
then associated with some forwarding
stated routers for example this can be
to push additional pallets into the
packet header now in order to conclude
my presentation this table summarizes
the design choices that are done by some
prominent proposals in the area but the
important takeaway message is that there
has been significant work in this area
that answers some of the questions that
have been raised but by the path aware
networking research group for example
how to provide native multiple support
or how to disseminate static part
properties such as beam capacities at
the same time there are many challenges
that remain unanswered so there is a lot
of work to be done in the area for
example how to convey dynamic path
properties how often do we need to
disseminate such information
how much information is needed for
example for obtaining accurate
congestion information or latency
information another issue is how should
the end point to look the end point to
lookup service interface be implemented
and one more interesting issues how to
disseminate or to convey this part
information higher up in the networking
stock closer to the application and I
think some of the subsequent talks we'll
talk will describe some of these issues
so thank you for your attention and
we'll be happy to answer questions we're
about five minutes for questions hello
Tommy Polly Apple so thank you for
sharing this very cool to see what I
think is most interesting is how you've
broken down the various categories and
shown the comparisons across them I
imagine for a lot of us the kind of
Scion architectures and stuff it seems
you know quite far off but I think these
principles when we look at other
solutions like what we'll see you later
on with like PVD and stuff seem to fall
into very similar categories of how
these could be represented two end
devices and up to applications hopefully
so I'd be interested to hear your
thoughts on what are the necessary
things to have end applications get
ready for this in a way that allows them
to take advantage of some incremental
path where steps now but then also have
the correct hooks to be paths of where
when we have some of these more full
visions like you have here so I talked
mostly about the networking parts or
you're talking more about this interface
between the network and the application
so when talking about part awareness
there are multiple things so you could
have like a fully path aware endpoint or
you could convey some partial
information so if a first step would be
for example just to give information to
the end point about the available parts
without giving an option to
select parsimony so for example I don't
know about these jointness of these
parts so it's really a bit hard to
imagine from based on today's internet
architecture but the first step would be
to giving information about the current
status of the past that could be used by
the end points that could be
probabilistic information because it's
really hard to debug your it information
but ideally it the ideal goal I think
would be to go and if the actual actual
control to the end point so that they
can combine these parts in the way they
want so this gives much more control to
the end point and you could see it as
being part of the routing architecture
which is which clearly doesn't happen
today
I tell me I think you might also want to
come up and ask that same question after
the next presentation so much might have
a handbook my question would be how does
private peering fit in this picture here
I mean you wouldn't you wouldn't
announce a private peer peering link in
your in your database would you so it is
true that there are some privacy
implications for peering because so in
the beginning process if there is a
peering link is peering link would be
announced down to the ASIS that are
below something that would not that
doesn't happen today at least BGP
provides this privacy but on the other
hand there are approaches that enable
you to determine what the relationship
is among to a SS if you look at a few
routing tables and see how they look
from different vantage points so this
information is partly disclosed today
but I agree with you that this
relationship become more explicit
through such a process because they are
clearly put into the beacons as they
traverse the topology today it's more
used assessment sorry today it's more
URIs --tx to to conclude back
exactly that's what I'm saying that this
becomes more explicit I mean today this
is hidden based on BGP but based on the
heuristics you can determine what this
relationships look like but it's also I
guess it's also hidden not only by a BGP
but also in the interest of the
providers isn't it yeah but I mean BGP I
mean referring to the typical BGP policy
is not like pgps the dissemination
method but through the typical gower
expert of progressing this how these
policies are implemented through BGP so
indeed the providers don't want to do it
and that's why they just announced based
on the garlic sort model so you cannot
determine this information today just by
looking at one table if you collect this
information and you have some multiple
vantage points as happens in research
often when we get some data like that
and it is possible to determine this
information Philipp diesel to Berlin I
wonder how you would represent multiple
paths was in AAS as well as multiple yep
just give me the so what I described
clearly neglects this issue about
representing multi-part information
inside the Naas and I would say that one
problem is scalability so inter domain
routing gives us a good abstraction to
scale this Multi multi path support one
problem of this is that you cannot get
accurate disjoint ins information so you
can have partly disjoint ins information
and let's say the more disjoint some
parts are at the inter domain level you
can assume that there will be more
descendants at the intra domain level if
they are purely designed for example at
the inter domain but if you want to have
such accurate information I think there
will be a scalability issue because of
the large path diversity that exists
inside the domains we have
a remote so is that what you're getting
up to say don't either
yeah yes yes it's presentation at a page
where and yeah I think you want to talk
about path like routing of passes
example and may we suggest is that there
are five rulers between the in horse to
enter point wrong and end points good
and maybe the routing state yeah I'm
sorry that you've got enough audio drop
out there that we can't understand the
question can you type it into Java or
turn off video okay try now I so let's
go on if you can type that question into
jabber Allison can you relay that if you
get to do the jabber because this I
don't think we've got enough bandwidth
off of there so sorry yeah so Aaron go
ahead and we'll get the question for
Allison so Aaron Faulk I worked on a
project called Farah which was sort of a
precursor to deira which I guess an
unfortunate selection of names that's
clever computer scientists for you and
the way that when we were working on
Farah and I think that near is the same
although it's been a while since I've
read the paper it was a somewhat
anachronistic idea of allowing end users
to select their long distance providers
when they use the intern
and the whole idea was to give some way
of Anna to provide hints to the path
that you wanted your packets to go and I
just wanted to make that comment because
I've heard several comments that were
really more about trying to do fine
green but fine grained control of the
path that your traffic took in the hands
of the end-users and that wasn't really
the intent of of Farah and Neera and
that it was the idea was to provide a
way for network operators who were far
away from either end of the connection
to differentiate themselves from each
other and therefore provide some
incentive for them to compete by
providing new services or better quality
or deploy new capabilities and so the
the point being that it was really about
providing some hints so that a end user
could express what they wanted which
kind of goes to stuff that's going on in
taps and and then this is sort of a
mechanism for how you communicate that
back and forth so not a question just
trying to add something to this guy's
cool thanks Alison do you get anything
on jabber all right I'm if you if you're
still on and listening Donna I'm sorry
that we couldn't get your question and
if you could send it to the list I think
Chris is on the list
and we need to neither session there I'm
sorry that we couldn't get that working
for you
all right so next is Laura
[Music]
okay good afternoon
local Shia also ETH Zurich it's my great
pleasure to be here it's my first ITF I
will talk today about interfaces for
path selection this topic overlaps a bit
what's going on in the taps working
group in particular I'm going to talk
about the socket API and efforts to
replace it with the post sockets API and
I will try to link this to research
perspectives and some research we have
been doing and that goes in the same
direction so using multiple copies of
the same components to improve real
reliability availability performance or
capacity of computer systems it's very
old idea multiprocessor systems
multi-core CPUs multi disk storage I
will a fairly common places today but
what about narrow paths so I think it's
widely accepted that multi path
communication can help to improve
reliability if one path goes down and B
TCP for example can how to effortlessly
and quickly switch path it helps with
mobility if client disconnects from a
Wi-Fi network for example he can
gracefully switch to LTE for example but
this is not entirely multi path it's
just switching quickly from a single
path to another and then multiple
communication also helps with the total
amount of bandwidth but I say I think
it's not the entire story and I will try
to use straight that so some might think
that's it would be preferable to use a
single very good network path and
multiple paths and some I think that
this perfect that could be for example
an optical fiber link
I think there's no such thing as a
perfect network path whereas radio waves
travel close to the speed of light in
vacuum on the surface of the earth
information only travels about 2/3 of
that speed in in fiber so latency is
significantly increased when using fiber
and so wireless has this latency
advantage but it also comes with other
drawbacks it has also the mobility
advantage obviously but it has drawbacks
in terms of Gerry run all kinds of
security implications so I don't think
there's a perfect network path and also
are arguably in today in today's
Internet there's a fairly limited amount
of network paths between one source and
one destination but we don't know what
tomorrow's networks be made of so there
are a number of projects you provide or
borne Internet connectivity through
balloons drones or lor bit satellites
and as we saw in the previous talk
future internet architectures like Zion
in particular will provide more path
control to an hosts and paths control
means that and hosts may use multiple
paths simultaneously so when I say I
work on the path communication and here
o notes paths TCP and yes this is part
of the story not about TCP is great
because it hides all the multipath
communication specificities from the
application so it means that an existing
application can use multiple TCP almost
out of the box but it also means that
multipath to speed is fairly restricted
in what it can do to best fulfill each
applications objective so I also hear
sometimes should we optimize for
throughput or latency she does the
application care about throughput all
agency and
I think in most cases it's both so I'm
more of course we cannot optimize it's
not straightforward to optimize for both
through boots and latency but I think in
most cases both matter so a most a more
meaningful question is that the
application need a reliable transporter
and are inaudible one so we're browsing
for example legacy matters but the
critical requirements is that contents
be delivered completely incorrectly
eventually and then we have applications
that refer to trade this complete
reliability for for a very low latency
so for something like a simple request
and response protocol multiple
communication might not be the most
interesting the best strategy would be
to send along the best path assuming we
know what that is or along the best
paths but I think first one very
interesting scenario was real-time
communication because some applications
have very high throughput requirements
and they have also very strict latency
requirements so applications have been
using the classic Berkeley Circuit's API
for decades and arguably it was so
successful because it was so simple but
we also think it might be too simple for
modern applications and networks it
offers mainly to abstractions suck
stream so a TCP stream and so Jairam for
UDP data grams but the reality is that
the network is not freely file and
datagrams do not offer much
functionality they're mainly glorified
IP packets and then there's a third
abstraction such htech packets which is
mainly bound to the HTTP stream control
transmission protocol which is not not
very common and not extremely deployable
in today's internet and it's multipath
but not really
it's mainly for failover
so here's a simple example of where
classic models for short so here we have
a source a simple application that
generates a constant rate I concerned at
a rate of 10 megabits per second and the
message is a lifetime of 1 seconds for
some reason it might be a live stream or
multiplayer gaming or something and we
have two paths with very contrasting
characteristics on the left-hand side we
have high bandwidth high delay high loss
path and on the right hand side we have
a low bandwidth flow delay low loss path
and so it's fairly easy here that the
optimal strategy is to send all data
initially on the left on the left hand
side path and then because it has a high
loss all the packets that are lost can
be retransmitted on the very reliable
path on the right hand side so using
that simple strategy of transmitting one
path and retreating along the other we
can expect 100% of the packets to be
transmitted before the deadline and what
I think is very interesting here is that
even if we had multiple copies of the
path from the left-hand side we still
wouldn't be able to achieve 100% because
the the loss rate is so high and even
with a couple of copies of the path on
the right hand side we still wouldn't be
able to achieve 100% because the
bandwidth is so low so really here what
makes us achieve our goal is path
diversity is the fact that we have so
diverse paths so we addressed this
problem a generalization of this problem
- and these different paths each bearing
possibly different characteristics in a
paper that we published recently at DSM
and so we formulated it as a linear
optimization
and here we have a similar example with
you
simple paths and we can see the result
of using each path and using a multi
path and optimal respect strategy so we
presented results for both both in
theory and in simulation with as3 so
this is one of the reasons why we think
it's meaningful and it would be
beneficial to have a more expressive
circuits API so the objective is really
to have a simple but but more powerful
API so the main question now is what
should be the knobs and dials
what should the application tell the
transport layer so that so that the
transport layer can make appropriate
path I gets you two paths assignment
decisions and also what should be the
dials
what should the application be able to
learn about the transmission of its
messages should it just receive the
messages when they're ready or should
should it be able to you so that's more
of an open question should what should
the application learn about the
information of these messages
so again this relates to the words that
that's being done in the in the types
working group with post sockets so I
will not go too much into the details of
this but all sockets is a transport
platform and language dependent API
which supports dynamic selection of
transport protocol stacks in an
explicitly multipath environment with
the message abstractions and there's a
concept of long lived associations which
are composed of one or more paths and
there is an ax synchronous reception of
messages so I wouldn't mainly talk about
the the properties that the application
can set for the messages the first one
is one I've already talked about a
lifetime or deadline for a partial read
ability the second one is a priority or
more exactly niceness which Express
which messages should be delivered first
then there's dependence this fine if
other messages should be delivered
beforehand
Adam patents specifies whether it is
safe to use and in situations that may
cause message to be delivered more than
once and immediacy is just to say do not
wait to combine this message with other
messages or parts thereof so again about
a lifetime
I think TCP versus UDP is often a false
dichotomy there's something that lies in
between and that's partial reliability
so packets with a lifetime can be
reference method may be retransmitted
but only for a limited period I think
this is a meaningful property because as
I said we cannot optimize for both
latency and throughput together it's
typically a trade-off so that's one way
to specify strict latency conditions and
there exists transport protocols that
use this concept of partial reliability
there's a personal reliability extension
to the SSB protocol and there's a
variant of this pickle deadline of water
2030 TP then there's niceness which is
just the inverse of priority and so it
goes together nicely with lifetime
because as both lifetime and niceness
increase priority decreases so niceness
is sort of the equivalent of lifetime
for reliable transport and by default
it's zero meaning that by default
messages should be delivered with the
highest possible priority but then it
can be reduced arbitrarily and
the last message property that's really
relevant for path selection is
dependence a message may have
antecedents specifying whether other
messages must be delivered first so for
example a webpage should preferably be
delivered before embedded media such as
images then aside from message
properties an application may want to
set policies specifying which features
of the transport protocols it prefers or
which paths or interfaces it prefers to
use for our cost performance or security
or privacy reasons there are multiple
domains to do that it can be at the
application level or the get me a user
policy or system policy so the first
example is that Wi-Fi might be preferred
to LTE for cost reasons the second
example is that an application might
require that these messages do not cross
certain networks for security reasons so
putting everything together I think
fairly hard problems lie ahead so this
is a graph we obtained when we solve
this optimization problem and we see
that when we have a high number of paths
in this case when we have ten paths and
we consider three own transmissions it's
a computationally hard problem to
optimally assign packet to pass so so
that's the bad news but the good news I
think is is that the assuming that path
characteristics are fairly stable the
the problem is not necessarily solved
for each packet and then the other piece
of good news is that not finding the
optimal solution does not mean that we
cannot find very good solutions with
your e6 and simplifications and finally
I think that's more expressive api's -
such as the post second CPI could drive
a new multi path fish search and a new
kind of missed path research
Thanks so yeah thank you for your
attention I'll be happy to take
questions
hi Brian Trammell not as chair um so I
have two quick questions actually go
back to your last slide it might be a
little I could see it from over there it
might be a little bit hard to see but
yeah that's linear number of pounds in
the bottom and logarithmic time for
computations so yeah clearly we can't do
this for every packet unless we have
yeah more than two pads and it might
there might be an optimization loop that
you can do here where you could say okay
well I'm gonna limit the number of paths
just arbitrarily in order bit but that
okay that's scary but yeah that's why
it's research um let me you know post
Achatz co-author taps participant pat on
let me see if I can let me freeze a
question and I think the answer is yes
so the difference between what we're
doing in taps and sort of what you're
doing with post sockets on top of this
transport selection engine is we care
about selecting this impact and - we
care about selecting the stack and then
saying okay well we have this
abstraction so you don't have to rewrite
the application when you go from stack
to stack and you're more interested in
using the message properties in order to
go on a packet by packet or flow by flow
basis as to how you do the the
transmission okay yeah cool yeah chair
had other questions
[Music]
actually let me get a show of hands how
many transport people in the room okay
so this was kind of review good that's
good feedback from the chairs well
thanks
how many routing people in the room all
the way in the back okay a couple up
front good okay my name is Rick link and
I'm speaking in the name of many authors
in at least two of them are in the room
so he and Tamia here maybe others we're
presenting at the inter area something
called corrosion a domain that can have
some intersection with the purpose of
this research group for instance nowaday
networks are becoming much more complex
than they were before
now if you look about the PC which is
there it's Capel physically two three
networks it can be associated through
the phone doing tethering over Bluetooth
can be connected to the Wi-Fi network of
the enterprise and can be a wired
connection to the enterprise as well the
enterprise itself can have two service
provider giving two different paths
including
connectivity to the Senate is a VPN so
at least three interface here and at
least three four paths actually to the
Internet one here the phone service
provider one switch provider to and the
VPN so how can an application select the
right thing in the old world the legacy
world of a PV for now maybe some of you
are still using it but no or do you do
it as soon as you select it one path you
do not
to ensure that the return traffic is
going by the same path selecting one
pass is correct but in some case you
want to be to have a symmetric path so
we need to find a way in a PV six
because in a PV six we don't if not you
don't want to if not because it's be a
stupid idea
a similar stuff a problem that has been
raised in the on networking group at the
last tiny TF by Ted lemon if you have to
interface or to ipv6 prefix and you
select your resolve let's say IETF doc
by using the eighty interface you will
get the CloudFlare CDN the closer's to
your LTE provider in my case it will be
something in Brussels in Belgium oh and
now I I want to go to this ITF dot orc
address VR my Wi-Fi here so we need to
travel from Singapore to Brussels
even if CloudFlare add a pop in a cache
here so we have multiple aspect here out
to selector physically a pass one
address we can use it the same another
way even if you have a single interface
in a pv6 we can have multiple addresses
per interface from different prefixes in
this case coming through the same router
but could have been coming from five six
seven ten routers on the same layer to
domain now by selecting the right source
address then the network itself can
route the packet through traffic
engineering s a v6 normal rsvp-te or
whatever or selecting basically at LTE
or satellite or whatever link so we need
to make the application aware about the
existence of multiple paths with the key
traffic engineering quality of service
so all we do it there is a concept a
relief a couple of years at the idea but
is RFC 75 56 they describe a
provisioning domain
a provisioning domain is basically the
consistent set of information then you
can use to connect to the internet
mainly when I pee address on interface
one DNS recursive server maybe Elena's
search list next up and a few things
Langley meant to you maybe now until now
most of the network I mean computer in
the 80s I get only one connection so by
default it was a single PVD no choice
for the application now I've seen a
previous slide you may have a you must
have multiple choice so you must have
multiple pvd's and we may want to name
them and this is part of this draft to
put a name to a PVD so an application
for instance can select one specific PVD
and we'll get a specific set of
consistent information and in the same
shot we are extending the notion of PVD
which was just layer tree information
the to do tree information to go to the
application layer by doing a two-stage
let's say PVD provisioning I don't want
to go into many details about the
protocol is not really the purpose of
this session here but it's simply sent
over an ipv6 router that Iseman we are
adding a new option there and it was
only two feet interesting for this group
the PVD ID which is using the kernel to
identify which PVD you want to use which
is why during and it's not a coincident
asan design of fully qualified domain
name and you will see why you also add a
sequence field and the sequence is
basically to say a I have new
information for you this is version 5
then maybe one hour later two weeks
after two seconds after you will send
version six it's a trigger for everyone
receiving this typically multicast
router advertisement to refresh all the
information why do I say refresh
because it's two-stage so in the array
you receive the layer 2 layer 2
information and then based on the fully
qualified domain name you use HTTP over
TLS and fetch this well-known URL the
container JSON file that contains some
metadata or application data so there's
an example here of this JSON file you
can have a name which is more readable
than a fully qualified domain name it
could be even a localized name put
either in French or they can be in
Japanese Korean or whatever to help the
end-user to make a decision but we can
also put there some characteristic of
the network until now we only put them
first up so let's say between the CPE
and the access network because typically
you know the maximum bitrate and the
minimum latency if it's a satellite line
you know it's capable of but ten or
hundred of milliseconds there but there
are other example I don't know whether
you can read on the bottom of the slide
but we can say for instance as a captive
portal it's also important for the
application if you are even IOT device
that means to abreu to upload its
results somewhere of usually can
traverse a normal captive portal so
there's no point of trying to use this
address is it meteorite yes or no
meaning is it free or not okay and a few
things like this so this could be an
opportunity as well for this within my
research group sorry to propose
information to be put there and we will
be all ears of course currently we were
thinking just an example not sure that
will be finalized in the PVD when it
becomes a standard the cost for instance
in the network access for now is little
bit too complex to under it but for an
x-ray vision or whatever an extension as
I said what about the bandwidth between
the CPE and the access network typically
it's known because if you are using VDSL
you know the which speed the videos and
modem is synchronize
captive portal wall garden as well all
of us will take the plane I guess to fly
back home tomorrow the day after in most
of the airline's you get a free Wi-Fi
only to go to the VOD right the video on
demand that's free if you want to go to
the real internet me to pay so there's a
specific characteristic as well for this
thing I mean a plane you don't have a
choice anyway so maybe less useful so
we've been working on this for about a
year
other authors by the way from Apple
there are people from Google interested
and Microsoft is interested as well so
there is a big momentum behind it so at
Cisco I'm working we have public domain
implementation the O'Reilly is there
with partially working al an external
including a user space demon because
that's where we need to get the
application the metadata with a washout
detector we have modified array DVD and
OD HCP for open wrt and ledee to work
and we of course we have implemented
this information sending into the router
but your shipping of course may be a
specific thing to say we are working as
well in the project calling meet h 2020
project from the european union where
basically they want to implement a
firmware like a post socket API right
and we have some meetings as well the
brian on this six months ago something
like that to cannot synchronize the
effort where this api you can ask the
application can ask some properties are
requests low latency request security
for instance and based on some
characteristic of the network and some
parts of the network information up on
the network trying multiple transport
UDP TCP httpd TLS or whatever or quick
and find the best compromise of course
this is by default done on information
coming only from the open operating
system on a kernel but with PVD we can
provide some additional information
coming from the network so it was a good
intersection here so it is basically
what I wanted to say today so there is a
way there is a need as well for
application to select the path maybe not
the path in the sense you mean it but I
think pretty close was one information
we can receive by PVD it's also the
segment routing header to be inserted in
all the packet if you select this
service so then we select a real path on
the network any question or you can see
them hi param also nasty question from
somebody who is kind of been aware of
this PVD work and now understands it so
thank you for the presentation this was
really cool this basically gives you a
less hacky DHCP options like interface
for non dhcpv6 v6 networks right okay
provides way more thing it's way easier
to extend this way right yes yes yes so
so less hacky because like you can hack
dhcpv6 up to a certain point and then
your you run a tax pay so you have a lot
more hacks phase here v actually I think
I should probably take the rest of these
questions offline because these these
people don't just need to see us have a
really long conversation about this but
you know when I have but I have an
architectural question about about pvd's
so the information that's there right
now is basically architectural II
limited to the first hop right it's just
about your access and then anything that
was sort of as part of the if you wanted
to implement the first n hops of a path
aware network with this your first hop
would be PVD the next n hops would be
segment routing and then you'd have to
do some magic to go in our domain at
this point right this correct I mean no
we could extend PVD to get more
information deeper in the network but
I'm not really sure whether it's
sensible in 2017 yeah
okay um and there's another question
I'll save for you for the open mic okay
so cool thanks Tommy Paulie Apple um so
co-authoring this as well but I would
like to just solicit you know feedback
from anyone else especially the
presentations we saw earlier on how they
could see this type of thing fitting in
I do think there is overlap of
especially how we could imagine
applications viewing the network viewing
things to preview T's to Brian's point I
think it's key how do you let
application see the pvd's right now we
are focused on one hop because that's
all we can really do but to some degree
the fact that a router is telling you
that it has multiple up links is
actually multiple how hops behind you so
your first hop is telling you what it
knows about the next one's and those are
represented as separate DVDs if for
whatever reason your router was able to
learn about more fancy things and it
could actually control your routes
through a Scion architecture if
applications were aware of pvd's those
could just show up as maybe you know 25
different pvd's and maybe the
scalability problem there but hopefully
you know each of these would be a
self-contained version of information
because beyond the extended information
one of the really key things of the PVD
is just the ability to say there is
something different here there are two
things even if you don't know what they
are you can try probing on them and just
use them differently yeah but Vic you
see thanks and Tommy let's take that
first question to be open to the open
questions session okay you want to come
back about so who's next
oh yeah so see beam is next
we're still there is so so I know
everyone so there has been a little
closer to the money you have to be it's
uncomfortable but okay okay so there has
been a list of a summary of open
questions that was circulated last week
and Alto is actually addressing the ones
in the green color basically about how
path property can be exposed to
applications plus a bunch of questions
that were raised on a mailing list
particularly regarding a mutual trust
between applications and the network and
privacy concerns and also level of
abstraction so the IETF protocol is a
transport protocol that exposes a
network centric abstraction of the
network so the goal is to guide the
application to for a selection of their
endpoints so as to trade network cost
efficiency with equal or better
application performance so this way to
to this end the auto exposes via restful
api is information services that are the
outer network map which is a set of
network locations that not network
location groupings with provider defined
identifiers and enumeration of the
related endpoints so the provider
identifier may be expressed in natural
languages so
it's an indirect and network agnostic
way to aggregate Network endpoints that
shares some common property a
characteristic so the second information
service is the outer coast map so that
exposes cows among the P IDs and the end
points of the map so again these costs
do not need to be the real values
because that will never happen everybody
knows it
but typically will be an abstraction on
real costs that give some hint on the
network performance it can be an
abstracted cause it can be ordinal
values so the base protocol as shown
here is abstracting the network of
abstracting the network so here is the
real network and it abstract this in
kind of a single switch abstraction with
the flows here the end to end points
here and here in this example so it
exposes one path pair destination and
within this path conveys one single cost
metric so well Panaji we may say that is
actually looking at how to connect so
where as the base protocol is looking at
where to connect so the auto working
group is specifying and working on a
number of extensions to address this
aspect so they mostly built on an
extension that is defining abstractions
of network traffic engineering like or
network performance like metrics that
can be of course abstracted so let's go
quickly through those extension
so you have one extension that is called
auto path vector so the auto path vector
abstraction details some in within a
path in an end-to-end path it details
some parts of the path that it the
network considers as significant and it
describes them as like abstracted
network elements which is a set of one
or more switches or links or any part of
the network and the a in the ane
properties may be exposed by the network
in a separate property map so here for
example so you have now some detail on
the path and the application when it
gets the fact for example that from this
point to this point the routing although
the path goes through these particular
steps and the path here goes to some
other particular steps it can figure out
whether for example - they share a
bottleneck and so and figure out what
performance or what capacity it will get
so the second how to connect a kind of
extension here assumes that there are
several paths available to the
application in Putnam lis path that
relate to the access type so here for
example the the application knows that
it can connect via Wi-Fi or cellular so
it requests a path performance given its
access type and SLA and here it gets for
example two values if I ask cell cell
and SLA of three and Wi-Fi and SLA three
so then here I can get two values and
figure out how to connect given that you
do not have necessarily a better quality
with Wi-Fi and now with 40 you often
have better you're better off
and if there is any special on the
weekend better of using a cellular
connection
the other another extension there is
called multi cast with constraints so a
multi cast with multicast I can request
for example routing cost and bandwidth
capacity on paths that I would like to
have with either lower routing or lower
cost and lower bandwidth or higher cost
but then better bandwidth so I will ask
all those to matrix and the auto will
return values only on those paths that
are meeting the constraints so this way
it's kind of selecting telling me do not
use that that that one path so besides
other how to connect if it may be of
interest to the panel G group to have
service and information service that
helped applications to decide when to
connect and this is done with Auto cost
calendars and so here you have an array
of of time dependent cost values and
here you have attributes that help you
to interpret those values in the array
so and here are other references and
thank you for your attention thank you
very much any quick questions on this No
ok so thank you and we'll go to the next
waiting talk
[Music]
hi hello everyone my name is Gil from
Huawei
today my topic is past awareness for
congestion control congestion control
without pasta well is basically they are
to a main method for hoster to know the
past when there is no pasta well is the
first way is by assumption the host when
they think of the network is congested
or is getting congested or is a protein
when he founded the event of Petra knows
or aqua decreasing or ACK know stir for
quite at no time and another method is
by a measurement when a host can mostly
put about increasing sending rate than
it amazing that the network is on the
night note I went into a kettle more as
to Buddha by decreasing sending rates it
amazing the network is congested then
canoes can conjure these past the world
is easy and explicit congestion
notification now currently seeing is the
only a standard way hosted use the
advanced properties feedback from
network and order for congestion control
either case could superintendency into
the center network will offer
information continue a more reach and I
created past properties hang our
research for networks it is founded at
some dynamic networking information from
a bottleneck device on the past is very
useful to the our congestion control
lack of ease the properties such as
ingress rate egress read performance
feedback of phone bottom naked note we
could get a higher penalty translation
and don't end you see as is shown in
Figure one in Figure one you can see the
accurate feedback method a red line
could occupy the available panel is very
very faster than we are
legacy method another fun is the Vida
properties
radio lingo stated such as a radio
recorded a spectrum you tonight edition
at her arte Penn Station or Wi-Fi device
people to adapt the variable wireless
network very well as we go to our shows
in Figure 2 the red line is the capacity
of the wireless network under the UH
president non-islamic our method we can
see the bragging I could adapt to the
red line very well the other kana then
how to a distributed the possible of
this easy I used to invent the beats for
information distribution as the ITF
standard but for rich and greater
properties
there's no ascend in a way now we only
could use the TCP and IP options for
distribution but this method is limited
by the option dance and has no problems
that means the middle box as well so we
may prefer a standard embedment way to
disputed these problems between paths
and a host specific sub layer between
TCP and IP maybe it's better like layer
3.5 the more of passed awareness but
before passed awareness hoster has no
idea about of the pass after pass
awareness hosted Mendoza passed them
could select and write the past and I
used pass the more efficient than before
so could we are to more about to the
past could we control the past
properties we have least idea because we
found the service like knife VIII which
leaves automated properties like a very
high up enemies and a known tendency
this kind of overflow sir cannot only
depend on the pastor F for the network
or a better synapsing overpass they may
need to control the past properties for
them like a pass resource allocation as
a flow setup and videos release as the
flows exit so that's it thank you thank
you very much
any questions on that okay so now people
won't actually try to use it as a mic
stand down
Oh dawn um can you yeah her in um Joe
can you come back I think there is a
question about the a page six there too
said and when the application wanted to
control the passport ace I think this
might be unfair because what if the more
than one application want to control
their passport days how would that work
to the resource allocation yeah but for
this kind of like a VR VR AR this was
the valuable service that we can add to
this kind of control properties for them
in just a for some yes some cases but of
all other cases it's easier to assign
them with the higher priority and not
just
property butter some resources okay
allocated for them okay so I am very
animal okay that wasn't obvious but now
I put together a little draft a little
bit before this meeting sending out to
the list I think about a week ago based
on so the idea is basically to try and
focus all of the discussion on the list
could you know maybe something going uh
about what I think the questions are in
this space and there are six we have
some questions and we have some more
questions so I'll just go through these
very briefly so how are path two
properties defined and represented right
so you could call this a closed question
right everything that does anything in
in exposing path or even last hop
information to the end points must have
its own vocabulary in order to say right
so Alto has the cost maps and the
network maps the PVD has this extension
thing where you have key value pairs and
you know some of the points in this key
value pair space are assigned so for
example the you know this is I think
metered is one of the things and that
has a meaning I think oh it seems to me
that all of the work sort of coming from
the ietf side has I don't want to say
arbitrary but they've kind of gone for
the most obvious way to represent those
properties for their use case and it's
not clear to me that in a fully path or
network that that's the best way to do
it right like so Aalto is focused on a
particular application space PVD is
focused on a particular application
space all of them are built in such a
way that a common vocabulary could be
built into them right not they all have
points of extensibility that there are
exercises that went
you could use them but it seems like
it's interesting to step back and
consider what those what these sort of
vocabulary items are and how you know
what they mean and how the definition of
that space implies what we can and can't
do with path or we're not working in
place sort of like whether we can or
cannot deploy it so we have a couple of
other questions how to implement
discover trustworthy path properties
Sion represents a point in this design
space so it is Aalto for the set of each
for the set of path properties they care
about so we have we have sort of like
running code here we have solutions that
we think that we can take from there um
how can in point select has to use for
traffic in a way that he trusted by the
network so this is this is really okay
so this gets I think a little bit back
to Dawn's question I've said something
about past selection why won't we just
run into the dscp problem of mark all up
my pack it's really really really
important because I want to go to the
network very fast my computer is telling
me to set that sit down okay please
confirm your dick German okay so in here
like as we saw from from Chris's talk
there's running code on these for both
addressing based approaches and PC FS
based approaches there are ways to do
this right so Sion represents again
another point in this design space how
can interface is the transport an
application layers support the use of
path awareness post sockets which is
taps seems pretty clearly set to this
but there are two other bigger sort of
higher layer questions that I think we
should address probably here one is how
can a path or a network and a path aware
Internet be effectively operated right
so the the network operations model that
we have right now as you tell BGP where
you're willing to accept traffic from
for which prefixes and magic happens and
you get traffic and inbound interfaces
and you can change your
announcements and you have a effective
and predictable control loop well okay
predictability in BGP is an open area
but you haven't you have an effective
control loop for being able to say okay
this traffic's going to come here I want
this traffic to go away I'm going to
stop announcing that prefix on that on
on that interface and the traffic goes
where you tell it in a path aware
Network the endpoints that are attached
to the network are also making decisions
about which paths are going to use do
something since this is already
happening in in sort of lake in
multipath networks right now and
multiple connected networks endpoints
are mobile and they are shifting traffic
from one interface to another sort of
and they degenerate to point case so
this is might be a problem that we in
the internet engineering community have
to handle anyway and this framework
might give us a way to think of that in
a way that we get a better handle on it
but the operations model is a completely
open question and it would be
interesting maybe to have some ops area
and input here or people have work from
the management space to come in and help
us out with that the second one is
really a layer eight an economic layer
question how can the incentives of
network operators and end-users be
aligned to realize that vision here
great
so why as this was actually a question
that was posed to me by Martin Thompson
as soon as he read the draft like five
minutes after I post it he's like why
didn't you consider this I'm like Thank
You Martin it's in github now so yeah
the working copy of this in in github
actually has this question and we'll
post that in any other questions that we
enable dictation language German unbound
Radnor dhalsim next and I'm sorry and
then we'll we'll post that after this
meeting if there are any other open
questions that people want to come up
and address I obviously have fuzzy ideas
here that might be a document that we
talk about but we need to have an answer
for the question why would somebody
actually buy a gateway that would do
this why would they buy a router why
would they offer this service there has
been some work but I'm aware of it's
been done in this space and so on and
maybe this would be a venue to talk
about that as well
that
my piece does anyone have clarifying
questions on the questions are there are
meta questions Ling from Huawei
I think these three parts are huge and I
just want to ask the smallest question
for the past election for address based
the selections that are you referring to
the sauce royalty so well I mean like so
we use address based pass election right
now all the time right you have a
destination address and that implies a
path you just don't get any information
about it but here I'm referring
specifically to segment routing yes
second marking so for the definitely we
can do it but how about way for a why do
I care about the legacy Internet no we
focus a lot of deployment right now more
than 80 percent yeah right now yes yes
and the coast where is slow for ipv6
yeah so so let me let me let me actually
take before Lee gets up and and and
causes something but I have to talk to
the Ombuds to move out family let me
just give you my personal feedback my
personal view on that it does seem to me
like there are a lot of enabling
technologies that work much better on v6
than on v4 for this sort of thing
right you could build like you could
replace pbd with some hacks Indian DHCP
you could oh are you gonna design this
for me Aaron or are you gonna go talk to
somebody about the feedback okay perfect
yeah thank you so I actually see this as
a if this is something that v6 does much
much better than v4 right like if you
saw the the API talk that Lauren gave
we're actually talking about having to
rewrite all the applications anyway so
moving to v6 is not going to be harder
than rewriting all these applications
I don't think Lee Lee Howard so I I
could imagine trying to build in a
description of nat zones if you would or
nap domains saying this is you know
we've got this instance of private
address space
I call them addressing contexts when
I've written about this area so I could
imagine so that's conceivable I'm not
sure the works worth doing but that
might well come out of the essentially
applicability statements that you're
talking about in the last couple points
here right on that which I'd love to see
hey how is this work going to be useful
being one of their early questions great
okay um so I'll actually point out again
so another thing that just came to mind
so I know that song on actually does
work with v4 right so it basically uses
song on routing through the internet and
then you can have the last hop address
as be ipv4 addresses and it just hands
off in the end point as2 v4 so this
there's a way that you can use an
overlay waiting to get v4 endpoints
talking to v4 end points over song on
but that's kind of a life extension hack
for v4 as I see it open question on how
the path of a network will make use of
path or network that could also probably
influence the properties of the path
that would be collected if the network
has to make use of the path of a network
rather than the applications wouldn't it
be that's a really easy so you're
basically talking about so I see that as
an intermediate stage right lakes are
you build like the way that we often
build these new technologies as you go
as you go local net to local net you do
the tunnel thing because you own bits of
the tunnel um that's a really good
question and I don't have an answer but
but that should get written down in this
document actually so you know how how
are these affected by like so we're like
all of these properties so you know
things like laurels work wouldn't work
there right because you don't have
enough information to say the
application can't go okay this packet or
the transport layer can go this packet
goes
this packet goes here but what do you
you know what are the benefits and then
what are the the changes in the model
when you go from a a local to local net
as opposed to endpoint to endpoint or
maybe even local net to end point or
endpoint to local net that's that's a
really good question so um I will go off
and and and and think about that for
this document and I invite you to help
me out we are doing this work in AI ppm
as well for collecting the IOM stuff
that would probably I mean there is no
encapsulation for it for it but it
defines what could be collected but
that's mostly focused on how you can
operate your network better feed it back
into the application I guess that also
has to find some place in case if if we
go with modifying the transport protocol
to carry and return the data in the
transport in quick and TCP and so on
that would probably be one other way of
returning the data for awareness for the
application of amis so it seems to me
that the IOM stuff could be used sort of
in the in the in the inter domain or the
intra domain but also in the inter
domain like so IOM actually right now
IOM is explicitly single domain or
single iom domain where that doesn't
necessarily overlap with ah yes but
usually does so that could be used as a
way to to measure dynamic properties in
a way that could be then disseminated
through a path dissemination protocol
like something on yeah that's definitely
a part of this I put that into the
gigantic bin called enabling
technologies but yeah that makes the
measurement part of this much easier
that's a good point to thank you could
you go to the next slide yeah so on the
last question I'm very glad that what
sorry I'm Tommy Polly I'm glad on the
last question that Martin brought that
up I would be not at all surprised if
that was also related to the fact that
you know he is chairing the captive
portal stuff and when I heard that
question the thing that immediately came
to mind was that because that is a very
clear example of a weird incentive
situation in which there are already are
quite unusual network properties that we
want to be aware
and it's not necessary multiple paths
but it is one path with funky properties
that we want to know and what are the
incentives around even that existing
case the network's letting us know that
they're doing evil things short traffic
denied because because the whole
business model is based on the evil
things that they're doing right and so
the one thing that that brings up is you
know as we are trying to build a
solution for captive portals hopefully
there is some sort of compromise that is
mutually not terrible that allows the
network to communicate the terrible
things they're doing to block the advice
but also enable the system to help show
their ads a little bit better which is
kind of terrible but important so as
we're looking at this I imagine that
some of these incentive questions will
be very fraught with compromises between
lots of parties and that is a necessary
part of this so we'll say that I didn't
want to bring this up at all that Aaron
kind of already did that one of the
things that having if you have path
property dissemination in a trustworthy
way so those are secured and you have
path control in a trustworthy way so
each participating AAS can know that the
path isn't forging anything right like
so so you're in a situation where we've
basically made KC is wonderful spoofing
detector obsolete which would be awesome
because I'm sure she does want to have
to do that then you actually can enter
into business relationships with a SS
that you're not directly connected to is
that a thing that's enough of an
incentive to get people to put these
things up maybe I don't know
that's C but it seems like we're
changing the business relationships that
you can build if we do this and that
sets up that that takes this problem
from the complexity of the captive
portal thing where it's like it's pretty
clear to see how you can analyze this
because these guys are trying to screw
you as hard as they can and you're
trying not to get screwed you know you
can kind of meet in an equilibrium if
maybe that equilibrium space is zero but
there might be points in that
equilibrium space here by basically
changing the
way that you can build business
relationships you throw this into a
giant I mean like this is this is now an
economic problem of a complexity that
I'm certainly not enough of an economist
to solve yeah I think that yet the
points that aaron brought up earlier
about the point of doing this path
awareness is potentially just to create
an open market
yeah of path so you can get to is really
interesting and really points towards
having multiple paths as being maybe a
way out of some of the terrible
incentives that we have today on locked
paths any great ox want to get up and
grumble about ATM alright so that's the
I guess we've kind of already gone into
the open questions part so I guess Mike
lines are open I'm putting my chair hat
back on and I'm going to pick on Tommy
so you asked Laurel and Chris a question
could you restate that because I forget
what it was I just remember it was your
first question of no Tommy
so I don't remember exactly what it was
but I think the first question that I
had given to Chris was essentially that
you know we're seeing that a lot of
these patterns between the various
protocols in the various architectures
Scion or pvd's or Alto have these
similar patterns of how we do path
discovery path communication and we also
brought up the point of api's and how
our applications interacting with these
and we could design kind of the perfect
API for each of yes exactly right so I
think this is a really good table and
when we look at the API is that we can
design whether they're post or neat
stuff I think those overlap but we've
also often defined the api's to be very
specific to the problems we want to
solve in that case so maybe we can make
it more general but how do we
evolved this to make sure that let's say
today I can write an API for PVD that
works on my multihomed ipv6 networks and
can I use those same properties to work
on Scion Network when it comes along
like what's the transition path for this
are there is there a difference between
kind of soft path aware networks in
which I can get away with just knowing a
little bit and maybe a world in which
path awareness is critical to be able to
use it well so how does that work I
don't know do you do you have anything
you want to sing on that or I think I
take that down as an open question but
if anybody from that table there has a
comment feel free to make it I think
it's an open question I think it's
something we need to think about cool
any other questions on this or should we
kind of try and wrap this up and figure
out what the next steps are I know I've
learned a lot this was interesting for
me I don't know I hope it was
interesting for for for you um let me
put my chair hat back on then and say so
we got one action item here Spencer is
still here so we can reiterate that he's
going to write his draft or he's going
to write us the start of a draft that we
can then point at other angry transport
people and have them contribute so I can
put this back over on the uh
non-functional nightstand because I have
my own mic over there just you know
assuming that the chairs are not looking
at the mailing list because they're
looking at the meeting I did send a note
to the mailing list about that just
making sure people can find me and
asking them to send me the name so that
when I have a good template I'm gonna do
my two first and see what you know see
what information you'd ask for it no
circle back could ask them but I just
want to let you guys know that could I
ask you as a one of the chairs of this
afternoon's TSP area session to plug
that effort over there as well
at least me or Miriah is awake now I'm
not sure that we both are okay but yes
that would be lovely meet me I remind
you if you forget I need to put this on
the ITF and I RTF discussed list that
basically anybody can remind me of
anything any time thank you
I heard a couple of bits of input for
the open questions draft so I will read
that and send it to the list soon I
actually want to get a little bit of a
sort of a sense of who's in here um as
the chair
who here has no idea what's going on and
is willing to say so okay Aaron do you
find this area interesting and useful
and you you think you get kind of a
handle you don't really have to have
it's not like a Boff question where it's
like do we understand the problem
because the point of this is that we
don't understand the problem um does
this work interest you just a sort of a
show of hands I mean are you here for
this or are you here for the internet
and the and the air-conditioning okay
okay a few hands good are you just here
to troll people who like ipv4 all right
so I have I I have a what I need as
chair to figure out what the next steps
are we'll put together an agenda for
London where you have really strong talk
yeah so if anyone would like to present
let us know and yeah we're also looking
for for suggestions for what fee like
the general theme of that agenda should
be like so these were sort of the first
two we're booting the research group
ideas um and we'll try to keep the
energy going it's much much fewer people
in here than last time I noticed because
you're the first meeting of anything is
like oh what's that I'm gonna come sit
down so um hopefully we'll have about
this you know will stabilize that the
count of people in the room bye-bye
London one thing I do want to make sure
that we note is that for a London we
should try to conflict out everything in
routing because and I know too that most
of the apps people are over in dough and
the problem with basically trying to do
a research group that ends up being glue
between applications and routing by a
transport and Internet is that is that
the only people who can show up here are
the is a 2.0 folks and the transport
area which we mostly conflicted so so
yeah I think um the speaking with my
assassin with my RTL I think we you have
to probably put like way way more
primary conflicts and you might end up
on Friday but and just tell everybody if
you come on Friday right but the other
thing is that you could consider having
two sessions and kind of bridging
between them if it's to allow for some
different perspectives on this we would
allow you to do that okay okay so - I
mean like so - shorter sessions -
shorter sessions that have different
conflicts and then the chairs work on
bridging them somewhat so that your
people can catch up you know give them
some catch-up between it because I think
it's gonna be impossible at some point
you'll probably want to have planning in
the room where you can actually get died
down and deeper and that'll be a good
thing for you but it's kind of
impossible to avoid the problems of the
scheduling here yeah so I see there's a
there's sort of a a smallish group of of
people who would definitely contribute
that we could do an interim yep but I
don't think we have a long enough list
of work to make that productive so so I
think we can I think we can once we have
a scope that makes sense to do that's a
really good really good idea
guess we give me some time back before
people could live the wrong there must
be blue sheets somewhere so raise your
hand if you have not signed them yet
please okay yeah maybe people took it
over to doe and they're signing with
Banerjee blue sheet and oh that would be
cool alright so with that thank you very
much um for coming to the second meeting
of the pannier G and we will see you in
London on the mailing list
you