good afternoon everyone
we'll stop the meeting in a minute
sure
welcome to PCE I'm John Hardwick
this is note well please read the note
well any submission that you make any
statement view make today the microphone
or in writing on the mailing list is an
IETF contribution or contributions or
subjects to the rules of RSC 53 78 NRC
81 79 if you want to read the note well
more closely then you can go on the copy
online before we start the session a few
points of admin please sign the blue
sheets that are being passed around
I might go my quiet it's cuz I'm sleepy
I get closer it's just better yeah all
right please sign the blue sheets
they've been passed around we have a
minute taker Dhruv is going to take the
minutes but he would like some help
please could you if you're not checking
email please could you go check the
etherpad
online of a PC you session and help
truth with minutes or contributions are
very gratefully received
is anybody in the jabber room that could
act as a jab scribe Adrian thank you
very much so we are streaming the audio
and video I see but that's not in vain
because we do have some people in the
meet echo room so please only speak to
the meeting using the microphones in the
room please state your name before you
speak so that the minute taken can
record your name and present as if
you're presenting please could you keep
your feet inside this small pink square
on the floor so that the people who are
remote can can see you and yeah my as
you can see there's only one chair today
my coche Julian unfortunately couldn't
travel to Singapore this time
so here census apologies he threatened
that he may turn up later in the meet
echo room so you may hear his ghostly
disembodied voice but it looks like he's
not there yet I guess it's still a
little early in France the usual
reminder for everyone please to use a
mailing list and use it actively and if
you have any discussions you want to
have please have them on the list if
you're making any changes to a working
group draft then it would be great to
discuss those on the list that's not
always the case but if you're making
changes it would be great to at least
send an email to the list and tell us
what's happened in your draft we're
actually getting a lot better at that in
the working group is really pleasing to
see but a lot of people are now doing
that I heartily encourage that please
please keep doing it if you have a new
draft please introduce it on the mailing
list it would be a lot easier to get
some time in the meeting if you first
socialize the draft online that's about
it
so onto the agenda this is the agenda
you have me to tell you about working
group status for the next 20 minutes
then we have one slot to discuss a
working group draft on stapled PC for
point-to-multipoint then we move on to a
new submission for PC extensions for SR
or leveraging the ipv6 SR date of line
segment rousing data bling and then
finally we will go on with four drafts
which we have previously discussed to
get an update and find out what the next
action is for the various drafts here
the Association type of have protection
that should say not projection the
Association type for bi-directional
osp's pset for supporting resource
sharing applications
and synchronization between staple pcs
do we have anyone who wants to bash the
agenda any comments everyone's happy
good okay so let's take a tour of our
working group drafts so we start off
with a slide that I have wanted to
present for a very long time after five
years and seven months we have finally
published a stateful PCE as an RFC
and thank you everyone for your
contributions and patience as we as we
got my drive through the working group
and out the other side improve EIC and
out the other side now we have our SE 82
31 nice good news for pretty much every
of the draft we have going in the
working group because they were all
depending normatively on it so it's
really good to have that out there and
with it dropped out a slew of other
things the LSP state synchronization
which which was kind of a companion
document to that and a piece of
extension for service aware LS piece was
also dependent on state for PCE and
there's kind of a double whammy because
another really important draft also got
to RFC in this period piece M s so piece
F over TLS securing P sub it's really
good to see they get published and I
hope that everyone's implementing that
further to that we have free drafts
currently the RSC editors Q we have the
staple PCE or LSP initiation which is
being edited right now we have the Intel
our extensions which depends on it and
we also have the bids draft for RFC 6006
that's stateless PCE for
point-to-multipoint all three sitting in
the RSC editor queue so I expect those
to drop out as our C's very soon
just about 45 minutes ago I submitted
another draft to the iesg so that's four
draft for experimental code points see
Deborah Deborah is arrived so Deborah
that's with you now please do your magic
and let's get up on moving a few
administrative items we have a new art
burrata on embarassingly on the Roc we
just published about a few weeks ago it
was an wrong reference he was actually
an indirect reference to a crypto
algorithm it was it was a reference to a
document which reference to the
documents which defined the crypto
algorithms so we need to correct that
reference we're going to correct it in
the errata
the office of compact confirmed that
there's no technical impact so there's
no impediment to implementing the draft
it was simply fixing a reference we also
did some early code point allocations
for the Association group draft we're
hoping to get that draft published quite
soon but in the meantime we needed to
get code points in place because there
are implementations that people want to
start building networks or building
building some sort of network with so we
allocated some new code points without
draft they now left it listed on the I
honor website so you can find them there
quick tour of the the drafts that are
still with the working group so the
first one the draft for inter area and
Inter AS applicability so the status
about is there was a shepherd review
that went back with comments for the
office to updates
I'd only office here today no okay well
what I heard I'm the word on the street
is that the authors are considering
whether the scope of this draft is right
considering they started writing it when
I was still at school and now we have
staple PCE and then the world has
changed they may need to update the
draft with those new requirements so
it's with them to consider that I'm not
going to force them to do it that if
they want to do it then great but if
they do do that then it's going to go
back to the working group will have to
review it again and that's as it should
be so we'll wait and see what happens
we have several drafts here which are
comparable working group last call and
they're basically waiting for bandwidth
for the document Shepherd's to ship them
on up to be iesg the first one is the
LSP setup type were actually this
waiting for me to make an update to the
draft it's an update with agreed so it
should be done very soon and then
hopefully we'll just be shepherded on
the next to relate to gmpls
whereas Yoo Lian tells me he's something
like 80% of a way through writing up a
shepherd report for through gmpls
extensions and I hope that he'll be
another 20% of the way through that
before we get to the next IDF meeting
and will will have removed this from the
list the w.zahn rwa draft is ready to go
Danijela shepherd that
a long time ago it's just blog tom on
gmpls we're gonna move those two forward
together we have about five drafts here
that are pretty much telling me that
they're ready for last call segment
routing which is basically a follow-on
from the LSP setup type that will go
when the LSP setup type is ready
hierarchy extensions where I think that
the draft has expired
I think the vas just down to the draft
being dormant while they wait for the
the publishing process there's anyone
here who's an author of hierarchy want
to make any comments about that I guess
not okay well I'll chase the offers
offline and make sure it gets refreshed
because we can't do a last call on an
expired draft the the next one is PC
Association group where we've just
completed the early allocation but a lot
of work is depending on that the
document seems stable we're going to
push that through to last call shortly
up to the meeting staple PCE also a
bandwidth again has been around for a
while is stable the officer saying is
ready and staple PC points multi points
you will be hearing about in a few
minutes time so they should all be
getting ready for last call so things
are moving on pretty well about end of
the Working Group a few working to
address for not on the agenda for today
first of all the yang model drew you
want to say anything about the status of
the young model from Warwick so
regarding the yang model basically from
our side more or less things are stable
and we have not made much change from
since we presented in ITF 99 and we
asked a few clarification questions or
to the yang doctors so we have got some
replies but we have not yet updated
those so that's one action point on us
so we will mostly be updating and then
our waiting game for the
eternal and the other documents that we
are referencing so the waiting game will
happen for them to get published and
then we can take up the piece of junk so
you think we need to wait for those of
the drafts before we can move this one
on yes because I think that's the yang
publication process there anything that
you are importing it doesn't need to be
published before it yeah we can't be
published before that published but we
could be at the same time we don't have
to sort of sit wait for an RSC number
for weekly yeah at least we can think of
getting yang doctors and other things
done at the same time as the detailed
models are you know getting ready yeah
okay
there are a couple of drafts here which
are related to the actn work from teas
working group start staple hierarchical
PCE and be applicability statement Dhruv
any updates on those drafts basically be
kind of refresh the documents based on
the changes that were done in the ACD
and framework as those documents are
getting ready for last Colin teas so we
have just kept them kept them aligned to
the changes there other than that not
much changes we are expecting in the
document as of them okay good
so this PC Association diversity anyone
what his feats of that one
so I think we addressed recommends that
we received a couple of time ago
in the latest version from my point of
view or there is one element that we
added that are not completely happy with
so maybe we need more discussion on it
otherwise I think the main point of the
main architecture of the draftees is
okay this just be small point to our
advice okay
policy Association draft okay for policy
it's almost the same so it's are clearly
stable varies maybe you won't think that
we need to discuss just whether maybe a
newer TLV subshell which well the
possibility of having variables to the
police if you see something that we need
to discuss okay and to dress release its
ass type of PCA 1vb gmpls extensions to
stay for PCA and the other stable PC LSP
scheduling where honestly I'm not sure
what the status of these is they seem to
have been dormant I don't more sure if
ask us we're finished or if that's
because people are working on them true
truth regarding the scheduling I think
we did make an update just before the
ITF and basically to keep it aligned
with the t's document as well as it's
getting progressed there there were a
few other changes we wanted to also
align to the way the RFC 8 2 3 1 tells
us to do a few things and the state
synchronization draft that is also on
the on the agenda today so basically
keeping the extensions aligned to the
rest of the PC working group documents
so that's the major update from the
scheduling okay so does that mean it's
is sort of just staying alive while it
waits for other things so what do we
want to do yeah basically more reviews
with
I'm already low the next step you okay
some of our drafts are expired as we've
noted some of them are expired just
because I'm moving slowly for various
reasons and that's okay we just need to
get them alive again so we can take the
next step or a to where the chairs are
wondering if they're still an editor in
charge or if the draft is now headless
there's a remote initiated gmpls LSP is
anyone working on that I think it was a
zephyr but I haven't seen south are for
a while or Letran then he's here he's
okay he's in Singapore okay well maybe
I'm trying to try to track him down
yes is every Singapore I think it'll be
joining someone I'll just bring him okay
that would be good yeah so I can talk to
his after I see if he's still still
going on that I think of the enhanced
errors I draft was alive a long time ago
and then it died because no one was
working on it and then she am from why
we took it over other things young from
Huawei is also stepped away so I think
that this one's now again dormant so
I'll save the pho the same thing I said
last time if anyone is interested in
this work and let me know I'm be honest
okay so how am I on says he would like
to take this over which is fine are you
able to contact Jen and yeah okay thank
you thanks that's the end of a working
group status any questions on any of
that in which case the first presenter
is I think a bond or the
point-to-multipoint staple PCE
when I spawn biram I'll be giving a
brief update on the progress of the
stateful piece PC for p2 the PDMP LSP is
draft there's been one revision
published for this since the last IDF
this revision contains some minor a
total changes to get ourselves aligned
with the progress of the three documents
listed on the slide at this point that
document is fairly stable there no open
issues we believe it's ready to progress
to the next stage so we like to request
the working group and the chairs to
consider this Falasca
okay so this draft has been around for
quite a few cycles it's been stable for
a long time I haven't seen too many
reviews of it happy to proceed to a last
call it would be great to see a few
reviews during last call my main concern
is there haven't been enough pairs of
eyes on it so I mean obviously we we
tried to do a Carol Shepperd review but
that's no substitute for multiple pairs
of eyes so I'll proceed the last call
and I hope and pray that people do do
review that okay so kiddies don't
forgive this get us on jabber didn't
just share we share and sure that it's
really for last call and he will it is
stable mainly but he would need a
refresh that you'll do tonight yeah
because I think it's the draft expired
caught a long time ago so yeah good to
see a refresh first and then we'll you
know get a refresh and then maybe guess
them someone to review that of them will
make me think about a last call
after that thanks okay so that the
comment said we're relating to the
estate all PCE or remote initiated LS
please okay so now it's I think Dhruv
those are the wrong slides
hello yeah this is drove I'm presenting
a piece of extension for sr v6 so
they're a bunch of other is our v6
documents that you are seeing in the
idea of today so within the B sub we
wanted to see what changes we need to
make to support it and whether it's a
good idea or not as well so so what we
are basically doing here we know that s
are basically allows you to steer
packets through both ipv6 and M
pianist's and use the same source
routing paradigm only the data plane is
change is different one uses MPLS stack
other use an ipv6 header extension
that's the basic difference so the
question that we have is should be C be
able to compute SR path for both ipv6
and MPLS forwarding plane and if it can
can P sub be used as a protocol to
transfer that information from the the
PCE to the the head node where the who
steering the traffic so these are the
two questions that are the most
important questions for the working
group before we can jump into how we
kind of do it right so from the author's
point of view are we kind of see like
what would be what would this extension
look like if we try to do it basically
in case of SR v6 the difference is that
instead of an MPLS label we will be
using an ipv6 address to identify a
particular segment and just an ordered
list of ipv6 address is instead of a
label stack you have an ordered list of
ipv6 address in this case so we already
have PC segment routing draft which
focuses on MPLS data plane if we extend
the same extension what are the changes
that we would need to do to support ipv6
data plane so we kind of realized that
main changes would be that we already
have an SRA ro and sr r ro sub-object
that we used for segment routing
a few changes needs to be made to that
to support SR v6 behalf capability
negotiation as a part of segment routing
maybe we need to separate it out and
since the parameters are different that
one is more focused on the MPLS and MSD
kind of stat depth and those things and
here we have different parameters maybe
doing it separately would be a good idea
and also since we have the setup type
maybe we could use the setup type also
as a way to signal that this is an ipv6
data plane so this was at the high level
what we thought would the extension
would look like messages I don't think
so we need to make any change to our
messages request reply report all works
fine they all use ero the only
difference would be that we need to use
an updated SR ero sub object and update
it s RR or sub job sub object to carry
the ipv6 data plane path so a quick look
on the top is the capability so in the
capability of the TLV itself can specify
whether the PCC or PC supports the SR v6
and the Mac's SL can also notify what is
the maximum the segment ipv6 segment
header length that can be used and this
is quite different from MSD so it's
better to have it in a separate TLB the
as I said part setup type the second one
and this is the updated SR aro sub
object compared to the one that is there
in the segment routing draft the most of
the top things remains the same and if
you remember there you have an S ID
followed by nai which is network and
node or adjacent c identifier so we kind
of updated that to also include the SR
v6 identifier and inside there's our v6
identify you have the SR v6 ID which is
a 128-bit ipv6 address and some other
information about the society what
function the Society has some flags and
what type it is and this type can
further use
nai that we already have to identify
that this si D belongs to which node or
which adjacency etc so the idea is to
keep it aligned to the s re ro s RRR oh
that already exists just a bit with the
SR v6 identifier and the function code
and some other informations that will
help us achieve the v6 requirements as
well so first I think to the working
group first question would be that with
this stuff we are making sure that the
PC and PCL can be used for both modes of
segment routing so we as a we need to
decide as a working group that whether
this is a good idea whether we should
continue to use B sub even for SR v6 and
if we do it in that way is this
extension what we are proposing does it
make sense or not so any comments yes
please thank you it seems fairly obvious
to do this I just I mean I had a couple
of Falls reading the draft one was just
to make you aware the LSP setup type
draft is changing so there will be a new
a new idiom for you to follow in this
draft once I change is done I think the
the capability TLV in the open message
is moving to a sub TLV from from the
top-level TLB so what are you wait until
I get the OSP set up tog draft out and
that come home we yeah you can show the
update
I noticed buried in the tags that you
have a dependency on the segment routing
draft which doesn't specify something
which I can't remember what it is but if
you could put that on the mailing list
then we can make sure I guess so I
assume the setup type is going to be
ready within pubic right sorry the
update on setup type yeah that will be
done soon and it will have an effect on
tree structure yes so with regards to
dependencies keep it simple done if
you'll start looking at the
programmability draft and all the
combinations you know you'll just wait
forever if keep us try to pass provision
and we did with employers yeah I think
that's a good idea we'll make sure that
it can be extended in the future when
that happens right now we can keep it
simple okay max is true again
so this is a park protection and general
piece of association when I wrote the
the slides I thought that I had to
convince the working group that
Association needs to be moved luckily
John has already put in his chairs slide
that he wants Association to be moved
soon so few of the slides we can kind of
move for a little quickly my work is
already done there but just to keep
people up to date it on what's the
changes that we have done main changes
since we wanted to publish in early I on
a location so we make sure that's
completely clean and it's taken care of
so luckily that's done thank you chairs
and ATF and some of the implementations
are already started using the only
allocated code point
and one more thing we wanted to kind of
show that currently this association
draft is being used in multiple
documents and it's important that we
kind of keep things aligned and make
sure that what is there in the base
draft is it's according to the base
draft in other documents and good thing
what has happened is that we have got a
lot of feedback from policy diversity
and we had in the last set of revisions
taken those considerations and that's
why we kind of made an update with the
operator operator configured and dynamic
association so luckily we have had a
good back-and-forth between the various
association types and the generic
association these things are things are
going well over all that we have two
working group documents three other
documents are on the agenda including
this one that I'm going to start talking
about very soon and then we have some
other documents as well which have been
published as well as presented in them
some other idea so there is a good set
of documents based on Association so to
the main topic path protection so Park
protection in fact was one of the first
Association type that was published in
fact this
was the type when we were when the
author's I was not part of the team back
then and when the authors were
considering part protection that's the
time they realize that we may need to do
a generic Association so that we don't
have every different use case trying to
do this in a different way so we went
back and said that let's write a generic
Association object and make the part
protection as a separate document where
the Association object is defined there
and this document just defines a new
Association type called protection right
so this document in fact has been there
for a long time since 2014 last it was
presented was in Buenos Aires but it's a
pretty straightforward document it
simply associate two or more LSPs to
provide path protection so it has a new
path protection type and it has a TLV
called path protection association TLV
which can be carried in the association
object and why are this you identify
among this group of LSPs which LSP is
working and which LSP is a production
LSP and what is the mode of further LSP
whether it is on a standby mode or not
so the changes that we did add since the
protection is a dynamic Association of
sorts it is created automatically we
don't expect operator to configure the
Association ID and other details it just
configure protection unable so since
this is a dynamic Association or the
text around it has been added some error
handling has been updated made sure that
we are aligned to the stateful PC out of
C at 231 etcetera and the text from
security and other manageability
considerations section was missing which
has been added basically we feel like
you know this is a quite important
document it's a useful feature we all
need protection and draft has been
stable and there are in fact known
implementation for the protection draft
this was in fact as I said the first
Association type that actually came to
the working group but somehow the
diversity and the policy and some other
documents moved i had much earlier than
this one thank you any comments on
protection so I think we all agree that
having protection is a good idea who has
read the draft I see about 10 maybe a
dozen hands which is a pretty good
number that's encouraging so we've got
information I think we will take it to
the list thank you thank you
[Music]
rakesh
good afternoon everyone my name is
Rakesh Gandhi I'm presenting this draft
on the Associated bidirectional ESPYs on
behalf of the authors listed so the
agenda is we'll look at the requirements
and the scope of the document there are
two Association or initiation types
defined double sided and single sided we
look at the PCF extensions and discuss
the next steps so the bi-directional
associated LS B's they are not new they
have been deployed in the packet
transport networks today they can be
corrupted or non core outed LS B's and
the properties can be asymmetric in the
forward and reverse directions like
bandwidth reduce so the scope of the
draft is associated bi-directional LSPs
as we mentioned the LSB is can be
initiated by the PCE or PCC and it can
also be used for state let PC for core
outed path computation for example so
the first one double sided initiation
where the bi-directional LSP is
initiated and both endpoints of their
LSP there is a new Association type
defined for it the Salas piece can be a
quarter or non core outed as we
mentioned and there was a restriction in
the previous version of the Association
draft where LSPs Association cannot be
initiated by two different pcs so the
restriction was removed and it works
perfectly for this use case
for the single-sided initiation case the
tunnel by the external is initiated on
one end point of the LSP and there is a
reversal SP that's also created as part
of the tunnel so we clarify the tunnel
construct in the in this revision so as
mentioned it's using Association group
there are two new new Association types
defined for single sided end that was I
did by the external SP the rest of the
object is populated using the procedures
defined for our SCP Association object
RFC Xeon Phi Phi 1 there is a new TLB
defining the Association object operator
configure Association and rage but as
these are operator configure
associations this TLV is not used so
that we can use the entire range of the
Association ID so there is an optional
Association group TL we define that
contains the flags for forward you
LSP reverse LSP and the core outed parts
there are some rules defined in the RSVP
for our T's working group document to
identify forward and reverse LS piece
and the last one error handling so as
mentioned the forward and reverse LSP is
belong to the same tunnel and during the
piece of communication there is a error
core defined to identify if there is a
tunnel mismatch so next steps we welcome
your review comments and suggestions and
requesting working group adoption for
this document
any comments questions
okay so this draft has again has been
discussed for a while has been on the
agenda a few times just just to confirm
what I think I already know how many
people have read the draft okay it's not
as many as I thought maybe half a dozen
hands yeah six people okay so I guess
we'll go ahead and poll and and see what
sort of response we get
again nothing like my concerns are
largely to see that enough people have
had eyes and reviewed it maybe a buggy
dumb question from me actually but what
is the difference between single sided
and double sided what do you mean by
that so so and single sided tunnel is
created on one end point and it contains
the boat forward in the USL ESPYs and
there is a RSVP OS LSP object is defined
reversible so it gets a signal across
okay I got it
any more comments for Akash yeah thank
you
Himanshu from Siena I think I've read
the draft and we it's very interesting
graph we are following this drop pretty
closely so I would recommend adopting
this my opinion okay
practices good information Thank You
Munson okay the next presenter is how am
I am
hello this is how men from Hawley and
I'm going to present dscraft
extension to PCP to support the resource
sharing based on past computation so
this market has been initiated three
years ago and was once terminated
because some scope and conflict with
some other works especially for the
Association groups works and by
carefully discussion with authors from
other draft oh we has aligned our scope
and the risk of this draft to support
only the resource sharing scenario and
specify this kind of strategy when the
new era piece used to to replace an
existing RSP and we also support another
scenario for resource sharing between
two hours piece with different
parameters including the endpoints or
bandwidth and some similar parameters in
the drafter we include the two different
use cases so why it's for a single PC
pass computation in the single domain
case and the other is a kind of multiple
PC interactions which can be applied in
either inter domain case or inter layer
case and considering the resource
sharing strategies we now provide three
different consideration that is you
share the link or you share the node or
you share the same as our G group so now
we are working together with the
Association a group draft by using the
Association group object I defined and
we extend this by defining a new TR way
to support resource sharing
okay this flowchart is a little bit
repeating what groups crossing his
picture but this one becomes more simple
because it is quite clear that
Association group objector is is is a
base objectified and we are going to
define different the TR is a comparator
with resource sharing missing the the
other extreme for past computation is a
kind of diversity so this rather covers
how how to compute different passing or
diversity ways but and our work focused
on how to do it in are sharing ways so
we reuse the Association group object
defined in the first route and we are
introducing a new Association type which
is named as sharing and we defined the
corresponding resource sharing here we
in the Association type object so this
is a brief view of the TRA and currently
we include a straight event of flags
here and the representative for the
strategy are sharing and the arab it is
the link and bit for node and the aspect
for SI ROG so in when any of this bit is
set to 1 it means during the past
computation the PC need to prioritize
that kind of sharing during the past
computation so it means that it would
firstly try to share the link if there
is no link resort can be shared then it
will try to find a path without ring
share so this is slightly different from
what is fully failure directly so if we
cannot find a pass without link share
then it will report failure its if
failed again yeah and the same procedure
rules
applies to every flex and for their
further node and as RMG beat pc just the
priority for our highest different
parameters to be feared for the past
commutation and there's such kind of
information to be shared that is carried
in the optional theories so currently we
bring this work back after team after
two years and we want to we have already
confirmed the relationship for this work
and the the other existing works we are
trying to make sure that we are doing
the right way and they if there is any
suggestion to the solutions well welcome
to to receive any comments and we will
also like to request for a working group
of the doctor thank you
I haven't read the draft this is manju
one of the suggestion would be to have a
link diversity instead of share link
diversity no diversity SLG diversity do
you have that or you have the in the
association diversity this one this one
is a separate crafter that always that
was the case so okay so this for the
sharing part okay
so if you officer are asking for
adoption by show of hands how many of
the remove read this draft this is about
10 or 12 people about 10 or 12 how many
people think this is a reasonable
starting point for this work and should
be adopted in the working group it's
about the same okay thanks very much
thank you
truth you're back
[Music]
hi the stove again your final
presentation it's on state
synchronization between stateful PC this
document has been discussed in the last
two ITF and so we will present what is
the latest update that we have done and
let's start with that so basically what
is this document this document defines
the procedure that how to stateful PC
communicate with each other and this
communication basically we are doing to
make sure that the PCE deployments are
resilient that if one stateful PCE goes
away it doesn't lead to disaster and
there is other the PC which can easily
take over some of the procedures were
already defined in a 2 3 1 the idea with
this document is to make sure that we
become much more resilient and solve
some of the issues that we found like
looping optimality issues etc especially
in case when the path computation is a
dependent bar computation and in for
example in case of diversity where to
LSPs who are related to each other and
when we are doing path computation on
them it could lead to some computation
loops etcetera which has been discussed
in the previous ITF meetings a couple of
times one thing that we can work towards
to make sure that we do this in such a
way that it can be used in various PC to
PC relationships whether we have a
redundant PC where one pcs is a slave at
another PC is the master and all
computation is done by one guy and only
on the failure it moves to the other one
or the two pcs are sharing and they are
load balancing between each other within
the same domain the next set is when you
are two pcs which are in different
domain and you would like to share
information then also the same
extensions could be easily used in both
peer-to-peer relationship or parent to
child relationship so this is a brief
intro on the state sink draft
so yes okay we are still continuing with
introduction okay there's more to
introduce so generic procedure this is a
generate procedure it works for both the
cases we call this piece obsession or
state sync piece obsession and we have a
capability around it so that you can
identify on which session we would be
exchanging this information and the
synchronization needs to happen from
both pcs so from one PC to another one
PC with his state and another PC with
another they say that's why it's
bi-directional in nature and some of
these state sync relationship you can
mark that yes for some set of LS B's
one of the pcs is the is the master PC
who's gonna do all the path computation
and within that Association group for
example if we take the diversity all the
LS piece must be delegated to that
master PC who will do the computation
and that will allow and help us not to
go into the computational loop and which
PC is responsible etcetera and the way
to decide this relationship is a simple
PC election that can be done based on
the priority we also need to make sure
that that how the NSP state needs to
move from PC to PC and maybe from one PC
to another so what are the set of
forwarding rules around that that when
PC should forward this information to
another PC II so those rules are also
well defined in the document and then we
have the sub delegation procedure which
is as I was talking about in master and
slave may be the PCC delegates the LS
p21 PC but that PC is not the PC who's
supposed to do the path computation it
can further delegate the same LSP to the
master PC so these are the set of
procedures which are defined in the
document so coming to the main part that
is what is the update that we have done
so the update was around how do we make
sure that the state that is stored in
the at the PC is the latest state so you
might be getting the state from the
device which as as for a 2/3 one happens
that the PCC is supposed to provide you
the LSP state
from the device as well as unable PC
might be sending you the states so we
need to make sure that we update the
state with the latest information so we
we have this procedure laid out for that
that how we could do that so the main
moon two points are that we need to keep
single state and make sure that that
state is the latest we will also
maintain from which all sources we have
received the state so that even if one
session goes down and if from other
session I'm still able to learn about
this information
I'll keep it till the information goes
from every source right so that kind of
procedure will help when we have a list
of all the sources so how did we be we
kind of debated what is the best way to
do that one thing that we we found that
since we already have in the state
synchronization optimization procedure
something call as the LSP DB version
which we wrote to do some kind of
optimization like when we can skip or
when we can do incremental DB sync
rather than doing a full sync every time
so if we can use this LSP DB version yr
which we can always figure it out that
which LSB state is the latest state so
but the value of the LSP TV version is
per session so what we had to do was we
created another theory called original
and SP DB version theory and the idea of
this TLB was to carry the PCCs LSP DB
version as it received from the PCC and
you may still have the LSP der DB
version which is between PC to PC so why
are this new original LSP DB version we
could always determine which which is
the latest state coming from the network
and the PC updates the state so what is
a rule the PC will update the LSP state
only when the DB version present in the
current report is greater than what is
already stored in them in my database so
this will ensure that we never use the
older state so let's take an example so
suppose you have you are receiving a
state via a PC e as well as PCC for
some reason this link and this path is
quite slow and the information those
sent by the PCC this information PC
always received first so let us take the
top example we report the status the pc
further forwards the status to another
pc e and includes the original LS p DB
version let's assume the version number
100 with this information and it adds it
into the database now some other change
happens from the same LS p so you have a
new version version 0 1 and while this
version is still going this guy is still
quite slow and it has not yet reached
but 1 0 1 we simply update but on the
slow link now imagine we get the older
state which is still not read reach the
pc e with the version number 100 and
since this is an older version to the
latest state we will simply ignore it so
why are this procedure very simple
procedure we could make sure that the
latest state is always maintained at the
PC and there is no reason for us to get
like if we are receiving the same
information from multiple places we will
make sure that we get the latest
information only so that's about the
updates so basically what is still
pending in the document we want to
explicitly add how to handle initiated
LS piece you see initiated LS peas as
well but technically there's not much of
a difference between a delegated LSP and
a PC initiated LSP because even when you
initiate the LSP it goes to the PCC and
PC reports and delegate that to the PC
so we have already the procedures
working for delegation all we need is to
clarify and make sure that it also works
for PC initiated so a small update we
need to make which we are working during
this idea of meeting and we'll try to
publish very very soon
this update overall I think this even in
the last idea when we have discussed
this topic there has been a good support
that this is a problem that's worth
solving and we hope that this you
consider this document as a good
foundation for us to work on thank you
and I guess adrian has a question
hi Adrian flower can you go back to her
it's like that one will do yeah yeah not
the picture one of the judges is there
an assumption that the synchronization
is always from a a master PC to a slave
PC and never never two masters yes yes
those procedures is where we we have
identified in this set of forwarding
rules so the the only the PC that's
delegated LSP so you did ECC would
delegate and LSP to a single PC only
that PC will further move that
information to others so other pcs for
example in in this case this even if
this was the latest information the
information would have not gone in that
direction and also the idea was that we
want to make sure that it's the master
PC where we need the latest information
so even if there is a delay at the other
side I'm trying to just understand why
we want to do this what the use cases
where I know you had a slide on that
didn't quite go into my head so is it so
is the deal here that there's there are
multi of multiple pcs because we want to
provide some sort of redundancy or
scaling to the network we're just having
one point of failure is is a bad place
to be okay yes in fact in the 0-0
version of the document that was the dus
case that is how we can avoid
computational loops but then we kind of
agree that we don't want to write an
extension that only works for redundancy
if the extension can easily solve the
problem for other cases as well so even
if it is inter domain or hierarchy we
should kind of use the same techniques
yeah I guess I sort of think of a PC as
being like a virtual device rather than
a physical box necessarily and when I
think about redundancy or load balancing
I tend to think more about a horizontal
scaling inside an implementation rather
than having multiple different
implementations talking to each other
using a public protocol so I completely
agree I think that model also exists
where maybe they are using an internal
database and sharing clustering solution
which are kind of popular but I think we
feel like both the things are kind of
needed if a PC is using an internal
thing doesn't care for a standard
protocol yes they can do within that as
well yeah that's a solid choice for need
for the standard protocol like whether
it could be done with the standard
protocol to get a feel for the need for
it but you had some other use cases yeah
well but I didn't quite understand those
so much okay at the inter-domain case
why would two pcs in a different domain
share responsibility for the same group
of LSPs so if you have end-to-end LS B's
and imagine you have an end-to-end
rsvp-te LSP and head knows definitely
knows the information but we also want
if you are cooperating between two set
of pcs to set up and n2 and LSP and if
there are some resources information in
the second LSP we would like both the
PCs to be aware of that information
because it's an end-to-end LSP and any
path computation if only the ingress
nodes nodes and other does not will not
give us the best optimal stateful PC
solution so if two PC's when they're
cooperating via request messages and
other things and if they have if the
ingress PCE learns the latest state we
wanted a good and fast mechanism to also
report that information to the next PC
so that the computation goes faster so
you will definitely not do this for all
LS B's because there's no reason for you
to share that information only for inter
domain LSPs and similarly in her Ikey PC
that I give it to the child PC child PC
wants to further delegate to parent PC
and how to send that report information
how to keep the database synchronized
between child PC and paren PC the same
procedure can help okay I I guess I'll
go read the use cases in more detail
offline see if I can really get to
understand those so the question about
do we want to take this it's work on the
obvious question is is it has anyone
read this if you've read this please
raise your hands we got two I think two
people so not too many people so I think
it seems like the draft hasn't had a lot
of traction and not many people who've
read it so I feel like it would be a
good idea to get more people to to get
involved show some support or at least
interest in solving the problem at the
moment I think I've been looking to find
if there's really interested in working
on this problem or if it's just
something where you know sort of
hypothesizing Stefan would you like to
add your experience like since one of
the operators came up to us and said
that this is a problem that they are
facing so maybe it's defined can also
add yeah that uh never is so yes the
finest formal range speaking so if we
are looking at the current PC
implementation we know that are based on
a application based redundancy so for
example using that AB a synchronization
and so on we had a lot of we have a lot
of constraints like for example you
should put all your instances in the
same site which is clearly not
acceptable for us because if the site is
failing you will not have any PC anymore
so we need to have something that is
more robust compared to what visa
application based redundancy is
providing so clearly accompanists where
dialog using Pisa protocol is something
that is really useful and
straightforward and simple to implement
so sorry also you could have the two
pieces in different sites right so for
example one in the US and vo go in
Europe or something as it with a very IL
2 DB between them ok the thing but the
backend database is you you think of as
restricted and you couldn't do that with
a single back-end database in theory it
seems doable but no one is supporting it
yeah
you have to yeah usually what vendors
say say are you should be at something
like 10 or 15 milliseconds max which is
not acceptable for us ok thank you thank
you drift that was the last presentation
so anyone got any anything else they
want to talk about or ok so thank you
very much
and we will see you again in London
thank you
oh sure I'll put you on I'll put you
alone
you