[Music]
[Laughter]
how about thank you for join and we're
going to start a meeting now
so because we have a dinner
okay please aware of they're not well
this apply for all the ITF activities
thank you to Dominique for a take
minutes
Peter Porter's prayer this is our agenda
so how about the outdoors are here okay
our milestones we can see that we are we
have some delays with some so we tried
today to discuss about that and how can
we improve them
we need like watering people that are
willing to do work okay this is our
state of the actors internet draft and
our open ticket
that we have to address the pretty
internet draft posts want to be
presented today and why don't we discuss
today okay be aware that we have five
years for to drop so about these okay
about this draft those are the thanks to
the Mike heard for twin comments those
artists light of past ITF as well so we
are updating several standards
ready with the ripple option type that
we have to update so another post update
to zero zero there were able option type
indicate that they when an IP ipv6 node
find and hot by hope either and doesn't
understand it should escape that
optional key process in the packet so
that comes a flag day between the X when
there is the network that handle 63 the
previous call a papal option type and
the new one so I proposed as was
suggested the last meeting us a total
configuration option but we are going to
put the bone so you say flag on that
cooperation option but what they're like
three questions or three topics that I
want to discuss about this document
because it's taking so long
like if I have to handle this solution
in this draft or we have to make a new
draft it's a problem that we have to
solve in this document this is one
question if you are you with that
yes so I don't know it's a question for
you if you think that we have to like
handle in this document or do anyone
[Music]
yeah so the various deployments I'm
aware of including the ones that my
company participate to they don't deploy
ripple they deploy something like Y Sun
or wireless heart or something like that
so that there is a consortium of sorts
which Peaks a number of features of
documents of RFC's I three respects
etcetera and says out of those bikes I'm
going to do this this this this this I'm
going to package that and then I'm going
to do some certification to prove that
you actually do what we say you do and
so so the they are the guys who decide
I'm going to use this particular
document I'm going to use RFC eighty one
thirty eight etc and when they release I
a standard which has a certification
package that is a flag day right and
that's the flag day we're talking about
I don't see someone just say oh I'm
going to play with various
implementations of repo of various sorts
without you know some kind of a
certification body which which packages
something and say this is interoperable
so I don't really mind about the flag
day I mind that a certification of some
formats at some point decides to go to
this new setting to go to six large and
a number of other things which
individually each each of them creative
like that even going from I Triple E
before 2015 to 2.4 a to do that form 802
dot 15.4 2015 creates a flag day I mean
not everything creates a lot of like
days but a certification body size oh
you use I Triple E 2015 you use repo
plus amendments blah blah blah blah and
we have a certification package for it
and that's that solves this problem
statistic
don't worry okay we we're going to
handle that
here rah rah each other from Wahby
so so basically the problem that I see
is with regards to the upgrade when when
it happened upgrade happens so it is
quite possible even though II the
certification body or Wyson accepts this
particular flag or this particular
decides to use this particular RFC still
there will be an upgrade cycle in which
case this would be needed so what I I
would really like to see this flag the
flag proposal to be kept in I mean
frankly speaking I don't have a problem
keeping this flag in a separate document
or in the same document as well but what
I'm trying to say is even if the
certification body accepts to decide
it's not like all the nodes are going to
get upgraded at the same time it might
not be possible so there might be few
nodes in the network which might be left
with the previous previous settings and
then they come up later yeah thank you
so if you're talking about backward
compatibility within one of those
tunnels yes this primary arise and
basically if your question is is there a
backward compatible text that's needed
to say for instance I'm seeing the old
flag in the back yet I put the new flag
instead or not or something or you say
the network cannot have backward
compatibility yes you could spell that
just backward compatibility section is
useful I agree with you but but flag die
and what I'm saying the standard is a
standard that embodies this must specify
how it works so okay I still think it's
okay thank you who's going to review the
document okay
Thank You Raoul what else but can
someone else
okay Thank You Georgians please read it
because it's in last column we already
have all these 24 use cases so we update
as well 81 38 when they have to
decompress they have to use the new
option okay this is the use cases for
reference okay thank you
next one is no I still have a question
this document is in very group last call
the very group has Co finished about
today as far as you know I have not seen
any reactions on the mailing list which
disappoints me a bit I must say so
please have an review the document has
been reviewed every passed I know that
there has been happy - quite a lot yeah
I know it nevertheless you also have to
go to six-month or brief before this
yeah so if you could read it look at it
also including these six like arguments
then it will be fine to have your
arguments on the mailing list
thank so much thank you very much hello
from hobby and this work is about so it
was that update last two last ITF and in
the previous IETF there were some
suggestions from Pascal Michael about
the guy about not changing the existing
bets in the Dow message and primarily
the updates are about in in that
particular context so briefly for people
who are not following this works the
work is about optimizing their out in
validation procedure so currently in RFC
esperar see for the 6 5 PI 0 the
proactive routing validation happens so
if a notes which is the parent it still
sends a no pad now from the previous
path and it's not optimal by design so
what we intend to do here is in place
the common ancestor node detects that
there is a change in the next hop and it
decides to sense a new new message
previously this used this we were
calling it no path down it's a
downstream message but in this update we
are calling it a new message type and
I'll give
rationale on why we decided to use a new
message time based on the discussions we
had previous ideas so one background as
of now all the Dow's flow upstream
except for our projection I guess and
this is the first time and maybe this is
the second time now that we have a doubt
which is going to go downstream so this
is the primary change in terms of like
overall semantics for Ripper okay
so this is the primary update so we have
a new ripple message code so previously
we are setting a particular bit in the
down message which said that if that bit
is set the message is going to go
downstream the problem with that
particular approach was it might it will
impact the existing implementations so
in the spirit of having new
implementations incrementally update
their code we decided to have a new
message type in a horrible message code
and it was been brought to my notice
that there's no message codes are
available in pain 20 so we could really
use those these bits are really reducing
so it's actually more costly to use this
bits than to use a new message cool so
we're calling it destination came up
object if people here don't like that
name it's free to change all right oh
yeah because I was talking over calling
it DC alright as of now but de comité
well as well thank you alright so these
are the rationals I've already talked
about it existing implication didn't
implementations do not need to change
and the ripple message codes are one
plaintiff also well you added a new
message along comes the ACK and you need
DCO a call so in this context
so in a way we are replicating things so
I would really like to have some
feedback from the working group on
whether we add a new message which I've
already done I've already updated the
draft to have a new message still open
but it comes with some package so now we
have what DC or ACK and one thing is not
where that is not mentioned in this
PowerPoint is you'll need also the
secure version of this so there is
something to be thought about
so if there are any specific comments
towards the send raising this one me I'm
gonna stay anyways but yeah if there are
any specific comments to this in really
like to take yeah the next steps
really we already had an implementation
but that doesn't count
it's it's a private repo the change is
trivial implementation wise it's not a
big deal yeah that's so any questions
here okay comment on that yeah yeah yeah
in fact you know we have been working
towards simulating this at a larger
scale so how it works in 500 moves as
metric lines and all this but regardless
of whatever those changes are or
whatever those numbers would be so the
basic criteria or basic design
limitation that this problem handles
that that's already there in place like
you are taking a path which is
suboptimal that's by design and we want
to improve on that
so I can give the numbers actually to
this working group maybe next time yeah
in the appendix you can have them well
sure yeah I can do that thank you thank
you for the we thank you how many people
have read this version of the draft one
two three four five
how are the main same people also
willing to do reviews of the graft
who is willing to do review of the draft
Bosco mom um okay fine
excellent someone else the more the
better
so to be nice to have to review and then
have feedback on the draft are you going
to deploy it anywhere if do you have
plans apart from the implementation that
also will be in an installation and it
plans about that I'm sorry there is an
implementation but will to be an
deployment of the in stay well yeah the
deployment is we already have a
deployment IC which uses this okay we
already have so but we don't have an
open source which has this feature okay
so that is what we are working to okay
thank you okay next one sorry I should
not call it a deployment sorry sorry to
interrupt here it's a pilot it's kind of
the result the performance in the
appendix will be very nice data okay
yeah it's our prediction so this is a
quick update on the doubt projection
most of the time I will need under our
projection will be spent on the next
presentation okay so I'm mostly a play
today I in a section actually to reflect
the new modes remember that we have now
a non-story mode thanks to request
that's most of the energy that was spent
on this was spent on the fast reroute
and I will show you why in the next
presentation so that that's about it the
biggest questions we have on this
document is not really on the document
itself but on how a controller would get
the full topology of the network so as
to to design all those project abroad so
basically this document is not a
standard document it cannot live without
the help of something
to provide the topology we have a subset
of the topology that can be obtained in
non storing mode just by looking at the
route which has all those hops tables so
we have a subset of the geotag so we can
do some routing there and our projection
there but if we want a Majin Airy case
of the projection then we would need
another protocol or some extensions to
repo to give us more information about
the the links and so I wonder if that
should be in this document as well or if
it's another document and if there is
advice in the room then Oh taking it
yeah Ravager the warming I definitely
feel that is a different document okay
are you willing to help build it yes
questions comments okay please read it
under view it ok ok please to see there
are so many people so what have we seen
we have a lots of drafts
some of the drafts are not going forward
they seem to be blocked and there seems
to be a reason for that on the other
hand we have drafts which are on the
same subject and I'm afraid that are so
interference and you should like to see
how we go forward and that's what I
wanted to discuss do not have high
expectations like we're going to solve
this today so what I wanted to know is
there is enough interest within this
working group to see how we can look at
those topics and to present a way
forward such that we have those
documents in forward and can see here we
go yeah that is the ID so no solutions
just make sure that we find some people
interested to do that yep
so we have
the topics that we have in our charter
and I use that to annotate where the
different drafts are being used about oh
this is interesting
oh that makes a difference so we have
here the topics I've separated them in
young models which has been has had lots
of progress we have a set of I think
independent topics so we won't spend
much time on it then we have in my
opinion duct manipulations which I think
we should think what they mean actually
for the deployment of the said of the
ripple and then we have bitmaps and boom
filters which is a new subject but for
which Pascal has introduced that there
are lots of solutions to go forward so I
should like to discuss those so what is
the young models I think I'm the only
one who's written try to do a draft but
I'm all alone and I don't think it is a
subject you should do all along because
about modeling and you have to have a
vision on how to do it and the working
group RTG area thinks that is important
to have these young models and I think
they are important because once you have
deployed ripple and maple etc reasoned
in the field you like to manage them and
get your information and see how well
things are going such that you can sit
back and yep so who is willing to
collaborate on these it is a bit boring
I know I tried it myself but you also
need a lot of knowledge and because you
cannot make this model just by looking
at the draft and then picking out all
the attributes I mean it's not enough
you have to know what they are what
they're doing actually so I am really
looking forward to some people
who are willing to either collaborate
with the maple one or me or to start on
the hippo Vaughn and I'm also willing to
collaborate on that volunteers so does
this also include some time back we had
a discussion on mailing list about
exposing the topology information
through some metadata does this also
include that you could include it yeah I
don't think there's any problem there
it's you get you have to network the
network has only servers where all these
maple things are happening and so you
want to get a good view of what's
happening there
as such they can make decisions about
the policy changes switching of nodes or
whatever and I think all the information
that helps you even if you have
high-level information which is not
actually described in the drafts but you
think are very useful it's there to put
in I think so you can also have to
describe how to measure it
yeah that is something that because that
that also has an impact so in a way now
projection also needs to have some
information okay but it's not fatal if
it's not be used but if you think about
that your work is going to be used later
on I think this might be very useful I
don't see any entries awesome yet same
game next subject
[Music]
so we have a set of independent topics
we have use of our people info a
eau-de-vie ripple which is use them
which I think are quite independent so
they can be put into the in the stack
and they know that there's no work
there's a flag day necessary but it
doesn't really affect all the other
protocol stuff yeah we have to forward a
select which is me I mean it's also
quite independent I'm alone I mean so if
anybody wants to help there then I will
be very happy to receive and co-author
but as long as I stay alone I don't
think it will go forward as it is
and then we have to I think that's it so
I don't think there's too much
discussion and necessary about all those
droughts
so regarding the dis modifications is
there any is there any feedback from the
author's no no yet this Pony Square
should know it I mean it is it's about
timing as far as I understood it's about
timing as far as I understood getting
the diario managed to do well so we are
free offers on this truck right now and
I think jenkees has moved to something
else so we can have we are low on
resources to to work on that but we are
still interested if anybody wants to
join and help help it moving you'd be
welcome but independent of debt that you
move forward you think independent of
having additional authors it will move
forward it will move forward but not in
the next two or three months because I'm
super busy okay then I think this is
cinder very interesting subject for this
group we have all these drafts which
talk about restoring the duck am I
correct in that and they do it for
different reasons as far as I understood
and there are different results and so
it might mean that there is no coherent
view from end user of the network or
manager of the network of which
algorithm should be used and what the
selection criteria are which you induced
I'd like to look at the example for
example of looking at the connections
and how should you optimize the routes
through the repo so you have this
measure essential so and you can have
different measures in it it's clear you
put them in and the network works like
that that's not the case here so I saw
that possibly we might have an RAF which
tells you how to modify the ducts so we
have a uniform way of handling the dark
so that it can be handled and then we
have all the day
current ways to handle them and
eventually decide how they can
interoperate in an interoperable way
such that the devant effect is reached
any suggestions about that for the
moment for me they are standalone
possibly contradictory drafts I don't
see contradiction at least in the work
group document once not in the working
group dimension so if we adopt something
later it has to be non conflicting with
existing work obviously or state that is
either oh but but we very clear on that
yeah the way you see it is that
ultimately you know we have done 6550
which was complex enough like that and
we want it to ship it so but we knew
there were things missing and the
content P Dow find since is something
that we could figure out the time or
just being able to pull some dowels from
selected targets so we don't have to
have all the states of the network when
you're on story mode we knew all those
things and we didn't act on them yet
because it will be now a number of small
additions which could be options for
instance in the final document what I
see is that in the future we'll probably
do a new repo will do will take 6550
will take all those amendments and we'll
make the internet standard for repo
right you see we'd have to take it from
normal it's the track to internet
standard and when we do that just like a
pv6 did with 8200 will package all those
documents which which became smaller of
C's and we will write the current
version of the whole thing right at the
moment all we want to do is do them one
by one make sure they fit well within
repo explain what they do and when we do
this internet standard we'll do the
packaging rightly that's how I see it
Eleni with that actually works like that
every 5-10 years they do a new presence
a to touch it info right there is a 2015
and in between the do amendments which
are small changes
these are amendments let me summarize
first understand correctly you say it's
we have two drafts they are on stand
alone they are correct and they have
described correctly it's only during the
deployment that might be interaction
which are not possible to be foreseen
and if you want to solve them we wait we
go to the understand that internet
standards what I said is as we take them
and we took to only the other ones I
still personal submission we have no
garage and we expect that they interact
without an issue right it's down design
for that unless we were very wrong they
okay and we just pick them one by one
make them arrive cease and when we happy
will do the reps eat I am 65 fifty and
we gather some experience from the field
about how the internal work and
everything then we write the internet
standard which wraps them together and
and if we found some small issues in the
field then we in the Internet's now that
would say by the way I should do this
with this one don't do that with that
one but we will take all the text and
and put it together ok fine that
understood so it's too early now and we
really have to hit need to experience to
do anything profitable here that's also
what you say so so we're looking so
there are lot of maintenance activities
that have been mentioned so you mention
additional topics that we had discussed
yes please yeah that's what I wanted to
see Adam amendments that we discussed
but I would say that would the working
group be interested in some sort of a
problem statement document before we
actually start this absolutely that was
the next stage so they had to I had to
variation this and the one is the
collaboration between the different
house I mean I understood Fusco Nazim
everybody seems to concede we first have
to gain more experience and then we if
we go to internet standard that's when
we write it up that's what we understood
fine yeah and the second one is we have
all these different treatments which are
proposed and how are we going to get
forward
from coherent view on which direction we
want to go and if there are new drafts
then we also can look at them if it fits
yeah thank you yeah that's great
anybody wants to do look on that so that
we have already this review no the based
on the discussion that we had on mailing
list the topics that was suggested I
would be interested in putting up a
problem statements document which talks
about those problems specifically what
do you think or okay all right okay so
basically what's happening Pascale again
is that we are experiencing situations
in the field or getting requirements
from some environments and with proposed
solution for those as amendments to repo
we are not incapable to say everything
that's wrong or could be updated in repo
and write the problem statement on that
I just don't know what I know is prime
by prime what we are facing we are
facing crimes like big geo tags and no
it's wanting to join it out do decade we
are talking about that at six - now
we'll bring it here we are experiment
we're experimenting packet loss when the
Doug reorganizes we want to avoid that
that the first we're not saying so each
time we experience something we try to
come up with a solution which is
compatible with what already exists and
propose that addition as an amendment to
repo but it's not like I have an O
encompassing view of everything that
people needs right so I starting with a
prime statement my view is no go we are
fixing prime which is diversity okay so
just having wiki entries for example on
the RIP on the roll wiki right by bees
efficiently so I was not suggesting
actually a major major major change to
the ripple or anything so I was
suggesting specific amendments given the
specific section an example would be the
use of DTS and the change in DTS in
number and it has to be burned out into
the device so it has to be stored in the
persistent memory well there isn't that
is not practical for my deployment is
what I
see because because the rights to the
flash are only limited DT s n changes
more frequently in case of storing mode
of operation and that's quite an issue
for me so things like this I want her to
bring out to the notice of this working
okay so Justin Vicky with all these
entries and maintaining them will be
sufficient you think yep okay that
solves my problem
then shortly so then we finally have the
CC the CC cast which has been proposed
by Kirsten who isn't here unfortunately
and there has been an alternative
example proposal by for using bloom
filters and bitmaps by a Pascal
Bosco proposes that we have different
documents so in one Barry's I see your
mouth opening so probably using the
wrong words a number of things actually
which relate to the same world and
correctly packaging them on this slide
and right today they are packaged as two
documents plus an encoding one and III
because we are this right I propose a
number a number of solution but I just I
didn't say we have we need to have two
documents I said we could do this we
could do this we could do this let's
propose that to the group and see what
the group thinks okay would put a slide
with this yes that's what I thought but
as I won't do not to have already the
decisions about which documents are
going to be down here but poorly
discussed later on the work on the
mailing list I sorta shouldn't put the
forward here yeah that was the ID is
there anyone who is interested in this
in this topic I thought it might be
interesting if you wanted to reduce
actually the the tables at set and the
headers for the during the routing so
having that and having salts awesome
good subject so I'm definitely a I don't
know the details of how be are actually
woods but I have seen the problem
statement and I've seen the initial I
have not gone through the details of
this the problem statements that it
tries to solve are pretty interesting
and it would reduce control overhead by
a big factor is what I'm trying to say
but given the fact that there are a lot
of things that are there already in that
context I don't know how to
so you mentioned about splitting the
combining mentioning all the functions
that these two document solves and then
proposing a solutions towards that did I
hear it correctly so between the seekest
and beer okay so first you got it right
there is a there's a non-coding which
takes a lot less space they are full
appear to us for unicast and mostly
multicast operation using bits which
point at each individual destination
that's beer so that you can say I want
to set it to do specific five guys just
by putting five bits in a bitmap and
sending to the bitmaps
that's yeah it's as simple as that now
the those two trucks combined in
different fashion three dimensions the
first dimension is storing the SIS non
storing right so do you write a source
right path or do you rot to explicit
destinations the second dimension is how
do you encode them do you encode them as
explicit bits like beer tells so you
have a fixed number of nodes in your
network because that the size of your
bitmap or do you express that as a bloom
filter which ICS a optimization which
gives you some more elasticity on how
many devices you can have in a network
at the price of more complexity because
you have to do all those ashing and
encoding and stuff like that distribute
the action
stuff so first dimension storing
non-story in six second dimension
encoding a bitmap and the vs. bloom and
the third one is is ears in mind that
now it's just scripts but anyway so I
must have it in my in my mail point
being that you could decide now how you
structure the work if we decide to go to
it for instance do we want sub to chest
out because it's three dimension like
nine documents you know I'm doing
storing with bloom you know that could
be many actions although you say Oh
bloom is for instance and optimization
that that goes on top of that it's
compatible with everything on the of
possible modes in which case I could say
there is a what I do without bloom and
there is how I blue eyes it'd be
optional so this is kind of the
discussion I want it to have do we want
to do storing non-story beer bloom
source route destination all those
things it is it how do you want to
structure that okay so I think we have
had those presentations from she cast
and your presentation on the last ITF I
don't see the that at this moment is
enough knowledge here to to see how do
you have to go forward may I invite you
for the next in London that you give in
20 minute presentation about all these
yep that will be very nice I would
appreciate it well have talked with
Carsten and see yeah I would really
appreciate that that would help yep
thank you very much
[Music]
okay one comment the OTB draft it's in
last call
please review and comment we need that
okay thank you
who's willing to review who ready drop
okay okay yes please because he's in the
last column so we need that your
comments okay thank you very much next
[Music]
move it's going to present
load-balancing he merged she documents
bride is the merge oh hi everybody
mama cousin from Edinburgh University
so this is the third version for the
draft and just a quick hint here we
combined in this draft to draft the
current draft
besides the who from how are we dropped
okay so we already presented this in the
previous in 98 Chicago meeting so let's
skip this and just lift these slides if
you have any question just to help me to
explain
so the a new staff started from this
slides and we added the will or we
amended the DI all by adding the in the
option Bart the do-rag metric container
in order to inject the parent address
besides those parameters and the content
of the metric of of the new metric as
you can see those parameters the flag
and the be flag which is in the case 0
and 1 whether it contains the parent
address or not depends and I will
explain this in the next slide and the
number of direct children for the CNC at
the moment it can be optimized and the
future to consider the accumulated
number of children not only the direct
number of children if the bones will see
that and the max number of children that
can hold can be whole and the parent
address optional it depends
optional or not based on the mode as you
can see here if it is in the storing
mode then the number of children can be
counted from the DAO and this is for the
upstream and the DI all just inform the
number of the data streams and the
proposed options as you can see at the
bottom of the slide however if it is in
non storing mode ok then the number of
children cannot be counted from the DAO
can be done by the io that's why we need
to inject the parent address in the d io
and from yeah ok so as you can see here
so this d io will back to this parent ok
so by injecting the parent
okay the the parent can count how many
children okay has and in this way we can
utilize the di oh okay in efficient way
to count the number of children and the
proposed rank calculation will be as you
can see from this formula okay and the
255 it indicates that this is the
maximum number of children can be the
hold cannot hold any more number of
children yes you know that for this to
work you need to change 55 50 because 95
50 says you shall ignore D is coming
from those that have a lower rank so so
what do you suggest
I'm just saying the drawing yeah you're
saying that the parent will receive a DI
yo from a child and read into that
packet and discover that parent address
in this cow it's being used as a current
uh-huh but all these mechanics will only
happen if the parent looks into that
packet and right now 65 50 says it will
ignore that back ok so just make sure
you would change 55 50 thank you well
consider that thank you very much he
sent deos
upwards these days we sent daos upwards
today okay thank you very much so yeah
and for the sake of
stability issue actually here we can use
another metric along with the number of
children so this is not the sole okay
metric okay to optimize the load
balancing and here I want just to
highlight very important point we are
not here measuring the accurate 100%
traffic we are here just to optimize the
traffic because this is random
deployment and we are not counting it is
indirect it is indirect and direct just
we can optimize the traffic as much as
possible in this way yes can you show me
the previous slide now again yeah the
one with a rank so so if I have more
children my rank augments so if I if I
have a new child my rank will go up is
that is that yes you're on goes up you
need to detach from the dude I can
reattach later well this is as I said
the rank for if we consider the only the
number of children in this for the
calculation but we can use the other one
beside it but that was my question right
it's not just for watching
no is it it is not maybe you use that
for watching you will get interesting
results right hmm okay okay so so let me
give some some background information
here which is coming from six dish so
for the last 2-3 ietf six dish has been
considering some primes we have in the
field again which have to do for
instance if I have too big do tags or
one smaller than the other and that is
not that needs to join which of those to
do tags if he sees both which one should
he join and so it's a problem we have in
the field we we thought that there are
multiple reasons why
a note should join dag on the left or
the dag on the right oh the parent on
the left or the parent on the right
which is kind of the question that my
mood is asking us today Ian so so what
six dish said is very clearly that the
metric that expresses the willingness to
be joined by a parent has nothing to do
with its routing ranek which is what I
want to extract from you and to confirm
because in one hand it's how good it is
to join this node or to join this new
dag and on the other hand it's the
position of a node without within a
structure you for watching nothing to do
and the other thing is okay in the
thinking you need metrics to build this
new thing which is not iraq we call it a
joint willingness or something like that
and it looks a lot like the metrics we
use for ranks right we want to spread
them so an example of metrics is how
many packets per second on the route
because the load of the geotag is mostly
expressed by the load on the root right
so if I have to do tags whatever their
sides are signs if one has twice the
packets at the root and the other has I
want to join the least loaded regardless
of the size regardless of number of
children grandparents and family right
but but it may be that in certain
situation the number of nodes in the do
diet plays a role because there's
management cost or it may be that the
number of children plays a role so you
see there are a number of metrics which
affect the willingness for a particular
node to be joined for instance of an
India storage I have to store the towel
in story mode right stuff like that so
so there are many metrics they are not
useful routing there are different
metrics but we could propagate them
through metric containers that seems to
make a lot of sense and we would like to
advertise that to note which one to join
the this these parents which advertises
this so it sits next to the ranch but
it's used just for the desire of joining
so we are working on that we are trying
to express the metrics we'd like to see
there we are trying to express how that
could be going down you know from the
upper layers the rotting layer well this
is understood from the matrix to the
lower layer all the way down to the
beacons so that it can be expressed in
the beacons that you hear when you
decide to join the network so we're
trying to look at that and when we're
ready and when we understand what we
really want to do then we probably will
come to roll and say a in this other
whole design that we see there is we
need those metric containers why don't
we piggyback them into repo we need this
in the g io - that has to be put in
maybe in EBS or whatever is is 15 for
but but we are doing this design it's
it's only in the process we are not
ready to to come here and say we want
this if it's your question but but we're
getting there we have a draft Richardson
we have interesting talks on the mailing
list and and so we are working on that
the number of children is not by
experience the most interesting thing
but it's useful in story mode decide
know how much if for instance there are
two parents which are equal for already
everything else I would pick the one
with the least children but first I
would pick the geotag with the less
traffic I would pick the geotag which is
smaller globally not just the children
of this before at and then you know all
things being a qua maybe I would look at
the number of children that's one of
those things which I look at so so this
is work which we are doing at 6 - if you
want to look at what we are doing and
participate to the 60 spanning list and
then at some point yes we expect to be
coming to you going to I Triple E as
well to do that in an ie of things like
that but it really has to do with join
nothing to do with repo should not be
that's right having a question talking
about this this information you want to
provide you a tizzy layer 2 or the layer
3 with a drowning I mean 66 a job or
role job ok what I just said it's just
same prime as the arrays at some point
we want to abstract what we see and
understand be with complex matrix at the
barrios into a no pack that we can carry
in the lower lower layers because what
no dlcs is a charm is a beacon so at
some point we want to be able to express
some information from the rata rotting a
router advertisement and some
information like this from the DAO into
in a compressed concise form into a to
merge eb pockets and the kind of dia
route information before me in one yes
we want to be able to encode some of
this information down into the the
beacon and that's what these drug free
chats on join thing does john priority
or whether it's coffee because that's a
big under did you I see but how we build
it is not an eye Tripoli crime but when
we when we encode it it becomes a
discussion with the at record because we
want to fit it into the directly effect
also no back okay let's go thanks I will
take a look at 60 thank you much yes
Thank You Pascal for introducing the
work in 60 but I have a question because
that the scenarios that can be used in
60 is narrow as far as I not can only be
used in the industry monitoring so if
you're saying that there is a work down
to balance they they load in 60 and I
think we can say the 60s can't it's just
like you are solving a problem in an
arid scenario but now we're talking
about and more right I mean now we are
talking about the repo so yeah you can't
solve it in sixties but but why not saw
this in this working group okay thank
you question
to make a small statement that is the
stack which is produced in six dish can
be used in other situations as well and
it works as well and probably maybe that
the restriction six sticks are not
considered but the writer said it will
be very nicely used okay just a filter
and just to say that this dish is the
working group where the joint is being
done ryuuji it's not because of times
that each and they're happening it has
to do with the fact that some group had
to do the joint process so we are
looking at the joint process what is the
security of the joint process what are
the flows for the joint process we get
two working group documents which what
one is we basically enema for IOT and
the other ones basically PSK variety
right so in that context basically six
is doing it is doing it for IOT at large
and as we are doing it realized that
part of the drying process is to select
a node that we're going to join and in
that context which again has nothing to
do with the seh and nothing much to do
with 15-4 in general just the fact that
we want to encode it in an ie at the end
of the day we consider what causes a
node to be modular the one you want to
join and the prime I am addressing I
found them in Y son not in six - okay
thank you very much okay so as I said
here okay so by using a stresses
threshold we can just control and the
number of children that we can hold for
each node based on the application
requirements so you can K set up the
threshold according to the application
requirements and as I just want to
highlight a very important point
caressed by Dominique regarding the
energy metric container for this stuff
actually yes we could use the metric
container for that and this is the
expected balancing after the after using
this metric but for the energy okay we
can see here there's a congestion okay
four not three and as you can see here
from this slide so all these nodes
okay and I done this by Kentucky
simulator right so when we have this
scenario all these nodes goes to three
and left to only with one child so now
three it is congested with all these
nodes okay now three if we use the
energy metric between three and two to
optimize the load balancing yes we could
do that but when when the energy of
three dropped or a drain or almost very
close to die then those node will be
handed over to two we are trying in this
draft to avoid this situation it's not
necessary to reach the threshold of
energy for three in order to hand over
these nodes or the sharing nodes to to
okay from the beginning once the dude
egg okay established or constructed okay
then we have to consider from the
beginning this issue to avoid this case
so this is the main point or the key
point from this draft happy to take any
feedback
how many minutes we left yeah totally
agree if you're on a balanced a network
you should use a metric that balances
the network but just one coming back in
the situation you described the note
three doesn't need to be close to dying
for the
to refer the tree to rebalance based on
the energy metric because this is a
8-bit value so you can start doing
something after she passed percent of
difference of energy between two and
three and the other thing is and I told
you this before the meeting just because
your draft states I'm doing the load the
the tree balancing stuff in order to
preserve and at all time you want to
achieve lifetime then use a lifetime
metric yes thank you I will add this in
the context of the elf the draft just
differently I want to have a balanced
tree yeah like a metric or the energy
metric in some scenarios there could be
problems like for example for the Y
sound they are aiming to have a natural
ten years but if one we saw this if we
want to solve this problem in one day
and then we cannot use this that time
yes thank you dick basically what
mahmoud said with which I agree is that
at the beginning of times notice to join
a parent and it's a joint time problem
and that's why we are working on the
join time metric at six days and like I
said there are many reasons why you
would want to compute this in the
fashion on other that's how it resembles
a rank depending on what you want to
achieve you have objective functions to
compute ranks and you need to have some
joint functions to compute a join
willingness which will depend on which
matrix your care for I take this example
if the guy on the left
not for is sending one packet per minute
and each of the guys on the right are
sending one packet per year I would say
that the loaded guy is the guy on the
left right and and it's so it really
depends on your network you have to
decide how your objective function run
works to compute around you have to
decide how your joint function works to
compute the joint
willingness which is what we are trying
to express right
that's six - completely agree yeah yeah
oh thank you now I remember my second
point which was please do write
objective functions that make use of the
diag metric container because in the
past I've seen too many of those just
ignoring the dmg I like it that you can
only go what sorry yeah I have seen if
you look at the existing objective
functions either just ignore the engine
all right you know
Oh f zero says I'm just doing hot count
and I don't need a TNT for that and and
SFX well and mr. X says I'm going to use
ATX and I don't need a dmg so please do
writing one that does use them gee I'd
love that as a co-op see all right thank
you very much but no half half talking
in your draft you say comparing to
previous situations
comparing to EDX excetera we are doing
better but again I think we haven't
exploited the full potential of the dmz
yet because nobody has ever used those
metrics you know the bit energy bit
whatever we have a whole toolbox ovation
that nobody used before I'm glad that
you get venturing into that all right
Arina
okay thank you very much the last point
just want to highlight that in terms of
the deployment okay Derrick and they're
all done some bloomin stuff in so we are
trying to and they tested it on the
smart meters devices and so we are
ongoing in this process
that's one thank you thank you very much
thank you
just for my information who has read the
draft or this version of the graph oh
very good
okay thanks that's we're about six seven
people are thinking please take out the
discussion into the mailing list so we
can have in the menu list that
discussion and we can compare with the
other sixteen approach and the metrics
that already are available it would be
nice if you can put in the appendix the
performance that you have with your
proposal and how it will be with these
kind of other with the methods that
already exist you know if your proposal
doesn't exist what how can we handle
with what whatever we we have already
pronounced compare and see how is the
performance with the comparison okay
thank you okay sorry
there John he's going to present then
you work hello everyone my name is
George papadopolis and I'm going to
present a draft I wrote together with my
colleagues Ari's Nicola and Pascal to
bear and the topic is related with the
extension of node States and attribute
[Music]
the context we are working here in the
area of the very music networks where
the networks in addition to be reliable
we need to be
to reduce the idiot at minimum to show
one of the potential solutions is the
packet application elimination and the
concept of theory is about each node for
2008 it's it's single data packet and
resume the ones to his default what we
call reporting and to his alternative
parent this is the application procedure
and then on the other side when a node
will receive multiple copies of a single
data packet he will eliminate the
following copies to reduce the
unnecessary traffic applied is the
overhearing procedure meaning what when
is transmits to a node simply note of a
may overhear this information due to the
nature of the wireless the broadcast
[Music]
information of the opponent a maker here
like this we increase the probability of
this information to manage to
destination so in in 60s working with
Wii Remote what's called requirements
set of requirements to talk of appearing
to be implemented and to work correcting
and some of them are the hot select the
default selection and what are the
requirements to do for this about the
permissible hearing sales without
acknowledgement since you're
transmitting and one will acknowledge
the other overhearing node will not
acknowledge which things to be discussed
the elimination issues
so in this draft we focused on the first
item here on the alternative parent
selection but not specifically how to
select a point rather than how to extend
this di information there you message so
that provide information regarding the
parent we would set all the call to go
[Music]
in the options for the so ask us it's
the four opponent a from the from the
ripple acres D and because II as a
associative opponent then what happens
is that a may have an addition to a
which is default appearances be as a
potential is not in his parents said no
rights or potential
and similarly because he's default word
of the day which is here underlined and
c-e-o he's including his part and said
finally we have note B which works in
the same principles cuz he's es default
button and a is what member of its
parent said what we do here is by
default message transmitted everything
this operation then every time when aim
is sent out within the area with the
container and say what we can define
here this part of mod set so every see
is look at here my button sets or CD in
and the same way they will say message
is in his neighborhood this is my policy
now when it comes time to this to pick
up his alternative parenchyma chick okay
this is my the for pointing from google
right and there is the full equation
this is more comfortable to call it
since I receive information from beans
way and I can check that they is very
opaque okay so what we trying to
construct here is the letter based or
postcode calls topology so if the end of
the day we're having one common ancestor
between R and B which is the organ for
pests so then s we pick up know dennis
boren be in the same way we have for the
other guy so a week of his own day as a
default and so whatever will be see in
the same principles and main work of
again people and d through our audio
message what when constructed here
so this is to summarize that we're
covering the four part and the
alternative
thanks to this da-jung message which we
implemented this planet mode set in V
everything these NSA object and we sell
via we are able to pick up our
alternative parents in order to employ
packet replication elimination procedure
so again not that this is small port
within the larger scope of pachyderm
education elimination there are more
works to be done and yes we
complementation Contiki OS and yeah some
questions further there are like to
review and previously so no D is the
common ancestor at the same hop as a and
it has it is mandatory to have in
communication sorry this node B is a
common ancestor for a and B it has to be
on the same hop though for this to work
right so no de Saussure and B Ola just
it has to so if there is no common
subset then this one this would then
there is no way to identify then there
is no way to do packet about application
you're right alright so one more thing
is in case of high densities network yep
yep so there is a limit on how many
parents said how much of how big parents
at you can send never strong so during
during explanation you might have came
across the strong push power how you're
perfect you're right
doing this in the distributed fashion is
harder so that's why if we can manage to
do this centralized vision of the
topology we can do a lot better job at
this from a centralized perspective but
this is the way we can do it
decentralized ideally for packet
replication the best the best way to
have I mean I don't know the solution
here but the best way to have is have a
complete disjoint path all the way till
border router if somehow that is that
possible again it's it's it's a lot
worse than that the scale again what you
see I mean churches did not have time to
tell you the whole story there's a big
story
part of the story is you don't want any
virus what you see is correct but we are
doing Wireless we have a lot lot lot lot
more lost on each hub but yes Wendy
sends to e you see this green arrow they
can be this day and so you balance you
balance the lumps that you have on the
direct path with redundancy and the I'll
type a so you really do P re at each hub
[Music]
because you eliminate the packet so you
wait for the two copies and then you set
up I have a draft in John 6 is working
which decays only because I was applied
unicast but using multiple things at the
same time to increase reliability for
the exact same reasons that you are
advocating yesterday so so that's what
we are doing actually with this thing if
it's centralized computation we also
practice that it works really well and
we have the video ratio with in due time
which is critical for determinism
becomes good I need to mention her chair
there is IPR behind this there is IPR
behind us for this topology please don't
name state their name their name shall a
way you can eliminate replication so the
idea is this is one of the requirements
right if I'm going box again when to
talk each in each packet the sequencer
so when you're going to the
[Music]
okay so so ishyama is telling us that
network coding works they are - and yes
I mean what we are doing now is topology
we are building a topology which enables
replication and elimination which is one
way of doing redundancy coding is
another basically see this as a form of
flooding we build something which looks
like a ladder you see and now you flood
it and it's not more flooding when you
flood something you see a second copy of
what you already flood you discard it
there are tons of history and now you do
flooding and how you limit eliminate the
duplicate copies of flooding you can do
basic flooding with the original frames
you can do Network coding you can do
anything you like the problem we have
here is just to build a structure
there's a limited number of links on
which you will apply those techniques
and so it's it's sort of an ode to the
fact that you decide to the network
coding one plus one redundancy or
redundancy at every house et cetera that
comes later
with you you asked some questions at the
end if it's interesting yep well this is
a very good question who has read the
draft it's originally in 60s draft but
who has read it okay have you heard the
presentation are there any people
interested to review it to work on it no
now I'm happy to review it
thank you okay
three the subject is using this group
and that is vision is Charter so great
let's talk about it many stories think
so much okay so earlier we discussed
about beer for repo thank you we
discussed about Sdn for ripple with the
Dow projection we discussed bf re-poll
now we just discussed that net for repo
so maybe maybe it's time to discuss the
spirit variable just to make sure we've
got complete picture okay so let's talk
about far out for a minute so what the
prom is so you get this dude I hear that
you are lucky you can see but I can't
and so I have the isolated this node
here which had a single parent bad luck
and that happens in do dogs and this guy
loses its last parent so that that's
when you enter this phase in repo
whereby you have to reparent to a node
which is lower than you are which means
you have to go through all those
poisoning or freezing thing which which
is the pain of any distance-vector
protocol so basically you have to
isolate a number of nodes which are
impacted by the fact that you lost your
parents basically all the nodes which
didn't have much tuition with you to go
to the destination and you have to
freeze them until you have repented of
one of them are apparently that you can
find a new exit pass through them
and the prime is with ripple it's gonna
take some time because you have to
poison wait for the resulting of
poisoning and then look at where you are
and when you know where you are you have
isolated or the impacted though then
from there you can rebuild something and
the problem we have at six dish because
we are building some networks which we
want variable is that sometimes we can't
afford to lose this packet and this
window of time for the distance vector
to reconstruct a new path is too
expensive so we are looking at doing
fast reroute which is this technique by
which you you go around the problem to a
point where the problem is no more so so
you have to find a way to go to go back
maybe or tunnel somewhere to a point
which is not affected by the disruption
that's a generic thing that first we
wrote does so that's that's why we have
this other insertions that are being
discussed at 6-man you know the fault
which does so starting to to that point
where the prom is avoided instance okay
so that's pretty much the problem how
can you keep forwarding packets and
possibly find a new parent which does
not create a loop faster than just
waiting for the methods that ripple has
today so there are basically two
approaches that we have been discussing
at six - and so I'm presenting them to
you and I was and we will see what could
be done within roll if we decide to take
this bus so the first thing that we
looked at is whether we well there is a
zero thing actually but I Simon is not
there with us Simon is claiming that in
most times I mean the the loops that
ripple creates by attaching lower the
packet can stain that look till the new
parent is found and sometimes the
brought the packets are not yet
destroyed and new parent is found so he
said that sometimes that saves the day
we can't claim it safe that every time
but it may happen right so we don't lose
every packet in the situation some are
caught in a loop till the loop is
resolved but that's when it's very slow
when there are very few packets right so
apart from that the sort of thing we've
been looking at we have looking at two
approaches one years the current
stinking of Freeport is to do things in
the data path
we already have this ripple packet
information in ripple which allows you
to detect that there are some writing
errors we've got like three flags in the
RPI
that allows you to know if there is
doubt or not or if your packet is going
down when should be going up and so you
have an inconsistency and based on this
it can see it consists in consistency
you can repair so we already have some
data path information in ripple which
triggers the routing but which detects
the error so we thought hey why don't we
use the data path to see whether by
exploring my children I effectively find
a path to the route which which avoids
me to wait for the freezing with the
risk that I choose wrong the child but
then I detected I eliminate it and I
take the next chart see basically rather
than waiting to be sure that this child
is usable let's try to use the shot
children we have and see if that creates
a loop let's pretty much the idea if it
does not create a loop then I can repair
onto this guy and I'm all set so the
first and there are two sub approaches
to that the first is on this screen here
and it basically says let me put a new
bits and we have one bit left in the API
so it's okay
let's let's use the bit to indicate that
we are sending the packet the other way
that we are we are sending the packet
down so when if we see it again it means
we sent it to the wrong child let's not
use that one so you basically you pick a
child
whichever and you say let me see if that
child does that that guy is Montessori a
child that guy is my child if he's my
child's gonna loop if it's my grandchild
etc it's gonna loop but if it's not my
grandchild if it's just somebody lower
than me but not my grandchild then it's
not gonna loop is a feasible successor I
can refer unto him rapidly right so you
want to discover that situation so what
you do is you effectively tag the
backyard say oh that packet went through
me I and you you you select one of those
guys and if you see the packet coming
back then this guy cannot be used at
speak another one and it's just just a
little trace that you place in the
packet okay so that's that's basically
you see this year the approach works
Rahul Rahul
but how do how does the parent know that
that the pbut was said or any-any flag
was set by itself but it does not it
will just drop the packets when they
come back he may actually basically the
idea is you expect only one breakage
right so you're the one in front of the
breakage to expect there is not another
breakage which which is being fixed at
the same time if there is too bad for
the guy below but the point is you want
to solve it's just you know something to
try to do something faster I'm not
saying it solves multiple breakage at
the same time etc you expect one
localized localized one breakage so you
just pick one child and you try it so
you send frames and if you see one of
those frames coming back you say wrong
child otherwise you keep sending your
traffic there and if it's if it's an
okay child your traffic will effectively
take it go to its destination with a bit
down so in the same context but if
there's a genuine drop somewhere sorry
drop off the packet if that packet is
dropped you don't see it you will say
another packet if that other packet
comes back then you know it's wrong
child but but maybe you know after after
the life of the packet is what it is you
show that this packet will live with
this bit on so if there is as you said
because your eyes are eating the prime
correctly if there is another breakage
later the second guy who sees this
packet may think is the one who said the
bit and in that case you will discount
the packet and say I picked the wrong
child so - - that might be confusion is
out - breakage that time and and the
next slide will solve it so I don't want
to spend too much time charlie okay so
this is my mood do you want to talk on
this slide just a bit it's in here the
picking the child based on what randomly
yeah and for how long
oh well till you the freezing source so
there's a certain time no it's just that
repo will solve this eventually it's
just that there is a short window of
time till you're apparent where where
you don't have a parent you're in this
situation where you're looking for
advantage it's like looking for a job
and during that sort of window you
should drop the packets
but rather than dropping them you say
hey let me hope and pick one guy who is
lower than me because I see nobody I
oughta well
higher than me so let's pick one flag
the packets as being tentative and and
if the packets come back think that it's
me that said the bit and say the guy to
whom I passed the packet I'm passing the
packets right now is not a good guy let
me pass the packet somebody else it does
number of drawbacks I just wanted to
mention it right it's very hard for
instance it when you switch and you see
a packet coming back it might be one
which went through the old path so that
there are a number of little windows
race conditions which are not too keen
but is just to mention that gives you an
idea of this sort of thing I want to do
in this type of case
just good just to optimize the selection
rather than optimizing the solution
could be pick the lowest Frank because
that's the guy which you know if first
the lowest Frank could be the if it's a
child then it's probably a direct child
if it's direct child that it will just
send you the packet back you can
eliminate it that's what I drew it's
only when you you have to dig deeper
then then you you may have a grandchild
and it's harder right so but the normal
case is you pick somebody with yeah yes
Frank possible that's what you want yes
you're right so that's it for the very
basic idea now that is that is just
using the existing traffic and you and
like we discard discussed its drawbacks
the alternate is to generate traffic to
send a probe but you generate yourself
so now you know it's yours because
you're so service is you right and
basically what you do is you ping the
route we are a number of selected other
guys so you pick like those three four
guys with the ideas Frank that you can
still see and you send a packet to the
route and you see if it goes back or if
the route responds if the route responds
you're very sure that this part this guy
is a feasible successor you can repair
it if the packet comes back
well you eliminate this guy from your
list and you pick others see so that
solves
number of the problem that we have just
seen in the initial case but you have to
generate new trafficking and so it's
basically an explorer of all the guys
behind you to see if one of them is
actually not parented via you if one is
found then you just switch to him and
then ripple will so you went down maybe
you went down too low
but now ripple will allow you to go back
up right and well that's it
and then ripple as you go down so some
other node will decide to stay with you
or move away etcetera that's no more
ribbon operation okay that's basically
what we could do in Charlie do you still
have a question or I see you well sort
of waiting to see if you would answer
the question but it seems like to me
what you have is a undesigned whereby
you're going to sort of eliminate
potential oops
other neighbors one by one and see until
you find out what the first method yes
the second is just you select a few of
them you ping the route through all of
them in power so the second one is not
one by one this is when you pick the
route so you could go into ping
multicast a big world this is a series
of unicast really so you just say I have
fought four guys which I think I hope
one of them is Sasebo I just ping the
routes throughout them bang bang bang
bang and the ping that comes back to me
from the route tells me that this guy is
useful the I can use any of them till I
don't know better the first packet that
comes back to me without going to the
route I eliminate directly I can still
use the other and the first which comes
back from the route now tells me oh this
one is definitely feasible it's the same
thing just by requesting a route to
whatever destination you want and then
they went insane Tintin
it seems to me you could pretty much
accomplish the same thing but saying I
want a route to a particular destination
and if it gets back to the route well
the route is likely to have a round
but if it gets back yummy you mean story
mode yeah I mean I talked about the
message it in in on storing mode any
message to any destination would pretty
much get that no no solution would be an
e phone on story mode mine works in any
case by pinging the route I'm sure that
I'm going higher than I am if you knew
by by heart
somebody was higher than you are then
then you could okay you could ping your
previous parent and that would work but
I don't know if it's much better
maybe smokers Li so if we free
optimization space we can discuss on the
meaningless like Peter said okay on
weekends
that just gives you that just gives you
ideas on how that can be done in the
data plane I'm not saying it's a fine
assertion I'm just throwing ideas at you
right yeah the other one which is more
of impact to us is basically to apply
centralized computation and probably
arcs to compute Plan B's in which case
in which case the doubt projection draft
is impacted a little bit thank you very
much
that was good so please go through the
slides we probably will do them next
time and I'll be glad to come back if
you invite me so we discussed the data
plane and there is a forwarding sorry
the writing plane cultural plane
solution which which can do the same
thing and we'll discuss it but it
impacts the whole projection that's why
we good thank you very much okay we are
running over so thank you very much to
everyone please keep this discussion in
the Middle East and we yeah I think
you'll continue and we certainly have to
maybe organizing and discussion session
next to the the normal world meeting so
we have to roll meeting may represent
the current drafts and we may have a
discussion meeting that we discuss all
these subjects
so that you can come to an common
conclusion there is that possibility as
well yep but look here you look at the
mailing list nothing happens it fills up