all right this is the sag security area
Advisory Group meaning if you intend to
be in a different room please
find the room otherwise we are gonna get
started we have a really tight agenda
today because of the exciting sect
dispatch experiments so let's see I
think then note well note the note well
and and the other policies that go along
with the IPR ones can you hear me now
all right great so welcome to sag note
the note well and the IPR and other
policies that are within this and we'll
get it up on the screen just a moment
so I'm Kathleen Moriarty and this is
Eric ware scoreline all right
now we are good to go thank you so
here's our agenda for today we're just
gonna run through our usual
administrivia and then we have one
invited talk so thank you to mince up
hang well it's off again is that better
no okay so all right I can hear it
echoing so just some be very very close
alright so we'll run through our usual
administrivia and then we have one
invited talk and this is by min-suk king
on inter-domain DDoS mitigation
potentials challenges and solutions so
that will be right after the
administrivia and we're gonna run
through our working groups and thank you
because I think we have almost all of
the reports so we're just gonna breeze
through this to try to give more time to
sec dispatch ace we have the report Acme
thank you for sending it curdle thank
you for sending it dots thank you I to
an ACEF thank you I thank you I'd be
stuck me Thank You kitten Thank You
lamps it's gonna be the fastest time we
get through this Thank You Miele thank
so off openpgp didn't meet Oh is it
close do we hit the close button alright
congratulations we will update the slide
yeah good job Zack um thanks second--
is somebody here from second vent that
could get up at the mic I think that's
the only one we don't have second en't
going once going twice
I will make sure it goes out to the list
TLS thank you for turning that around so
quick yep
I took line thank you trans thank you
and related working groups so here we'll
just breeze through we have a bunch of
them that got sent to the list already
if you have something important you
think should get shared with a security
area if you could please and you
represent one of these please go to the
mic and I can say them in case you can't
see them so anima and I don't care what
order I just have to restate which which
related working group anima Dee bound
dime dispatch Demark deprived HTT biz
quick net comp ntp perk radix cider TCP
Inc and Utah any of those I think some
of them we should get some reports that
we haven't seen going one
going twice alright so related CFR G we
didn't get a report does anyone want to
give a quick summary hmm IRT F open
proof sec I don't think there's a report
to give we didn't have a meaning this
time and w3c all right I guess with that
I think let's see what the next box so
we had to and I believe both reports oh
I know we have a report for suit already
so thank you for sending that and and
the t p-- both made their report in just
in time thank you
alright presentations min-suk if you
could please come up we'll swap over to
your slides and look forward to your
presentation did I set a record that was
there was progress there okay ah hello
can you hear me back there okay pink box
Thanks okay good afternoon everyone my
name is min su Kyung I'm from National
University of Singapore local and I'm
also a first attendee of the IETF I'm
enjoying this first-time event for me
and today I'm going to talk about our
ongoing project very recent ongoing
project on the inter domain DDoS
mitigations and I'm really happy to
discuss this with you guys with ITF
community because I believe that this is
this topic is especially related to some
of the working groups including the OTS
and the teep is it working
okay cool and as I said this is our
ongoing work so if you have any
suggestion feedback and you know
anything after that the talk just please
let me know that would be really helpful
and I have a quicker so as many of you
already know you know large scale
volumetric attacks are so common these
days and they often congest more than
one networks and they on the internet
and we've seen the escalation
mm-hm no I need to wake it up frequently
[Music]
hello cool thanks
so we've seen the escalation and volume
of ddos attack traffic you know we've
seen 300 gig in 2013 and 1.2 tera last
year so huge increase and the volumetric
attacks often flood upstream autonomous
systems as well according to a recent
Arbor networkers report and worse yet
there has been couple of advanced link
flooding attacks from academia including
crack or melt and crossfire attack the
claims to be able to you know lunch
flooding attacks against the links
they're connecting multiple aliases or
even the you know links inside on AES so
this entire domain DDoS mitigation
sometimes becomes really necessary for
large-scale against a large-scale
volumetric attacks and in particular
inter-domain packet filtering operation
is often necessary when interes links
are flooded because and and then they
you know ejs cannot do anything about it
and large portion of AES is just flooded
and they have no capability to you know
filter those traffic so they need to ask
they're up streams and typical form of
this inter-domain packet filtering is
this outsourcing mechanism that is on
AES asks another AES for packet
filtering and the state of the art of
this kind of outsourcing is has been you
know noticed recently by AT&T and the
CenturyLink you know so they they
announced in the last nanog meeting last
month they announced that they've been
working on the automated packet
filtering outsourcing between the two
AES is for DDoS mitigation and of course
IETF thoughts is has been really doing
great job in in you know standardizing
common channels for inter domain
coordination so when you talk about the
inter domain mitigation for DDoS
actually the Holy Grail really the holy
grail of the inter domain mitigation is
what we call the source and filtering
where destination AES directly talks to
the AES
that are actually serving those
potential attack sources by directly
saying that hey please drop XYZ packets
and then you know so say yes okay okay I
will set up you know some firewall or
packet filters and then the packet are
you know dropped at the source AES and
the meeting that the leaders attacked at
the destination is mitigated and this is
actually an ideal form of DDoS
mitigation because it really stops the
the attacks earlier by outsourcing the
filtering to the source AES and a couple
of examples including you know D word or
stop it you know in terms of you know
academic projects there has been clear
advantages reduction of bandwidth waste
because you stop the attack you know at
the source not at the destination so you
can save lots of bandwidth and you can
cut you can reduce the cost and also
some resource demanding filtering
operations like complex complicated rate
limiting can be also and we you know
executed at the source is because source
a is is not under attack but destination
is under attack so they have resource
also some local context at the sources
can be used can be utilized for example
the source is may know some you know
user suspect you know list of user
suspects under their customer networks
so it can be actually used so this
source and the filtering looks really
fine but this has not been deployed in
the current internet due to the lack of
trust between aliases so what do I mean
by this is simple source AES and
destination a yes they actually mutually
untrusted the reason is that they have
there is no direct business relationship
between the so CAS and the destination
is is they are you know multiple AES
hops away from each other they are
basically random guys on tape on the
internet and there's no direct agreement
between the two so they mutually
distrust each other and this these
mutually under untrusted AES may launch
attacks to each other for example the
source a is on the left hand side may
try to modify the requested policy from
the destination AES you know the the the
request and even worse it can may leak
the requested policy from the
destination AES
also the sources may not have any strong
incentive for doing this for the source
AES I mean yeah because you know
filtering operation at the source AES
incurs non negligible cost
so really the source a is needs a strong
incentive to do that but we don't have
we don't see the strong incentive for
this and worse yet there is a risk of
dropping packets for the source on
behalf of others so at the end of the
day the source is helping the
destination at AES which is you know
random guys on the internet and it the
source is may be blamed for dropping its
own customers packet at the end of the
day so to that end we believe that in
order to actually implement this source
and filtering we really need to think
about the collaboration rather than the
outsourcing so what that means is that
source and the destination is is
collaboratively determining the
filtering policies so if as you can see
in this animation you know destination a
s submits its own policy if you're doing
policy to the source AES and at the same
time source yeah yes submits its own
policy its own filtering policy to this
the the packet filtering mechanism and
the those two policies are composed into
the composed policy PSD here and this
composed policy is used to filter
traffic for the DDoS attack at the
destination AES and we believe that this
collaboration pure collaboration
architecture provides a significant
incentive to the source is because
source a is now can express its own
policy and for its own customers for
example let's say the source AES has
some premium customer or
mission-critical service that he really
wants to protect when there is an attack
again attacks at the destination a yes
and now the source has a opportunity is
a capability to express that and really
enforce that but as we try to really
implement this you know pure
collaboration operation we immediately
faces a couple of
security challenges first how to really
how can we really guarantee the fare
policy competition between the two you
know so say yes and then destination a
is and at the end of the day they are
untrusted they they don't trust each
other how can we do it in a fair manner
second how can we protect the sensitive
filtering policies from each other you
know those two untrusted AES is I mean
their own policies independently created
policies and it is combined and in some
way and how how do we guarantee the
privacy of those policies and the third
what if the source is who's actually
executing the the filtering operation
wants to bypass stuff packet filtering
when it doesn't like the decision of the
packet filtering so these three you know
security concerns are really the major
concerns we discovered and we've we just
summarized that I know a couple of
desired properties for this so first
property we really need to have here is
what we call the verifiable fairness so
that is policy composition of the two
must be fair and verified by both source
and destination aliases so again this is
a collaborate collaborate on platform
not the outsourcing platform so the
fairness really is the key between the
two untrusted AES and by fair what we
mean by is that we find we try to find a
middle ground between the two policies
two independent policies so in this very
simple example on the left hand side
there's a source a s source a yes may
have four policies I mean I'm sorry for
flows and the top top one is the higher
pass of higher priority and the bottom
one was has a low priority you know for
one ABCD and destination AES may have
different policy in different order I
mean for for simplification we we assume
that they have same flow definitions but
as a as we compose those two different
policies we may come up with compose
policy that is roughly in the middle
ground between the two so that's the
roughly the idea of course we have a you
know
better definitions in our working papers
so that may be the more important part
is that the 2a aces should be able to
verify that the fair competition and
enforcement of their policies are there
and should be really verifiable by the
two untrusted aliases
so that's property number one and the
second desired property is that
filtering policy of each AES must be
protected from each other with some prop
privacy guarantees the reason is really
simple you know filtering policies are
inherently sensitive for example you
know the the Preferences of the
filtering rules could be from private
contracts between aliases or propriety
algorithms or the the policy rules may
leak some of the attack information for
example which is which customer is
actually under attack or you know it may
leak some vulnerable points of them
their networks also it may leak some
intern internal whitelist and blacklist
policies of their you know that which
they never want to reveal to any other
AES in the world so what we want to have
is just to have some negotiation
mechanism - that guarantees some level
of degree of privacy lastly you know
third desired property is simply just to
make this bypassed attack impossible so
in other words sources may want to evade
this this filtering policy but we need
to have this what we call the number
pass ability property so that any
filtering operation must be invoked for
all packets from sources to the
destination a is so to that end we
actually built a design and build this
middle box based filtering mechanism and
we believe that this is a really
practical design choice for rapid and
widespread deployment so in this simple
diagram on the left hand side there's a
source a is on the right hand side
destination is again they are you know
far away from each other they don't
trust each other of course and our idea
is that we put the middle box inside the
source IES and this can be very I mean
right next to the egress router
and simply they it receives two
independent policies from the two
networks source and destinations and the
policies could be you know 5-tuple flow
definitions and with some priorities it
could be some other things but as an
example that could be a policy and it is
composed into the common policy and
which can be fit into the classification
and the rate limiters so there could be
multiple rate limiters for each traffic
classes and so what when this middle box
receives the incoming packets from the
source and to the destination again the
destination is under attack and this
nation is requesting some you know
packet filtering and based on this
composed policy they they block I mean
they drop some of the packets in other
words right maybe some of the packets
and then the remaining packs will go to
the destinations so it actually we built
this everything with a commodity
hardware and we could achieve multi
gigabit per second throughput and the
two major functions
I mean control plane functions and data
plane functions are protected within the
trusted execution environment so trusted
execution environment or te e is used
because these capabilities the memory
isolation or X isolated execution and
remote attestation would be really
really useful to offer security
properties for that and in one of the
the biggest one is a verifiable control
and data plane operations so we we show
that you know this te based middle box
for the application of you know
collaborative filtering can actually
satisfy the three desired security
properties if you remember those three I
remind you the first one is that you
know policy competition and enforcement
of the of the two policies can be
actually isolated and verifiable by the
two aliases because every you know you
know the executions of the policy
competition and enforcement are
protected by trusted execution
environment
and also this is is now can negotiate
the desired level of privacy so for
example if the source a is trying to
learn the composed policy PSD here then
he can actually try to do that we
actually demonstrated that the attack is
possible within less than 10 seconds but
we also found that there is a trade-off
between the anonymity and the fairness
privacy and you know fairness and buy-in
by writing down the exactly what level
of privacy is is required by the two
untrusted aliases we can actually
provide the desired level of privacy
also bypass can be immediately detected
and with a secure per packing logging at
the middle box also this per packet
logging should be implemented within the
te e because we need to provide
authenticated really on the logging
information this there's a little bit of
a performance issue here because in
order to do that we may need to copy all
the packets I mean the line at a line
rate to the trusted execution
environment so in order to solve that
problem we we propose a near zero copy
technique that copies only the five
tuple information into the TE which can
which enables us to achieve multi
gigabit per second performance so we
actually designed and implemented this
middle box using Intel SGX plug-in in
the Intel SGX platform so and we could
achieve a so far 1.8 gigabit per second
filtering performance throughput with
three Intel SGX course so we actually
have four in course so there's a room
for improvement we're actually
optimizing it and we used you know Intel
CPU memory and network interface card
there they are all you know commodity
devices and tcp is about 1.3 k source
line of code and we we integrated the
SGX with DP DK for higher packet
processing and imported a couple of
libraries to the
SGX so our plan is to scale out this
thing with securely load balanced load
balancing and the parallel middleboxes
for up to 10 G 10 gig or even higher
throughput so in conclusion I try to you
know talk about this inter domain DDoS
mitigation and in particular try to
convince that you know collaborative
source and filtering is really the one
that we need to we need to design and it
is possible so so the potential is
really clear this is a really the ideal
form of you know defense for large-scale
DDoS attacks and but there is a
challenge you know AES is do not trust
each other and the solution is that we
need to really you know move from
outsourcing to pure collaboration and in
order to achieve this collaboration we
need as one solution in point we
proposed a te based middle box which
satisfies the three security properties
that is verifiable fairness and the
privacy and non bypass ability so thank
you for listening and again this is a
really an ongoing project we are
probably under halfway through writing a
paper and optimizing our implementation
so if you have any suggestion you know
any issues with assumptions or or
anything just really open for feedback
even collaboration if you can contribute
to this ok thank you my room engineer
Liam co-chair of the dots working group
yeah we've talked thank you for for the
presentation we as the working group
were not doing anything new or
sophisticated as that we're of course
doing kind of hop-by-hop signalling and
I just welcome you the same way you were
talking about collaboration to customer
to come work with us on if you have
ideas and suggestions on our work as
well thank you
and mine just a question in a comment as
a question you said 1.8 gigabits a
second but with packet processing
applications like this often the packet
read is more important but what's the
packet rate how small when packets are
being filtered so I here packet rates
and the smaller pack is kicking you yes
sorry I was just wondering how what the
packet rate you was because usually
that's like that other than the
bandwidth packet rate is more important
that information I need to check with my
student but I'll answer that because in
one point eight gigabit a second of 50
other buy packets isn't really that
impressive but if it's 64 my packet does
have quite a lot in terms of throughput
it's not that impressive that the reason
we have this degraded throughput oh not
not that the 10g is that we were using
SGX
and it naturally encouraged in a context
switching we try to minimize the context
switch and that's the result for now and
I just one comment related to the zero
copy I mean you know sure you don't
incur the copy costs on all the men
copies and stuff they still have to send
that packet somewhere there's gonna be
implications to the PCI bandwidth of
your system and the other interface that
you need to send it out of so you I'm
not sure that logging every single
packet that gets through the filter
isn't necessarily a good idea because
that itself is an attack vector on your
middle box so it could be brought to a
halt or stall out or something if if you
don't if you're not careful without
allocating resources to this copy so I
understand you have concern about this
per packet logging and you know zero
copy stuff so yes exactly that that's
really the the biggest part of our
performance issue and then we try to
minimize that using near zero copy
meaning that we try not to copy anything
but 5-tuple information and we believe
that you know 5-tuple information is
actually necessary we need to you know
cop
that into as SGX in this case because we
need to really detect the bypass attack
and that's the only way as for as far as
I know thanks okay thanks I don't know
can't go more thank you for the
presentation
I'm trying to understand get my head
around a couple pieces that that seemed
to be missing to me so one of one thing
is that the bypass ability that you
described if the only input to the
trusted execution environment is the
five tuple and then the only output is a
approve or disapprove of the five tuple
then how does that produce non-bio
possibility right so I I learned from my
team IDE that I'm supposed to drop this
on the floor but I don't right so how is
it not by passable it seems it seems
eminently by passable to me because the
actual sending of the packet is not of
course within the TE my second question
has to do what you or I don't know if
you want to get feedback for that or my
second question has to do with you've
presented this in a in a two-party
scenario you have one source a s and one
destination is and I'm wondering what
the state of the work is for dealing
with the fact that actually there are
thousands of a s is on the network how
does it scale to the end party scenario
okay so let me answer to the first
question first so that the question is
that five tuple is five tuple is good
enough for bypass detection so if you
really want to detect per packet bypass
any if you want to detect if there's any
packet that's trying to bypass it then
is insufficient but our goal here is to
detect the bypass between different
cross the traffic definitions or traffic
classes so in other words uh maybe I
missed that we skip that part but the
our middle box in securely logging all
the packet counts per traffic class and
the destination should be should be
counting the same thing per packet per
traffic class and they compare
at the you know infrequently so if some
packets are missing where some packets
are injected within the package class
traffic class then that can be detected
but so in order to achieve that property
that level that granularity of detection
5-tuple
seems to be a reasonable compromise so
so what is the what is the recourse for
the destination AAS if the source a s is
is allowing bypass you're saying that
now it's not my it's not non bypass
ability now it's detection of detection
yes it's a weak form of non bypass so so
if I'm the destination a s and the
source allows a bypass what is my
recourse so allow you mean so you
detected bypass right you're the
destination is you detected by pass
what's your recourse what do you do aha
so what do you do so if you detect it
then since this is a bilateral
relationship only only between the
source and destination so if destination
clearly knows that source is trying to
bypass it then their temporal contract
is over the this this collaboration is
just over aborted so that's we we
believe you know detection might be
sufficient because it's just just
between the two a ESS okay yeah it's
something we knew we had to make you
know this design point is so how do I
know
can you sir can you take go on to the my
second question which is about the the
end party scenario how do how do how do
i as one a s negotiate these contracts
with the thousands of other a SS that
are out there so we we know that you
know the malware's
are distributed across the internet but
their distribution is not that uniform
so we we are assuming that the source
can identify a reasonable number of
aliases that has large its producing
large number of packets so so that it
that the the the contract should be you
know bilateral independent so
destination you should should be able to
make
individual contract temporal contract
with the multiple source ASIS that's
what we assume okay we're going to cut
off the mic line in the interest of time
okay this is Linda Dunbar I'm the chair
of the working group interface to
network security function which is to
standardize the policy like a filtering
policy and in our working group we have
a domain like a controller and then the
function so there's a relationship but
for your case I'm just curious like do
you have a controller to consent the
policy or you are depending on just
between a STS and the policies so I'm
not sure if I really understand the
policy policy part o the working group
is to define and standardize the data
model between two peers like between you
and me I want you to filter a certain
packet so we standardize those kind of
policies so my question to you is as
earlier person were asking do you have
kind of a hierarchical way like I have a
controller to tell all the Aces of the
policies or is it purely distributed so
for now this is a purely distributed p2p
model but later we we will consider more
hierarchical way where there is a
central you know controller globally and
then assign these things in a more
organized way but for now this is a
purely PTP okay so are you assuming in
each guess there's the billow box there
to be able to do all the filtering yes
in order to really you know enjoy this
capability yes yes it should have
multiple middle box okay that's seems
very expensive solution is my comment
Bank a dark
I guess I might try harder to understand
the trust part of this so we start out
with the two aces that don't trust each
other yes and I guess the source is has
the mailbox and so then they come to
talk to each other I guess is the trust
rooted in like the manufacturer of the
processor that has the trusted execution
environment that's right the mood of
trust about the operation I mean the
execution of this fairness and the
enforcement of the fare policy is comes
from the manufacturer in this case in
cell in case of Intel SGX it's it's yeah
if you use te is there something you
need to assume yes vanadium soonest III
can't I'm sorry to say I can see this
working
ever ever ever and ever BGP is not
technology baby piece politics right so
you people setting their policies people
are making money on on often DDoS
attacks too so I don't see anyone using
a box like this because you won't put
your trust in someone else and and and
again back verifying who are using it
and who are not using it ah III you said
you were half through I think you should
go back and look at look at from the
story on because this will never ever
work and this has this as I would say I
would say content data networking has a
bigger chance of working than us
I'm sorry I missed the last part I
thought that was just a comment okay so
so I'm saying you should be doing board
and look at it again because this will
never work no one will use this if you
could be constructive - that would be
good just another Tony how can I be
constructive because this the BJP is it
that's not how i speedrun an isp we will
never use it and i promise you my
friends in other eyes peace will never
use a box like this and that's because
we we want to set our own policy that's
what you do with bidipi yes this is
actually sort of doing that you know in
it allows you to express your own policy
for
someone set the policy for me because
someone is setting me for to do to do
filtering going out right and so that's
that's our outsourcing model you know a
is setting a filtering no I still saw
that I that I get some policy towards me
right and the question is who so should
I sit and monitor all these policies
coming in if we have 65,000 AES numbers
out there there are sending me policies
all the time if everyone is using this
this does not scale so memory maybe I
can clarify this this is used only when
there is a DDoS attack in the normal
peaceful situation is always there
continuing DDoS attacks all the time I
think he understands your point yeah
yeah so so when when DDoS attack really
happens what what the current you know
the situation is that you know maybe you
know much better than I do it but you
know when the filtering is happening at
the destination a yes then source areas
has no control over whatsoever you know
the destination would determine which
packet should be dropped or not and now
it enables the so CAS or CAS to express
certain level of policy and at the same
time the destination AES will benefit
from from this mechanism because it can
sort of outsource the the packet
processing to the source a is so so I
mean my argument is this is a win-win
situation again III told you that there
are I space making money on DDoS - right
so people want this DDoS okay like yeah
yeah thanks for their comment yes yes
thank you very much min-suk for your
research and presenting it here today
thank you there's additional
constructive feedback
so there's additional constructive
feedback he is very open to receiving it
so thank you and open mic
I knew since I didn't make it to the
secretary dispatch two sec dispatch
tonight at 6:00 p.m. we're having a
small meeting about short-term
certificates but the considerations for
using them and whoever wants to
participate you're welcome we'll be at
the collet room thanks to you I've hi
I'm Jim Fenton I've been reviewing a few
internet drafts lately that have some
thing the security considerations aren't
quite what I would like them to be in
particular people seem to be putting a
lot of normative content there and I'm
concerned that having it there in
security considerations which I consider
to be more of a discussion of the
characteristics of what was said earlier
is is kind of the wrong place and people
implementers are likely to miss content
that's there so what I'm wondering in
RFC 3550 to doesn't say anything about
not doing that so I'm wondering is there
any plan to update that and if so can
you can you add this funny you should
ask we've tried so so there's a few
things to respond to there there is no
strict guidance on how we structure the
security consideration sections there
have been experiments where people have
done a security requirement section and
a security consideration section I
haven't seen one of those in a while and
that's a case where you would separate
out any musts you didn't have before and
put them in so no we don't have any
strict guidance on that if you do see
problems in you can think you could
clarify documents of course responding
to the editors and working group is much
appreciated you know so your reviews are
much appreciated to get to a revision of
three five five two we need feedback
right so we yo have had graciously
volunteered he had brought up he had
done a presentation with a prior
volunteer I think I want to say it was
like Berlin
that might have been one of the meetings
but he got up here and we gave overviews
at several meetings several sag meetings
he requested feedback at the mic we had
discussions on it
even just two meetings ago asking for
feedback we had lots of enthusiasm in
the room and said all right where did I
do this
and nothing came in so if you'd like to
give feedback on that and see if you can
drum up support for for that we'll see
if you have us still interested and has
the time for that or find other editors
but it's it's been a community a lack of
community interest in providing feedback
okay I'll look for the I wasn't one of
those other presentations all the close
up and maybe get in touch with them
thank you thank you and you could just
post if anyone's interested post to the
SAG list we'll see if if there is enough
interest and if there is we'll go
forward with it it would be a good thing
to do anything else okay so now we will
switch over to sect dispatch and if you
have feedback from the sect dispatch
experiment please send that to ekor I on
the chairs Tim and Nancy
[Music]
okay so just oh you do okay go for yeah
well we we are we are really organized
trust me
so welcome to the experimental security
dispatch so we are trying this for the
first time so bear with us real quick
I'm not going to go through the note
well hopefully you've been through
enough sessions you know what it means
what I want to say first and why I'm
circulating two cards is originally we
had slated for US House Lee to be my
co-chair unfortunately he was taken ill
the good news is he is out of surgery
so we want to wish him well we're
circulating to get well card so please
feel free to sign them but please make
sure I get them back at the end of the
session so very important so he gets it
um and I do want to thank Tim for
stepping in at the 12th hour
really so with that given the
experimental nature of this what we're
doing is we're mimicking the process
that is being done by the arc dispatch
so that said we're here really to help
as the group is namely apt to dispatch
the work so given the full agenda and
typically in the art dispatch the
presentations are given about ten
minutes really more like five to seven
minutes for them to present we discuss
and then we ask the question to you
whether it is something that the IETF
should do if it is we get to discuss
whether there's a home within the IETF
and if there is great we'll make sure
that those chairs are aware if not then
we ask the for the question as to
whether we should form a new working
group or whether we should ask one of
our security area directors to sponsor
so hopefully there are no questions but
maybe we'll we'll say one minute if
there's any questions clarifications
quickly going once going twice good
we've got a full agenda so with that
with that we've got five presentations
and if time allows there's potential for
61 so with that we have Ron are you on
meet echo hi everyone hi - hi Nancy hi
Ron are you able to hear me ah good
evening so give me one second here I'm
going to put your slides up I'm trying
to make it go full view all right so go
ahead hi everyone well first of all I'd
like to wish rust speedy recovery
because he's the one who first contacted
me about this and thank you to the sac
chairs and thank you for Nancy and Tim
for hosting this session today I'm here
I know I only have five maybe or seven
minutes but I'll go through it really
fast so today this presentation is about
an open
GP extension for the OS CCA algorithms
so if we can go to the next page I'll
explain to you what OS CCA is so in
China today there is an institution
called the office of state commercial
cypher administration which in short
which is called Oscar but governs usage
of cryptography in China and especially
it is enforced in hardware designs where
non-approved cryptographic algorithms
are disallowed so we're talking about
the normal ones that we see the sha a
yes and those ones there are actually
only three oscar proof algorithms and
these are named sm 2 sm 3 and sm 4 so
the names sm actually refer to an
acronym in chinese which means
commercial cryptography sm 2 so LLL
explain these three algorithms in the
coming slides
our extension extends openpgp to allow
these three algorithms to exist in the
protocol so people in China could use
encrypted emails through open PGP so
this draft defines the usage of these
three algorithms within open BGP and
also an additional profile on just like
the NSA's be sweet
we call it the Oscar SM 2 3 4 as a
profile for open BGP usage twister next
slide please
the first
would like to explain is the sm2 it's an
elliptic curve cryptography and the
standards that were just published and
actually just went active earlier this
year in March this is the family or
standard called the gbt three to nine
one eight from part one to part five
different parts of this standard define
different parts of this algorithm so
this is an ECC that contains three
separate algorithms it's a digital
signature algorithm a key exchange
protocol and also a public key exchange
sorry a public key encryption algorithm
the last part part five defines the sm2
curve that is recommended so the sm2
algorithm uses a 5-1 two-bit public key
a 256 bit private key for more details
of the algorithm you could have a look
at this draft traction sm2 blah a short
history of this algorithm it was first
published in 2010 it was standardized as
a commercial cipher in China in 2012 it
was included in an ISO standard 2015
formally standardised as a national
standard in 2016 and this year actually
last month it was included in the latest
ISO digital signature standard one for
Triple Eight specifically an open PGP we
utilize part two and part forces of the
standards for digital signature and
public key encryption the usage of SM
two adheres to the data formats
specified in GMT triple zero nine 2012
for interoperability this it defines an
asn.1 format that is already implemented
in crypto public libraries like open
peep sorry open SSL and Bolton the users
of open PGP with sm2 uses the part 5
elliptic curve defined which is called
SMT
amended the next slide will tell you
about the sm-3 hash algorithm which is
defined in the standard mention above it
is a 256 bit digest algorithm designed
as a replacement for sha-256 it was
designed by Professor Michelle Yin Wang
who was you probably remember was quite
famous for the sha-1 it's a brief
history is that it was first published
again in 2010 standardized in 2012
published as a national standard in 2016
and this year again just a couple months
ago it's now included as an
international standard in open PGP we
use it as one of the registered hash
algorithms so sm-3 could be used
together with other public key
algorithms such as RSA sm2 and so forth
the next slide will give us M 4 which is
a 128-bit block cipher it uses an 8-bit
Xbox with 32 rounds of processing for
more information you can look at this
draft at the second point the sm4
algorithm goes back to 2003 where it was
standardized in this GB standard for
wireless LAN it was designed for
wireless LAN encryption and therefore
it's a short block cipher that is has
supposed to have excellent relied
realizability in in simple hardware so
it was published in 2006 as by the Oscar
standardized in 2012 published in 2016
as a national standard and 2017 a couple
months ago it was added into ISO one
eight zero three three which is a
document for block ciphers in open PGP
we use it as a selectable symmetric
encryption algorithm as an alternative
to AES 128 and the last
I would like to show you is that SM 2s
and 3s m4 the implementations are
already provided in Bolton in open SSL
support in MPLS & Liber SSL is coming
when number of processes today already
implement sm-3 and SM for including
Intel chipsets and upcoming the arm v8
course our own we we have our own
implementation of open PGP called our NP
we already support all these algorithms
and in terms of Kahn security
considerations there are no feasible
attacks against SM - SN 3 and SM for
today for more details you could have a
look at the IETF drafts so proposing to
move forward this document given that
the open PGP workgroup has recently
encountered some turmoil we would need
security area director for sponsorship
we would like to request three extra
whole points in the Ayana
PGP registry which is listed here for
the document we would like to add more
examples and we would be very happy if
anybody could provide some constructive
feedback and reviews of the documents
thank you very much thank you Ron um
just add a little bit to that so um to
actually use those algorithms with open
PGP will require those code points being
assigned those code points have to be
assigned under IETF review yes Ron
already did some of it did get half the
you know did ran the algorithm open PGP
would have been the obvious home for
this work it's closed I don't see a new
working group opening so the question is
really whether this work is important
enough to move forward under AG review
so we have a line at the Mike if you
could folks could be quick thank you hi
this is Daniel con Gilmore xi2 chair of
the HP working group thank you for
bringing this up so I'm sort of curious
about why you're proposing it now when
it looks like these things of
around for several years I was looking
at the looking at the drafts there's a
there's a sort of strange chain of when
the drafts were formed this would have
been a good thing to mention probably in
the open BG working group when it was
open so I'm sort of curious about why
like why is that like why do we need to
do this at this point instead of when
there was a working group yes so I was
um actually previously in contact with
Barry and he suggested to me that the
open PGP working group was only going to
deal with the revision of four eight
eight zero and right which involved a
cryptographic refresh right like that
was the that was the attempted goal yes
was a cryptographic refresh yes so here
you're offering updated cryptographic
algorithms actually I was specifically
referred to this draft when I talked to
Barry and Barry suggested that I contact
the security area directors directly
rather than going to the group because
the group's the Charter of it was
specifically just to revise for a dado
for you know what were problems people
had with it so we suggested that we'd
bring this directly to the area
directors to not disturb the work of the
group okay yeah that I mean the work was
disturbed as it was I see hi Sean Turner
I'm probably not getting nearly as
entertaining as deg um why we're here
though right is because the Ayana
registries are set up as IETF reviews so
you can't get a crook you can't get a co
point unless you get Haiti sponsorship
so another solution to this is to update
the registries to allow other
specification types then you can get a
registration and go either through an
area director or to the ISC
it's your call but that's a different if
there's nothing to do with your drop
that's just like procedural mechanics
that would have to happen Thank You
Shawn I totally agree with that um it's
just that you know how are their style
and I think we need to update you know
some RFC in order to make that possible
right
all right well that's just it's another
option Thank You seanix it's Stephan
Pires just to come actually me not
constructive sorry and so I I think
having specifically supporting sweet
beer was a mistake I think adding other
national algorithms would be a mistake I
don't think we should do any of that if
we want new algorithms it should be
because they're better not because
they're you know come on to some
geography thank you so this Richard
Branson so I just wanted to confirm that
this looks like it has kind of the same
API footprint as the algorithms of open
PGP is already using this really is just
a code point assignment there's no new
like mechanism or protocol around this
yes you're right
yeah I'm just gonna +1 Sean here saying
we should probably just fix the registry
here
I think this would also if this hasn't
been kind of through the CF RG process I
think it would be beneficial to kind of
get some of those folks to take a look
and give it a thumbs-up or thumbs-down
sure thank you hi Sean Leonard and anger
Inc just for my edification as well as I
was in the group what is the status of
implementation as well as specification
in the asn.1 you know s/mime CMS
certificate realm because unlike the
registry issue that we have with open
PGP where it requires IETF review you or
you know whoever can just assign an OID
and by agreement start using it right so
but I don't I could you address that all
right so um open PGP doesn't
unfortunately it doesn't directly
utilize all IDs in the selection of
algorithms it was like that for I guess
a long time so I it boils down back to
you know the the Co coin registry issue
that you know for open PGP to work with
these algorithms it is necessary to
update that without actually changing
the protocol for the SM algorithms sm2
specifically is actually already used in
the certificate standards however those
are standards within China so those are
only national standards that apply SM 2
and the usage of SM 3
as a hash algorithm within for example
SSL Certificates so that is already in
use today however there is no
specification at the IETF on how this is
actually done in English got it and is
it your view or your opinion that
perhaps it should be documented in the
ITF because there is deployment even
though it's in one well I would say you
know it would definitely be beneficial
if there's actually an official
specification that is at the ITF I think
that would be very helpful at least you
know for the IETF community so I would
like to answer one more question about
you know why this is the why do we
propose this now is that because SM to
sn3 and SM for has just been
standardized they actually just became
active earlier this year and in fact the
SM to curve is not yet active it will be
active in early 2008 so this is when
everything comes together that is
actually usable makes sense okay thank
you I mean from yeah from my perspective
I think that it I don't my personal view
is I don't see it as harmful to have
more definitions of cryptographic
algorithms and using them because I
believe in cryptographic diversity in
contrast to some of my colleagues
wherever basic I don't believe in the
Sith rule of to a sequence algorithm I
think more defining more is better
choosing whether to use them is a very
important issue but that's sort of
orthogonal together that's double be a
different consideration yeah I think
it's okay in from that person I fully
agree with you Thank You Sean this is
dkg again I'm speaking here from someone
who's been in touch with several
implementers in the open PGP space do
you have I see you have a list of
implementations in boh-chan and open SSL
and embed TLS none of which ever believe
are open PGP implementations yes so SM 2
3 4 are cryptographic algorithms so what
that point meant was just that these
algorithms are already available if any
implement I wanted to use them so in
terms of implementation of this our own
of them
called RNP which you could find on
github it's an open source project it
already supports the usage of SM to SM 3
and SM for in open PGP so right now we
utilize experimental code points but if
you know we get to get a registry to
insert our code points then there would
be already a standardized implementation
okay so so despite what Sean said
earlier I believe that for the elliptic
curves in particular we do actually have
oh I DS we do use our ideas with an open
PG yes to identify the curves that's
true so that's so that should not be a
required like you don't need to do
anything there you just can stuff the
OID in for doing your ECDSA
yeah yes that's true for easy si okay
time for example if you want to use SM
for for symmetric encryption we would
need it would it would not be the OID
okay but you your bulleted list here
includes the public key algorithms which
I'm assuming is ECDSA right or the
equivalent of the ECDSA so you're asking
for an additional code point beyond yes
that would be to use it as a public key
algorithm just like how RSA is used so
so I'm not
not convinced that that's that that's
going to be necessary but I have to look
at that I don't have to look at the
crypto for it sorry sure okay so based
on the comments and discussion it feels
like there's a couple of paths as Shaun
suggested and I can remember oh there's
three okay yeah so the first one is we
we don't need to do anything here or we
don't want to do anything here the
second one is as proposed here we find
an ad to sponsor I don't know where Eric
went well Kathleen's on her way out so
and the third option is suggested by
Sean we really don't need to go through
the draft rather we need to go through
the Ayane registry and even in the
registry I would put the question as to
for sm-3 and s and for we need the IANA
registry not clear that we need to do it
for SM too
so given those three options I'd like to
do a hum oh yes so you should have done
this so implicit in the ad review we see
you should be done this implicit in
having a go to - to an ad would be a CF
RG review first hi Eric wish boy ad hi
Eric I think is before yourself but I'm
not gonna even sponsor a document that
as a Co point for this I'm not gonna ad
sponsor or docx you ate that it's a Co
point for this because I think that
having it is the precise purpose of
lighting the precise purpose of like
having sex dispatch was not to have a
bunch of algorithm they had a good RFC
so we could 8380 spots of them so they
could have Co point assignments so um
I'm happy to have I wouldI sponsor that
the things I won suggested which is
loosing the registry and um and then
they can do whatever they want um less
tedious parts that's her choice but I'm
not a any sponsor like a draft that does
there's basically a document is it
solely for a co-payment
so don't as useful so if there's no ad
that would be willing to ad sponsor that
that isn't a choice although that's not
quite what we we thought we'd signed up
for here but that's I understand so
we'll do the because even if initially
I'm not trying to said you should of do
people think that we should pursue that
doesn't mean we will actually do it we
would pursue a change to the I Ana
review policy for open PGP so that
future algorithms can be done without
being something that has to be done
through the group I think we we should
do a hum on that we were out of time so
let's start with that
how many people think that that is I'm
sorry sir the community one comment
actually there's a curtal working group
that is working on adding things and so
on
and it doesn't list a PGP open PGP
because of an PGP working group or other
live at that point but it's not anymore
so actually we could add add this to
curdle charter that's something that
ladies could tend to charge tariff to
curdle were contributing definitely so
you're saying it could go to curdle is
the working group you thought it could
go to I wouldn't of thought I didn't
think that when I reviewed it but that's
that's Kate it could go to curdle I
think but uh the thing it doesn't solve
the long-term problem okay which is a
pretty special we're gonna do sorry
sorry now I really take this before you
cut me off again
and I move I I definitely in strong
support that we solved this question as
Sean proposed and I ask the chairs
whether we can come on that so we're
gonna do two three options the number
one option is that we would do nothing
where the documents is something we
don't want to pursue the number two
option these are not in order these are
just the three the second one would be
we revised the IANA policy for open PGP
and the third is that we asked Ron to
take this to curdle and see whether
curdle is willing to take it on as a
working group item before that I'm
channeling PHP
no the algorithms curdle can add are
fixed what no the colonel is loved to
add a favorite no that that's that's
true it would it would require curdle
would have to decide that they were
willing to change their charter and
request a charter change to be able to
pursue it so number one okay we're clear
clarify for folks since we're talking
about humming on changing the IANA
registry right not everyone maybe knows
what the IANA registries are here so I
just want to provide a point of
information so people can know what
they're voting on or humming on or
whatever it is that we're doing great so
the registries I believe that we're
talking about are one octet registries
right and we're talking about changing
the Ayana registration policy for a1
octet registry that currently is set up
with depending on which one there's
between ten and twenty ten and twenty
four points assigned out of the two
hundred to six with a range of ten
reserved for private experimental and
nothing explicitly assigned above 128 so
we're talking about changing IANA
registration policies for relatively
small registries thank you that is a
really great clarification thank you for
pointing that out
with that we're gonna still back to the
three hums which is don't think the IETF
should pursue this number two would be
change the IANA policy in spite of it
being a scarce resource and the third
one is asked Ron to first confer with
CFR G and then take it to curdle so so
that's a two-step process on the third
one so on the first one how many people
think that this should not be pursued
well now okay how many people
think that the Ayana policy should be
revised so that i hf review is not is no
longer required for the open PGP
registries a little more how many people
think that it should go to that Ron
should take this to see FRG and then
request assuming that goes well request
that the kernel group take this on okay
so so we're just clear I home for both
two and three because they're not
mutually exclusive like we should fix
the registry and run this through C FRG
before the well well we we will continue
that the discussion of number two but I
think number three was clear enough to
say Ron that what we would like to do is
because there aren't any other SM series
algorithms you'd use in now in the IETF
we're sending those to the C FRG if the
C FRG is comfortable which I would you
know then then you would take this to
the kernel group to see whether or not
this is something you want to move
forward right I just like to make a
clarification that it's not only the
requestion of the requesting the col
point is that the the algorithms inside
there are some specific things that need
to be done to use SM two three and four
in that is documented in the document so
it's more than just a a call request but
echo my request is necessary right but
it's the code point request that forces
it to by IETF review and yes okay so
just to put a process we can Richard you
said you are you know you think we
change the registry you say you think
June's registry the way you do that is
by bringing that to next dispatches
match yes okay okay thank you
in that balloon yeah so tell us several
identity training next so the problem
we're trying to solve is that when you
have an issue or a fix it certificates
well the client establish a chalice
session with an attacker except of the
GLS legitimate server so both the client
and the server
our victim of this attack and most of
the times they don't even notice they
have been a victim on that next slide so
what we propose is a an extension for a
TLS 1.3 which is a second factor
authentication so basically what it's
it's a trust on first use mechanisms and
basically what we do is that when we
you're connected to a server so let's
say dot example.com you want to be sure
you we want to check that the identity
of that server is the same as when you
you were doing a session with that
server previously so it didn't change
the identity so next slide so how does
it work so that's the first session you
have nothing so you you have performed
your TLS handshake so that's why it's
the 10th occasion has been done and what
you're asking for from the server is a
ticket and the ticket is basically an
encrypted secret based on the TLS
handshake so at the end of the decision
you you have the the ticket the lifetime
associate to the ticket and you generate
a pining secret basically the ticket is
defining secret that is encrypted by the
TLS server is it a question
no sure Paulo it's after question isn't
this TLS resumption no because they know
it's not TLS resumption you just checked
that the you just checked the ability of
the server to to to be able to decrypt a
ticket but you are not providing any
information about the session
this is dkg this reminds me a lot of
tack this reminds me of tak dhina T ACK
dude sorry I don't know what I'll quit
you want me to look out there
yeah draft Perrin tak okay
so sorry that's the first exchange so
you just get a secret now okay so we can
go to the second step so that how you
get a ticket and basically you are able
to generate what we call the defining
secret from the TLS exchange and you
have a ticket from the server so the
next session next slide when you're you
perform the TLS exchange and what you
want to make sure is that the server you
you are actually connected to is the
same as you've been connected previously
so you send him the pining ticket you
received and the server from that pining
secret decrypt that secret and generate
a pining proof which is composed of the
pining secret and the TLS exchange
secret so once you have that proof the
other side the client can also generate
that proof and you can checks that the
proof sent by the server corresponds to
the proof it has locally generated and
because you have a binding between the
secrets and
you can make sure that the server is
able to decrypt the secrets and has the
same and situations as you have so
basically that's the same server you're
connected to now
as previously so when you receive that
you stole that and next time you
initiate a session you do exactly the
same is there any question regarding the
mechanisms sure poetess so again I think
it would be useful to see why this is
fundamentally different from let's see
HP KP Tech HSTs certificate transparency
and session resumption okay so to be
fair he has some of that material on the
on in both in the draft and on the
slides and I wouldn't let him use all of
the slides they didn't have enough time
so but maybe you want to summarize
quickly why you thought this was still
necessary so HP KP the main difference
is that it's a second factor so we did
not h p KP can be seen as a you use HTTP
as a side channel to configure the TLS
authentication began terms but just by
saying this is this so if you get that
has to be used for the TLS
authentications we do not use that we
use a second factor which means it's a
it's not associated it does not it does
not have any impact to the TLS
authentication the second difference is
that it's a TLS extension so it's not
only for HTTP over TLS and well because
it's a second factor we have absolutely
no impact when you change your key for
the TLS authentication so because a lot
of the difficulties for HP KP camps from
that you were actually bind to the key
used for the ETLs authentications so we
removed that change and
that's a well we believe that well you
don't have backup key also to handle so
we we think that's it's a very
simplified form its amplified very much
compared to HP k PP that's a so okay so
um at this point we need to go to the
mic and I want to remind people that
what the decision that we're making here
is and strictly on the bits and the
bytes
up level it this is a is this work
something that we need to be pursuing in
the IETF and if so then we have to
figure out where the right home for it
is so okay I think a Turk could you just
confirm this is basically the same work
that was presented at ITF 97 in the team
yeah it was not me but it was yarn sure
presented yes and so there hasn't been a
huge overhaul since then the difference
is you in yeah I think we we refine the
document but the principles were there
okay probably not beyond clarifications
and maybe positions but yet so this is
dkg you asked for questions on the
mechanism and I actually on policy so I
hope that's okay yeah but I'm curious as
to what you think the client should do
if the server does not produce the new
pinning proof so what what do you expect
to happen on the client-side if the new
pinning proof is for whatever reason
doesn't match or isn't available is it a
hard fail yeah it's a hot fail it's a
hard fail and so so that what you said
the difference between this in pkp was
that you were bound with pkp you're
bound to your certificate ski and here
instead you're not but instead you're
bound to this other key this bad key
here right that's so so I think one of
the things that made it difficult for
people to adopt pkp is that there was no
document that provided guidance on or
and no implementations that provided
some simple implementations of key
rotation schedules and how you couple
that with pkp headers right the way the
way that we could have gotten pkp to
work better would be to say
here is a standard policy that you can
adopt for your server and here are a
couple of implementations that implement
that policy yeah so do you have such a
document that's we have we we have a
round down ramp up mechanisms and well a
simplification is that you don't have to
well you don't need to synchronize so
that's a that with them you don't have
to synchronize with there it's the TLS
the certificates key okay so your own
separate key you don't have to worry
about dealing with the CA yeah but
you've got clients that are out there
that have only seen one key sorry I'm
trying to understand I'm a server I have
a set of secrets that are important
secrets you've added a new secret to my
store right now I have to protect that
secret if I lose it I cause hard fail on
all of the clients who visited me in the
past right yeah and and I need to have
some policy for if I accidentally
so I have two ways I can lose it one is
I can lose track of the bit so I don't
know it anymore and the other is I can
accidentally publish it right yeah so
what is my recovery mechanism as a
server for dealing with those two use
cases so so it okay could we up level
this and say are you saying that this is
too brittle to be something that the
IETF should pursue I'm saying that I
that as a mechanism I don't mind it but
I think the policy that will result will
be 2 will be brittle unless we have
documents that describe how to manage
these secrets in a responsible way I
think we have that so we're cutting the
line at Richard hi hi Sean Turner so
we're here right because you've
presented this at least once to TLS the
TLS working group basically wasn't
interested didn't say anything that was
one person that really got up and said
something and it was pretty negative um
and you need a go point and that Co
point is still the whole standard track
thing we're changing that so in TLS we
said we're gonna check we're gonna open
up the cipher suite or the registry for
extensions to be spec required so once
we've done that in the next two weeks
month or whatever it'll be available for
you to take this
will draft to the ISE and get a Co point
that's fine and that's what I think we
should do because I think there was not
a lot of interest in the working group
and I don't want this working group to
become TLS part two I bet that's not
what this working group would not follow
any document through sect would dispatch
if it became a group would not follow
any document through it makes things
someone else's problem or it makes them
go away that's the goal we are going to
reiterate we are dispatch yeah right
this group does not take any work okay
but uh yeah Richard Richard Barnes and I
guess since I'm the last in line I'll
take the privilege of proposing
resolution here I think we following
kind of following where the direction
Sean was but I think we should not do
any work on this I think it's something
that can clearly be done outside the
IETF process with the new registration
policies and I think it actually is
pointed in a direction that is not
really direction at least the web that's
headed hpk P support is being rolled
back in a bunch of browsers now and so
because people had exactly the problems
the dkq is mentioning and deployability
so i don't think there's really this is
really something it is in tune with what
I understand to be the direction that
the internet is headed and if there's
alternative channels for realizing so I
don't think the IETF needs to do any
work for it so I think that's
straightforward that from what what you
and Sean have said it's going to become
specification review which will which
will allow you to get the code point
that you need and there probably is not
interest in the right working group to
pursue it so we really suggest that that
be how you prove a percent or proceed or
yeah yeah as independent submission it
is there anybody who thinks that that's
a bad summary hum now the summary is
that since TLS is going to change to
specification review and there really
isn't sufficient interest within the
community to follow this document
through if they want to get the code
point they can do it by independent
submission and that would be what we
would suggest
well the tls group is doing what they're
doing and then they can is that Stephen
Fry though that that's what you said
there's a totally true statement until
you said and that's what we would
suggest because we might want to suggest
this is a bad idea
yeah but I think that's the whole point
of Independence I mean it's a good idea
that the independent streams that the
ITF shouldn't do anything about it but
like we can't stop him from you know
putting it on a website and requesting
on a register code point so you probably
know the reason I'm doing it because I
my understanding of this process is to
provide an effective way to say no not
just we suggest you can go and do
something else but but we can't say no
to an independent stream submission
so we're saying no to this community
supporting the work further right yeah
so I mean so the point the point of the
of the complaint reassignments in TLS
right or to avoid having to make
decisions on documents if you look for
any Co point assignments and um we're I
don't have any position on the event
submission it's like don't do it here
this is how you get a core points out of
it so all I'm suggesting is that in for
the purposes of this we should just stop
at don't do it here that's fair enough
what we're saying is we're not going to
pursue it in any of the working groups
here come now if you agree that we
should not pursue this in any of the
working groups within the security oh
yeah how many people think we should
pursue this within the security area
that seemed clear enough to me okay this
is Nick Sullivan for randomness
improvements for security
yeah okay hello
can can you hear me okay great I'm Nick
Sullivan this is a proposal that's a
very simple proposal that should help
out with several security protocols next
next slide please
okay so the general problem we're trying
to solve here is system level randomness
failures if you think back to the Debian
bug and other sort of things where the
system itself can't seed the
pseudo-random number generator with an
unpredictable data this can happen on
different operating systems and can end
up impacting quite a lot of
implementations of protocols especially
in the case of ephemeral tiffin where
keys are generated on the fly or for
connections if these if there is a
system level randomness failure you
could expect that lots of connections
are compromised at the same time next
slide please there have been general
solutions proposed to this sort of issue
before the idea is to take a long term
secret that's specific to this the
application or the connection and mix
that in with the randomness this is
specifically presented as the Naxals
trip in a paper by LaMacchia Lauder and
Michigan the idea is you have the
private key this is a long-term secret
in TLS for example this could be the
private key of your certificate you can
hash this into the RNG pool so if
there's a systemic failure on your
operating system at least your
connection will not will have the
entropy of the secret key mix into it
the issue with this is that sometimes
the private key is not available whether
it's in an HSM or or other other places
the proposed solution here is very
simple is given a long-term asymmetric
key you sign or encrypt a static value
with this long-term key and then mix
that result into the random number
generator before using it for generating
ephemeral diffie-hellman key we have an
example of how to do this in the TLS
draft and a formal security proof that
came along with this from my co-authors
next slide that's basically it
so is this valuable where should I live
steam power yeah I think it's a good
idea for somewhere I mean III would
ideally like to see somebody update 40
86 but I you know I can't force you to
do more work than you're willing to do
so if if you're not happy to update 40
80 we're a bit divided if you're not and
I think doing this somewhere will be
fine
and it could be eight I think you since
life I would like to ask you for a small
clarification are you talking about
using private keys with some
deterministic algorithms always
probability plans so do you want to sign
some static value is deterministic
algorithm or this is about more complex
scheme this should work with either
deterministic or randomly generated
signatures the only the important part
is that the resulting value is signed by
something that is an unpredictable long
term secret and for example if you were
to in in TLS if you have an RSA key you
can assign a value to terminus tically
with ECDSA you can sign
non-deterministically the signature
itself is not predictable which is the
important part and you can take this
signature and sort of share it along you
don't have to actually do this for every
single connection you can kind of do it
once per long-term secret as long as
that piece of those bits are fed into
the RNG everywhere you should have
protection from this systematic failure
and the same question for the
aesthetic value which is signed is it
static or it is some time dependent or
counter or something this just has to be
static you can have say a single string
for TLS the protocol for example then
it's only for a single usage yes so if
you have if you need signature aesthetic
value so it's only for one users know
that yes at the point is that you mix it
in with the system randomness and it
adds at least as as much entropy as the
secrecy of that private key provides
okay yes and solution is it might help
in some critical failures thank you
Thanks and if this is a subtle question
which I think under the editorship and I
would for a double check um avi as you
know on ECDSA in non deterministic mode
requires a random K um and having a non
random K is bad so if you have a so now
we have it we have a chicken-egg problem
if we have a weak PNG that we use to
generate the k is that caused a problem
or is the fact that's being are we fact
that we're assuming the PRNG is is
inherently strong just badly seeded
remove that problem so the only issue
with predictable case is if you use do
multiple signatures so in the case of
ECDSA you would want to do one signature
per long term key and that would be safe
thank you um curious have you done any
testing on this a Linux system orangie
and see what kind of results you get
from from the resulting entropy after
you sort of cold start it
sir can you written can you repeat which
one so did you try this out would say
the Linux system or in you and say comb
started it and just edit this and see
where you how much entropy did you
actually wind up but it's very difficult
to measure entropy well but there are
statistical tests you can do
statistically if the system RNG is is
random this will be random as well any
any public key signature or encryption
algorithm of a static value
will imbue upon the results as much
entropy as is the key length or the key
strength and if not then that signature
algorithm or encryption algorithm is is
weak right I was just curious whether
you actually measured it then on in real
lights in unreal life systems we haven't
measured it I'm not sure what exactly we
would even measure all right I mean you
could all right we can take it off a
chair statistically it's gonna look
random rich sauce yeah hi this is a cute
short neat hack we've tried to rev large
fundamental parts of security policy and
recommendations before so let's just
give this over to see if our gene let's
just give this over to see if RJ and
have them publish it I mean there is no
code point or anything that he's needed
so there's no reason who couldn't go
through the CFR G and I think we're
having enough questions that it might be
something that just going through CFR G
would actually make people feel more
comfortable about using it as well so
that would be certainly an option there
did you actually consider that or is
that yeah we considered see if our G you
just thought that there was a chance
that maybe this could be an ad sponsored
document set to smash seemed like the
right venue to make that decision I
actually it's exactly what we're here
for so that's that's fine I just wanted
to know whether you had ruled it out for
some particular reason okay yeah
personally I think this is it does seem
to be like a little higher level up the
stack then see if our G typically deals
both side I think it seems like a useful
bit of MEC you know both in the fact in
the sense of being sort of a
construction built out of cryptographic
primitives as opposed to permit itself
and in a sense of being you know closer
to a mechanism you would you would
leverage in a protocol as opposed to a
generic primitive you would use it's
something to be agile around so this
seems like it would make sense to me as
you know either a tiny short-lived
working group or an ad sponsored
document if the ATS are willing to
accept it what was the what was the
first option you said it make sense but
I missed the first one so one of the
things changing hats over to former Rai
area director one of the things we've
done in the RAI area with dispatch is if
there's a document that needs a little
bit of work needs some review things
like that you can spit
you can spin up a working group to focus
just on that documents so we've had some
some documents come through ride
dispatch that had a small workings that
lasted you know it's three or six months
just to deliver one document so fairly
focused fairly quick hit and then shut
down the working group so I mean if this
this doesn't really seem like it merits
quite that much effort so I think eighty
sponsorship is probably better but that
would be another option if you know the
80s and weren't comfortable taking it
directly that way
okay well meant to say about effigy is
that these kind of solutions are used in
some system I'm aware of but they used
these time stamps as part of an input of
signed data for mation into the apparent
G and I think that kind of techniques
can be used well no other good choices
are left but they must be analyzed so
maybe this is good for work for safer G
thank you thanks but and actually if
there's other techniques that would be
another reason to spin up some larger
effort that somebody might want you to
do so okay so I think we have three
options will do a quick hum I think the
three options as I as I understood them
would be pursue this take this to the C
FRG actually spin up a working group to
actually look at other possible ways to
do the same kind of thing other
techniques to include this and refine
this but maybe add some other pieces and
then and the third one would be ad
sponsorship so let me just want to know
that a little bit um I like I think what
I'd like to hear from this group is do
you think this is suitable for 80
sponsorship and then Kathleen like
another conversation or that we'd like
to do so I don't but I I don't want to
get him pointed that the the the working
honey on like whether we sponsor stuff
yeah yeah yeah yeah so let us do the
first two humps and see where we are and
then the third one we can say right go
ahead all right so how many people think
that this work ought to be taken to the
CFR G please hum now for yes how many
people think that this merits spinning
together a BA force more or maybe going
directly to us to a working group to
work on something fairly focused but in
this area hum now okay I think that we'd
like you to take this to the CFR gia it
seemed like there was a lot of interest
but a lot of people thought it ought to
go to the CFR gee I don't think we need
to do that do we need to do the third
one how many people think this should
just be ad sponsor then we should ask
the ATS to consider ad sponsoring this
much weaker okay so see FRG was it okay
thank you okay so next is max
hi okay max Paula CableLabs and open sea
I'm here to talk about the simple idea
OCSP over DNS it's been around for a
while next slide
so the idea is very simple
enable DNS has a turtle mechanism for SP
responses and this is all it is as a
proposal next time this comes with some
benefits and most importantly and
increase availability for a replication
information so birthday certificate most
because of the nature of DNS the data is
closer to the user and the cache the
caching system of the name DNS my
actually helped me in reducing the cost
of running verification or providing a
location information for large
infrastructure also there's other added
benefits for example if where the NSX is
deployed you can actually address the
problem that we have today we'll be
submitting and disappearances over HTTP
mostly time is HTTP not https
distributed through CD ends this comes
with costs but also comes with the
possibility for man-in-the-middle
attacks to prevent you from reaching the
delicate information and on top of that
he does is it doesn't suffer from the
synchro reference of okay I want to use
the LS so I have to validate the TLS
connection this is either because it
uses a different set of keys and other
benefits that come from this is that you
know in some environments think about
some devices that comes online in a
network and before we actually allowed
to perform any real action or even
access HTTP HTTPS resources they need to
provide some form of authentication or
authenticate some servers that they need
to connect to DNS might provide a way to
actually validate the validity of the
certificates presented by other parties
could be IOT devices communicating
between each other or communicating with
the controller or even you know the
device fetching their own SP responses
and
embedding them in the TLS session with
other devices stapling that and of
course this you know it's just a DNS
query which is fairly simple for
application to do that they don't have
to be SP requests next slide so the
draft is very simple technically is
there's two things that we define the
one is record for the Aussie SP response
data in the DNS it's just the binary
representation of the of the hospi
response the draft doesn't propose to do
any changes there and the use of DNS
your eyes in the eye DN a-- in their
certificates so that applications can
actually use that and fetch the the the
SP response related to the entry that is
in the certificate self next time so
what's the impact to the application now
very little in a sense that usually you
do these three things first retrieve the
UI from the certificate from the
authority info access with the SS method
ID or CSP
that doesn't change in the proposal
basically if he if the scheme in the URI
is the NS a set of HTTP usually it is
then you do the query through the DNS
system and then you just process the
data that you receive because it's the
OCSP response very simple to do and
doesn't really impact that much they the
processing of the from applications that
part of you excellent so this is all
this is all it is there's very simple
proposal as I said definition of the
record for in DNS we provide some
example on how you how it ca can
actually build this target for the DNS
by using maybe the serial number of the
certificates but since we don't mandate
a specific format because you want a and
the client application to be very to be
very easy particle application to just
get the target from the certificate and
just made the query we don't want it for
any particular way to construct this URI
[Music]
and as I said before before this you
know some advantages that come from the
nature of the DNS itself there is a bit
of cash Global is really cash that my
help in reducing the cost of providing
replication information and in some
person in some environments like OCF or
CMI where we're introducing actually
strong authentication for devices this
might be a way to improve the security
the overall security of the system we're
shortly certificates is not really an
option and that's it that's all it is so
questions not in terms and not a
question a comment so the only thing
that I found remotely interesting in
this was the discussion of caching it
turns out that there's a much better
mechanism that already has far better
caching than what you described and
that's OCSP stapling why not use that
not you can use that absolutely but
someone has to to fetch those that
stapling right there also is B response
so for servers right for servers is easy
for client might not be as easy as just
I'm not saying that it is a replacement
for you know the way that you do today
if you if you can do vs. PC it also be
stapling for TLS sessions but really
fine there's many other use of
certificates that might not have that
option and so it's just any in addition
not a replacement for what it is today
if today your application just works
fine you support OCSP stapling that's
great do it in other environment might
not be as easy that doesn't really I
don't find that it all persuasive the
other thing the other point that I would
make here is that you you you said that
this would reduce the revocation the
cost of providing revocation services I
don't think that's true because most of
the cost is in signing as someone points
out behind me and what you've done is
you've created an extra now
now the DNS is responsible for holding
all this information and there it
doesn't need to hold it in every single
recursive resolver that's ever been
touched by this this DNS query there's
really only one place that you need to
put this and that is the entity that's
going to be presenting the certificate
which is again why stapling is perfectly
adequate Thanks
so what cutting the mic lines there and
I'm asking everybody to be very
efficient so that we can get one more
person presentation in sure so I just
wanted to throw by to that Oh first
sorry I was back here before you were
I've been waiting since Keating that's
up co-chair two comments no I was here
before him for the cost of providing
notification infrastructure you're right
there's a cost associated with signing
those responses but most of the time now
many large CAS they just pre compute
those and put it on CD ends accessing
their access to see the ends Citians are
you have to pay for that so that's
that's the cost that might be reduced in
case of you have large number of clients
connecting directly via HTTP this is
happening the past and you get for high
volume and high frequency systems you
get billions of requests a day and
that's a city with costs so okay I'll be
real fast
two things one you can request a dienes
or a type because it's all pretty
straightforward without any sort of
expert review or anything like that just
go to Ino and felt the form and you can
get that r-type right away second I
think the N on top will sort of give you
the advice that of course you should use
text records right so okay exactly I was
gonna say that new aura types do not
deploy on the internet and DNS SEC has
kind of the same property here that's
not going to make anything better
because there is no circular dependency
on any other transport security because
the OCSP requests themselves are signed
and so that addresses the security
concerns you have yeah so DNS SEC is
only going to be a deployment blocker
it's only going to introduce more
breakage so my answers I think we should
do it and do nothing here okay
beyond one store for Apple I have a
couple of questions um I think my first
question actually let me address the
OCSP stapling comment from I think
Martin OCSP stapling is um well one
disadvantage of all seeming stapling is
that it's always sent by the server on
any new handshake basically and that
might not be needed because the next
update for it alone says P the request
is typically in the timeframe of weeks
so it's just just additional bytes that
are not really needed so there's
out-of-band fetching where actually it's
in the request path but this fetching
from either DNS or CDN as it's done
right now it's probably still a ballot
but it thing to do um my other my
question is though that you're um I just
looked at the RFC for CSP and it seems
to be that the request payload needs to
carry a little bit more than just the
serial number in fact you mentioned in
your draft that the serial number is
even kind of optional and the DNS URI
that is in here but in fact there are
more there's more information in the
request payload that probably cannot be
conveyed through DNS requests year and
we're gonna have to skip past those
details you guys can take that outside
because though the decision here is is a
better one so thus my apologies but we
just don't need to keep it moving get
you more yep
hi Sean Leonard so overall I'm in favor
of this work it's not the first time
that OCSP over DNS has been presented
and I think that the time has come to
give it a try I did read the draft it is
experimental and whether it becomes
experimental or not when it's published
I think that a working group approach
because there are they're dragons here
there's implementation details you know
but I clearly see their applications and
as somebody who has managed to cram a
lot of superfluous information in the
DNS and significantly reduce our
operating costs I think it's a good idea
so I mean I kind of reflect what Martin
said but also I mean so this is to you
know get around possibly over caching on
on the CDN what about the caching
proliferation that happens with various
DNS caching resolvers like I don't think
this is going to make the problem any
better it could actually make it a lot
worse ok so I think well I think we'll
start with this simplest question is
this work that ought to be pursued in
one form or another within the security
area
uh-hum now if you think it is work that
should be pursued within the security
area in some form how many people think
that it doesn't need to be pursued
within the security area hum now that
one is stronger so you have the other
option that was was suggested about from
the back of the back ok thank you
so we got one last one and we are right
back on schedule you're okay and I'll
apologize to Marcus cuz we ran out of
time yeah all right hi guys I have three
things to say this will be short I think
all of them are around EAP that the idea
started working on in the early 2000s
more extensively we defined the
framework and multiple different out in
the case of methods including APC many
APA ké this presentations is around EAP
aka and that has been actually fairly
widely or very widely implemented if you
know if you have a phone in your pocket
probably implements EAP aka it's been
somewhat widely used or deployed and
acts actually using the implementation
like a millions not billions of users
primarily because it's it's not the
method that one use is for if you have a
2g 3G 4G network you're using a native
aka authentication scheme
and a 3gpp protocol to do that the
ultimate and EAP is only used if you
were to access a wireless LAN with your
operator credentials but in 5g this may
actually change because the 5g signaling
mechanisms will allow use of EAP to
authenticate phones that connect to the
5g radio so that's the information piece
next slide please
so I have two drafts around this topic
and one is a very simple update of the
existing latest RFC 5448 on EAP aka
prime which is a further development of
the original aka draft and this minor
update relates to actually just one
reference in in the old RFC points to a
version of the 3gpp spec that gives a
table of how you bind certain contexts
where you do this authentication into
the keys of the authentication method
and that is planned to be changed
because now there will be other context
namely the 5g context so if you ought
indicate with you know within the 5g
network you will use a different string
to mix with your euro key and that's a
really like the smallest possible reason
for updating an RFC but I actually
happen to believe that if you haven't
even the smallest issue in an RFC used
to fix it and I think the idea should be
able to do that sort of thing so that's
that's the update piece we and I there's
no idea of updating anything like you
know adding new functionality or
anything like that
of course you could consider adding
security considerations if you learn
some new things and you actually have
learned some new things I didn't do any
of that for this verse and take a look
at the draft and and please provide your
your comments next slide please
so the other draft actually relates to
attacks and relates to pervasive
surveillance concern so after the
Snowden revelations some of the
on Revelations we're actually quite
interesting from the point of view of
the mobile networks and and SIM cards so
we had the story in the newspapers
around some intelligence agencies
breaking into the systems or the
organizations of SIM card manufacturers
that manufacture these by the millions
or hundreds of millions and and deliver
them to operators and you know basically
saying that you know in some cases the
agencies have been able to get to the
sim the smart card manufacturers you
know the actual data in the card through
the manufacturing or provisioning
process and there's nothing to do with
the actual technical means of you know
actually even though the cards or the
authentication protocols this is like a
other level of attack if you have you
know national security letter or you
blackmail the guy who you know does the
manufacturing process or or you know
have a point a contour person you will
get some key material no matter what
what the technology is underneath but it
does point to sort of changes in this
security situation or threat situation
so we should assume that you know some
of this well could be happening next
slide please
so obviously the operators and the
operator associations have been looking
at this very seriously and they've done
many improvements so they've taken very
serious now that the whole process like
okay gets access to to the the
manufacturing process and and and their
technical tools and how they communicate
the keys between the manufacture and the
operator authentication Center but
nevertheless I don't think we can rule
out that some vulnerabilities remain so
this other draft I won't go into the
technical details but the basic idea is
provide perfect forward secrecy which we
didn't have in the original ABAP a
cavers and and with peer fruitsy for
secrecy of course you can get you know
protection against passive attackers if
the agencies get the keys then they
don't necessarily get the data of the
the users traffic
details you can look at the draft
there's no current officer requirements
for this from 3gpp or anybody else but I
thought this would be prudent technical
move on our part next slide so next
steps happy to get feedback if we could
get some of this into the work program
of the IETF I'd be really happy should
point out that there's some coordination
going on with IETF and 3tp and various
topics on the EAP space there's actually
more than this particular topic that I'm
talking about now and I'm keen on
updating the existing RFC's that that
they are you know up to the current
situation and I'm also keen on worrying
about threat situation with regards to
intelligence agencies and and pervasive
surveillance so that's it when you know
maybe one more thing that you know if
you're thinking about EAP in general
there's also some other drafts in this
space that we're not talking about here
now but but that that may factor into
like if we put some work somewhere do we
want to do it where so that's it thank
you so you are you are you actually
looking for a you know new work in the
security area with this or are you
looking for groups to give people to pay
attention to this work I'm trying to
think
dispatch now is are you asking us to
dispatch any of this work at this point
I I would like a place for this work to
happen at the IETF and also obviously
very much interested in technical
feedback okay so Kathleen Moriarty we
have had recent drafts pop up on the sag
list in regard to eat and there's been
confusion about the list and they had
created a new list we had what happened
the old list is still actively used but
when I just tried to get to it for the
eat list you just wind up with a login
page so maybe those subscribed are still
happily getting their eat messages but
might be difficult for people to join so
I think we have to straighten that out
and also find out the larger interest in
this space and maybe just use this new
reap list
I think there's more to this decision
but I am seeing what yari is saying is
there seems to be a lot of renewed
interest and so I'd like to hear
thoughts as well the line cut worth it
with the gentleman in blue Sorry Sorry
yeah my name is hi Graham drama wowie
Thank You America communication actually
I myself is about contributor to the 5g
security standing in 3gpp and yeah I I'm
a quite agree with this proposal here
because recently there are some new
attacks for the ipiria for the telecom
networks and so and the five-year top
the EAP framework for authentication and
so I think it's necessary to enhance the
EAP message for the future use great
yeah thank you thank you okay thank you
very much my name is Kia Maia I'm the
3gpp liaison to ITF I just wanted to say
thank you for yari for bringing up
especially the first but also the second
draft EAP is for sure success story and
I would really like to see that that the
drafts are going forward and can
progress and thank you thank you I mean
she from tomorrow and I think that the
EP work is very important for the 3gpp
as that is the first time that you use
the EAP for the where D for the wide
where these connections so I think that
if we we have more EAP measures than the
method it can have much more choices for
their layoffs indications Thanks
thank you thank you sir so I think we're
gonna move let's do a quick hum either
so the choices are do you think that
these that EEP
these two drafts and perhaps others in
the area of EEP are important enough
that this the security community should
spit up some new work and take this on
uh-hum now if you think we should do
that how many people think that that we
should not okay I think it's pretty
clear that something should happen so
we're gonna have to figure out I don't
think we don't don't quite have the what
but we'll work on that Thank You yari
thank you everybody for your patience as
we work this experiment oh don't forget
blue sheets and please I need to get
well cards back so that Russ can get
them
[Music]