[Music]
all right we're gonna get started in
just a minute
alright hello everyone this is the TLS
working group meeting at IETF 100 here
in Singapore
let's see you should all be pretty
familiar with the note well since this
is Thursday you've probably seen it oh
and 15 times already but please respect
it we do have minute takers and jabber
jabber scribes the blue sheets are going
around
remember when you speak at the mic to
state your name and let's as always keep
this professional are there comments
from the peanut gallery down there there
are professionals good all right here's
our proposed agenda we do have a fairly
packed agenda especially since we want
to get to resolution on the TLS
remaining TLS one three issues and make
progress on DTLS as well
couple other perhaps especially eye on a
registry graph we also want to start
moving that board document status I can
find my slides here where they all right
so we got two dots in the RFC tersky
there it's miss ref they're waiting on
another reference um so we're about done
with those that's great the Dane draft
is should be ready to go
so that's really good because we've been
kind of pinging them a little bit since
the last meeting we adopted three drafts
for delegated credentials SMI encryption
the record size limit extension
I think the delegated credentials in the
SMI encryption stuff is kind of still
kind of in its infancy getting getting
to go worked on but Martin do you want
to say anything about the record size
limit extension draft
yeah Martin Thomson um I think this is
done so I I think we're we're done
though it was kind of blocked on an
issue that was on until s13 about record
sizes that we discovered that's recently
been merged and that was the only thing
I was waiting for alright alright I have
an implementation if anyone wants to do
interrupt testing on that one I've
talked to a bunch of people it's a
little tricky to implement sometimes
because you have to restructure the code
a little bit but it was worth it okay
great so we're gonna probably go ahead
and working group let's call that one
hopefully by tomorrow there wasn't a
whole lot of discussion on the list but
I think it was a pretty straightforward
change and basically nobody said don't
do this at this point so be ready for
that
TLS 1.3 has been through to working
group last calls at this point we're
gonna discuss some changes today and
then we're gonna do we'll probably end
up having to do another targeted working
group last call so we're just talking
about the new changes since last time um
and we have as you will talk about later
today that we think Joe and I are
writing that draft at the eye on a
registration update document is ready to
go
we'll have to identify a shepherd since
we can't Shepherd our own documents and
we'll have to make sure Kathleen hits
the button for us because she has that
power because again we shouldn't be part
of progressing our own documents in
progress is details 1.3 we're gonna hear
about that later
look at example handshakes 40 us 1.3 dot
that draft is going to get pumped out
once we get 1.3 out the door apparently
it's pretty easy to go in the grease
draft has expired but David said he was
going to update it yesterday so we'll
see and today we're going to talk about
supported Authenticator for TLS and to
get compression the extension isn't on
the on the agenda but it's still a draft
and that's it any other questions
so there are ex
so what we did last the very last
they're really really last time I have
to stand up a dog rat tails am i great
um next slide
um so there's only three that we'll talk
about um the only important thing really
is this middle box issues thing um so
and then we can talk weekly and you know
these keep trickling in these we keep
not closing the draft so hopefully once
you close the graph then things will
start trickling in on next slide so as I
sort of said in the email um we were
finding that middle boxes sometimes
appear to be kind of sad we need to go
shave kill at one point three um so with
some more data later but this is our
initial data from on Firefox beta on a
forced test versus CloudFlare by which I
mean um CloudFlare yes Ben
just for the chairs are the slides in
the data trackers I'm wearing so what I
mean by a force test this one is
basically a forced a/b test so we have a
we have a we have a CloudFlare sort of
cloth for our servers they're
essentially identically configure
between you know one some DTLS one three
and some don't bother wise or dedica um
and they just basically do or question
both of them and look at the error rates
so that way we don't miss pleasure
organic testing or something David we
talking about later they'd be crumb um
so um this um no C's or vinegar or is
like incredibly hot um that's like well
everybody seems to see you can drive
these numbers down a little bit um I was
looking at some of our numbers from
earlier day and some of the problem is
like China blocking things so like we do
force test against Gmail like you like
remove China like that Erica's way down
but um they're less on the ordinary from
Taylor's pretty high um regardless on
we're not willing to take a one-point
seven or eight point seven or a point
this is not one point seven hit come to
the point tails one point three um and
so um if we were to do this um as a
browser we need to continue to fly back
but which I mean we need to somehow
probe whether your environment could you
tell somebody and if not we need to turn
details a point - um there's a bunch of
ways to do that one way to do it would
be to UM to you know do it every
connection we do it we to do it
like like I kept a form sector
do something on so on now on opinions on
whether this is like just crappy on
different but um regardless I think
there's a general consensus to be better
to not have to do it if we possibly
could on and so on the Google Chrome
team with a boring team on base no
suggestion Baikal nekritz um has been
working to UM like figure out how to get
rid of this and basically how to like
screw around with the team with a non
cryptographic parts of tales from e3 to
make it work enough I tales from way to
the bosses go they just let it rip um so
um the order of operations here is I'm
going to talk briefly about the PR I've
written based on their work and um some
feedback from people um and um then and
just walk you through what I was doing
and then the David's gonna talk about
the data in chrome he's got it next
slide so there are two parts of this PR
um one of the things you always do any
other things you can do we don't have to
do um the always that the parts that you
do um generally pretty look pretty
reasonable um and are things that like
would have been reasonable design
decisions that we just didn't do when we
did one three initially um so um we had
a longer skirt the first one is how to
do version negotiation so we had a
better long discussion
initially about when we did supported
versions about where the server should
not altered version it wanted and we
sort of people and we and like people
went back important you should be in the
server's extension supported version
extension or it should be in server
below version and eventually shouldn't
in server hope version because that
seemed like the more normal thing and
even though is LOD to have like a thing
and then respond in some other place on
turns out that's bad
so on the bristles to just reverse that
decision which is say to the server holo
version the main the main version field
be um tilt from point to and then to
have some indicate the actual version
you're selecting um the second change um
we are we had on because we thought they
were not necessary remove session ID and
compression the compression feels and
then server below um because there's no
rushon and there's nobody essential
presumption and so they seem and there's
always some little weren't sure this is
a great idea and it's kind of painting
your parser by the way because if like
have a conditional party or pressure so
and um so um again and so that and then
the next point is um there was a
remember we like nailed down the record
version layer two or three away
represents right now um and it turns out
that like you don't let that if you're
gonna claim your machine tales from
point two um so um basically after the
server below user 303 instead of a 301
and again this like there's like nothing
particularly crazy about this choice
it's just that you made the wrong choice
initially um so those are like
reasonably like like renditions we just
could've made differently we just did
is there any intuition why over 303
instead of the 304 yeah
because because you guys are claiming to
be telling some point - um so in
innocent supported version was in the
server Hall
um so now we get to the things which are
like a little less like happy um it
turns out um and it there's some so I
don't be our measurements that if we
like HR I give me a handshake
tape-delayed nobody's there recognizer
completely freaked out and so on the
proposal here is to and a niche or and
server home or some type overlapping is
information that's the idea here is to
merge a torrent server blow into a
single message and you can do it is
basically by looking at a special set
most written about you like I'm their
defend this to you as like an aesthetic
design choice I'm simply gonna say that
like I once already
alright I want H or no one way to make
it work um so um and it's not it's not
ridiculous is just like night yeah
Thomson one thing I observed was that
some of the code that deals with the
values in the server hello actually make
some sense in the hello every trial
request processing all the extensions
are different
yeah it's a little bit weird but it's
not that's not the worst part of this
yeah right yes um so
okay um so this last thing I wouldn't
say isn't gonna make any sense until you
see the next slide but you have to do it
otherwise it doesn't work
which is you have to ignore it any time
you receive a change safe respect
message during the handshake if just
throw it away
um so um the reason you're gonna do that
is because the next slide please
which is that if you think about boxes
you have to do what we call
compatibility mode and this you pretend
a such a presumption so you make a fake
session ID value which I think we said
is random but like I don't have the ran
of it just to be like not like obviously
like um and the server echoes it is if
it was your resumption um and then
basically you send change type respect
messages in the problem happening if you
were doing like if you're doing if
you're doing Redemption namely the
server sends one way after the server
below um and um that's where you come
over to the finish and you click like
sometime after the client hello if
you're doing like one RTT you do it like
basically when you're beginning a
behavior of your second flight if you're
doing 0tt you hopefully do at the
beginning to think like a row um we
don't have measurement that second thing
works but like with a zero duty felt
Punk's out there like you just retry
with one hour TT if it happens
occasionally disaster um that's not an
insecure flower back it's just at doing
um and you have to be willing to fall
back like every browser stack basically
I mean if you're doing zero TT you're
quite give me prep sorry anyways a 0 TD
has to be willing to deal with like a
bunch of our conditions when the server
didn't like 0 TT and like every browser
stack we tries and so like we try and
there's ladies um so um the so as they
you don't ever you don't have to do this
and in and you wouldn't do this in DTLS
and you wouldn't do it like in the quick
in bed um but you would do what you were
doing it you do it you were like I'm in
a box
um um initially um I did vision this is
each side had a unilateral compatibility
mode um and that's almost entirely true
but Warren Thompson points out that the
clients the ones in the middle box the
client kind of wants to tell the server
like you really should be setting this
on the the CCS and so what
what isn't in this PRA we should change
is that the server receives the non non
empty session ID it should generate the
CCS any case yeah Montano observed that
if the client doesn't do these extra
compatibility hacks it's basically
nothing you can do at the server end to
repair things right so it has to be the
client that initiates this behavior and
if the client knows there's a middle box
there and the server doesn't follow
along then it's just gonna fire and I
suggested must in fact that's why I
think we can might put insured must have
you find good yeah I didn't want to
fight about it but yeah this is no no no
not must if the session ID is present in
the client below the server must send a
change Cypress back at the appropriate
right would be poorer why resistant a
must
he's gonna come in this next slide I
don't want the client step in force so
come again part of why I resisted a must
is that people a lot of people think
that must means the other side should
have to enforce and I don't find that
important I certainly don't want
enforcement right yeah okay there's a
line cow microts um one thing to know is
that the server does not necessarily
know that the session ID is so it seems
yeah I think if you're gonna switch it
here you're gonna have to like fine have
some we distinguish random session on
register and then actually arguing for I
wish require to be random appearing
honest um so if the client knows that
it's not behind a middle part so it
wouldn't say send a fake session ID and
then it wouldn't create this ugly it
mostly well it would most likely not get
this yeah
and we could actually say should not
chip doesn't do any good job a part of
the know any good otherwise nothing
questions I haven't followed this but
are you trying to make it look through
the middle box an obsession with some
shoes move on yes okay
if the middle box does not have to
session ID is going to reset it um so
some middle box to death but apparently
with our experience has been that
especially if frequent that things
working again right
David's gonna talk about the data it all
depends on the policy yeah yeah no we
know we know we're aware this is a risk
this is about getting the error rate low
enough that we're going that they're
willing to make those little boxes
change I mean to be clear those little
boxes how like is their responsibility
ultimately like those middle boxes are
basically broken right live in a box
it's okay so you step back a the middle
boxes we're dealing with or defective um
what I mean by that is they're not
proper they are not properly handling
TLS um properly handling TLS version
negotiation if they were probably having
cells version negotiation and they were
fine um the problem is their perspective
and so if you um and so as well and so
it they probably so what I mean by that
is when they receive the client alone
the the responsibility either to do
version negotiation and downgrade or
Mike you which should be fine or to not
your version ago she ation and that not
screw the data but but the doing is
intermediate thing whether with are
basically um passing either passing
through the extensions that are
recognized and then during this or and
then mirroring the server's version or
they are trying to do state machine
especially at the wrong version level
and all those things are possible
um so nobody has to do correctly is it
has to actually the version negotiation
it works not so I don't want to argue me
what's correct forwards incorrect right
so what might happen realize yeah which
I understand your concern you're trying
to do sure yeah
well as a on those middle boxes are
implementing version negotiation then
this will work great
even without this water so Martin talks
another thing to observe here is that in
the case of a hello every trow request
we're not as certain that it's going to
work right none of the experiments that
we did actually implemented that and it
looks slightly different on the wire as
a result of the fact that there's a
handshake message that appears
afterwards right the CCS ordinarily we
encrypt all of the messages that come up
to this CCS and they just look like
application data and they look like TLS
one through application data records and
for all intents and purposes of yeah the
middle box is happier so session
resumption but in in the case of hello
every try request that's a little bit
different again it's a risk I think
we're willing to take yeah
as a red model is red light so oh so now
that everything looks like 1.2 are we
we're not doing virgin negotiation the
old way with 1.3 oh I'll be introducing
this part are we introducing a possible
problem with making that problem worse
as soon as we did supported versions
that was a problem I mean that the
basically the problem is you come to be
hungry you shouldn't be porting
extensions you don't recognize and if
you're doing that you're gonna have
problems
so yeah voice averse negotiation like
when there's a version out arm basically
we don't have to we don't actually Bev
in some what happened if we did we try
to do the overseer she imagined but we
do know it cause problems with servers
so voice it out that may have got me a
clear fall this year but I think that at
this point we have like double down on
that rather than back yeah obviously
people your net stuff Apple um I brought
this question up during the hackathon as
well I'm wondering if we should include
a recommendation to let's let me call
this yeah B compatibility mode um to not
try to engage in compatibility mode on
the first requests because if we did do
that that an ossification will always be
the case and nobody will adapt to purity
that's 1/3 yeah I guess I don't think
people ready willing to have I don't
actually really going to have it be
dramatically slower on every connection
behind middle boxes what we've been
thinking of doing is basically giving
you a basically running the captive
portal tester and giving you a saying
your mother box is blasted why don't you
complain your event instead of trying
instead of trying to basically penalize
every connection I think that I spoke to
some implementers and I think the
agreement is that they want to do this
anyway I'm just wondering if we should
put in a recommendation and address the
issue of ossification specifically yeah
my sense is David is not very saying
what about this but part of getting out
of compatibility mode
David Benjamin so the data is a little
bit confusing on this front but we have
some reason to believe some of these
these middle boxes are a little staple
and if you offend them they will black
fool you which kind of makes fallbacks
problematic I'm also generally skeptical
that like adding a fallback is gonna
convince them to do anything because hey
it works
and they probably won't even realize
something is going on so should we that
that I think I can iterate that does
people question on email I'm able to
measure because that our experiments
lend themselves well back to a
measurement time that grits um I think
that we should just not put any
recommendation in this and then
deployments are going to do what they do
and if it seems like a reasonable way to
move things towards better compatibility
then deployments else okay
next slide Yeah right on so there were a
couple issues raised here um about how
we oughta do this um so um the list um
so several people said we should only
have the compatibility mode um um I'm
not asking about this um for several
reasons I'm personally I say we don't
need it for tailfin point three quick or
DTLS and soak up those protocols enjoin
um um the data is extremely fuzzy and
that's why this italic is here on what
do we need client-side CCS or not um I
don't think we understand that but it's
possible you might not need it and
should I be yeah should I keep having it
forever um and I think this is blessed
it is more like unicorns and fairies but
um at some point we might actually get
enough people fixing their mailboxes
that we stop sending server-side seas
yes David doesn't blame you shaking his
head no but I mean I said of course it
varies um so it should be sad if we ever
in a situation to position um so I guess
um I don't wants to sort of speak up for
only about a pony mode um okay I guess
people will list I do you want to
you want Mike um right
so I guess um do you wanna get given I
guess can we at least record for the
minutes that people were not in favor of
only I think about a pony mode because
like we're in need because like
otherwise it's gonna be like fighting
sound of us with no consents before you
are home or yes Pam if it's um I think
it's easier to implement anyway not
having to enforce anything alright so
yeah I guess the first thing make our
people generally okay would like this
just like okay bye rain baby by which I
mean going to hold their noses and like
move forward with this with OJ toes okay
so if you're this is a question for the
general approach not not specifically
compatibility mode but the other changes
made to make it look more like first is
there any of people who want to get up
and object to that okay um I would like
to give everybody who worked on this
like their beer back this is insane like
what why these middle boxes they're
meant to do either deep packet
inspection to help you with your playing
tags or to somehow protect you if these
boxes are not getting updated 41.3
they're dead in the water and they do
nothing so they will either need to be
updated on a to support alert on 23
natively or they need to be removed from
the network meanwhile if this breaks you
can just go back and and suffer one
round-trip of latency to go back to TLS
1.2 why are we hobbling till has one for
three for the next 15 years just to
support these boxes that should have
been removed or updated from the network
anyway like is latency that important
not about latency
it's not about latency is about having
it's about having a secure fallback is
that basically now that means any person
and networking force you back to tail
some point you and you can't do anything
about it
I don't have a middle box anymore but
when I used to have a middle box
I would never fix it if it worked we
make TLS 1.3 so that it works with
existing nickel boxes so I think I think
my assumption here and I'm hearing
speculating but is there two kinds of
metal boxes right here one are just
basically ones that are doing on non
deep packet inspection between state
machine enforcement those guys are right
will never change and the second is the
set of people who are doing um who are
you who are doing like decryption right
and those people like we're gonna let us
back 1.3 are gonna change using traffic
all right so then let's take a hub now
so the first time is for if you for
leaving compatibility mode out now are
you do you support the changes that
occur outline on the first so first
we'll do yes and then we'll be done
so hum if you support the changes that
active proposed
um if you did not support this
Thanks I think that there was
overwhelming support for them first okay
so for now now we're gonna do the same
thing for compatibility mode any
additional okay so please hum if you
support the changes for compatibility
mode what you want is please hum if you
think it should be required and please
how many think it should not be required
right you please tell me if you think
the question is okay I I have a question
here are you asking about whether
compatibility mode exists nails manager
the question is the question is you do
only have compatibility mode or should
you allow implementations do not send a
fake such an ID and not said Jesus ages
that's your understanding but I'm trying
to get what's in Joe's head because he
said the first slide on the last one
which means that he could have narrowed
that to not compatibility mode so are we
talking was the first hum for everything
that was in variant in echos slides
including compatibility mode uh yeah so
I think that the basic thing for
competitive over on the first line right
okay so okay
x-ray statement fine thank you then as
echo said you should say should we
require it should we not require it no
credibility much so so should we should
we require that the client and the
server both do the stop do the stuff
that isn't on the compatible you know
it's like all it's all the time as
opposed to as opposed to the server can
do yeah sure right like so so basically
the like okay what would be will
compatibility mode where the question is
with the client always in the face
session ID or the client only do it
conditionally on its own choice and with
the server always saying change that
respect because the clown is an
accession ID or to only do it at the
price I'm sorry that was intended ease a
PP foot okay are we clear are you
sitting um maybe you also asked at the
end what up the people actually
understand the issue because that's a
very detailed issue that may require
some thought so I have my opinion but
like I'm curious on how many people
actually okay so the first question is
should we require compatibility mode you
only have compatibility mode I've got a
problem because I think I have different
answers for the client and the server so
Myatt so my assumption is where it will
put if if you I proposed ribose this
text looks like is this that the client
can add its options to the patient ID or
not the arm client can have to add its
options and change their perspectives or
not and the server must send a change
their perspective the client sends it a
session ID that is where I approach the
person's tech say that is called an
option a and ok and call option B that
the client must always send a fake
session ID the server must always
accurate and they must everyone was
always in the same Jeff respects good
for a or b so b is the must
okay so so for we're gonna start with
the hum for option B that you must
always use compatibility
please home if you support option B okay
and then please hum if you support
option a and then please hum if you feel
like you don't understand the issue okay
thank you okay next next slide or back
back to back to the feature no sorry Bob
above that that's gonna fine you like
spoilage brother um so people suggested
that if you're worried about a going
mode you should require the client to
enforce that see cardinality the CCS or
the server for that matter is a client
which is ruined
um which is to say dad um brew science
and CCS exactly once in the place were
supposed to send it um as opposed to
like an infinite number of times or zero
or whatever on like um I guess I would
be fine I mean different and different
but I would live with requiring you to
send it exactly once
I think requiring you to enforce it in
like crazy pants and like when we get
meet them with even much much harder and
we've like our board he's like very
simple on this and it would be like a
huge pain he asked if account or in
choice it occurs the right place this is
Dan Gilmore so I also think that
requiring the client to receive it seems
to pick a specific number is crazy
I want to know does this bogus CCS get
factored into the handshake - no it
isn't even even it doesn't even know
that isn't even encryption but so we had
this the there's a hash of the running
handshake yeah it's not a handshake
message it wasn't even the handshake -
into one point he'll and so this is just
bytes on the wire that we're gonna
everyone's gonna pretend didn't exist
exactly so for the middleboxes
yes you think they're very important
they look
so Martin times an echo and I had a bit
of a discussion about the enforcement of
the CCS thing and it is very unpleasant
to enforce this because you have to have
knowledge about all sorts of things
particularly in the zero RTT case where
it's going to arrive at a particular
point in time we just not expect the
exact thing like that the other thing to
note is that when the CCS arrives you're
expecting to be receiving encrypted
handshake messages and so you're gonna
throw that away
or drop the connection likely it's not
it doesn't flow through the usual path
it flows through the error handling path
on your record decryption so it doesn't
actually happen you could look at the
tape first way you can look at the type
and that's what we did with a dummy like
you
so what I propose this text say is um
that the server hat the server has to
send it and the conditions I indicated
previously and otherwise we don't say
anything that call it option I so I mean
there's anybody is any talk to that
everything we should enforce does
anybody think we should like acquire
accounting I think we can just call that
okay next slide
Dave is getting up I'll say um we we um
I thank you for doing these measurements
by the way um we have some measurements
coming but we had a little glitch right
so we got from the test code um so I
have data which seems to suggest I don't
know what I don't want to characterize
what it says um this crazy um arms I'm
but hopefully we'll have our own data
relatively soon when I understand Paul
so apparently like you already made a
decision so I actually have it easy I
don't have to convince you all with all
these disgusting numbers
oh sorry alright is better uh next slide
I guess because there's no contact yeah
so back in February we tried to deploy
draft 18 and we're really excited about
it and the one thing that did go well is
nobody hates to tell us one through
client hello like everything we did work
the server hello didn't really work
our numbers are even more horrifying
than occurs yeah that that means a
fallback if even that I would be laughed
out of the room for suggesting we deploy
that thing we were really just making we
found those numbers it turns out middle
boxes are intolerant to the tailless one
free server hello
never mind that this is actually a Zico
suggested not these are file this is
violating our protocol invariance but so
it goes next slide
yeah so we went and tried to figure out
getting as much information on these
middle boxes to be cut which turned out
to be kind of difficult because like you
have to get these people to talk to
their IT people and so on on a general
rule that we found is the tailless
terminating middle boxes this is sort of
like these boxes that will like
terminate the connection they are a
trusted CA bla bla bla they generally
work v because they're just a client and
server connected back to back if your
servers implemented correctly the client
is appointed correctly then everything
works out fine haha there's some fun
that's yet o deep but there are a bunch
of other middle boxes that are in some
ways the same middle boxes and different
configurations try to process tell us
about terminating it
they do all kinds of random things
sometimes we're just checking length
prefixes because they thought that'd be
fun and yeah as a result they parse a
whole bunch of version specific messages
which is not like this violates all of
our assumptions about how we change the
protocol and they break unfortunately
although they are not working correctly
that 92% was kind of a horrifying I
don't think this is an oversimplified
picture like we do break some of the
tools terminating about middle boxes
because they have some parts of their
process that you could probably describe
as a non terminating middle box did this
is sort of airplay okay next slide
so oh okay so yeah so given that draft
18 was not going to work we went and
tried some options based on Kyle's
suggestion we test it so we actually
have some local configuration to test
with there's some some of the like
information we got from about the photos
so we iterated locally where we could
but what we have locally is not even
close to the like wide range of stuff
we're seeing in the world so we had to
run some tests in the wild that's
unfortunately take some time which is
why it's been like a year so in our
first round of experiments we did not
realize we had to make the record layer
change and resulted in that PR 1051
increment is the server plaintext
content type proposal so at least in our
experiments that's a no-go
also omitting the client session ID
gives you an error rate of ninety five
point four percent so that also doesn't
seem to work the experiment version
seems to work but there was some loss
and we have these confirmed by user
reports their user reports are not a
great metric because you got like ten of
them total but thankfully we got some
for the experiment version next slide so
based on that we managed to reduce it
and change the record blur version and
that seems to work it actually does
better than one too but I suspect that
the noise because these numbers are kind
of fuzzy we also tried to get some HTP
level metrics so these are metrics for
conscious so the reason the baseline is
higher than occurs is because we throw
out the TCP level failures so once we
successfully connect TCP if then we
check where the hand at handshake
succeeded we also tried to get some HP
level metrics they were added late so
I'm not confident in whether or not they
like to measure what we're trying to
measure but they are consistent in that
it doesn't explode and it's been on beta
for a few weeks now and was on my
channel for a bit and so far no user
reports around this time in the last
round we did have user reports we'll see
if this survives disabled I'm very
optimistic
Yeah right moving on
David thanks for doing awesome it's mine
[Music]
so Cedeno can go more thank you for
doing these measurements and for
reporting back
I confess that I am uneasy about the
unreproducible 'ti of these experiments
so I I appreciate that you have the
resources to be able to pull this off
most of the rest of us don't
and if we're making decisions on this
basis how are we gonna know that they
that they're born out and experience
that I mean that that that's that that
shrug is what I'm feeling right now and
I'm sorry like I appreciate that you did
the work and that you brought it back
here that's awesome but I don't know how
we can responsibly decide to use this
information or not use it makes it
honestly I don't have a good answer I
mean after has been to do some
experiments on the suicide like this is
part of why middle but the middle box
problems are much more annoying than the
end point problems because end point I
can just tell you here's a URL it's
behaving great harm like we couldn't do
the experiments of that right like I
mean we have some local configurations
but they're not really the local
configurations said that like we didn't
even send the confession there's my take
on this a we're gonna run our own
numbers and I mean like like what's
gonna happen is people are so basically
on we and chrome and basically you know
hackathon everybody got this in their in
their versions right and so what we
opposed to do is is roll out like to as
far as we can down our channels to beta
and drop 22 which is gonna have this in
it and then we'll have direct user
reports of failures if it fails and then
we'll have a little bit of time in the
Delta like all that um but on the end
this end and and because it'll be our 22
won't be it won't be 1.3 good like it
won't be committing us permanently
there's a totally screwed up but I don't
see another way to make the change I
mean like the bronze with the field
that's find out right and um so like I
mean
showed me this tell me what they wanted
to do when I was like kind of like
vomiting and um but I mean I'm persuade
I'm I like I can tell you the data we're
seeing now isn't good enough without
making any changes it is not good enough
so um you know this is visible yeah so
so I think we can all agree that the
proposed workarounds are horrific well
and and and and and also that that
losing the large things of traffic is
also horrific right we're stuck with
these like well no not so great choices
let me just understand maybe then the
data release understand right um at the
end of the day I mean if rific would've
been afraid acacia crap that um they're
really good I mean like this we're going
now sorry can you dial it back to 0.75
sorry I think they're just honest that
at the end of the day right um the you
know I may take the crypto I'd be really
worried but this is just this orbiting
it's formatting but it's complexity in
the implementations right we've been
bitten by a mutation complexity in the
past and feel that this is why we
resisted the state rule quite in the
state machine so on the complexity side
at least our experience is by far the
most painful part was just teaching our
stack that there were now six different
versions of tail s13 the actual changes
were not too bad
Metro code size for us hi Nick Sullivan
Claire um I'm committed we're committing
to build a website we have it half made
that allows you to very fast to change
changes in TLS versions so that it
doesn't take an entire browser rollout
to get the code in into browsers and do
these experiments so there are there are
ways of quickly updating the code it has
it doesn't go out to everybody it has to
it's a selective group but if someone is
having problems we can use it to like
this to debunk then I think you know so
you say that you would be a lot more
uneasy if there were changes to the
crypto but
it's not entirely clear to me that you
could actually characterize this as no
changes to the crypto because you know
we now have these safe respect messages
that like everybody's ignoring and
they're interspersed among the crypto
and I feel a little bit uncomfortable
about that not a lot of we also have an
application data byte and like record
their version
rich sauce Akamai and open itself
um I share a little bit about Dan's
concern about the non reproducibility I
think a lesson to take away for the
future is more transparency more
involvement with a wider group of people
experiment the I understand the
trade-offs with that um also in terms of
a lesson for the future I agree with her
that this is just like offending geek
aesthetics but we should explicitly
document why this is happening not
naming names or shame anyone perhaps not
in the published formal document right
say that for bad attitude
um but just so that in the future and
someone comes back next year and we
start TLS next TLS 2020 um oh yeah we
had to do this back then because there
was this problem with intermediaries
some of that's in the document but or
more will be welcomed if you wanna yeah
it needs more okay I'm like I could get
crack at that so in addition to the
documentation if we're talking about
what this means for the future I'm
wondering if the folks who are building
out these measures infrastructures could
commit in some way to having the
measurement projectors be able to report
when we can turn off the grid sets we we
can't leave I mean anything I'm not
asking me to make commitment right now
but like though that would be it's one
thing it's great to have this data in
the design process but if we're adding
things that we know we want to get rid
of eventually it'd be great to have the
folks who have that infrastructure be
able to help us also get rid of it let
me plan I'm ordering identify packet
officially yeah I'm like I'm skeptical
and a little bit concerned about the
black holing but it might it's like we
weren't actually measuring for this is
just we saw some secondhand some like
evidence which pointed to it um but all
right like if like we can experiment
with doing some
Thanks thank you very much thanks David
really better way like I did great work
by the chrome team in nekritz that was
like really nice okay great um so now
that we resolved like the difficult
thing this other stuff is like smooth
sailing so um we only have two minor
trivial issues but you have PRS for um
right now the close notify Intel tell us
one too is like foreclose on certifies
um the I basically um the UM when your
reciprocal identify you're required to
flush or discard all your outstanding
untranslated data but of course means
you can't hit like we're can't let stuff
you already sent and you can tree campus
on from the TCP buffers so like what
presumably means is you like ditch
whatever is in your application bunker
they thought that if I like a this is
like kinda incoherent um lots employees
don't do this I was looking like I don't
think everyone s SL does apparently only
boring does NSS doesn't um um so so it's
kind of silly um no one it goes back if
this isn't like SSL version 3 no one
knows why it's there you know we have to
do like you know call coach or like
asking or something um and it turns out
their application reasons why I don't
want up close because partly cuz they
special from TCP and partly because if
you have a protocol which expects a fin
business how you things are how you was
done with this side in sometimes you
want to keep running after that um so
the puzzle here in peer what 1092 is to
um basically just remove the thing that
says that you have to like um do you
have like flashlights or data allow you
to keep sending so it's a half closed um
this is this is nice thing is this is
back without of all previous behavior
because as I said it's unobservable the
other side didn't comply with this
requirement in the first place and um
and if you choose to end of course you
can always continue to comply with the
Carmen few stitches um so um we this
aggression a little bit a while back and
I sort of like what kind of person waded
off but I've been frustrated now that I
think this is the right answer
um so I guess
one question that did come up by Hubert
Carrillo was how you respond um if
you've already sent close in to fry and
you get some sort of and you get some
sort of bogus packet which can still
happen because it which could always
have happened because you can assign
clothing apply another guy's stuff it
could be in flight and then you send an
alert or you just like hang up the phone
um like I would probably eat this
entirely on the rules don't the rules
don't prohibit doing this and I just
personally that interrogate this
question yeah um on Thompson I agree
with that point and it says actually
does block rights after receiving a
close notify I checked oh but it's it's
like a very small number of lines of
code to remove well it would not be you
would not pick up non-compliant reckon
he did well we would remain compliant
it's just yeah it would be inconvenient
for talking about doing yep I would make
that change about okay after so I I'd
like to I like them I anybody objectin
reemerging this PR okay I'm gonna like
words as PR like when I sit down um it's
already done it's like just a button
push okay next slide okay on this is a
little more hairy um so sixty sixty six
on totally prohibits resuming the
separate elements so if you like ago she
Wes and I won and you you cannot like
can't like re try to resume that's night
to and it was that thing is I don't
quite have a survey but I talk to people
or my understanding is implementations
like your story or inconsistent about
actually enforcing this rule I think
people may be okay I think um so in
particular like if you have like an
internal session cache like probably you
don't like you know probably you don't
accidentally try to resume with the
wrong s and I um but um but certain
servers aren't good about that
unfortunate us and I I'm not assumption
know I think NSS actually is um but I
mean for an endpoint boyhood is I think
open does not um so um the on Victor
posted posted this PRM 1080 bit
definitely have I'm suggesting basically
slightly relaxed these requirements
um to make them a look a little more
like HTTP connection coalescence namely
but the client is still required to only
resume
yes Nye is in the certificate but if the
ship can have multiple subject names it
could like resume any of them on.i
but it should only resume if the SNI is
the same on because the reason is the
server like probably isn't gonna let you
do it anyway if you change it on the
with it the intention here is we've
opened the door for the server would
have some other extension later where it
said like listen I could lie you to
cross resume anytime you want um
so um one day I don't think as in
pictures PR is a requirement that the
server must check that the SN is the
certificate but that by shot that killed
um the UM from my perspective I I'm a
little a little uneasy at this point
probably answer um uh I'm an easy bet
folks we have seen problems with SLA
management um there's a paper by um
Antoine de Malabo and other people about
um about SLI mismanagement session
caches um but uh those were deactivated
one two on but the situation but most of
those things actually turn out to be
situations reading inconsistencies
between like be did the SMI lady should
be Hostetter and stuff like that and it
turns out that like we already have what
those problems with the HTTP connection
classes we've already basically decided
that like we're gonna think tweet oily
but out of the sands and it's difficult
as if they as if they were part of it
part of the connection state um so like
I know I always hate taking something
out which kind of feels like a security
concern so I guess I'm not gonna I'm not
only this program advocate for this um
if I had to like actually like ok like
yeah I had like sigh form with other I'd
probably go for it but I'm not I think
I'm really take I'm not I'm not gonna
make recommendation getting scribble
yeah not insulting I'm gonna argue for
taking it simply on the grounds that
we've basically already taken on the
risks and it really does still say don't
change the S and I it's just that we the
weaker of crack the door yeah and I I
think would be foolish at this point to
do anything other than send the yes and
I the exact same this and I as before
cuz we could we could if we wanted say
must not unless you're so extreme it's
okay that would be that would be that
was able to me that would be the
room for the door Bonacci open yeah I
like can you hear me
okay so so basically this is the reason
I believe this is reasonable is we
currently support if you're connected to
foo.example.com and the chair site give
a part at example.com and you'd have a
wild card for start at example.com then
you can HTTP connection pool but if you
connect to food at example that come you
cannot later resumed and zero RTT to
bar.example.com and there isn't security
wise any reason to do this
so say PR lifts the strict requirement
from RFC 606 six it still discourages
implementation from always cross
resuming and there are two reasons for
this one you don't necessarily know that
like all the main served within the same
search actually shares a session key the
second ticket encryption key and wasting
one-time tickets is suboptimal in terms
of performance and two there are some
implementations which might not be ready
and get in some ways confused as ever
mentions there were multiple bags in
implementations where they did not quite
realize what was going on so the premise
is originally I wrote a TR which added
an extension to new session ticket which
allowed you to do this and Acker told me
to bring it in a separate draft and I
will later brink and separate draft is a
working group agrees that in general
this restriction is unnecessary I will
write I have a draft to actually
negotiate
cross resumption so this is mostly
opt-in and this is mostly CPR is mostly
agreeing diseases crypto security-wise
safe to do and it's only implementation
issues which are preventing us from
turns at microts I mostly agree with
Spectre um I think we're basically in
the situation where it's som some
basically use it as a way to select the
certificate and other use cases will
actually when you're just using it to
select a certificate if a slightly
different sni value would you say
because you to select the same
certificate then you're gonna do the
exact same thing with like a VGA
connection coalescing that seems silly
to forbid resuming the session but then
just resume different SNI and send
connections in place so I think like if
we don't merge this VR we're gonna
basically end up in the same place we're
at right now where it says you must not
do this in a spec but some of my
patients routinely ignore that be sure
you did it that 1030 I I think I'm
confused about something and I hope you
can disabuse me of a so walking through
this what I imagine happening is I go to
have an example that that net it gives
me a set of other subject all names and
certificate I may or may not have any
interaction with those names I get my a
new session ticket I go away and I wish
to come back and go to bar dot example
dotnet instead of food that example
dotnet it's not clear to me in this case
why I don't make an initial request to
food at example dotnet confirm that I
can I get the same subject all names
back and then proceed talking to bar is
the reason latency is the reason I don't
want to make a request of
foo.example.com thing else going in
Viktor can answer this but but I think
latency and that the browserstack
doesn't want to do that right it depends
basically at the when you come down when
you when you come down from the like
that the point where you're making the
TLS connection like you've already
decided by HTTP you're gonna do okay but
remain a different opinion but that's my
impression I'm not sure I quite
understand the question so the reason is
that you're trying to connect to
foo.example.com and then you talk to bar
dot example.com but you don't have an
existing connection to foo and
connecting to bar is trick to it faster
than connecting to foo and then trying
to talk to bar later
so I thoroughly agree with you that it's
faster if you can do this this cross
subject all named presumption but it C
it certainly seems like it would work in
the other case if you had some query
you're willing to do foo that was known
to be ID PO query which is what you do
is you des and I you basically send I
mean if you want to do what you're
suggesting you would send whose us and I
write that you would work at the
certificate you got back if it contained
bar you would continue if it didn't you
would even put you would have three
aside the latency issue
yeah I agree it's a latency issue I just
wondered whether it was just latency or
there was some other mechanical problem
I think it's just latency and some love
but information convenience I mean like
what were you mean like imposing in
these because all the problems by
basically doing by basically you'd feed
in food you feed in bar we do the lookup
we find that we find the certificate
they had do in barring it we look at the
s and I we use the first time and then
we just throw the SNI out put a new one
in and then we look at it look at the
origin it's a zit okay or not on that
means but I means or he won't work and
it means it means okay that that was the
point I wanted clarification on I
appreciated thank you eating's right
Google I just want to say that uh I
definitely like support doing this for
the reasons Victor said didn't figure
did a really nice job summarizing so I
don't really need to to say much more
but I mean one added note about like the
two first names is they may may or may
not be able to actually serve you the
same content so it's not like oh I could
just like connect to that one and then
connection pool or like
it might actually it isn't for latency
but like they made people wait a second
I mean be uh yes you're such into the
case we're basically you're saying you
might have foo and bar and they share a
session shaking encryption key yep so
they can cross resume okay but then they
send different things in the backend and
so on now I mean like and it's and so if
you get the wrong s and I that you end
up basically talking you know like
basically connect to the wrong they're
basically giving like yeah redirect you
were right so I I guess I see that how
you could do that but will point out
this is exactly the sort of this type of
configurations that got people in
trouble with s and I and such a
presumption confusion in the beginning
right exactly having the exactly keying
your behavior the behavior of light
which surgeries into on the S and I and
having those be different and have been
having to Machaerus actually heard of
crushing at the session cash is exactly
how you in trouble um like if you look
at the host header it's cool but if you
like say you like say you basically
assume that like beyond you know I I
mean I mean well so I think what's in
trying to point out is you can have
foo-foo one and food two dot example.com
and they might be like physicalist
different IPS and you but they shares
the same ticket Turkey so it's kind of
like connection pooling except it's kind
of more powerful than connection pooling
in sense that IP can differ but they're
still cryptographically the same machine
no I agree I'm just I'm just saying that
if you have a situation in which in
which you have in which you have that
they sometimes you have the SN I'm
surveys yet sometimes it's not some
parts of the other faiths overlap and
some parts are if they don't that's like
how you get confusion um I don't know
how to mount an attack here I'm just
saying that you would you go back and
read the paper by by don't alone others
like they like they were like basically
taking advantage of confusion are
routing good secure Google I mean
generally in support for cross as my
second assumption
other it's not clear to me that just the
fact that you sure the certificate
to the same beautiful cost and in that
case you will be sending every data on
consumption that's not destined to the
healthiest mu which is like food which
is this is where this is why picture
says you shouldn't do this unless
someone tells you otherwise it's I agree
its finest I'm told you otherwise david
benjamin so on the confusion side I
think it's actually less dire than
you're suggesting you see is that
Diaries okay and so well so if your
protocol so like whether or not you look
at like something like the host header
or the SDI is like largely a function of
the protocol in h2 we have like very
solidly said you look at hosts and not s
and I because otherwise cause the
employee would work in h1 it might be a
little bit fuzzier um but suppose I were
to cross resume a food Arcana session
with bar calm the s ni that I send is
still bar calm and so if the server were
to look at the s ni it still says bar
calm the now there's a slight subtlety
here which is the s ni is ambiguous in
that you might believe s ni is a
connection level routing thing in which
case it is not part of session state or
you might believe s ni is like some
negotiated property of the session and
that when you resume you like use the
same one if you believe in in the first
interpretation where it's a per
connection thing then like cross
presumption is just like this is a ball
of crypto like either worked or didn't
work but like this is a key either you
have this is a PS k I know you have the
desk area didn't have a guess k if you
believe that is a per session property
then now you open the door to this
confusion where the server name API in
your like library returns foo when the
other one was bar in that case I would
say that like so I think we should merge
as PR but there's one subtle consequence
of it which is um if you believe it is
per session state you must implement RFC
60-66 as well otherwise you will get
confused could you you think you could
send a and then yeah I cannot um like
there is already a must in there it's
just that like some implementations
ignore it so we ignore it because I'm
expecting that Victor will come down and
ask us for it pretty soon but in
preparation for that we removed all per
session as a nice date there are some
limitations which both ignore it and
have procession that's a nice date and
that combination is not a good
[Music]
people think um I guess we've cut in
discussion I haven't heard anybody
really against this as I said I'm
waffling you wanna does anybody object
to adopt in this view
I know Antoine did on the zombie github
but he's the only person I think I will
do this directed by the chairs whatever
it is
yeah we should merge it okay I'm so I'll
wait for David to send me a PR against
the PR and then all personally um okay
next slide right so where are we um
emergencies be ours
um issue 22 like a Bronco um it won't be
this week but I hope it'll be like
Monday um I could be this week if I like
actually get dancing up into anyone um
and then I promise you 22 I mean it's 22
and then like I leave it the mechanics
to you do you want to do I mean well
we're what do you want will it will be a
target working-class there's no doubt
okay I guess I just want to make sure
that we do you have any feeling for what
you might be able to get your test data
oh we have so this is in beta now I did
like the thing is in beta now um I've
got to like write the experiment
actually test it which I'm gonna do like
basically next week and I'm hoping to
have data in the next I would say I mean
the optimistic version we're gonna have
data by the end of the month the
pessimist version I have dated by this
time next month yes very much
yeah I suspect we're gonna have
something a bit sooner than that I mean
we we landed the code for this they
become botched experiment on what Friday
sorry yeah um you were you were giving
me
murmurings about weird numbers on
Tuesday so yeah so there's some
possibility I could have it um dependent
dependent have to catch fire box um
that's that's the best thing we'll sort
of that um so what I'm concerned about
right is bit you know I the numbers that
we got from Google I think um a grave I
think that to be responsible we have to
make sure you have another data point
that's all so you actually get that data
to show that's basically the same kind
of range I don't want to so why don't we
do this I'll commit to reporting back to
the working group end of next week on
where I am about the gram having the
data and maybe I'll have it or may you
have it real soon and I'll report back
and then we can you
you modulate your working auscultation
that's what you couldn't you right away
yeah that's my dear it's get twenty-two
out my sumptuous that data is going to
show the same thing so Shawn you're
saying you want to wait for his results
before you issue working good last call
or would you consider the feedback from
the experiment is just another working
good last call comment I mean my
assumption is that it's gonna there's no
reason why the Google numbers they are
what they are so I think I think say no
evidence to suggest any differences so
my theory basically so the minute you
pump out 22 I mean it's two weeks I
still have to go through a tip laughs
calls let's not the end of the world
right at the critical finality point out
that we basically discussed all of the
changes the technical change is just
about to try in graph 22 right here
right now so this this slide deck is
pretty much the working group last call
contents I think there's a few other
twiki things but maybe I knew as I move
the server certificate type in the e8
yeah I did I'll just go faster yeah okay
well I don't let you manage this I don't
know I think they're plan so they'll go
ahead and you pump it out we'll do the
working class call will I guess I one
day I mean David are you how far away
are you for having 22 employed person
because that's actually getting you may
be smaller than us I don't know version
on like running code or it like we just
need to change two numbers because we
called it 7004 I mean you have in GFE oh
and the GFE that might take I'm not sure
exactly the timeline but maybe like
orderable so basically the two sprints
we can do we can do we can do basically
their experiment with trivial
modifications or we can do 22 um and um
I can get I mean obviously like the
latency for 22 is like how long it takes
us to get it get into Firefox and Chrome
which is going to be a couple more days
at least we will report back asap what
we plan to do but at least we can
definitely can definitely do a we can
definitely do any spare in it I like the
way our stuff works I can test get
anybody's circle so once again another
set of server farms I can nest against
them too um and I'm happy to publish the
code we're getting pretty easy for doing
this um so like his worries a matter of
like I need to be able to for Firefox be
like I think it's up some servers are
configured with one of these permits so
if you end up picking are like random
fake one like when we go and switch it
to 22 there any thick one will still be
there the question is I'm not sure
exactly when okay it might like it might
be order we will report back there the
list like you're soon yeah right this
week or min nationally don't worry fancy
that we're going to do we should build
that something I should I be fantastic
because having then we wouldn't then
Gmail be out of the picture and we this
didn't much more today we've already
done so in that case movie 22
um and yeah rich sauce so was the plan
to do a last call after 22 comes out and
though yes so if the working your black
obviously were to confirm confirm unless
that these changes are good also I'd
like to I think after we get
confirmation of Google's numbers then do
the last fall it's not gonna material
affect anything even if you make it just
one week um it looks better
family actually Martin I just realized
you have to talk is we it well up look
22 then we want that okay but if it's a
guy's neck as long as 22 lens and boring
SS all we should probably be able get
for CloudFlare and the next two weeks as
well fantastic look like the vast
majority of our like our one three is
like cloud player and Gmail so if we had
so I don't take a huge one three
regression or a numbers but up okay so
we'll work on that okay that's it for
channel 23 I'm not thank you everybody
okay with honest and Meg Indra Candra
like last minute couldn't make it
honest over there um so um during a
modest number changes since oh one um so
um I did this short record hunter thing
which I can talk about I'm talking to
each of these things um short record hit
things
sure record headers um I added the I
basically made it clear you could do an
empty AK um which you sometimes need in
cases where you're receiving like say
you receive the servers incriminate
extensions but university the server
hello like you like to build a shortcut
the round-trip plan um and I read her
ski updates without you faxed keep it
really well that's light so we had a
loan discussion of how to make the
record header short he back in back in
Prague and people and I sort of took
home that like we hadn't taught the
might as well we could as well as we
could and Martin and I went back and
workshop in a bit and so we figure out
how to improve things quite a bit I
think um so um basically the idea is
that there are actually two new header
formats
one of which is um basically just a
trimmed-down version the original
hundred format and one of which is like
actually like super compressed and the
point and the key difference between
them is do they have a length field and
zucchini can you pack more than one in a
in a record alright more than one in a
UDP Datagram and so um so this is the
first one which is basically just like
the existing record format except
they're like I took 64 bits and crammed
it down to 32 um and I did that by base
making the sequence number sequence
number of 30 bits long Epoque 2 bits
long and um and otherwise exactly like
the current one some Thomson I realize
haven't asked you this question before
um it's the reason that the sequence
number is much longer in this form
because you want a larger sequence
number spaces is your fallback that's
why basically cuz is he that of Orient's
um yeah um so on you this this is just
like wait where ever use details 147
actually use this and and because your
version ago she ation first you know
exactly what you're getting by the time
using this value so it's pretty
straightforward
um next slide there now fancy one is
this is basically Martin's which is
basically a you take up rocking the
sequence and you pack them in to a
single um into a single two byte word do
a word with the appraoch being one bit
in the sequence being or remaining what
12 um so the this this has some
restrictions on which is why it's not
the basic format um first of all you can
only do one or tgd because on the epic
bit is too short to let you basically
destroy any which are the multiple a box
that are employed during 0tt work that's
part of why the other ones got two
pieces that are one and the other is um
dad you can only have one run for
bracket because no lengths you can't
figure out how long that hello in the
value is but it's to buy their prices
much better um so uh yeah so they um and
by the way you if you work it out um you
candy mocks there's a rule 5d marks but
basically the bottom line is that no
matter what because these values always
fell in the 32 to 63 range and and the
um contact the otherwise application you
can always forget what it is
so it works fine yeah mutton thompson uh
the the draft that talks about they max
puts turn channels i think no no this is
it this is the turn channels are
separate or something yeah this is this
is always in the duty was already a
safety TRS range thank you
vivid so I think this is fine but you
didn't mention that you know what you're
expecting because you pick the version
at this point um is that actually true
if the server hello got reordered with
an encrypted packets well you can't you
can't you can't process that anyway
right right but you wants to drop it on
the floor cleanly and not accidentally
think it is a server hello and be like
well this was a garbage server hello I'm
gonna break the connection now I know
you want that you want to get scrubbers
overload also can't Caprica server low
you know it's you know you know that
this is bit number three safety so you
know yeah the point here is that server
hello will be 22 and yeah well the other
encrypted stuff will be 23 and this will
be between 32 and 64 okay next slide so
um you need to UM so the one thing
you'll notice is you used to be.we like
youth long ass values and they couldn't
overflow and so you know things are
simple um if you're wanting your short
values if like deal with it values being
short and so basically you know
reconstruct the sequence number in that
box from having from just the residue at
the bottom on the we're using the same
algorithms as quick uses basically which
is you the next sequence number
basically what you do from is you um you
know since us you know the right-hand
side of the sequence number and then let
the inside is uncertain to within like
is uncertain to within basically you
know it could be one up or one down
effectively of like the previous left
hands like you perceived and so what you
do is you basically use the full
sequence number that would get you
closest to like the thing you expected
to receive next
um it's not works fine the does
um a um basically what you do is
the lord of into the epic match you just
decrypt right away if the higher bridge
the epic match that don't morbid about
don't match then basically you file that
you week is like the epic like the next
one or the next one down um and then you
look to see what sequence over would get
you closest and you take that I'm
actually Martin's gonna save you in a
second we don't it on that you won't
actually to deal with this as badly um
if you keep the key update patch it he
wants so but so this is a pretty simple
world um we don't have
we have this implemented but we think it
work um and we haven't had the first man
put in class because yes like right um
you go forward one more and we've got
that ok so right so um uh the I brought
a poky update back on when you're taking
it out you're doing like a story we like
looking at the epic fit and like going
oh well go forward but now you don't
need that um so um yeah and we're trying
to avoid trial decryption so basically I
put the camp date back in and right now
we're just like the old time favorite
which is you saying send the key update
and um you start changing you change
keys right all right and then you have a
update request knock down our request to
death and the other side respond and the
way and and you just and the reliability
is papered over by having the acts in
normal um so um that's the way it
currently is um Martin persuaded me
after our conversation on the but I do
originally been right when I complained
about this before
um and that was wrong now which is it's
not a good idea to start sending it
right away because you have reordering
then basically um the receiver has some
complicated elements are managing it us
neutral decryption which is like roast
branched out the packet which eventually
things will succeed like not be great um
so Martin suggestion was that unlike
chillin point three you um uh you know
you can't change the new key until you
perceive that he updates acknowledgement
because they even their site is ready
for it and and if you do that then the
other side also won't have to worry you
and and if you couple that with the rule
that says you can only have one kept it
in flight but you already have on the
other side well unambiguously they'll
determine which iPod things are from and
they want to do any any concepts that
she was ever the other way um so I was
sort of backup on this but I think what
is the right answer so um I'm gonna
propose you to change the document to
say that none of us ever Lee says I'm
the only sort of annoying bit is
different than the TLS 1.3 rule but
that's not a hard implement because you
have to keep this data round for thee
the returns would timer anyway yeah come
on Tom somehow out of poker trying to
implement this and ran into problems
with timers so it's not necessarily
perfect because you in the test that I
was running I still had the the
handshake related time is running and
overlapping nose we're trying to do a K
up there was a little truck that not be
true either way right that's gonna be
true any and otherwise I think that's
just sitting down and thinking it
through and working I spent ten minutes
on it yeah I think I mean the bottom
line is details why do you have one time
writing this as workers
write this this will this should work
I'm gonna make this change in what's
anybody bucks and then also route
simplify that perfect circle okay back
one more flight right um so this is like
I think chewy non-controversial on there
are cases where you can't repair part of
the flight um so say you get on Sh let's
see it's a sh t er sent right and um
and for some reason the e company comes
in first so you're just succeeding on
this thing you know it's encrypted um
you got that bump it's you know what
it's from but you get do anything with
it cuz you don't have like the keys
needed to crypt it right so um and now
I'm like deal and detail this one point
to you would just like I don't know drop
on the floor preferred or whatever and
like eventually there a guy would like
retransmit the server hello you'd be
fine right but part of the point of like
the act of ordering in details or three
it's like avoid having to transmit time
now it's basically for for like things
when you're getting partial messages and
so there's one case where you could we
can't be recover on and so right now
it's re-written in version two arm of
radius or whatever was on the on this
case just battery um but but I change
this time as you can see is in this case
she's had an empty and empty AK which is
now permitting like just a matter of
changing the floor like zero instead of
one um and then and then the other side
doesn't it change its logical the other
side logic is the same logic which is
whenever you get an act basically unless
if you haven't retransmitted recently
you just right away of everything you're
missing and the um and so this causes
the other side to return the whole
flight there's no way around that
because you because you can't punch
things have an encrypted otherwise you
get that lock on so on this shortcut to
retransmit timer so it's better than
nothing and it's basically only thing
you can do in this cases and given there
which isn't hammers are quite long it's
actually a pretty big optimization so
non Thompson there's one thing that I
just thinking about this one there is a
possibility that the other side didn't
pick till ice one three when you
received that that message
and that's probably only in the case
where the there's a clear text message
coming back I mean he's sending you he's
sending you so no no no the client could
send the second half of its clients love
potentially or so um I don't so okay
let's let's work this route yeah when it
when it's the Clark way when this when
you're playing this role in the client
there's no problem because you never get
because there's no way to get ie um
there's no way to get you that already
knowing you're one free but basically
there's no way of getting an encrypted
packet period ah on but if it's a clear
text packet that say the second half of
the server hello which would be a bit
weird because that you should not even
if you don't have oh yeah alright so
you're right you right you can't you
can't you I told you know you're doing
one three you can't send the knowledge
at all right are makes me look careful I
that yes but I think that's almost never
gonna be the case I almost never there's
a few corner cases that we're gonna have
to do a little bit careful about yeah
particularly when when pieces of client
slows come in and with pieces of server
agreement otherwise mostly the rule will
simply be if it's encrypted you can wait
that's true that's true even with that
the yeah ordinarily if you got eight you
got the second half of the server hello
you would think to a cat anyway right
right okay um
next slide that's like so that was the
only competition literally um boys ASCII
update thing so I first issue the next
version and you know absent complaining
if this working basically didn't have
those tales are great so all along we
knew that the detail aspect would come
pretty quickly after the one point three
the teal suspect I've done so I mean I
think we I think there are fewer voters
of this um let me adventure there'll be
a number but right now it's basically us
I think um arm so if you wanted to wait
for us to have it off with arm that'd be
okay but um I don't know how far along
you are you pretty close
Palance was just complaining to me about
how difficult this drive 22 change is
gonna be to implement so I expect that
it's going to take a little while for
those guys to do I would buy two would
like to see at least two people talking
to each other okay it doesn't matter
whether it's us in them or us and
someone else but maybe I submit that
would be fine today so you wanna wait
you want to wait until we have a just
proof that we're not completely insane
okay should only take a couple of months
we're here anybody have any other issues
that they want to bring up okay I'm
doing a booking group last call on this
one I think it would be useful because
it would encourage their notice to take
a very close look at it like like it
happened with TLS again right it's a
working class call it might be Bill
working through class although I'm
actually okay with just doing for class
Hall so I'm happy with that I mean we
can make it longer if you want or
something like that but if usually cubic
upon and they're still I just want to
make sure that we don't get a
publication with that
Angra having we're having to
interoperate interoperating
implementation I think that really does
that helps us get through the ixt right
does work create okay that's good okay
last I want to talk about that I'm going
to sit down is the connection I do stuff
on so this is actually a personal draft
I'm hoping at the end of this gonna ask
for working reception so um this is
joint work with Hannes Thomas and Tobias
um
this unlike everything else I'm talking
about is not entirely baked um though it
is not entirely unbaked either um next
slide so this is like recap from frog
initially like the same basic craft was
in DTLS 1 3 and people I think we're
kind of sad because they felt like it
wasn't quite as finished perhaps and
like also perhaps they felt like
the privacy properties were like awesome
that they were hoping for and then
writing in the details may inspect might
not be a great idea
so um mostly just did we like took the
same stuff but I happen to do and I took
it out and put it in like and put and
put in a different draft so next slide
so the basic idea is like really
straightforward the extension that
basically says here is the ID that I
would like you to use when you send to
me and then um and then the potential
negotiation and then once you've done
that then you send with a sentence I
gave you and as usual at the client like
once like use the server's ID button
once and as oh man he sends an empty ID
to listen just listen their side on
software negotiation works and so you
can always say I have like a zero length
ID what you do if you like if you want
to receive if you want to send what Roma
not receive with one on the important
they're not framed on the wire and this
is gonna be a point of like some
controversy in a minute so just FYI
um next slide so I don't even like I
didn't even write up like the
negotiation I have in a document but
they're not gonna do it here um like so
obvious um is with the wire form it
looks like oh by the way this is also
for one two people wanted that um so
like it goes into the sequence someone
length on the wire and exactly the place
you think it does um morning yeah I just
I just had a crazy thought how can we
reorder the connection ID and the length
yes but I would like the connection idea
to be indistinguishable from ciphertext
let's let's all off that for a second is
it other framing if she don't like that
um next slide um so one point three um I
didn't manage them put this in the draft
because if you doing
I pleading competence um but it's pretty
obvious so because we look like on the
zone graph contains like the details of
point three ciphertext Russians that are
the new ones right it's like goes in the
same place it goes before the length and
when there's no length it goes before
like they're not unlike ones ever text
um so it's like pretty obvious um next
slide so one thing that people noted was
that like this got a privacy problem and
you don't want like have the same
connection ID like in perpetuity and
as I think I mentioned repeatedly like
much to sort of my personal
embarrassment after spending like a
crap-ton of time trying to figure out
how to like do you know privacy
preserving connection IDs like I gave up
included ID not to do them and that the
best we had to do was like give people
um you know an opportunity to say here
is like a new connection ID please use
this one and since they're delivered
under encryption like maybe when you
maybe if you like and do you were
changing your IP address you could
change IDs like I freely admit this is
like not um so um I hacked this thing up
and it looks like this which is
basically the message called new
connection ID and it says please now use
this kind of heavy like like here's a
new conditioner you could use and it has
two semantics that are indicated by this
like enum the semantics are either throw
away your existing connection IDs and
use this one now or here's one you might
want to use in the future if people like
it um so just we have lunch today
yesterday there was some confusion about
this I'll try to walk through in a
minute
um the idea is that you that I might
want to give you five connection IDs in
case you want to change and cuz I know
you're gonna change IP address if I
don't know one um and so so what I do in
that case is I basically I give you I
give you one in the sort of the
connection and I give you four more with
the spare marking here and that means
just add them to your pool um and then
um and then say like and then like say
my connection IDs like I'm using
something cryptic in Chinese and so I
decide to troll over my cache ie ticket
ID encryption encryption key um then
what I want to do is I want you if I
want you to flush and stop using all the
old ones I can throw away the key right
and so then I send you like one
connection ID with like the immediate
bit sad which is like throw away all the
other ones and then I send you four more
with the spare bed set it's like this is
not like ideal um I'm like I'm trying to
think as I was having a bunch of people
that maybe it'd be better to make this
an array in here and then you wouldn't
have to sort of send a pile of them um
okay then you would have like sort that
the message numbers um you start to sort
them a little bit by the way because
otherwise well they might come in but um
I'm not sure that's the best mechanism
so I don't like not you know I'm not
from the amendments will be exempted
yeah nan Thompson I think the potential
for having to sort by measure message ID
is gross we have to be anyway because
because the immediate bit means right
yes of course
have to because you have yeah so I don't
know um again
like um I guess my view of the state of
this document is I mean I said at the
end of this ass for acceptance and one
of things I've been asked for and I
assume people want to screw with some of
the mechanisms here so I'm presenting
this but I'm not like saying this like a
funnel for yeah I think we can iterate
on this this is just it's just
rearranging the bits around exactly okay
next slide um so right um so the bunch
open issues people raised I in private
analyst but the biggest one is do we
need a way to tell if I connect ideas
present that's the idea here you might
have a server which will allow you to
use connection which would like you use
a connection ID doesn't enforce it and
so now you might be getting messages
like from people clients which didn't
have a connection ID eight clients we
did and now you figure out which ones it
is and like I assert you can do this
with some packing this but I think
people I talked to were kind of sad
about it so um I know my co-authors are
gonna want to talk about this topic
though I think I proposed you want to
this topic until after excited wheeler
stuff the draft or not there's no point
like iterating on it if we just hate the
whole concept um um the second topic
that came up oh these things basically I
probably defer o'clock decided that um
the second thing that came up was um do
we need to allow could actually update
for TLS would play - um and I know I'm
sort of been taking data tube that's
what I'm working on 1.3 and on caramel
1.2 but I know that people don't go that
way so we have to sort of like live with
that on the last point that came up and
this is embarrassed to say that I knew
about this because I worked on it for
quick but somehow forgot it when I did
this work um is that if you just like
how the record sequence number advancing
one at a time you get cross connection
any leakage um and so you need to change
that you need it like basically we
randomized the sequence number when you
start sending um the UM technically
speaking you could just reran demise you
know laterally when you changed that is
not however ideal because the screwed up
the ng replay mechanisms um because when
you get a new message see CID you know
it's it you know that the sequence that
was very analyzed but the question is
what's the let where's the left edge of
the replay window um and you don't know
because you just got something like
maybe in the middle look there may be it
may be a middle of a flight right and so
we nice the only compute or the next
edge of the replay window is
that the good news is we have this
technique in quick where basically you
just essentially you basically have
basically at the beginning a connection
you just I wish a short key that you use
for basically to compute the gaps
between the knit between the connection
ID on sequence numbers and we could just
place that right um so as a same sort of
barrows like I think I designed that
somehow forgot about it
um so these are all pretty modest I
don't know is your existential for like
the existence document or not um so next
slide so I guess like are there - my
question is are there any existential
issues in this document it would stop us
from from adopting it you hear about
them um and if not I like to ask for
adoption okay any anybody have any
issues yeah how many people have read
the doc
yeah okay thanks anybody have any issues
that they want to bring up down to be
asked on Renoir we so not an issue with
adopting I would have an issue if you
wouldn't adopt it and that is I have
literally millions of IOT devices out
there that have trouble behind a net
okay so this is a very life real issue
at this moment and I hope we can fix it
somehow thank you okay anybody objected
to adopting this document yeah sure if
you were going to do a hum if you are in
favor of this adopting this is not you
are in favor of adopting this document
please um if you are not in favor of pop
adopting this document please oh yeah do
we have trying to cover the one up an
issue that I wanna talk about or it's
like okay can I just show you the next
lines if you'll know what I wanna talk
about right think about this on original
list real soon we're gonna adopt them
document I'll put the approval in all
right Nick you're up
hello I'm going to talk today about
expert authenticators next slide please
so TLS exported authenticators is a
draft that's meant to solve a specific
problem which is that some application
layer protocols they need additional
certificates whether it's from the
client sign post handshake
authentication in TLS 1.3 is a little
bit awkward and optional and perhaps in
some scenarios given a TLS connection
you might want additional server
certificates next slide please
exported authenticators is a way to
allow TLS library to export a piece of
data that allows you to bind an
additional certificate to the existing
connection and this can be done on the
client side or the server side the
structure of this blob is to find a
document it looks very much like a
server hello series of messages
certificate certificate verify and
finish next slide please
this was proposed by ATF 96 adopted at
98 and we've had implementations since
then I have worked this since IETF 99
we've had some small minor cosmetic
changes to the draft at the last ITF you
discussed this and the discussion was
that this perhaps needed some academic
review or some sort of formal analysis
before moving to last call next please
so in the meantime guess Kramer's and
Jonathan Hoyland from Oxford have
created a preliminary tamarin model to
prove the security of expert
authenticators in the context of HTTP
two additional certs there's some
promising results for this next slide
please
but in in recent discussions there is a
little bit of duplicated logic or
undefined logic in the draft right now
as written it requires the application
to select certificates and to select the
extensions that go into this certificate
furthermore there's no real binding
between requests and responses other
than the context so the logic for
selecting certificates and selecting
extensions already exists in TLS there's
a construct called this certificate
request and certificates in TLS 1.3 are
bound to the request next slide please
so with expert on authenticators we came
up with a proposed change to the draft
which is a new exported request
essentially this looks exactly like a
certificate request object and it will
be incorporated into the exported
Authenticator in that the signature will
cover this exported request if present
next let's go so that's that's basically
where we are with the expert off
indicators there's a PR with comments up
on this and want to raise this see if
there's any questions I think instead
it's the formal model the family is that
aware of it somewhere but is it sort of
like did they posted not yet I updated
passive Jonathan with new proposed
changes and so they're working on
adopting their model to this new
proposed change and once they have that
it should be posting
yeah so Martin Thompson one of the
reasons why I proposed the change was
that in looking at this there was a
number of parameters that were feeding
into the hopper that sort of determined
what certificate was being chosen by the
other side and none of those were under
the under a hash and that made me a
little nervous
and this actually works out really well
from an API perspective because it means
that if you do implement implement this
inside your tail I stack and you're
reusing all of the machinery for
certificate request certificates verify
all that sort of stuff
this
naturally it's neatly within that within
that model you can put those signature
algorithm negotiation we've never
separate independent from the stuff
that's in the in the handshake it just
seems to work out really neatly so I
like to change right so this change was
was recently was this week so maybe we
want to see if anybody has read it worth
anybody else has any thoughts for or
against this change what he said
anybody uh anybody against this change
is anybody read it I got one I got - yes
all right cool so I mean Mike that was
one of the one of the driving these
cases from your former employer I think
what we should do is well he wants to
take it to the list do you have a
timeframe from when you think that the
tamarin results will you know be closer
to the final I I don't have an explicit
on one but they they seem to be close
and the new changes from from what I
heard did not seem to constitute a big
challenge excellent so let's I work with
you to draft up a message driven home
all right thank you
so it's also to be noted that HDPE has
considered putting on the list adopting
the additional certificate strap which
depends on this document so so there's a
dependency there
Thanks it's dim project okay so you're
using the certificate request I remember
I did that's the old one that allows you
to specify algorithms are deceived by CA
that's right the TTL s13 certificate
misspent request which is just a context
and a series of extensions okay the new
mark
all right Oh cheer hat on so tried to
get one of you guys to write this draft
and nobody did so Joe and I volunteered
to write a draft it basically went
through and looks at all Diana
registries we need to update them um I
want to make sure this isn't a blocking
thing for teals from point three so
let's get this in gear and get it done
so just talking about the draft next I
wasn't sure how much time we're gonna
have how long the key loss discussions
are gonna go this is the quick don't
bury the lead this is basically what I
want to do so we got time let's go into
the next slide these are the changes
that we made I mean the big one was to
be factoring so essentially the internet
it started it's been growing if we put
in registry and the rationale was in the
introduction and it seemed like it would
be better to put the rationale for each
one of the changes in the peeps
intersection so we did that we decided
that you've got that recommended column
we've probably better actually explain
what it's there for
then we did the better we did a thing on
the list where we figured that we would
remove the CC and that's cipher suites
from the recommended column um they can
still be used they just won't be in the
record when you call we obviously needed
to add a security considerations and
basically we took the warnings that we
had for the sec receipts and had them to
every crypto related registry basically
it says warning don't be an idiot and
just implement these things when we
actually look at the algorithm um and we
we had an expert with you to the
supported groups that's really it so
this is mainly a big procedural document
so we're at the point now next there's
no really open issues in the github repo
so our theory is next get Kathleen to
start her ad review Steven Farrell has
kindly offered to Shepherd it forth
because obviously he can't ship her own
document so I'll work with him to get a
shepherd with you any comments
how many folks have read the document
I'll be honest I suspect that really
what can happen is the general review is
gonna uncover some things because that's
what they do they look like they care
about things like anti registries I
don't really think that any of you are I
Ana experts on the registry so I'm kind
of okay with that actually yeah
we do have some time so you don't have
to fly through these impairments hello
Makka pakka
I six I'm going to present the final
extension in style service and this is
intended both for ALS and Els both 1 2 1
1 3 so the problem is that servers are
vulnerable to denial service attack
against handshake essentially we never
say that kind of a beautiful sunny fine
little messages if we gain the server to
react in the first place parfum
processing can shake up to even steps
being a server to host a copy with
several concessions and the cookie
exchange complicates the effect upon us
in some extent but it is oriented only
to non fat adversary' so of course the
service is still exposed to own path of
bursaries ranging from adversaries able
to screen and inject messages for
instance a confined flows into city
before leveraging that is cooking
possibly up to adversely
in addition able to stop traffic most
likely from legitimate clients as the
whole state of a new several a stage of
course the specific attack attack in
fact this is particularly impactful on
constrain our devices relying in
visualizing the power loss networks our
goal was to essentially consider also
how to contract unpacked adversary's and
we're essentially proposing a client
hello extension intended does not have
to both he and I still s12 Murphy
including a park entry token encoding
basically announced and the Mac
completely already knows the handshake
token is built up by conquering the
first relation with the server and
provide for firing that requests trust
encore in first place establish
handshake with the server then
practically the
has to check the handshake talking to be
fresh and it's not the device and in
case it name Jake otherwise it aborted
yeah some more detail on the protocol
the server is associated with one
yeah only and they share along km it is
then visibility a to generate a token
essentially well the TA can be
associated in principle to multiple
servers that have to be registered in
advance on the PA and for each handle
server the TA as a pair waste hunters it
as any choice 0 upon certain
registration and that is used to do the
N Shake token as to completely solve and
and mortification for the tae receives
requests from client entity establishing
the session with the server and has to
verify that that client is authorized to
proceed the handshake with that server
in the first place and this very
rejection process is otoscope to the
document but kind of your locally on the
very same ta or out of evidence provided
by the client the client has obtained
and beforehand
and of course communication with the TA
I mean between the client and the TA
must be secured the specific things are
Alice couple is document well as we see
there's no additional communication
needed in TA and server yeah this is
just a graphic overview so you start
from the TA endless journey long term
PKM
client requests gate establish handshake
with server s the a generic token
provided the client on this new channel
then the file starts to handshake with
the fine hello including also the e OS
protection extension with intern sever
verifies I think a success the entry
quality isn't supposed to
otherwise it's meet the boat it
somewhere little step by step so the
final party s worth of innovation with
us then the DA considers the counters at
us as token dance and complete smack on
the ass on desktop announced as an H Mac
using the long term key game share with
the server it is dense a token
fascinating token aliceandmac implements
the counter associated to that server
the knees apart look lighten so the
only semantics to me is is agreed
between blue tae and the server after
then the client simply prepares the
client below infants used to start the
unshaped with the server including also
us protection of potential bomb and the
area of sanctions to define hello and
simple starts in shape then the server
receive the client hello has to check
that the DRS protection attention is
fresh using the token Alice in including
extension so it has to recompute the Mac
and check it against the convened one
and it matches negative it has the body
en shake immediately otherwise you just
don't hear any specific protocol and in
the docking to cover some additional
points as the social assumption this
extension is not strictly needed for
session assumption actually caused given
the existence of a session already the
server is perfectly able to assert ones
validity and even possible replace of
client twenty hello sent for assumption
can be handled by means of other
mechanisms like white below recording
but TLS one Tuesday's that at least
clients are supposed to the parental of
messages sent for Assumption including
extensions that they would include if
they were starting a new session so if
you won't be a compliant with this and
this is very important we considered the
TA came provided client the end she
talked and talked about before plus a
limited number of the Samsung tokens
built up for it the same logic
essentially be used by the client in
case of session assumption and just for
the sake in the end to be combined with
that statement
Plus as I mentioned when processing the
extension the server is supposed to
check that extension is fresh and
there's mobile using token us including
the extension in the graph we propose a
possible approach do that based on
sliding window and of course it's up to
you to arrange wind of proper size so
that you can clean off the actual
accuracy or of the plate I know messages
and and the memory overhead on the
server plus of course it may take a long
time but eventually the context of s on
the server drops around and that is of
course you don't want to reuse km now
pairs to generate a shake tokens for
requesting client so when that happens
the PA must know the long turn key with
the server and that is first we
recommend the TA to enforce rate limit
in issuing nancy's or essentially and
say tokens to recipients to avoid that
even legitimate clients can quickly
consume the non spaces even server at
the same time than serve other
requesting clients yeah there's a
related document actually indeed ace
working group environments where details
about the transfer protocol so the
security protocol to be used are left to
separate documents called profiles and
there is especially the DTLS profile for
such framework that in the latest
version has a knowledge the problem and
is pointing yet this document as a
possible approach to address it and that
is quite easy to achieving the profile
by the way because it is efficient that
the authorization server and framework
acts as the trust anchor on this
approach
yes the next that this version is
actually a major revision of the
previous one we submitted for drag the
overall approach is not the same what we
have a final simplify the design improve
the flat model in consideration mostly
I'll give dr. Meg thanks again for that
but of course other feedback that you
are very very welcome and this activity
will also consider within an EU project
about security in smart grids where we
produce also proof of concept
implementation of this approach on
details one two in California and
standard but that implementation is
aligned to the design describing version
zero when our next step is of course to
the line that implementation two special
one of the drop benkei dock so I've
actually read the draft a couple times I
read a couple weeks ago and then again a
couple days ago and still left me kind
of confused to your talk today helped
somewhat but it sort of seems like you
know the proposal is to make the DTLS
server more robust to us at the expense
of moving that out over to the TA and
the TA is perhaps still susceptible to
do us so it seems like this is only
useful in the case where the DTLS server
is sort of under-resourced and the TA
server is heavily resourced and better
able to withstand the do Estep that
right okay and then the other thing is
that I'm sort of we're concerned about
the not exactly statefulness but the
timeliness against the the client has to
get this this token and it has to use it
pretty quickly they're off because of
the way the the lack of direct
connection between the decal server and
the TA means that it has to do the the
sequence
we knowing in earlier train detected
these things are valid and so the DTLS
client could get these these tokens and
then just use it for a while its tail
and astok trying another one sure but
the client is impossible that session
plus it shouldn't be practically probing
the window size for perfection sure I
mean it's just there's there's gotta be
some tuning going on there in terms of
the various implementation limits and
the size of the deployment and I don't
think that's discussed very wall in the
context in the proposal just decided 17
because you said that communication
between the client and the game must be
skewed and be honest with you okay I
just wanted a second ago we have an RFC
age 19 or kiddos protection and slightly
different approach
[Music]
min PI from Symantec light you say
particle video server is socialized one
PA does though oh man it is supposed to
chef to the tosser from a server to the
TA right protect that pac-man that ship
to that yes now as I'm sure you need to
secure communication between client yes
well you can do that with other means
that possibly provide other solutions of
their own against that but even if you
go for Els for detail is between PI and
and gay I can first assume that it's
more reasonable to have relative with
you TAS or bastard against that or
easier to protect and way compared to
many more devices that connect at
servers they're putting much greater
numbers
this is Hannes um so so far we had the
us mechanism added to detail s already
two previous version and still exists
today with 1.3 and I haven't heard any
complaints that it it doesn't work it
doesn't fulfill its purpose so I'm
curious whatever you so may be solving a
problem that hasn't been out there yet
did you did you notice any efficiency
with this he does mechanism the cookie
exchange you you do have also so in
difference - in the old Daedelus version
you had to add this
hello retry request had a verify request
depending on which version of TLS and it
basically does a return readability
check it also has a cookie mechanism
which is a useful thing if you to avoid
reflection attacks and also to delayed
state allocation and doing heavy
computation which is pretty good in some
sense so did you encounter any problems
with that mechanism without actually
having to add anything beyond that no
significant a cookie exchange does not
cover on part of those reads that does
the limitation we're trying to
but you mechanisms can't exist yeah yeah
so you bit your big as the other speaker
said you you basically move the
protection and from the toss
vulnerability to the server and to the
DA Spooner ability to another note
because that will also be on back
presumably yes and I find it reasonable
to do that because it's reasonable to
need to have a few days quite robust
against that rather than mean more even
constraint servers but it sounds like
you I'm sort of reducing a DOS attack
again so bite a distributed
infrastructure to a Dorner ability
against a small number of nodes that
sounds somewhat tricky but done so I
guess the question is who has read this
crap I have a show of hand all right now
we're up
eight my name is Don Francisco so myself
and Richard and max I can solve a
problem routine today in appointments
the two related draft so Hannah's
actually on the exact same day on
October 30th submitted a similar draft
which is a four layer TLS which is
essentially application or TLS and
there's a related draft as well in the
animal group about bootstrapping and
what we're trying to solve here as a
problem is not explicitly solved in the
animal draft the risky draft so our
motivation it is what we're seeing today
and it's a device boots your problem you
see when a customer's deploy some of our
endpoints in our our collaboration on
point specifically but um for endpoints
the
unboxer network sorry the unbox box and
powered up for the first time in our
network there's a TLS terminating middle
box between the device and our Cisco
Cloud and the device is dead in the
water it doesn't cross the middle box it
is no way of connecting for cloud and
what we're trying to solve that problem
the device counts duty let's validation
that is don't you trust a private CA
root from the middle box how do we do
and there's a few different ways of
doing it the first one is expensive and
involves an integration if you Devi was
doing it the first thing we could do is
we could put an operator specific
configurations call you device prior to
chip in it so when it leaves the factory
we know where it's going we put specific
configuration with the device directly
across the middle box the second one is
the operator disabled to get a
termination on the middle box
Colet our device connect to cloud
doesn't really work as well and the
third one is the operator of the
manually installed private CA routes on
my part our position so mechanism two
and three are currently doing to the
inner core networks no one's happy with
that the operator think it's too
expensive it's too time-consuming but
we're proposing to do is work around
this by a device logic so what we want
to do is establish an application near
connell over the middle box to establish
a secure connection to cloud and
download the information
from the clouds enable device I'm secure
Network the device could simply download
the middle box cross information using
that channel and then fall back to
standard narrator TLS there's multiple
different ways establish an application
they're encrypted Channel we could find
something using gilfs art JWA J Dilla
peak we could define an encapsulation
using noise and our wiki just reuse to T
let's document again tequilas record
application there are design goal to do
this as simply stops when this few lines
of code as possible on the client and
it's few lines of code hopped on the
server and our rationale is device are
really called tequila stock API is a
network layer funny just get the drug
Chicago's that API is twice and the
second time we call to this tunnel that
information over the over the
application and so transfer what we're
proposing to do with transport to TLS
packet inside a QP and I'm transport
perplexity less per clicking the button
must buddies the reason why we're doing
this it's the lowest common denominator
if it's greatest chances conversing
middleboxes we're discounts at
university making proxemic where this
chance to get to work louder that's the
reason why one due to those common
denominator and the application Eric
Taylor serves the district address using
standard takes me guess your eyes it's
more suited to applications that look
like HTTP and as I say what we're trying
to do is just use a security to
bootstrap and then fall back that's
impossible
so the architect is pretty simple
we've this built and functioning using
open SSL see we've proven route you can
gather the ATT as well and the what
we've seen is the standard T let's tax
and all support unplugging network layer
and we call the top TT let's talk AP
item at the bottom at regard for
kilobytes and and then you can transport
for tea lights lights over whatever
transport you want and we're proposing
this transport unit already
the the application architecture pretty
simple you can see there in the bottom
and the application essentially
establishes two theater sessions one
with the application there from the
transport layer for the application area
session you just extracted height from
the bottom of the demon stack and
sheltered over HTTP transport human box
so there's uploads and discussion points
here both doggies want to turkish all
the way down and so we're doing an
application Aaron Krypton and over the
transport layer and water preventing
middle monsters from Franklin except up
and block that same question is equally
applicable for Annie and client
application crypto but are using noise
to be destroying something using all day
and jwe it's the same temperature
applies of preventing limited box and
intersecting - seeing that this looks
like encrypted traffic and running on a
blockage go turns out from talking
little memory box benders and most
middle boxes don't do that because they
chatter there's a brick and he thinks
what we were intending doing is just
using application air TLS for the
handshake and then falling back to maybe
or using key exporting and encrypted key
encoding
don't necessarily need to do that so one
of the questions we need to ask is is
just read application areas for the two
round-trips for the handshake then
followed by clicking mechanisms are
really just transferred all your
application data inside the teal at all
time under transport reliability pitched
messages can get lost
transport each other's records inside
the hand kick and that is somewhat
mitigated by PS using a TLS for the for
the initial handshake then falling back
after your first e-bikes
transport lightly he isn't such a
problem than either and one of use HTTP
connections and that isn't going to work
for life in all scenarios we have
deployments where we have HTTP proxies
in front of pilot permit in little boxes
so your endpoints don't have to connect
any way and then wanted all to connect
it's going to hit the middle box and pls
virtualization is gonna pay all the
energy and then if you try to do a
second connecting top of that connect
our complaint perspective they mean get
the deployer reverse proxying come to
your service and how to connect there
and below to break many bottles come
back I'm finally for a serve decline
signaling and you can upgrade WebSocket
necessary serve the point Sydney becomes
less important as well he just used this
for danger time take the first T
Washington's alright therapist brought
um I think people behind me have
opinions but usually I don't have a
question um so you um what happened to
me issue P connections aren't like that
like ten H CPH attention is like we live
description of the server right and so
you pull up the connection and you start
doing this stuff and then you know the
the server turns down I shouldn't figure
out what on what's holding that
connection to why basically yeah yeah
well well connection tracking not touch
exactly right and my point is my point
is like you you so do I understand this
draft to me edge to something
you um you know they should be
connection your busily time to tell us
the tell us records over HTTP right
which is like like um um or these
purposes in are probably my point is you
do that and then you're like sending
some data and the server is like yeah
you know I'm like tired in this
connection it I said the right and
now you three can own your connect like
yours back like your back you back I
just don't want right I mean you can do
what is like like like what is the
mechanism that do not care if the TLS
connection survives past the termination
they should be connection or do you have
if you're gonna do this work right yeah
arm but if you're if you're gonna if
you're not going to use this sporting
thing then I actually think you may need
you tell us con ID um did you to
basically right
possession what no not a matter of
finiti it's a matter of it's a matter of
from the tls perspective when you
reconnect to the server right on dad I
mean so you can just be like you can
just save a lifetime with the TLS
connection is bound the lifetime of the
HTTP channel right but that's like not
really great because like I mean like
what you really would like to have is
like that there's no logical connection
between the between the HTTP connection
in the tailless connection and then when
you like if you actually it's torn down
you don't through the resumption you
just do something else you just
basically say well yours like record
number 322 and I just sent 321 right and
so I'm just going to figure out like I
just like it I guess I try to feel like
like that's definitely one thing you
could say um you could say as a ketose
comedy or like that
mark Nottingham is this thing is that
good enough like this you know Wow okay
so we have a number of efforts in the
ITF currently or coming up that are
describing how to do things over HTTP
and there's existing advice for that in
BCP 56 this and we're working we just
adopted in the HTTP working group or a
vision of that a fairly substantial
revision I this is probably one of the
more flagrant cases there and and that's
all I'm warning you it's gonna be looked
at through that lens if you adopt this I
think as an organization we probably
need to work through how we use HTTP a
bit more before we get to such an
advanced state you know HTTP for better
worse is becoming to be regarded as a
transport by people I mean hey the next
version of HTTP is being defined in the
transport area so I don't know if that's
good or not but I think that there are
numb
problems here having said all that there
is a discussion in the HTP working group
right now about how to negotiate to open
up effectively a new tunnel in an HTTP 2
and upwards connection and I think you'd
have a much more positive engagement if
you went through that kind of route and
and the exact mechanism is I think there
TVD so I can't quite hear you
our opening tip is we turn off Tila
search validation so our motivation for
this is the point of a standard maybe
are the middle boxes just just carry so
the middle box is interposed usually you
know just on port 443 or so can you just
use a different port are they going to
be blocked generally that's why but work
through you don't come down
yeah right and and there's a bigger
discussion everything needs to happen
here and it's happened in various ways
in the past about how we feel about far
wall traversal and different mechanisms
thereby yeah ok
mohit so I'm still trying to understand
like what's the problem that you're
trying to solve is like you have a
middle box that doesn't know anything
about this on unbox client and and you
unbox it and now it wants to wants to
connect to some application server from
where it will get credentials for the
middle ball am i right or some sort of
information right so I have no
information about the middle box yet but
I will connect to a server and get some
information about this very box so like
since the middle box doesn't know
anything about this new device that you
just unboxed why would it allow you to
connect to any application server like
well so you're assuming that you will
allow some HTTP traffic to go through
for you to do the TLS handshake so I
think maybe you need to look at other
possible solutions for doing this and
how probably other networks do this is
they do it even a layer below IP so they
usually EAP and you can do radius
tunneling to any server on on on the
cloud wherever you want to and send
these send the information about the
middle box you want to
I'm just throwing a new idea at you
because what most gateways do do this
authentication right they do use here
fee and they do use some back-end like
radius or diameter wouldn't that be the
bear approach do it done pushing it even
further up because I don't know anything
about this new device that has just been
unboxed so I will only allow it to
connect to some server for a little
while until it gets credentials to
authenticate to me I can't hear you
sorry if your total radius or diameter
or anything like that you think or how
tightly created Earth the server's
running on the premise network I mean
you do appearing and these are things
that are already deployed today and then
define wherever yippee method you need
to send the information about the above
the middle box that's up to you sure
it's and I will be happy to help you
this is something that I have looked
into in the past so maybe we can take
this offline
uh also another offer of help if it's
helpful first thank you to everyone
involved in the anima brewski work
having done a credential provisioning in
factory key provisioning for a couple
billion devices I think that's really a
good way to go also with the the middle
box hat on though if we were to expose
an interface or if there were a way that
we could sort of authenticate those IOT
devices to know that it's just an IOT
device and then it's an IOT device just
trying to connect to its vendor and just
make a policy change if it would would
that be helpful to have something like
that built into the protocol is an
option or are these a strictly always
sort of an adversarial relationship
begin today we're talking a policy we
just want to ask for customers to do em
like this whitelist
white.this assist with the means that
our device team can get out all right so
you're doing it best just on domain
whitelisting forget what currently is
doing fitness at the minute Mike this
may be would you be open to us working
with you to do something a little more
surgical and a little safer well so like
while you teen max is one of the names
on this draft right so max is heavily
involved with the animal is one of
Biscay craft authors as well and this is
one of those specific use cases in that
isn't explicitly addressed into Brisky
draft but if if we do have Brisky
compliant networks and we don't need to
do this okay thank you
this is Hannes so I would like to
provide a little bit of motivation why I
think your work is useful and I think
why this group should take a look at it
and pick up this topic and also what
motivates me to write a very similar
document publish it at the same time
um I hang around a lot in its IOT groups
and they're um in contrast to this
working group people believe that Els
doesn't provide enough security in terms
of Indian security so that they would
like to extend it even further and the
consequence of that is that the
proponents are designing a TLS like
protocol app the application layer
totally from scratch basically with the
same design principles and that led me
to believe that why can't we just reuse
the same mechanisms just at the higher
layer as well and the use case I'm
looking at is not necessarily HTTP of
course but a co-op and deployments where
you have segments along the end-to-end
path which may in some cases not even I
be like you start from a Bluetooth
low-energy devices and go to your smart
phone and so on and it turns out similar
to your experience that doing that is
actually not just possible it's actually
fairly easy and requires very little
standardization overhead um so I think
this is I appreciate your effort and
I've fully supported hi this is dkg so I
came here this morning to come to the
TLS working group and I didn't realize
it was coming to a support group people
who have been assaulted by middle box I
appreciate it so this is all a
cat-and-mouse game yes
I appreciate your mousing efforts like
we need apparently we need more Mouse's
but I don't understand where this all
stops I mean you've already said Turtles
all the way down as your first
discussion point here and what you've
designed looks to me like a generic
stream transport over HTTP I don't I may
be misunderstanding it I apologize that
I had not read your draft and I'm not
sure why this needs to be TLS specific
if what we're designing is a stream
transport over TCP over HTTP so that we
can stuff an encryption layer in there
why does it need to be
pls what I mean yeah I mean it's
basically it sounds to me like you want
connect so that you can get past middle
boxes that are gonna be confused by
connect and let you through
I just you know we can specify all kinds
of mouse protocols and then the cats can
get hungrier and then we can specify
more mouse protocols but I don't know
like at some point I don't know where
that spreads and you have it you have a
vision where it ends well so we're about
to talk about the Kinect stuff because
we really don't think connectors gonna
work in all all the defunct nerves that
we in visit because the cats are already
too hungry for Kinect is that why well
let's take it offline take I'll talk
about the connecting after this right
okay um well one of the reasons why
we're proposing like actually
standardizing transporting Kayla's
records is and also we do intend falling
back as soon as we establish trust
because it's a TLS record it becomes
really really easy for the middle box to
explicitly identify work what were
transporting to see you don't see it
they will actually be able to look at
look at the byte stream with it that is
a TLS record I know exactly what this is
and so you think that the middle box
that's currently rejecting your TLS
records when they recognize that will it
no trans on running in the middle party
no it's not the middle of the projecting
our TLS records because there are
devices of the first middle box we've no
leaf crossing into the box
well you're trying to make a TLS record
go all the way through to the end point
past the middle box and they're a TRS
middle and the middle box is rejecting
that connection and substituting itself
oh okay yes yes yeah yeah so it's
throwing your attempt to connect
outbound on the floor because it's
interposing itself yes and you seem to
think that that I think the point I was
trying to make is it the the more common
case is that when the middle box
interposes itself in TLS layer it's
authenticated under CA that the device
you're the client doesn't trust and so
the client drops the connection client
you know the middle box means happy to
let the thing through easily even if the
middle box is happy to lock you can
clear the client can't verify the
server's identity yes you can't actually
get out right so I understand that but
what's happening is that the interposing
Box doesn't want you to make a
connection to the endpoint and what you
seem to be proposing is that you'll say
fine I'll connect via your interposition
and then I'll connect to the endpoint
which surely you'll be ok with and I
don't see how that logic follows you see
what I'm saying
well okay so this is a question for the
middle box vendors on for middle box
vendors in general then pocket water is
their answer to any application around
one crypto yeah I mean there's a variety
of answers that question depending on
how big of an asshole you want to be
like you could go the full like ABS
proxy like we can obscure this as much
as you want and ultimately they're gonna
be the cats are gonna be able to lose
information because the whole thing
problems or something
so I think that the more the more
conciliatory ants may give you some hope
is that you know in the kind of stages
of grief that we're going through here
in the support group this is actually
kind of the acceptance stage of grief
but we are trying to be okay with the
middle boxes but I think of Brian in his
presentation last night the patient's
off like talked a lot about how you know
clients needs to be able to trust things
and you know adapt their posture this is
about adapting the posture for the
network's you're in at the at least in
this use case that Owens articulated so
that that's what gives me some hope that
you know there because this is designed
to make lives easier for them both
middle boxes and the devices that it
find them there may be some possibility
of baton
i you have mirror formerly a middle box
manga there's a reason that the middle
box is decrypting the traffic it's not
because it is fun because the middle box
wants to get to inspect the content then
you go and make the continent cryptic
the first rule of firewall is firewall
is supposed to enforce policy cannot
understand what's trying to do this is
word and weird you drop so by doing this
extra layer of TLS or any any other kind
of crypto you're making you're marking
your traffic is weird and making it so
that the middle box is going to drop it
unless the little drop box has a
specific rule to get this particular
traffic go through and then you don't
need to decrypt it like in a business
environment
I bought a new samsung fridge in this
empty fridge wants to talk to some
samsung cloud for whatever reason that's
a potential effect that's something that
the middle box wants to get rid of the
middle box is there exactly to get rid
of that stuff yes I understand that I
know I thought middle box vendors and we
are a middle box vendor house watch for
middle box group as well right and in
general if the middle box starts to drop
any traffic it doesn't understand that I
think maybe this is encrypted I don't
know what this is it's going to break
you money application the middle box
don't actually do that blog deployments
if it's if it's a boy's room it doesn't
understand and it thinks maybe this is
encrypted Asia it's not the ANA drop
slap just break everything we gotta get
outta here mark Nottingham I really like
the points of the occasion you brought
up in that this feels like a tactical
response to a problem in in that you
know you you can't get through current
middleboxes and so this is how you would
engineer to fix that problem and that's
the mine but when we standardize that
that kind of has a different bar you
know this is implying that it is the
appropriate solution for the problem and
and and your engineering this way is I
understand it because you know it'll get
through existing middleboxes
and you're kind of like opting them into
that without their engagement I'd much
rather see something with engagement
with the middle box community where you
can work out something that's explicit
and that has a future rather than just
what feels kind of like hope based
engineering you're hoping that they
won't decide oh we're gonna block that
too and so yeah I'd still have a lot of
concerns and thanks TKG for that respect
all right so just so everybody's clear
we're not gonna have a working group
adoption calling this draft there's
obviously more discussion needs to
happen do that I've no problem using the
TLS to do that a gentle reminder you
need to go there's this there's a thing
in here so um thank you for your time
but please expedite leaving the room
thank you
you