we're going to talk about extracting all
the information that we find on slack
once we have credentials
really it's not a vulnerability and
slack it's just using slack to our
advantage as an attacker and also
they'll talk about blue team stuff
hi I'm Kerry Roberts I used to be a web
app developer until I miserably failed
the pen test which I didn't know what
that was at the time and and so I knew
nothing about security and I was told to
fix these big vulnerabilities and I felt
really stupid because I didn't know what
anything about anything they were
talking about so I'm kind of all I
nothing person so I was at a point where
I'm like okay either I'm not gonna be a
developer or I got it just embrace the
security thing so I decided to embrace
security started taking some training
from sans
and got some education so now I'm in the
InfoSec field it's exciting and I love I
live local here and I love to ride
motorcycles four-wheelers in the
mountains
so I'm Tony hamburger I am very
background I currently live in
Bentonville Arkansas working for the
incident response team at Walmart as you
can see I have very background in
networking security data loss prevention
HIPAA compliance been with the Walmart
IR team for almost a year now before
that was on the data loss prevention
team okay so this is a little disclaimer
that we're not endorsing product and
we're also not officially representing
Walmart even though we both work for a
Walmart so slack
some people may not know what slack is
this interface where we can chat with
people so here we have like Carrie
talking to Martin just sending messages
back and forth you can also send files
on the left you have a list of channels
that you can talk in so kind of topics
there's public channels that anybody can
talk to who is part of the they call it
workspace so if you can log in your you
can talk on the public channels there's
private channels have the little walk by
them that's you only can talk there if
you're invited so you might create a
channel invite your friends to chat with
you they're not everybody who has the
login can read the private channels and
then there's direct messages where it's
kind of one-on-one although you can do
it to multiple people but it's not
really a channel it's just like hey how
about the four of us talk you usually
more temporary than the channel and one
thing to note is up here in the URL you
see this channel ID
CCE four four that's unique per channel
so if you
these different channels on the left you
get a different channel ID and I just
point that out because that comes in
handy when we learn more about this grip
that we can use to extract information
from channels so slack is really popular
last year they noted that they have six
million daily users and that was a year
ago
there's over fifty thousand teams pain
for to use the slack service although
you can also use it for free and forty
three percent of the largest 100
companies in the nation use slack so
it's widely used and more than half of
those are outside the United States so
how many of you use slack at work girl
it's just freaking number so sometimes I
talk to companies and they say you know
we're not worried about what people put
in slack because we have a policy
against putting sensitive inside but
yeah what we did we left because the
policy here you know it's just so easy
to share information on slack that's
it's easy that you I can drop that file
in you know full of passwords or to type
you know somebody say hey Joe what's the
password for this Wi-Fi our system so
there is a lot of sensitive information
in there even if your work has a policy
and against
that an attacker might be interested in
extracting so slack provides an API
which is like a way for for you to
program programmatically interface with
it so we can use the API to do
everything that the web does for you
when you're just browsing through
channels you're doing point-and-click
but you can do that with you could write
a program to go see what all channels do
I have access to what are all the
messages download the file so you can do
that through an API and here's an
example I have circled the channel
histories it it fetches all the messages
from a channel so we can make that API
call
in order to use the API you have to be
authenticated so you need a token and
the token usually starts out like X 0 X
s or maybe X 0 X P there's a few
different tokens and then a dash and
some other numbers so if you have that
token you can use the API and extract
information from that slack workspace to
get the token you can you can login to
the web interface and the first request
it does to get your messages will ready
turn your token so there's an example
down there of a token and you just get
that when you busy slack so if you were
going to watch your network traffic you
can see here token you can also go in
and like sign up for a token inside your
profile but she could also just grab it
after you log in so I released this
PowerShell script called slack extract
and that's what we're gonna talk we're
talking about today we're going to use
that to extract all the information a
user has access to so we get their token
and we say we want all the files this
user can read and all the messages we
extract from it so if you go to Europe
that URL there at github CLR to abate
psycextra you don't see this script then
you can use it for your own purposes and
it has a little readme there which is
shown here there's three basic steps you
just enter PowerShell so you start
command
ates enter PowerShell with that command
PowerShell exec bypass you import the
module and then to see how to use it
it's kind of a self documenting script
you can just say get help with invoke
psych extract that's the name of the
function and if you do full it'll give
all the examples all the parameter
options you can use and so that's the
best way to get started so the basic
usage for the script you have to give it
at least three things the first is your
slack URL so in the examples today I'm
using slack extract a slack calm it's a
psych workspace that I signed up for
just for this demo your place it might
be like company name that's like an
output folder name so where you want all
this data to go into when you download
it by default it goes into your
documents directory into a folder called
slack extract and then inside of that
whatever name you give it so today for
the examples we'll call that my
extraction so we'll see a folder created
with that name and the last thing we
give it is our authentication so again
this is
a hack of slack but we're actually doing
this as an authenticated user the only
hack would be as we stole those
credentials from someone else which is
typically what I would do on a red team
with let's to borrow this from somebody
so for the authentication we can either
give it what I call the D cookie because
slack has a cookie and the name of the
cookie is the letter D so it's the D
cookie and it's your session cookie you
can think of it it's the temporary
password that your browser keeps for you
so you only have to log in once and then
every subsequent request your browser is
handing over this temporary password or
this D cookie which says yeah this
person's really logged in don't make
them enter their password every time so
you can give them the D cookie you can
give the script the D cookie and it will
exchange that for the token or you can
just give it the token itself if you've
gotten that some other way so how do we
get there this is just this is just an
example exchanging the D cookie for the
token so all we have to do if we have
the D cookie and we'll talk about how to
get that next is make a request to work
to face like complex messages and in
response you get that xox token back and
and that's we can use either one of
those pieces of identification for this
group so how do we get the D cookie
the easiest way depending on what level
of access you have to that user system
or your own system is to just look in
the browser and say you know ask the
browser to tell you what's the
the D cookie for slack calm and I've got
a demo video of that next there's also
ways to do it like from a command line
interface maybe you don't have graphical
access to your victim
you only have command line access here's
some examples of using PowerShell to
extract it from Chrome or from Windows
and you don't have to try to write that
down but those those commands are on the
wiki so if you go to the github
repository there's a wiki and there's a
lot of information about how to get
these deep cookies or these especially
things
okay so we're locked in the slack here
we're going up to the three dots menu
and go into settings and we're going to
search for cookies because we're looking
for this D cookie and scroll down we see
content settings and then we click on
cookies and see all the cookies inside
data and to make it easier to find will
type in slack comm and search for it we
see select icon there and here's a
cookie called D we click on that and it
tells us the content of this cookie is
bla bla bla bla bla that's what you need
to use this group so that's how if you
can do that you can use this screw
okay so here's an example of so we've
started up PowerShell we have import
ported the module and now we can call it
with invoke - slash slack extract we
give it those three required parameters
we give it an output folder name so my
extraction we give it our slack URL and
we give it either the D cookie or the
API token here we're giving it the D
cookie and I put a dot dot because it's
so long and ugly I don't want to put the
whole thing on there but that's actually
a big cookie there so if we were to run
that with a valid D cookie we would get
a folder in our documents directory
called psych extract with and then it
makes this my extraction folder and
inside that folder there is here's where
inside at one of these channels so
remember at the beginning of the URL had
a channel ID so maybe the general
channel has this ID the random channel
has another ID so we're inside of one of
these channels you'll get a directory
for every channel the user has access to
so usually people have access to a lot
of channels inside each channel you have
a folder full of files so all the files
that that that has been uploaded to that
channel and I folder full of messages
and those messages are written to disk
JSON files so right down here you see
each one of these is a message with some
details about when who hosted that
message and when it was posted part of
the filename is a timestamp so if you
sort by a file name you'll be reading
messages in order and then uh bottom
right you see one example of one of the
JSON messages which tells you who
uploaded it when and and the message in
this case was any news about the
carnival next month so this makes it
easy to do offline searching of the data
from slack without it if you're familiar
with using slack if you want to read
more than the last few messages you got
to scroll up and it loads it as you're
scrolling up and it can it's really slow
and that's slow to read through look
through and search through especially
downloading files is slow that way so it
also creates this meta folder which is
kind of the data about the channels like
what's the channel name its death
so inside chant the meta folder we've
got the channels meta and so that's
information about channel so you get one
JSON file for each channel and that has
information like the name of the channel
the topic the purpose whether it's
public private what it used to be called
when it was created and at the end it
rolls this all up into a excel file a
CSV file so that you could open this up
in Excel and you have a big list of all
the channels and their topics and you
could search look through for ones that
sound
maybe you want to go to those channels
and search for sensitive information I
said that you run this and it downloads
all files and messages but actually
there's some default limits but you can
change that to be bigger but by default
it'll download up to 10,000 messages per
channel and up to 2,000 files per
channel because you can fill up your
hard drive pretty quick running this on
big slack instances so if you just run
out without really thinking about
setting default - you will have those
defaults but if you really want to
download more than that
for any channel you can there's a an
option to specify a different limit and
we'll talk about downloading agent
profiles and logs later so when I gain
access to a user on slack when I'm doing
my testing I'm interested in finding out
who else works for this company so it's
a really typical scenario for me if I'm
testing a company is I go to LinkedIn
and get a list of everybody who says
they work for this company so maybe
that's I her out there's like 300 people
that claim to work for this company and
then I turn that into like first initial
with last name
user name and I tried a login to slack
with those user names so I'm I'm trying
to guess a password for one of those 300
users so maybe they're using like fall
2018 because that's common for people
that use season in the air combinations
so I'll guess a few passwords for those
300 users and eventually get in and as
soon as I get into slack I'm interested
in that whole all the users is if I had
a bigger user nameless than what I got
from LinkedIn then my chance is like
maybe if I guess if fall 2018 was good
for one and three hundred people and now
I have three thousand about live
usernames and I try that again
you know I'm probably going to get ten
there's ten times the users so I'll
probably get into ten years or accounts
so when I get access to slack I want to
extract the user profiles because that
tells me every user in that slack
workspace so now I have a very good long
valid list of mutant
for my password Jessie so one option we
can do with invoke psychic strike is we
give it that we give it the - extract
user slag and in this case we limit the
users to a thousand that's just to show
you how to change those default limits
and then the dot-dot-dot is really the
fact that we still need to provide the
URL the output folder and D cookie or
token but I didn't want to tak that
there so for that we end up with with
inside the matter directory we have a
user's folder and inside the user folder
again as a JSON file for every user and
it's named according to their user ID
this unique alphanumeric here and each
one of those Jason's if you look on the
left it it has a lot of details about
that user which I can't even read
but it has like the profile image and
their time zone and their name display
name whether they're admin and then
again at the end once it's downloaded
all these user profiles it writes out
this CSV file with all that stated - so
if you open that up you've got this nice
list in Excel of job titles phone
numbers their names their display name
which often is like their Active
Directory user name because that's a
easy thing that they fall to in a work
environment so then you have a nice user
name list that's different than their
external user name and helps you when
you get on the internal network and and
information about whether they're admins
so that's useful for building a user
name list and also for targeting maybe
we want to fish somebody and we really
don't want to fish the head of IT
because he's probably not gonna fall for
it or maybe we do because he will I
don't know and but that gives us some
insight into who's who at the company
another option you can just give the
script the private only flag so that
I'll only download information from
private channels because you might think
that people both more sensitive stuff in
the private channel instead of the
public
and maybe you're in a hurry or I've
limited disk space so you just tell it
only give me the private channels or you
can tell I'm only interested maybe
there's you looked at your CSV file and
there was three really interesting lis
named channels
and you're interested in what's in those
channels and you can specify
specifically those channel IDs you can
also exclude certain channel IDs it's
common for people that set up boss
so automatic scripts that post to a
slack channel you know maybe when a
server goes up or down and those
channels get extremely boring to read
and there's millions of messages just
like this server disconnected the server
rebooted the server did that so you can
Lance out and you see it's not posting
passwords anything and then you you
decided I really don't want to see a
million of these messages or bother
downloading so you can exclude channels
from your extraction and then also if
you're an admin if you the credentials
you have a slack admin on a paid
workspace this doesn't work for free
workspaces but like an enterprise
workspace you can also extract the
access locks which is this - extract
access logs option and you get a folder
full of JSON files again and it tells
you who connected at what time and from
what IP and what the user agent is so as
an attacker that's valuable to me
because now I see where people are
connecting from and you know whether
it's their phone or their computer and
the user agent string tells you
interesting information about their
system so you're going to know
there is Windows or OSX or Linux and
sometimes it will tell you more about
the software what version of Office is
being run and what browser they use okay
so maybe I can't get the D cookie
because the easiest way to get the D
cookies to login in your browser and to
read it from your browser but maybe I've
exploited somebody's system and all I
have is command line access so I can't
bring up the chrome menu and look
through it in your typical way because I
only have command line access we can
also just ghost out and search for their
token because either one works for this
extra psych extract and here's two
examples on OS X we can grep for the
token from the application directory or
on Windows we can use PowerShell to
search for it and then we can use a
token instead of the D cookie so that's
handy if you don't have graphical access
to system
okay so here's a demo of that whole
thing working
okay so we're logged into this slack
extract workspace over here on the right
and we've got a general channel which
has like a picture of a carnival and
this weird mask thing and then we've got
a random Channel and it's got blue bird
and some stickers and a pink unicorn
pink rainbow uniform that's important so
we're over on the Left we see I I using
an option to write to the temp directory
instead of the Documents folder in this
case so we'll bring up the command
prompt
we've already imported suck extract so
now we can just call it and Bob slack
extract we give it the sake all of the
slack extract I select I come an output
folder of my extraction and we'll when
we run this on the left you'll see that
folder pop up and then we're telling it
to put it in the C temp directory
instead of the default My Documents and
then we give it our token
come on
okay so we have here slack extraction up
on the left and my extraction we get a
folder for every channel and inside the
folder we see a folder for files and
messages we got all the messages for
that channel there this is small for
space and inside files we will see those
files pop up as it downloads it
downloads all messages from all channels
first and files last so there we saw the
pink unicorn show up we can go over to
the random channel here we're
downloading those images from the random
channel they're at higher resolution so
it takes a minute but there's a carnival
and the image so now we have a like many
gigabytes of information that's probably
sensitive to the company that in my case
that I'm testing and we're also gonna
extract users so I added in seed over
here on the right I added a - extract -
users and now I've got a users directory
and I can open up the all users and I
see that spreadsheet pull up here's all
the users of this workspace and their
title if if they've entered that for the
profile they're really user
they're images so that's that's candy so
now I have an offline copy of this data
I can look through and see if any like
files are called password txt or
anything or I can search through the
text and look for the word password or
you know for Amazon s3 keys or anything
that might be sensitive in that
environment so if you go to the week
that wiki on my github page there's two
helpful pages there one is the
authorization page and that goes through
all that we talked about here some
commands you can run to get the D cookie
or the token and that video is also
there how to extract it be cookie from
the browser so you'll be able to use
this script and then also there's some
helpful information on how to grip
through the results and I say grip
through their results because you're
running this on a Windows system which
doesn't have grep but you might have
grep there you know you might have
installed the little boot - app or
something and half prep but the problem
is the script writes in default
powershell output
formatting which is utf-16 so if you
grab for a word that you know is in
there because you can see it this just
doesn't really turn it and makes you
really frustrating but hmm so I give
some helpful hints
wikipage of how to basically use
PowerShell to do grep for you because it
understands that format or you could
change the script output in ascii if you
wanted instead
but here's useful searches you might
want to do and examples of how to grip
with powershell so if you wanted to
extract all the user names you could use
this powershell where you recursively go
through the director here in and select
name from the users directory or you can
extract email addresses you can distract
job titles and names and write just the
names to a file so i like that one
because now I can take that list of
names and go back and password to dragon
on some external portal and have more
success with a bigger username list and
then so the advantages of using slack
extract are we quickly get all the data
on our system so if we lose access we
still have all that data also is there's
a potential that the network defenders
you know have queued up some keywords if
they see people searching for password
through the like web interface is that
goes through slack itself but they see
people searching for they sensitive
words they might alert so as a red
teamer I want to avoid searching for
things that might alert and if I do that
offline
they won't see what I'm looking for and
again if I lose access I still have all
those files and trying to look through
files online is really slow and painful
because you have to slowly scroll back
through and right click and download
each file but now we have all this class
hold down and and we can do quicker and
more powerful searches with grabber
power to powershell creping now is where
i turn the time over to Tony he's going
to talk about so now you know that these
kind of tools exist for attackers to
quickly pull a lot of sensitive
information from your network so it'd be
good as defenders if we knew how to
watch for this detect it so that we
would know and the account was
compromised and that's what Tony
so now that we know that all of this
stuff can be pulled out it's like we had
to come up with a way to figure out how
to detect what's going on
we of course sat down with Kari she
taught us the script inside now we all
looked at it went through it really
carefully that's something I really
encourage you to do go look at the
scripts go look at the API methods there
there are two basic types of audits or
logging api's that you're hitting you
have your standard API so that a user is
going to be using and then you have your
audit log api's which you'll have to
have a paid Enterprise Grid didn't use
most of that the audit log api's can
give you access to areas that you're
just not going to have as a free slack
account it's just not going to be in
there to use it you do have to be an app
owner or an admin so the general user
can't use the audit log after start
scraping through your slack because of
course then you're looking at it inside
of trust issues so once you decide
you've got the data what are you going
to do it that are you gonna build a
custom learning module or you gonna pipe
it into your scene you really have to
decide what is best for your
organization look best for your
presentation so as I said you have the
audit log API on the standard API we can
do as admins of a payment account you
can use the standard API to do the calls
like the one Kerry was talking about the
event audits or the event logs which
says for this one a user logged in and
it gives me a the first time it was seen
and the last time
scene and that's the first time the
combination of the user-agent the IP
address the user sometimes of other
metadata has been used in combination to
log in as well as the most recent time
that combination has been used so that
can be good but our audit logs give a
better more accurate information they
break things down into an action and act
or an entity and context format so in
this case because this is a log in or a
log out of it our actor and entity are
gonna be the same exact information if
for example were striped me out all the
files it's actually gonna have an actor
the entity is gonna be the file
information so you're looking at the
file ID inside of slack the file name
other descriptors about and what type of
file it is so this is a real basic
breakdown of what we've got we have your
audit log API so really require an owner
or an admin account on the paid
enterprise grids it's designed for
monitoring not real interaction so
you're not gonna be pushing stuff to
slack but these accounts there are these
tokens because you are doing all of this
with token passing it separates logs
your login event is gonna be separate
from your log out okay it's not going to
be like the event logs that says hey I
logged in and this is the last time I
saw this pattern you're gonna have
downloaded files uploaded files Stanford
and corporate exports if you already
have a corporate a corporate environment
for slack you can actually export all
these logs for different compliances so
they
have those you can actually see when
that was done to see if maybe a user who
shouldn't be downloading them is users
joining the channel and role changes if
you're watching for administrative
changes hey what account got accessed
and then got elevated that shouldn't
happen you can access it through there
your standard API met methods are gonna
be accessible to any user they're
designed for user interaction so viewing
messages sending messages uploading
files downloading files as I said
they're going to be less comprehensive
so it doesn't really allow for checking
good logging it's not a great method so
we had to learn our source and call the
API
one thing we noticed is that the
autoblog API uses a bearer token to pass
things that means that the token
actually has to be passed as a header
value which I'll get to here in just a
minute
the token can be a little problematic to
set up so just as some points make sure
that you read the documentation that
slacks got online and it's got some good
documentation set aside a whole bunch of
extra time to work on it and be prepared
to contact slack I mean have their email
address already ready for support
because there's a really good chance
you're gonna have to reach out to them
about the token it may not generate the
first time first five times you do it
just know you may have to contact them
they may have to give you some extra
tips copy and paste is your friend and I
know the seeds dumb but you may write
for example user underscore logout very
basic you can't really mess that up when
you type it but you're gonna type it in
you're gonna hit Send and it's not gonna
work but if you copy it straight off
their webpage or copy it out of notepad
it works just fine we haven't figured
out why this is something we noticed
I've spoken with other people
they've seen it - four of us tried it in
multiple different browsers multiple
different compilers didn't matter we
just can't tell you why exactly that
works so calling the API this is where I
was talking about the bearer token
you're gonna have proxies if you have
any on your network you're gonna be
calling directly to slack API comm if
you notice it's Carey's script you're
actually calling into the organization
dot slack comm or whatever your
workspace is called you're hitting the
API directly for all the audit log
information we're gonna normally be
passing it as an application forward
slash Jason and then we're gonna pass it
the action is this a login is this a
file download is this a walk out of it
we have to pass it what event we're
wanting to look at when we do this we
have a 9999 limit which is the default
for slack but you can actually set it
lower if you're looking for very
specific information and it has some
other options you can pass like I only
want stuff within the last seven days
but if you notice we go down here we
have a we have a header token and that's
actually the bearer token that's where
I've made a function that just passes my
bearer token to me into that variable
and I actually have to pass it as a
headers item if I don't it's not going
to return anything this was consistent
not only here in Python but also in our
powershell we went through and recreated
this with powershell just because some
people don't like python some people
like our show I'll give it to you in
both so here if you notice I've got a
headers item or a headers variable and I
actually add that token as an extra item
I can't
I can't just shove everything into it
didn't want to return that but added a
separate item when without through hero
blue - headers headers works just fine
and as you can see just from the
PowerShell you'll see the results down
here we give it 200 back and then we
start getting the JSON format out of the
content we get that with the Python also
but it's gonna be piped into a variable
so if we take this information either
from powershell for python pipe it into
a simple text document or jason document
you'll see the exact same type of output
we're looking at with kerry script and
you're gonna see this too broken down
into the actor that entity the context
all of it breaks down you also have your
user agent at the bottom and a lot of
times you're gonna have to log in on key
so for login logout you're gonna see
that external IP where they connected to
from that can be a good indicator so
once we have the data we had to figure
out what to do with it
what are we gonna do slack generally
uses a structured database so of course
most people think a sequel is the way to
go but it's not every now and then slack
will go through and they're like hey we
didn't include this item that's really
important for logging so we're gonna add
it to the structure that's great unless
you're using a structured database
then you had to go rebuild the tables at
new call so we went with
kibana what are we gonna do with our
results we're gonna pipe it into the
bomb and we're gonna look at it
we're gonna use the last dessert so we
took our elasticsearch and our phone and
if you can see here you can see a real
quick patter and we could review okay
you know the weeks are busier we can see
that we're happening to key off of file
downloads for this specific instance
because we're looking for identifiers so
if we're wanting to really quickly you
are our talk stalkers who downloads the
most files we could fairly very quickly
in kobata switch over to a visualization
tab say give me all the information on
the count of the users so here you can
actually see the user ID which we'll get
to here in a second as well as a count
of how many files each person downloaded
so when we're looking at it the user ID
was our key item well you have to figure
out what what can we keep of what
doesn't change the user ID field
happened to be it and as you can see in
some of our testing here we have this
user ID up here that ends in ds8 and
they downloaded 741 files in 30 minutes
most users aren't going to be
that fast effort so we went down we have
some information I want to know what the
username is associated with this idea
because I don't know who it is so I said
let's take a look at that in Ulsan it's
Kerry Roberts and its compliance experts
and it's Tony hamburgers metric script
please ignore and not Kerry Roberts so
we knew it was Kerry if she changes her
email if the user changes their email
their ID world or their username I'm
sorry we're gonna notice based off that
ID so a clever adversary might go in
here and name something compliance
exports because that's a bot you would
expect it to be a body but it's not it's
an actual user ID so that's why we can
look at all of the data we've seen if we
see it up tick all of sudden who had
this ID six months ago because that's
probably gonna be the actual user so we
decided we wanted to build some custom
alerting with ours before we go up tight
to get into a seam let's make sure that
we're triggering on the right
information so we actually went in here
and built with Python a very simple
custom learning module we looked for
what we looked up the data to start off
with and said hey what can we see that
we know for a fact is a flat-out false
positive let's not looking to do that
then we went through and said okay how
can we start tuning this to see only
true positives for more true positives
so we've built a basic alerting rule
then we built a basic email system and
all it doesn't say hey when the alert
triggers email me something and I made
it extremely simple all I wanted to do
was see what was coming in get the
alerts that way we can act on them and
move so I literally only get the ID and
how many files are that's it it doesn't
have to be fancy just it has to be
functional once I do that I can pop it
into Mike the bottom workspace simple
thing pop in the user ID
narrow down the time field what do I
have I have Kerry Roberts downloading a
thousand files so I know that somebody
transcript with Gary Roberts ID just
pulled down with a thousand files it was
a very quick easy thing to do if you do
it every five minutes if you wanted or
even you're so automation when you're
going through I've been talking about
the different types of api's and
primarily focused on the audit log API
when you build an audit log API token
you actually agree with slack that you
will not hard code this token anywhere
which is one thing we have to do we
could not put it a number straight up
scripts you can't work so we have to
keep that in mind we also have to keep
in mind that we're gonna have to
regularly as a blue team rotate these
tokens because these tokens can straight
from any single channel all user
information we can we can collect
significantly more information or you
have to keep them safe one way is treat
it like a password
rotate it so automate what we can that
that seems like a no-brainer we
automated everything we could we
automated the script to go out and call
the api's we automated it putting it
into the databases and then we automated
the alerting system then that allowed us
to look at the very quick and very messy
sometimes alerts we were getting the
late false positives I mean some of you
could see like why are there 20,000
downloads oh I see why there are 20,000
downloads that's normal
so we did have some hurdles with this
whole process not all the API logs are
called when I said that we were focused
more on the files downloads that's
because the message downloads weren't
logged so there are some api's that
aren't locked they could be called too
we can't detect it
slack's already aware of this and has
been working on this but like Esther and
I said we can't speak on behalf of
anybody all we can tell you is the
limited knowledge we have so optimize
your data from the start when you're
building a database a large database
does anybody can tell you it's gonna
start being harder and harder to query
break it up break it up into chunks if
you're using last to search or Cubana
break up your indexes it doesn't take so
much CPU to start scraping through and
you don't wind up doing like I did at
least once or twice and killing your
whole database and rebuilding all your
structures DLP data loss prevention make
sure you're monitoring for the loss of
tokens or D cookies those leaving your
network when they're not being called is
pretty significant if you're seeing some
of these API calls being used with a
user token from inside your environment
that's probably not a good thing
because general users won't be using
these methods just inside your
environment
so lock discrepancies we noticed this
and we looked at this multiple times run
multiple different scripts to get it in
different formats and we could look at
it there are 25 times 4 log outs than
logins that kind of threw us for a loop
so some of the logs do have
discrepancies when you're looking at it
well I should have one log in for every
log out that may not be true so if
you're seeing a large variance get what
somebody else have them see if they're
seeing the same thing it may not just be
your data it may be across the board
then our API rate limits the limits are
documented very well in slacks website
they live well this type of API can only
call this many per minute at this point
breaks down really nice but we run into
things like the audit log API while you
can query at X number of times but when
we're actually implementing it and using
it in reality we're not getting that
many we're getting half that many so the
larger data set we're having to pull for
example like log outs 25 times more
after you free that 25 times more data
pull down that we had to put in a time
limit so basically we have to put an 8
second pause between every single query
on the API just to get that information
to come back to us otherwise we were
running into timeouts for you've queried
too many times
so that kind of wraps up the detection
side of it do you guys have any
questions
what's the most interesting thing you
found in a Slackware they had a policy
against putting sensitive data into slag
from the red side or from the blue side
yes from the blue side we've seen
everything from tokens credentials
direct server IPS internal links
external links information for external
services