sweet alright ladies gentlemen this is
looking at we're going to be looking at
fantastic malware actually the title of
the official title of this I really
struggled the title believe or not was a
extracting information for common
malware for worlds and what that really
means is that we're going to take a look
at the normal matter that you folks see
every day I don't know about you guys
but I see three or four malware email
campaigns throughout my week we are
actually doing so we are not doing any
reverse engineering we are not doing
debugging we're not doing anything else
besides taking malware and take it
running it and checking it out most of
the modeler samples are going to look at
today you can literally do in two
segregated VMs you got your VirtualBox
you got your Windows and you got a Linux
box which is going to lie to the malware
the only one the only exception is Zeus
panda banker which is which does require
internet if I have found but I included
it because it's a pain in my butt and I
hate it we will also look at trick bot
the trick which is extra icky before we
go any further I'm going to ask you guys
to ask me a question which is why are we
doing this that's a fantastic question
I'm glad you asked that we are doing
this because even though we have our
mind cast we've got our proof point
we've got our app River we've got all
these emails sanitization technologies
they're not always a hundred percent
just this was just September if you
notice here I've got believing how this
was an open directory and I have 100 X
103 px 106 e^x and I don't standing here
net wire Remco fantast
now I know my indicators are gonna be
however this is what I got
anybody notice any discrepancies don't
dance style 102 porfavor I had no 102
exe on this list and believe it or not
102 dot exe was actually lucky bottle so
if I knew that was lucky but then I see
okay great
so now I know that I've got my fre dot
php' which I'm gonna see on my network
the real reason we take a look at these
so we know what's attacking us we have
lots of campaigns that come through I
can tell you straight away the one that
always drops panda Baker is Hanson er
Chancellor tour doubt it downloads eagle
pony pony until the end of September and
you could set your watch by it Monday
through Thursday 8:00 between 8 o'clock
and 10 o'clock and bam it's coming in
with effects with all these other
subjects those large campaigns that
you'll see coming in throughout your
your day those will generally be well
analyzed you're gonna have a proof point
on them you're gonna have Palo Alto on
them most of the time those are the ones
that are going to come in you're pretty
safe with saying okay yeah we have
thousands of emails and just came in
even if they're undelivered if you're
looking at something like proof point
you can still say holy crud I've got a
boat ton of these coming in somebody's
analyzed them and it's good to go
it's these 1 Z 2 Z's it's these right
here that you have to be careful with
trip pile will normally come in
sometimes on a very large scale campaign
but other times as I as I've experienced
they come in 1 Z 2 Z 3 s and fours just
enough under the radar so if you don't
know what you're looking for you're not
going to know what to look for on your
network
any questions so far I was told by my
family to go slow unlike my standard
speed of gerbil on crack sooo questions
anything all right so the tools we're
gonna use all of them I'm a real big
open source guy the more open source the
better only because it makes it easier
to use for my perspective I use a lot of
Linux in fact as we look at this one of
the crucial things a tech help list calm
on Twitter really spoke this well he
said you handle your Linux malware on
Windows and you handle your Windows
malware on Linux we're gonna be using
VirtualBox who had a Linux VM I would
highly recommend matter of cell from end
game security I believe she has a post
and I'll post through all these on my
pastebin after this talk she has a
premade set up ready to go
VM with I netsim really hot stuff makes
it super easy to lie to the malware
which we like to do Windows 7 vm will be
using i netsim so i netsim there's also
a great one called fake net these are
what we're going to use to just
basically lie to the malware that it's
most of these affect all these except
for paying a banker will request some
sort of what's my external IP address IP
chicken IP an info I think there's a can
has IP what is my IP address all these
ones are just so we can find out what's
my external IP address will use I netsim
and the Linux VM to lie to it if you
want to get a little more esoteric which
I have done I'll run my own Apache
server on that van and I will actually
go down to I will go down
the responses from IP chicken or from IP
net info and I will actually copy the
responses verbatim how they look and I
will actually create different websites
within an Apache instance that will
actually mimic the exact responses but I
netsim does just a great job as well so
I will reiterate that when you are using
this type of technique using VirtualBox
I would strongly recommend you actually
handle it on a Linux machine if not if
you are willing to take the risk I would
strongly recommend wherever your source
is you use something like 7-zip to do it
to encrypt it zip with a password this
way you're going to prevent yourself
from accidentally clicking on it and
having a horrible rest of your day so
first thing we're going to do you can
choose whatever internal network you
like 171 60.1 and 0.2 is what I've
chosen all your 192 block 1 I 2 1 6 8
blocks those are fine as well you'll be
wanting to set these up as an internal
only network on VirtualBox
you can see here I've got this set just
a the router the default gateway and the
preferred DNS are the Linux box which we
just set up really easy make sure to do
a pain test test make sure they can talk
to each other so what I've done here is
I actually run VirtualBox on Linux as
well so I have a VM shared directory so
the VM shared directory is what I share
on the Linux machine itself and that
allows me to share from the guest to the
host that one I have read and writable
there's nothing in there it's only if I
want to copy something from the hook
from the guest to the host
now SF case
this is actually where I have them our
so that's sitting on my host machine so
when I want to make a copy when I want
to get this malware from my Linux box VM
on to my Windows machine the first step
is I use my Linux VM to copy from my
host to my Linux VM and this is why
movement Monday I have no idea why they
call it that but that's what they called
it from there we will SFTP that file
across from our Linux VM to our windows
BM so our process is our host machine
preferentially Linux which is holding
the malware we copy it from the Linux VM
on to from that machine onto Linux VM
itself and then we SFTP it across to the
Windows machine after we've got that set
we're gonna tell our we this that we're
gonna set up RI netsim really quick
really easy you can actually just do a
search in a place I think they're all
set that end up 10.1 anyway we tell it
hey we're gonna buy to our internal
address 117 to the 6201 same thing with
our DNS the default response is ein it's
an HTTP server I've been a giveaway so
we want to change that into something
that's not blatantly saying hey I'm fine
it's him
now where absolutely does look for that
first thing we look at is agent Tesla
agent Tesla is a key logger it is one of
many that I see constantly this hawkeye
key logger as well they're very
prevalent they can be anywhere from
embedded within documents to downloaded
some documents will actually I've seen a
lot of recent ones where they'll
actually go out to a bitly link the
bitly link will go to a loud coca la or
there's one other
I think it's confident mo they'll
actually download either a JPEG file
which is literally an executable or they
will tag on the embedded executable
within the JPEG file it's trivial to
execute it out we run this and a good
thing that I do is I keep an eye on this
bad boy right here so when I have five
Meg's of memory used I don't think much
is going on but I will tell you that as
soon as I run it I will keep an eye I
normally have both of these running I
have a nice wide screen monitor I have
my Linux VM on one side my windows VM on
the other and I run a packet capture so
I can listen the traffic as soon as you
see the magic of check I peed in DNS
there or you know that it's loaded into
memory
at this point in time i suspend the
process and i create a dump file I may
not have all the information there yet
but I will
I actually for especially for agent
Tesla I make about three or four process
dumps I let it sit I will resume the
process and then I'll do a search search
stream sometimes I have to refresh it as
soon as you start seeing this gobbly
you're in like Flynn you know you
got these are base64 encoded and
encrypted entries that we use that is
the key which is static key that 1v2 I
don't know why they haven't changing it
what they haven't changed together I
will add one more time make a dump file
from there I'm going to use a new on
track on Twitter as a very sharp region
I believe he works for Palo Alto he
created this all I did was add one more
entry which is import base64 and
basically weaponize this I'll also have
this up on Facebook we copy all these
back over three dump files over three
dump files over and from here we strings
these out we do al for a wide
- extracted basic b64 we run that script
which is here that's literally all this
is I kid you not copy paste add the
import base64 under there that's that's
seriously hit and we will have this
amount of excitement it does look a
little nasty at first you can clean it
up with grep sent off at the end of the
day this is what you'll get and you will
see that this one actually - ftp lassic
comm jungle at 6:00 calm people who say
gee that looks like a password are
probably right that's probably a
password agent Tesla comes in three
tasty variants usually we see the SMTP
version which may use TLS betweens you
will not be able to get the threat actor
in this case jug alas XCOM sometimes
they do a phenomenal fail where they
actually have their email go out and
clear text and they do an authentication
it's basics before you get the
credentials that way in this particular
case though it was FTP variant so if we
saw a if we saw a DNS request for alas
XCOM we would know that somebody has
opened something bad and their day has
just gone pear-shaped our next little DC
that we're going to look at is panda
banker we will start with that same
process we're going to copy it over from
our host operating system onto our Linux
VM we will then SFTP it across from our
Linux VM to our windows 7 box we will
run this and what will seem like a very
long time but you will actually see two
service host processes Python at this
point in time I actually will do
dumps as well but I will also begin to
look for Strings within this and the
phrase that pays ladies and gentlemen
and I usually just check for underscore
config as soon as you got an underscore
conferring the goal why because now you
know your bucket ID is 2 6 10 and you
have all the configuration information
needed
dump it lesson out bam there you go
there's their entire conflict up to and
including the base64 encode is processed
name which is usually putty dot exe
botnet ID is up there your web and jex
your b and c modules your grab or your
socks your key logger all that garbage
is right there for you so again if you
suddenly see this on your network
someone has just to open something that
is very naughty and you're going to get
the role it's a no response questions
anything all right
a last one to my particular favorite but
i really is trick but same process we
copy it over from host the linux vm from
linux vm to windows 7 vm the process now
is so fast that if you have process
hacker running which come tasty you will
see a service has been deleted anyone
want to guess with that services god
bless you Windows Defender it's kind of
rude you can also check and this one
will absolutely take an eternity I teach
you nothing you're going to wonder if
anything actually happened after you
click the executable oh my gosh what
happened
you can check because trick bots will
actually create a scheduled task as you
can tell it says it's every 10 minutes
if you catch it wrong you will actually
have to wait 10 minutes which is really
lame this is what it has started this
actual start I name my boxes ran
to make them look good as much as I can
in what will seem like an eternity
service house will finally show up you
will also see network activity the same
with agent Tesla you'll see your check
IP you'll see your can't I have IP all
these other ones I didn't dive any use
another one that trick Bob will
continually try this is why my external
IP is another this is why it's really
good to have these running side-by-side
run you can use t sharp you can use TCP
dump whatever you want to use a hoarder
so you can just so you can see the
traffic you can actually if you're just
doing it on your on a host machine as
well if you're running Wireshark you can
listen in on that a V net that
VirtualBox Ethernet interface as well
and listen to that as well from here the
phrase that pays is MC comp mic Charlie
Charlie us for November Foxtrot as soon
as you see this and you may have to do
several refreshes you're going we don't
even have to do any dumps through this
one all we have to do is save it right
down here you can save their strings
that will actually save this the entire
search this is our version there's our D
tag
there's our command and control servers
which are going to download a boat ton
of nasty modules up to including latest
one which is quite a sale grab over -
there's REO B's copied over in fact on
my VM on my Linux VM I don't even I have
the bi-directional clipboard work
rock-and-roll and I just copied straight
over copy this into Visual Studio code
XML format it posted on Twitter like a
boss if you happen to see Ford 449
you're going to have a bad day for the
rest of your day this is why we take a
look at these things these small sort of
okay it was a malicious attachment
grande wasn't blocked I get that a lot
well was it blocked yes it was
Oh fantastic wasn't fantastic but the
bugger-all wasn't right we want to know
what's attacking us so we know what
indicators to look for these are all the
goodies that we used I strongly
recommend visual studio code it is
cross-platform it is a as I've used it
more and more it's been a really good
replacement for notepad plus plus again
I will post these up shortly
any questions
please I use Windows 7 because Windows
10 is also a pain in my butt trying to
get it to stop running antivirus Windows
10 is fantastic for the common person I
would have my Ballmer in Windows 10 as a
analyst oh my gosh stop I have to make
special things special scripts just to
kill the thing I actually use Windows 10
for static analysis which is fine and
dandy but seriously I had to make sure
to disable all the all the antivirus
check the Windows Defender it is amazing
that that's currently why I've also
found there are certain types of malware
that will I ran on just the other day
the dotnet would only run in Windows XP
so I have a window I have no idea why so
I have a Windows XP VM I have a Windows
7 VM which is 32-bit only I also have
one which is 64-bit only I have all
three of them and I have seriously used
all three of them to analyze certain
hours that just won't play any other way
other questions don't think they're
inane questions because they're not
anything else
that's a great question
I recently kind of sort of switched over
to making snapshots but for some reason
I found for a long time than making
snapshots was having to remember to go
back and restore the snapshot later
it's terrible okay I better do this
great analysis you started up I had
firing out oh crud I forgot to restore
the snapshot I just cut it out stop it
restore the snapshot I've actually gone
in and set the drive once I get
everything all set up I got all the
tools that I need paid dump whatever
process hacker I will actually go in and
set that drive to immutable and so all I
need to do is as soon as I shut it down
it automatically if nothing was ever
stored into the disk when it's when
you're using it for snapshots then it
stores in the disk there's a caveat with
that however the bonus point about if
you're using snapshots you can if you
say oh gee I needed a file off that off
that image I can actually just start up
my virtual box again and boom
everything's fine and dandy I didn't
restore the snapshot yet so I can still
grab the file or the artifact that was
dropped but that's a really good
question so far immutable seems to be
the best method for me but I have
switched over a couple of them to the
snapshot method just because a lot of
these tools get updated really
frequently x64 debug gets updated just
almost monthly and I'd like to keep
those tools current so that's why I've
kind of switched over there to the
snapshot man anything else okay
the last bit before I go as you go out
and as you look at these malicious code
as you defend your companies defend
families but one thing to keep in mind
is that everything we do every service
every product it is all about people so
as you approach your day and it's two
o'clock in the morning you you're on
call and you're looking at an IDs alert
keep it in the back of your mind really
at the end of the day it's all about
people
all right thank you very much
appreciated
[Applause]