they're not just consumer products IOT
czar ending up in enterprise enterprises
and they're typically you know think
about you're thinking of like what
Amazon echo you think of nest
thermostats and then you also are
thinking about printers right because
because probably the most common IOT
device that's on these networks and use
five by people are printers and
historically these devices are typically
left out of policies for manageability
and security and monitoring stuff so
let's jump into this I'm going to talk
about the threat landscape this is the
fun part this is the part I love okay we
know cybersecurity is a disruptive force
some of the numbers that we've got
worldwide cyber crime would be a six
trillion dollar problem by 2021 the 2016
data 1,700 significant this sooner
really loaded me when I first saw this
1700 so but notice it says significant
now how how many of you guys remember
the Reagan era okay so I think there's a
lot of there's some people in here that
weren't even born then okay and during
the Reagan era the National Defense
organization
defensive tech security in the US they
had on average about 8,000 attack cyber
attacks a year okay 8,000 today so by
the way Reagan was back in the 80s okay
guys today it went from eight thousand a
year
eight million attacks okay on the US
government eight million okay this this
just blew my mind when I heard this so
it is happening and it's not good so we
know that the adversaries are evolving
okay and why and how their attack
sophistication is increasing not
necessarily because the individual is
becoming more sophisticated but because
the tools that these bad guys are
developing these hackers are developing
they're they're sold on the darknet you
can go on you can go on the darknet buy
these tools that are readily available
for hacking into systems you know
there's there the eternal blue one right
that happened on that was back on
windows 7 eternal blue scripts where
that and code there's tools that are
developed by and for hackers Metasploit
how many people have used math boy yeah
okay great reverse engineering tool
right we use it for testing you should
be using for you can use it for
penetration testing without developed by
a hacker
okay Ida Pro same similar concept Ida
Pro is developed by a hacker it's sold
commercially now so these tools that are
being developed there they're developed
by hackers and they're being bought and
sold for hackers
you know they're being utilized so I'm
in the manufacturing space for our
printers what can we do to counteract
these attacks the sophistication of
attacks well I'm going to get into more
details about what we mean by we have to
be build resilient devices what does
that mean it's got that there's actually
a definition and there's a new
specification that we'll talk about in a
second but essentially resilience means
that you can protect yourself to the
degree that you can in the event that
you cannot protect against everything
you need to detect certain things in
certain anomalies that may be in your
devices that are occurring and then
recover the resiliency is the ability to
recover so let's look at what we I love
this one these are destructive attacks
okay destructive attacks are out there
to actually damage data damage companies
you know bring them down it's a loss of
revenue it's a loss of data if you look
the one that I like them you know this
Shamoon 2012 hugely devastated saudi
aramco one of the big oil refineries in
saudi arabia okay so i heard this story
from mafia boy he was the guy that
brought down the walls you know brought
down Wall Street back in the 90s so
imagine you're in your company you're an
IT guy you get an email from a friend
looks like it's from a friend it says
click this link okay this guy
this is Shamu
well this guy clicked the link and a
picture of the us-american fight comes
up on his screen and it starts burning
okay and as it's burning people are
getting up inside the company going what
the heck is going on so it brought down
30,000 pcs in a matter of minutes
because what it did is if they basically
overrode the Master Boot Record and you
couldn't you could not bring those pcs
back there you have to they had to go
and walk to each one and reinstall the
BIOS reinstall the operating system and
God forbid if you haven't backed up your
data it was gone so a huge impact to
Saudi Aramco during that time the other
one I'll point out is that the Ukrainian
Power Group so this one about a quarter
of a million people in the Ukraine there
were without power for hours and what's
interesting about this one
it was the reconnaissance that was done
before the attack these hackers spent
months collecting information collecting
passwords you know and through phishing
attacks or various means but they
basically gathered all this
reconnaissance information and the
logistics of it
we're just if you look at how they
attacked it with it
within minutes a quarter of a million
people without power it's just
impressive very impressive some of these
other ones are going to talk about
Mariah was an IOT device IO T attack and
so with Reapers I'm going to get into a
little bit more details about those but
you know you can kind of see wanna cry
Petya those were grand somewhere and you
ran some orders where essentially it
encrypts all the data you guys know
there's like crypts all the data right
and if you pay the ransom supposedly
you'll get you know the key that outs
you decrypt it do you know what most
instances when somebody paid the ransom
they got nothing they got nothing back
and and then not Petiot was specifically
I'm gonna just screwed screwed through
all the data on your PC and forget about
a ransom I don't need that I just want
to you know distract cause you know rap
the destruction of this information so I
do I want to keep moving quickly here
but NSA did a presentation of RSA this
year so basically this is the these
statistics are so kind of mind-boggling
right so ninety-three percent of the
2017 incidents were preventable with
best practices what type of best
practices are they talking about
hardening endpoints like setting
passwords closing ports and hardening
your network okay so 93 percent could
have been you prevent it very easily and
then the 90 percent of cyber incidents
are due to human error
human error they either inadvertently or
purposefully do this
the perk down on the bottom which is
sort of interesting about this NSA has
not responded to an intrusion using
zero-day exploit in the last 24 months
so zero day exploits are new new attacks
right new attack vectors what that means
is and this is the part that just as
amazing is that they are using existing
hacks
okay so what's old is new again that
eternal blue some of the existing hacks
that are out there they're getting the
tools on the darknet and they're
attacking devices because they're not
updated you know Microsoft came out with
you know fixes for a lot of these facts
and other other devices did as will we
on printers we have a hard time getting
our customers to update their devices we
are fixing security vulnerabilities in
our products issuing security bulletins
and issuing new firmware and about 70
percent of the time they're not updating
their devices so you know these are in
points that are going to be on your
network and they're putting your
infrastructure at risk right this is
another telling one about a cyber
security agent from the FBI actually
this base turn Boise 70% of the time the
device on the company's network hardly
cause that initial breach is unknown
what does that mean they weren't
monitoring those devices and in most
instances that's an IOT device
during them how many customers are
monitoring their thermostats that if
they're you know the smarts thermostats
or their printers or any of these
devices and yet they can be used to
attack an outlet and bring it down
so IOT is the weakest link you know
there's a big predict seventy-five
billion units of IOT devices will be out
there they're there grantees are playing
with security flaws there's boner
abilities in those in them there's weak
default passwords lack of software
updates they're not you have to actually
have these updates occur and make sure
that they're timely and they're applied
to the device and then we have these
distributed denial of service attacks
where they're using these devices as
botnets and essentially bringing down
the network and I've got a couple of
examples infect the next one was let's
get to that but a lot of the device
manufacturers don't make security a
priority and that's why these devices
are targets of attack so arrived did you
how many guys have heard of Mariah
and where I attack okay yeah brought
down the internet on the eastern
seaboard so people could not get to
their you know favorite web sites out
there
Mariah actually attacked 2.5 million
devices and and what they targeted were
you know security cameras DVRs and
Printers printers were included in that
they looked for devices that didn't have
passwords that they're just blank rights
only do have default passwords
the default password is like no topspin
at all it doesn't take you very long to
figure out what it is and they found
these devices they were running SSH or
telnet
and weak passwords that boom they could
inject their color right into him and
they basically brought down created a
distributed denial-of-service on the DNS
server the dining DNS server so people
couldn't find get to their websites
without with no DNS you can't use a
hostname to get to a server right this
is the other one Reaper IOT botnet
effects networks okay this the reason
this one's a little scary is that you
don't know that you've been infected and
these these these these little malware
on these devices is sitting there and
the one thing that the malware typically
does when its installed on an infected
devices that tries to phone home to its
commanding control center right and so
it's exchanging information externally
and asking what do I want to do they're
predicting that this could potentially
be there waiting for enough devices that
they can utilize to create this
distributed denial-of-service so and the
only way to know is if you were running
Wireshark and saw these packets going
out from these devices these devices
don't have like antivirus software
running on right IO T's just don't so
what are some of the common attack
vectors that you have the the default
passwords is a bad one buffer overflows
that's where you know
the input and this is you know not a
good thing either because that's
typically where they can inject code is
using a buffer overflow and some of
these others unpatched you know I kind
of talked about them patched systems and
phishing attacks as well exploits those
are still occurring so what our cyber
resilient
devices are going to just bring this
thing up a couple of slides to kind of
share on average for every hundred lines
of source code how skilled or what a
code cook developer you are there's
typically on average one defect the odds
are against us so recognizing that you
can protect your devices and harden them
to the best degree possible do you want
to be able to detect those potential
attacks and then recover from those and
this is kind of going through what are
the steps you go through so protect
detect recover during the initial
startup the first thing that loves
bootloader loves the BIOS right you want
to make sure that that is rooted in
trust otherwise
it attacks the device and you
essentially want to own it
there was a canon device where they were
ready to do on the printer and just
started up it means you're doing running
on the control panel that's something
that's just been rootkit
you want to secure the defaults and
click data or grass code signing
validation doing boot so that you don't
blow a code that hasn't been validated
write a little code that's become from
the manufacturer and then code signing
validation when you're doing update and
you want those updates to be automatic
right so that your customers that's
[Music]
typically it will pop in at night when
it's plugged in but that's what we want
all these IOT devices to do because
there will be four abilities found in
these devices no question about it
then you want to monitor these devices
to understand what's going on in them
and then some device monitoring as well
looking for anomaly so one of the things
that we have our HP Labs team found that
when malware attacks remember I said the
typical thing that we'll do is call a
command and control server well guess
what what most names should it go after
can't go after an IP address because by
the way those servers could shut down
fairly quickly host names get shut down
by
you know other things you know other
other monitoring to monitoring you know
companies that are monitoring here net
will shut those down so what they do is
they have a domain generation algorithm
okay so what since Eric tries all these
host things and you'll have hundreds
opposed to a DNS resolve the message is
going out well if that happens the
device can detect that right so we have
betted technology and then printers so
that if we see an upsurge of DNS packets
we assume out the device Bennett has
been is potentially compromised at that
point you go through a reboot flash
memory and and essentially start up back
up in this new state so we're going to
start seeing some more of these
detection capabilities occurring so good
news and bad news good news is the
manufacturers are starting to do things
but that is as government's getting
involved okay so I've got a couple of
examples of what's going on with the
government because that there did you
know consumers are at rest
Dana's at risk and it costs a lot of
money to recover from these attacks
so there is a miss specification you
know this was a good reading for you it
goes out and tells you what how to build
a device and it actually HP you know
quite a few other companies that
participated in this and it defines what
cyber is delicacy is in there can tell
us it doesn't tell you how it tells you
what you should put into your devices to
protect them and I'm not going to go
through too many details on on this but
there's a whole list that you can go out
you know roots of trust I'm sure you
can't we get the device protecting you
know the
suitable code there's just lots of
things you can do automatic recovery and
things like that you know the UK
government just recently in fact came
out and said ok we want to protect our
consumers we want to protect the
consumers in the United Kingdom so they
basically have identified that poorly
secured io T's increases the security
risks and large scale attacks right they
can use them as botnets
so they right now they're encouraging
manufacturers to secure io T's we signed
on with another company Centrica v we
signed on and said this is important we
are going to do it but here's the here's
the guidelines right no default
passwords we talked about that that's a
big risk you know we have implemented a
disclosure policy so that if someone
finds an issue in their device they can
post that and there's a lot of others
I'm not going to go through all of these
but basically you know it's getting into
just these are basic security hygiene
things that you should do when you
develop a device right
be sure to software integrity it's for
personal data that is protected right
that it's encrypted appropriately so
enough to be outdone the state of
California came out of the Senate bills
2700k by 2020 network devices must have
and by the way network devices is so
broad it's not just either T's it's in
the device that's shipped must have
password beneath each device or forced
users to set their password so this is
you know again some of those attacks
that occurred on my ot devices basic
things did not have passwords so we are
going to start seeing the legislation
coming into play requiring these types
of things on my devices now what are the
some of the things that you can do from
a security development best practices so
this is about trying to develop products
from the beginning the security top of
mind Gartner came out ok in 2016 Gartner
came out and predicted that customers
will demand that code is adequately
secured that it's developed with
security best practices and I can tell
you in 2018 we we have seen an increase
in customers that are saying I want to
know what I'm a seafood developer best
practices because this is this is
serious so this is only going to
increase and so it just kind of
highlights when we talk about the
security differently development best
practices what are we talking about here
right you you need to ensure all your
all your engineers are trained on this
you want to ensure that you have you
know when you first start a project you
need to identify what is it you're
trying to protect as a customer data is
a you know your own intellectual
property what are you trying to protect
in this and then back in 1999
invited to Microsoft and Microsoft have
gone through a whole series of attacks
on their Windows operating system they
have they deployed a hundred engineers
to focus on security okay that wasn't
okay doctor you could say this is a big
problem let's move all over hundred
engineers they came out with some pretty
cool secured the government best
practices you can go to their website
they have the stripe model which is it's
an acronym for you know spoofing
tampering repudiation you know
information disclosure it's actually
really good to use that stripe model
when you're actually developing products
we use that at HP and then using tools
on your code like static code analysis
tools and security secure coding
practices Oh wasp has a great list of
checklist of things to do when you're
developing code right you put all of
that and then the penetration testing is
critical as well find out what points
are on that device
and software updates this is making sure
that the firmware is updated on these
devices so that because because again
security is not constant
what's secure today will be secured
tomorrow correct and they will find
weaknesses and we must provide an
automatic mechanism in fact this is what
you know the NSA was talking about
what's up old is new again because we
fix this issue in the product but the
customers weren't updating their
products aprender the the other piece of
this is monitoring so s is an IT
organization event company we should
know every devices on your network
you should be monitored for instance you
should ensure that those devices can
integrate into any of the security tools
that are out there are simple tools that
are monitoring like Splunk that are
taking the band's front they actually
consume events from these all your
endpoints in your network and can tell
you when your devices are at risk and
then input protection tools like McAfee
and Symantec using those tools to
actually ensure those devices are
secured those
these devices need to be first-class
citizens and
environment because they are actually
not really these environments today and
I'm in summary okay i io t it i know i
went fast but you guys are starting
going tired and stuff so okay I know
it's almost five o'clock on a Saturday
so I really appreciate you guys hanging
in there
IOT devices are an emerging security
threat due to lack of security we saw
many examples of that with some devices
just don't have password set and they
need to be designed with security from
the beginning and you know what that's
going to add cost to it so thank you
guys appreciate it
[Applause]