hi and we're going to talk about
breaking out HSTs and h PK p.m. firefox
internet explorer edge and possibly from
thank you for all for coming i'm
circular Santos I'm head of innovation
and laboratory 11 path which is
telefónica digital cybersecurity the
Union come from Spain Shayla hi I work
as a security researcher at 11 paths as
well and 22 years old and I came from an
action team ok let's start with a deeply
in tradition we all know what happened
when credentials are sent over the
internet in clear-text
anyone in our learned network can make a
monumental attack onto a steal our
credentials that's why this was so
necessary to add a new layer of security
in order to provide it SSL and TLS were
created
so now sensitive data should be served
over a secure communication channel in
the application layer we can see it as
HTTPS on the web browser so you are
still our credential should not be so
easy but we said it should not be so
easy
instead of it should be impossible
because there are well-known attacks
again SS or until yet
for example this poodle
crying half-hearted in fact the whole
ecosystem has proven to me at least not
as strong as result but in particular
there are two attacks more common than
those mentioned before the first one is
HTTP s tripping
commonly implemented using SSL as a tool
in a man-in-the-middle attack in this
scenario the attacker gets in the middle
of the client and server communication
redirecting all HTTP requests over HTTP
with this the attacker can steal the
user credentials because he or she will
send them over an unencrypted child the
second
come on attack it's the rock
certificates you know how it works
someone gets into a certificate
authority network or plays the role of a
certificate authority in a system or get
some problem in the process of issuing a
certificate and they get to issue a
certificate that it's not the real one
is quite similar to the real world but
it's not the illegitimate one so all
this common this both common attacks had
control measure which is a H HSTs
HTTP return for security and a PK P
which is HTTP bubble clipping others for
certificate pinning HP K P is one of
them not the most popular because you
know chrome is gonna deprecated
Justinian's a few months ago but it's a
way of making the certificate also to
remember that for HT HSTs that it has to
be access always by SSL and that the
chain of trust has to be always the same
for the browser the first time they use
a visit the web page and then the other
time has to be the same basically having
the same three certificates or chain of
trust so this is start explaining how
HST exports when we access a web site
for the first time and we try to do it
over an unsecured connection the web
server will respond us with our 302
redirect into HTTP and that first
execute connection is the one that
sslstrip take advantage of from there it
will avoid a relation to HTTPS making
the communication with evicting our a
non secure channel but the question is
what happened is that first unsecure
connection is not intercepted by an
attacker the second request will be sent
over a secure channel while
sir and the HST header will be set it on
the user web browser in the second
equation we can see the strict
impartiality header with your respected
max age but what is means it means that
from now until the max actions file for
that website they will server the story
that will also will result from itself
every HTTP request over HTTPS making no
communication over an unsecured channel
so do that it is not the first as your
request SSL Street has nothing to tell
such so it won't work
the attacker won't be able to sniff the
traffic and to steal our cadential in
clear-text
about HP KP certificate post difficut
pinning the whole idea is to remember
the certificate chain for example if we
go to G hub which is this simple here it
will send as a header called public key
pins and it got headed you will see
string a pin sha-256 string which
represents one of the certificates and
it just at least there I've seen commits
you to have at least two pins one of
them has to be one represent one of the
certificates in the certificate chain it
will trust and the other one needs a
backup one that can be anything is
supposed to be one certificate you gonna
use in the field one certificate you're
gonna use when the some kind of problem
for example this spice or whatever this
hash this string is base64 encoding as
basically the sha-256 of of the
certificate exactly like that it's like
the SPK why am i in the in the
certificate but basically is it so you
can send as many spins as you want but
at least there has to be one
representing wine the certificate chain
and one representing a backup that is
not in the indexer Tiffa
a chain of trust if you visit that
website again and the one the pins that
you have sent to the browser are not
anymore in that website you will see a
webpage like this in Chrome have you
ever seen this well it's a is it says
like network SSL Pinsky not in the third
chain that means that this certificate
I'm getting right now in the network are
not the ones who told me to remember
so I blocked the site because these
strings has changed in some way we're
gonna focus here now we briefly know
what HP KPIX STS means we're gonna focus
on how the browser's remember this
information and story we're going to
focus on Firefox Chrome and Internet but
we have we have studied how they they
work with this store this information
and we try to supply it in some way
we'll begin talking about Firefox
Firefox introduced HSTs feature on
version 4 and HP KTM version 32 this
browser is a data related to HSTs and HP
Kadeem in a text file name site security
service state dot txt located in the
Firefox user profile folder if we open
that text file with a text editor we can
see in the first time T domain along the
type of hello receive it can be HSTs or
HP IP and the important second column
there we can fight this car this car is
a numeric value that is insulated as 0
the first time that the user visits a
web site after the score will be
incrementing by one for each day that
the user visit the web site again it
take a reference the current system date
in contrast to the value store in the
third column the value stored in the
third column is a number of that from
epoch when the user visits their website
again in an actual score is is
the higher the score the more often you
visit the website in different place and
a score is a concept that belongs only
to Firefox it just has the way they have
implemented it so another value that we
can find in the text file is the max
page that this is the explanation tank
of Sagada so as we can observe the text
file is not friendly to analyzed
that's why we made that simply playing
for firefox named ping patrol where we
can see the sign information in a
friendly way we can see the domain the
type of Hiva the score value the first
access time the expiration time and if
the two menus hpk P we can see their
respective pins as well this plugin is
in the officials officially started yeah
you can undo something and it represents
the Skouras as we said I'm the higher
the score the more often you busy and if
the HST max hspice reverses back to zero
so what is the cutest thing about
Firefox the very clear finish that the
maximum quantity of HSTs on HP canopy
and restart Firefox saves is adults of
24 it is explained in the Firefox source
code and it should be noted that I don't
mind I use both protocol will achieve
two entries in the text file so the
question is what's happened if we
thought of fill up those ads house from
24 entries with Schenck entries we will
assume that the entries will begin to be
overwritten to test it we made a simple
JavaScript model that can be used
together with weather cab in a
man-in-the-middle attack in order to
remotely inject
lot of Schenck HSUS entries to start
over right the decisive security service
state file in the victim machine and
this javascript model we generated
random subdomains with a respective HSTs
hello we are owners of the cloud pinion
dot-com website and we have a SSL
certificate for that domain so it's
subdomain we look you one slot into the
site security services that file into
the victim machine as I said we can use
this javascript module together with
weather cop in a simple man in the
middle attack using the approximate
Alicia yes we're gonna see a video right
now when we run a basic web site and the
attacker is we want to check fast that
the browser actually remembers the the
domain instagramming in this case and
I'm gonna give a rash of junk entries
with our cloud domain.com own website it
can be anyone is public but this is our
own and we're gonna check later we're
gonna give this rush of junk entries I'm
gonna check that the attack has removed
this domain and then we want to inject a
better cut usual SSL strip attack as you
can see here the maybe necklace or
Instagram visit by SSL and they are
there in the in the implementation of
Firefox in the way they days they store
the HSTs
entries with our time in ceramics they
should be always be visited by by HT a
Stas and now that sucker use better cap
to inject this JavaScript that goes to
cloud pinning calm and start like asking
a lot of new domains to fill up this
thousand twenty-four entries and once
they the the attack in the between my
team and the user goes to random place
right now we use just hola mundo es or
wherever the attack starts sending junk
entries
it takes about two minutes or maybe five
depends on the speed you just you start
in the JavaScript speed you start
injecting Jack entries and once the
injection takes place he will go the
victim what we are going to check that
the table the a fashion 24 table for
Firefox which is the maximum you can
remember is fill up with our own clown
painting stuff which is junk and
Instagram is gone so it's that easy to
make Firefox forget one of the HSTs
entries they used to do remember now the
attacker is gonna make her SSL strip
usual attack using Baraka it's it is am
I in the middle he has to be already in
a hostile network of course but remember
that the this is just a previous attack
removing HSTs previous attack for real
money in immediate Axl you're supposed
to be in the network all right and when
he visits Instagram the SSL strip at
Isis taking place and Wow our we got
that before this mallet came out in five
four so she's entering email and
password as as you will guess this
password will be in the attacker machine
just write that as you can see email and
passwords in clear-text in the attacker
machine so as we saw those hosts HSTs
and HP copy entries has been our writing
however not all of them why because all
their perfect score
inside the firefox or skull we can't
find a comment that is plain how the
scar system works as we said before this
car is animal in value does is
initialized to zero the first time that
the user visit the web site and after
will be incremented by one for each
light for each date that the user visits
the website again there is a limit of
had also 24 entries and when this limit
is reached those hundreds with the
lowest score will be over writing by the
new entries all of these means that is
most likely that which our previous
attack we are over writing those entries
corresponding to the web site that are
not the most frequently visited by the
user because we are expecting
shangkun trees with the score 0 and with
this we are about writing another web
site with the score 0 as well or 1 as
maximum so in a natural in a nutshell
the lower the score the score the more
likely you're going to be a victim so if
we if we try to rise up our own score in
our own junk entries the more likely the
good entries will be a picture from this
assertion 24 table so what can we do
some years ago was presented a two-lane
DeLorean that was developed by hospital
him and this tool allows an attacker to
chain remotely the current system date
of a target machine it depends a little
of the Linux or Mac OS versions on Linux
and some mac version are more vulnerable
but this tool was developed for using
against HSTs
trying to change the current system
state of the target forward to the max
age of the header of the HSTs Heller's
but even if we can do it
actually there was worser one so any web
page is the system time is XS currently
subsequent to the real time so however
we will use this tool in
different ways in order to complement
our previous attack so women making a
first chunk at UTS intersection and with
this we get honest curves here after we
will use Silurian to forward the target
system date to one day on the future
after that we can make another Franken
trees injection with this we will get on
a scale of 1 and if we continue applying
DeLorean together with the giant
enticing section we can increment the
score of our shank entries so with this
we can start war write those entries
corresponding to website frequently
visited by the user this main website
with a higher score so in the next thing
we will make this attack trying to rise
up out the score of our own giant
entries so the good entries will be the
will have the lower scum or will be the
score and will be easier to be evicted
or forgotten from your from your Firefox
let's see the video we here check that
the pic Tamizh is november the 9th and
we have already done the previous attack
where our score is 0 and now the
attacker that that is gonna run better
cup for rushing the junk entries here
and the lowering in the other common
control so with our JavaScript pointing
to cloud pinning calm we start the
attack and then we set DeLorean to make
the user they jump one day before not a
lot of days but just one day so next
time you visit cloud pinning calm it
will be like score one so even to has
asked for an NTP update which is quite
frequently and then he is on November
the 10th he visit whatever webpage
that's a place and the under the table
we now fill up with junk entries with a
score of one and maybe we have already
removed some good entries and legitimate
entries with a score of one it's more
likely then we could not do it again you
stop the attack
which we run again the delorean attack
two days after the our own system date
we run better cup to rush a lot of junk
entries to the big team even to us again
ask for an NTP update so they attack the
DeLorean that takes place now he is on
Saturday the 11th the user again visit
whatever web page or a mundo es for
example and if we check the table again
or our giant entries we have a score of
2 right now so we're more likely to
remove entries with a to score but we
also remember that policy is to a big
the domains with the lowest score
so this attacks may be a little complex
because it depends on how many
legitimate domains you already have but
it may be it may be quite effective
delorean doesn't work with windows just
works with even two but it's a quite
easy attack for man in the middle and we
need maybe we need some time enough
inside the target networks maybe hours
back for placeable during a hotel and
you visit a captive portal or during an
internal pen test are the best scenario
for this attack because you have plenty
of time to rise up your score a lot and
it will be every single they will be
more likely to remove your legitimate
domains and if you have more days
it's more likely as well that your max
age aspires so it means your domains
you're visiting the expires and tries to
get in and they get a silver score again
at the easily a big set again from your
table so if you try this attack for
maybe a day maybe two days maybe three
day they success arises because you
don't choose which domains you're a big
thing of course but it's more likely
they have the lower score they easily
Arabic from this table and with a higher
score we have more chances with a high
score of our own domains we have more
chances to remove a system domains but
even if it doesn't work as a side effect
a very interesting side effect when you
have a lot of entries with the highest
score the new they are more likely to
less likely to be removed so you're
filling up this a functional 24 table
with a lot of junk entries and at the
end of the day result the side effect is
that you feel you end up with just one
entry that is gonna have a score of zero
because the new ones you have to
remember them and it has a silver score
so if you have a lot of we had to score
three score 20 score whatever at the end
of the day what you have is just one
slot left to remember the HSD a HSTs or
HP copy and this is all it all the new
entries that you getting remove by the
new one all the time so at the end of
the day in the long term you defeat the
system because you have just one single
a slot to remember and any once you
visit is going to over rate overwrite
that one which is a fine interesting
side effect AK what about chrome I said
from follows basically the same
policy as five is it stores these
oldest information in a txt file in the
in the user profile it is adjacent with
lots of parameters yes basically the
same it doesn't have to do anything with
the score anymore okay if uses a JSON
and they expiry time the Lapine's and
whatever and this this string here is
the domain for privacy purposes the
chrome doesn't store the domains
themselves and and the rest of the the
parameters are the same but we have
created pink patrol for Chrome as well
it's in the official source well so and
we got to and hash the domains because a
very easy technique if you have visited
them these domains are in your history
so if you go to the history this this
plugin goes to history texture of
history domains hashes them and if they
match it they are the same so you unhak
these domains in some way and the
curious thing about how chrome ester
storage uses this storage is that it has
no limits at all no limits the number of
domains and no limits in the number of
pins Firefox has a limit of one kilobyte
of pins that means about 21 pins he
can't remember but Chrome has no limit
at all this means that you can set
literally as many pins as the HTTP
header allows you to that means a lot
that means about thousands of pins and
it will remember whatever number of
domains you have ever visited it's a
completely different philosophy from
Firefox so what happens if we try to
fill out the database with thousands and
thousands of large journal entries large
giant entries means
domains that gives you back not two pins
not three pins but thousands of things
we made up proof of concept I went as
well with this whatever Free Willy
portal or whatever then we you enter
this email your domain for example click
on connect and you will see here we have
made a simple system that sends this pin
and another one of course because you
need a valid one remember and the backup
once by the way we use this backup
concept as a way to inject as many pins
as we want random pins we send four
thousand pins for the domain and we said
it 50 thousand times all in a row in a
second in a few seconds so in this demo
we're gonna we're gonna see how this
works
they you suggest clicks on this connect
site and we'll see in this ebook frame
that is continually injecting this habit
if we could click on this head as you
will see like a massive HTTP header with
thousand of pins and it's taking every
chance the campus will be longer and
longer and longer and here you can see
it's transferring make a lot of
megabytes and these megabytes coax
directly to this file which is a txt
file and dumps the information just
right there so the longer the
transmission is twenty megabytes first
now 30 megabytes transfers it's gonna be
translated into data into your your file
right nice forty megabytes just this is
real time and in a few seconds we get a
massive txt file or a massive system in
less than 10 minutes later in the bench
on how many pins you saying and how
often do you send them we're gonna have
like 500 megabytes of
information it's a lot we're not gonna
fill up the harddrive with this but a
for Chrome is incredible difficult to
handle this file as you can see with
just five thousand five hundred
megabytes you cannot even type I don't
mean anymore it just freeze there so
this this is real time as well you
cannot even type so chrome is useless
right now because it's trying to read a
massive file of 500 megabytes maybe not
more powerful computer it has to be a
little bit bigger but doesn't matter so
the attack is very easy to achieve and
you can try it in different ways
you just visit a website as long as it
has a Java Script you may have this
problem whatever website and it doesn't
have to be a man-in-the-middle at all
chrome stocks work properly in a few
minutes and this is forced to clear
browsing data and chromium but he will
not be able to do it because you cannot
even type and transfer security file has
to be removed the lead or some way it is
to start over again so HSTs or HP KP is
broken all the user may switch to
firefox where we can do the other attack
as well what about Internet Explorer or
edge well as you can guess there's no
documentation about this Internet
Explorer has doesn't even support HP KP
and it will not because going to be the
parade but it supports a STS we have not
real we need a different investigation
this because it's quite complicated but
where we saw is that it uses a what he
wrote makers of Microsoft calls e-s-a
database which is 10 Sylvester H system
I think and we have used the the closer
thing to to read this table we have
found this a nice soft tool core
es es e database view but it doesn't
pass information the right way so you
get to see this information but it's not
properly seen what we have in the second
column is the other domains which are
hash it
they are hashes in some way we don't
know how and we see combs like last time
you said with which is updated
supposedly and dated when I tell
Explorer they use it for some reason and
as we said there's no absolutely no
documentation about this and we haven't
seen it before on the internet or
whatever so what we try to do is the
funnest thing about internet sport is
that it doesn't even seem to work we
make a simple test that is we created a
hundred and thirty one requests to our
cloud pinning comm site that gives you
an HSTs hover or whatever and we
expected that this table was altered in
some way because when you visit go well
you visit Microsoft you visit a popular
Outlook Facebook popular domains this
database is altered in some way you can
check that last time max use it is the
real last time you have used that
so this HSTs entry number whatever in
this table it's actually touched in some
way by internet's product when you visit
a very popular domain but when we visit
our own domain is not even touch it's
nothing written in there so it's not
remember at all the the in in what is
suppose has to be it has to be and what
we would be a service that even if you
restart the internet portal will start a
computer it doesn't remember nothing
about visiting this website that is
sending you a properly just a street
some possibility heaven
yeah in order to disk or why you turn as
parallel as since not water well we
began to analyze the The Grocer behavior
in run time when we access our website
with HSTs like our above there is not a
useful documentation on that the only
thing mentioned is that there is an API
called HTTP host HSTs enable inside the
wininet library and the sort that was
our starting point who are along our
research we discover lots of metal
related to write tests yes and every
time that I use or visit our website
some of them are involved the first
method invoke is check HSTs after get
HSTs in Adel and depending on the result
of this function the rest of the methods
might be invoke so the number was
function related to a chest years he is
an impression that Internet's player and
age are ready to handle with a chest yes
however we found some issues the
function said we consider our frequently
invoked by the web browser every time
that the user visits a website so so in
the sequence see that we can see here
there are more method related to a chest
years but those method related to the
store of the HSTs entries are not invoke
with the same frequency or at least when
we assumed I that they should be
involved that's why we think that there
is a kind of problem in the storage
process a conclusion we got is that
there is take a share is a cachet the
one that remember if the user visits the
website over HTTP or HTTPS but it's not
because the HDL protects from itself so
the question is what happened if we
clear the cache a in this video we're
gonna show like
we're visiting Google or Instagram and
they visit by SSL which is which is okay
but when the user just removes capture
or removes the the data and we get back
to this HSTs database that is supposed
to store all this information the
information is there so this information
they have remember about Instagram or
Google should be there and next time you
visit it it should be accessed by SSL
because of the HST itself HSTs itself
but just removing the cut in Internet
Explorer the attacker just send some SSL
strip usual attack and when you use a
visit with Internet Explorer Google in
this in this place you will see that
it's being attacked with SSL strip -
this is the typical attack you go to
www.google.com and HSTs is not taking
place and for instagram is basically the
same just removing the the caches is is
just having or removing the effect of
HSTs
even that the even the table has not
been removed at all where it should be
stored but for some reason when you
remove the the catch the catch a a the
SSL strip attack is successful and as
you may guess when you get your you
serum and password in there the attacker
will be able to see it in clear text and
remember that they usually just remove
the link name sport catcher so the
highlights about internet paragon - we
can say that most of their website when
we remember us was protected with a
chest
we'll some kind of problem in the
storage process so we think that it's
the wrong circassia the one that
remember is a user's visit that website
over HTTP or HTTPS but it's not because
of the HSTs production itself so as a
consequence restarting the browser the
machine or more effective clearly cachet
leaves the user with other real HSTs
protection so we need a deeper
investigation or in the next product is
to reverse engineer it but well we can
change that there's not a strong bed yet
for improving these implementations
because as you can see five four here's
a txt file Chrome as well as simple JSON
file and as a consequence no one seems
to be safe if even you even using HSTs
we have done a little more research
about some problems in the in the way
they they implement this and there are
little details but these are the bigger
ones that actually is gonna remove the
the or or make the these mechanics
useless in a practical way for the for
the for the most common process remember
that the plugins are available and
available and the crop income is
available as well if you want to make
some some improve with your own and have
your own conclusions so this is all
thank you I think we have time for some
for some questions
[Applause]
maybe there's a question is there a
question there there is another one here
yeah turn did you have a gone well and I
don't know if there is a microphone no
someone writes the handler ah here thank
you for a great talk so you mentioned
the total DeLorean and all of these
fields seems to have expired race what
happens if you just set the time of the
target to past well past the expiry
would that work as well that's the
DeLorean was meant to be like taking you
two years forward in time two years in
the future it's great it works that's a
way to to defeat HSTs that's one way to
defeat it but what we're serve is that
it has a this is another way okay but
aside just to say something it has a big
problem that if you set your aspire time
two years in the future and the user is
right now two years in the future it's
quite likely that when you visit
whatever domain always CP in your
certificate just says hey this is this
is not the real time so this is not
valid
so the the growth is gonna block you
because of the osep and there are gonna
be some problems with certificates as
well they may be they may be um the
expires as well the certificate itself
may expire if you if you said your
computer to two years in the future
perhaps a lot of problems right one day
two days is okay with always CP and
certificates it's not gonna spiring one
today so it's a little bit better way or
let's say
less noisy way but it's perfectly okay
to get you back in the future until HSTs
expires okay thank you thanks for the
great talk as well I was just curious if
you reported this behavior to Firefox or
not and what was the response if it was
report we did not we did not because
they're gonna they're changing all the
time we haven't even had time to check
for quantum right now I think it's
exactly the same and we did not tell
them about this because they are there
they know it I mean this this comments
that we're seeing in the source code
explain this but they don't seem to be
to have any problem with it they say
it's okay
in the proper comments in the source
code thank you for the great talk have
you tried to investigate the mobile
environment meaning the Android or iOS
we did with well there's a funny thing
with chrome Chrome for Android works
exactly the same it's exactly the same
if you connect you may see this txt file
with Jason it's exactly the same it's a
funny thing that with Android 4 which is
quite old and chrome HSTs doesn't work
at all they say that it does but it
doesn't it never uses this file don't
ask me why but it's just Android 4 4 4 4
5 factor is the same as well and we did
not check the native Android browser
which a Chrome and Firefox if you ask me
for opera for example operas chrome it's
basically exactly the same as well
did you check the webview based
applications such as the
I spoke up itself the Facebook app sorry
yeah for example the Facebook app which
basically is just a web view so in our
analogy it uses the same implementation
than the Chrome we didn't but Oprah's
chromium and chromium uses this part
this part is chromium not chrome itself
hi how would you fix this is there any
good remediation for this we said this
is not a strong bet I mean I will have
use a proper database I will have
checked limits of course I will not use
the score system which is an intelligent
way of making you remember and store for
longer the legitimate domains but it has
some flows I'm not a software engineer
or architect but I'm quite sure that
better ways I mean it's not just a
single txt file that you dump there and
it doesn't matter how how big it is or
or just a simple table with a fashion 24
different entries that are gonna be able
reading in the long term I'm not a
proper developer but I will use at least
a single SQLite database or something of
course but what I say is that it's not a
but I don't know how to fix it but as
you can tell it's not a proper bed I
mean I'm gonna do it the right way it's
like we're doing it and we forget about
it and we'll check later
no questions okay thank you very much
[Applause]
[Music]