so I guess we're alive this is me this
is David Wong and I came here to tell
you a story so my story starts with a
timeline to hash functions near for an
MD for where it is in the beginning of
the 90s they go they got quite popular
unfortunately sniff who quickly got
broken by the newly introduced
differential cryptanalysis nd4 remained
unbroken for some years and became the
de facto standard for a hash function
but also to construct hash functions so
MD here stands for merkle-damgard so the
construction became the standard to
build other hash functions and other
hash functions using that standard our
md5 sha-1 even chateau and a bunch of
others so yeah MD for unfortunately we
realized that it's broken it's not very
secure md5 we quickly realized that or
not that quickly and actually md5 it
took a lot of time to deprecate it was
rather painful was used all over the
place right from certificates to storing
passwords so yeah sha-1 got broken
earlier this year right if you were at
blackhat us you must have seen Eli from
Google giving a talk about that
so no more sha-1 and our left push a to
shadow is is really the standard that
everybody use wherever you are on the
spectrum of security you're a developer
if your pen tester whatever you are you
must have seen shot or you must have
used shattered right it's all over the
place so the question we had back then
was is shadow going to fold them fates
right it's built on the same
construction the merkle-damgard
construction that i'm not going to
explain here and if it falls the same
fate do we have a back-up plan
do we have another hash function that
you can use to replace shatter and the
answer was not that clear back then so
the NIST's an American organization
decided to organize an open competition
like the AES competition for the new
standard hash algorithm shattering so it
started in 2007 lasted for five years
five years in which 64 different
candidates from all over the world
thoughts to become the next standard so
Chateau was designed by the NSA sherry
is really an open standard so 2012 five
years later finally kid Shaq is
nominated as the winner so whenever I
say sherry I also mean kid jackets
though it's the same algorithm now other
candidates that didn't make the cuts in
the last round were Blake Russell JH and
skein it's not that they were insecure
it's rather than we only had one
position for the winner and if you look
at Blake you might recognize that name
because it had had a second life after
the competition by releasing a second
version Blake - and it's been adopted by
quite a lot of standards and
applications
all right so 2012 Kasich wins 2015 three
years after the end of the competition
we finally have a standard so it's a
nice standard called FIPS pub - - it's
kind of an ugly name or BPF but anyway
whatever we have a standard only two
years ago right so it's pretty recent
so that's try three and I was my intro
to why we build shot three and why and
what's shattering and here's my outline
and I'll basically spend a few slides
next to explain to you how shot three
works so I'm not going to go too much
into the details I'm just going to give
you some intuition or fight words so
don't worry
no equations no math it's pretty cool if
you focus on the next few slides you'll
go away from this talk with the
knowledge of how shot three works after
that I'll be looking at strobe which is
something built on top of sha-3 it's not
a hash function it's actually a protocol
framework so it allows you to build make
much more than just hash functions the
third part of this talk will be about
noise which is another protocol
framework actually anyone here has heard
of noise before the noise protocol
framework it two three four people five
so it's something to build something
like TLS you can think of it like that
and it really doesn't use chattery so
there will be a break from shuttering
and find finally at the end I have a
surprise but more about that later
alright so time to focus Shari Shari is
something it's in the field of
permutation based cryptography in crypto
you have a lot of different fields one
of them is just a field of things built
on top of permutations so that's why
it's called what a permitted what is a
permutation
well don't worry I have a good
explanation for that everybody knows a
es right he has the core algorithm to
encrypt things it takes 128 bit inputs
plaintext and it gives you a 128 bit
ciphertext right that's how you can
encrypt and from a cipher text you can
decrypt and get back to your plain text
so it's a one-to-one mapping between all
the possible inputs of 128 bits and all
the possible outputs of 128 bits right
if you don't have this one-to-one
mapping if you have a ciphertext you
don't know how to decrypt it you don't
know what Planet X you can get and here
I pretend that I use a key of all zeros
so the key is known everybody can use it
to the create Anchorage we don't care
there is no secret here so every time
you'll see this function here this
permutation you can think of AES with
unknown key I'm going to I'm going to
build something called a sponge
construction this was invented as part
of the Sheree competition to build the
new hash function shattering so this
replaces this merkle-damgard
construction that I talked about
previously remember okay what is this
pond construction well first I set the
input of my permutation to all zeros
okay
bunch of zeros so the permutation kind
of randomized this and I get an output
no I decide to split my inputs and my
outputs into different parts the first
part I say the first are bits and here I
choose a very simple example I have five
bits here are the inputs and the output
are the public parts okay it's public
and the remaining bits of the input and
the output are see bits here three bits
are the secret part and you're going to
understand
I call that public why I call that
secret but just so that we're in the
same page if it's AES right you take the
plaintext and you just say the first
hour beats are the public part and then
really the remaining part is the secret
one all right so a hash function is not
very good if you don't take an input
right so we want to have something and
here to have to take the input inside
our algorithm what I do is that I just
XOR my input with the public parts and
at the beginning the public part is only
zeros right very easy
so here it's very easy if I have an
input of only five bits because my
public part is five bits but what if
it's larger well if it's larger it's
easy as well we just split it into
blocks of five bits and we XOR the first
block of five bits with my public part
okay we don't touch the secret part then
we take the second block and we ignore
that with the public part after
permuting after using something like a
yes right
we permute again and finally if we have
only three blocks we XOR the final block
with the public parts and we permeate
again make sense
it's just what we call absorbing right
it's it's a sponge function we absorb a
message make sense now how do we get our
outputs it's not very it's not very
useful if we don't get an output from
that right so hash function what we can
do is that we can just read the public
parts so here we get five bits if we
need more we can just permute and read
again we get ten bits if we need more we
continue to do the same this is called
squeezing all right make sense ready to
sponge we absorb our message and then we
squeeze it to get an output and that's
really all there is to shattering so we
have a paper proof a mathematical proof
that this word this is secure as long as
the permutation at its core is secure
how do we know that the permutation at
the core is secure well we don't really
have a good way of doing that the best
way we know of is just just to try to
break it so that's why the competition
lasted for five years is just people
trying to break it using linear
cryptanalysis differential cryptanalysis
bunch of other kryptonite is trying to
invent new attacks just to try to break
it after quite some time we get more
confidence in the function and we we say
it's secure or we know how to play with
the parameters all right so that's a
three and know that I got that out of
the way I'm going to explain strobe all
right so I'm going to use this de-spawn
thing to build more than that so going
back to that slide so remember I absorb
my input and then I squeeze it to create
an output but what if I don't stop here
and I just continue and then I start
absorbing again and then I squeeze again
and then I absorb again and then I
squeeze again is that possible well the
kid Shack team said yes it's possible
and they came up with a new construction
called a duplex construction and
basically that's what happens here you
absorb your input your squeeze you
absorb your squeeze you absorb your
squeeze all right that's interesting
what can we do with that can we do
anything useful with this well one thing
we can do that is interesting is that we
can absorb a key right we XOR a key with
our public part and when we absorb a key
is very different from hashing is
usually you hash public stuff and here
we hash a key right we absorb a key so
it's a key mode when we use a key
keeping the secret parts private is very
important if you leak the secret part
somehow I don't know some memory
disclosure then the attacker might have
the entire state right
the public part and the secret part and
now the attacker can reverse all the
permutations there is there is only one
here but if there was multiple
permutation you could reverse all the
permutation to go back to the key
remember I said a permutation is
basically like AES with a non key that
means if you have the ciphertext or the
output you can get the plaintext or the
input right so you can reverse this
thing so really when you're using a key
when you're in key mode you really want
to keep that secret part secret anyway
we absorb icky we permute so we get
something kind of random you get the ID
how can we encrypt from that I really
absorb icky we permute we get
maybe here five beats five random bits
how can we encrypt something like that
well very simply if you think of
one-time pads or stream ciphers or
things like that you just X or your
plaintext what you want to encrypt with
this bit string this random bit string
and you get your ciphertext and to
decrypt you do the inverse you generate
the same thing yeah the absorption of
the key and you make sure that with the
ciphertext
and you get back back the plaintext
right its encryption 101 okay but if you
know about encryption probably you know
that we never just sin we never just
encrypt and send the ciphertext like
that just because if there is an
attacker in the middle the attacker in
the middle can tamper with the
ciphertext and after when we receive the
ciphertext after decryption the plant X
will be tampered with so usually we want
to protect the integrity of the
ciphertext by generating something out
of that ciphertext that we can append to
the ciphertext and like that we can make
sure that nobody modified it right
usually you use something like a ES GCM
that takes care of that
so here a very simple way we can just
absorb the plaintext permute exactly
like we did for hashing right and we
create basically a hash out of that
plaintext and out of the key because we
absorb everything so the the thing here
in the public parts will be generated
via everything that was absord okay so
on the other side when we receive the
ciphertext and the tag we decrypt the
ciphertext by doing this little dance
then we absorb the plant X that we
decrypted and if we generate something
different then we know that someone
modified the message but these are
details you don't have to understand
everything here but this is what we can
use this top likes construction for what
if we want to encrypt again well we can
just continue here and permit again do
this little dance to encrypt and then do
this little dance to generate an
authentication tag to authenticate the
ciphertext and it works we didn't set up
any nonces and encounters any IVs it
just works the second cool thing here is
that when I generate this tag number two
I don't only authenticate
this ciphertext here but I also attenti
Kate this one here that I absorbed and
the key so basically whenever I
authenticate
something our authenticate the whole
session not just the last ciphertext the
whole session so this is a very cool
property to have for protocol because
like that you can make sure that you
have consistency on both side of the
connection nobody has reordered messages
replied messages inserted things or drop
things both side of the connections are
seeing the same thing strobe so the
point of my second part is a protocol
framework that gives you access to the
duplex construction so you have all
these functions here and you have what
they do on the duplex construction so it
don't look too much at that it's just a
nice diagram but basically that what
strobe is it really gives you access to
this state and every time you do some
operation you're continuously muted that
states influencing new things that
you're going to do in the future and
being influenced by what happened
previously so before I get too much into
the details I just want to give you an
overview of how you would use that as a
developer so a very simple example okay
what does it mean to use the strobe
protocol framework so we're going to
build a protocol and I have two devices
I want to encrypt communications between
them what I will do is that I
instantiate the strobe objects via this
function and a string so for example my
website would come or my protocol or
something like that then I absorb or
shared secrets so I absorb it with a
function called ad that strobe give us
gives us authentication authenticated
data and I do that on both side right so
shared secret so both devices have this
shared secret I know I have a secret in
place so I can encrypt so I can use the
same encrypt command to encrypt the get
request for example right makes sense
I'm sending some encryption encrypted
data of course I want to authenticate
what I just sent so I use the send Mac
for message authentication code with a
16 byte mark and I send that and on the
other side I receive it so I do the
inverse operation to decrypt
receive ank and I use receive Mack to
verify the tag if it's incorrect it
means that somebody must have tampered
with the connection so I can just abort
the connection a very simple protocol
right I just use these functions on both
sides of the connection and I encrypt my
data now if I want to continue
encrypting I will just continue to use
the sent ank and send mac to encrypt and
authenticate and I will never have to
figure out how to create some non C's or
some IVs and every time I authenticate
I authenticate the whole session not
just the last thing I sent so Straub is
first and foremost this thing it's a
flexible framework to build some
protocols it's more than that though
since you have access to all these
commands to all these functions you can
kind of mix and match them to create
just simple cryptographic operations
what do I mean by that well imagine you
want to hash you have the code of stroke
because you're using it to I don't know
build your protocol so you can just use
drug to instantiate it as a hash
function and here I call my hash
function david wong hash it's my hash i
absorbed the message i want to hash with
the same ad function and then i use
another function PRF to get an output
and here i want a 32 byte hash so here I
just use the same code the same code
base to just use it as a hash function
so it's very interesting because you get
not only this this protocol framework
but you also get a cryptographic library
for free all of that relies on the
shatori standard it uses the permutation
in size of shatori so the security comes
from somewhere it's not just roll here
on crypto and since it only relies on
sherry it's very very very small it's
only a thousand lines of code for the
reference implementation in C there is a
Python implementation there is I made a
goal and implementation it's also a
thousand lines of code so it's very
small it's very good for embedded
devices and all that stuff so if you
want to look at the specification it's
on strobe dot sourceforge.net by Mike
hammer
and it's alpha so it's it's still
experimental but it's it's so it's built
on solid foundations all right so that's
basically what a stroke is just this
kind of protocol framework built on top
of sha-3
so now I'm going to talk about noise so
I if you kind of lost track of what I'm
talking about I'm really taking a break
from sherry so you can get back into the
talk now what is noise now this is a
protocol framework to build stuff like
TLS so I'm going to be talking about TLS
first just a recap so what is TLS tillis
is the de facto standard for encrypting
communications right we have other
standards like SSH or IPSec etc but GLS
is really the most popular one right
it's a very complex specification I
don't know if you've tried to read the
specification of TLS it's called a
request for RFC record request for
request for what request for comment
thank you our secrets for comments it's
a lot of them actually
you have SSL version I don't know what
TLS 1.0 TLS 121 tell us 1.2 so depending
on what you want to support you have to
read several ones and also a bunch of
these I've been broken in the past so
there is that it's not just one
specification it's also if you start
reading one of them you have to read a
bunch of them so there are a bunch of
them for certificates if you want to use
certificates and a public key
infrastructure they're a bunch of them
if you want to use different
cryptographic primitives there are bunch
of them depending of the extensions you
want to use of course certificates have
their own extensions and it's a lot to
digest
if it carries a lot of legacy decisions
a lot of things are done to really
support older versions so if you look at
TLS 1.3 you will see that a lot of
messages really look like older versions
of TLS or SSL just because otherwise
nobody knows how to parse these messages
and it breaks the internet so it's kind
of ugly and because of legacy
and of course if you want to use it you
have this huge and scary libraries I'll
just mention OpenSSL but basically
OpenSSL is so scary that people have 42
make it better so you have like boring
SSL or libras to sell etc if you want to
use it it's not that simple so you have
to configure it and the documentation is
not very clear usually so you have to
read these books but then these books
are pretty old so it doesn't really work
for the new versions and so I'm a
security consultant and I often look at
clients using open SSL and most of the
time they forget to use the right
function - I don't know verify
certificates or verified the hostname in
a certificate orders just verify the
return value of a function and then you
have a an open fill so it's quite tricky
to use now if you want to implement it
yourself first don't even try to do that
it's not it's impossible right so that's
something I tend to look at also as part
of my work and it's always riddled with
bugs so that makes my job more fun but
don't try to do it yourself if all these
libraries have had their share of
problems right you have a lot of
vulnerabilities file every day not every
day but you have a lot of programs it's
not because there are bad developers is
really because TLS is very complex it's
complex to implement so that's bad and
worse the kind of thing I see sometimes
are reinvented protocols proprietary
protocols that are influenced by TLS so
that's usually that's completely broken
so don't even try so here the problem is
that complexity is the enemy of security
TLS is way too complex to use or
implement it's it's it's hard it's it's
not easy
people make mistakes but it's not their
fault this this thing is not easy to use
so do we have an alternative if we want
to use something else than TLS what is
out there well the nice protocol
framework is exactly that was invented
by Trevor Perrin the inventor of signal
the signal protocols and it's it's a
framework so it's exactly like the
strobe protocol framework it's not
something you can use out of the box
it's something that you can use to build
a protocol something they can use to
build something like TLS
so for example Telus most of the time
you will use certificates or a public
key infrastructure and if you don't want
to use these it's it's tricky it's very
tricky in noise you can just use plain
Keys we don't have to use these
certificates and if you don't want to
use a public infrastructure if you
already know the public in Advent for
example if you have some shared secret
or something like that you can do that
as well
entry it's very easy to do that so noise
is actually a lot of different
handshakes a lot of different ways to do
things that you can choose from it's
very flexible so if you look at the
specification you will see that maybe
like maybe not half of it but a large
part of the specification spends a lot
of time analyzing all these handshakes
and telling you what kind of security
you get for what kind of handshake
you're choosing once you know what you
want to use for your specific setup it's
very straightforward to implement it's
around 2,000 lines of code if you want
to implement the whole of noise and
usually you just want to implement one
part you don't have to implement it
yourself of course you already have
libraries in all major languages to use
it so you just use these libraries and
you build your own protocol out of that
and once you have what you want there is
a minimal configuration or zero
configuration and it just works it's not
just a weird protocol that I'm telling
you about today it's used by whatsapp
which is by slack by the beacon lighting
Network it's used I've heard by
governments but I don't have any insight
into that it's used by a lot of people
so it's it's not it's not just a weird
spec so bottom line if you have a good
excuse not to use TLS noises the answer
not anything else alright so I'm going
to spend a few slides trying to explain
to you how noise works so when he is
noise first you have to choose what
cryptographic functions you want to use
they are not so many and you don't
negotiate which one you want you just
have to choose in the beginning and then
you have to use these ones you cannot
change so for the key exchange you can
use curve two five five one nine or
curve for free eight there
pretty famous actually curve 448 was
invented by Trevor by Mike Hamburg the
creator of the Straub protocol framework
anyway if you want to encrypt you can
you stretch out 20 point 1305 or AES GTM
one is fast in software the other one is
fast if you have a hardware support and
finally if you want to use a hash you
can use black 2 or chateau so remember
this Blake was in the shaft 3
competition and you can also realize
that there is no shot 3 in there we're
really far away from shattering alright
so you have a client you have a server
you want to encrypt that out so first
you do a handshake if you know TLS it
should be pretty straightforward if you
don't know then it's going to be
protocol 101 for you so here a client on
a server exchange what they call
ephemeral keys keys data are generated
only for this session right those are
not long-term study keys once they
exchange these keys they can do a quick
change they can do what we call detail
man-cakes change and then they get some
shared secrets that they can use to
encrypt sin what we call a post
handshake phase so here's just
application data whatever you want to
encrypt it's a really protocol 101 here
this most simple kind of key exchange
you can do now is called ephemeral keys
e a token e and when you do a deal
medications with two or more keys you
will call that e e that's how noise
works and then noise right this kind of
handshake by just writing it with this
syntax where you send a client a formal
key and then the server sends his a for
monkey and then they do an D filmin cake
change on both of these keys so that's
the notation you will see if you look at
the specification there are other tokens
there is a stokin for static keys long
term keys and since there are there's
another kind of key you can do different
kind of D film and key exchange where
you need an F remote key of the client
and the one of the server or the inverse
or you do a development exchange with
both study key and if you have already
pre shared key or pre shared secrets you
can you can do that kind of key exchange
as well
so reading a lot of tokens and these
tokens are used to build a lot of
different protocols a lot of different
handshakes you really and they have
names and you really have different
handshakes for every situation if you
want to authenticate the server if you
have public infrastructure you can if
you already know the public key of the
client you can authenticate the client
like that if you have a pre-shot secret
you can use that a lot a lot this is not
an exhaustive list you have a lot of
them but today for this talk I'm just
going to focus on the NX handshake the
first n means that the client is not
authenticated the second letter X means
that the server sends its study key as
part of the handshake so that means that
my rings ring a bell
if you know how FCPS work that's exactly
the web browser web server scenario
right when you go on HTTPS google.com
the browser doesn't send a key doesn't
send a certificate but google.com really
sends you a certificate right so that's
exactly what's happening here so I chose
this handshake pattern so I got if you
don't tell us you know HTTPS you can
understand and can follow more easily
all right so let's read the first token
there it's an e token that means that
the client has to send an a formal
public key has to generate one and to
send it and now the client is done there
is nothing more so the client can send a
payload can be anything can be hey I
want to talk to that server now that
server or it can be the name of the
client can be anything but it's not
encrypted now is the server's turn right
so the server has to generate his own
public key ephemeral public key and send
it and I call that re for remotes a
ephemeral no we have two kids we
exchanged two public keys so we can do a
different key exchange on both of these
ephemeral keys which I'll put a shared
secret which we can use to encrypt the
next token the next token is a static
key and so here I call it rs4 remote
static encrypted we can decrypt it and
we know we have a new key to study key
of the server that we can use to do this
es which is a D filmin connections
between the ephemeral key of the client
and the study key of the server and then
it's the end of the handshake pattern so
the server can send a payload as well
and encrypt it with a new key derived
from that last key exchange that payload
can contain whatever the client the
server wants to send probably here a
signature over its public key from some
certificate authority or some pointer so
that's that's about it that's what noise
does or when you do an NX handshake
right you exchange some public key some
ephemeral public keys some static public
keys you do different key exchange and
then you can encrypt simpler that all
right so I'm going to be talking about
that more I'm going to go through that
key exchange one more time but this time
I'm going to be more specific I'm going
to show you the internals of noise
what's happening under the surface and
this is my most complicated slide so
time to focus again and it's quite heavy
and basically here you only have the
view of the clients just because I don't
have enough space to put the view of the
server as well on top you have three
different states they don't matter too
much to our dress structures where you
can store some values if you kind of
know noise you can follow along
otherwise you can just ignore them so
the first thing you do when you go
through a noise hand check is that you
initialize both the client and the
server what they're going to do is that
they're going to hash this string and
here this is the name of my protocol
this is noise underscore NX my hand
check pattern underscore two five five
one nine my key exchange algorithm then
ASG cm and shadow 56 I'm pretty
conservative I'm choosing these
algorithms I hash that and I store that
into value called H more on that later I
also store that into a value called CK
for chaining key again I'm not going to
explain that yet so now remember the
client sends the net ephemeral public
key right so first the client has to
generate it and store it somewhere and
now we're going to do something weird
we're going to hash
public-key that we sang with the
previous age value and it's going to
give us a new edge value all right know
it's time for the client to send a
payload whatever the client wants can be
empty and we're going to do the same
thing with the payload we're going to
hash the payload with the previous H
value that we just cut from that
previous thing and we get a new edge
value and this kind of looks like I'm
absorbing everything I'm sending or you
will see letter receiving so you can see
this is kind of a hint as to what I'm
going to do later
I'll change these parts by this just by
absorbing it but this is pretty much
what the H value is it's an absorption
of every message we send and receive so
it's the same thing on both the client
and the server now the server it is turn
sends and remote ephemeral public key so
we store that somewhere and we absorb
that now we can do a DPL man-cakes
change and we put the output into h KD F
which is a key derivation function with
the C key value this chaining key it
gives us the next chaining key and a key
that we can use to encrypt and so you
can see here the chaining key is really
used to generate encryption keys now
that we have a key we can decrypt stuff
it's good because the server is sending
us an encrypted static key so we can use
the key we just generated to decrypt it
and here if you know AES GCM you know
that there is an authenticated data part
that we can use to actually authenticate
anything we want so here we are
authenticated this edge value and by
doing that we authenticate the whole
transcript we authenticate the whole
handshake we make sure that the server
is saying the same thing we're saying
the same sequence of messages so it's a
very good property of noise of course we
absorbed the cipher text we just
received and now we have a new key to
study key of the server so we can do a
new D filmin cake change we put that
into H KDF with the chaining key to
derive a new key and a new training key
finally oops we receive a final payload
the server is done we can decrypt it
with the new key we created we can
authenticate the edge value so we make
sure that the handshake looks the same
on both side and we absorbed this
ciphertext and all the handshake is done
so what we do finally is that we put the
last ck the last training key into HK D
F again it gives us two keys one key to
encrypt from the client to the server
one key to encrypt from the server to
the client so it's like TLS
all right that's that's quite tricky
right it's it's kind of dense I don't
know if you could follow that if you're
watching the video on YouTube then
that's better because you can rewind
right but yeah that one of the point of
that slide is really that it's
complicated it's not it's way less
complicated than TLS fortunately but
it's still kind of dense so what I'm
going to do is that I'm going to
simplify that and that's really the part
the the the last part of my talk which
is called disco which is a merger of
noise and strobe I make sense again
maestro disco and I'm just going to
simplify because when I looked at noise
I was like I can simplify that using
strobe I can make it more elegant more
smaller easier to implement and all this
stuff and I'm going to show you how I
did it so going through the same
handshake one more time so a third time
now but this time using strobe so I
initialize it and this time I've brought
a ESG cm and shout 256 actually
throughout also HKD F&H Mac that are
used in noise I throw out a lot of this
symmetric cryptographic algorithm and I
just replace it with strobe so that your
cut base is now much smaller much
simpler and I use this in each strobe
function that shrub gives me to
instantiate strobe objects now remember
I have to send a public key as the
clients I have to generate the public
key first nothing changed and now I can
absorb the public key in my state with
this
and clear function makes sense right
we're sending something clear we're
sending a payload now well I can just
use this send clear function to you send
my payload and absorb it in my state all
right
the server's turn we receive a public
key that we store using the receive
clear function right we receive it in
clear makes sense now we have two
ephemeral public keys we can do a check
change detail man between these two keys
and we absorb the result with this ad
function that strobe gives us now we
receive an encrypted study key we can
just risk decrypt it and also
authenticate the whole hand check
everything that we have absorbed so far
via this receive a a G function which is
really receive encryption and receive
mark now we can do a new detail man with
that static key that we just received
and we absorb it with this ad function
and I will receive a payload that we can
decrypt with this receive a EAD function
and that's about it that's the same
handshake that I went through previously
simplified by stroke if you had to
implement that it looks easier right
compared to the previous diagram and
much more simple and here at the end if
I want to separate two states one for
the client to encrypt and one for the
server to encrypt I can just call my
state and kind of differentiate them
into two different states and I can use
one for the client one for the server
and here I can just continue to encrypt
and continue to decrypt I don't set up
nonsense or IVs or counters and every
time I authenticate something I
authenticate everything starting from
the handshake I want to go through the
same handshake one last time but to show
you exactly what's happening with that
double x instruction and this is
something I really couldn't have done
with AES DCM and shout 256 and HK D F
and and H Mac but I can do it because
it's so simple and so against that I can
actually show you what's happening under
the surface so here when I initialize
what I'm doing is that I absorb this
string by exerting it with my public
parts so remember
the diagram that I had on sherry I had
the public part on top here I just
rotate it and my public part is on the
right my secret parties on the left so
to absorb the string I just XOR it with
the public part no need to send a public
key I generate it and I just XOR it in
my public part if I reach the end of the
public part I can just permute and start
again on a new block right exactly what
what I was doing when I was hashing with
sherry I sent a payload what do I do
I ignore it in the public part now I
receive a public key I'm just gonna
absorb it all so I'm just gonna going to
XXR it in the public part it's pretty
easy right it's pretty elegant no I'm
doing a detail man between the two keys
I just saw it in the public part now I
receive the encryption of the study key
and a tag I do this little dance where I
permutes and I generate some random bits
out of everything that I have absorbed
including the key exchange and I can
decrypt the payload and then I can
permute again to generate some tag
verify that it's the same one that I
received otherwise somebody's man in the
middling me and I can cancel the
handshake no I can do a new DPhil man
with the new static key that I absorb in
my public parts by exploring it and
finally I receive a payload encrypted so
I can do this little dance again to
decrypt it and to generate an attack
that I can verify and that's it
the handshake that noise is doing or
rather now we can we can call it disco
is this thing it's pretty simple right
we're just ignoring stuff and sometimes
we're permuting compared to the previous
diagram it's pretty elegant so disco is
on disco crypto come pretty easy to
remember and what is it it's a draft
specification it's an extension of noise
that noise protocol framework right
still drafts still experimental from
that I made a library called lead disco
so it's a plug and play protocol so it
allows you to do something like noise
where you can
encrypt communications between two
devices or more but since I'm using
strobe it's also a cryptographic library
to derive keys to hash and and so on so
it's a protocol analyzer it's written in
golang it's available at the same
address
so the specification and the library are
Disko crypto comm so you can go on it
today and the whole lot is only a
thousand lines of code if you don't
count the primitives the cryptographic
primitives so if you want to audit disco
live disco it's very very short it's
very small of course it's not very
useful if you don't have the
cryptographic primitives so if you want
strobe strobe it's very small right it's
only a thousand lines of code so the
total is two thousand lines of code
finally if you want to use the protocol
you need some key exchange algorithm
curve two five five one nine is two
thousand lines of code so you have to
add that so the entirety of the library
we strobe the cryptographic library and
the protocol is the same amount of lines
of code as curve two five five one nine
so it's extremely small if you want to
look at the code and make sure it's
secure yourself you can do it right it's
not gonna take you that long it's based
on noise which is let's say a stable
draft at this point sitting in it's
being used I mean what's up use it for I
don't know how many many users strobe is
alpha but I suspect it's being used by
Rambis other moments since it's been
developed there disco nabisco are
completely experimental so I came here
today to give you a glimpse of what we
have what new things we have in the
applied crypto world and what it's going
to change the landscape of the applied
crypto but it's going to take some years
now I came here also to hype some people
adding more eyes more testing and at
some point down the line we might have
something that is very small and
Wireless carried on TLS to encrypt our
communications so that's about it the
whole disco stuff again disco crypto
calm I write a lot about crypto on my
blog cryptology dotnet
I write about security
technical articles or less technical so
come take a look there and you can
follow me on Twitter user one underscore
David that used to be my city in France
and of course I work at NCC group so if
you need some someone to look at your
crypto call me give me a call if you're
a consultant or if you're in the app SEC
team of your of your company or anything
like that you can also talk to me I'd be
happy to help you or or talk to you
about crypto or security in general so
yeah I'll be here or at the conference
if you need me
thanks some questions there's a mic
hi so I didn't see in a protocol the
presence of static private key how do
you verify who you communicate with so
like I said noise NX is pretty much like
the web browser web server scenario so
alright I have to go through that again
but basically remember I said that you
can send a payload at the end of a turn
right the client sends a payload at the
end of its turn and here the server can
send a payload at the end of his turn so
that's the point where you can include
parameters which verify you're
communicating partner exactly you know
the next probably you would include a
signature from some authority right the
client trusts I understand thank you
sure another question next question
question here
thank you for a nice presentation I
really appreciate it DLS is going to be
extinguished hopefully but still
yesterday there was a talk that we
shouldn't put all our trust in like one
cryptographic primitive because in case
this shown that it becomes broken or
backdoored then we are kind of screwed
right and here what you're doing is
basically using sha free for everything
right so in case there's a vulnerability
or weakness or backdoor into free that
means that all of this is broken as well
right so so there are two different
schools of thoughts I would say there
are the people who think you shouldn't
put all your eggs in one basket and have
as many cryptographic permits that that
we can have for example TrueCrypt you
can choose what what you want to use to
encrypt tell us you can choose your
primitive the other school of thought is
that we've had a lot of things broken in
the past and this cryptographic agility
is kind of a mess in TLS so we must it's
better to make sure that one thing works
well and just use this thing for
everything else so like that if you want
to audit your system you have just this
I don't know the thousand lines of code
actually shatter is even less it's like
maybe 200 300 she gone Twitter there is
a Twitter account called tweet Pheebs -
or - it's 9 tweets if you concatenate
all the tweets together it's an
implementation of chattering but it's
very very small so it's better to have
one thing to edit and then make sure
it's secure and like that everything
else relies on that and you don't have
many threads running around now if one
day we realized that the permutation of
chatter is broken we can just replace it
and it should work because we have
proved that the construction on top of
it works right so so does that answer
your question
all right another question where I we
still have to mean it so if you have any
question just ask
thanks for the talk very nice I had the
question use with you steel rely on
isometric keys to prove the identity of
the other party you communicating with
so so you don't have to this is one
example this is nice annex you have
other handshakes where you can just use
a pre-shared key so some so no public
key well you still do the ephemeral
public key parts but you rely on that
shared secret so not on a static key
long-term study key I'm asking that
because I so talked recently talking
about quantum computing and how it could
affect the trust we have in a symmetric
keys is there a solution you have in
mind for this kind of problem also so
for quantum crypto pretty much all the
symmetric crypto we have should we stand
whatever quantum computers we have one
day we have any when it comes to public
key cryptography so here curve 2 5 5 1 9
or curve 48 probably it would be more
difficult so right now we have a nice
kind of open thing it's not a
competition where a lot of people have
submitted designs for signatures for key
exchanges that are secured against
quantum computers I think it was over
like 2 days ago or something like that
so research is ongoing this is not
something that we have now or rather we
don't have confidence in these
algorithms now but in the future it may
be in 5 years 10 years will have solid
post quantum crypto please another thing
I can tell you about that also Google
Chrome made some experiments they
included post quantum key exchange but
since they were not sure it was secure
because hasn't received the same amount
of cryptanalysis they also included a
normal creation so something like 255
1:9 and what they would do is that they
would do two key exchange in parallel
one with an algorithm that we know that
we're fond of that we think is secure
and one with the post quantum
cryptography and then they would export
the results to use that as a key so like
that if the post quantum crypto turns
out not to be secure you can use the
other one you can rely on the other one
if one day we have post quantum
computers you can rely on the post
quantum crypto algorithm so so do they
are called hybrid schemes where they mix
both algorithms together like that you
can rely on both of them I just allow
myself to add for the google chrome
experiment because I was busy with this
it was the New Hope algorithm right and
they embedded it into an ECC because a
signature was not included the algorithm
itself is secure and it's used by infini
Infineon Infineon now for new contact
contactless chips they produce these
chips already are you talking about the
post quantum algorithm yes okay new hope
right yeah they prepare themselves for
connected car infrastructure so that
there was no hope but what I said that
they did was to do that hybrid scheme
where they would use new hope as well as
together exactly that's what they did
they embedded new hope in in a ECC
elliptic curve scheme right but New Hope
has no signature integrated so that's
why they did it right it's quite
interesting and I believe that this is
not in chrome anymore so that was just a
test and they removed the test but they
were just testing all right more
questions I guess we can call it yeah
all right
thank you
[Applause]