hi everyone welcome to jailbreaking
Apple watch my name is Max Vitali and I
guess we beginning how my security
researcher had company name
look out where I focus it on hardware
and software exploitation for the last
few years I was after of viral jailbreak
for iOS TV IAS and Alfre watches and the
last year I was lead researcher on a
Pegasus exploit chain so Apple watch
what is Apple watch
basically it's smart voice device that
was released in 2015 it's used Apple s1
s2 or s3 protesser depend on a model but
all the protesters just 32-bit are m7k
architecture which is derived from our
m7a instruction set so depending the
model it 512 for 768 megabytes of RAM 1
or dual-core processors and all the
models around watches how does it work
so before you can use the Apple watch
the Apple which need to be paired with
iPhone device and Apple watch prefer the
Bluetooth connection for pairing and for
install an application like extensions
or over-the-air the back so it's use
bluetooth Apple watch can use Wi-Fi as
well for receive any calls or receiving
emails or messages but Bluetooth
reminders main communication channel a
few times I hear a question like why do
we even need to jailbreak a watch first
of all it was interesting for me from a
security researcher point of view to get
a test to a filesystem to understand how
the war chest works and maybe like quick
interesting user data like messages or
emails and after all it will be nice to
run the buck tools on this small teeny
award screen like radar or Frida and it
can be used to attack iPhone so we can
send them out for my data back to iPhone
and see what happens
so before going to like deep into
jailbreak details a quick overview of
airport security I will not like focus
on each of those points just want to say
that our security is mostly called in is
security
they're like secure boot chain the code
sign in the sandbox even the exploit
mitigations like address space layout
randomization kernel mode user mode
stack and heap Canaries data execution
prevention like pretty much all the same
as we see in highlights so what is the
possible attack vectors I get a pretty
good like one day exploit for WebKit and
that I plan to use on a Apple watch but
unfortunately the WebKit is not
supported yet on what shares so I played
a little bit with the export so there is
a small a diagnostic port on Apple watch
that we can connect to boot ROM and I
boot send some message receive some data
back
this research is still ongoing so
basically I switch to make more easier
way to drill break a watch which called
application extension base it started
from watch ways to Apple added support
for application extension which means
native code that's running on a watch
and if we pack our jailbreak inside the
application extension and run on a watch
we can achieve the initial codification
so this is how the jailbreak may look
like the initial code execution can be
achieve it by packin ever seen in
application extension then we need to
leak a kernel base or like break ISL our
next dump the whole kernel
only for a kernel there encrypted I will
talk about this a little bit later next
fine gadget set up a primitives patched
kernel disable security restrictions
run stage client on a watch looks looks
doable right so what is the box of
interest that can be used to jailbreak a
watch I found that CV 46:56
was never fix it on watch us to it was
fixed only on what you s3 release and in
combination with CV 4680 it can be used
to jailbreak any versions of fortress 2
for what you three that little bit
different story Siri 2370 is is a pretty
nice but and one bug is enough to
jailbreak the whole system and for watch
was for its it's still in building
research but CV 1386 one looks pretty
promising back to watch is to so if you
remember the least we need to lick a
kernel base and there is a CV which is
680 it is the bug that I discovered back
in January and there is a lot of
information how to exploit it I just
make a quick overview so the object
constructor missing bound checking and
the object is always number which
basically represent a number in any
tournament and attacker can create oh
it's number object with higher number of
bits or in other words with control at
length and the problem is that later on
when we try to read object back to user
mode the object length will be used to
copy that many bytes from kernel stack
it needed so in other words would
control how many bytes will be copied
from a kernel stack we can lick the
kernel pointer and one kernel pointer is
enough to determinate where the kernel
is located and this bug is nice because
it can be triggered from the application
sandbox and in combination with Stevie
46:56
which is used to free in is centralized
binary today Adam was like point in to
the debug again there is a lot of
information how to exploit it I just
made a quick overview so there is code
that doing the serialization of the
binary encoded data and the object that
represents a string called our string
was delegated during the initialization
but the pointer to the object still
exists in the memory so later on the
retain method will be called on
delegated object and cause to use after
3 which means if we reallocate or a
string object fast enough and point into
like a fake we table we can get kernel
level code execution this bug can be
triggered from the sandbox as well
so we know larger currents located in
the memory will break the cattle are we
service info leak we get the kernel
exact now it's time to execute like
interesting edges in the kernel but
here's the problem for a watches - in a
time I was working on jailbreak there
was no watch s kernel dumps available in
public as well there is no decryption
keys or Apple which kernels so back in
in a time Apple was encrypting kernels
for ideas watches and TV OS before they
release watch a 3 so I have an idea if
we control the oystering we can point
the oystering to beginning of the kernel
Android kernel is like a string to user
mode the problem is that we need upset
for a we table which mean and this we
table of set is store it in a kernel
which means to dump a kernel we need to
know some information inside a car like
a chicken-and-egg problem and I start to
looking for any way to dump this or
stinky table and found there is a
reference of a stream pool table in iOS
and sterilized binary and IO centralized
binary is referenced in IO centralized
XML but the fund seemed did I all
centralized binary is exactly the same
function that we get our bug that we can
call the user 3 and we can control the
all the input arguments in a centralized
binary so I have an idea
why not try to like leak some
information of a kernel by a penny clock
the penny clock is just a log that
created by system when when it crashed
so we can control the fake object we can
control the pointer to a fake with table
so what is we use the address we want to
leak as the address of the we table so
this address will be and call the user
to free so this address will be the
reference it will retain call the system
will crash because this address is not
executed but it will save the penny
clock and the penny clock will save all
the register stage
and one of the register will
see the content of the address so in
other word we can dump the four bytes of
a kernel so I say hmm that's that's
interesting that may work it's maybe not
the best way to dump a kernel but I
start to to dump a kernel by four byte
until I find the reference to our
sterilized our string every table so we
use that rest one to week as a we table
address the watch will crash away wait
until it restore then i jailbreak my
phone SSH to phone it's around the
spatial synchronization service which
fetch all the crash reports back to home
copied them to my Mac parse this panic
part of the register state read four
bytes and put it in the assembler then
repeat the whole thing so overall it
takes me I don't know like more than 50
crashes to dump like this for provide
and like after which crash watch take
like four or five minutes to recover as
I use the very very third generation of
Apple watch and it takes another four
minutes to run the synchronization
service copied back to my Mac so it's
like 10 minutes per one crash and it
takes in two weeks to dump OS 3 imitable
but but it was enough it was enough to
construct my exploit so now I can create
the OS drink object point it to the
beginning of the kernel I get the real
with table offset so I read it to user
mode using our registry and show gate
property so lick the kernel heater
calculate the kernel size and read the
whole kernel into user mode which is
good but there is no symbolist in it so
like there is just just a raw memory
dump so I look for all the kernel
extensions by looking for micro header
magic find and list all the contentions
I find the cyst end table and the trick
here that Apple did not change the
sequence of the system calls to not
break the backward compatibility which
means as
to find the beginning of the system cold
table you can automatically resolve
around like 500 symbols the same thing
for market reps so if you find this two
tables you get around like 600 symbols
in in a Down
well I kids object with table resolving
may be useful to anyway I get a colonel
down I get a semi symbolic a to colonel
so as can carry off for a for a good
gadget and as I get the exact primitive
with user to free I just use read and
write primitive read and write gadgets
to set up a primitive again I will not
focus that much on a primitive there is
a white paper so it interesting please
like reference date watcher is three
there is a different story
so caramels are not encrypted anymore so
which means that you don't need to dump
it like where four bytes and symbolic
ate it you've got a symbols but Apple
changed a little bit security which like
new heap loud sound fixes in Apple
mobile file integrity
it is a driver the chicken or like code
sign and all the certificate and there
is more sandbox restrictions but it's
still vulnerable to CV 23 70 which is
pretty nice bug it's a heap overflow in
a Mac voucher extra reside and the
problem is that there is a user mode
structure and one of the structure
fields will be used as argument to copy
in front and the copying copying data
from user allocated buffer to a
communicated buffer and as we control
what we copying and we control how many
bytes we are talking it lead to a fully
controllable hip overflow there are a
few ways to exploit this bug I prefer
the ones that can be represented which
we can allocate the Mac messages and
corrupt the Mac message headers and
corrupt the mark message buffer bounds
which leads it we can read and write out
of mark message bound and this bug can
be even use it to lick the castle
so if we still know or lick the address
of the hip we can allocate the user
client and read it back and the very
first pointer of object will be pointer
to we table and the we table is always a
constant so we can calculate the Kaiser
our slide from the table address again
this bug can be triggered from the
application sandbox so for bus for
watches to in watch a3 will get caramels
we set up the primitives now it's time
to patch a kernel so I use a classic
approach is called the patch finder as
all the gel breaks do before to support
that many variations of different
kernels and offsets so you look for
stringer bite pattern find the reference
to it and with some additional
instruction analysis it's easier to find
beginning of the function or the
variable you want to reference simple
armed emulator is super helpful to not
do it all the calculation by hand and
again fiscal table and mock back table
so as soon as you find the beginning of
the tables it automatically give around
600 symbols which can be used to do a
patches so now it's time to patch a
kernel the first patch is how to get
root as we still in a sandbox we still
run it as a mobile and the fun thing
there is no kernel page protector on
Apple watch so which means as soon as we
get the kernel right we can easily dodge
the kernel code and we can easily by the
kernel page tables to switch these pages
to be writable so in other words just
find set ready function and write out
the check which prevent you from
non-privileged process to escalate your
root and just call tetra 8000 you get
root or if you don't want to patch a
kernel and like mess with all this
kernel text we can iterate a heap and
find
proc structure for our process in a heap
and in this proc structure it will be a
pointer to you cred structure in this
you cred structure will
feels like UID GID just sets into zeros
which leads it our process became the
same thing for sandbox so we are still
sandbox it but in you cred structure
there is a pointer to assemble label and
if we knew out the sandbox label there
is no label there is no sandbox so we
can read and write pretty much anywhere
on a system getting a kernel task so
care no task is pretty nice way to read
anywhere write anywhere in allocate the
kernel memory again if you can patch the
kernel we can patch the task for pit
function and remove a check which
preventing get kernel task port or there
is other way without patching a kernel
iterate a heap and find like the kernel
task and save the send right which is
like itself into our protest ask which
support then read it back by task get
special port and swap everything back so
in other words we get the kernel
centroids and return the special
structure in user mode which contained
the kernels and write on it in other
words it cannot happen and no care no
question so we get it colonel tasks now
it's time to disable code sign checks so
there is a global variable called debug
and it's got reference by a function
called PE I can help debugger
it's like internal Eponine and it
enabled the debugger capabilities around
the kernel and all the kernel extension
so we can patch it globally by setting
the back to 1 or there is a import table
like NL simple pointers and there is
like imports in kernel extensions so we
can redirect the simples to sound
functions at like Row 2 Row 1 so in
other words set P I can help debugger
only for a kernel extension that we need
in addition we need to patch c CS
enforcement disable and allow invalid
signatures there are two variables in MV
kernel extension in an a constant data
just by jump to one and this leaf that
we can run any ensign
called an apology one last thing is
around the root of s so root of s this
mounted is read only which means if you
want to add the new file as the root
filesystem or like change any of
existing ones suitable prevent us from
doing it but there is a function in a
kernel called the mock mount and it is
checking if it is a root filesystem and
if we run it on the release kernels like
return null or so so just watch out this
check and called call mount to remount
system partitions that the partition as
a read/write there is other way to make
this patch without like touching a
kernel text all in a heap there is a
root fSV node pointer and there is a
pointer to mount flags and one of the
mount flags it represented this file
system with a root filesystem just
remove the root filesystem flag call
remount and switch everything back so we
we can remount filesystem without
touching you cannot cannot text on a
systems before Apple filesystem there is
two additional patch required and there
is lightweight volume manager which
basically set a hook on the right so
when you try and even if is remounted
filesystem when you're trying to copy
file is to protected partition it will
not write any data it will just write
zeros so we need to patch is write
protected check and set B ICANN has
debugger to one on all the systems
before Apple file system anyway i
remounted the root filesystem and it's
time to like drop the payload so I
reckon pile the SSH client for our m7k
and CH as well recompile the basic tool
package like LS mode for our m7 key and
copy everything to root filesystem
then I run a drop beer and was surprised
because it got killed by sandbox which
means it on watch here there is much
more restricted sandbox and on is so the
calls like bind connects and receive the
forbidden but as we get the colonel
right we can knew our specific sandbox
operations just in the sandbox term
extension so I done this around the SSH
and here's a problem here's a list of
all the available interfaces on the
watches there is a WL 0 which look like
like Apple Wi-Fi direct but in my case
it's support only the Bluetooth
connection and it was the problem it was
a problem for me because I plan to
connect to Apple watch directly from my
Mac and start looking for a way how we
can do it since for Luca Tedesco or
point me to this trick we we can use
mobile framework on on a Mac to send a
special message to a phone say hey
please start forwarding service port
with the port number 22 from from a
watch we still bind a port and a watch
to some random port on a phone and
return it in companion proxy service
port so in other words we can bind the
port on a watch to a port on a phone
then bind the port on the phone to port
on a Mac and connect it over the local
host this is how it look like I run my
proxy did bind the port and now I can
connect to the port abandoned from my
Mac it will use iPhone as a proxy over
like USB Bluetooth proxy to connect to
watch yeah we'll get the shells found it
we run the new name and we see its watch
is 2.2 running on the very first
generation of watch
I run the list of all the processor of
the processes and here is the jailbreak
of the watch pound in other words
watches it's like super similar than I
guess just for co-pilots here is a drug
beer instances running on a watch yes
and as we get the ssh connection we can
copy or copy files to watches copy files
drama i watch is which much easy
so I recognize the NVRAM a binary and
use STP to copy it to watch copy into
user beam ok password prompt done now
switch back to my station run the nvram
- peep which lists all the like user
motor testable and there are variables
similar sync - if you want to copy files
from from a watch we can use SSH with a
pipe and like redirected directly
somewhere on your Mac so in this example
I archiving all the private frameworks
into a file called the frameworks tar
and it will be save it on my micro you
had to prove the twig copied something
yeah literally we just dumped it one
half megabytes yeah so it was like a
quick overview of SSH over the Bluetooth
but there is more so we can SSH over the
Wi-Fi it's the watch case support the
2.4 gigahertz Wi-Fi spots it's a little
bit tricky to force watch to connect to
it but it works so the interesting thing
that I found is not involved at all
which means we don't need to connect any
like proxies the phone we just need to
lick the address of Apple watch and
connect it directly over to Wi-Fi yeah
so in this example I already live the
address of Apple watch and I just
directly connect from a Mac get the she
responded and in this case I'm running
the Watchers 3.1 again on the very first
generation of Apple watch the same list
of the processes the same STP in this
case I recombine the kickstart is a
special tool
and it's least all the kernel extensions
just in a render copied to my Apple
watch run the kickstart yeah
so we see the address which we decide
this is the name of all the kernel
extensions in errata yeah so it's one of
the final thing I recommend the pink
tool to prove that it works
if we knew out all the sandbox
restrictions we can even force watch to
talk with outer world for example let's
try to ping Google yes we see it works
so that's Apple watch okay
so Apple watch it has a test to SMS
calls health information even some
photos and other private data can be
synced to watch some of the models get
access to GPS location directly or fetch
it from a phone in these to answer our
calls and involve it even Apple pay of
course after you made a jailbreak you
get access to hold the user sensitive
data like messages called histories
contacts and so on so I go deeper I've
rode the framework that allow me to
interpose and trample in the system
functions which mean when the data got
synchronizes from a phone I can catch it
on my Apple watch which mean some stuff
like call recordings is possible as well
so if you use Apple watch on to answer a
call on jailbroken watch it's possible
to record this call it's even possible
to create weeks for a watch as we see
two weeks in Cydia now change the layout
of some of the UI elements and so on or
run tools like Frida and radar on on a
watch
I would say it what race security is
mostly equal to is I will do a really
great job to secure the both system and
it's pretty hard to jailbreak the modern
Apple operating systems but still data
forensics maybe a little bit easier on a
watch because there is no hardware
protections like MCC like kpp on a soul
its I'm pretty sure Apple will edit in
any future models but data forensics a
little bit easier now and as both
systems are secure the exploits for
Apple watch for watch and iOS became
even more available as it's harder and
harder to exploit it with each new
versions this is it you guys have any
questions no questions
oh there is one great presentation you
foresee Apple enabling kernel text
protections so that it's not read right
I mean yeah rewritable in the future so
you can't patch it could you please
because it's like oh yeah so earlier you
had mentioned that you're able to just
simply patch kernel text do you see
Apple enabling readwrite protections or
write protections on kernel text in
future well as soon as soon a poll will
move to 64-bit protesters for Apple
watch they will add to cannot batch
protects for sure
I think there's only reason why the lack
of kpp on Apple world because it's still
such a to be processor and it's may
cause additional like performances as
the very first implementation of kpp was
like a special message service that
running hypervisor and continuously
check the kernel page tables I think it
may be a performance reasons or is it
did not edit it yet if you understand it
like in like more detail it exploitation
please refer to a white paper how to
exploit all the vernal abilities that I
just mentioned and like there is a one
of the first version of this talk which
was more detail it in a way how I dumped
the table by 4 bytes so yeah you can
reference it to if not other questions I
think I think we're done thank you
[Music]