good morning everyone it's great to be
here
welcome to lost in transaction process
doppelganger my name is Holly Burman and
the security research team leader at in
silo with me here is Eugene hello Eugene
:
social developer from Salem and today
we're gonna be talking about
doppelganger chizz a new evasion
technique for for Windows and we're
gonna start off by talking about the
history of evasion techniques we're
gonna move on to talk about AV scanners
and all the different factors to
consider when implementing one then
we're gonna discuss transacted NTFS or
txf as this is known it's known by
Microsoft and then move on to discuss
the evolution of the Windows process
loader over the years finally we're
going to get to the doppelganger NEX
accusin flow followed by a live demo and
then if we have time we'll discuss a
mitigation in redstone a story of a blue
screen of death that we ran into while
conducting this research so advanced
code injection techniques and evasion
techniques evident with a spurt for many
years now notable methods are ghost
writing atom bombing power loading
propagating which was only recently
released a few weeks ago we have
reflective loading which is loading of
dll files into memory without ever
placing them on disk and we have process
hollowing which is basically running a
malicious process inside of a container
process so let's take a look at a bunch
of these we'll start off with ghost
writing this as the author describes it
is a paradox writing to another process
without opening it nor actually writing
to it and it's an injection technique
from actually over a decade ago from
April 2010 and it hasn't really received
much attention so it's why I decided to
cover it in this talk the goal here is
to inject arbitrary code into a process
in this example specifically
explorer.exe and do that without opening
the process without writing through the
processes memory without creating any
threads in the process or using a PC is
in whatever
now this technique works by by first
finding two patterns in ntdll we're
gonna call them the loop pattern and the
jump pattern now we're gonna use these
two patterns to achieve what we call a
right what we're which is basically the
ability to write whatever we want into
the target processes address space and
do that into any address that we want so
let's start off by talking about the
move pattern the move pattern is a
simple pattern made up of two
instructions in assembly code the one
being moved from a an immediate value of
stored in a register and then storing
that value in the memory pointed to by
another register so an example would be
this where we have move the contents of
EB X register into the memory where ei X
points to and now what we want to do is
use set thread context API which
controls the registers of a thread and
set the EAX register to point to an
address in memory where we want to write
the double work and then write that
double word into EB X and by that we can
write a double work wherever we want in
memory the next thing that will happen
is we're going to return which is the
next part of this little gadget here we
have and this return there's a problem
with it because we don't know where it's
going to return to and so what we're
gonna utilize here is something called
the jump pattern and basically we're
just gonna look for an instruction that
is a jump zero which means it's gonna
keep executing itself again and again
and an infinite loop it's gonna stick
the program and that way we're gonna
avoid a crash and so using some tricks
that we're not going to cover right now
we're gonna get the return to jump to
this to this jump and everything is
covered in this blog post if you're
interested and then this ability enables
us to iteratively one double word at a
time write whatever we want wherever we
want now once we have this right what
wearability you can get creative and
think how can we use this to execute
code in this specific example the author
decided to write a shell code onto the
stack of the of the
target thread and then using separate
context call virtual protects to change
the protection of the page make it
executable and then run shellcode
another injection technique that
actually we released about a year ago
which was in October of 2016 is called
atom bombing and that uses the global
atom table and APCs
which are async procedure calls now we
actually witnessed this being used in
the wild by dry decks the notorious
banking Trojan now atom bombing works by
basically having a malicious process
store code in the global atom table now
this is done by using the global add
atom API and then what we do here is we
have a legitimate process we issue an
APC call or an ASIC procedure call to
the legitimate process and thereby sort
of force it to retrieve the code from
the from the atom table and store it in
its own memory in the readwrite location
at which point we go on to do some
return oriented programming to allocate
virtual memory that is executable copy
the memory from the readwrite section to
the executable memory and then finally
execute the shell code now all the
methods that we've discussed so far
ghostwriting atom bombing and the rest
allow you to execute shellcode and a
target process so usually an attacker
would want to have their code running
inside of a legitimate very
innocent-looking process which would be
either a system critical process or a
process that's used by the user and so a
crash in the in the code of the malware
could significantly impact the system if
it's in critical windows process then a
crash could lead to an even a blue
screen and then if it's in a user
application such as Internet Explorer
then obviously the user is going to
notice something so it would be very
nice if there was an ability to create a
process that will host our malicious
code and if it crashes it doesn't affect
anything in the system and that's why
cross hollowing was invented now the way
process Halloween works is that we first
create a legitimate process in a
suspended state from something
just SVC host and now what we have is a
process that's running in the system or
it's not yet running but it exists in
system it will be seen in the and the
task manager for example and this
process has a process environment block
which points to the main image that is
loaded now at this point it's important
to note that we also have the EAX
register that points to the entry point
of the executable which means that once
the process starts running this is the
first instruction that's going to
execute so what we go on to do is we
unwrap the main section the main image
and so we have sort of a hollowed
process and this is where the method
gets its name now at this point we move
on to reallocate the memory for our evil
exe and then we use this memory that
we've reallocated to the right for each
section in our malicious code we write
it into the target into the container
process at which point we can move on to
relocate the image if we need to and set
the base address in the process
environment block if we changed it in
this example it's not necessary and
finally we have to change the ax to
point to the to the correct entry point
by using set thread context and at this
point all we have left to do is to run
the process and so we resume the thread
and everything works just fine now this
technique was useful years ago when it
was invented it was able to bypass a lot
of security solutions but nowadays
vendors are aware of it and are able to
block it that being said let's talk
about how so the most trivial
implementations of process hollowing
will create an image that is entirely
read/write/execute
because it'll allocate everything in one
chunk and it won't correct the
protection and this is easy to detect a
numerous way so we're not going to get
into that but if the malware authors are
a bit more creative and they don't just
copy the first example off of github but
actually implement themselves then
they'll unmapped the executable and then
reallocate with correct protection for
example in which case first of all the
mapping of the main execute the unmapped
of the main executable is high
suspicious and also what we need to
understand is there for every address in
windows in a process in Windows we have
something called the virtual address
descriptor which is a structure that
describes the properties of that address
and the start address of the thread is
going to have an image map property or
an image map type when it's first loaded
legitimately but once the the threat
actor reallocates the memory by
unwrapping the the main module the type
is going to change and so we can detect
that let's say the attackers get even
more creative and they decide to for
example overwrite the original
executable without unwrapping it
realizing that this change will not be
reflected in the virtual address
descriptor so in this case we need to
understand how Windows works when
mapping images when mapping an image
there's an optimization that makes the
pages of the image shared so that if we
load it into multiple processes then the
image is loaded is shared one time
because we don't want the image to be
loaded into every process independently
and thus taking more memory so when
Windows does this in the something
called the PFN database which describes
the physical pages of the opera that the
operating system is working with the
pages themselves will be marked as
shared now once a process tries to write
to that page the page will be turned
into a private copy just for that
process because it's no longer shared
and this change will be reflected in the
pfn database and so the flag that
specified private specifies private or
shared will turn from 1 to 0 which means
private and this again we can detect the
attacker and you can get more creative
and try to unmanned dream ramp remap the
image but again if it's not an
executable than the virtual address the
script is not going to match and the
most the best way to do this to make it
look as genuine as possible is by
unmapped
and remapping in another file as an
actual image in which case first of all
the start address of the thread is not
going to match the
address of entry point of the image
that's actually loaded and also the file
object that is associated with the
process is going to be different from
the file object that the virtual address
descriptor is pointing to so process
Halloween not so great anymore given
what we just saw the rest of the
techniques we talked about which are
atom bomb and ghost riding etc they are
missing this file mapping property right
they there they create this dynamic code
that's this it seems like a runtime
generated code and it that's something
that modern solutions nowadays are able
to detect because it's highly suspicious
so we need something new wouldn't be
cool if we could create a sort of a
Silas map file but we know that a v's
scan files so we need to understand how
scanners work very well if we want to
try to slip something past them so for
that I'd like to call Eugene to help me
out so we'll talk a little bit about how
the scanners scan the files before
they're being executed let's consider
the generic file execution process at
the beginning file is opened and then
this section is created out of file and
the the memory is met into the memory
space of the newly created process and
then the execution stopped so varied
interception can happen we will cover
some places for example a the a file
execution can be intercepted
during file open process so usually it's
done in the mini filter on the windows
during the create file called the second
place that can be intercepted by
antiviruses is a they acquire for a
synchronization callback which is called
during the section creation because a
section is created and the third place
that we will cover today is the process
in creation notification routine which
is a called just before the process
starts execution and it's say in this in
its form that about that allows blocking
of the execution is available only for
I mean is acute Abel so before we going
further talk about a a you see some
examples of how antivirus walks I let's
discuss how a what should be done that
once the execution is intercepted so
antivirus have to scan the file and
decide if it's malicious or not the
scanning can be done either from a user
north or from Kenya or from any
combination of the two it's up to a
vendor to decide how to scan the file
and the target file that is being
executed there should be somehow access
so it could be opened by name it will be
opened by file ID on some file system
that supports it and of course they a
file object if it's already a available
could be used a the simple object will
be used to scan the file so again it's
up to a event or to decide how to how to
access the content of the file
of course very scanning the file on each
change is not practical if you do it the
operating system will be on just getting
files if we do anything else beside so a
the every vendor had has to decide where
to scan the file so they have some
distinct points where they scan the
files and they if we scan the file
before its execute it's completely blind
for the rest of the thing techniques
that we have talked about so if the
content of the memories change or
somehow files change in brought into the
memory it's completely invisible for the
a file in secure file skinny so let's
see some examples of the a real a real
starts taking from a well-known Windows
so in the first example we can see that
the execution is blocked a during
integrated process just before the file
is opened here a antivirus in the mini
filter Kovach blocks the execution in
vowel it's blocked from the other
process a usually it's a antivirus
process it's a tries to scan the file by
reopening it we can see from this
example that the file is opened by file
names of the file name was taken from
the original operation and it's used to
reopen the file and scan it the second
example is the same
in creation so in this specific example
we can see that the the Windows Defender
in this case tries to create a section
to scan the file by other AV vendor
blocks it and tries to scan the file
before the others can do it and in this
case again like in the previous case the
operation will be blocked until the file
is scanned and then it will be resumed
depending on the a content file it's
fungal issues will be blocked there's
some issue with a specific place
it's called Eclair for synchronization a
because the mini filter API don't allow
us to see all the parameters that is
which which are passed from the user
space so then we map the section in user
space we have a parameter that tells the
Windows kernel that we are mapping an
image and we have another option which
specifies the page protection but inside
the AAV callback we have only three page
protection don't have the image type
this they was if in the user space we
map the image we specially donnelly for
example they the the windows will still
map the file executable but the anti
viruses you'll see only the patriot only
a page protection and they they might
decide not to scan the file because they
might think that it's a it's only a data
file it's by being map of course the
windows water will never do it but if
the file is manually loaded into the
memory for execution it can happen and
the last place that we would like to
cover is the execution this is not the
file scanning it's not file operations
actually an execution operation so here
we can see that a just after the process
was created the same Indy create process
routine was blocked and the antivirus a
would go to scan the file is exactly as
it does in the first example it's
important to note that a this specific
operation is performed
it's not not as part of file operation
so any subsequent a changes total
mappings to using files will be
invisible to whisk oh so it's only
useful for the main executable because
it's in its blocking a version this
function is available only for main
executable it cannot be used for dynamic
link libraries because it's not on the
order a Windows as well in the Society's
bank to the subsequent changes to the
process using files so it's not an easy
job to create an anti-virus we have to
decide where to send the files how to
scan them there's always a performance
considerations and the antivirus vendors
have to support different platforms
different CPU types different file
systems and this makes it work very very
complicated but we would like to talk
about one more layer of complication
that the antivirus have to do B's it's a
transaction on GFS photo reduction which
if s also known as 6f short a was
introduced on Windows Vista and it's
implementing completely inside the
windows a kernel it's a works for local
in DFS a discs originally the Microsoft
repertory solution they are proposed to
use it for a multiple file updates that
has to be performed as a atomic
operation is that all the changes would
be committed to the disk or would be
rolled back depends on the result of the
operation it can be used as part of the
watcher transaction involving other
applications but it's out of the scope
of this talk and they usually this is
used for a installation processes you
can consider you can think of
installation that changes a lot of files
during the installation process and then
if something happens files has to be
wrong but instead of writing the lot of
code that role but the file since
installer just can roll back the
transaction and every changes would
disappear
it's very nice feature but just before
we continue a you can taking from the
storage developer conference but back
from 2009 you can see that we said this
was a very major change to the kernel
code a watch part of a
ntfs driver was written to support
instruction we have
a lot of new functions we will talk
about them little bit later and a lot of
a functions that there exist previously
were changed to support transactions so
we have a really huge change in the
specific area of kernel and it was
duplicated it was duplicated a very
shortly after what it was it was
proposed by Microsoft and if you look to
the interview miss the annual you just
see notice don't use it anymore and it
usually happens is deprecated features
they're still used not usually used by
Microsoft in storage after today the
latest windows update will use
transactions so let's see some API
before we start we just have to a real
manual transactions have a special
function so they the application here
has to be designed to use transactions
they they know don't come out of nothing
they have we have to create a new action
using transaction function we usually
end the transaction using transaction a
commit or rollback depends on what we
want to achieve for functions in the i/o
that avoids these file names we have a
special function which ends of is
transacted a board and the this function
in addition to the regular power options
takes the one more option which is
handle two transactions of the open
transaction then we can access the file
by its name you inside the transaction
and all other functions which watch
these file handles we'll just walk work
also with transactions so let's see some
example in this example we create a
transaction we create a file inside the
transaction let's say it's a new file we
write inside this file and we close the
file
so if if it would be a regular file and
if you would go to the directory with a
Microsoft Explorer we will see this we
would see this file but because these
files created it says the transaction is
completely invisible for the application
outside the transaction until we commit
the transaction so no only now then we
commit the transaction the changes can
be observed by other applications at the
end we have to close the transaction
handle
you so so what do we have so far we
talked about history of evasion
techniques we talked about the inner
workings of Av scanners and all the
different factors to consider when when
implementing one we talked about NTFS
transactions and you must be wondering
what's next well naturally transactions
make life very hard for AV vendors now
what we want to do is want to leverage
this and try to create a process from a
transacted file that being said the
windows loader as most of us know only
accepts the windows process loader only
accepts a file path to create a a
process and we don't have an API create
process transacted so what we're going
to do is we're going to try to dive into
the process creation process on Windows
and try to see if we can find a way to
somehow create a process out of a
transacted file so comparing the create
process function between Windows XP and
Windows 10 superficially we get the
impression that Microsoft changed
completely how processes are created but
if you look deeper into it then then you
see that Microsoft moved most of the
code from the user mode library kernel32
to the NT kernel itself and somehow the
function in kernel 32 became longer
logically the steps remained mostly the
same but let's take a look at the
process loader on Windows XP now we're
gonna take a look at this in assembly
code but for those of you who don't know
assembly it's okay the words are pretty
clear and I'm going to explain every
step as we go along so as we can see the
first step is we call an internal
routine which goes on to open the file
so we open the file here we with a few
permissions that we're asking for the
file and if that fails then we try to
open the file again with less
permissions which is I guess something
that all of us do in our code sometimes
at this point we create a section
section is an object that can be later
mapped into memory now the thing to note
here is that the type of allocation is
SEC image while the page Protection is
page execute now as Eugene said before
this is how the windows loader does it
but nothing prevents an attacker from
passing a parameter of section of
section paid protection of page read
only which could cause the antivirus to
skip the scan altogether at this point
we call the kernel to create the process
object to create the new process now the
thing to note here is that we use the
section handle that we opened before so
the steps are we create the file we
create the section and then we create
the process from the section so the file
has already been opened at this point
now the kernel what it does is creates
the process object using the create
object routine of the object manager and
then adds the process to the list of
running processes at this point we move
on to talk about something called the
process parameters now process
parameters are a structure that every
process has on Windows and it's crucial
for the ability of the process to run
without this process cannot run and it
contains it contains stuff like the
command line of the process and that
kind of thing now at this point on
Windows XP we can see that we have a
subroutine called base push process
parameters which what it does is it
creates the process parameters allocates
memory in the new process for the
parameters copies the parameters to the
target process to the newly created
process and then finally sets the
address of the parameters in the process
environment block now the important
thing to note here is this happens after
the process is created and it's
implemented entirely in user mode and
we'll see why this is different in just
a second when we take a look at Windows
10 at this point we create the thread
for the process the main thread and if
the flag specified we resume the
execution of the thread and that's it
for Windows XP now if we compare this to
Windows 10 we still have the same
subroutine that's inside and we can note
that the first thing that happens here
is that the the first function that's
called is base create process parameters
which creates the parameters we can see
the parameters being created and filled
out
some data but this happens before
opening file before creating the section
before a process even exists at this
point we call this new system call it's
not that new it was introduced in
Windows Vista but it's this this suburb
tested this system called called anti
create user process is does not accept a
section handle like the one in Windows
XP did it actually expects a file path
and the kernel opens the path for us the
other thing to note here is that the
process parameters are being passed to
the kernel as opposed to Windows XP when
this was copied post process creation in
the user space code so if we take a look
at the kernel routine we can see that we
try to open the file in kernel as
opposed to Windows XP when it was a user
mode if it fails then we try again of
course well then we create the section
just like in Windows XP except now it's
happening in kernel at this point we
copied the process parameters from user
mode to kernel mode and then we move on
to call the allocate process routine
which again calls the create object
routine to create the actual process
object allocates virtual memory for the
process parameters copies the parameters
to the new process and then sets the
value in the process environment block
from this point on there's not much left
we are allocating the main thread we
insert the main the process and thread
into their respective lists at this
point the process create notify routine
that Eugene mentioned earlier is called
and we leave the kernel and if we need
to we resumed the thread according to
the creation flag specified okay so to
highlight the main differences in
Windows 10 we have anti create user
process being used instead of anti
create process the X now NT create
process CX receives a handle to a
section while NT create user process
receives a file path luckily for us and
to create processing X is still
available in the latest Windows 10
least because it's used in the creation
of minimal processes which is a bit
beyond the scope of this talk now the
only thing is unfortunately the all the
supporting user mode code that we had an
XP is no longer available for us so what
we need to do is we need to implement
the the heavy lifting on our own by
ourselves by creating it ourselves let's
talk about doppelganger so our goal here
is to load and execute an arbitrary
executable inside the context of a
legitimate process and we want to use
none of the suspicious process hollowing
API calls such as an map view of section
virtual protect set third context APCs
and that kind of thing we want a visa to
scan only clean files or to not even
scan us at all and we don't want to be
discovered by advanced forensics tools
so we break doppelganger into four steps
step number one transact step number two
load step number three rollback and step
number four animate which brings the
doppelganger to life let's take a look
at step number one transact first off we
create a transaction just in the example
that Eugene showed before with a simple
transaction aware application at this
point we open a file that is a
legitimate file such as SVC host inside
of a transaction so we have a nice green
clean looking file object that we just
opened and it's open inside of a
transaction what we're gonna do now is
we're going to overwrite the file inside
of a transaction and now it's tainted
with malicious code the only thing to
note here is that anyone looking at this
file from the outside doesn't see our
changes they're reflected only within
the context of the transaction context
step number two load what we do at this
point is we create a memory section from
the tainted file and so we have a newly
allocated section object that contains
all the malicious code that we wrote to
the file at this point we can move on to
rollback
which is as we talked about before when
you're working with transactions when
you're done you need to decide if you
want to commit the transaction and save
the files to the disk or if you want to
roll them back because you ran in
some kind of error in our example we
have no interest in committing the
transaction because we don't want
anybody to see the changes we made to
the file so what we're going to do here
is we're gonna roll back the transaction
the file becomes green again and clean
and this really effectively removes all
of our rights from the file system now
we move on to step number four animate
using the details we found out before
from examining the windows process
loader we can call the NT create process
the X routine that was used in Windows
XP to create a process from the section
that is create that we created and so
once we do that we now have a green
process a nice clean looking process
that's running our or hosting our
malicious X section at this point we
create the thread of the for the main
the main thread and we move on to do all
the heavy lifting that we need to do
that Windows XP s user time libraries
libraries used to do for us which is to
create the process parameters to fill
them up with to fill them out with the
correct correct parameters to allocate
memory for the parameters to copy it
into the doppelganger process and then
to set it in the PB of the doppelganger
and then finally all that's left to do
is resume the execution run the process
and now we have a nice green process
that's running and the Avs will not take
a look at it so let's see this live in a
demo
I have here a virtual machine that as
you can see it's running Windows
Defender on the very updated definitions
December 7th that's today and what I'm
gonna do here is we have this password
dumping tool that's should be well known
to everyone and well we don't really
think this is a hacking tool on our own
or on its own Windows Defender seems to
think so so let's try to double click it
and see what happens
virus and threat protection threats
found so Windows Defender found threats
obviously the executable did not run now
what we're going to try to do is we're
going to create a doppelganger of
mspaint which is the windows utility for
making nice little drawings and we're
gonna have this actually execute the
same tool except this time it's going to
read the tool from disk in an encrypted
form so that defender cannot scan it and
let's see if defender has any problems
with this with this action at this point
the tool was executed this is a fully
functional tool it can be used and as
you can see Windows Defender doesn't
seem to mind process Explorer can help
us take a look at what's going on here
maybe we can figure out if we take a
look and take a look at the process we
can see that we have mspaint running and
there's nothing here showing us that
it's actually a different tool that's
being hosted inside this process it
actually even preserved the icon which
is really interesting if we even try to
verify it'll say that the this is
verified that's really nice
[Applause]
thank you
so while conducting this research the
first time this thing we ran this thing
I'm Windows 7 and network just fine and
then we ran it on Windows 10 and the
system crashed and so it turns out that
there is a bug that was introduced in
Windows redstone and reported by James
first raw and its null pointer to
reference so the empty create process
the X when it receives a zero is one of
the parameters it tries to dereference
it without checking first and so the
system crashes for for an access
violation and luckily for us though
Microsoft was nice enough to fix it for
this talk because if the bug was
introduced in redstone a while back and
fixed in the fall of craters update two
months ago so if this lecture was taking
place two months ago we couldn't do it
on the most recent Windows 10 release
but now we can so thanks the affected
products of process doppelganger are the
following that we tested we tested all
these they were all bypassed what we did
is we took the executable such as the
tool we showed before we saw that the
antivirus Flags this as an executable
when we double-click it then we loaded
it as a doppelganger and it was able to
run with no problems if you want to talk
detection and prevention then first of
all it's not so easy but a simple way to
go about this is to scan the file object
available in the create process
notification routine and to use the
exact object not to reopen the file and
if you get an error while trying to do
it then you know doppelganger is taking
place so you could you should block it
about DLL files this doesn't help so
what you can do here is try to scan all
sections even data sections because as
we saw the flag is in the mini filter
callback are are actually misleading as
for forensics if you want to detect the
process in retrospect that has been
doppelganger you can take a look at the
file object of the associate with the
process and if it has the right access
enabled then then you can know that
something fishy is going on here and
there's a good chance it's process hot
process doppelganger
and also specifically on Windows 10 the
II process structure has something
called the image file pointer which is
supposed to point to the file object and
this doesn't this will be null in a
doppelganger process to sum up process
doppelganger allows us to take a
malicious executable load it in the
context of a legitimate looking file and
create a process out of it we use the
Windows loader right so there's no need
for a custom reflective loader of any
sort the file is mapped to an image file
correctly on disk just like any legit
process and we don't have any of the
unman unmapped dynamically generated
runtime code that is the that is usually
associated with modern malware and is
detected by modern solutions this can be
used to can be leveraged to
doppelgänger ll files as well and it's
completely file s and even advanced
forensics tools such as volatility won't
detect it at this point this works on
all Windows versions starting Vista and
bypasses all these solutions that we
tested the security solutions we'd like
to give a special thanks to am remiss
give and Budhia vote who helped us a lot
with this research and without them it
wouldn't be possible so thank you guys
and thank you all for coming and
listening and at this point if you have
any questions we'd love to address them
[Applause]
all right what are the question that you
would like to ask them
thank you for the talk I have one
question just to double-check if I
understand correctly with this technique
when you execute the malicious code it
will have all the privileges the process
you are using for that will normally
have right so for example if that was
the MS paint and I'm executing my
mother's code it will be able to do
anything which the the MS paint process
would be able to do is that correct yeah
yeah it's running with like Emma's paint
the process gets the token just like
Emma's paint but it all depends in
Windows on the context on which the
process was created so if it was created
by an unprivileged process then it won't
have privileges was created by a
privileged process then it could do
anything thank you next question
cents for presentation I just have an
equation do you guys investigate it like
this transactions API that you used on
Windows I doesn't have any kind of
memory implications so like we we agreed
while on transaction should be created
somewhere right so maybe Z's like
implications are detectable okay so that
is they're actually written to choose
the file system in special files and the
details of this can be read about online
on MSDN it's documented hello my
question is what about access rights is
are the the rights checked just after
committing or at the beginning of the
create transacted file
can you spoof also a process that is
unavailable to you yeah I don't follow
all right the binary there there was an
example about svchost.exe yes what if
it's a protected process that's
unavailable to for example you don't
have rights to read it as you mean on
the file system level yeah yeah I don't
have access to it so no if I can't open
the file then I can't do anything to it
yeah but in theory I could just copy the
file somewhere and then and then do it
from there okay thanks
anyone else has a question
thanks for attack what about code
signing and executive signings are like
certificates for for executive executive
battles sorry so as we saw in the demo
if you took a look in process Explorer
for example which tries to verify the
digital signature of the process that's
being executed so it looks legitimate
but if you take a look in memory at
what's running if you investigate this
at runtime then then obviously you'll be
able to tell that something happened
so like the signature will not match
we still have time if you have any other
questions then before your lecture one
question about do the up locker prevent
this those the app Locker check the
memory contents or those very violent
discs so that's a good question and I
actually not sure about that because we
didn't take a look at app Locker and
this and this research we mostly focused
on on bypassing security solutions by
seeing that they don't the in correctly
handled transactions so I don't have the
answer for that next question
we still have the means
I was wondering have you gotten any
response on this from Microsoft is it
will it be patched somehow so we've
actually disclosed this to Microsoft and
they didn't deem it as a vulnerability
which it's not the operating system is
behaving as it should the only thing the
only thing here maybe that they could
they could change is to add in the mini
filter called back you could you could
tell the antivirus that a section is
being created for execution even when
you can kind of fool it into skipping
that but other than that there's not
much Microsoft could or should be doing
it's the anti viruses who should handle
transaction correctly thank you
so to that point about Microsoft not
considering this vulnerability are there
legitimate cases where you would use
transactions here for creating
executables so that that should really
it shouldn't happen because as we saw
the the Windows process loader the
official exported API it only accepts
file paths
there's no way to run a file out of a
transaction it's only using the system
calls directly that enables us to create
a process from from a handle if we take
the handle to a file we create a section
then from the section we create the
process but that is something that the
Windows loader is in charge of doing and
as you saw in Windows 10 is no longer
even happens and user mode it happens in
kernel mode it's just that the the old
system call is still available ok so
then the real question is why do they
persist that old method flat why does it
still exist yeah so it's a bit beyond
this scope but the general idea is that
NT create user process creates a proper
Windows process while NT create process
is just a relatively much thinner
wrapper around the function that creates
the object of a process and so it can be
used to create a minimal process which
doesn't have a lot of things that a
normal process does and it can be used
in running things like other subsystems
on Windows such as for example the wsl
the Windows system over Linux which can
be used to create these types of
processes which are not normal Windows
processes thank you next question
so this is a follow-up question of a
question that was asked before so they
asked you for a reaction from Microsoft
but did you get also some reaction from
the antivirus software companies yeah so
antivirus software companies have been
aware of this issue it's it's online if
you look up Antivirus Plus transactions
you'll see that it's a known fact that
they don't handle transactions correctly
they're aware of this issue they just
haven't taken care of it yet and that's
what we're trying to show here is that
even 11 years after this feature was
introduced fully documented and and and
people have discussed online that that
anti viruses don't handle the
transaction as well still 11 years later
and all the anti viruses can be bypassed
using this technique
that anyone else has a question
thanks for your talk um I was wondering
if this could be used in a way with
exact rules which elevate automatically
which are signed by Microsoft so say you
pass the parameter of a processbook for
example in your example when you pass a
parameter for acceptable that you want
to elevate and you said inherits this
visit the security descriptor fell
through the process which you the post
process so could that be used for like
process elevation or yeah so you're
talking about Auto elevating processes
right yeah that's a very good question
and it's something that actually we've
dealt with in the past you can see on
breaking malware on her blog we we
actually did some USU AC bypasses using
exactly what we did specifically as we
used a Auto elevating process and we
changed the environment for it so it
loads our DLL but so this could actually
be potentially used for this but it's we
haven't gotten around to to testing that
yet but it's on our to-do list our thank
you
if you still have a question we still
have time yes yeah you still have time
guys yet
[Applause]