okay so everyone good noon thank you for
coming to for tonight presentation today
I'm going to present you a research that
I've done on an iOS kernel module and
ice driver called Ethel a ve driver and
so the agenda the main agenda for today
first we will review some of the core
attack vectors on iOS and some of the
actually also related to Mac OS second
for a second I will present the
vulnerabilities that I found some of
them and then we'll get to the
exploitation part of how to actually
take those from abilities and take them
into a fully working exploit and then
fewer to bore jailbreak and small
surprise and finally QA QA and
disclosure timeline so a little bit
about myself my name is Adam donenfeld
I'm a security researcher work mainly on
iOS and Android
I I do over mobility assessment and
exploitation so more the offensive part
and currently I work as a senior
security researcher for as imperium and
additionally additionally I would like
to thank sook of RAM and Univ Carter for
helping me with the presentation and
supporting me during the times of
frustration so let's start I will start
like I said with the review of the
attack surfaces so in iOS and also on
Mac OS there are a lot of attack surface
we can categorize them into different
sections let's call it this way mainly
cisco sitting calls now on iOS on new we
have Maxis calls and FreeBSD syscalls we
also have a MIG which is an
auto-generated
messages interface so you can just put
it's like it works like an idea you you
write an idea ideal and templates
templates and then some code is
auto-generated and finally we have iokit
and by the way I okay it is profoundly
based on me so to actually issue IO kit
cause eventually everything is
everything goes through a nigga but I
get is a huge platform and even though
everything is that is going over big it
deserves its own bullet here as in an
independent category so sixty seconds
about our kit so I hope it is apples
apples collections of resources tools
frameworks and everything for creating
Bibles falls new and unlike let's say
unlike Linux driver for example those
drivers are actually written in C++ it
is done because they do have some macros
which gives you some basic reflection
capabilities now it's super cool in my
opinion for divers and additionally you
have some layers some isolation between
an actual driver and the communication
channel of the user mode and the driver
again if we compared to the normal Linux
drivers of Windows rivals
additionally Apple gave a huge amount of
pre built-in types you have pre-built
dictionaries arrays integer strings
whether that's you have those types from
Apple and finally I think this is the
best gift Apple could give to offensive
researchers because it's an amazing
platform for exploitation of this new
kernel now I want to review some of the
projects that have added dependent on IO
kids so you can see
that's a list of recent jail breaks that
were based on IO kids own abilities it's
not the fullest the only reason I
actually didn't try to move them is
because I didn't have room in the on the
slide but there are more jail breaks and
projects and obviously probably you know
more texts that are no jail breaks which
depend on iokit now the question that's
probably most of us asked is why hackers
love I get so much what makes Eric it's
such a good platform for attacking so
first of all there are a lot of drivers
which definitely increase the attack
surface now there's no I mean we don't
really know that for a hundred percent
but I believe there is a there is a disk
the people who work on our kids don't
really work on is new and that's why
there are some miscommunications between
those two groups which leads to bugs I
hope it is like I said out it is written
in C++ and which means there it does
have actually objects so for example you
have V tables now if you can overwrite
something and you can override a veto a
bill you can override function pointers
and you can hijack the kernel very
easily which is by the way something
that you can also also do to bypass the
new kpp and MTC mitigations because
those are not protected finally because
most of the IOT drivers are not
open-source less people look audit that
code I think it's a mistake and I think
our kids is our kids Intel in term of
Security's underrated undermined I mean
is new is a little bit more protected in
my opinion again just my personal
experience so how do we actually use
iokit how do we actually communicate
with titles so the first thing we do and
I just wrote a basic snippets here to
get the get a handle to a driver so this
function gets it gives out a connection
to a driver which is by the way just a
port and it's a
it gets a name of a driver that it has
to look for so the first thing we do we
call that we gets the i/o master pot but
this is like I said I hope it is fun
essentially based on me so this is a MIG
Pole which gives us that being master
port the master port is used to it to
get a list of drivers so here we say
yeah give me all the drivers which are
based on IO service which is all the
drivers as we will see soon we get an
iterator back and then we can iterate
all the drivers we get the name of the
driver we check the name that we are
currently running on and if that's the
name once we just call I will service
open another API that uses me to get a
connection to the driver so you can see
master ports gives us an iterator which
gives us a service like we can iterate
the service and the service is
eventually deport so how do how do we
actually write diverse for iOS oh no
it's actually not really documented and
I personally understood how to do that
just from reverse engineering drivers
this cannot function it so those levels
have an external methods if you're
familiar with Linux it kind of reminds
il CDL drivers of there's like mmm
drivers overrides the external method
function which is called every time the
user wants to communicate with the
driver the users issue those the issue
those comments using an API called IO
connect call method we'll see an example
soon so like I said the drivers must
override the external method and because
everything is based on me everything is
based on messages because maybe it's
just a messages so again I'll connect
call method ultimately calls mash
message will see example soon flow so
that's the signature of the of the
external method functions that drivers
have to override and what the user gives
is an index
that's the selector so that's just an
index to recommend let's color this way
it also gets arguments which is a struct
that contains the input buffers and the
output buffers from ends to the user
this patch is the pointer that dispatch
is the block of is the function the
script oh let's call this way the file
the function the script oh that will
eventually be called target is the
actual driver and reference is something
that I actually never saw you know I
never seen any driver using it actually
so that's an example of the the override
of that function so like I said before
the selector is something the user
supplies so obviously because it is
completely controlled by the user you
have to check that this is the actual
method account that it doesn't go beyond
that account then the driver takes the
appropriate function block this is the
external on method dispatch it takes the
function block like the function script
oh it takes it it puts it into the
dispatch target is the driver itself
because like I said in the beginning
there is an isolation between the
connection of the communication of the
user and the driver so that's the driver
and this is the communication and I said
the ref is never used and then the the
super implementation of Excel a method
is being called there are you user
client implementation and this is just
checks that the user buffers in the say
in the appropriate size with the
function block and that's actually what
that's ultimately called for the
function it's not necessary to call that
but that's what that's the appropriate
way to do it but you can do it yourself
also without calling this one so we saw
how the drivers implement its nuts
everything you have to know to actually
call implement the most basic user
driver communication now let's see what
the user does so that's the function I
showed before that's the driver while
trying to communicate with so a lav
it is just the communication with the
driver that's the handles of the driver
now we call function with index 0 so
I'll select o is 0 here we create a
struck and input my buffer in in the
size of 8 bytes and output struct 4
bytes and we actually because the output
the size might be different we actually
have to supply a size parameter which
the kernel can override so like I said
index 0 and we can see that here because
we select though is now 0 it takes the
first the first the script off from here
so in our case s open and like like here
you see that the input is 8 bytes the
output is 4 bytes so here eight bytes 4
bytes and that's it that's the whole
thing between user and drive a lot like
the basic communication so again the
whole flow user calls IO Connect called
method we see it here
io connect or method which calls the MiG
function IO connect method which calls
much message it drops into the kernel
the calendar gets into x io connect
method which calls is IO Connect method
which eventually calls the drivers
external method implementation so so far
that's everything about the code now
let's see how it actually looks in the
binary so so this is an example from the
drive API lav driver like I showed you
before that's exactly like in the code
you have a pointer to a function you
have the struct input size you have the
struct output size by the way this is
these two zeros if you want to just pass
an array of integers but I mean you can
just pass an array of integers but it'll
cannot pass a struct so it's up to date
today to the drive you to the size so
that's it now we know more or less how
drivers work and how users communicate
with them so now let's see the
vulnerabilities so here's the list of
the vulnerabilities I
found one of them is in IO surface I'm
not going to get into that vulnerability
but if you I mean details are available
online and if you want more explanation
feel free to ask me about it and what I
am going to talk about is so much the
vulnerabilities I found here I didn't
have to use all of them to actually
create write a full exploit but I'm
going to show a few of them that I may
be enthused just to learn now in order
to understand some of them we have to
talk a little bit about IO surface so 60
seconds about our surface our surface is
a channel object which is used to share
hardware accelerated graphics data so
frame buffers for example you can show
them across multiple processes the the
advantages of using an IO surface object
and not actually send the frame buffer
data is that idle surface Maps the data
so instead of sending out gigabytes of
information you can just send an hour
surface object like the earth surface
object the process asked the colonel to
map the data that the earth surface
object handles and then the calendars
Maps the data so just the mapping of the
same physical memory which is a lot of
time and it's a very convenient way of
passing a lot of information and our
surfaces are shared by an ID you can
create a global surface so anyone can
each map that information based on an
i/o surface ID you can create a platter
you can create private ones doesn't
really matter for our specific case but
still nice to know so to summarize it
our surface is just an object that
allows you to transfer data so now what
is a PLA V driver so every driver is
responsible for hardware accelerated
encoding a video encoding in iOS it's
not available on all six unfortunately
there is absolutely no information or
documentation about it on the Internet
and unfortunately like most of the I key
drivers there are no source codes which
means that I had to reverse engineer it
so here's the table of the external
methods of epilady driver I just moved
the the properties of every function so
it gets into one slide but one of the
things that really attracts my attention
in that table is that one of the
functions required a very large amount
of input which could somehow understand
because yeah videos have a lot of
properties so maybe I don't really know
what's going on I mean offer a reference
glance it looks suspicious but you know
it's not like I can do something about
it but it also gave a lot of information
out which is also something that usually
you wouldn't expect from a driver
so I started reverse engineering that
function also said session settings
that's the name I gave to the function
based on logs from the based on the
prints in that function so I spoke
before about this function this script
oh so you have a function pointer input
count and output count so a buffer sorry
so the input buffer is in offset 30 and
the output buffers in offset 58 so x1 is
the input buffer x2 is the output buffer
now let's see what a function does so
first of all we put here yeah so the
input buffer gets into X 19 and the
driver itself gets into the the
connection so it gets into the X 20 so
it fetches something from our input some
keyword then if we actually put
something in that offset which we
completely control because that's the
input buffer if we supply if it's not
now then we jump here but if it's not we
see that it gets it gets something it
gets some integer from our inputs which
of
reversing reverse engineering that
function I know that this is an iOS
surface ID then it just gets the ice
surface ID it puts it back in to offset
1 7 8 into the input buffer which is not
suitable from the user anymore by the
way and then it continues it continues
further now what what we see here is
that we can supply something and if we
don't supply it the camel puts there a
valid channel pointer and continues on
which means we control we can get the
kind of thinking that we have an outer
surface object control and we can supply
any others we want and the can I will
believe that this is indeed and our
surface object
so to summarize the primitive we have
here we can supply any can address we
want and they cannot believe it's an
isle surface object you know it's it's
important to mention we can also also
supply a user mode address but because I
wanted to O bypass the SMAP or pun
mitigation that are in the new versions
I'm sticking to channel Channel pointers
here because the kernel will not accept
user addresses if if that mitigation is
enabled so one thing that surprised me
with that behavior is that why is the
kernel expecting the user to actually
give in channel addresses so I said it
must probably someone supply those
channel addresses to the user so I look
for that and in selector number seven I
saw that just like before we can supply
a surface ID it puts that into the input
buffer but then for some reason
inference for some reason dictates it
from the input buffer into X 9 and it
puts it back into output buffer so what
we get here is an info leak so we can
supply any i/o surface ID which is
completely something that his user I
mean it's not really usable but it's
something that you could share to to
talk about the specific surface
we can get it scandal address which is
completely something that user is not
supposed to have so let's summarize what
we have so far to actually craft the
exploits we can fake a nice surface
object which is an aggregate object so
it has variables so we can fake a
variable which means you can hijack the
kernel code execution we also have the
address of that aisle surface which
which means we have the answer which
means they have we can bypass map
because we can still stick to kernel
addresses the only thing we don't have
is some some way to bypass a sub KS
allowed so that's the last thing we have
and then more or less we have all the
bypasses for every mitigation in order
to I Jack the camel code execution so I
at that point I said okay this level is
very interesting let's dig further to
what it does and I saw that eventually
all of those functions lead to the same
do the same code into the same yeah the
same function so all of those selectors
wrote just wrappers to the main logic by
the way command gate if someone is
interested it's a way it's in a
synchronization mechanism in iOS and o6
not really relevant to this example but
there's also very importance to know so
that's how the main logic looks really
unpleasant if you have to do a click
reverse engineer nevertheless we have to
head to reverse engineer it's understand
what's going on so let's quickly brief
it so the driver is put into X xx the
user the user client like the
communication channel of the user is put
into 22 and something which you are not
so exactly sure what is is put into 21
and 25 is our input buffer so what I saw
someone is that it's takes like I said
25 is our input buffer it takes from X
25 a surface channel address which we
can control but
we can also put a valid journalist here
so x 1.is canal an isosurface scandal
others it puts idiots also a lot of
other information not really relevant
i'll surmise it because it's not the
important part here what it does it it
gets the iris surface object and then
like I said before it maps them from all
surfaces are meant to map to assured
information so it Maps the information
to another address space so what
eventually it does is it puts into X 26
the map of the data of the Isle surface
so everything X 26 points to a kernel
address which we fully control its
content and because it's mapping we can
also modify that data and during the
execution which unfortunately they
cannot didn't consider at all so nothing
is locked in buffalo everything that is
in this buffer can be changed anytime so
what I saw eventually that the camera
does is here's the X 23 is the channel
address of that mapping mapping it takes
some commands from the form X 23 then
there is a switch case one of the
examples that I saw in that switch case
is that it takes a kernel address from
that mapping it checks if this kernel
address is not now if it's not now mmm
if it's null it allocates some data puts
it back into the mapping which is also
an information disclosure because we get
to how to have camel address in the size
of X 28 and because it's mapping we can
read it and then it takes that pointer
and it's it initializes it so not only
it's an info leak but we can also
initialize the first X 28 bytes of any
kernel point that we want which is by
itself might sometimes be sufficient to
create a full exploit but why borrow
when we have such better primitives here
so again our goal is to eventually
it's the kernel-based to bypass que es
Salaam so eventually it gets to some
function which is called map y UV input
form say Sadie
again that's the name because from the
idea of it from the KA prints but we
don't really have to understand what it
means to find the bug there so it gets
the soil surface can I let us into it
three puts it into our map date map data
lots another one late again and what it
eventually does is x-23 is our mapping
so it takes an integer a controllable
integer from there and it also takes a
pointer from there
now then x2 is get in here and mix to is
a point to be completely control now I
puts the code here into a pseudo code
because in assembly it's a little bit
more annoying so and I want everyone to
understand so controllable pointer is
the mapped pointer we put there from
here so it's it's something we
completely control it puts there a
mapping then it extracts the the address
in from that pointer and then what it
does it from data extracted address it's
the references this address in specific
offsets into our controllable pointer
then in some of that it checks whether
this is it checked keyword it checks
well the high 32 bits are zero and if
you're not and the kernel panics so this
is a very interesting primitive view
because we can put any others we want
into controllable pointer and we can
read from that address so we can have a
very powerful in folic now the reason
again that this is not there isn't that
here it's any others we want and not iOS
surface buffer manager is because this
is a controllable pointer so after iOS
surface before manager is being put here
we can still change the content of that
pointer because this is the point of a
completely control
so if you put it in if we point it into
something we control you can just change
it right after it sets your day before
manager so if we summarize the problem
we have here our expert if you want to
leak a specific address at least one of
those rules have to happen because if
you want to lick pad with 100 we can
take 100 - 38 and then we have to make
sure that you know that Delta plus 50 is
not here and that's the summarize of our
primitive at least if one of those
addresses is not now we can lick any
other so the address and of course
because this is just the reference in
kernel memory mix has to be a valid
kernel address so here we have an info
leak we have heap in Falak we have sort
of semi absolutes Colonel Reed and you
have a channel called hijack so we have
a lot of freight is let's see if we can
craft and exploit from all of them so
our plan is as follows first we create
an our surface object we will lick its
can huddle address because we have the
vulnerability that gives us the general
address from any surface ID and then we
somehow have to lick the kernel base to
me to find the K cellar slide
calculation we three with three the the
i/o surface object we spray data in the
same size so our spray data gets into
the same kernel address we have to so
that it gets in the same channel address
but statistics show that this is
unbelievably available and then we give
the kernel address to the channel and
they cannot believe it's a real surface
object because that's the first one
availability I showed here this time we
can put different V table pointer for
example which will lead to execution of
the kernel to somewhere else you want
and ultimately our goal is to get can
read write gives
sell food and enjoy your life so again
and let's see how we take advantages of
an advantage of the absolute it so again
our goal is to lick a constant journal
address so we can calculate this slide
between the leeks address and the
original artists so again X has to be a
valid journalist so we do have a valid
kernel address we have the i/o surface
object which is a can a valid key others
so let's start to see if we can somehow
leak something constant from the coladas
obviously the first thing that comes to
mind is the V table because it's always
it's a content is constant Cutlass
always slided from the candelabras so
that's the Isle surface object and again
these are the offsets we have we need X
18 1 C and 3 C so 18 is that one C is
also that and 3 C is the current is the
memory descriptor and unfortunately this
is never now and remember this crypto is
the memo is that actually it's the
actual memory that the object that map's
the data of the earth surface so of
course this is also never not so we
can't unfortunately leak the V table of
the i/o surface but lucky for us
pirate surface is a very big object so I
just reversed I just kept understanding
what's the other parameters the other
variables of the object are so our
surface creates and an object surface
maintains the list of something called
IO fence we don't really have to
understand a lot about it it's just a
second ization object that our surface
uses it so it actually has a list of
those and lucky for us after that list
there is a lot of controllable
information these are called bulks I
have no idea what they actually used for
but we can completely control them so
everything we see here is completely
controlled by the user so we want to
lick either one of those lists so lucky
for us if we control everything here we
are able to actually click one of the 1n
and I offense object so now once we have
it let's see how our face looks and when
we can lick its variable so most of the
of the offsets we need to be zero or not
snarl lucky for us the last one is zero
if the eye offense is in a surface kill
now because we lick the eye offence form
a surface skill that it must be in
surface skill which means completed is
never zero in our case so we can lick
the vtable and calculate the aslo so
back to our plan we create an object in
our surface object lick the address now
we can lick a vtable of an eye offence
so we can calculate the ksl of slide 3d
surface spray with a fake object with a
fake v table and then hijack the code
execution now what I wanted to do here
is to have the best spray the best
reliable spray ever so that I wanted to
make the exploit as reliable and stable
as possible and now for those of you who
are not familiar with I was spraying
there is a very common play Colonel hips
playing iOS and our six as well and I
all uncivilized XML you just give an XML
to the kernel they can serialize the XML
object which by the way had a very
interesting vulnerability I think it was
last year yeah
and anyway so but there are a few
problems with that first of all there is
up to this presentation I didn't see any
persistent family so usually
can you just answer as the XML extract
the relevant information and then
immediately free that information and I
also didn't want any limitation on the
spread data and I wanted to be able to
spray as many times as possible and so
luckily if lucky for us
I'll surface maintains a list of
properties which are written as an XML
data so why do we select online for
those of you interested so what it does
it just uncivilized or invalid data then
it gets the first object as the value
the second object as the key and then it
just puts that into dictionary
dictionary which our surface holds
that's how the set value function looks
like it just checks that the key the key
is nuts
creation properties and if it's not it
just calls the it just takes the all
properties dictionary and such puts the
other object which is the key and the
value is supplied so yeah so this is
very good for us because it's persistent
in the memory because these are only
properties that are being kept in the
memory we can spray pretty much any data
we want because there was no specific
limitation the implementation as long as
it's valid as long as our XML is valid
and we can do that as many times as we
want we can put as many values as you
want into the i/o surface object and we
can create a door thing that is an
actual limitation on the number of i/o
surfaces just the common memory
limitation and but that's not everything
about display and this is the first time
I saw a good channel generic Kalakh can
display in iOS like that it's not only
that you can put and set those
properties you can also with those
properties back because that's that's
the point of those properties if you can
set them you can also read them back
which means that we can also everything
respite can be read back so for example
if we spray the channel
and the channel modifiers our spread
data due to another vulnerability we can
just read back from any Kiwi ones our
data so eventually we can also also hit
hit our information so this is extremely
powerful it can save us for example an
information disclosure because again if
the if for example we we spray in an
object and then the kernel are no puts
it into a list we can leak that list if
it's a linked list just that's just one
example and this is extremely useful for
us playing in a camel hip sprain in iOS
and o6 now again my goal is to the goals
are have arbitrary kernel he general
memory read write and we I also want to
be able to call any function and I want
to be do that to be able to do that
anytime I want without any statistics in
mind so deterministically so our current
primitive is to hijack I put a fake V
table so we can we can hijack any
channel out of three ones so you can
call any candle address we want and we
control only or we control only the
first parameter which is the actual the
actual spray of react we had so now it's
time for to look for the gadget so there
is a very fair now it's a very famous
gadget called
on unsterilized theorized again we
control x 0 3 control both these X 1 X 3
then we control X 9 because it also
derives from extent and eventually X 3
is again something that we control so
this gives us the opportunity to control
the first parameter X 0 the second
parameter X 1 and we can jump to any
function 1 we are not able to control
the third parameter however so what I
did here I wanted to be able to con a I
had to put interesting stuff into extent
and
18 so extent is just the kernel spread
address plus some offset X 18 is what we
will see soon be the third parameter for
a final vote so it free is just that see
Scott I'll handle size twice and X 20 is
just calling unsterilized also always
say let us analyze again what will
happen is that we will get to that
function again and we are going to have
to use that as the first parameter the
second parameter is going to be X 18
from before because we control X 1 so if
we call it again it's going to be X 8 so
it's the third parameter this is the
fill parameter the the second parameter
is going it is going to be LD cache size
handler which is a sis cattle and the
function we are going to call is copy in
which gives us a new industry primitive
we can call any function we want and
control the first three arguments which
is enough for a single deterministic
right on the kernel arbitrary address
arbitrary data and arbitrary size so
what should be over right so a small so
my guess most you know there is a new
mitigation Apple did its kpp or a MCC so
unfortunately we can't override
constants or we can and we also cannot
override kernel make a text so kernel
code so we cannot override
we cannot change V tables because they
are constant but what Apple didn't
protect is this cattle
now the reason sis cattle are not
protected is that they are dynamically
loaded and therefore they cannot be
static they cannot be it
that's why the function point tell us
which Apple did not protect and we can
override it
so again our goal is to be able to
authorize to be able to be able to read
write and Bob deterministically anytime
we want
so what it is and by of course wiper
sync npc and all the new medications
Smurfs and everything so what I did was
I of about - Cisco tells one of them to
walk to my spread data to my splayed
channel address and the second one is to
modify my sprite channel address again
because I wanted to be deterministic so
once we established a successful single
right I want to be able to establish as
many red lights as possible so the way
it looks is that I have two sisters so
the first one of them over lights our
spreads data which is which resides in
the kernel so we over also we overcome
this map our mitigation the second sis
cattle takes a small portion from our
spread data and wops based and issues
hope to always realize or serialize
based on this data so again what I want
to do to actually issue any call is call
sis cattle and once this cattle to
modify my data call this second one to
use my kernel resided modified data and
then we can we can get to any others to
job or up to any other swans so the way
it looks is first of all we we have two
valid Cisco cells we call formal first
call we call our sterilizer serialize we
control only the first two arguments we
call over serialize until all civilized
civilized again this time we control
three arguments we call from that I mean
we call again using those control three
arguments we call copying which
overrides those two sis Qatar's and now
every time I want to
call some function I call once eschaton
this cattle calls copying which is
constant which constantly overrides a
specific kernel address which is our
spread data so we override some
parameters here this second sis cattle
will call the oil de-serialize a gadget
which will call itself again to control
three arguments which which ultimately
will call our modified data this way we
can achieve kernel readwrite and kernel
function call deterministically and so
we have we have cantaloupe so the way
how are we going to achieve cannily
rights so because we can call any kind
address we can also call copying and
copy out which means we have arbitrary
candlelit light from user
deterministically and that's it we
that's the exploit the capabilities were
looking for and we successfully
successfully achieved them so a few auto
jailbreak the exploit is available on
github you can download it and just use
it in goods friendly behavior and not in
any unintended way about jailbreaks so I
said before that I don't intend to walk
on a jailbreak not because I am against
it I think javac is a very important
power part of iOS it's just that Cydia
in my opinion is not good enough we have
kernel exploits we will always probably
have them
CD has to be refactored and changed to
be able to walk good with a MCC and kpp
now Ziva I test the diva on ten point
three point one with with triple fetch
and I got it to be very stable and so at
least ten point three point fund is
possible to be a pound if you want to
experiment with that ten point two point
one already has a working experts for
some devices the only the only reason
TenPoint 3.1 wasn't implemented in my
opinion it's just um just because of the
offsets nobody actually took the liberty
of modifying the offsets for ten point
three point one other than that I don't
see why someone wouldn't use it by the
way someone did write a jailbreak for
ten point two point one by using Ziva I
didn't test it myself though so
conclusion given a little surprise and
this is closure timeline so I must say
Apple are not abuse the first vandal I'm
walking on but they have been the best
one in communicating in communication
with security researchers they are very
open and friendly they listened listens
to my opinion suggestions and they
actually cooperated with some babies I
asked them to do some changes in the
advisory and they did it
unlike other vendors and they never
ignored me and which is something that
sounds that it sounds like that's a way
to be but it I mean other vendors just
stopped the communication for some
reason it is compared currently in my
opinion the most secure operating system
the still some work still has to be done
but I mean we are getting there FL
adding ever led any new very powerful
mitigations over the time now in iOS 11
in - eggs Apple fix all the bugs and
that's it we can purple stuff and go
home or not
and so I just I wanted to give a little
bit a small sneak peek about a new
project we are working on
it's a kernel exploits this time
accessible from the sandbox a very
powerful kernel buffer overflow
unfortunately I can't give more
information about that because Apple
asked me asks me enough to but I
promised to put a working for at least
the full crash because I did not explore
it to be to be completely working so far
like a full
would exploit but I think it does have
potential and what we see here is iPhone
10 11 point one point two eleven eleven
point two was released this week I
didn't have the time to upgrade and test
it I'm not sure if Apple fix that or not
I think they did but I'm not sure if you
want I also have the device here with me
so someone wants to see like the version
and everything and the device crashes
you know I don't think it's that's
important but if you want to see it then
can come and asks later and so that was
it thank you very much
if you have questions about everything
as long as it's not oh an 88 jailbreak
but job like questions are also welcome
to you that's the time thank you very
much I hope you enjoyed the presentation
and i beautiful questions any questions
yeah I mean someone's coming with a
microphone just a second
hi thank you very well presentation
Thanks
just a quick question that however
everybody is always asking never got a
question that answered how much time
this type of thing cost and work and how
much about about this device right yeah
well finding this and exploiting that
and making work okay so the IO surface
hijack vulnerability and the information
disclosure it was like I don't know it
was already done on the same day the
problem I mean the the thing that took
most of the time was first of all the
information disclosure
second of all debugging those crashes is
an unpleasant process you have to read
from a crash dump you have to fetch it
and it with device specifically because
it requires a sandbox escape each
iteration you wanted you needed a
sandbox escape and debug was written
before the I mean I could always do it
on earlier versions then 10.2 but
actually debugging it is not the most
pleasant experience but from the point
that I said from the point I found the
first I hijack a execution which was the
first day of the researcher of that
title till the day I said okay we're
done it was within a time range of less
than two weeks everything so I think and
it required more time because I
dependent on another information
disclosure vulnerability but
unfortunately it didn't work out 12 19
different problems so I really had to
work most I didn't expect this delay I
think it would could have been done in
less time but everything was in one and
a half weeks maybe something like that
so that's it any other questions
I just wanted to more about the
questions and it's not always the case
it really depends on the vulnerabilities
and on the left how reliable you want
the exploit to be how many version
versions you have to support and a good
Pacific deterministic exploit in my
opinion again it depends on the
primitives you have might take again it
might take sometimes six months and I
take one month it might take three days
again depends on the primitives you have
so that's my two cents about it
any other questions okay so thank you
very much