yy
[Music]
[Applause]
well welcome back everyone and
everyone, thank you very much for waiting for us, I
know the wait will be worth it,
we are now with lady carvajal in this
wonderful space and  I want to
introduce her before leaving who is a
lady is truly an
incredible professional is a
telecommunications engineer and has specialized
in ethical computer security issues
hacking has more than 8 years of
experience as siso and
information security consultant for both
The public sector as well as the
private sector is as an organizer of the
hacklab pierce latam community, I hope I
have seen it very well, whose objective,
like us, is women on it, is to
share knowledge, generate spaces
for interaction to reduce the
gender gap and help more women
enter  In the world of
cybersecurity, she is passionate about what she does,
that is why she is also here and also
likes to study co  Many of
us will do the problems that we
can never stop studying so
lady welcome to this space
we listen to the whole stage is yours and
we thank you very much for being here
we had some connection problems
but everything is perfect welcome
well so many  Thanks to you for
the invitation first of all I apologize because
for the delay I had
internet connection problems but well hoping
that everything is solved
so good then again thank you very much
and I hope that what I have
come to share the day is useful  Well today
I will proceed then to
share my screen
and please confirm when you
can see it
I will minimize here
I see it perfect from my perfect screen
ok because today I want to give I think
it is not a new topic for many but
It is a subject that sometimes, due to the same
common
daily life, what we do and how we do it,
we let pass some tips that
can help us  ar to give value to what we
are doing and today I come to speak
specifically about what a
true vulnerability analysis should look
like and how it is the result of the
vulnerabilities that we are
finding in the
information systems that we are auditing that
can really be used to identify
the level of risk to which
the target that we are auditing is exposed behind
the target, since there will be a
private public entity, a sector, etc.
where we can show the true value
of what we are doing then,
that is why I have called it that way from the technical to the
tactical  because we cannot pretend
and turn this vulnerability analysis process
into a fat button issue
where we are simply going to be
at a scan, we print a result and
present that client scanner
this is also not only from the point
of view of us as open testers
I hear soon security analysts that we
are dedicated to doing this but also
of  From the client's perspective, how
is he receiving these results,
then here is a brief
introduction of
who we are I always represent my
community that I carry them in my blood
I come leave clubbers can is a
community of girls who intend to
do the same as what  The same that today
joined us here and let's say we become the
same feeling and it is to share the
knowledge I am a telecommunications engineer,
a cybersecurity consultant,
I have different
certifications, including I need it, the
lead auditor, 27,000, etc. Yes,
if you have any questions, you can
contact me through me  twitter ok
good let's go into the matter a bit
here of course I also make an
advertisement that is not paid politics
simply so that our
community also recognizes that we are almost
sister communities with all
those who are doing and working to
promote the participation of women
in these branches of knowledge they
do  e that we can reduce that gap in
women's participation so we
are all brother communities
and today we will really see what
blood in brings them to because blood in
because in blood in vulnerability
analysis activities are considered
some tools
that we can start to  use if even
suddenly those who are listening to us
do not know how to start doing a
vulnerability analysis or want to
rahm while they serve to start I insist
that this
is this this presentation that I
bring you today is also very focused on the
value that we are giving it  to these
vulnerability analyzes when,
above all, we present them to the client, not
only we, as 2060, are going in front of
a camera, but also that we are
generating
the life cycle of vulnerability analysis,
evaluation, remediation, etc. as value in the market, some
indicators that from the perspective of
the organization can propose if
we are or are  s working with a
company where we were hired to
do security evaluations or
we have certain or certain
services in charge and we need to identify what
is the real level of risk that
these applications have and are
exposed or not exposed on the internet or if
they are simply within  a
network segment or an internal villain or within
a plateau or etcetera times what
would be not times I do not want to share
a series of concerns that in the end
help us to reflect if
what we are generating today as
vulnerability analysis is really useful or not
It works or if only with a
vulnerability analysis we can determine the
risk level of a computer system, it
is
good and here I want to start also
it is not paid political advertising
but I highly recommend this
twitter account where you can find very good
information about
tutorial tools  attacks or
protective measures from gluten
and that  can be implemented and that
we can test of course and that
we can prepare our laboratories
to put into practice what we are
learning when we face a
real scenario where we have to
apply it, it is worth it
then they are the ones that normally
identify or must deal with when we are
talking about the  blood and of course
this is already the blood in and the retina and what
it has is a subject that has already been
very controversial that many of
us already know but suddenly for those who do not
know
here it is simply worth
clarifying how from the
Security controls from
defensive protection measures we can begin to
articulate different strategies that
allow us to safeguard, let's say, the
information against those who want to
obtain a value, steal it or simply
circumvent the information systems that
we have implemented then there
are the sysadmin network administrators
the infrastructure managers
of the  s databases
etc. that are playing a very
important role that is sometimes very
unknown one says know and the
people behind the blue team are weak they do not
know they have a false sense of
security but sometimes you also have to
reflect on what can  That those
efforts that these
people are making are those that they know are not
within reach, then what is done if in
Brooklyn
the security fundamentals of
identifying, let's say what
those security gaps that we have
currently configured in our
information systems are,
what are the  Measures to detect
abnormal behaviors that are
happening through our network is an
infrastructure that is
not visible to us so
we have to find a way to
make them visible
in time and place even if it is no longer as
if you are well in front of it.  of the computer or
as a pin tester, well here we are
playing systems of course all  It
touches sides, there is an activity
regarding that intelligence of threats, such
as detecting them, and identifying
god patterns that allow and model
a better security posture, because I know
that there is how it works and how
its operation could be altered,
here we find all those capabilities
also of
forensic efforts.  As soon as
an unexpected event occurs, an incident,
an insider is trying or managed to
infiltrate information, so those of us who
blood in also have the capabilities of
this type of tool, processes
to investigate it, to be at least the
first responders capable of
stopping the impact that it may be
generating or  that could have generated a
security incident due to a security breach
tools such as 100 100 now what we
call orchestrators that allow us to
correlate all those
security elements that cannot, let's say, be
joined by their system due to their
operation then there appears the
famous solar that inte  gra all these
security controls that today are
being implemented live the trend,
let's say of protection,
that according to gartner and different
specialists because they are bringing manufacturers to the
market, etc.,
we fall short in implementing systems
with a single purpose and now we
need to have
complete visibility  of everything that we are
implementing then it is not only to see the
100 or the vice or the ips or the pop or well
all these security solutions that
are from the blue team we are managing and
that each one is going its way fulfilling
its purpose but now we have  The
challenge is to live all that intelligence that
is being generated then the
knowledge so that it allows us to go on,
let's say,
hunting or identifying which
threats that may arise and of
course everything concerning 15 in
response and those capacities to detect
in time in time space in  a place
that is happening in my
information systems and how can I enter
ar  sponder or if my own tools
have the capacity to respond
and here nothing else that this session brings us
complements
both for the pen tester and for the
company entity to which we are
making a bridge is a
security analysis that many times we even
criticize  We ourselves in like
other parties but other analysts do
or implement a
vulnerability analysis and suddenly they sell it
to the client as they made tremendous
bridges and in reality it was not like that it also
serves so that people made them
the security administrators all of a
sudden  They do not have the technical knowledge
because they can understand how we must
identify so that they are not getting
their hands on the opa or when a
vulnerability analysis can really
provide value of course, it could provide
threats, malware analysis and well
now the advanced symptoms that are
integrated with the  with the orchestrated
so that is like the context in
which today we are  Basing this
presentation
and if you have any concerns of
course because through the
established means of course you can do it there
will be things that I do not know I could not
answer during the session but
through me from my twitter I could
respond
vulnerability analysis then it is
important to understand that  it is a
true vulnerability analysis that understands
how it can be differentiated between a test or
another type of analysis that seeks to
identify security gaps in
information systems each
vulnerability analysis has a focus a
purpose it is already
we do not know if it searches showed it will go you know
about  A tool that helps me
analyze the weaknesses of a firewall
to see that there are no fat button tools
that you run with one click and it
ends and there is already a
vulnerability analysis let's say that things do not
work that way then here
to clarify and for what  all handle the
same the same definition the
vulnerability scan involves  creates an
automated tool that allows you to
discover holes and
defense skills and exposures present in
information systems these tests
are white box because they are white box
because the person or entity or
who we are doing it if we are
doing it to a prior
written authorization and  Once the owner is formalized,
let's say the analysis knows that
the people of the blue team are doing them, they
also know if we do not
already belong to that team and then they
will already have some measures prepared in
case something goes wrong always when
we even launch these scanners they
can happen  things where
multiple requests can knock down
services if we don't know how to configure it
then let's call this a
white box approach
and they differ from many others it is
true because when one talks
about vulnerability analysis I insist
people sell it as open test or as
tests of ethical gardening and this is not the case,
these tests differ  ian
of vulnerability scans because they are
automated, these scans are
generally configured through
a tool and there are a series of steps
not to identify an objective that
should soon be well known to identify the
objective is to collect the greatest amount
of information about the workshop by  which
I am going to do a vulnerability analysis
and launch the tools that
are generally automated already have
some patterns, some signatures where these
engines analyze whether or not it meets the
criteria of a vulnerability,
these take minutes unlike
other bridges or other exercises that  They
come to me to measure the risk because the
others may take days because hours, days,
weeks depending on the complexity and
the type of black fishing, gray box,
etc.,
are scheduled schedules as
I had previously indicated, they are
passive here, we do not seek to
break my
or exploit any vulnerability
we simply confirm them in mu  cha
education are not confirmed,
false positives can simply appear there,
which is the following,
many false positives are reported because the
scanner equaled certain criteria and if they
are, they may be possible when even
rice the results of this scan are thrown,
there relation to what is
certainly or  it may be very likely that
this vulnerability is happening or not
what happens here also with
vulnerability scans the
same scan you run for a
target based on the patterns already
defined by the engine can appear in a
target bet then already
These results are already configured, these results are previously configured and as they
will be identical in the case in which
of course it has the same
security gaps but it will not have any
differential, it is valid and the last thing because more
exploitation is what really differs
from ours and  of other tests of well
let's say of security
here you can know that it is not tried
identify if there are
zero-day vulnerabilities or security gaps that
have not been previously identified
because there would be no way to check them and
generally well, here in the management
we are going to see
a process that I do not want to
mention here at the moment
now I want to talk a little  more of what
are the annals what are the types
of vulnerability analysis and
internal external vulnerability
analysis of vulnerability analysis that are
done to wi-fi networks or simply
focused on the purpose of the target that I
am effects that can be based on
applications
based  these network
devices in communication devices depends
on the focus that we want to give it, of course,
there are tools
in all of them, there is always a pattern, which is the
one I just told you, collect all the
information about the network through
different tools
identifying security gaps  here
generally manual tests are not done
or let's say it is
the most common  The only thing is that manual tests are not done here
but I come to
tell you that later in other light
we cannot keep these
analyzes or those reports that
Espanyol is generating lists because they can be
false positives so you can put
another person here who  run a
program it would not make any difference if
I as responsible for security or
account esther or security analyst
because I am in front of truth you have to
put that color and that flavor of
hear that in front there is a person who is
at least saying yes  This can
be verified by means of a possible
exploitation or not,
then basically if we are
dragging or doing a
vulnerability analysis from an
external environment where we do not have access to the
internal network, then if we do a,
let's say a previous analysis and look for
information through  of tools that
allow us to identify which are the
ips ranges, which are the
emails that are being  They are managing the
mail server etc. to identify
weaknesses in the web servers if they
exist and that they are exposed to the internet,
one could do a type of
vulnerability analysis and external
of course here without breaking or penetrating
any type of system information
the vulnerability analysis is coming
internal where I as a responsible
open tester or security analyst
must do in my schedule
of vulnerability analysis if the
entity has it then it makes a
discovery mapping to identify the list
of new assets here it is very common to
identify that people or  The companies
the entities have no idea what
they have connected to the network and not that it
is necessarily published but that it
is within their internal network within
their vilán that are controlled by
operations by arias, well the
hierarchical structure that they have to
decide and  turns out they find
test servers that
someone created years ago to  try a
specific field and left it there forgotten and that
machine already continues to generate
internet energy costs and so on and is already
forgotten without being suddenly updating the
device database.
internal so here basically
different tools are used like
what do I know
on the map to discover which are the
servers, equipment, devices that
are giving a live and what are they
saying here hey here I am I look and
I send you a package so you know that
here I am  that are listening and
well it also serves to identify
which are those network segments that
are over there forgotten in the
firewall where one goes and looks and they have 55,520
rules in the fa in the firewall and how
there have been administrators at different
times and  at different times in the
life of the firewall then there are rules
that are not touched simply because it is not
known if they work  They ion or not and in case we
turn off the policy in the firewall
because today the operation of x service can fall
so what works well
is let's leave it critical, true that tends to
happen then for that
those types
of security vulnerabilities also serve for  measure
the state and the state the level of risk
of our wi-fi networks there are tools
too and there are analyzes, let's say manual,
that can be carried out sometimes the
proxy filters do not work sometimes
there are security gaps in those
access control lists sometimes  There are no
controls over the ips that connect
to the wi-fi networks and from there one
begins to run an analysis of the
security gaps that it has
without exploiting them because that is the
objective of this exercise, however,
sometimes one  It is raised whether or not
a vulnerability is really exploited, but
it is really worth hiring a
vulnerability analysis service
without there being an exploitation or without
There is a vector of compromise where I
can identify how a person an
attacker can break my information systems, they
would meet all the
objectives or not
and finally, they are
vulnerability analyzes based on
applications that these are the most
common, not many times they are  They hire
specific services to hear
this is my transactional portal, look to
see what it finds and then it
becomes that I am partializing
the security levels for each of
the assets that I have in the
organization and the pen tester
is also having a view  closed
and very limited if you are suddenly
evaluating the level of risk per
application and not in a holistic sense,
then here we have different
tools that right now we are going to see them
there one can identify
outdated services two libraries in the
software that are being made that
are using and are published
as information disclosur  e as
the was top 10 tells you where it says hey you
do not reveal you do not reveal the versions
of the packages or the
information systems that you are including
among your applications
avoid publishing them because today
there may not be, it may not be a
vulnerability  to liquefy and not because I have
the latest version as of today
July 8 but tomorrow the 9th can leave a
greeting and if I already know that I have 3.0 and right
now it is stable
and right now we are in 4 and a
vulnerability appears
in the last action then what is going on  to pass
then that
vulnerability analysis also works around
the time and moment in which
the
good analysis is done and of course that in the top 10
also gives us a tulle of
tools to do
vulnerability analysis because
we have already come a bit  Which ones there may be
n there are a thousand there are 25,000 there are
also tools that one creates and there are scripts that
one automates so that this can be
done in the shortest time that is given by the
experience  ncia knowledge in
programming and others, but these are the
basics, each one will obviously have their
favorites and will not like any of
those mentioned here, it is valid, this
is a let's say a basic level for a
person who today does not know how to start,
so come on.  look here go to google in
google and tell me these are the
tools that there may be more there
may be less start with these if
you don't know or if you already have a
slightly higher level it also works
always true for all scans
let's say to identify host
identify services identify a
vulnerability for example with meta
exploit sorry you cannot identify if
this exploit is susceptible to being
exploited through a
specific hair that is already uploaded in
the msf database correct
n more because it is the tool is  Like the
keychain that one has as a
security analyst in his pocket, he should not
leave it at all because it is a
tool that is very  lti generational and it
serves at any time for
any recognition in the mab is
very important and also because it has its
own scripts since they evaluate
security levels etc. open bass in
packaging is an
open source tool that your linux if suddenly
have a  Laboratory with which they do
vulnerability analysis here already
from the point of view of who executes
the pen test of course we are
having different views so I do not
get lost in the view from the business and
the view from the bridge is who
executes those analyzes
So when you are the one who is going to
do that exercise then here you will
find these tools and then
open bases is an
open source tool where you can launch is a
vulnerability scanner like nexus
like hacu net is like open bar like
themes like which etc. in  where as
others are paid here another thing is that
those those engines when they are licensed
get to be very c  expensive and in some
cases the value increases depending on
the number of targets or the
frequency with which you are going to run
these tests, then when there is
money and it can be invested there is no
problem, the problem even
when organizations do not have a budget
to  to buy the tool then
you have to go to a staggered company or to the
mitation we think that they allow one to
do this type of analysis
we have on the other hand nets songs you
in scripts that help you to
identify
weaknesses and which is that it is also
a  The topic is a paid engine but here it is
important if you have
institutional emails from your
universities because you can acquire that
community version and you can have access
to the
vulnerability analysis engine which works very
well allows you to scan at least one
target
of an application.
vulnerability analysis to an application or
installed on the virtual beach to
make different  rents analyzes of up to 16
I think they can keep there it works
for a year then so it is
quite good yes yes we are learning
already the application channels come
as alive I allow that it is an analysis of it
is a scanner for its exclusion for
applications sometimes not yet  They ask you
today if I want to analyze my website
open bass serves me well because this open
base is more focused on making scans
in infrastructures on the host as such
in open ports but not on
identifying security gaps that
are in web applications
and then well  here it is that it was not that it
is another must-see the bar suite there is a
version also that is convenient there is a
professional version in the professional
because of course there are more
attributes and more components that
help you facilitate the signal starr account,
there is true there for  of course not
not to base the results on the
tools but here we are talking
from the vulnerability analysis and
here  There is a scope if we were
talking about a bridge, it is because the story would be different
and we would be talking about
other correct tools as well
or whatsapp is like the open
source version of the bar suite so it
is available to anyone if they have a
laboratory with full wired linux  And
with mud there is also
and good because those are the tools and
you could use it if you are going to do it,
let's say enable a website,
okay
,
what happens many times when you go
to audit you find that the
architecture of the application is
developed  In for example w in
wordpress
or in some content management platform
that we know from history from
experience that they tend to be
vulnerable in time if one is not
doing a correct organization,
then
let's say that they are very attractive to
make doors  Security are the truth
and there is already a scanner that is double or
sometimes I change there are many others
insist  or but it also works and because
connectic's website is a license, it
is also a paid tool that helps us
to do that
and so we will see an example when
we also want to do more
specialized, more focused analysis because
we already have a target, we already know that
it is there.  running on the target what
services have what are its ports we
identify that it has an
ssl certificate because today we want to know what are
the intrinsic weaknesses that the
certificate has, it may have algorithms
of inscription crisis that are already
sinful so it may even be
using an ssl and  Today we are using
tse version 1.2 upwards the
others are already pre-expensive because they
are already vulnerable so it can be their
call and they can also find that is
the scan and put in the port because the
certificate can also not be only
installed and in the  443 or in the
web service but also sometimes the sikhs admin
install in their certificates for
rpp connections
and  From there you can also run
another type of analysis, especially for
service immigration
now that we have identified that
the smb protocol is on the server and
that it works as an active directory,
then we are going to see if we can
identify which users
are created  on the site or if that
active directory is well configured,
not because we use tools such as in
a forlin or psoe moves from client, they
are already specific for the service that
we want to audit if it reaches
a level where we already
identify that
or  Well, there are also scanners at the
network level how to save
to identify or violate sites and
web site portals is the whole suite of
craft housecat to search for hashish
identifies passwords etc.
then between scanners there are like
flavors and colors web voucher
then here at this point  of our
talk because we already know that it is a
vulnerability analysis which is the
difference from others to  Analysis what are
the tools that we can use
I insist this is not a conversation for
expert people who already design their
own scripts and go beyond a
test to a test to a reptile that is not
why I have called it gluten because we
We concentrate here on how from my role
as a specialist in
information security I can identify I can
do vulnerability analysis it is worth
here
in time the time at the end and more
with me with my internet topic because
nothing to do a desktop test
where we do a
vulnerability analysis to a target
mounting is not a laboratory to see
what results it gives if they have not yet
had access to identify or have a
report a vulnerability analysis
this is one there are many thousands here I
bring two specific
of what is the  vulnerability scan
report
here also important one in the
tool in the engine that is
doing the vulnerability scan
can configure  rar can
say to adapt it to the needs
that one requires and not leave it by
default because by default it also
produces results by default so the
more personalized the scanner is
the objective, as the better the
results we can obtain, that is to say
give it a level  not so basic to the
scanner because sometimes you don't even
do that because it turns on,
the scanner service gets up, run read like ave
x and pe and the result is already nice to see
that this is not about then,
well here to see what here it comes  The
second part of the talk and it is
where you want to take them and that is what I do
with this vulnerability analysis,
what is being delivered is fine or I can
improve those results
then of course the
result shows what is or what is the
severity of 15  of the vulnerabilities
that I am finding in front of the target or
the targets here one can scan an
IP or a segment of ips or different ips
randomly what  and I want them to be in
different places,
let's say summarize the same uniforms,
customize as much as you want in
the scanner.
Okay, then what happens here? Let's
say you found the result of
this example is that there are 63
vulnerabilities and that it weighs 63 because
averaging there is a level risk
3.0 that here gives being here also
copied the table and then of course
each vulnerability scanner will
have measurements and criteria
for which it is high low critical
medium true there are some that align with
the cb of as vulnerabilities as
vulnerabilities of  the aniseed there are others
that there are no results entering you
cannot see ok
according to cb 3
this vulnerability is critical because
I am going to show you what
that methodology is or think is that
anyone who does this can do it, they
can go there  and revalidate whether
or not these vulnerabilities are in that state or not,
and well, here there are flavors and colors, they
are located graphically.  Actually, the
report is spectacular so that we do not
tell ourselves lies, it is spectacular, but
that is really, look at the level of
security that the audited systems have. It
is another matter. It is also true.
There is a high medium low or
informational vulnerabilities
here I do not stop to define what it is
to you because it is medium that is low because
if you are curious because as I tell you,
each engine that does this type of
analysis has different
criteria parameterized and it is  here the crux of the matter is
true this is one of acne tics
says that it is one sometimes they classify
casualties as casualties and one goes to review the
service and you can have a medium level
because an exploit can be designed for
that specific service and in the end
would raise that ranking
these are the results and this is what
is generally presented to people who
request
the analysis or that if one commits this
access p  ues good because it leaves a lot to
say then then well here
I bring you
I believe that cbs is well known to everyone
and as vulnerabilities
consists of version 3.1 and 3.2 now well
let's say in this the improved version
where it then evaluates what happens one
When it already obtains
these results and as a good security analyst,
it goes and says today it turns out that
I did not know 60 vulnerabilities
that of some are critical so if
the tool does not have it configured if
in its operation, then the ideal
would be to catch those vulnerabilities  and
evaluate on what the entity is known
the context the moment if
really that value that is being given
to the vulnerability is treatable or not and
why I say this because what is going to
happen after you deliver the
report is you that  do it or the
company that does it, the entity is going to
say ok about that I am left with the
criticisms that are the ones that matter to me are
the ones that cause me the most  Laughing the averages and
the casualties, he left them for later, he cited
because technology cannot because I
do not have people who love me and that and there
is the management of vulnerabilities
and I insist on this from a
business vision then if we deliver
a product where we say that  A
vulnerability is low by the scanner
but if we do it and give it a
value of the real criticality as it
can change that vision can change and of
course it can change those actions that
are taken against what we are
identifying
then well here in your word train
open you can find the danish
simply adapt it the
copyright all still on the side of the anise of the cbs
s there you can find this
information and then it is how one
should reevaluate recategorize those
vulnerabilities that are finding
hear there is a score from no impact
none of  criticality This is based on the
probability of exploitation and the impact
that it is possible that this
vuln  reliability could be
exploited and what would be the impact of it
being exploited then, as they are evaluated,
let's say in a range that starts from
0 to 10, where since 0 does not have
or 0 chicks since 0 risk is
probability of exploitation decreased from  0 to
3 9 and sorry from 0 1 to 3 9 medium from 4 to 6
higher than 7 8 9 and critical because 9 and 10
then this is a calculator there
you will find the
super calculator is super beautiful one just
takes the  parameters that it requires
to model its vulnerability
according to the target that it is analyzing
and evaluates it in three very
important components the base the temporality and the
environment then the base is what this
vulnerability has represented then
what is the vector of act that if it is a
through the network or if through the network
you have to reach another tary of
escalation of privileges and the attack itself to
exploit that vulnerability, the
complexity of the attack may be medium
if you do not  You need a user or your
user needs
first if it requires an
administrator user or if it requires
interaction with a user what is the
scope of confidentiality, integrity and
availability if you are affecting
for example if it is a
cryptography vulnerability because you identified it in the
use of the certificate  Sure, then the
vulnerability can be focused on the
denial of service due to the use of
x components, then
we must be affecting the confidentiality,
the integrity, the availability, if the
vulnerability concerns an attack or that, well,
it would be the availability
according to then there is one, select the
type of vulnerability or the type of
scope that the girl is vulnerable to
temporary status to today then to today
July 8 there is an exploit published there is
an exploit ok is explorer is published it
is within your reach you can design
a script to upload a pay  what
you already have previously created from
another
and that
already ex  They have remediation, that is,
the supplier, the owner, the manufacturer
may have already taken as happened with a good face and
eternal button of terna blood on the wind, it
is from the patch that
the remediation is already published after that if
I do why not and then  If it affects
confidentiality and there you will
find some attributes that you
simply select and it will
calculate
and the environment here this dimension of the
environment is what that target means
for the organization then you may
be analyzing the portal of the
intranet where the
internal communications of the
officials are shared to see that if
the criticality of that asset falls soon as
it is not high truth then it will
reduce that impact because it is a
park that is internal that only
shares information that is not  sensitive type
then there we will evaluate
which is the attack vector the same
attributes that we saw previously but
this is based on the  environment where it
is stopped because that target is not the
same as the transaction center was evaluated the
transaction portal of
the correct entity
what are the security
requirements availability requirements and the
same attributes that you select but in
this environment in this in this  dimension
based on the inter at the end of this
exercise that will happen that will give you
a score that may be very different from the
score that I have is the dawn channel of
skills and here you are already
giving a value to your work because  you are
trying to identify if that
vulnerability can be exploitable
and well it is important to also clarify
that there is a life cycle of
vulnerabilities and this is not only
about going to break to scan and that's it,
my task is over, not this as always like
me  Then it always has a cycle and the
vulnerability does not end when I
identified it, the vulnerability ends
when I remedy it, I put it in
production and I go back and test for it.  This
is what it is about,
as a security analyst, it makes you
laugh that technology tells you, `` Listen now,
patch and dance.
They were effective so here it already
happens and sometimes it also happens I tell you that is
why I put it as from gluten
because sometimes the same people who
identify in which patch or it may be
that the security area is
identifying and they vote the ball to the
area  of technology or the technology agent
who is here watching this
talk and says hey if that happens to me or it
happens to the company I work for or
when I started to work and when I am in
this environment, it will happen to me because
this  It is something that has happened in time
and today it is identifying itself more, it
is the same speed with which it
identified, it will be the same speed with
which it left, because what happens, what is the
use of the client once, you
have 125 thousand  vulnerabilities sorry
because of those 125 I am only going to patch 10
immediately because I can because it does not imply me to
change the version of the server
upload the current version of the database of the
database engine in 3
I can then I bring this here
this morning because it is  something like that when
one from blood index came out
patching vulnerabilities I want to
reach 100% you can as if I am going
up the mountain and I already see the
peak and I think I am five
mountains behind and I am almost going to get
what is going to  arrive and in the end it is not
remedying, that is, all this you are
doing I am throwing it away
there is a very interesting report
he felt the institute where they made
one is still close to the process
of vulnerability analysis and he says
that almost 25 percent  One hundred of the
vulnerabilities remain open
throughout the year, sometimes it
becomes a quit that you identify in a
first scan and then you re-launch
the retest on f  beautiful rita is that one
sometimes also as
law service providers say how it was
added is going to give you a tweet is because
I know that you will not be able to patch that in
six months
well
that is the modus operandi of these
analyzes and then  the average time of
repair or remediation of
vulnerabilities is a minimum of 100 days and
this becomes something that tells us
where the management of
vulnerabilities is in all
capacities and not to decentralize in
identifying those vulnerabilities but
in remediating the clear ones  that if
we just stop to
identify them, well, now
the problem is for blooming
when it has to look at what to do with
those security gaps that
identified it, then there is
more detail about that study that is not a
lie and in  the reality of what happens
in the industry there I also leave the
reference
but then here it is not about
generating alerts do not panic
without  However, know that how is the
movement, how is the modus operandi such
as the management, since I bring you and
small sections of that report that
are very interesting, so there it says,
for example, that the average time
measured for remediation of
vulnerabilities when they are identified
that  they are for microsoft operating systems it
is 15 times shorter for those
of oracle ibm hewlett packard
because well you know that microsoft
every Tuesday every Tuesday publishes
security patches for all its
systems
for all operating systems so
that may be one reason  It may be
other than the one that is very curious not because
one is going to see that management
of the remediation implementation and the
most patched are those of Windows 1 because
because Microsoft has strategies to
publish patches and that they disappear every Tuesday
and another is because  is to
remedy read them not you are a bit
for people or if to be more specialized
not all exams systems
operate  tives windows and windows and
depending on the flavor of windows
it is also not so easy it is not so easy to
patch
well here I do not stop because I think
we are running out of time
so
I leave these s
for example most
companies are not  They can or can barely
keep up with the rate of exploitation of
vulnerability and sorry
and if here we have to reflect on something if this
is the case for vulnerabilities that
are already published that already exploits
around the free access internet
as they will be even more so for
vulnerabilities it should still be
Sometimes it may be because it receives an alert
from the government sensor because I received
an alert from miso that begins to
remedy faster but it does not always pass
mind
and health entities
take less time five times,
let's say five times more  slow to
remedy because it will be good if
I leave them for your reflection.
Today today there are already solutions and
computer controls that allow us to  They allow us to
patch a little faster
and get rid of this problem that we are
identifying when we already have the
hot potato, the pot is burning,
the soup is spreading and I don't know what to
do with all these vulnerabilities,
so here comes the evaluation of
those capacities.  in the people that I have
in the tools that I have and
solutions that the industry has created
to leave appear to make our
heads not hurt and it is hear patch aip virtual file
the famous the famous virtual martín one
of those that I think is very
interesting is the trend micro which is
called deep security where you
go to islands, the operating system
that is usually vulnerable are the
policies and some indicators of
compromise that can be
involved and you leave it with isolated hear
this I'm not  happening I am not applying
because I can not upload the
operating system but I have it to customize I
have it protected I am identifying
threats because also  It is used to
identify threats to that
operating system and in a certain way I have
a protection measure and
my level of risk is reduced, so there
was a level of risk, the
inherent risk when applying the
vulnerability is reduced and I already have
a risk that the entity is
accepting if I am from the 2nd from the
computer security team of
technological assurance
any of the areas and flavors that
you call those who do
gluten activities
then here apart from these
tools there may be others I
do not know that because there are also
strategies  To address this issue of
vulnerabilities, which are what
brigades brigades of party brigades can do, for example
, and where
all changes are uploaded in a
controlled environment
and therefore the time in which the
vulnerability is open is reduced because one
thing is vulnerability  that I just
found for my unified system and
another like that can  become an
attack vector reaching through
other components of the network etc
then here are a series of
alternatives to what I say
migrate brigades walk brigades hire
external people who sell the
rapier patch that may be at risk and
scan with  people are good etc.
that there are some capacities that I put and
that are extracted from the guide
the enterprise sports management
technologies of the anise there is also
a compendium of information that can
be very useful if you are if you
are the leader of security and  that you have to
go or if you are the penta estero, the
security analyst that you have to
remedy because he tells her how
life has already provided us with people who have
done what we are doing
because they are not going to invent the wheel for me.
to read what they have done so they
can find it
and well
after all this he has already told you about
the challenge is to do the same is to try
to create the same script  enario with which it
was tested once again to create
that same scenario you will see what results it
produces by creating that it is proven that
almost 70% or 50 come out again or
the same vulnerabilities appear
and well with this I am ending our
small space  With this topic, I
thought it was important to share and take away
the focus a bit from what
with a vulnerability analysis
we can be, we can
really identify the level of risk,
we may fall short or not, you
will already draw your own conclusions and how to
avoid that simple how to avoid  that
the fat button application
becomes a problem for me and
they do not really value my
knowledge and my title of security analyst
here this is a vision for the
people behind the
renting teams which indicators  It could not
be because this is another issue that one
finds a lot in companies
if they have indicators that measure
the management of the  s vulnerabilities and
it is always in the red because they can never
comply because they say I am going to patch in
15 days the criticisms in a month the
average ones and in six months the high ones and they
are never complying because their capabilities
and their strategies do not work, so you have
to formulate a  framework that
allows to follow a methodology true
because this is not only going to launch the
scanner this is a methodology
identified reported treated the
vulnerability the remedy I make a catch
and return identified test etc. It is
a life cycle of the management of
vulnerabilities how  You can identify
if this process is really being
effective with measurements that tell
me the reality is that my indicator is always in
red when I have to
comply especially
with regulatory agent results to the
superintendencies who is
monitoring the business because  well here are
some that are also published in the
my 1840 in revision 3a you can already
find this  to the bibliography
where they tell you how often
the games are checked looking for the
missing updates this is another
tweet of the matter it turns out that they go and launch
the vulnerability scanners children
of the mz another server on the plateau sees
another a printer what do I know about the  of the
month etc and then it says so because I do not
mix the targets we mix locations
and to her I think I am at a
risk level and that is a mistake that is a mistake
because you can be so good that
you choose the one who is vulnerable or
So bad that I chose to be that it is well
organized and that it is a critical asset,
so sometimes segmenting those
targets can also become a problem
and can skew the results of the level
of risk,
although asset inventories are frequently used.
What was I telling you at the beginning if
I have, I don't even know what I have in my network
connected and I don't know that it is live or that
this type of indicator
is not, what is the time?  or minimum average maximum in
applying patches to another another
important issue here is that sometimes
change management processes tend to
hinder from deployments
to patches so I can't patch
this until the following Tuesday when
there is a change committee and  It supports me in
the transition to production because I already tried it,
tests and then I will increase the
production but that is only approved
once a month and then until the next
month well or in December or the end
of the month when the operation is at full
or  I am closing the year in accounting or
etc. whatever the scenario
I cannot then I have three or
four months left the vulnerabilities are
identified and I do nothing
these are all real life cases
I am not inventing anything and if you
have had the opportunity  If you participate,
you may be reflecting on
this that I have come to share with you
that more than the average, what percentage
of Jose are complementary  being patched
at what time what percentage of patches
are applied what cost savings has been
achieved how important this is to at the
end
and show top management at the bar
bording and what is the return on
investment they are getting if I'm
doing this guy  of exercises so
that later they do not apply to me, do
not authorize me only a
vulnerability analysis but some
reptile tests where I do not give anything and look at
how they enter, or in the end everything is a
cost-benefit balance and like me
I can implement these types of
exercises so that it gives me a
holistic view of the risk level of my
organization
and finally, what percentage of the
budget of the information system
of the agencies the entities dedicate
the patch management if I have money
to patch or not  if not good then take
the risk and
but it is a prayer and saw the
sky attached so that nothing happens to them
and finally with some conclusions
that were left to them  to their conclusion and
for their review so they can think about whether to
really do an analysis if it is
really only a game vulnerability scan should be done
to the
most critical assets or not if it should be
done to all the assets of the
organization or  If again, do a
vulnerability analysis and focus
on doing another type of test and especially
here I was missing one if I am doing a
fat button vulnerability analysis I am giving an added value to
what by scope is a generality analysis
and  Well with this ended, thank you very much
for your attention and I hope that some of
what I have shown you and will serve you for
your daily life
[Music]
Natalia
and
we gave you this creation, you can already hear it and
yes, thank you very much lady for this
fantastic detailed presentation.
It is very clear that the analysis of
a disability is by far of what
example that very applied interesting is
fantastic
thanks to questions from us
anti slap and he wants to know what
are the weaknesses or errors at the
infrastructure level that you have found in
the vulnerability analysis authorship
that you have carried out
well here undoubtedly
always always are
unattended open ports where one can
find rdp connections or
open ports  For connections to rpp,
other tests that we have carried out and that
we have found to be very common and that
is when one is directly auditing
targets such as active directory, their chip,
especially active directors and tests
the vulnerabilities or tests the
exploits or simply testing if it is
vulnerable  or not from that version of smb to the
exploit that is published and from
just checking it, all
the users who are published in the
policies appear then to summarize they
are always bad configurations that are made
from the and sarney some due to
ignorance others due to carelessness but
in the  most is lack of organization
exce  Cascade of grace lens, thank you for
your presentation for having you here,
said noor with all the experience and
the public, although it is well, thank you very
much
yes
good here
[Music]
and
yes
[  Music]
[Music]