uh good morning everyone hopefully
you're all hyped up on uh mountain dew
or coffee or whatever it is that keeps
you going in the morning um
my name is david floss i'm here to talk
to you about powershell
a little bit about myself real quick
though i am the uh offensive security
lead for echelon cyber and risk
basically what that means is any of our
emulation of criminal activity like red
teaming pen testing web app testing i
run our company's
section for that
i come from a red team background in the
private sector and then prior to that i
was in a special operations unit for
cyber
so i got to do this stuff for for fun
i have my linkedin up here in case you
guys want to come check me out i post
red team and pen test
tips every week
especially for october since it is cyber
security month
and then i do have a twitter it's at the
beach loss but uh all i do is post memes
there so if that's what you're looking
for that's available there
uh and just because we're a small
company i want to shout out
our company real quick we are a
consulting firm in cyber security that
does defensive offensive and advisory
work
but past that doesn't really uh not too
important
so what's today's goal today i want you
guys to walk away with like this healthy
dose of paranoia when it comes down to
powershell
i think it's pretty important
considering the fact that over the
course of the the last couple years
we've kind of gone away from paying
attention to
powershell as a whole
as everyone started moving over to
c-sharp for their malicious binaries
so how are we going to do that
well first we're going to talk about
like why i.t admins love it and why
attackers love it kind of set the stage
right
and then we're gonna go into bypassing
controls some of those are organic like
science script execution amsi and white
listing some of them are are not so
organic um like uh an edr's enumeration
alerts
then we're going to wrap it up with some
malware deployment
and
a few tips on how you can protect
yourself
let's jump into it
so why do admins love it
quite simply it's everywhere right it's
on windows linux mac i've had it on my
my mac machine i've had it on my linux
administration machines it's perfect it
has a really wide market share
and it and it works across the board
it's easy to use and learn this is
actually one of the first applications
or programming languages i've i learned
or scripting language i guess in this
case
even before
even for python
and lastly it enables more functions
around remote administration
i originally started my career as an i.t
admin
um and powershell was taking functions
that would normally take hours down to
just a couple minutes to run
so why do attackers love it well frankly
it's everywhere right windows linux mac
you can put it on your kali linux
machine and
just negate the need for impact to
interface with a windows machine
easy to use and learn everyone likes to
bash on microsoft so there's a ton of
resources out there for offensive
security
uh powershell
scripting right
and then it enables more functions
around remote administration
quite frankly when you look at it this
way it really shows that the attackers
have an advantage
um i think what a lot of people just
don't seem to realize is that if you
gain access to powershell
you can
just run scripts from memory you can
copy paste into the terminal
uh you can import it via
netweb requests there there is actually
no need for
scripts uh like mimikats from powershell
or power view or any of that stuff to be
on disk so it makes it very difficult
for like signature based avs
to detect this kind of activity
additionally it's scriptable.net so this
is the reason why we saw a lot of people
go from powershell over to c sharp
because it's basically the same thing
and we'll get more into that later and
then again organic security functions
are always getting defeated people just
love to on microsoft for some
reason
so they they find new ways of doing it
um quite frankly
like in about 95 of my engagements when
i was still running as a red teamer
powershell was the
the the major factor in how we gained
code execution or privilege escalation
lateral movement
just by it being there you open up a lot
of avenues for attack from an attack
from a threat actor
so let's jump into some of the cool
stuff now that we've kind of set the
stage
the first one is kind of it's going to
make some some of you attackers out
there uh roll your eyes and that is a
sign script execution and the reason why
the attackers are rolling their eyes
right now is because this is not a
security control
uh but i bring it up here because
a lot of my clients believe this is
security control and if you read the
documentation from microsoft they write
it as it's a securing control for those
who don't know
script signing execution
is just a policy that's placed into
powershell that
will force the the scripts that you're
running to be signed or unsigned or
self-signed right
um
and the reason why people think this is
a security control in itself is that
when you try to set execution policy
which we can see in the screenshot
uh to bypass it actually says nah you
can't do that right especially if you're
a low privileged user
but the reason why this isn't like
uh
security control is is this right here
uh it's quite simply easy to bypass by
just executing powershell with the flag
ep or execution policy and then bypass
and then you have a nice little
uh bypass terminal
and something to note though is that is
only for this terminal right um when
you're doing the uh code execution of
set execution policy within powershell
you're trying to change a registry key
in the htlm uh hive
but when you just run powershell exe
tech ep bypass then you're
just setting it for that that one time
terminal so if you close out a
powershell it won't affect any other
terminal on the system
but it helps um
again i just wanted to throw this out
because it's really important uh don't
treat this as a security control or stop
trading as security control
uh and that brings us into the cool
stuff and this is going to be what a
majority of the talk is going to be
about which is bypassing amsi
so amsi or i what i call amsi
for short is the anti-malware scan
interface it is a
known
known good hook into
powershell and other scripting
languages within
microsoft for security products to use
so they can monitor
execution and like office macros windows
script host things like that
in powershell itself it it additionally
will
try to block malicious scripts and
functions so
the iex new object download string which
is probably the most commonly used
command to import malicious scripts into
your network
is just flat out blocked like amzi goes
nah this this is too dangerous
additionally
strings like mimikats bloodhound power
view even itself amsi utils is
considered malicious in its eyes and
it'll block you from being able to
execute if it sees those strings
so it's it's kind of nice um
some known integrated antivirus
applications here like mcafee sofas
kaspersky windows defender kind of a duh
there there's probably more i really
didn't dig too deep into it uh to be
honest with you uh but these are the
ones that are openly admitting that they
use amzie as part of their tool
so
here comes another really fun easy
bypass
powershell 2.0
for those who don't know powershell 2.0
is installed by default and
even the newest versions of windows 10.
and it has absolutely zero security
functions uh which is why when you look
at like matt graber's power view or
other windows enumeration scripts
they'll usually try to downgrade to
powershell version 2.0 really quickly or
right off the bat because then you don't
have to worry about any of the security
controls or script lock logging and
things like that
though to caveat all that
dotnet2.net version 2.0 is required for
powershell 2.0 to execute uh which
doesn't come by default but if you're
running old applications that require
like.net 3.5 then net 2.0 is
is bundled with that for some odd reason
uh which is kind of weird but this is
really easy to downgrade to
in fact all it takes is a quick little
screenshot i don't even have to show you
a demo of what's going on um and the
first command up at the top we're
running ps version table to show you
that we're running uh powershell version
5.1 and then we're trying to echo ams
utils this is like a test that we as
attackers will use to see if amzi is
still working
uh and you can see that it doesn't like
itself being called so it goes and
blocks it but then you can just call
powershell.exe tech version 2 and then
oh cool now you can echo amazing utils
right so stupid simple and is actually
like very widely used
and is still widely available because
most um
most people don't realize that it's just
sitting there
right so
what can we do
if powershell version 2.0 isn't
available we need to find some way of
crashing it right
so this comes to the fun part of
where we're going to get to and why i
think powershell is still so dangerous
and when we left it
or stopped paying attention to it it
just
kept working or our attacks kept working
so when we want to defeat amzee what
we're trying to do is put amstee into a
failed state the reason being is is amzi
doesn't have a self-recovery function
meaning if you somehow set it to crash
and you get the field amsy and it failed
to set to true
uh it'll just stop working it doesn't
try to reload itself which is cool uh
for attackers it's really bad for
defenders right
so back in 2016 matt graber the genius
of powershell found that you could use
reflection to just call the mz and it
failed field and set that to true
and this is the reason why amsi utils is
actually a band uh string within amsi uh
thanks to mac raber
and this was fixed relatively quickly uh
the problem is is
this line below it where you have the
concatenated strings of amazing utils
and amazing and it failed well that
worked all the way up until 2020.
um i was using that on most of my red
teams up until last year right
that's kind of scary because they state
in their documentation that amz does
concatenate um before code execution
which just wasn't true but this is
actually a really good use case into
showing you guys that microsoft really
didn't fix the issue they just kind of
pushed it to the side
um
we're going to stop through that real
quick right so the first thing that we
needed to do here was figure out
does
or have our we need to set the static
right so we need to call amsetils and
make sure okay yeah it is blocking it
uh and then we needed to see does
concatenation still work right so can we
call amsa utils with a concatenated out
and we can
so that begs the question all right how
deep down the rabbit hole do we need to
go before microsoft says this is
malicious
um
so
the next thing we need to do is figure
out okay can we just call
the field can we call amzee and it
failed
and it turns out you still can
you can you can concatenate it and as
you can see in the screenshot below we
do get all the information from amazing
it failed
so something weird is going on that
isn't as straightforward as as most
attackers would think
well what it turns out is and thanks to
secure this for writing up a great
write-up on on what's going on here
but when you
uh
call a field and then you set the value
um
ramsey does a little bit of regex from
that and then goes okay i see a few
things that are that are matching up i'm
going to concatenate the strings within
the
the get type and get field and if they
equal a malicious string then i'm going
to obviously block it
so it's kind of cool because now they're
now they're thinking okay maybe if we do
some rejects we can we can catch this
stuff
uh the problem is is amzee this still
sucks
um my number one rule when when
defeating
just about anything in powershell is
when in doubt encode it out
uh i would avoid base64 as a whole
because it is a organic command
structure within
uh powershell but what you can do is
format to hex
and so in the two screenshots below what
you're seeing here is the concatenation
of the mzutils formatted into
hex on an encoding of uta utf-8 and we
can print it we get our nice little hex
code over here to the left
and then when we do the same thing for
mz and it failed
we get this nice little hex code again
so
from there we have to create a one-liner
to figure out how to turn our hex back
into text right because we already have
our text in the hex so you're gonna
sweet little like dr seuss rhyme there
as well so the one liner is quite simple
all we have to do is split each
individual character and then convert it
back into
a um
well a character right we take the hex
code and we split it into a characters
push that into a result field in that
result field then prints mzutils
so what does that look like quite simply
it's using matt graper's method with
uh
with hex
so the first thing we print out
zamasutil will show you that it is
functioning mg is functioning we print
in our
macgraber method with our hex code and
our single line for
breaking apart or breaking back into
text for both amz utils and amsi and it
failed
setting that value to true and now we
can call amzi showing that amsi has been
defeated using this method
so this 2016 method really still hasn't
been fixed
right
and uh
i i can tell you this is probably one of
my more favorite ways of showing clients
that they uh
they're not as secure as they think they
are just because they have some organic
controls
the next piece and i wouldn't worry
about writing any of this down uh is the
rasta mouth method mouse method oh it's
a tongue twister
the the reason why i wanted to call this
one out in particular is because this is
kind of an interesting way of doing it
uh rossa mouth actually found that you
could patch the loaded dll
and that's kind of scary for people who
are attackers because or even even those
who run edrs
because if you're able to patch the
loaded dll you could possibly unhook the
dll um
and and load in something that's that's
clean from from your edr from kernel 32
or ntdl232 right
and this is just c sharp code that's
running in powershell
the only caveat i would say is when you
run this kind of code is if you're an
attacker don't use ad type because ad
type leaves a temporary
dll on disk and it's an artifact so you
can
get caught from that
but basically all this is doing is
loading in the amz dll it's finding the
scan buffer library and then it's
overriding the first couple bytes
and the reason being
is when amsi calls itself in amsi scan
buffer and z context amazing it failed
it always looks for the
first uh first couple bytes that are
static
and those static bytes uh
translate to like amsi so it's just
looking for like the first four letters
of its name and if it doesn't see that
then he goes oh i'm corrupted set it to
failed
and you're good to go
so this is a relatively old method as
well i didn't do any obfuscation on this
one and as we can see mzutils is running
i'll eventually copy and paste it in
nothing's coming up from amsi we're able
to load in our our c sharp code and
call amse again
right so this is a really
relatively old method as well that just
still works right out of the box the
nothing has really changed in this way
of doing things
the only only difference is i think if
you ever saw this in the wild it would
be
i am scroll wheeling um
all right i totally screwed that up give
me a second there we go
uh the only thing i would say if you saw
this in the wild it would be
done using like matt graber's method or
the offensive security method for
loading in
dll imports so it would be reflectively
loaded in so you're not putting anything
on disk
but for the most part this this
technique still
works
right
there is one other one that i kind of
want to go over real quick and
hopefully you guys can still see my
screen
but it's the
offensive security method
which is
right here
and the reason why i like the offensive
security method a lot is
this particular method um
reflectively gathers all the assembly
types that are loaded into
powershell and then it uses wildcards
cards unlike iutels and context to find
the address and then overwrite the
address of amsi contact so
if we just type in
mgutils again show that it is blocked
and copy in our script again it's going
to allow us to print it
but
what i think is kind of cool here is we
can actually kind of
go out and look at each individual
section so when we type in gather we can
see all of the loaded function types or
assembly types that are loaded in
and
maybe i just cancel it there we go
yep
and we can kind of step down and see
like
where each piece of this is going
so when we pull up delta we can actually
pull up all the functions within the mz
uh the mz dll mzcontext mz session mz
and it failed
amazing lock object and what i think is
super cool about this is we can actually
pull
the address for amsi context
right so if we pull up context here we
can oh actually it's going to pull up
the wrong thing
but
adder will work in the same way so when
we call the address variable here we can
actually see the memory address that
it's dynamically loaded into and that's
what we're copying over using.net
because net is available to us in
powershell
this is a very nice like red teaming
little
eight lines of code because uh
it's very hard to detect
and and see
um at least i i haven't been caught in
that regard from it
but i just wanted to point that out real
quick before we continue
so what happens when you can't run code
to bypass amz
whether that's through
restricted language mode like restricted
or constrained language mode or app
locker application whitelisting
blacklisting whatever you're trying to
do
well quite simply
powershell is just a bunch of loaded
dlls on top of command prompt it's
that's why it's called powershell right
so you can just quite easily create your
own powershell using living off the line
binaries
or you can be lazy like 90 of us in in
the pen testing and retaining world and
just use this wonderful
program called ms build shell which can
be found at the github and what ms build
shell does is it uses the
net
version 4.0
executable ms
build i think it's ms build
uh to
uh build a cs project file yeah here we
go
so
because.net 4.0 is installed by default
build.exe is also a living off the land
binary it is installed by default
uh the first thing i did here is i wrote
up ps version table so you guys can see
that
it's not running powershell currently
this is just a straight command prompt
but what we can do is we can take this
cs project file which doesn't get
flagged by antivirus programs because
in itself it's not malicious and if they
started flagging on that
kind of activity you would potentially
start flagging on legitimate activity
but very simply all we have to do is hit
enter here
and it builds us a shell the errors that
we see coming up is is the application
trying to disable amsi
um quite simply as the old mackrevers
method you could just edit the lines of
code that are in there and then this
would come up as uh or nothing would
show
but i left it in just so you can see
what it looks like as a default but
now we can run ps version table
and we get a ps version number but when
we look at the top here we're not
running powershell we're running ms
build shell
so
when you look at that from a
perspectival application whitelisting or
blacklisting like this is not going to
get caught
the only functionality that you would
lose inside this terminal would be your
tab functionality that comes with uh
powershell
but i mean that's no big deal
and then i think i just exit out of here
yeah just so you can see it shows us a
build exits uh it doesn't actually leave
anything behind
the only thing that would possibly be
needed on disk is the cs project file or
you could host that at a distant
smb server
and it would still function the same way
there are other ways of doing this i
kind of don't want to get too deep into
it because it would be a little bit more
outside the scope of a powershell but
there are other projects like powershell
dll project
which you can run the many different
living off the land binaries to run a
dll
um
there's my personal favorite which is
the sync app
publishing server
which is a script that's given to you by
default
you can break out of that and and send a
request to a distant server
be that your attacking server and you
can use netcat to capture it
and you'll get a sweep powershell
shell from that
uh if you want to learn more about this
stuff i would definitely check out like
ired.team they have some great write-ups
on
using
powershell without having to use
powershell
and then the last thing on on bypassing
alerts is going to be enumeration alerts
this is this is something that i think
is more red team focused but it is kind
of an interesting way of looking at
things
um edrs have gotten really smart on
being able to detect the heuristics of
an attacker enumerating a dock or a
workstation
and the reason being
is because most people just run like
jaws like which is just another windows
enumeration script or other enumeration
scripts that just call ipconfig who am i
netstat net sh but those are all
applications that are built and listed
in system32 so if you go to system32
you'll see them quite obviously
um
we'll come back to our our powershell
screen here so you can kind of see what
i'm talking about but if we type in who
am i
right we get this nice little
uh callout well
if we don't want to use those system32
executables we can use net from
powershell to build our own
who am i
using environment variables and
net calls so in this case who am i turns
into environment user domain environment
username
and it looks
pretty much the same
with some better capitalization where it
would normally be seen
though when you start doing things like
ipconfig this is nice and neat very cool
to look at uh the.net library for this
doesn't look as pretty what did i screw
up
oh
there we go
so it's not as pretty but it does get
you the information right and you can
use powershell to format out these
strings uh to to make it pretty
you know say you want the os build
version
you can you can pull the os version uh
push the system environment for os
version into a variable and then pull
out
version and build
and now you have the build version of
the application itself
uh and then you know there's some fun
things that if you really want to get
down to it like you can print out which
edr or antivirus system you're using as
long as i didn't screw this up
uh and and format that out
and because windows keeps track of most
of that activity you can just print it
out but this is this is stuff that won't
necessarily get you caught well this
this edr information might because
you're going to call a cmi
cim
uh instance but the other ones are using
system environment variables
and
dot net
basically pretending to be like an
installer
so if you can change up the way that you
call things
you start defeating the way that these
edr products are detecting enumeration
which allows you to live on the machine
for a lot longer
right this is just a screenshot of the
same thing
so we talked about all of that
just to get to malware deployment
um
this is this is the fun stuff
basically with malware execution on
powershell all you have to do is take
your c sharp code and turn it into
powershell code vice versa it's dot net
right
to get basic code execution you need
virtual alec
and create thread from kernel 32 and you
need the marshall service to copy your
shell code into
uh the allocated memory
and then you do still have to do uh some
av avoidance like reflectively calling
your dlls and um a little bit of shell
code obfuscation
just because you're creating a new
thread
so what i think is cool about malware
execution is that if you're using the
mac graber method which i think is the
best for beginners in
pen testing and attacking using
offensive powershell
the top
line of code for where we're importing
kernel 32's virtual alec is from p
invoke
and the one right below it is how we
would import it into macrae's method
it's quite simply the same uh just a
little less information you know you're
still calling out hey i needed to be an
in-pointer or integer pointer i need an
unsigned integer
um all that jazz and then when we want
to call it it's it is pretty much
exactly the same right this is how you
call it in c sharp and this is how you
call in a power shell
very simple straight to the point
another thing that's really brilliant
about powershell is it helps out with
shell code obfuscation
right
and it is still necessary you don't want
to put just like meterpreter shell code
on a um
in a variable and just call it a day
somebody's going to catch that
but powershell reads bytecode as decimal
instead of hex which is
perfect if you like messing around with
numbers i'm not too much of a fan of hex
code and trying to format hex when you
when you start doing uh obfuscation
so
like zero x zero zero becomes zero zero
zero and zero x f becomes two five five
uh and say you to do something simple
like a caesar cipher which is pushing a
byte to the left or to the right in this
case in this example we're pushing the
byte five to the right zero zero zero
becomes zero zero five two five five
becomes 260.
um but because 260 is over
um you know uh by its maximum range
we need to use another function within
powershell which is uh given to us quite
nicely as modulus right it's a
mathematical function and the operator
is the percent sign
so say you're trying to set your offset
um
to to not go over
your 255
you just do 256 minus or plus your
offset and then modulus that by 256.
so then zero zero zero becomes zero zero
five and two two five becomes zero zero
four
very very simple to work with uh
especially when you're doing a caesar
cipher
so what does that all look like
basically what we're going to do here is
we're going to run our
multihandler as a interpreter reverse
https
and we've already
pre-encoded it
with a caesar cipher of
so i'm showing you oh
let me not click the the wrong buttons
here
so what i'm showing you first is that
powershell is running under 11496 just
so you are aware because we're going to
execute within this process and that
amsi is currently running
and we've talked a lot about just
copying and pasting things into
a terminal if you have access but
say it's like a ton of code you don't
want to just sit there and wait forever
what you can do is use dotnet web
request
to create a new rubric new web request
and read that into a variable
so if there are any people out there
that want to utilize this code
please do it's quite fun um
it functions just like how internet
explorer would
minus
uh you're not
reading into a variable on internet
explorer
but the cool thing here is once we have
it into a variable we can just execute
that variable
with iex content
so we're not directly writing it into
the
powershell application at first
then we're going to call invoke b size
because let's say the
function that i called it give it a
supplied offset of 66.
one thing to note here is that there is
an antivirus running nothing has popped
up
and we can call back and we see that
there's a session running
the uid the paid 11496 the uid is the
low priv user that we've been using for
all this time
and i think that wraps that part up yeah
i have a much longer explanation of of
this code too uh that we'll be releasing
a little bit later
just in this case the time limit kind of
constrain this
so
now that you're hopefully a little bit
paranoid like what can you do how can
you fix some of these things
quite simply like my number one thing is
always to disable powershell uh you
wouldn't give your users python so why
would you give them powershell
i get this doesn't work for everyone but
what people seem to forget uh is that
gpos do allow you to
apply like these application
blacklisting or whitelisting to specific
ou's so your administrators can still
use powershell i would just limit it for
the the users
also look at expanding your application
blacklisting you know not everything
microsoft provides you is safe uh dde
auto is a prime example of this
definitely use some ai based security
products because they are going to hook
into kernel 32 and to
ntdl and like i had mentioned like
sure you might be able to unhook it
within powershell but with a better ai
based security product it is going to be
able to detect when a sensor is being
bypassed and alerts you on that activity
and then last
but not least
and this is less for the people in the
room but microsoft kind of has to fix
their stuff right i can't say it's just
a feature anymore there is a lot of
issues and and
vulnerabilities within powershell that
have been functioning since its release
and because we've started to focus more
on c-sharp binaries and
other attack vectors
people just forgot that powershell
existed
and
they left it at oh we have constrained
language mode or we have script signing
execution or we have amz
right
they forget that this is the majority of
the way that attackers get into your
network and stay here
fileless malware attacks utilize
powershell yeah it might be through your
registry but it's still calling
powershell
so any ways that we can start refocusing
on these
attack factors using the application
would be beneficial to the security
community as a whole
so that's my talk
here's my information again for anybody
who wants to jot it down or wants to
download these slides from from our web
page