all right
well i hope everybody has been enjoying
um
this b-side that's
had a lot of really good talks
mark had a good conversation good talk
about the cmmc protocol which goes right
along with with where i'm going to and
then stephen kirby talked about pci dss
which is one of the most common
frameworks that covers most businesses
but sometimes when it comes down to this
people just kind of wonder where does it
all start from where do we go so let's
talk about grc and what grc is grc
stands for governance risk and
compliance
governance addresses how you make what's
your plan how's your business going to
be set up how's it going to work what's
going to happen if you have a disaster
or for instance a ransomware attack
governance would be where you would
determine how you're going to handle
your business then you get into risk and
that's looking at what are the threats
what's what's your issues what are your
problems what are things that we need to
deal with and those will vary from
industry to industry and then finally
compliance and compliance is one of the
areas that is the most changing in our
industry because as you can see it's
based upon laws regulations standards
it's things that are changing and
constantly being modified and updated so
grc well it seems like this kind of a
little nutshell
it really has a lot of complexity to it
and when you look at this graphic
you'll see there's different pieces to
grc and each one of these pieces kind of
blends into the next one and so you know
for instance if you're doing audits
those audits are going to bring about a
strategy management what am i going to
do what the audit findings what am i
going to do but it's also going to bring
about what are the controls i'm going to
bring into place to make myself
compliant for the next audit
so
why do grc first of all
most businesses are or will be needing
to meet some type of compliance
you go down to the mall even though they
may be there at that little
vendor in the middle and they're selling
their credit card stuff
if something happened and that person
was found out to be storing all the
credit card data they would be out of
compliance and they would now face the
laws and the penalties of the law for
keeping that data and not securing it
and then you get into the larger
corporations and for many of the
corporations in order to do business
with the people that they do business
with they've got certain compliancy
requirements that they have to meet
you also have it's not a one-time event
so when i go in and write a compliance
document and i say okay i've evaluated
my business i've looked at what's going
on in my business and i've set out all
my plans and i've written them all up
i'm not done now i need to go back and
look at each one of these documents
again i need to start over and reassess
where am i at where has what has changed
what's come up you know ransomware
malware spam fishing all of that stuff
is continually evolving and so our
compliance is going to be changing to
keep up with that
mitigation becomes more and more
difficult if you don't have a standard
you know
a lot of people go into the industry and
they just kind of focus in their one
place and they don't think about the
fact that that little piece of the
industry that they're working in
is doing what it's doing because there's
a standard some of you are greenville
tech students there's a standard in
order to complete the class and that
class sets up that standard and if you
don't want to comply with it you're not
going to be successful in completing the
class well businesses are exactly the
same way
but the nasty part for businesses is
they're not the ones necessarily who are
creating the requirements it's it's the
bad guys it's the people who are trying
to get into their system that are going
to have to affect enforce
how that business is going to react and
how they're going to respond to those
risks and that mitigation and that's
what compliance is all about is looking
at that changing landscape and
determining how am i going to deal with
it what what am i going to do to deal
with these risks and finally it's an
open job market on the 31st of september
i did just a quick
search in zip recruiter under grc and as
you can see almost 6 000 jobs were
listed out there under grc on zip
recruiter with a salary ranging between
102 and 171 000.
you know it's an open industry we have
so many requirements coming by if you
listen to mark's uh presentation on this
channel the first presentation on cmmc
that's a a new standard that everybody
is talking about becoming compliant for
especially if you want to do anything
with
purchasing or connecting your business
into the federal market
you're going to have to be cmmc report
compliant but cmmc compliance is still
still changing and still molding and so
getting into these jobs are going to be
a little bit easier now than it will be
later but there's going to be a growing
number of jobs needed to be able to fill
these compliance spots for the gr for
the cmmc
so where do you start
you know for a lot of people
they don't know what to do i want to
kind of do grc but it can be a daunting
task i remember with the university when
i started my job in 2018
while we were doing many of the things
that made us compliant and would show us
to be compliant
we didn't have
didn't have any idea where we were going
well we had the privilege that the
federal government came to us and said
you're going to need to be compliant to
this 800-171
so i didn't have to go search and find
the standard steven just gave a great
presentation on using pci dss
as a data standard just replace
credit card information with secure
information and you have a compliance
standard you have a place to start from
so the beginning of where to start is
find a standard
then determine what industries will be
need to be covered by that standard you
know sometimes we do it the other way
you're interested in a specific industry
and so you'll go look for the standards
that meet the industry but you can do it
backwards you can look at the standards
and say you know i'm kind of interested
in this standard this standard kind of
keeps my attention i see where i could
kind of fit into this market
and then you'll find the industries
that'll be covered but you can go either
way either either way we'll keep
everything flowing just the way we want
it to
then gather the information
attend b-side events attend training
events you get on youtube you can find
all kinds of information on youtube
about hey here's the standard here's
what's going on in the standard here's
how to be compliant in the standard now
of course
you have to be careful you can also find
information out on youtube that's not
going to lead you in the right direction
so
gather information see what goes on with
the industry see what goes on in that
compliance standard and what are you
going to do
and finally
maybe the place to start is with people
you currently work for
there's a lot of companies out there
that
while they in practice
are compliant with standards
they really don't have the paperwork
because when it comes down to grc
much of the grc work
is the paperwork it's the creation of
the documents that say here's what our
standards are going to be it's the
documents that say hey here's how we've
got our network configured or here's how
we've got our information secured or
here's the practices for account
creation and how we determine what a
user can or can't do on our network
because when it comes down to the
standards
the reviewers will look and see what
you're doing but they're also going to
see what you have in writing and when
you're dealing with the federal
government which i have to in my case if
i don't have it in writing as far as the
federal government is concerned
it's not going on it's not happening and
so many times you can be working for
somebody and they just need somebody to
help with the paperwork they need
somebody to help with the reviews so
sometimes the place to start is to go to
your employer find out what they're
doing and find out if they need
assistance in this
finally you can look at the different
standards organizations nist has been
mentioned a couple times in some of the
different presentations and pretty much
if you're going to do anything that
deals with any kind of data from the
federal government
this is going to be the standard that
you're going to comply to
but nist covers more than just cyber
security you'll notice it's the national
institute of standards and testing
nist is the one who determines how
they're going to be uh what what the
standard for crypt cryptological work is
they determine what the standards are
for determining uh the atomic clock
determining what a unit of measure is
nist covers this very broad area but one
of the areas they cover
is cyber security
but nist is pretty much related only to
the united states
iso is an international organization so
you've heard of iso ratings like the 27
0001 which was mentioned in a previous
uh previous presentation
but there's also in industry standards
that really don't have anything to do
with cyber security but it's still a grc
event because you're looking to set up a
standardization of how something is
produced how something is manufactured
so that it can be determined to be
compliant with other entities from an
international point of view so that they
know they can work together pc idss
again this one's pretty much the united
states only but we are seeing it move
out into some other countries that deal
a lot into the united states
gdpr this has been in the news
a lot
but this pretty much only deals with
europe but maybe you're working for a
small organization who
is building a product or is offering a
service
and they pick up a customer who happens
to reside in france
well your company is now going to have
to show how you're going to be gdpr
compliant with the data that comes from
those users there in france what you're
going to do
here in the united states gdpr is really
a guideline for us we don't have any
real requirements here in the united
states to be compliant to gdpr but the
practices that it outlines many many
organizations have sought to put into
place because
california with their ccpa is a very
similar guideline to gdpr
and so if you deal with
transactions and deal with individuals
in california you're going to have to
make sure that your data protections for
those individuals
is ccpa compliant
i worked in the education industry so
ferpa is a big
big compliancy standard for us
but ferpa really only deals with just
student data and student records it
doesn't deal with the rest of the data
that goes on in our organization but
ferpa is that overarching
certification that we have to keep up
and there's many others
again depending on the industry in you
may find a standard that's very specific
because of what you're doing i have a
friend who runs a air aircraft parts
organization and they've got some very
specific
standards that they have to meet to be
able to sell aircraft parts even though
they're not manufacturing they're just
basically a wholesaler they're buying
parts and selling parts they still have
a whole bunch of standards that they
have to keep up and be able to stay in
compliance with in order to sell
these aircraft parts and so depending on
the organization that you're working
with
the the requirements and those standards
may change so you need to see what are
the standards that i would need to be
working on during the industry that i'm
looking toward
finally how do you help a business
well this chart shows a risk reward and
that's really what grc is what we're
looking for in grc is we're looking to
find out what the risks are before i can
figure out what my rewards are i've got
to know what the risks are so categorize
them by level find the risk find out are
they severe are they moderate are they
low what's the category that they're
going to fall on and then give a
priority to the items in each level once
you've determined what your risks are
then you have to deciding how do i
prioritize them where am i going to put
the priority and when we do the priority
we're going to create a plan and that
plan is going to start with the items
that are going to fix the highest risks
that we can but have the greatest reward
sometimes those risks are going to be
low risk but they're going to have a
great reward sometimes they're going to
be high but you want to start with that
highest risk as high as you can get with
the least amount of effort
mfa
everybody hears about it it's almost
become the standard buzzword but it's
amazing to me
the number of people who still
don't know what mfa is when you mention
the term to them
most people do it you know if you have
google account or if you have a yahoo
account or if you've got some account on
the internet
if it's doing what it's supposed to do
they're going to want to know that you
are who you say you are when you try to
access your account and that's the
purpose for mfa and turning on mfa has a
really high reward and it really doesn't
take much effort in most systems it's a
click of a button that says we're going
to turn on multi-factor authentication
now getting people to comply or getting
people to put the things in place for
multi-factor authentication can have a
little bit higher cost to it
but that's going to be determined on
your industry in my industry having a
cell phone and then getting a text a
code and typing a code in is more than
sufficient for me to be able to
authenticate my users but you may work
in an in an organization or an industry
that needs to be so more secure so you
may have to be able to put in biometrics
or you may have to have multiple
layers of multi-factor authentication to
determine who the user is based upon
the
uh security of the information that that
user is supposing is supposed to be
using another one of those things that
gives you fixes a high risk but doesn't
take a lot of effort
is turning encryption on all mobile
devices and systems if you've got a
computer or your user's got a computer
that accesses or uses company
information
it should have encryption on it
and that just protects you in the case
of it being lost
if that users you know we have this
happen from time to time someone is
traveling and i'll get a phone call my
laptop's been stolen
well in our case all mobile devices for
the university require that data
encryption is put in place and so i can
go out into our management system i can
click a couple buttons and i can lock
the device down nobody's going to use it
nobody's going to get to it even if they
destroy the device and pull the hard
drive out of it because encryption has
been turned and turned on for all those
devices
i'm not worried about somebody getting
to the data that we want protected
and that's a really easy thing to do is
start with those high risk low effort
items
and then look for ways
for gold to meet goals without high
expenditures money is always tight you
know everywhere i've ever worked at
including when i worked for myself there
were a lot of things that i saw that i'd
be like oh that'd be really cool i wish
i could do that
but the money just wasn't there
but especially when it comes to grc
there doesn't have to always be a large
outlay of money
there are so many government services
and so many industry services now that
are offering you
great
risk to reward benefits for instance one
of the best ways to help protect your
users is data security training
take the time to have the users go
through training quarterly annually
semi-annually whatever you determine is
the best method for you but put them
through training well that means
somebody's got to create the content
not everybody is a creative genius i for
one am not
we contract with the company to do our
data security training but there are a
whole lot of government services stay
safe online
is a government service the
cici
is another government service and many
of these services will offer free data
training yeah they might be simplistic
yeah they may not cover everything that
a company needs but in to get started
when money is tight
get these free services use these free
services to go out and train your users
to go out and gather those resources
as was mentioned the
dss in the last uh last session was
mentioned that many of the documents to
create this are free out there on their
websites you can go to their website
again you don't have to pay for a large
service with a large organized
documentation system to be able to make
yourself compliant or start to reach
toward compliance you can reach out and
use the free services
and also to understand that the best way
sometimes to fix the problem is just get
engaged with the users
when i started our risk system in 2018
at the university one of the biggest
things that i learned very quickly is
that i had to get out and i had to seek
opportunities to talk in front of our
faculty and staff to talk to them about
the need to be secure the need to be
compliant the need to pay attention to
the emails they're receiving because we
we live in the higher ed realm we are
one of the prime targets for malicious
actors they are sending emails into our
system all the time trying to get our
users to give up their username and
password or even
even more common nowadays they're trying
to get our users to buy apple gift cards
uh so that they can you know give them
to somebody who's busy
and so
that's sometimes the best resolution to
fix your problem is just get involved
with the users go out and talk with them
take the fear and the worry about what
they're going to do and what's going to
happen if they accidentally click on the
wrong thing get rid of that fear help
them to feel comfortable
in being safe
once you've got your plan work the plan
don't give up because of a failure
so many places
they create a plan and they look at this
plan as though this is going to be the
thing that's going to keep this issue
from happening
we all work with people
we're people ourselves
we all have times where we're sitting
there flipping through our email we're
really busy there's a whole bunch of
stuff going on and all of a sudden this
email comes through and oh it looks like
it's so valuable it looks like it's so
real i need to i need to respond to this
quick and then find out oh oops i
shouldn't have done that those type of
things happen but failures aren't
the end of a program failures are
opportunities to re-evaluate the plan
let's look at the plan what could i do
or what could i have done
to either help train my users or help
the company to put things in place to
protect the data in my organization if
something were to happen
and then be willing to update that plan
again
grc is not a one-time event it's
something that we have to understand
that we have to continually go back and
change and update and be willing to
float and flex
based upon what's going on
and then update your knowledge
get involved in organizations like
b-sides that will help you learn new
things
my market that i work in is grc
but i'm also involved in the defcon 864
group
they're a little more pointed toward
penetration testing toward that side of
the market
but i enjoy going to the meetings and i
enjoy listening and being involved in
webinars about penetration testing i
don't do any of that for a living most
of what goes on when it comes to that
goes over my head i watched ben's uh
presentation about his tool which i
think is a really cool tool
most of it goes over my head because i
don't do anything with penetration
testing
but by my
getting to know
what he does and how he finds the issues
that he finds and how he does his test
it helps me in creating my documentation
to say okay wait a minute if this is the
way that the bad guys usually go about
what what can i do
to get stuff put in place and then i can
document that hey these are issues and
we need to now go resolve these issues
take any training you can afford
it's wonderful that some of the things
that are being given away some of the
items that are are being given out are
testing penetration testing classes or
times
opportunities to get onto penetration
systems to to practice and test your
skills
take training go out and learn something
maybe it's not even something that you
feel is associated to the the item that
you're doing
it's just the fact that you're willing
to expand your mind expand your thought
process expand what you know because
sometimes that new little piece of
information that you gain from something
is that little thing you needed to give
a nudge to help you understand how i can
better
prepare for
an event that i wouldn't be expecting
and by going through those trainings you
can get that or even better
get someone to pay for you to go to
training because remember
knowledge
is power
never become complacent with your
accomplishments never get to your to a
place where you're oh i understand this
i know what i'm doing i'm just in a
great place i'm going to continue on
when we get to that place
in this industry you're going to find
yourself being left behind because the
industry will continue to move the
continue the industry will continue to
expand and change
yes i might be compliant from you know
10 years ago
but the industry changed and those
things that i know
probably are not as relevant anymore
so now what
well determine your model
what are you going to do
are you going to work for someone
or maybe work for yourself
as was mentioned in the cmmc chat in
this channel in the first chat
there's a lot of people who are going to
be needed to go out and do these
evaluations for these companies
maybe the the model that you're going to
work in is not that you're going to work
for someone else but you're going to get
yourself the training education you
needed you need to be able to become a
cmmc auditor
and now
you're going to make the engagements
maybe through other companies who are
doing this and you're going to offer
services you can work as a contractor
maybe that's the model that's going to
work we've got all kinds of small and
medium businesses around us many of them
have no kind of plan in place they've
got nothing in place to help protect
their systems help protect their data
because they just see themselves as a
nobody but the bad guys want them just
as bad as they want the fortune 500 and
so maybe you can work for yourself and
go out and offer services to these
companies to help them to become
compliant help to protect their networks
helps protect their data
or you can go to work for someone else
narrow your focus
when i started in the computer industry
back in 1993
i had the mindset that i was gonna learn
everything i was gonna know how to do
everything there was to do with a
computer well back in 1993 there wasn't
a lot that could be done with a computer
but it was still bigger than ultimately
one person could become a master of and
and do really well
and today we really need to narrow the
focus find the part that you like find
the area that you want to focus on and
focus there
but don't be afraid to change that
you may work in the grc industry and as
you work in the compliancy and you
create the policies and you create the
procedures you evaluate the risks
you may all of a sudden decide you know
hey
that thought of being able to go out and
detect the risk those that thought of
being able to go out and and expose the
risks by penetration seems really really
interesting to me and so your focus may
start out at one side
but you may change and be willing to
make that change be willing to step away
from maybe what is the comfort zone
and move on into something else
but again keep a focus find a spot that
you want to work in and then stay there
once you've narrowed the focus create a
plan
determine how am i going to get there
how am i going to get a job for someone
else or how am i going to be able to
work for myself what training what
certifications what things do i need to
be able to come to a company and say
i'm valuable i'm worth hiring i'm worth
employing
once you've created your plan
work the plan
just keep at it don't give up maybe
you've got to start out in an area where
i'm not quite in the area that i want to
but it gets my foot in the door to get
me started i always chuckle when i see
the ads you know this is a this is an
opening entry level position but we want
you to have four years of experience
how do you can you do entry level and
have four years of experience
so sometimes you've got to try to get
yourself into those situations and you
you give your experience by showing that
hey
i went out and i did this training on
the side that gave me give me some
experience i got involved in this
organization to give me some experience
going to b-sides going to
capture the flag events just getting
involved in things that would build up a
resume and show that hey i have the
knowledge and the skills to show that i
can be of benefit to your company
and then as i said earlier
never be afraid to change
because sometimes in working our
industry
you hit a point where you get burned out
and that's a really tough place to be in
when you hit that burnout stage and for
a lot of people
their way of responding to burnout is
they just completely walk away from it
because they don't want to make a change
they're afraid to move to somewhere else
they're afraid they'd maybe fail or they
maybe wouldn't be good enough
never be afraid to make a change
sometimes a model that you're following
is going to come to an end because the
industry has just changed so much that
model doesn't work anymore
so be paying attention be watching
what's going on and always be willing to
tweak and change just a little bit about
what you do
and how you do it
i knew my plan my my conversation wasn't
going to take up the whole time
so
i'm to the end of my presentation but
i'm more than willing to answer
questions and help anybody in any way i
can here's my email address you're more
welcome to email me i'll be glad to
respond back to you and help to offer to
help assistance in whatever way i can
and thank you so much for being here and
for
paying attention