excellent
i'm technologically challenged i'm one
of the old guys that always had 12
o'clock blinking on the vcr back in the
day so
uh it how i wound up in technology is
another question altogether
i'd like to thank you all for stopping
by my talk this morning uh my name is
stephen kirby i'm a
systems slash security engineer for
rns solutions
a small uh
logistics company out of
jackson tennessee and we're going to be
talking a little bit about how we're
using the pci dss
security framework as a general purpose
framework uh
for controlling our security environment
give you a little bit about me i'm a 30
year it vet started in the late 1980s
and for me uh besides greenville is a
little bit of a homecoming
i spent about 12 years in athens georgia
at the university of georgia and for all
the clemson fans better luck next year
i grabbed i gravitated to security early
on uh
started out with nobel netwear and moved
into dozens of play a dozen or so
flavors of unix
and i even do windows now uh generally
under an assumed name
i do hold multiple security
certifications
and that's always important because you
know
if you're not certified you don't know
anything right
and as i mentioned i am currently a
systems engineer for rns solutions out
of jackson tennessee
a few caveats are in order before we get
to too far gone into this
number one i make no claim to be a pci
dss expert
uh
my current employer are not is not
subject to pci compliance requirements
and so we don't do this in air quotes
for real
uh
don't assume that anything i say matches
the pci's interpretation of their
standard
they know better than i do
and if you're doing this
to
in order to process payment cards don't
let me lead you astray we could be a
little bit more flexible than the pci is
going to be when when it comes time to
do an audit
i would also stress that the opinions
expressed here are my own
and they're not those of any employer
past or present
okay
a high level uh discussion of what we're
going to do what we're going to talk
about in the next few minutes we include
four major points number one
just so we start from a common ground
we're going to talk about what is a
security framework
we'll talk about some of the most
popular frameworks
and see if i can answer a question why
would i want to use yet another one
aren't there enough other good ones out
there
i'll talk some about how we chose to
adapt pci dss
at rns solutions
and we'll bring about some key takeaways
uh
i will emphasize that my perspective
at rns is that of a very small business
i can tell you that as of last week we
had 104
uh office 365 licenses
and a good number of those were going to
contractors and to
uh third-party vendors that were using
them for for purposes other than their
primary email we are a small shop and
that definitely has an impact on
anything that i talked about
if you have to put it in perspective our
security team consists
primarily of me myself and i and not
even all of that i have responsibility
for uh managing linux and windows
systems and
uh general networking issues and
anything else that crops up
we have two other engineers on one other
engineering and our manager
on on the technical end the other
engineer has no
no formal responsibility for security at
all
and my manager is uh spread thin as it
is he has a good security mind and i'm
very fortunate uh to have him that's one
of the reasons why i'm there
but
we're
we don't have a probably a single fte
devoted to security full time
if you have a large organization some of
these things may not be
as beneficial but for us a lot of things
i'm going to talk about today were
critical because the alternative really
was having no formal security program at
all okay an introduction to security
frameworks what is a security framework
well
a security framework is a high level
strategy for protect protecting
information assets
it provides guidelines and best
practices frameworks provide guidance on
what to do but they don't tell you how
to do it
typically a framework will say
use strong encryption
they will not say
use a aes-256
there will probably be probably be some
understanding that you would use an
industry standard and ae256 definitely
would qualify
des probably does not
but that's not going to be specified in
the framework it will be specified in
some of the supporting documentation
uh there's several examples of popular
general security frameworks i'm going to
mention three iso 27001 or actually the
entire iso 27000 series
uh the nist cyber security framework or
the csf
and the cis critical security controls
the first one that i'll mention is iso
27001 or as i mentioned the 27 000
series
and
it's part of an international set of
standards it was originally developed as
a british standard
back i believe in the 1990s i'd have to
have to go back and check on the date
but
uh
it's grown in popularity particularly in
europe in the last 15 20 years
one of the difficulties or
obstacles that you face with iso is that
the official standards documents have to
be purchased and they're not cheap
uh there are a number of them and they
are
for our but given our budget they were
prohibitively expensive
the good thing one of the good things
about 27 the 27 000 series it is very
structured and very formal
so
if you are a large organization with the
resources resources to throw at it
uh
it allows you
to develop a very thorough framework
the iso uh 27000 series assumes an
information
security management system is already in
place so it's not really
there are some uh startup costs
associated with trying to implement this
standard
the main benefit from iso 27001
and other other associated uh frameworks
is getting certified by an approved
third party
and that costs money lots of it it's a
it's an expensive process to go through
and as i mentioned with our small staff
and small budget it never really was a
serious contender
the other thing worth noting is that
it's not as popular in the united states
as elsewhere
as i mentioned on the slide
see also soccer and formula one
uh this is very popular internationally
not so much here in the us
here in the us probably
the big dog would be the nist cyber
security framework or csf
it's also very detailed uh
special publication
800-171 r2 is the short form of the
standard designed for non-governmental
agencies the original
framework was designed for
federal government agencies and
contractors and for them compliance is
mandatory
uh the short form there i mentioned is
113 pages with extensive links to
external documents so it's quite
detailed most recently revised in
february of this year one of the
problems that we ran into
looking at it
is that it doesn't way to prioritize
individual controls quite the same way
that
pci dss does and we'll see what i mean
by that in a moment
it allows quite a bit of room for
interpretation and it has to because
it's
it's intended to be a one-size-fits-all
type of framework
and it can be a little i can tell you
from having looked at it
that if you're a small shop it could be
a little bit daunting if dedicated
resources are small or non-existent
one of the other popular security
frameworks here in the us would be the
cis
uh
top top controls they're now called just
the top controls because the number has
changed
uh it got it began life as the sands top
20 and then became known as the cis cis
top 20 it's now the cis top 18 controls
because the ver in version 8 of the of
the framework released in may of this
year the number was reduced i think they
combined some of the elements
one of the one of the benefits of the
the top controls framework is that it
does help prioritize individual controls
for example if you're a small
organization there's an implementation
they've impl they've introduced the idea
of implementation groups
and there are three three levels of
those implementation group one is aimed
at small organizations
uh implementation group three would
probably be applicable to a fortune 5 or
something like that
it's easy to overlook the cis
controls because 18 to 20 controls
doesn't sound like much the reality is
it's much more detailed than it sounds
there are a whole lot of subsections
under each individual control
and if
if we had uh not gone with pci dss this
probably would have been the
framework that i tried to implement
the problem with cis is that it doesn't
have the kind of supporting tools that
we're going to look at here in a minute
that pci makes available for
folks who are trying to implement their
framework in order to comply with
payment card processing requirements
the way to get started is to quit
talking and begin doing and the reason
that
i would give for why we decided to go
with pci dss as a general
non-binding framework is that it made it
easier for us to get the program off the
ground up and running
um
we started in may of this year really
and we are already in the process of
completing our first self-assessment
uh i'm not sure i could have pulled that
off if i tried to go through
and implement some of the other more
detailed standards
pci dss or the payment card industry
data security standard is a another
security control and compliance is
mandatory for organizations that process
payment cards credit and debit card
transactions
it's not intended for use as a general
purpose security framework
but it can be adapted for that use very
easily in fact
if if you want if you want to know the
presentation in a nutshell download some
of the pci tools do a global finder
replace find card holder data replaced
with sensitive data and you're done
then all you got to do is all you have
to do is go implement it
the idea of doing that was presented in
a cissp training course i took oh
a year or so ago taught by kevin henry
who
uh basically taught developed the
training materials for isc squared for
for
the cissp
i thought it sounded like an interesting
idea so i that was the first thought
that popped into my head
when i was trying to find a framework
that we could uh that would work for us
in a small company
pci does produce a spreadsheet that
we'll see in a moment called the prior
prioritized approach tool and i found
that to be very useful
it helps decide which which uh controls
need to be implemented first it actually
it's color coded
with here so you can look at at a glance
and say okay i need to do this group
first this group second and this group
six down here we'll put off to the very
end
it makes it easy to track and document
implementation
as you proceed through the spreadsheet
and through review the controls there
are sections to indicate yes we did this
no we didn't here's what we have to do
excuse me here's what
here's our plan going forward
and i think that that is a key advantage
of other uh of pci dss
over other uh for security frameworks
for example cis top 20. you could
develop the same sort of documentation
for
any of the controls that i mentioned
earlier
but you would have to go out and do that
for yourself with pci you can download
it from their document library
make a few pro a few appropriate
customizations and have a full suite of
documentation ready to begin in a matter
of days
a few of the things that i like about
the pci dss are that the controls are
focused and detailed they provide
structure but not constraints again they
don't specify that you have to to use a
particular level of encryption let's say
but they do specify that it needs to be
an industry standard and i would want to
document what that standard i'm
following is
in the spreadsheet as i work through it
the controls are adaptable for
organizations with small acting staffs
because at the end of the day
pci is targeted at everybody who
processes credit cards or debit cards
so
they will have to i mean they have to us
be adaptable
to organization mom and pop grocery and
drug stores for example
uh they won't those folks won't
necessarily have to provide the same
level of documentation that a larger
organization would say a
credit card clearing house but they have
to be able to provide some information
or find someone who can provide it for
them
the concepts are easy to explain to
non-technical personnel
one of the easiest sales jobs i've ever
done was ex having to explain to our
leadership
that our goal is to process our
sensitive information with the same
level of care
that we would process if you were
dealing with credit card transactions
that intuitively made sense to them
because
because so many organizations are
familiar with pci dss
it's easy to communicate what we're
doing to other organizations that ask
about our security policies
and the as i mentioned the biggest uh
advantage that we have found
is that extensive documentation is
available directly from pcids dss at no
charge
uh and that's certainly a welcome uh
benefit for an organization with tight
security budget
this is an example of the
prioritized approach spreadsheet and you
can see there
a whole list
of subordinate requirements under the
major requirement
install and maintain a firewall
configuration and you have prioritized
lists one through six level one being
stop what you're doing and do this first
two is what you do after that and then
there are an additional six levels of
uh
priority
you can indicate it are you done yes or
no if you're not explain why
and then provide a little bit of
explanation out
uh
in the additional columns
and you have documented the stat the
current status of your security program
in a very detailed fashion once you've
finished
the uh
process in the spreadsheet
pci uses a
three-pronged approach basically the
first stage is to assess and identify
all locations where sensitive data might
be stored taking an inventory of assets
and analyzing those for vulnerabilities
that could expose sensitive data
the next step is to repair find the
vulnerabilities and fix them
and then
the third third stage would be to report
a document report document your
assessment and your remediation details
and at that point you're ready to to
begin the process again so this is a
continual cycle assess repair report
and we are now at the report stage for
our our first pass through
there's some things that are useful to
keep in mind
when you're uh trying to apply pci dss
one the most important is that unless
you're processing payment card data
there's no need to stick to the absolute
letter pci dss
uh you're not going to get penalized if
you don't you will be you probably will
be less secure
but so long as you can say you're
keeping in the spirit
that probably is going to be good enough
for example
uh there's no you need to use third
party a third party for external
vulnerability scans penetration tests or
audits
uh you can take that you can do that
in-house so long as you're not trying to
process payment cards and we have done
so we we do conduct
external vulnerability scans against all
of our environments
uh using a third-party vendor that we
contracted with for a very small
charge i was quite pleased with that
if we were doing this for real we'd have
to use an approved scanning vendor and
the cost would have gone up
substantially
informal self-assessment can take the
place of an audit and we'll talk about
that a little bit in just a moment
and the pci dss does offer guidance for
performing such an assessment
uh
pci dss requires payment card
information to be deleted
as soon as there's no longer a business
need to retain it
that's good practice and i definitely
would do that but there are some things
that our management wants to keep around
longer than i wish they would
we're not we're not failing to be in
compliance because of that so it does
give you flexibility whether or not that
flexibility is a good thing uh
is subject to debate
there's no deadline to achieve
compliance we do not have a sword
hanging over our head that if we don't
get our assessment done by
31 december
that we're going to no longer be able to
process payment cards because we're not
doing that this is just us
using this framework to go as a as a
form of guidance and there's no no
penalty for falling out of compliance if
uh you if you're your next cycle you
detect that something is no longer
working
it's not the end of the world you need
to fix it but it doesn't put your
ability to do business at any risk
it may be something you need to address
as soon as possible maybe today or
tomorrow
but you're not at a risk of being having
your ability to do business suspended
there's some sections of pci dss that
may not apply for example we don't
develop applications in-house and there
are entire
chunks of some of the security controls
that don't apply to us those were those
were my favorite sections i sailed
through those
uh some sections are aimed service
providers and those are outside entities
that could impact
impact security of cardholder data you
won't need to necessarily worry about
those
important points to keep in mind would
be that provisions are not restricted to
information that is stored
electronically
as difficult as it is for us and what is
now almost a digital age to remember
there's still a lot of paper records out
there and those paper records need to be
secured or securely disposed up too
pci does take that into account
pci envisions the secure environment to
be a subset of the company network but
when you're processing sensitive data as
opposed to
payment card data it may not be it may
not be possible to simply isolate
off into one segment of the network your
accounting department may need to be
able to talk to hr which may need to be
able to talk to the ceo ceo's office and
the cfo so you may wind up with a larger
shared environment and that means that
you're going to need to look at some of
the controls that we would normally
apply
to a
segmented environment and apply them
possibly to a larger segment of your
larger spread of your network
there are a few common pitfalls that
i've discovered in reading and in our
own experience
for organizations that are attempting to
comply
even either to the letter or into the
spirit with pci dss
the bugaboo for every security
professional i've ever known has been
failing to change default passwords on
network devices routers switches iot
uh
printers
uh printers
uh multi-function printers are very
useful as penetration testing tools
because
most of the most of the default
passwords you can find through a
google or a search engine
uh and very few
it seems to be common practice amongst
uh printer service technicians
to keep those set to the same thing for
convenience sake and there are seven
have been several um
conference presentations on how to use
set up a reverse shell on the printer
and use them to capture
uh
credentials as people come come to
log into the printer to print something
poorly written web apps that allow sql
injections and sql injections is hard to
believe are still an issue
but they still make the a wasp
top 10 on a regular basis
sql injections or exposing a database to
the public internet
directly i mean it's hard to believe
that those are still problems but they
are
uh and then another big issue would be
exposing sensitive data to insecure
networks or endpoints the the most
obvious example would be
byod devices
that are excuse me
allowed to connect directly to the
company network
or
are somehow able to gain access to the
company network through guest wireless
because that wireless network isn't
properly segmented
i show my age here
sack it to me reminds me of the late
1960s uh comedy show rowan and martin's
laughing one of the by phrases or
catchphrases
on that show with socket to me so
if you remember laugh in you know where
this came from and if not well i'm old
organizations that prom that process
payment cards are required to submit
responses to an annual self-assessment
questionnaire
and the saq
for self-requesting self-assessment
questionnaire
is a standardized form that can be
downloaded from the pci dss document
library
we're working with with the
questionnaire for class d merchants
and we found it very very useful
the one problem that i did run into was
that
the form as it is delivered by pci
is a pdf file so i spent the better part
of about three days converting that into
a spreadsheet similar to the
uh one that we looked at earlier once i
got there it great that greatly
simplified the process of doing our
self-assessment which we recently just
completed
uh with modifications that
self-assessment questionnaire provides a
great template for an annual review of
an organization security practices i'm
using it to prepare an end of the year
report uh for our ownership and
management which is something that
they've never had before
one thing i will say is that you should
not fail fear failing your first
assessment
particularly if you're starting from
ground zero
uh in a small shop that has not had an
active security program before you're
not going to get everything done in the
first year what you can do is map out a
road map for what needs to be done
and maybe come up with a an improvement
plan
to get the top priorities taken care of
in the next
six to eight months
uh since we're not using pci for
compliance purposes our objective is a
little bit different than
uh
the standard we simply need to identify
what we need to do
what we're actually doing both what
we're doing well and what we're not
doing well
and we're going to we're done we need to
identify
what we're not doing but need to do in
future
and then develop a strategy to close
those gaps
the final section of the saq document is
at
a station
of compliance or aoc the other aoc
aoc doesn't assume or require full
compliance even for
environments that are in scope for pci
dss
what it does necessarily
it provides an ac what it does is
provide an action plan for non-compliant
requirements and a timetable for re for
completing those requirements and it can
be massaged to generate a summary of
your current cert security practices
that you can share with your with
customers and potential customers in
fact that's exactly what we intend to do
some key takeaways
from this
uh things that you're going to need to
look at
especially carefully
if you do decide to follow pci dss
one is network protection
you're going to need make sure you've
got
firewalls in all the right places and
that your network is properly segmented
uh as has been mentioned elsewhere in
other talks this morning
there's no such thing as a
there's no such thing as a security
professional who doesn't believe in
network segmentation
you'll need to be careful with passwords
and default settings make sure that
none of your devices are using the
default passwords the users are
choosing secure passwords because we're
stuck with them for the time being
that i would emphasize making sure that
none of your passwords have been
involved in a data breach because the
definition
of what constitutes a good
a secure password has changed
considerably in the last uh five or ten
years
and make sure that all the default
settings are all the settings on your
network devices and pcs are configured
correctly
uh you'll need to make sure that
data at rest is properly encrypted
the data in
in transit is properly encrypted
that you have malware protection and is
kept updated
that systems are hardened if they're
patched and the unnecessary services
have been removed
make sure that each user has their own
account and that a password is assigned
to the account and that you can track
exactly who has done what in as much as
possible
you need to restrict physical access to
sensitive data make sure that
your
your cert your main server shouldn't be
on a pc sitting under somebody's desk
it's been a while but i have seen that
you need to restrict physical access to
sensitive data
for example backup tapes if anyone's
still backing up to tape
that's almost as good as having access
to the data itself it needs to be
secured it needs to be encrypted and it
needs to be stored securely
you'll need to have logging and log
management set up some form of central
log management or storage for example a
seam
you'll need vulnerability management
practice both internally and externally
you'll need to conduct regular risk
assessment and documentation which turns
out to be easier said than done we're
still wrestling with that ourselves
and you'll need to perform regular
reviews at least annually and following
every any major change to your
infrastructure
summary
security frameworks are a useful roadmap
for developing a security program
uh dependent upon available resources
some more established uh frameworks may
not be viable for smaller organizations
my advice would be to find a framework
that you like and stick with it
the pci dss was developed to secure
payment card data but it can be
leveraged to create a viable security
framework for both small and
medium-sized organizations
i thank you very much for coming by my
talk i think we're done a little bit
early
if we have questions i'll be glad to
take them and i will provide a link to
the slide deck in the chat in case
anybody wants it
thank you
and let's see
great stephen
and i know my experience with this is um
this is mark um i work for a company
that had nine um
nine other companies that i oversaw and
two of them had the pci compliant
compliance requirement
and they had they had a contract in
place to do the external scanning
and i thought it was fabulous and so i
you know got with the same company and
put a contract in place to scan the
other seven country companies
now it was a totally separate agreement
so it wouldn't you know mess up their
results but it was just so nice to be
able to get the same type of information
easily it was so easy for me to do that
yes
that that's wonderful we actually went
out and
evaluated some companies that
uh
provide this as a service not
necessarily for pci
and found one that allows us to do uh
they're actually selling open vaz
uh which
again probably
wouldn't have been my first choice but
the price was right
and it does allow us to at least
guarantee that
for example i can promise you that we're
not that we don't have rdp running on
any of our public ids that was my first
big concern when i got there
uh and those are the things that you
need to check for it it helps to make
sure that you have things buttoned up as
well as you do because i think if you
ask
any systems administrator anywhere in
the world all of them would deny that
they have uh
rdp port 389
3389 exposed to the internet
and we know obviously that has not been
the case
and another issue that you encounter is
when you tell somebody they need to do
something
they're like well that's just your
opinion yeah we've been doing it this
other way forever
and when you have some type of standard
to stand behind you and go well no
this is the best practice according to
this industry standard this is why you
need to do it you tend to get more
traction if it's an industry standard
you're trying to implement versus what
could be considered your opinion
yeah and that's one of the reasons that
we
adopted a framework
developed in our program because it was
easier to sell to management they
intuitively understood when we said
we're pro we're handling all of our
sensitive data the way we would handle
credit card data it made sense to them i
don't know if i had said well we're
doing this because the government
the
this agency and the federal government
said to do it i don't know that it would
have registered quite as solidly
and that's that's going to be an issue
probably more for smaller organizations
like ours than it might be for some
place that is a little bit larger and is
and is more in tune
with uh
government requirements