all so um hello everybody my name is
some
Jens meh I'm must assign student at the
University on of pool home a piece of
the developer
once in the time and currently into
block forensics
that's the type who may be
a bit misleading at this talk is
basically about among insects action
about them to be out of gathering
important information from I'm
that locked files um important in this
case means
um a text with alarm briefly discuss
various techniques
to find attacks against them %uh that
accept applications
also the pups ever but more are the
publications um
with selling it's essentially a long as
they can serve a standard doing based
approaches afterwards we'll try to
characterize these attacks
into himself from who did something and
what exactly what style are who
in this case refers to about the
attacker
like your arm you see are coming from
Switzerland
a you see up parked somewhat net or
from you see I'm a machine at some
stripped or see a human being
trying to get into I'm seeing I'm
what occurs to don't you take itself %uh
ruling on in terms of the
severity of the attack so we are trying
to at least %uh distinguished
between on successful and long
successful attacks
are ever seen showing the stock has been
implemented and
some prototype so you that can test it
with your a very own X locks
afterwards if you're curious so here's
our scenario
arm a.m. we are some customer 0
wherever some upside got contact got
owned %ah
sometimes daily pretty cool ASCII art
behind
now and other cases they try to steal a
very private
data and if you find it in the Internet
I which tennis maybe that's good
%ah in any case um probably some
application wasn't secure until
now we are interested in and how did it
we should be on
else I've just reset or service arm
would just get
went again next week so what do we do we
make an image of the disc we r
we look for suspicious files %uh perfect
or sense on
research for unusual activity in the log
files
are since we of course didn't use a what
security and audit logging
um we only have just done basic Apache
wrong
in doing so whatever excess locks which
is certainly a very common scenario for
post-op around six
um but for some reason luckily our
we all know we think that the lock parts
have not been manipulated because
de vere story with separate machine I
was crypto and a pendulum the end
we think the log files are fine a and
interior so
are with we think we have pretty good
chances to
to understand what happened are or not
a why the basic basic problem is so I
was like fuck
that they are preludes a and by youths
they i mean they can get
really really rich don't we are kind of
lazy and
at least we don't have the motivation to
a minority
manually refuel terabytes of luck for
data so
from who remembered yet that could be in
the
could have happened weeks ago and the
defacement snow also we might really
have to look to all those to favor um
so we can we have some critics tools out
there like crap that
all can't hotel called I but
maybe you want to do something that was
more specially designed for the chop off
I'm finding a funding attacks a or
suspicious
um activity in the talks arm
why not using a to design for a chop
on because we simply have known or not
in the
open source field at least so what do we
have
use a market study of from mostly open
source
some stuff we have got some some really
good
number publication have also a
intrusion detection systems on that
layer and what security does a
really good job on BF overstep sent a
framework we have on PHP ID s for
PHP based other publications aunt and we
have a bunch of commercial
among the publication firewalls out
there arm
to Smyrna network a lever and then on
the
on the local level we have from kind of
many tools
um a a forum analytics and monitoring
and forensics
um which 10 Canberra collectively can
work on the on the log files does not
have to necessarily
but the lights are or HW stats are
designed for use for
for bed analytics go excesses circle
program
i'm for the console way up from left
blank
and and from P-flag switch to work on
any conflicts and you can really do good
analytic stare
go um going to detail so for certain
fields look for purists
um so designed for forensic spot
if they are not especially from fall for
web stuff so
what's more like out I assign any kind
of data
but they don't vest some special and
it's for
of up blocks um so dead yes why not
just combine both routes are credit to
lead is based on
on look data and but uses T about the
evidence from the world of web
application firewalls
um so from the only a the only to alum
I'm aware of this on scalp which on
which basically on
use the song the field 25 PHP Eid yes
them
um um at just to you bets against the
filters
and marks it as undertakers a certain
severity
this is a good start but it does not
make use of a request unless the school
eso is provided by Pete PIDs and so I
just a test as yesterday a simple
URL encoding belief the attack
undetected
so and that's the only two at least I'm
well from the open source word
so we might be a up david says
sub-crater
something up little bit more bounce
so here's a typical up look fine in to
come from not
on which is the use by a pitch she and
others
but fault as you can see here one of the
values of two
you accrue string permeta called pages
some somewhat different
on the rep on meaning an attack is
trying to include our password file
instead of a regular page so this is
just a simple example for a local file
inclusion
arm gets you so some are also you
probably of familiar with some
week and maybe a execute a hour include
even the route fall to execute the
commands if there were some
logical a programming error in the
invocation
a get access to the database on to trust
that scripting or
maybe that's come these days arm to from
by the overflows expert below of loss
and there's many more
it's just a gif you some short
understanding
of on but different kinds of the input a
pro detection technique
would have to be I'm capable of handling
so um as always there is some two
approaches
um which it says the country based and
UN bases
um what be implemented um
is some to him to just use PSP NDS so a
regular expression
based on approach um than an approach
based on
a statistics to lengthen their picture
distribution a call to
char so the text much you ok a
and then I'm missing during based
detects mature
I'll which is based on hidden Markov
models accordance yes
8mm on that's all up on you um
some morning from a patient outcome to
will come to
no will later see 'em what to do with
that
so from a set there's been
lot of research in the field of on
detection and prevention of
on the pace attacks in the past two
years arm
with approach is based on the contrary
it switch your back in 2000 them and
tough matching for were able to chat
scripts
are laid on more complex regular
expressions
where develop to cover a pro to arm
a a range of attacks
I'm so what we did is a just use PHP ID
s I'm pipe the
every your a field value through it um
so also be used to catch PIDs
conversation
and from the obfuscation and
normalisation process
and then mentions outcome against the
mmm
the provided about the seventy regular
expressions
I'm which mmm try to match for for
certain kinds of attacks
also in the end PHP ID s purchases are
some numerical value as a result
are called the impact of the attacks so
we do nothing more damn
shelf make use of PHP Eid yes
on lock files
as for from some really basic statistics
on
there's been a some ideas like a have a
look at the lengths
from the long and the you have a query
string is a relative levy more
unusual it may be um to make more maybe
an attack arm also your arm
why characters of the 11 a better teach
its
are commonly seen within your crew
strings
I think strictest my PE evidence of an
attack
up fifteen approach is based on the
court's Distribution Manager
relative frequency of characters arm
within your query string well use buy
I'm very proud people out there
so what we do is who tough to use yet
the of two lengths and it has kept a
distribution in a very simple way
fall replication issue a Christian
permitted values
we calculate demean of the ok ruins of
lawn
of a numeric characters are we do this
but simply removing all digits and
and unique code letters and then we
compare it against
um commune also non of an american home
meaning special characters for certain
you're a querystring permit
are you say that's too simple probably
absolutely is his
I'm but it is pretty fast in sort of
love walking through dozens of regular
expressions and
generally if the variance and
and the moon um of from love
a special characters for a certain oMG a
publication are lower than
which is for many publications true NPF
good chances
a to to use a simple algorithm at least
two
get the cove a few um
sir detection module is some this
machine learning
this as being too %uh um
a few to freeze the action that in the
last decade I'm many many interesting
approaches we have
senal approach is based on bias current
estimation
self-organizing maps deface um people
accused
neural networks pay for transformations
and drums just to see if you know a few
up in the last year's hidden Markov
models I'm have proven to
gif very good results are forum
detecting on a texan but traffic or
that for traffic in general so I'm with
what we did this just a use approach
a that for some percent in 2009
implemented at
and arm that's why I'm test a
shortly I'm not going into details on
what it'll look like models
are up this with probably kill the young
to talk
us to tell me it's just a learning base
model where we are going to lengths
of some observations in this case the
system
the values like we had some on use
in X wiki and then it is the password
once
and um hope to give them some prediction
about in this case that the probability
of
from some for observation like a cute
easy password
um first of all the people who do is
something we have to create
some to Daytona I would build on a Samba
of
models normally five models us
seems to be a very good value the more
to to that
let's go to performs to less um if you
would do not take enough
models them our results are not good we
do this forever you're a creep strain
pair metaphor every web application
a tough to find bypass so ever
replication that this
on our server the convective I'll use
I'll in the retina of a dick will use to
NA and their numerical values to an end
up this is a to get as Rick results
because
to changes very often and if it changes
it gets less you sure
but be seeing that it takes hopefully
are not carried out by only
of America a characters
um we are we train the model so you
think the bombast a rhythm
and a then test um certain um
a value like it is the password a Sat
Nav Association using their
over the PR guru um so it's probably if
it's
a non malicious a value that
big cat as a ritual in the end to be a
player
mutia classification system arm and
South
take the a Tia NTT
model with the highest probability to
get less false positives and in the end
the best result acetyl
to the some totally nothing you and um
what's more and implementation at the
year
and um yep of
so we did some evaluation I'm be used it
rained out of our institute some
up sir at some tricks locks 60,000
macbeth
altogether 40,000 day are on income
trading has been pretty fair took by
some five always
Aki es so we are sort we think that most
of the attacks didn't even get to the
locks
which is good because be one stand a
text free almost here check free
training data set we need to this I'm
new
if possible important doctors had a it's
okay to use disarm
in the terms of just messing up a false
positive rate
Theft Auto in you be used some for two
real-world exploits from
the resources like move from or what is
called now
online command execution local thank you
soon
cross-site scripting cross-site request
for Sharia and searching a string
section
arm the payload spirit of place in the
while yourself normal web applications
up the only thing was beyond use HTTP
GET
because we simply don't see arm post
starter interlock system at most major
drawback up
who come to that later if i dont text
carried out by pulsed
a mostly we won't eat and normal excess
Knox
so I'll just a result um as you can see
the hidden Markov models
um to give them the best detection
results um
generally do also the slowest um
mmm it even detected 100-person from
of some so that the Cirrus you're a
person enter one
under a nexus hundred-person
um of the true positives but with the
with some
interoperable a false positive rate of
on
one president so you vote probably
choose the trash held
a in the upper left for a corner
somewhere to get
up best resorts in the end
their coats distribution this case was
very well
%ah even better than PSP NDS but this is
because of
that doesn't that did not contain from
that money the friend from a while US
so if the if the values are variants of
Tobias
it's not that big if you do not have
that many special characters normally
um then does not you can get
quick results it's also number you
fastest
as for PHP Eid yes um that's not just a
a rock-solid
um a much you to use
um because it's not its independent of
the training data so it
give them the same from result even if
it's just one request
while the statistics the meet several
values
the learning-based evidence to even meet
a you need more a training data
to overcome so pissed PIDs disarm
just a rock-solid choice
so on all the of those detection
algorithm some
um therefore completed and but we still
have
thousands of lines of a potentially
attacks on but just too much state %uh
still
and to less information so what we can
do is some
get information um about the attack on a
little bit more and
even more interesting maybe get
information about the effect
i'm for you take a weekend cooped his
activities into
sessions and Andrew
try to see if you it's been a a human
being or some
machine some script up can also do I
couldn't kill mapping or
or look up with her if it came from some
what that maybe because it might be
interesting I'm
then we can from we can try to evaluate
if
and an attack was successful or not
because we don't care about
unsuccessful attacks nominee
so we try to at the missing context here
well known as for session identification
no
with its just based on the into request
time delay and
change %uh from user-agent: i'm dumb
then after we have several sessions
weeks a random scan
if it's just one thing the request of
some for most
something you brought the do not care if
we don't have
especially that one or ability a on our
server
own talk to detect might be a bit more
dangerous because
somebody strung some scripts or so well
don't know a human attacker is probably
the most dangerous
some kind of attack because a it's
carried it means that
real human being is trying to get into
our reps ever
arm also it's interesting that off from
the flow if that people first run
automated scans and Dan
led a comeback as human beings and tried
to to look if
if a result of the scans really the
to mentor approving and try to I get in
line
um tower rooms out of the stole from
Robert detection techniques
I'm pretty easy but for to say its
argument echoed if this only
one request per se it's some random form
saying whatever
it's a row if the robots the doc txt
file is requested
tenant might be a might be a machine
of course the gym can do that too up if
so lawn cat pose two crests
I'm the same but also of course it could
be a I
a human with some with some the summer
program if the a rinse time delay I'm
for web applications
meaning not image yes which is
identified by the fight tenseness
less than one second um then we think
wealth nobody conflict at first
if the a total number of other
publications is correct then
1000 um maybe that's a mission to
and if the the coat of
from HTTP response code stirred our in
their four hundred sector like fun for
just some created they're not dynamic
threshold than
might be a mission to the custom when
you sit down and professional because we
think that the human being my two
ruin if if you always get formed for you
want click on the machine but just
try and try and try for publications
that that that don't exist
so arm next week and the get some more
information about the attack a weekend
do some keogh mapping this was a
was simply fails idea I'm West thought
it's about what's up some some local
company near a cologne
and I applied to the density-based
up by our algorithm and at the idea was
that
might be unusual if fear
the request doesn't come from a a
certain um
a hot spot of activity are its able to
totally dumb but again it's totally
discriminating against people
originating from from trees in this case
of
and its forget about that but it's
interesting to somehow I'm
no bear architects a come from on a
give traffic a level than what we also
can do is some
just at some DNS like a list information
um we do this by I'm requesting several
is like a barracuda central or whatever
socialists are made for several um
a kinds of from of like a
spam a so don't be no other that Pietrus
has already
p.m. prop up the been up the suspicious
of spending that's not too interesting
interesting maybe if it's part of a
botnet
um interesting maybe if that the attack
could use a some
some open the http or socks proxy is
was interesting um is some if the
attacks carried out by
the tone effort police up don't suit or
network operators
be out doing a great job and defending
us from prison
what all the surveillance programs are
called a what's under that
so arm for us to some just yet another
unsuccessful scan matter depending on
your
a network setup if you are connected to
the Internet
then probably know because you will have
to this are a couple of minutes
so we somehow all it would be
interesting to know if the attackers
succeeded
um so I want us to succeed mean in this
case
of when used to somebody find this is a
tough information disclosure like home
to pass a FEA the developed occasion
or sit down file disclosure like someday
Tyseley
morrissette the compromise of the server
or the
hacked accounts so to this kind of
depends on
on your setup and your security level
um what we now do this with South a be
tough
a replay via text for every single
request identify it as a tech we replay
it
the match for up certain signatures and
then a a single word that might be some
a
summer group some info on the King of
Iowa leaking
well let's fall deposit £5 for example
this is just the next
excerpt on for some sauce put five as a
private key so
we can match for um Arum shes PSP so
uptight and whatever if
this is important for us are some
five-part the sleek some
database a messages leaked on
yeah we can do that bus but isn't that
kind of teasing um in many cases did the
web server isn't up anymore
if it is might even even didn't change
its contents by replaying the attacks
are
may be blunt um to evaluate the success
of attacks
along with on the the logfile
information
as you can see their so how to disarm
as some anybody any idea
that's a very good idea I first I
thought about the
no the about the HTTP response code
I'm but arm that that's really not make
sense for web applications anymore
I'm a bit from make sense for HTTP
access
the or something like that i'm for it
she excess
um about but to a6 unsuccessful looking
for replication
always 200 we all this just get 200 I'm
so we still don't know if T to see
possibilities
um included or not
so estate stuff that what we do is
we are we look at the bites and where
you are even though we don't know
the we have no access to it actual
response be do a
half the fields from but just some the
bites
sent we up okay
what we can do to see from St Peter's on
scouts is some
maybe for the fall we can at least say
Obama okay
they look for some a and that doesn't
exist and we can maybe
exclude that but become very much more
from
response cuts so as far and bites and
value
um week and we can look for our clients
in there in 10 say old
if there's not lie or den their actual
consonants response different
don't normally and then it might be a
interesting
I am problem list that we don't have to
know me up
alright of the static content was always
the same
are bites and value on then we get
something else and and we know its own
our clients so we often half to
like a in the example we have from a
paints a news blog in exons on that
therefore
alt sometime in the content so but with
so it can see there's some some hot spot
a in some magnitude of on
of value we also can might maybe have
several hot spots
um that's why we use a a density-based
um
up by Igor Adam the are look up by
effector
well which is pretty slow but um but OK
on
because we do this only a for requests
addicted as attacks
on so I'll to Silent Spring
experimental attempts to produce a very
high up
false-positive rate yup but some
but it it in the test kind of worked on
so on
as you can see I'm tatt password is a
2,219 bites if that is the size of
or a possible filed them movie I've got
a problem at all
onto bikini might also be a a flyer
bout whistle some trash holding you
might be able to handle this
in the end you probably have to mentally
so check it
I'll as such just said to
reboot
yeah I wanted to show you some
on some examples of the rock room
who some personal notes just ignore that
now we have
some to have a script so to take some
time for so I'm so here we go
I'll as we can see I'm
this is some some example a summary
world
lock file on yes I'm a time line of the
year
attacks up there um we r
have certain colors for the the impact
I'm
week and I may be search for a certain
a a strings like a passport
so and the
look a okay somebody's tried to include
but so far it's tough on for so
we don't we don't care we can sort by
client
by home by the impact um by
film some kinda yeah i text
classification made by PSP ideas but
you know that's a that's not too to
clear
week and we can say we only 12 Service
Co 200
which might be more interested because
we don't care about all that a settler
400 the have a records and pecan also
say
%uh let's just a take let's have a look
at the
at the attacks originating from
apartments off from mmm to a service and
people who have been no spam already
so things like that weekend you can sort
by the
requests are method up what's we also
can see in this kind of association very
good is so
were that
I'm for example you can very often see
I'm its a over there
2045 20 and so on a
so that song thats all new
wha the same stripped on which scans for
a risk assessed at sei
it it I would steps um ok but so you can
easily see an
in this map kind of with all essential
the
I hope it for ex bf another kind of like
go
more what you with gif for some
automatically generated report ok you
can read it
for example this host this remnants can
last year of
from I don't know where I know we don't
know because to take a coach's identity
up because it comes from pot plant
so don't even try taking a its esta
the has got some severity I don't think
that's true in this case
just so give me a second
so
at ISIS our um order to set aloft
institutions WEA
we r via included some fires of the
from well dusty excrement for the text
with the
it is the password or whatever included
so that the the
two bites and value has been set to GR
to the
corresponding value if the effect would
be successful and
a in many cases it just detected by a
some kind of
I'll play affect up are
insult good up
totally not cool.
so maybe we can look at
to us once
I'm that's also a real-world example
which is also interesting
because some we can see it some
I hope you can read it it's a targeted
scanned and a and the
nato non-human attacker um and
you can see with some with some the
publication severe mostly targeted
and she also we have some
some property as current section
a it doesn't I didn't up I didn't you
can
automatically say you were angered
encoding and duplication a
this wasn't an adult in this case of arm
anyways just some some example
up are use more from
for some tool called a square does P A P
PHP and
we don't know if if that's a legitimate
to a servant
yep also we can see if
an attack was carried carried out by day
or night
but just like this one so it might be
interesting if
in this certain time so on that the
attack was carried out
maybe from a a midnight to eight o'clock
because
then it probably was the some a current
not some
government guy because to rate work from
8-5
maybe have might be interesting okay
this is just some
some expert experiments with his other
facial
you can offer get a Tesla some CS
the data or it's a sin or XML
whatever deity and produce up
so from
yeah I think that's almost the last
night all that's just some
briefly discuss arm discussed um some
come to missus often take a2 you've ate
detection um for all the
learning based algorithms um clearly if
an attacker can write to the training
data and some poison
large porch portions of it I V F just
simply lost
I'm the same as for statistics arm
in the first case arms can make no more
requests um
looked like identified some attacks and
the other way around from so
from that's a real problem we need mmm
not taught her put her first into clean
training data about
ninety person or accused large portions
of the trend data should be on
should be regular from requests I'm else
all the only answer to space approach to
some will fail
so I was treated to a two count two
messages um
is that from we would just ruin until we
have
on enough examples and then stopped
ringing so what's all
also performs issue and be only your own
from
that's a 100 different IP addresses
I'm so that's still not perfect but
an attacker has 2 FXS to very many IP
addresses
and he has to a to poison the training
data at the very beginning
to from to a to make a slow texter them
undetected another condom issue maybe
vote
P a hybrid approach and just some
run PHP at yes to filter out large
portions and then afterwards I'm
run crew learning based on approach
what else can I take it you I'm it there
so so many ways cell phone peyot up this
confiscation the bat
like URL encoding Orem hundreds of ways
to to obfuscate
you need JavaScript on one condom issue
some
to just use some the PSP idea some
conversion
inching for all the texts los utiles and
then
are hope that the deal for skating on a
is so I correctly applied
than the latter problem with that a
think it can use Vick tourist that
are simply not locked or a not visible
to us
um this is a real problem we use it
don't have access to post data set
or to any parts of the hd2 body or
header
so on just carrying out your tech with
pills instead of getting will
um will simply be in effective way to to
you a time detection
on forensics laser and that the Apache
developers
don't really make it too easy to lock
posts a top
so group then we have found some a text
that are
trust I'm just not visible to the server
on because it's
never ever transmitted there like you
know dawn based
cross-site scripting
what also what can be done is some a
try to hide at the flow of the attack
the the course of events and
from separate steps um so slowing down
he attacked
from in in time our quote carrying out
from
and many from multiple origins I'm
to hype that all the steps um are part
of one and the same
on preaching arm on the other and we can
also create
just feud of nonsense attacks maybe
hundreds
thousands hundreds of thousands and
making the
detection much with trigger but then
making it difficult for them to see
which attack is to really attack a text
that was meant to be
successful because it's still difficult
to see
woohoo tutsi distinguish between
successful and unsuccessful attacks
um the on the look far based um
site what in taken 2 s.a to attacks
against it locking itself
um obviously if it's like a fruit or
in somehow right access to develop file
some
he can remove any evidence of this
behavior
of cleaning what you do with some we run
a simple props
outlay a test against the 2.5 I'm into
request I'm time delays
I'm so we can detect if these a nice kid
truncation within the locked it up um
but does our players can also caused by
a natural phenomena
normal phenomenon like up temporarily
disabled
doc services are networked on time so
run some clock changes are no company X
is a Christmas
so and so we you if we detect the
that lot but has been many politically
thats we don't gain anything of that
so well with store you look for us on
safe place
maybe a separate machine so what we also
can do is maybe a
denial of service dept separate machine
that to take two locks and safes them
so weak and somehow denial of service to
that the doc
server over 10 sent one by to an old
version of Apache and
stanfield simply stop logging up but
this is fixed here's
our last but not least a and take a can
do I love looting
by just from sending really really many
requests so artists are not infinite and
in the end
I'm will at some point I'm which the end
of the disc
a can no longer go up and the attack was
carried a hot
I don't know if it's too practical about
maybe um
maybe in the is something to think about
I'm
if the if if locker tation that is based
on them five sizes
that and we could some carry out the
attack I'm afterwards um
making my much of nombre requests um
and then by rotation the attack might
get overwritten
um so maybe that's something to think
about for
for rent
so thanks for your attention to um I
hope to
and try to talk um of source code a
research so and this presentation is
some online at like it up
um 14 link the implementation is some
still pretty much
Prix of a coat a there are pics inside
their property exploitable
I up by specially crafted look path so
a maybe it's your home for two to try
this out
um also I have to think that's an
interesting project
um feel free to join or 240 just
talk to me later at the beer arm
so I think we have time for one question
to I don't know any questions
and you for use you talk funny
quite interesting minute is in some
see someone's do PCs and
that's going to receive as and in some
cases
which it wasn't visible saddam bases
nice lines sees you trying to find
and actual successful attacks so if we
take for example ceaser
deng's on steinway
that you York as you call it
can detect season a
I'm not sure if I got a question
correctly but what's meant
somewhat that if on the attack is only a
click against declines
then if you can't see it from the server
side them know we have no chance in
detecting it
isn't that something is okie C
thanks for top first about back from
for company which operates my speech
freemen servers
about fifty customs and you can
meant rhythm data and we always have
the problem we need some for whose you
were this large amount of data do you
have any number
we yourself forms norms the
not too well there
um so it's a if you have got there are
hundreds of megabytes it's a %uh still
into
depending on the algorithm it can be and
some minutes but if it's more than
you're getting into trouble um well
if somebody wants to help improve the
the I word himself
your free it's a open source project up
I it
maybe use of time for dis with some
which is not
really sign for to chop but but you
could give it a try because it
verse relief options fast I'm not sure
lotsa a lot better
thanks
Sonando thank you here