awesome so today we're going to talk
about building products people trust I
think this is a really critical topic to
talk about especially and this time when
we continue to see products blatantly
abuse people's privacy their security
and just not being responsible for the
actual value that they're creating so
why is this important I fundamentally
believe that building products people
trust is how you win and you can win
long-term if you play this game right
time and time again companies can lose
tons and tons of users when they violate
trust or their users privacy we're
seeing people flee Facebook right now
because of blatant abuse of privacy and
security on their platform I'm in ways
that we didn't really even understand
that could be done whereas in comparison
if we look at companies that embrace
security and privacy companies like
Apple they continue to do really really
amazing things at huge scale so to start
I want to build a little trust with you
about me as it was mentioned I have a
background in theater and dance which I
was like to talk about because it's
important that you bring in people with
different backgrounds I think you
fundamentally build better products when
you have diverse people actually
building them my focus is on usability
so as a user experience designer I've
now turned to product manager and a lot
of companies that maybe you know locally
that I've worked for ultimately I work
at high scale high-growth technology
companies that's why I think there's a
really interesting point of when a
company grows really really fast you
have to be careful not to make terrible
decisions with your product that impact
millions and millions of people so what
are we gonna talk about today first I
want to talk about fundamentally what is
trust Trust is something we understand
is a whole but it's really hard to put
your finger exactly on what we mean by
trust I want to look at the types of
trust that you can build and we'll look
at a couple of psychologists definitions
of how to actually build trust we'll
talk about why trust matters why does
your product need to build trust we'll
look at what I like to call trust fails
products
that have done this miserably and some
of the results from that and then we'll
look at actually how do you build trust
into your products so I fundamentally
believe that trust underlies every
single day of our experience you drove
in a car here today you didn't even
notice that you were trusting that other
drivers on the road understand what the
little dotted lines on the road mean
that it's a lane that you stay in and
the cars go one direction and cars go in
the other it's something that we don't
even think about but this is a moment of
trust where you're actually trusting
that other drivers agree with some set
of rules that are unspoken so what is
trust we're gonna look at this through
the frame of these two women they've
done research a lot around the areas of
trust and I don't want to recreate the
wheel here Frances Faye you may have
heard of her actually she is it was an
executive at uber lots of really
interesting things happened at uber and
are continuing to happen in uber
particularly related to trust she was
brought in based on her experience at
Harvard to come in and basically change
the way Buber as a company thinks about
trust and then we've got Rachel Botsman
she's an author of a wonderful book that
if you like this talk I encourage you to
go read who can you trust looking at how
you build trust and communities so I
want to start with this first concept of
peer-to-peer trust this is something
that every single person in the world
fundamentally understands at some level
how do we build trust to another person
a one-to-one and she believes that
basically trust is a three principle
concept and if you have authenticity if
you have logic and if you have empathy
that trust stool stands up but if you
are missing any one of these things it
falls over and you lose trust so what
does she mean by these you're more
likely to trust me if I'm being
authentic part of why I talk openly
about like my experiences because that's
a
to start building trust if you sense
that someone's being honest and truthful
for you you're more likely to trust them
second if you sense that there's
actually logic there's rigor to my logic
basically you can follow my train of
thought
and see logically how I progress to the
decision or the thing that I'm trying to
convey to you you can understand my
perspective and then finally if you
believe that my empathy is directed
towards you you're more likely to trust
me that's a pretty basic thing we like
to feel like the other person
understands and hears us these three
things together are the fundamental
concepts of trust to another human being
makes a lot of sense really obvious I
want to take a real quick detour here
and talk about rigor and logic because
this is actually something that's
fundamentally changed the way that I
work there's two ways to show your logic
basically you have one where you go tell
a long story improve all your points and
then you come to this magical bang
moment of a and here's the idea that I
came to there's the other model where
you start with here's what I want you to
talk away you walk away with and then
I'm going to talk you through why and
how I came to that conclusion there's
one problem with this model it's human
attention and I hate to say it but the
one lady in the audience you probably
have understood this by being cut off
early on and not getting your point hurt
women tend to start with the one where
they take you on a journey to tell you
what their conclusion is men generally
start up front I actually used to go on
really long journeys in fact that's kind
of what this presentation is I'll hit
you with a point later but you've got to
make sure that that content is really
attention-grabbing or else you never
actually get to make your point
and I think this is true in your product
too if your product doesn't immediately
tell me what value it's solving for me I
don't care and I'm gonna get distracted
by the 50 million other things that are
happening in my life today so be up
front so now I want to move to talk to
about how do you build trust in
communities a human to humans what does
that look like
so Rachel believes that
is a confident relationship with the
unknown it's actually the mechanism that
we use to build confidence when we are
in a situation that we don't understand
I love this tweet I think it's fantastic
we used to say your mom would tell you
like don't talk to strangers on the
Internet and don't get in the car with
the stranger now we actually summon
strangers from the internet and they
drive us places not only that but we
actually stay in strangers homes too
with Airbnb this is completely changing
the way that we build and conceptualize
trust so she talks about this as a trust
leap basically you're putting trust in
some platform that there's some value
that you're wanting to gain there and
you're willing to make that leap into
the unknown to get into a stranger's car
to stay at a stranger's house or let a
stranger stay in your house we talked
about Airbnb I like Airbnb because they
are actually talking about how they
build trust in their platform their blog
their design blog goes into a lot of the
ways that they build trust in their
platform whenever you come on board is
an Airbnb user there's two different
types of experiences people who are
inviting people to stay in their homes
and people who are looking for homes
when you list your home on Airbnb
there's a whole lot of steps about what
types of content how to take good photos
ratings and reviews to help build trust
and confidence that your home is a safe
place for people to stay in and on the
reverse side if you're looking to stay
at an Airbnb house when you onboard is a
it is an end user they step you through
how to upload a profile and provide
demographic information you have a
history and a score as you stay at
various properties and get a reputation
rating that a homeowner can actually see
when they're deciding if they want to
accept your your stay really fascinating
and Rachel's book goes into a lot of
details about both uber and Airbnb so if
you're interested in this concept her
book does a wonderful job explaining
this but ultimately she calls this the
trust stack that when there's something
that we kind of sense the value but we
don't understand or there's uncertainty
in it what needs to happen for us to be
able to trust that platform the first
thing is we have to trust the idea both
parties have to individually want to be
part of the platform you need to like
the idea that hey I have an extra room
in my house I want to make some extra
money I'll let someone stay in that room
and then controvert and then on the
other side you have someone who maybe
doesn't want to stay at a hotel once a
cheaper rate or to have a more local
experience they're both buying into the
idea of the platform of Airbnb the same
thing is true with uber people want to
go somewhere and I want to make money
driving people somewhere second you have
to trust the platform you have to
believe that the platform is looking out
for you in Airbnb you hope that the
platform is going to Black List
homeowners who are trying to scam people
or crazy partiers who are just looking
to trash a house you're trusting that
the platform is doing the work to try to
maintain health and safety and then
finally you actually want to build trust
with that other user when you get
connected to another to an uber driver
or an uber driver decides to pick you up
how do they make that decision that this
is not some drunk idiot at 2:00 a.m.
who's going to throw up in my car that's
what the platforms are doing they're
building a reputation rating
ratings and reviews there's lots of ways
to do this but if you can trust in the
idea the platform and then the other
users on that platform you can easily
build that trust to get to completely
unknown people strangers to go in on an
idea and actually create value now
what's interesting is that Rachael talks
about how Trust is changing and
particularly how technology is speeding
up that change of trust when you think
about Humanity as a whole we started
with local trust when humans were just
cave men or small cities we didn't have
the ability to fly to different
continents it was really as far as I
could actually
myself there was really a small handful
of people that would know me for my
entire life is a cave person very local
trust I I've grown up took with my
next-door neighbor next to me I know who
they are I know their character like I
can vouch for them it's very local trust
and then we start as we industrialized
people start moving people have carts
they can now go much much further than
they could have ever have walked we have
airplanes so you can now fly across
oceans but before you could have never
crossed so we need a concept of portable
trust how can you trust in random
strangers who are literally coming from
overseas or from other countries that
you don't know anything about that's
where we we have institutional trust
things like governments things like
banks where individual companies and
corporations and institutions actually
stand as a way to measure trust between
two unknown parties and now we're
actually starting to move into
distributed trust where you actually
don't need to know anything about the
other person that you can trust in the
system things like Airbnb and uber
examples of distributed trust where we
can take distributed assets and create
unified value across them and what's
really interesting is that technology is
helping this move even faster so I don't
want to spend too much time on this but
I think it's an interesting talk about
why is Institute wise distributed trust
better than institutional when you think
about institutional trust your bank the
government you may not know how that
actually works it's a big monolithic
thing that you don't really have
transparency in to how it works it's a
closed system you don't really have
direct control over earth you do it's
through a long arduous process of policy
change etc it's a centralized think
there's a single point of failure for
many of these institutional systems and
it's a very top-down approach you have
to trust that the institution has your
best interest in mind and that may not
actually be true whereas distributed
trust is transparent we all know
collectively how that
distributed platform works we have
visibility into its by definition
inclusive because there's no one sync
party that gets to decide how it works
it's too centralized there's no one
single point of failures we talk about
security and technology solutions
decentralisation is great it helps build
resilient systems its accountable and
then it actually is bottom-up there's no
one single Authority and said everyone
collectively gets to decide how that
thing works so let's look at how trust
leaps are accelerating and it's really
this idea of how how do we move from
local to institutional and to
distributed and certainly there's some
future state of this as well if we look
at personal transportation and like I
mentioned before it was as far as I
could walk and then we invented the
wheel in the cart and we could go much
further distances then the Train and the
automobile and the airplane you can see
how technology allows us to go farther
faster in to broaden our experience and
our horizons the same things true with
payments in the early days you need to
barter you need to have something to
trade
that was worth value we then moved into
physical currency where we abstract that
but it doesn't matter that you want to
chicken and I don't have a chicken
I can chain coins instead we move to
credit cards where when you think about
it a credit card is a really weird
mechanism cheques are also the very same
way it's basically just an IOU and as we
move to centralized banks where we have
money and our bank accounts that we can
trade via swiping a little plastic
credit card or writing an IOU on a paper
check now we're moving into digital
payments I can pay with things with my
watch and that's actually not a bank
account number at all it's just a
transaction ID and we're now moving into
things like Bitcoin and blockchain based
currency where transactions can globally
be trusted because there's a central
ledger you can see how technology is
enabling a lot of these advancements and
allowing us to move faster and that
really is what the focus of this
is that technology really accelerates
the rate at which we make these trusts
leaps and it further distributes trust I
think this is a really powerful concept
but it's one that comes with great
responsibility so I want to actually now
pivot into talking about types of trust
so we looked at trust peer-to-peer a
human to a human and then we looked at
trust in communities let's look at now
the types of trust that you build with
people and in communities this is from a
study by HSBC they're a bank an
International Bank study 12,000
participants across 11 countries it's
pretty globally representative there's a
full report if you want to search for
technology and trust or trust in
technology really awesome report that
has some great data in statistics but
they have this chart that I really like
basically you have an interaction a
level something very very shallow that
you don't really care about or something
very deep that's a very deep
relationship and you've got a long term
relationship something that you don't
expect to change and then you've got a
temporary relationship you divide the
crotch and up like this you end up with
a really interesting grid we're up in
the top corner long term in deep that's
love that's relationships you expect
that person to have a very deep and
long-term connection with on the
controversy on the contrary temporary
and shallow something that is very very
temporary very lustful shallow and
long-term is something necessary we
don't really care about it but it's
something we're investing in long-term
and then finally deep and temporary
something that we choose because it's
functional it provides value to us so
let's look at a couple of things on this
map pretty obvious up in the corner love
family and friends these are people that
we build long-term relationships build
deep trust with them on the other end we
have lust startups and new technologies
blockchain and whatever the new
JavaScript language is today or a
library these things come they go we
forget about them and
it's very very infrequent that these
things move out of that stage in the
necessary side we have things like
government work financial institutions
things that we just have to have even
though we may not want to do them here
who here likes their bank nobody we have
our banks because we need them we need a
place to put our money so that we can
have credit cards and actually five
things that we want we may not really
like government we may not agree with
government but we can all see the value
and the organization and the structure
that that brings to our countries and at
the top you have the functional and the
functional is what we deal with every
single day it's the things you choose
because it makes sense experts you go
and see a doctor who knows about the
very specific issue that you have you
trust them because of their
institutional knowledge you've got
things like objects cars phones laptops
we choose these devices because they
help us accomplish something it's
functional and websites things that
provide us some amount of value and the
moment that they don't they go away
let's keep looking at this they actually
did an interesting look at brands what I
find fascinating is Apple and Samsung
remember this global study apples
therefore primarily the United States
Samsung is for many of the Asian
countries these are companies that have
transcended just functionality to
actually creating fans who love their
products I personally live in the Apple
ecosystem I have one of every Apple
device sitting on this desk right now
that's something where Apple has created
not only devices that are functional but
did I actually really like using that I
love using every new Apple product I'll
go out and buy Samsung I personally
believe differently about that but
Samsung is loved on the other side of
the world largely because their products
are priced
more sensitively to the countries where
maybe you're not looking for a premium
product whenever you are talking about a
company or a brand I really like this
framework because it challenges you to
ask what value is a product providing
you and how deep is that relationship
so why do we care about this what's
interesting so this study also asked the
question of I believe technology will
make the world a better place you see
the United States here 67% of people
believe that that was true that's
actually the global average which i
think is an interesting note but you
notice that some of the Asian countries
it's a much higher percentage technology
forward countries like China and Japan
and Asia
you see competent countries like the
European Union where that's a little
lower that kind of explains why we're
saying things like GDP are much more
concern about how technology is changing
the way that we interact with our world
they would a step further and then ask
people have you heard of this technology
very very simple have you heard of
watching 59% of people had not heard of
watching what's interesting about this
is that after they asked them if they
hadn't heard it they gave them a one
sentence overview of what that is and
people dramatically became much more
accepting of that technology people
didn't know what Robo advisors were for
using artificial intelligence algorithms
they give them a one sentence
description of what that is and people
are like oh yeah okay I could see the
value in that I use that it's
interesting in that it's very very
simple things like giving very basic
definitions of what technology does that
makes people much more open to using it
this isn't super complicated and
certainly as people learn more about
technologies they've become more
normalized we now see peer-to-peer
payments and fingerprint recognition
things that we generally accept now that
were very controversial when they first
came out a great lesson where just by
helping your users understand what your
technology or what your product can do
can really go a long way to building
trust now here's the slide that really
upsets me in this study they asked
people what are the things that concern
you most and this is sort of how the
questions can I'll quickly mention that
you'll see the colors represent
different generations there's not much
difference in generational perception of
different challenges but the one thing
that stands out to me about this entire
graph all these things with red arrows
are technology fails people commande
concerns are concerned about their data
being leaked bank accounts being hacked
debit cards being cloned identity theft
email scams begging for money these are
literally problems that are causing
people everyday worry and concern more
so than being lied to by close family
member or buying something faulty or
fake or actually physical harm by being
mugged we're literally causing people
daily distress with the technology that
we're building because we're not doing
it in building it in responsible ways
this slide makes me really upset and
angry because I do fundamentally believe
technology can make the world a better
place
but not when we're not being responsible
with it technology distrust causes a lot
of our daily worry and anxiety and it
doesn't need to be that way and that's
what this talk is about is how can we
build products in a way that trust that
people trust them and it we respect
people's privacy and help them be more
secure so I want to now use some
examples what I like to call trust fails
I'm not doing this to call out
particular companies but I think seeing
examples of why certain data breaches or
privacy violations or problematic I'll
start with the first one which I'm sure
you're all tired of hearing about
Equifax what's interesting about Equifax
is that the scale of the data breach and
the fact that the peoples who data was
breached didn't necessarily even know
Equifax had it or even knew why they had
that data
Equifax of course is a credit monitoring
service they collect financial
information to make literal decisions
about if you should get loans or be able
to buy a car they're getting all of this
information
without your permission or knowledge and
then they're not protecting it things
like your social security information
thinks that can't be changed your name
your address your gender your phone your
driver's license photo your passports
actual military and state IDs this is
just blatantly terrible a company that
you didn't know whose data that had your
data then didn't responsibly secure it
absolutely unacceptable and then they're
using that data to make decisions that
can literally lose you the ability to
buy a house or car or whatever that
thing is next is one that hits me very
close I am an openly gay man grinder is
a hook-up app unfortunately they leaked
location data basically it's a
location-based app to find other gay
people around you literally with an
unauthenticated api that anyone on the
internet could poll you could pull exact
GPS locations of users particularly in a
minority class I travel a lot and there
are countries where I can literally be
put to death and this app is leaking my
exact geo coordinate that's really
problematic really concerning in an app
that's supposed to bring community and
connectedness actually puts me at risk
and most people don't even know that
this is a problem
secondly they had a third party data
leakage they allow you to set HIV status
in the application and unfortunately
they were sending that to third party
analytics company first of all without
and encrypted an unencrypted connection
so anyone could sit in and read those
messages and then secondly literally
it's tying your username your email your
geolocation to your HIV status this is
something that should be healthcare data
HIPAA compliant and it's not literally
unencrypted can easily be watched and
it's tied to GPS okay like oh my god
this is terrible
these things have been fixed interesting
enough I've done data requests with all
of the major dating apps OkCupid Tender
grinder scruff grinder is the one
company that has yet to send me data and
I was telling you the data that I've
gotten from these companies is
terrifying every time you log into a
dating app it's got your exact location
and it's got that history for every
single time you've opened that app why
why do companies need that data they do
not there is no reason that they needed
that data certainly if they're going to
collect that data to provide their
service it's their responsibility to
secure that next this was earlier this
year the FBI sound an urgent request go
restart and update your routers because
Russian malware is now sitting on major
brands like Linksys Netgear and TCP link
routers that are very likely in your
homes and what's difficult is I don't
know about you all but have you tried to
that your router software not exactly
something I struggle with it and I know
what I'm doing I can't call my mom and
say oh yeah gotta go update that router
software good luck I don't even think
she has the cord to go and plug in to be
able to do it fifty five hundred
thousand routers in at least 54
countries this is less problematic if it
were easy to update but the fact that
it's not easy to do literally the
hardware itself is compromised your host
and if you don't update the software
properly the malware gets back on there
and it watches every single thing you do
online hugely problematic again
companies that aren't doing their job to
help keep their products secure this
one's fun who here has an Alexa device
in their house okay less than I would
have thought okay there's a woman in
Portland where basically she was having
a private conversation in her living
room with her husband and somehow said a
series of trigger words where Alexa
engaged a phone call with one of her
contacts and then streamed the audio
from her living room her friend then
called her
a few minutes later and said hey were
you just talking to your husband about
this this thing and she was like what
what do you talk how do how do you know
that that was happening she literally
did not know that she had triggered a
hot mic in her own living room that
streaming her private conversation and
we're literally choosing to put these
devices in our homes every single day
Facebook I'm not even going to talk much
about this the Cambridge analytic a
scandal how they're using psychographic
data to rig elections basically those
cute little quizzes we all played four
years that told you like what character
we were in a TV show or what show you
liked leveraging psychographic data to
then target you with ads to change your
perception and to basically try to sway
elections what's interesting to me and
this one is that this was using data
that we voluntarily gave but didn't
realize how we could how it could be
used against us Facebook wasn't putting
proper controls around our personal data
in their platform and then that was used
to buy ads against us it doesn't stop
there though Facebook you may use them
log in with Facebook that little SSO
link that seems like a good idea yeah I
don't need to create our username and
password that I have to remember awesome
great except just a few weeks ago
Facebook had nearly half a million of
their SSO login tokens compromised how
about you but I don't know every single
website that I gave Facebook SSO access
into there is a settings panel buried
behind ten menus where you can see all
of those applications I looked at mine
347 websites that I had SSO tokens for
through Facebook as an user there's no
possible way I could have known the risk
vector there much less how do you
actually go and change that what do you
actually do at that point Facebook told
us months after that compromise had
happened you literally have already been
compromised in systems that you don't
even think Facebook is associated with
very problematic it doesn't stop there
though Facebook just a couple weeks ago
released this device called portal
that's literally a video and audio
communication channel so you can chat
with your friends and
family ok interest is sort of like Alexa
guess what they use it for first of all
I like love this photo Zuckerberg CEO of
Facebook if you look at his laptop here
he's got tape over both the microphone
and the camera on his laptop
he doesn't even trust the devices that
he's using every single day but yet his
company is building and an always-on
microphone and video camera that you put
in your home this is from a couple days
ago Facebook admits that it's camera
equipped listening device can collect
your data for ads they pitched this
product as something to connect with
your family and to always stay in touch
and instead or listening in to those
conversations and marketing to you to
ads we all had that weird case where you
say something in a conversation and then
weirdly like you start getting marketing
ads in all over the internet and you're
like how did they know that this is how
they know that there's literally a
device now that they're selling that
does this and they're actually admitting
that they're doing it so that brings me
to how do we build trust in these
products it's a difficult thing to do
we've talked about what Trust is what it
means but it's very very different to
actually build that in your products we
looked at some examples of products that
they failed at this I fundamentally
don't think these companies maliciously
were like yeah we're gonna put a piece
of hardware in someone's house that we
can listen to it and collect and market
ads to people I don't think that's
what's happening here this is where
companies are making very isolated
decisions the cascade into unforeseen
problems the grinder example they asked
for HIV data to help everyone be more
informed on the platform but then
accidentally didn't implement it right
and then started spewing that data all
over the internet we're making these
decisions maybe with the right heart and
mean but then don't take the
responsibility for what that actually
means for our products so what I'm
really talking about when building trust
in products is
how do you build trust to a machine it's
a very different concept the machine I
can't look at a machine and look at how
it's looking back at me or if it's mad
at me and doesn't want to talk you don't
have that feedback mechanism so it's
very different to actually build trust
with machines I go back to this
mechanism this is something where I sort
of plotted various types of things and
how they fall on this so we talked about
like Sam boys that Apple has people who
love technology
you've got your phone's your wearables I
put wearables at the very top because
it's something literally you wear on
your person that collects data very deep
connection but it's still temporary the
moment my Apple watch breaks I'm not
gonna use it anymore
what's interesting is that Fitbit did a
marketing blog post a few years ago
where they thought it would be fun to
aggregate everyone's data anonymously to
try to make broad strokes about what
people are doing and the blog post
basically was what does everyone doing
at 8 p.m. at night there's a sudden
spike and everyone's like going and
exercising not exactly what I want my
fitness data to be used for a fun cheeky
blog post they're talking about sex
people have sex at night and by
aggregating and time adjusting that they
were able to see spikes literally in
people's fitness trackers I don't like
that I did not consent to my data being
used for cute cheeky blog posts even if
you are anonymizing that data it's not
ok we have things like banks and
governments we use them because they're
necessary and they have high switching
costs it's difficult to move banks it
takes a long time you lose asset access
to your money for some amount of time
you've got transactional things that we
just use them because we have to
payments or websites
SSO logins we have fun little things
that are lusty like I seen on TV like
we're gonna laugh at it we're gonna
think about it for 10 minutes and we're
never gonna remember it ever again so
when you look at the failures of what
actually causes these things to fail
with functional items its literal
breakage or it fails you just stop using
it because it doesn't provide any
function privacy violations
you know if I'm wearing a connected
device than its spewing data all over
dinner and I'm gonna stop wearing that
device with love family and friends
you've got things like betrayal and
scandal that ruin those relationships
and then with lustful things it's just
either not important so you can forget
about it or it has no utility so you you
just don't do anything with it with
necessary things it's that constant like
oh there's another fee from my bank
there's another thing that's annoying to
me they're not meeting my expectations
and that finally builds up to a point
where I stopped using that altogether so
what's interesting about this is that I
think Trust fundamentally is a
differentiator for tech products you can
totally change the growth curve of your
company if you build products that
people trust people when they trust your
products they become advocates for your
products and your growth curve tilts up
but how do we actually build that trust
it's difficult we talked about how do
you think about trust but how do you
actually build it in practice I want to
again go back to the principles of how
we build trust with people and how we
build trust in communities that
authenticity that logic empathy the
competency and reliability and honesty
these are words that generally we like
that are things that we would like our
products and the services that we use to
honor so I want to go through a couple
of examples of just very obvious things
that you should do and I hope that
there's no one single way to say how to
build trust in your parts because
they're so different but I hope this
gives you some like things that you can
remember and talk with with your team's
we talked a lot about Alexa and how I
maybe don't like it but I think it does
a really great job at being clear when
the lights blue it's listening that is
such a genius idea I've literally a
three-year-old can understand how Alexa
works I talked to it the lights on
awesome I can ask it for something and I
want you to build consistency into your
products this is from the Apple human
interface guidelines
Google and Facebook and other companies
have their own as well use these these
are designed because it's what people
expect software to do when you're
choosing to not follow patterns on
platforms you are actively choosing to
trick people and to confuse people
I really if you're gonna violate this
you need to have a really really good
reason why for example on Mac OS the
blue button is the primary action that
you were intending to take this is a
secondary are you sure you want to do
that yes I want to secure empty my trash
and give me a little context about what
that actually means and then I want you
to provide continuous continuously prove
value of your product this is from
KISSmetrics an email marketing platform
they help you understand what their
product does for you this many people
converted through your campaign on our
platform literally data to prove that
the the proposition that you're signing
up a product to be used for is providing
value to you
so in summary education is very simple
you need to prove your products
competency and show the logic of your
product make it clear what's happening
and why what is it doing do people
understand what it's doing and then
shoot for value I do this because it's
just incrementally better I want to use
a service because it's ten times better
than what I'm doing today I use the
spreadsheet for something I'm not going
to replace some new fancy app unless it
provides me 10x value then that
spreadsheet you need to build
consistency because consistency builds
confidence in your product across the
entire product suite as your company
grows you get lots of teams that start
doing things in isolated manners that
maybe aren't consistent across the
platform you need to be consistent it
drives a trust in your entire product
suite and then you need to be relevant
humans contextualize interactions if I'm
talking with my mom I'm gonna have a
very different conversation with her
then I'm gonna have with a random
stranger
we contextualise things your products
should contextualize as well and should
have some common sense into it this is
an actual story where travel software
someone went in typed
Paris into it and it was like cool great
$4,700 or whatever price it was and
they're like awesome yes I'm gonna book
that what did they book it was not a
trip to Paris France it was a trip to
Paris Texas and it was so expensive
because you can't fly to Paris Texas you
have to fly to another place get on a
train and then rent a car
what who googles I want a trip to Paris
Texas nobody if you're a travel platform
you know that when someone types Paris
they want a trip to Paris France basic
common sense into your products and
simplicity wins
Alexis blue when it's listening it's red
when it's muted we can argue about if
this is actually muted or not but that's
a different talk for a different day
again the UI principles of Alexa genius
and that's why they're in everyone's
homes because it's obvious how it works
this is Spotify I love Spotify I think
it's cool it suggests a new music that I
would have never chosen to use but this
is an actual error I got one day an
error occurred why is my music not
playing that's all I care about
I use a VPN which had gotten
disconnected and triggered I can't
connect to the internet to stream your
song
okay that's context that you've given me
you lost Internet access
great I know how to solve that problem I
don't know how to solve this problem
build empathy into your products if they
error don't blame me because I don't
know how your product works you can
design empathy into your products this
is something Mel chimp does when you
type a username and password it's gonna
tell you hey we don't have an account
for that do you need a request what your
username is little tiny moments of
empathy actually helped me use the
product and helped me actually
accomplish the thing that I was there to
get now you may ask
wait this can be abused yes you're right
it can be abused but what's interesting
is that they're actually using this
abuse vector where someone could
basically enumerate user names they're
using a web application firewall laughs
to block that you can only do this three
times before it says nope you're a robot
who's trying to enumerate
user names but then they also collect
those malicious IPs and use that to
block across their platform they're
using a moment of empathy to actually
collect data about their malicious
attackers and then blocking that across
their entire platform that's a really
cool moment where you gave value and you
created value for yourself internally
there are what tons of moments where you
can do exactly this rather than say no
we're not gonna build that feature
because it's a security risk probably
not or there's at least ways to mitigate
that chrome is another interesting one
to look at they've vented the concept of
auto-update what was the last time you
thought about updating chrome never
because it's always up to date it can
patch it any velocity that it wants
because it does it for you behind the
scenes that's awesome
take the the the mental load of having
to what what version my on like Java is
out of date like I know there's
something bad about Java so hopefully
I'm not installing the bad one that
people to know have it update itself
this checks and validates that the
downloads it's getting are actually the
right ones and are safe and secure
so in summary of security there we go
build reliability and empathy empathy
into your products if you're gonna
collect data make it explicit people
need to understand the day or you're
collecting and if you collect it please
secure it and if you can't properly
secure it or you don't have the
resources to secure it don't ask for it
period end of story
it's your responsibility to secure data
that you asked for
and then finally handle problems within
errors empower rather than blame if you
think about you go to a restaurant and
have a bad experience you don't get
blamed for that the restaurant doesn't
say well you were bad you know patron no
instead you say I want to talk to a
manager and the manager does whatever
they can to help make that situation
better imagine if your product errors
out and rather than saying oops
105 arrow 500 o X whatever it is what if
it said hey it looks like you were
trying to accomplish this here's a help
ticket about or a help article about
this or do
talk to support click here to start a
chat help me solve my own problem try to
get in front of that and of course build
your products so that they don't error
out but if they do and those error
states build empathy into them
transparency is another one that I
really like Apple does this really well
this is something that they're going
very big on I encourage you if you want
examples of how a company is building
security and privacy into your products
go to apple.com such privacy literal
examples of how they're building their
products with privacy and security in
mind they're very upfront about what
data they're collecting they use this
little handshake that I really like it's
like an agreement I'm gonna give you
data and you're gonna give me value and
I can clearly understand what that means
these are not legalese Terms and
Conditions these are real human
explanations of what a product and
service is doing Twitter as much as I
maybe don't like Twitter this is a
really well-designed privacy Control
Center the defaults are another question
they're all on by default which isn't
great but it at least tells me what it's
doing a description that's
understandable and if I want to go learn
more if there's a link off to that and
then I can actually toggle and control
it I can control what Twitter does
that's awesome
here's an example of what I call don't
be creepy this is a cycle act that I use
that basically you turn it on it listens
for sound and movement using the Geo the
gyroscopes of your phone to give you a
sleep score what it does however though
is that it looks on the network that
you're on for other people who are in
that network the let me tell you the use
case here is that if you and your
partner both use this app you're in the
same bed and they want to use the data
from each of your phones to cancel out
movements if your partner gets up in the
middle of the night I'm a single man
this was 2 a.m. when I woke up at a
hotel
Emel is my coworker why does this app
broadcast mo to my phone and on Emma's
phone it says Taylor McCaslin iPhone X
what this is something behind I'm on a
VPN on a hotel Wi-Fi network in the
middle of the
and someone can detect if I'm there
using this app that's creepy I don't
care if you had a good use case for this
you should this is just obvious that you
should not broadcast this kind of
information so that brings me to smart
defaults know what defaults you are
opting your your customers into this is
actually the recommendation that I have
for you to go set you to your lock
screen today I can walk up to your
unlocked or to your locked iPhone and I
can trigger Siri and I can ask it to
call your wife or tell me what's next on
my calendar or call my dad turn these
things off turn everything but return
missed calls you don't need these things
on a lock screen especially now with
face ID we're littering you look at it
and it's unlocked know what you're
signing your customers up for with
defaults so in in summary here be honest
and act with authenticity make it clear
what you're collecting and what you're
doing with that data use smart privacy
defaults and explicitly state when
behavior changes if your auto updating
my program and you're changing the
behavior that I expect tell me about
that so finally if you're wondering how
do I actually do this in my companies
talk to your users who use them they
will tell you mind-blowing things that
you never would have thought about your
products and when I say talk to your
users I mean really listen to them ask
them why and when they tell you oh it's
because I want to do ask them why do you
want to do that ask again because you
want to get down to that root cause of
what is the problem you're actually
trying to solve deeply understand the
situations that they're in and why
they're using your products and then
finally empathize with them maybe there
we go empathize if you do this with your
products you will build better products
and you won't make some of these blatant
mistakes that we've seen today
ultimately building trust is not easy
and technology products but it's worth
it that's all I got
thank you
I probably got a runaway so thanks for
coming and I'll hang out and answer
questions