good afternoon no flea a that good lunch
and you know we're going to make it we
won't do a lull so you don't go into
sleep so make it a bit more exciting so
my name is sue brakmar Swamy I lead the
secretary architecture and engineering
team in DISA and just to kind of give
you a little bit more context of what we
do so we take care of everything that in
every single product under visa to make
sure they are almost voluntary free
right be our goal is to make sure
honored personal we can be resilient
against the creatures but we ensure from
life end to end from architecture design
SSD LC pentest post post production
monitoring the whole product security
umbrella is in this or in this team so
unlike most companies where architecture
is just blueprint we are actually much
more hands-on so today we are here with
their two more speakers my colleagues
here we know then Oleg will Lesley
they'll be the key speakers I'm just
going to give you the highlights and
then I'll hand over to B note so won't
talk about the journey that we had for
the last three years right this has been
a very long journey and before I go into
the presentation how many of you here
actually are doing data production in
some ways right which means encryption
hashing devaluation okay most of you so
you know in this age right as we know
that the data is a new currency and of
course hackers want to go for go after
the honeypot there's value so the data
is going to be not that that's the place
eventually they want to land in so our
goal the mission that we established
three years back is to ensure that the D
value every single byte that we collect
frost has installed in visa right we
have over three billion credit cards and
we our seven trillion
records that we actually try to protect
every day so this is a very monumental
task so we had a we had a very I would
say the the support that Dakar
from the Board of Directors all the way
was unimaginable right we got all the
support we got we don't have an issue
the resources so be there in some way
we're very fortunate to have a very high
support top-down and bottom-up so
today's agenda as I said we'll do it
quickly we talk about the why because
you know us yes InfoSec folks right it's
always that we should start with the why
before we go and start in all giving you
know king of the standards and the
policies and the resolutions so it's
kind of obvious to a lot of people but
it's also a difficult part right because
you're trying to explain why is it
important for you to think about data
data security from the get-go so that's
what I will be covering and we live we
know talk about the maturity models
basically you know every every company
has their own journey and you know there
are different ways they approach so we
actually looked at one of the things
that we assess on a yearly basis we have
partner who come and assess our maturity
model right so take advantage would
right so they have been giving us
assessment that we use and we use that
to support the investment decisions as
well as be able to plan for the next
year and the building blocks obviously
there's a lot of building words that
come together to deliver a solution at
scale
we'll talk about the benefits and then
take away okay so know it's something
out right in so I want to start with
obviously I don't have to preach the
choir here right you know they you know
this is the this is a outdated data here
we're not even showing some of the
recent breaches that happened in 2018 so
you know it's matter of when versus you
know if right it's a matter when the
breach is going to happen and the reason
why I want to bring the slide up is you
know there's a lot of investment that go
into information security program
and you know at different levels and but
yet understand where the attacks are
coming from so this data that we got I
think the source is OS 62% of the
attacks are actually exploiting the
features so this is the noise you know
features the developers are measured by
the feature velocity and how fast they
can deliver the with the features right
obviously they know they have been
incentivized
to deliver things faster and cheaper and
innovative way so when they released a
new feature is it you know all the
things that can be exploited right those
are things that we had to worry about in
SS DLC and 30% of them involve web
applications right so if you take
Equifax Equifax you know the hackers
wins right into the struts ma library
and be able to we X filter exfiltrate
data so the web attack surface is
growing every year obviously everybody
has presence on the internet and a lot
of times applications are talking back
to your core services internally through
ap is right it's no longer a standalone
portal they're all interconnected
measure there in fact you know in 2005
Amazon went with making sure the
Amazon's
C was just be sent a memo said if you
don't get on board on s in a soap or you
an hour
rusty you API bandwagon you'll be fired
right so he throws a mandate that he
established to make sure everything is a
service so there is a lot more
interconnectivity of services and the
last one is interesting because no
longer the attacks are happening simply
through human beings he you know he
can't afford to just sit there and hack
the attacks or to start the
reconnaissance of a kill chain starts at
the very early stage with a bot scanning
automatically and figuring out where
potential weak spots are right once they
figure out the weak spots then you have
a human being now including some of the
artificial intelligence techniques are
used to go much more deeper right so
it's kind of a methodical way of how
pathetical and very sophisticated we
have
hackers look at similar so it's no
longer just user sitting behind a screen
and obviously you know data breach comes
down to you know it's not about you know
simple brand impact obviously this brand
will be impacted stock price may take a
hit but it's really an existing shell
threat right if you don't do data
protection in some ways and making sure
you guard your particular crown jewels
right it does have impact on the company
itself so with that mandate right and
and kind of pivoting into how companies
approach we you know if you walk into an
RSA Conference right it happens every
year and by and large most of the
vendors are actually focusing on you
know appliances solutions and network
security the you know how do you harden
your data center right so the but that's
ninety percent the investments and but
they attacks if you look at our attacks
only twenty of a personal attacks are
coming through network right the biggest
attack most companies worry about on
network is DDoS right because that has a
high impact on your service availability
but the sophisticated attacks the much
more laser focused they are going to
come through a web vector or ap a vector
or some other vectors so this kind of
shows that you know the mindset we are
if we're still living is that to secure
the perimeter right the you know what we
have what we call the soft chewy Center
secured by a hard shell of mmm security
right so and but the if again if you'll
flip that chart Saudi a person of the
attacks are coming through web and yet
ten personal investment going into the
you know securing your applications and
data and so I think I'm sorry mr. Slye
programs sorry went too fast so now the
coming back will be you know the Y so
for us you know we worry about
obviously they're in the consumer impact
we worry about the regulatory
requirements
now with especially GDP our right
there is impact on I mean you know it's
a impact on your bottom line the GDP our
penalties can actually go up to 2 to 4
percent of your revenue so if you're
making a twenty billion dollar revenue
like us right that's a significant
impact so we can't be worried about the
you know the cost of remediation
I think Equifax is still reeling from
the breach they had and they're still
spending investing money to you know
work with you know work with regulators
apart from cleaning up apartment making
sure your application is patched now we
are deal with all the other is the post
you know post breach right working with
regulators making sure that you know you
have a program that is much much
stronger and be able to prove to the
auditors that you have raised the bar
and you know the customer loss right
obviously you know this is something
that every you know we always say the
consumers vote with a wallet they have a
choice right if they have to choose
between us and our competition you know
if they don't trust us our brand you
know they will go and reach out to the
wallet and get the next next great card
sorry how to use a different digital
payment method so this is the area that
you know eventually it drives the it
drives us to think about how to ensure
the crown jewels are protected so with
that I'm going to hand over to Vinod and
every node is going to talk about the
maturity model Thank You subra yes it's
1:00 p.m. I know actually so I was in
couple of sessions and at 1:00 p.m. so I
know how it will be so
but I know actually like it sobre worn
by giving you the numbers which we
always see actually in the newspapers
okay
and we always reading actually what is
happening not only we a as IT
professionals even high school kids and
middle school kids
nobody's knows what is happening
actually in the data world the preaches
okay so everyone knows actually what is
happening but at the same time are we
really addressing actually that problem
being a responsible IT professionals so
so my first job actually in 1998 I
developed a crypto component which can
be used by ASPA applications it's in
1998 it's like almost like a two decades
I complete it still I am solving the
same problem actually which I started
actually 20 years before it's not
because actually the pro the solution is
not there the solution is not is there
for the last two decades but it's not
formalized it's not dictated it's not
pushed by the management as subra
mentioned most of the focusing actually
on network security which is fallback
actually the infrastructure but the
front ending is web application yes in
the last one decade actually we are
saying we are focusing again on web
application security right that's where
actually we have war ASP but again we
are focusing on actually how to fix the
problem how to fix sequel injection okay
how to fix other injection but at the
same time we know that actually hackers
are more smarter than us and and instead
of actually looking only at how to fix
the sequel injection so if we need to go
beyond actually and we need to see if
SQL injection what I'm whatever I am
trying to do if it is not solving the
problem yeah make covered devaluation if
he steals a if a hacker steals my data
is still valuable information that I
lost so so if we devalue actually the
data which he can hack so that is a that
is the thing actually we need to say for
example sequel injection
if simple injection is not addressed
then their database can be in the hands
of hackers right so let me get into the
details as well the maturity model why
do we need to talk about maturity model
and until we see the news about the data
breaches not not from the small
companies like not from the startups
from the bigger companies we need to
keep on discussing on this maturity
model it's mean that there is still room
actually for us actually to fix this
problem so everyone has possibility to
educate these and improve this so we
tried actually putting this data
production solution maturity model and
every organization is focusing on
enterprise security maturity model how
can how they can improve security
maturity model overall but then they're
giving like one line or two lines they
encrypt and give the data so it's not
giving actually the more details
actually how exactly that encryption
need to happen so there is no specific
timeline there is no specific framework
there is no specific budget allocated
actually for the data production as so
so everyone need to get you to the
deeper of a hand-up provide a charter
and fix this problem and I'm like you
I'm in over 20 years actually in this IT
industry and most of my time actually I
spent in security and I'm lucky to have
lucky to be part of visa at this point
of time and before joining this
diversity completely product development
I was with RSA Sam's and Hawaii
technologists have many product
companies I work and building security
products this is the first time actually
I got an opportunity changing from
preacher to actually implemented earlier
I was preaching as a vendor to everyone
a you need to do this you need to do
this you need to do this but now
actually I'm implementing that and if
some other company maybe I will not get
this opportunity in this I got an
opportunity as Supra mentioned last five
years my primary for
is again protecting the data and
defining the data practice strategies
and solutions in risk meter and this
activity actually from that experience
so how exactly anyone actually can
follow this and this is actually a basic
elements we put together and defined as
a maturity model from level 1 level 2
level 3 level 4 and this is not the de
facto it is one of the best bases
actually and someone can integrate more
of coffee
so as I'm saying actually like we define
the level one which we calling it the
basic security the major elements is
every every company has to know where is
their data and what data is actually
sensitive so first they need to be score
actually where is the data when we say
that at all
we both report what is sensitive
information for the tender price so that
if that is different for each
organization that's depending on the
business model so they it will be
changing so so they need to perform
actually we don't need to perform data
discovery again automated discoveries
are not not hundred-person covering at
the same time you need to shell out a
lot of the process speed to is core
actually where your data is and so it
need to be a mix it actually so both
automatic disco as well as manual
discovery need to be there and another
one is a data of death now then we need
to have a data protection functionality
need to be available as a framework
availability and the nature major
features is like encryption and
tokenization apart from that once the
data got protected we need to provide
access controls both for data as well as
key just providing access control to
data is not enough so the key is the
main main key for the data to be
protected
so the key access management who can
access the data need to become know to
be addressed so this we are calling a
two level one
so being selective level one so
definitely every product whoever is
developing enterprise product must need
to ensure that they have the switch and
the same time whoever implementing a
product application in a company either
with the courts application or homegrown
application they must need to address
this so why we say away we said actually
there must lead to in the last query of
journey I interacted with many big
vendors big product vendors enterprise
product vendors still most of them are
lacking this feature encryption in their
application their statement is oh we
will not take care of it the database
administrator will take care of it
what are we said who is the one of your
data your application is the one of your
data not the database administrator I
have not a system administrator so you
need to control how it need to be
protected don't delegate actually there
is your responsibility to the downstream
so so we need to take it for our
actually and we need to see our vendors
all addressing this problem and the
second one is the repeatable maturity
again data production it's a it's a very
weak term
so where is the data so data typically
will be defined actually in three
different places and that I press in
transit in reviews so we need to ensure
actually way that the data is getting
protected at all these places not at one
place because the threat can happen
actually anywhere and another important
factor actually a key to a rotation in
the real key capability this is very
important actually when we think of like
what happens actually the data is key is
legally kick you're compromised so we
always believe in the difference in
depth so whatever security controls we
put we know that actually it's not it's
not under that's insecure okay so we
need to be prepared for the worst so at
the same time there the tiered approach
so application level DB level and access
level like these are the different
levels actually where the data will be
managed at application layer database
layer
the file system layer in the last actual
storage level so where do we protect the
data and what is the what is the results
of it and a solution framework one and
Enterprise designing it need to have the
solutions for all these levels ok yes
application level is the best it's not
mean that solution should have only
application level because there are
there are valid reasons why Nia
some applications cannot use application
level data production if you say my
solution framework does not have DB
level and the system level they will
stop and Crippin the data because they
don't have application level data
production and level play is a managed
Security Manager maturity so here we
select Li so far we are talking about
level 1 level 2 it can be implemented by
any organization any product company
because it does not cost too much other
than the development time so where is
coming to the level 3 here we are
talking about a centralized hardware
based key manager system this can be
invested actually then we medium to the
big companies where as a small company
startup company they may not be an
equation to invest money actually on
procuring hsn's and integrating with it
but imitatable years and other services
yes that is also possible so that's why
actually I know there's actually 2 level
3 otherwise that is also very important
factor
so here the keys need to be centrally
managed and another one is interoperable
with KMIP
and PK sis lemon these are the two
standards so we are familiar with the K
might be here and pick is his level so
the pkcs 11 is a two decade of old
standard which is very important
actually to be known by every developer
because if we don't know that actually
he don't know what is the capacity they
can integrate with a centralized key
manager and in the same way k MIT which
is one decade old standard from biases
and that is bringing actual fourth
generation key management systems
adoptable by any product in an
application so the last one is
optimizing security whatever we do the
keys always make me in the memory ok so
even it's a fraction
I'm the keys went there in memory
there's a probability of attack so that
is a optimizing maturity we need to see
actual how it exactly we can address it
so the latest one is is SGX but there
are different different features
available actually to address this but
it's not hundred percent foolproof as of
today okay getting to be usable details
actually in the data discovery so as I
mentioned actually operating in manual
disco II need to be there it's not just
manual discovery or you're not just out
of it it is Corey what did it automatic
disco is very costly as we have
experienced we could not able to churn
through all the trillions of Records
that to find out where is my sensitive
data so it should be collaborate you and
the security teams need to discuss with
each and every application architect and
have have a security or picture review
and understand and post them actually
where is your data and both the parties
need to be responsible it's not like
just security or today and the
developing team need to know that
actually why this question is posted to
me okay so they need to be open actually
in terms of for providing work sensitive
data there and the data protection
functionality when I say the encryption
tokenization so an encryption was there
for most most of the time as we know but
the protonation again is like around 10
years or concept actually came
so the tokenization resolved there are
some use cases why sun applications
cannot add up encryption if they have a
business logic
business logic actually which required
put for a bit of the same data so
they're disguised actually to use the
encryption so that is the reason there
are two major features came like format
preserving encryption and tokenization
so one solution need to have both of
them and as I mentioned key access
management key solution for all data
production and make sure you have a
centralized key access control it's not
just like a local key access control and
the same with the data
controls so the level to as I said think
beyond just at rest protection okay
so we know that actually our
responsibility is product data
everywhere but most of the places
actually when everyone focus on that at
rest so they say actually my data is
resting at the stories yes always the
data will be resting at the stories only
it's not mean that actually we need to
protect it the rest only okay so if we
raise your product at rest hundred
percent like storage level the threats
on voice level and DB level and
application level is not getting
addressed so it's almost like you're not
providing in necessary security there
there are some cases where you are not
you cannot enable application level data
production only those cases you need to
look for other alternatives and with
with other additional security controls
so so that attracts actually you need to
you need to focus actually whatever the
data is residing for more than a
specific time not the specific time is
considered data at rest so that if that
depending on actual each organization
how the other security controls so if
your other security control very
controls are very good you can make it
like if the data is resetting no tell
you an hour then it is dead at rest but
if you feel actually like the other
security controls are not strong then
minimize that timeline also so then call
it as data at rest and take care of
protecting the data and in the fly in
flight so when the data are moving from
one component to another component it's
not only within the organization with
the partners outside the organization
make sure your data production framework
have a have a functionality to protect
it actually on the why it's not only the
TLS just enabling the TLS is not enough
because when you are interacting with
the third party entities there are a lot
of intermediate network
actually we'll be there if you're just
relying on the TLS the transport layer
security so you are protecting it up to
the terminator TLS terminator not the
end up location but if you see the one
about the data the end applications of
the warners of the data it should not be
with any other any other intermediate
hops and the in use as I mentioned this
is again a very very tough tough problem
to chakra at address so so in use in
inside application exactly when the data
in during processing so the data
actually will be in years so we need to
make sure actually like the data is
protected in the threshold yes it's a
very very challenge problem actually so
the level actually still we are
continuing here here it's a as I
mentioned actually the key rotation and
rekeying is very important so assume
that actually I encrypted the data and
the key cannot be rotated so what
happens actually in the wall are like in
the middle of the lights and one says
hey he's got a compromised so there is
no means actually to rotate it like you
will ask actually the management hey
give me one month time I will shut down
the service let me rotate the data let
me rotate the key so no so you need to
design actually your application
integration thinking that you
you really haven't needed actually to
rotate the key and have it to by design
so that actually like a jewel you can
you can rotate the key and the V key at
any point of time it's not only after
two years if someone asks you to rotate
it key to remind you should have been a
person to rotate the key tonight without
shutting down your application so there
are different actually proven methods
available and just adopt them so don't
think that actually it is a after map
don't think that lock a let us see
actually after two years because the key
can be the key can be used actually for
two years so but your application need
to design such that actually it can use
it and if you are developing a product
and you're integrating actual encryption
make sure you provide this capability
and application Larry data production as
I mentioned mentioned right so so the
levels actually with application tier
database and file system level and
storage level ok so all these things
that actually you need to first by
default think that actually how to solve
the data production in my application
layer because as a application wanna
Europe the warrant for the data not the
database administrator or segment system
administrator so if you are not
protecting it and delegating there so
you're Lee you are leaving some room
actually for attackers to attack your
data okay
so always like your and most of these
languages again depending on actually
with technologies so you can you can
increase the technologies there so make
sure actually your solution framework
have the capability to integrate
standard set of languages and as I
mentioned pkcs 11 and KMIP so these are
the standard protocols so what we are
seeing actually most of the applications
some vendors but enterprise vendors so
if big vendors the top
under vendors they're still there
they're still not adopting these the
problem of not adopting this no I mean
because this 11 in decay might be so if
I'm a vendor X Y is there I say yeah I
have actually capability for encryption
right where are you keeping your kids
yes I'm keeping the keys next to my data
so what what is the use of wait I lock
my house and I keep the key next to my
door so there is no there is no
valuation there so some some little bit
more vendors like around 40 to 50
percent that going forward in there
saying yes I'm encrypting you the CAC
data and I'm keeping my key in another
server hey how do you interact actually
with observer or no you need to buy this
product so why you need to buy this
product because it is proprietary so I
already have external teaming is a sin
mica in my organization I spent a lot of
money and if each and every application
vendor is saying I have actual my own
key management use my key management
system and it's a proprietary then it is
a discouraging point to me I will stop
enabling actually external key
management so we are leaving a room for
the opportunity to attack some vendors
actually going forward in their cert
they're supporting pkcs 11 which is a
two decade world again the problem with
the pkcs 11 is it's very improbable
that's true but in typically most of
industries the HS are procured by lead
basis and it's by application by
application so if we have hundred
applications to be productive you need
we'll have to venerate isms so it is not
shareable the infrastructure is not that
easy to share between the applications
but the data is pretty much need to be
shared from one application to another
application there is a need
it is not a option there's a need so the
cave might be what from biases they
brought up actually the key management
interoperability protocol and calling it
as a fourth generation key management
systems and there they are making sure
actually the application that we came in
it with shareability concept is address
so so applications need to focus on
actually adopting this KMIP
so as i mentioned actually if you are a
if your enterprise if you are an
enterprise you are dealing with one of
your vendor talk to them tell them you
need actually KMIP ok so at the same
time if your product vendor and make
sure actually you enable encryption also
support KMIP you end up the database and
file system there are traditional
transparent data encryption available
actually both at our file system level
and database system system level and
they can plug to the centralized key
manager so use that actually
functionality just not enabled TDE but
also make sure actually integrate with
the external key manager that's where
actually real problem is getting solved
if the key get compromised there is no
means of actual product in the data so
the next level is actually fix level 142
level two applications as I mentioned
actually like this is the next level for
data production data productions
make sure actually you have the
infrastructure which is cannot be
compromised
the keys are getting short and you
design such that actually you have that
encryption keys as well as key
encryption keys okay it's not it's not
again a hard and fast rule that you need
to follow the exhaust exact pattern
depending on your use case how
frequently you can go to the centralized
key manager to face the key yeah there
you can keep Gmail a key encryption keys
for that encryption keys but have the
capability so as I mentioned KMIP and
pkcs 11 or important make sure that
really like as a product other vendors
please make sure that really like you
are enabling these two and level four as
I mentioned actually like in memory key
so always the data when you are
protecting actually the key you always
need to bring it here for the
performance zones so the best
implementation is performing encryption
if you can tell from a remote encryption
that's best but the performance always
actually consider file fragments and I
expect to actually one of my when I tell
apply in 2000 so she was actually
knowing about encryption from 2000
onwards so she was developing an
application she she said actually know
where my manager did not ask me to
enable encryption but she's handling
actually tear sensitive data so so when
people are actually implementing it will
very to focus on encryptions and also
and the in memory production is very
very important when you are actually
enabling your production so memory but
again it's not hundred percent getting
addressed as of today so we need we have
still a room actually to improve on
these technologies yeah so these are the
different building blocks actually when
we put together what are the different
requirements we have for a taking care
of the data production there are items
so whatever we discussed so far
everything put together yes the
requirements comes in this way not in a
formulated manner so no actually on how
you hand out to over like we'll be
talking going like how it
to be taking pain taking care for the
dead actor so edit union to what this
solution is built from I would like to
talk about like two aspects since we
announced in our presentation that it
will be related to their circles I would
like to focus observe how they
implemented in such a way that we are
onion at the same speed as everybody
else right this is very important the
only DC isn't this is complex everything
which is related to cryptography is
complex you've seen maturity model
presented by the note and you could see
that there are a lot of things that you
need to implement to get to the highest
level of maturity for big heavily
regulated companies it's important to
have it at level four right and when you
think about this and look at Emerson
which is happening around there like
natural question is how you implement it
in a safe way
is that everybody else is happy and you
are not a showstopper and there are two
things that I would like to talk about
here in this regard you use if you think
and I never seen this like actually in
any dev ops or DevOps
presentation that people talk about
architecture build right I think the
first things that you need to have it
you need to have like a really flexible
API based architecture because if you
don't have it you cannot integrate it
fast with anything and this is like six
layers at high canopies which make sense
to use when you want to build a
comprehensive cryptographic system in in
your organization which requires a
higher level of data protection the most
important thing from developers point of
view here is probably a level one at
level one you should have what I call
external interfaces this are interfaces
that your developers team will be used
and you need to make sure that for each
language that you have a new
organization you have such a library
this Union this interfaces should be
universal you need to own this
interfaces you need to build them to
make sure when that when your back-end
provider is changing or configuration
with changing or anything this change in
back-end your users applications are not
affected this is important because as
soon as the developers implement
something and move it to production it's
extremely difficult to get rid of it and
to tell them to do your something else
so that's why again I'd say in all in
interfaces is very important and this is
what level well of level one is all
about and the second part is probably
not that obvious when you try to talk to
cryptographic backends and we have
different kind of hardware security
appliances we have software service
gateway and so on
you usually have a lot of configurations
this configurations are related to
things like endpoints the protocols that
you are using are most importantly it's
related to authentication and
authorization and if anyone work with
any appliance like for example SafeNet
or in grant network attached encryption
api's you will see that this
configuration files are huge there are a
lot of parameter so you need top
structures as well and that's why we
have the second layer which is mostly
about configuration parameters and about
seems like a syndication and acid
ization so you can see that you can have
LDAP to control access / HSM you can
have some kind of secure vault where you
store in shared secrets you can have her
some files stored in PK pkcs12 for a
format or in java key stores you can
have passwords you can even have bearer
tokens which are coming from other
authentication systems like all us so
it's important to have abstraction for
this layer and if you have just this -
everything becomes simpler from the
interview they just create an object
with all these parameters and send you
something like Java factory parted for
example to derive security providers
that you can see at level 3 that will
implement all interfaces that have been
defined at level 1 right so this way if
if something has changed on back-end the
only thing the developers would need to
do is to change the configuration file
every since l everything else will be
the same then you would need to make
sure that your specific crypto service
provider solution protocols you need to
make sure that they understand is a
native API that I just mentioned
residents of API switch are very popular
now in hint this is the main as well and
finally a level 5 is kind of optional
but this is just like yet another
abstraction layer if you you can create
some Universal interfaces on server
layer so that you can simplify your
development at layer 3 this your
cryptographic service provider so this
way all differences free calls coming
from layer 3 to level 5 would be related
to configuration and everything else
will be the same you can do again any
popular interface here protocol do use
any popular protocol like rest or
something else and the last layer if you
build all of that the last layer number
6 this is where all this specific HSMs
hardware security modules live you can
also have software servers like came
it's a server it like aware at least
about one company which provides a good
implementation called crypt soft so you
can see the sauce as well there are
other contemporary approach how you can
replace this HSM module serious pure
software solutions it's related to
multi-party complete
stationed in cryptography and there are
companies who are providing the
solutions as well so choices are mainly
as you see but the most important part
here you need to own the interfaces
which you see at layer 1 and you need to
make sure that your solution is vendor
agnostic all right so now when we are
done with architecture let us take a
look how you can run the whole program
your cryptographic solution
enterprise-wide eclipta graphic solution
and natural banner so usual diseases
like faces faces that you see on the
screen they are not specific to their
cryptography but they are like tasks
which are related in crypto it is that
you can solve to achieve to achieve a
better speed or whatever you implement
so very often I've seen this
misconception coming from they have SEC
ops advocates who were saying that you
know if you are doing something manually
you're not doing develops you're not
doing they're Cecrops and this is
probably true for small companies where
everybody will want easier to they have
say cohorts category for bigger
companies you see on the top at least
like three items which you cannot
completely automate right and again we
required to do that
because of different kind of regulations
and policies that we have internal and
external standards you cannot a tomato
architecture you completely you cannot
have a me design review you catamite
planing
but you can you can you can use some
workarounds and at least make it a semi
automated process if not completely
automated for playing and we're like
you're thinking about licensing probably
provision in some boxes triggering have
architecture in design review you might
think about adopting some tools like an
ANOVA service now whatever
which will allow you to create a
workflow so you need to have a
well-defined workflow and in this
workflow it's important for each step to
have a cell aid it's also important to
have some escalation procedures if the
AUSA cells are not met and this way at
least you can automate completely but at
least you will know approximately how
much time would it take for you to
complete the request of radiation and
you cryptographic service to your
application for architecture review
again people high in volt it's important
to have some standards because if a
security architect has standards where
everything is defined it would be easier
for him to do assessment and to tell
developers what his mission at when you
move the design it's important to have
different kind of patterns it's
important to have a reference
architecture again to make sure that all
of that is reusable and Israeli for
anyone who wants to enable the
cryptographic services this is the last
three like development testing and
monitoring this is where like you can
apply the most automation for
development to make sure that developers
don't need to go to read all the
thousands of documents related to
security compliance you can just give
them libraries code snippets until just
use it and you will be compliant that
would be the best solution for
developers test in my testing is
important we are probably many of you
had this book created by DevOps founders
like Jean Kim and others the Phoenix
project and remembers there was like an
episode when SSN was encrypted but it
was not integrated well this as a system
as a result nobody was able to receive
their salary on time right so this is
how critical problems with cryptography
could be it could be even worse it could
lead to data breaches and so on if you
don't do it properly so it's important
to
regression frameworks for tasting which
are specific to cryptographic functions
because developers do have zero in a
regression but it's not necessarily
related to two algorithm to parameters
of those algorithms they just will be
placed in functionality so it's
important from security part to provide
this kind of framework to make sure that
each time and configuration has changed
each time when when there for example is
change and back-end so they could run it
and see if there are any problems
manatorian again can be automated it's
very important and we not talked already
about importance of performance so each
time when we give how a cryptographic
service to anyone we usually tell you
how many encryption decryption per
seconds they will get and the team
developers and rely on the artists is a
way to create your own isolates and if
you like in unlike transaction business
it's very important to make sure that
this way met as a otherwise the company
will have legal and financial problems
so that's why it's very important that
to create special kind of testing tools
and framework that would evaluate first
that system is alive and the second that
second one is that SLA is not regulated
for example you can do a certain number
of us cryptographic operations a second
so this is like returning to playin this
is a very Greek in running out of time
I'll be running faster this is like a
quick spreadsheet that can help everyone
to choose the right level of data
protection again a very important our
preference here is application level
encryption this is a most flexible where
developers are all in everything then if
if it's not available because we would
recommend database level encryption if
they are not dealing the structured data
if it's only file systems and it's file
level and the last one
is disk level I should probably like
reorder to them like but but this is
idea so if you just read all that I
don't want like to explain and all pros
and cons here you can read it later on
but the idea is that you need to go from
the best to the a worse encryption and
this spreadsheet will will help you to
do it
so going to conclusions like what what
will you achieve is like you he applies
this framework if you dream reason as we
described and enterprise level you will
have and agile and consistent data
protection that would allow you to solve
the most of your compliance problems to
satisfy your internal external security
requirements at a product level it's
very important to have all these tools
libraries and methodologies because it
allows it reduces the risk first of all
of making a mistake when you do
cryptography in product development
teams and it will speed up their
processes and it will save them time so
they could do they can stay focused on
say like real priorities like creating
new features and so on and and develops
it's it's very important to have
standardization libraries patterns share
them these developers to make sure again
sub-second run at the web speed so we
have this is like angle just bring all
of them here key takeaways the most
interesting part here is that all the
takeaway is if you like look at them and
read them you'll understand that they
are basically all related to their
Cyclops process great and it's very good
that we can apply all of them to our use
case when we are trying to implement a
comprehensive cryptography
encryption program in any big
organization they for example data
protection as a service if you look at
the FC cops you will see the an approach
where everybody is saying security
should be really implement it as a
service when that agnostic helps you to
decouple your solution from any specific
vendors it requires you to be very
careful these two inventors many
presenters were saying that it's
important to make sure that everything
that you can do through you I can be
done through API as well so the same as
here efficient processes and automation
again I talked about this not everything
can be automated but there is always a
way to use tools and to make sure that
at least time expectations are set up
right and the users who need the script
a graphic services to be implemented
would know exactly how much time it will
take to achieve that and then they can
plan properly standardization is very
interesting part here is like one
specific which is related to
cryptography it's very important encrypt
you remember this like statement that
like just Karen who was taken apart from
Jamal you don't want allow like everyone
to implement the Roman cryptography to
him to build your own cryptographic
algorithms so standardization and
cryptography cetera is very important
because you basically reducing
maniability you reduces the API calls
you removing some unsafe cryptographic
and various insane parameters and they
don't from from one and they don't need
to think much about how to use it and on
the other hand you're reducing the risk
of making mistake when cryptography has
been implemented champion security is
very important as well you all know that
ratio between security engineers and
developers is probably one to ten if you
limit the security engineers to to those
who look into cryptography it probably
will be one to one hundred right so it's
important when you sit down with
developers
telling them about your solution it's
very important to make sure that
somebody can actually pick it up from
dev team and then share this knowledge
inside this dev team and probably in
other dev teams as well
you