I'm based out of Houston but I love
coming to Austin I feel a very close
connection to the information security
community in this city so it's great to
be back at last con and hanging out with
the folks I've met before and and
meeting new folks so I'm here to talk
about the Eisenhower Eisenhower and the
internet and you may be thinking
immediately
what did Eisenhower have to do with the
internet and furthermore what does the
interstate system have to do with that
as well so I'm going to talk through
that and hopefully this will be a fun
journey we're going to take together a
little historical journey let me
continue introducing myself I'm
technical director for NCC group North
America tell you more about NCC group in
a second I've been in IT since 1995 and
started focusing on InfoSec in 2001 I'm
a Louisiana native but as we say I got
the Texas as fast as I could
about 22 years ago studied music at LSU
as David mentioned that I went to grad
school in 2005 to try and make myself
feel like a legit InfoSec person hasn't
worked yet but it spent most of my
career doing blue team information
security the biggest industries and in
Houston or healthcare and oil and gas
but I've also done a little bit of work
for the DoD and aerospace in Houston at
Johnson Space Center so that's me oh and
I know I've been told I need to update
my profile picture that was used online
yeah my beards had significant gains
since then so I have the greatest job in
the world I think I get to do a lot of
these sorts of shows and I love
advocating for you my fellow information
security professionals and also
advocating for our industry it's part of
my job and I really really enjoy it but
because INSEEC group is sponsoring me
being here you have to sit through the
short commercial I'm sorry he'll keep it
brief we've got about 2,000 employees
globally 35 offices across the globe we
were founded in 1999 were traded on the
London Stock
exchange were part of the footsie 200
and last fiscal year we generated 313
million dollars u.s. in revenue so it's
a good company
police iris oh look at that mint so yeah
we've in North America a lot of our
growth was through acquisition there are
several firms listed up there that are
now part of NCC group we've got a
variety of consulting services from you
know in North America we were primarily
thought of as red teamers we also have
other services we provide as well as you
can see and I show you this slide to say
the here's our office locations I'm very
very hopeful that in 2019 I'll be adding
Houston to that list we're hoping to
have brick-and-mortar offices in Houston
if for the longest time I was the only
employee working remote there but we
were up to four employees in Houston now
and I'm joined by one of them today my
colleague Mario's is over there yaar is
in town so say hi to him if you haven't
met him he's won our first Houston based
Account Manager so you know hopefully
you'll buy you coffee or a beer or
something all right let's get into it
this deck started when a young colleague
of mine once asked we were talking about
security problems that are very
pervasive when you're talking about
communicating on the internet and
there's just fundamental problems with
you know things like authentication and
protocols that are broken and those
sorts of things and he said why didn't
they think of that and my initial
thought was you know geez kid what a
naive question and then moments later I
thought wait now it's actually a really
good question why didn't they think of
that and I didn't know the answer so I
it was a pet project and I just want to
try and figure out okay how did we get
to where we are now and how did the
internet really start to begin with and
you know the metaphor the information
superhighway is what we called it for
the longest time and so I wanted to it
occurred to me that I should start by
studying and try
to understand another big infrastructure
that was started by the government and
so let's start by talking about
Eisenhower and the interstate
bear with me trust me I'll bring this
together
it started in 1919 there were 80
military vehicles then lieutenant
colonel Eisenhower was tasked with
getting those 80 vehicles 3,000 miles
across the country it took two months
and as you can see from the picture on
that side
it was fraught with problems there was
no consistent infrastructure being used
that you know there weren't good roads
things were running off into ditches and
it was it was just a mess fast forward
to the 1930s and Eisenhower found
himself in Germany there was something
going on in Europe at the time and
German had already built the Autobahn
which was a national system of roads
that they could use to very efficiently
get around Germany and Eisenhower
thought that was a really good idea and
America
should do something like that and
because of that once he became president
he realized that he had the power then
to ask Congress to pass the federal aid
Highway Act of 1956 so he's really known
as the father of the interstate system
to honor him for that Congress passed a
bill in 1990 that legally changed the
name to the Eisenhower interstate system
so if you've ever been driving around an
interstate maybe you'll see one of these
blue signs from time to time and that's
why it's called that because Eisenhower
came up with that and you know what's
happened I mean in this country we love
our cars in Texas specifically we love
our big pickup trucks I Drive a half-ton
pickup truck for no real reason at all
but I love it car culture is not just a
big deal in this country is anyone
familiar with the Michelin Guide ok so
it's a book and it lists restaurants and
a very nice restaurant
however many stars you get it's you know
it's a nicer restaurant
it's no coincidence that it shares the
name with the tire company because it is
Michelin tire that publishes that book
and you might think well why would a
tire company want to publish a book
about Nancy's restaurants the answer is
the Michelin folks figured that if they
could convince French people to drive
around in these fancy restaurants than
they would have to buy more tires so
that shows you that infrastructure being
in place in Europe had a really big
socio-economic impact right think about
historic route 66 in America now route
66 is not a part of the interstate
system because it was built before the
interstate act happened but entire
cities and towns sprung up based on
their proximity to route 66 and then
when the interstate system happened and
people stopped using route 66 those
towns in many cases dried up and went
away again those economic impacts that
that infrastructure had on those local
areas and of course you know screenshot
from the movie Cars if you have kids but
or not perhaps you've seen the movie but
it's a big deal Oh trivia question does
anyone know where the middle of route 66
is nope right here in Texas does anyone
know where Adrien Texas is I should look
that up I'm not sure where that is but
it's in the middle of Texas so what's my
point
what started as an infrastructure built
for a very specific use case ended up
having a profound socio-economic and
sociological effect once turned over to
the private sector because Eisenhower
didn't just say we're going to build all
these roads and move military vehicles
around while we're not using them for
moving around military vehicles other
folks can use the this system of roads
as well and it as it turns out it became
a big deal the ability for us to freely
move about our country easily as big as
it is is a significant advantage
so similarly ARPA was founded and I'll
tell you why they had a problem
Sputnik happened in the 50s and America
was shocked they didn't know that Russia
even had that capability they didn't
know that they were even doing that sort
of research and the government knew that
they somebody needed to be in charge of
researching things to figure out what's
going on they knew they couldn't do it
alone though
so the DoD partnered in terms of with
private researching organizations
depending on what the research project
was and that's how the Advanced Research
Projects Agency came up and guess who
founded that it was Eisenhower so he had
a keen eye it seems for figuring out how
to solve fairly complex problems just as
a point of saying it in 1972 the name
was changed to DARPA which is the DoD
Advanced Research Projects Agency to
kind of underscore how important the
notion of Defense is to that agency they
initially started off as I said that it
was in response to Sputnik but they
shortly a couple years after that in
1960s NASA was founded and took over all
the space travel related things ARPA at
that time decided okay we're going to
focus on computer science problems so
the idea was if all of our computing
resources are in one place that's a
single point of failure we need to have
the ability in order to defend our
country to be able to exchange
information across great distance well
the technology didn't exist at the time
you know there was only so far you could
stretch a cable right so ARPA decided
they were going to try and solve that
problem again researchers from all over
the world were involved new protocols
had to be invented packet switching had
to be
invented and this is what the first four
nodes of the internet looked like is in
several research facilities in in the
United States and I mean it would be
nice if the network to be protected were
that simple right have you seen a
topology map of the of the internet
lately
well it's grown it's a lot bigger
it doesn't even resemble a network map
at all but you know from those humble
beginnings you know we deal with the
internet every single day you know again
suffice to say it's gotten a lot bigger
the first message so if you want to talk
about you know when did the internet go
live the research I did seems to suggest
most people agree it was on October 29th
1969 at twenty to thirty one researcher
was trying to remotely log into another
machine that researcher typed ello and
then the whole bloody thing crashed it
took several hours to reboot the
internet which it's funny even saying
that but eventually that message the the
paper I read said that they were type
trying to type log in I would like to
use this forum to start the rumor that
they were in fact trying to type lol so
we can all go home and tell our kids
that Lowell is not a new thing that's
been around since the 60s so in terms of
I mean part of the question I was trying
to answer for myself was you know when
was the internet invented and and by
whom because you know every time I give
this presentation someone will make the
Al Gore and invented the internet joke
more on him later but there were as I
said it was the the Department of
Defense that had the idea but literally
people from all over the world were
involved and I don't think it's fair to
necessarily say one entity or one
organization is responsible for all the
research that went into it so my
conclusion is this vague comment here it
was invented by humans in the 20th
century there were a lot of folks that
were involved in that just as with the
interstate system there was a very
specific problem that they were trying
to solve and so in terms of the question
why didn't they think of that the you
know think about you know in the early
days the DoD you had to be in the
military or a part of the DoD or a part
of one of these research firms so there
were no design requirements for dealing
with unauthorized users for example
there were no unauthorized users you
were in the DoD somehow and non private
networks we didn't have a way to deal
with that because again there were no
non private networks that there was just
one internet and everybody that was
using it was a part of that network so
in terms of as security professionals
thinking about you know why are we why
do we still have clear text protocols
why did we even have clear text
protocols to begin with and so on and so
forth the answer is not that the people
that built the Internet were you know
naive or foolish there was no design
requirement and if your engineering a
solution to something you're not going
to solve a problem unless there's a
design requirement behind it right so
the fact is the internet was not at all
designed to do what we're doing with it
today so what happened well ecommerce
happened interestingly I found out that
you unit is claimed to be the first
not-for-profit Internet service provider
and something like 1988 they went for
profit in 1990 the world was an
organization that offered full internet
access in 1989 well what do you mean by
full internet access before 1989 even if
you did have access to
the internet ARPA would keep some stuff
segregated off and as private citizens
we could only access certain parts of
the Internet as it existed that changed
as I said in 1989 full access was
finally granted to non are / approved
users by 1992 and so I started going
back in time thinking what was my first
internet access account because that
seems like really late I didn't think it
was 1992 before ARPA started releasing
control of it commercial applications
were remained prohibited until 1995 and
that's when eBay and Amazon happened
around around that time so before 1995
as private citizens we could use the
internet but we couldn't sell stuff on
it again it wasn't in the design it
wasn't built to do that so ARPA said no
no don't be doing that please that
having been said it's not that ecommerce
didn't happen the first e-commerce is
believed to have happened in 1971 or 72
somewhere around there where some
college kids sold a bag of weed to each
other I'm certainly not advocating for
anything I'm just stating the facts
that's what happened it might close some
loops about our industry though come to
think of it wouldn't it all right so the
security concept I'm getting at and the
thing that I hope is interesting to you
as it is to me is that as I've said the
initial design requirements of this
infrastructure excuse me the initial
design requirements of anything you're
building is not necessarily what it
becomes ARPA was specifically interested
in computational time sharing across
great distance you know they won one
computer in one state to talk to another
computer in another state and they you
know engaged academia to help them out
with that so a whore's interstate system
fueled America's love for road trips and
travel beyond you know that that what it
ended up do
was far beyond the scope of what
Eisenhower had in mind when he asked
Congress to to fund that and certainly
we have far exceeded ARPA schools from
the 1950s and 1960s so whenever you give
if any of you do public speaking giving
predictions is always a risky thing
especially when it's being recorded I'm
happy to be wrong on some of this stuff
but what have we seen that that's
happened with roads well I found a
project called a t smart corridor and
they have a lot of really interesting
information about the research this
organization is doing on how to make
travel on interstates more efficient
they do things like you know metered
ramps if you've seen those you know the
flow of traffic entering the main lanes
is controlled to try and reduce
bottlenecks and what overhead signs that
will tell you if lanes are closed and
and you can use overhead signs to
reverse the flow of traffic during
certain times day and local street signs
that can provide quick and efficient
information about detours again with the
idea of making road travel more
efficient so roads started you know as
your interstates rather started as a
hard flat surface right and yet that's
what it was now we've got things like
adaptive construction materials toll
roads sophisticated lighting dynamic
planes self-driving cars so we've come a
long way from a hard flat surface right
so what I think if you kind of stretch
that metaphor a little bit what is the
internet going to do based on what we
now know about the interstate system you
know it started off as a networking
infrastructure no internet working by
the way trivia the in the early white
papers and technical documents that ARPA
was authoring they talked about internet
working was what they called this thing
that they were trying to do that was
later shortened to
just internet so if you ever wondered
where they came up with the name
internet it's the shortened version of
Internet working recently I read in a
style guide I do a lot of technical
writing that once upon a time Internet
was a proper noun and therefore should
be capitalized all the time some style
guides now say it's okay to use a lower
case I and drives me insane maybe I'm
just old school and resistant to change
but internet should always have a
capital I my consultants I Drive I drive
them nuts with edits on on that one so I
think it just as we've improved the
materials we've built roads with I think
we've already seen a lot of things
happening math based encryption will
include elements of quantum computing
that's you know very difficult if not
impossible theoretically to defeat
broadband is going to become more and
more broad our pipes are going to get
bigger and will become more and more
ubiquitous as well there's a lot of
people in the world that don't have
access to the Internet if you think
about it in context of you know this was
a network designed by and for computer
scientists right and the way you support
such a network with computer scientists
is different than when suddenly you
introduced you know mere mortal humans
that are using it right as that
population of users increases and were
able to transfer more and more data
faster and faster I think even though
we're making inroads in solving some of
these security problems I think it might
actually get worse as those users the
population of users and increases I also
think one side effect of those previous
two bullet points is going to be the
physical possession will continue to
lose value and access to information
itself is really what's going to be
important to us as we continue moving
through the 21st century so as David
mentioned and I mentioned I have a
degree in music so if you would imagine
what my CD collection must look like
you'd probably think wow he's probably
got a pretty impressive
collection of CDs and records well
shockingly I don't own a single one I've
gotten rid of them all because now all
the music I listen to is on a cloud
service somewhere and I'm perfectly
happy to use such services so I don't
have to manage physical inventory of
things what's important to me is not the
CD it's just having access to the
information and since I've written this
slide deck since then if your consultant
yourself or in your own organizations it
does cloud computing ever come up in
conversations around the office I mean
it that's you know we can stamp our feet
and clench our fists all we want but I
don't think it's going away
I you know I think that's a that's it's
here to stay in fact I think last night
when I was up on stage I referred to the
internet as a fad at some point yeah
it's not going away
and I think we've also seen since my IT
career started we've kind of seen
InfoSec challenges moving up the OSI
model at the 90s you know every security
problem at the end of the day was a
routing and switching problem it seemed
like you know as layer 3 issues and and
that was it then well wasp happened
I just remember where I was so obviously
application-layer attacks are thing and
have become very very important and I
think that migration up the stack is
going to continue to layer 8 which of
course is the the user or the chair
keyboard interface to use the technical
term and so I think even as we get
better at defending our applications and
defending our networks the human is the
softest target and I think I mean we've
already seen you know phishing getting
more and more sophisticated even there's
time-based attacks on one-time passwords
and multi-factor authentication I think
that trend is going to continue as well
I'm happy to be wrong and if you have
predictions of your own I'm happy to
hear about those also so just as I
mentioned the smart highways and self
dry
cars did you know that there's a a
second internet the internet to project
was started specifically to kind of
solve some of these problems of this
infrastructure being designed and built
starting a very long time ago it's an
interesting product that a project and
I'm not sure that it's ever going to
like we're gonna have an internet outage
one day and turn the whole thing off and
switch everything over the internet to I
think as that research continues
elements of that technology will be
incorporated and into the global
internet but if you don't know much
about it yes it's worth looking into
oh and one prediction I left out sorry
is self-driving car does anyone have an
automobile that has driver assist or
self driving features anything like that
I mean so I think that's cool I cannot
wait till I have a fully autonomous
vehicle I love driving my big pickup
truck but driving around Houston if
you've ever had to do so well yeah
that's why it my beard is gray it didn't
used to be this way it's maddening but
will self-driving cars solve the problem
of automobile accidents and in your
opinion I mean even if they can
communicate with one another and the
humans just ballast at that point will
accidents still happen I'm cynical
enough that I think they will because
humans remain capable of making bad
decisions and so even if the car is
driving itself I don't trust myself or
other humans for that matter to not mess
with it somehow and make it malfunction
I mentioned quantum encryption a minute
ago so I mean if you believe that in
theory quantum encryption cannot be
defeated
because of the uncertainty principle and
all the science behind it will attackers
still be able to steal someone's data in
the future of course they will because
humans are going to make bad decisions
and we're going to implement it
improperly and something's gonna happen
and a hacker is still going to be able
to steal our data
no that sounds really really cynical but
we're all information security pros here
I think it bodes well because the
problems not really going to go away
it's going to change and it's going to
keep moving around
you know we solve one problem and then
another problem pops up and that's why
this topic was so interesting to me
trying to figure out it okay the
problems we're solving today won't you
know maybe we'll maybe we will solve
them at some point but another one's
gonna come up and I really think that
layer aid as I call it the human layer
is where the attacks are going to
continue to be concentrated I know by
the way that I've got the enviable spot
of being immediately before lunch let me
pause for a minute to thank you all for
being here
and trust me I'm just as interested in
lunch as you are so lucky for you this
is one of my briefer slide decks that I
give so let me start to wrap it up here
we all that having been said I told you
a story about interstates I told you a
story about the Internet and a little
bit of a history lesson
I believe this pretty strongly that has
security professionals it's not enough
just to understand how the technology
works I mean obviously I mean we have to
understand how the technology works but
more importantly I think if you believe
that layer eight is going to be the
problem
where the problem goes moving forward
then we also have to understand how the
people interact with that technology the
context of how the technology is used is
what the hackers the bad guys are really
good at figuring out before we do and
they take advantage of that so again not
to repeat myself but you know just as
interstates don't require you to be in a
military vehicle the internet doesn't
have you don't have to be in the DoD to
use the internet anymore it is long
ceased being a thing only used by
computer scientists and you know I
mentioned cloud and if if any of you who
are in the industry 20 years ago
you know did you anticipate that we were
going to be dealing with the things like
people were going to be putting
computing assets and information assets
and somebody else's data center I
remember the first time I heard the term
BYOD at a conference and the speaker was
suggesting that someday you'll be able
to buy your own computing devices and
bring them to work I was sitting there
thinking you're out of your mind you
you've obviously never worked in the
corporate network before because that's
not happening ever well now there's an
entire industry built up around mobile
device management and those sorts of
things so anyway in closing you know
like I said I think our jobs may become
more focused on the use cases and how
our users interact with the thing if you
have ideas of your own I would love to
hear them I'm not claiming to be right
on this stuff I'm happy to be wrong or
if you disagree I'd love to hear your
opinions if not today please do stay in
touch I'm on Twitter and there's my
email address you can hit me up there
it's unfortunate that I've got to be
back in Houston by 3:30 or 4:00 so I
need to leave pretty soon but anyway
this is my story
comments or questions or to see I don't
see any hands going up thank you very
much for your time today I hope you
enjoyed it and enjoy the rest of laughs
last time thank you
[Applause]
you