Thanks who is ready for a fun afternoon
of compliance discussions so we're here
to talk to you about assessing the
maturity of information security
programs and thanks for the intros so
again I'm David in information security
since about 2000 and I have a computer
science degree but find myself in a
position where I also find compliance
topics for the interesting security
compliance risk as well as internal
audit which is why I'm not scared to say
that I enjoy a good audit I'm one of
those weird people so who doesn't enjoy
compliance that's let's get started so
it take a quick look at the agenda so in
case you just stumbled in here and don't
realize why you here the goal of our
talk today is to provide you a solution
how to measure maturity within your
information security program so how
we're gonna do that is first we're gonna
look at the problem what we're really
looking to solve whether the core
questions we'll look at some defines and
key terminology then we'll look at some
available solutions for maturity models
as well as security frameworks that we
considered from developing our solution
then we'll dive actually into what we
created and it's wrap up with some
conclusions so like I said let's start
with the problem so many of you know you
work in security there's constantly new
threats and you've grown abilities new
compliance requirements as well it's
just figuring out ways to do things
better so to address that you're going
to continuously improve your security
program through David's like
implementing the tools it's going to
meet controls
tweaking policies automation patching
all these things are going to impact
your overall security program so David
and I we used to work together and we
found ourselves in a situation where we
were drastically improving our security
program I'm through all those projects
that were mentioned as though we felt
like we were doing a great job really
the question became is how good are we
at security what type of metric to make
sure
to tell how good we are at security and
then how can we quantify the progress so
we're doing all these big projects I'm
how can we show that we're progressing
to the current security program and then
when you look at a security program
holistically within the control how can
you specifically identify your gaps and
then finally how can we communicate out
that out to the business so those are
the core questions that we're looking to
solve but before we get into how it
solve it I just want to set a baseline
with some of the key definitions and
terms that we'll look at so these are
not new terms I'm sure you've all heard
of compliant to its immaturity but there
is a lot of different definitions out
there of how to define what these are so
I'll caveat but these are how we define
them to make more sense to us within the
solution so compliance that's the easy
way let's look for what everyone loves
so it's adherence to all the security
laws the regulation the metrics of
standards all this stuff we're trying to
avoid though we have to do things like
PCI HIPAA or DPR so then there's
compliance and then we look at risk so
the risk definition that we thought was
most appropriate is from this SV 853
they do a much better job explaining it
than I can so I'm just going to read
what the definition is it's a measure of
the extent to which an entity is
threatened by a potential circumstance
or vet so typically you're measuring
that by either the impact and as well as
the likelihood so we're not going to
talk a lot about a risk management
program but what's important here is to
understand the relationship between risk
and betray maturity so typically within
organizations you have a risk management
program you're measuring the risk from a
moment of impact restore to a critical
risk
hopefully for any critical hive's you're
gonna want to put a mitigation plan in
place to reduce that risk so that's why
maturity comes in
so refer maturity we're looking at a
measure of the quality of the control
that you've implemented for that desired
control so you pick you control to help
reduce that risk and now we're looking
at how quality is that control because
there's different maturity models that
you can look back to do that and
typically there was in these five
different sections things like policy or
integration we'll get into what that
means a little bit later in the present
but the further drive the point tables
come right example what risk means yeah
so I'm kind of curious who in the room
is more involved but like managing a
security program on the compliance set
of sites a couple of you and then other
a lot of application security folks here
at Laskin good deal so and and who
actually does like risk assessments and
risk management using some sort of like
more or less formal methodology
okay so there's different methodologies
right you have like quantitative
approaches and qualitative approaches
but I really wanted to to dwell a little
bit more on how do maturity of controls
and worse
interact with each other because they're
not the same thing and I think it's
pretty important to understand that so I
have an example here let's look at a
risk assessment saying oh you know the
scenario is basically unauthorized
network traffic might reverse my company
networks edge between the internet and
the internal network so if I don't
mitigate this risk at all
that's a pretty high risk I might
express it and like qualitatively or
maybe I'm able to express it
quantitatively doesn't matter for our
case I put a number on their site
you know annually I might lose I don't
know a million dollars because of
threats that traverse that boundary
between the Internet in the internal
network so what do I want to do about
this pretty typically I put in a
firewall right segment my internal
networks from the external internet and
I put two options in here I said okay so
one option for firewall is we'll put a
firewall at the edge all incoming
traffic from the Internet is blocked all
outgoing traffic from our networks is
allowed and that sits there and
it's job and you know we expected to to
mitigate this risk there's another
option that takes that father and says
we're going to implement this firewall
but we're also going to block outbound
traffic we're going to look at the
actual traffic that's being blocked look
at whether you know it might indicate
like indicators of compromised
internally in the network and we're
going to look at metrics and see whether
we can improve our firewall rules based
on those etc etc so what do you guys
think like which of these two options is
more mature yeah I I would agree
so pretty simple that's not we put it in
place it's it's there we don't maintain
it going forward just sits there and
then option two we continuously look at
evaluate how it's working and iterate on
improving the configurations we keep it
patched and so you'd think that probably
if I can rely more on this control that
I'm putting in place at the end of the
day my my risk is going to be lower than
if I put a control in place but really
don't take care of it and maintain it so
going forward from there what did we
actually come up with to look at
maturity of our controls it's a lot of
standards out there those of you in the
compliance world know a lot of these
acronyms they suppose frameworks that
give you lists of controls security
controls to implement that you can use
as your baseline and there's also
standards that deal specifically with
how do i express maturity of programs
may they be securely related or not and
then there's a couple standards that do
both Cobert gives you sets of controls
but also a way to manage maturity
hi Trust has that built in to some
extent this is a thing called mr. Prez
nah and so what we settled on is we
basically determined well none of these
overlapping frameworks out there meet
what we want to do so we're gonna take
the the NIST cybersecurity framework who
is familiar with that right okay
and we're gonna take mists Prisma
standard anybody here that I know what I
expected
personal stands for program review for
information security assurance and while
it comes with its own sort of like
control objectives and lists of topics
to review it also has a maturity model
built in so we decided to combine the
controls on the cybersecurity framework
with the personal maturity approach so
it's great a lot of you are the raise
your hand so you must be familiar with
the new security framework but if you're
not here's a snapshot of what that looks
like it's a fairly new framework it was
established in 2014 to help cement the
security executive order the way that it
breaks down Security's into five core
functions looks at identity protection
detection response and then recovery it
also breaks down into categories and
then further into subcategories the
reason I chose this particular framework
is one we felt like the functions and
categories are really easy to visualize
and communicate to not get security
professionals or really anybody within
the business we also felt like the
categories where generic enough to be
able to map to any of those other common
controls other kommen control frameworks
like ISO or high charts or PCI all those
other things that you'd have to comply
with were able to map that into the
cybersecurity framework and consider
that in our valuation secondly or
thirdly is the emphasis on responding
and recovery a lot of cybersecurity
frameworks out there don't look at that
it's just a piece of the framework and
that was important to us as an organ
sation so this is the Miss time security
framework as we mentioned we use this as
the core baseline and then adopted the
maturity model so in the next slide
you'll see what that looks like so
here's the baseline of what that looks
like so as David had mentioned the niche
original model does have its own base
baseline as well but we kind of drop
that who fell like then there's some
framework with more robust so we took
that and then just add it on to the
maturity model so this is the prism of
maturity model and it looks at it with
maturity within these five different
areas so when we were going through and
evaluating controls how we evaluated the
controls was first we said does this
control have a policy in place and
approved policy in place is there a
detailed procedure that says how can you
execute on that policy how well hasn't
been implemented across the organization
is it everywhere is it actually being
used how can you test that for his
effectiveness and then finally
integration can we optimize on that
control I may continuously improve on
that so the five core sections that we
looked at in the next slide this is
actually putting data into that and
viewing our compilations so this is our
solution surprise it's the back of excel
sheet you can find appreciate that but
really what it is so this is a
cybersecurity framework here
what we did is soom into the particular
identity so we can show exactly how we
did those calculations so just to break
it down further we have our function
those are the kind of the highest
baseline then we look at category and
then we look at sub category and
subcategory is where we really start and
start to evaluate maturity so add sub
category letter level we look at again
what I just went through and the person
model around policy procedure
implementation and with those scoring
we'll talk about how that sort works in
just a minute but with that scoring we
come up with our maturity model I'm
returning score so a couple things to
point out with the maturity we also set
a goal for each of these sub categories
reason why that's important because for
some of these categories you may not
want a five maturity you may not want to
test it really just depends on your
organization and what's important in
critical
you so you want to set that goal for
each of them and then finally we set a
priority how important is this to us and
how important ever risk is it to us as
well and that's important because as we
go through and we see these deficits
between charity that's what we can
better prioritize which projects we want
to tackle so David's going to talk a
little bit how the calculation works
going on some examples of how it's used
yeah so let's look at a couple of
examples on this spreadsheet so again we
have we dove into one of the
cybersecurity framework functions poking
down into categories and subcategories
and then for each subcategory we look at
do we have a policy that defines the
control objectives for this category do
we have whose leader in place is it
implemented fully and then once it's
implemented are we like do we have
metrics are we testing it are we making
sure it's effective and then lastly do
we go back and based on these metrics
and testing do we improve upon what
we're doing and so one thing to point
out here is that we have these five
areas policy procedure implementation
testing and integration and basically
depending on whether you meet all of
these you end up with a maturity score
for your Kotak with this between zero
and five you know five fully mature you
continuously improve upon what you have
and so a couple things that are
interesting in this approach to
measuring maturity that we chose and
when we look at the yellow pieces here
as examples we say for subcategory ID
pe2 we have an implementation in place
it may not be perfect but we're doing
something yet because we don't have a
policy and because we don't have any
procedures in place this implementation
doesn't count at all towards maturity
the overall maturity writing is so zero
so basically the point here being
he's maturity levels are hierarchical
if you don't have a policy if you don't
have your control objectives defined
that you want to manage toward then you
can't determine whether implementation
applies at all to what we're trying to
manage again so doesn't count
another thing I wanted to point out is
the the green highlighting up here
basically for our subcategory ID a and 3
are we mapping data flows in the
organization we have a policy in place
we need to do this we're supposed to do
this there's an objective to do this but
we're not doing it we don't have any
procedures it's not implemented and yet
even though we have these five maturity
levels I we get a one and a quarter a
one point two five as a maturity weight
and the reason that is is that we are
biased to what these first three
maturity levels it's more important that
we have policies and procedures and an
implementation and then you know whether
you're testing and integrating or not
you get less points for that so it puts
a bias on okay let's put this in place
let's operate it and then once we get to
a state where we start improving and
measuring that's icing on the cake in
some way if you will so what what yeah
question good question I will show you
that on the next slide because now the
question is what do we actually do with
this so you know there's there's some
compliance wrong sitting there working
on the spreadsheet and assigning
maturity writings but then what we
really want to do is report on the
maturity of our controls and then our
overall program right so you can do
things like break it down into the
cybersecurity framework
categories that you see here and you can
say a Jaffa you talked earlier about
like what's our goal we don't want to be
like perfect that everything we do we
need to like dedicate our resources to
what's most important so for some
controls we may want to be just too
perfect others are not important enough
for us in terms of mitigating risk that
we need to operate them at like for
maturity levels so in blue you can see
we have goals defined and then the
orange here says where are we actually
compared to our goal with the maturity
in these controller areas and then what
you can do with the priorities is you
can look at the gaps you have for a
given control or particularly or however
you break it down and say well certain
gaps are more important have higher
priority for us to mitigate and others
and so that informs your upcoming
initiatives basically exactly and so
then what what else can we do it John
fun so here's another example of report
of call this kind of the executive level
report so this is looking at it at the
highest level I'm looking at it from
identified protect those five different
functions and it looks at it over a year
of time of how are you for dressing it
into these function areas so this is
important because let's say your
executives or your business are saying
hey we need to be dead better and
identify your assets in this chart you
can show how we're doing better of
course if you're looking at it from this
hierarchy level you're going to miss
some of these details so you want to be
prepared to be able to dive down deep
and to look at what the details are
where are you missing policies where you
missed procedures but having this kind
of bar graph who's able to understand
and look at where you're at from a
progression level within the five
functions
yeah absolutely like this morning we
were sitting here and thinking like oh
we had an application security
conference like mmm so so really if you
look at it the Badlands then typically
you'd expect to have certain like
security controls built into your
software development life cycles like do
we do code reviews are we training our
developers how do we do testing what
kind of testing do we do do we do threat
modeling and so there's frameworks that
that give you lists of controls that you
would want to build into your SDLC and
so what you could easily do is instead
of using this cybersecurity framework as
the catalog for your controls
you just take either your home gone or
like standardized framework for the
security elements of an sdlc and then
you start measuring against those and
your maturity
let's make sense yes
yep right so so one thing that we wanted
to talk a little bit more is we we
looked at their spreadsheet and so okay
we're mapping maturity against the
cybersecurity framework functions and
categories and sub-categories but really
depending on where you are in your
company worth managing compliance maybe
you don't do any of this right now
and so just mapping against the
cybersecurity framework is a good start
because we talked earlier about it's
fairly straightforward it's really
generic it's easy to talk to executives
about like sit down into these five
functions but really if you are living
in a more complex environment in terms
of compliance requirements typically
what happens is just to take this as an
example here you may have like the
cybersecurity framework says oh you need
to manage your physical assets but then
what that translates to is somewhere in
your company you have a common control
set or whatever it may be called a
policy that defines how you actually
need to do asset management and it's
more likely that there are more details
and here then what the cybersecurity
framework tells you and then if you're
in an organization that has multiple
compliance requirements then this common
control set may be based on like a whole
bunch of standards you're managing
against right so there might be first
and foremost if you do risk assessments
then you have mitigating controls that
are defined in your service out of your
risk assessments so those go into this
common control said just these examples
you might be managing against ISO 27001
as a baseline so the requirements from
that standard go into your common
control set and you might be managing
against FISMA and the requirements and
special publication 800-53 and so the
requirements for asset management
FISMA also go into your common control
set and from there then
what we are doing in the presentation
you earlier Sauer of results and whatnot
we simplify that into the language of
the cybersecurity framework just as a
way to have a straightforward way to
talk about we are on the flip side what
that means is that if you are the one
who is actually going and assigning
maturity ratings to these CSF consults
you need to keep in mind what your
command control set is so you know CSF
may be very simple the requirement in
there but then behind that since the
sole policy so when you are saying do we
have a policy for everything we need to
do then you need to take all of these
things into account so it makes sense
okay deal so conclusions well so why
don't we bring it back to the problem
that I talked about these problems that
we're going to solve and just talk about
how we solve them with this solution so
obviously we have a kind of data now
around our controls around our control
quality to be able to solve and make
metrics for some of these so how good
are we have security to think the best
example is the one David showed we were
able to show here's our goal against
what our current average is we looked at
how can we quantify progress so that's
as you saw in the other important you
can quantify progress by looking at the
metrics and seeing how it goes over time
to show if there's specific project
let's say we're doing a big project like
that segmentation you're gonna show
their progress within that metrics
because you're gonna see an increase on
automatically increase within that so
how do we identify gaps in control
quality quality so we're able to do that
because we're actually looking at it and
breaking it down between the maturity
model we can actually look at do we have
a policy in place and that's breaking
down the quality or is it not being
implemented we just have the policy so
we're able to look at it from a granular
perspective to understand what the
quality of that control is and then
finally like I mentioned before we have
a ton of data so you can break it up as
you like be able to develop different
reports different metrics on something
specific just as from the day effective
but you can
to look at it from the specific control
perspective as well so you don't have a
lot of more flexible and freedom you
know have you use that data to
communicate that to the business cool
and then finally well because all of you
are excited to go and do something like
this on your own now right and we wanted
to to point out a couple of things to
keep in mind that we sort of experienced
and thought about while we put this in
place the first thing we talked about
this early in the beginning
don't confuse maturity was with risk so
in all likelihood if you stand in front
of whatever yardas audiences maybe your
executives and say once our firewalls
are at a maturity level of five and we
like keep them moving on how they work
all the time our risk is going to be
zero probably not to the fire one might
be as effective as you can get it but
there's still risk that you know
somebody circumvent it or manipulates it
so risk and maturity are not the same
and you need to be careful about how you
express that to your audience then
maturity ratings are only as objective
as your humans are so this is not a
quantitative approach unless you get
really good at having like useful
metrics for all of your controls that
you're trying to look at there's still
like subject matter experts like Java
and I who sit there and say oh we have
all the policies that we need for this
control we think yes we want to give
ourselves the one and then we're gonna
look at procedures and we're like well
do our like technology teams have
procedures that implement these policies
properly and we look around we'll say
like yeah maybe you wonder maybe
mostly 0.5 and then we look at
implementation and we start like digging
into like how this is actually
implemented how do we measure
effectiveness etc and at the end of the
day it still asks just assigning a more
or less subjective writing on what we
think where we are right so this is not
not quantitative measurements if you
want another thing to think about a
control that has a high maturity level
may still not be effective in what it's
supposed to do and and where that can
happen is if you have a control
objective that's not clear enough about
what exactly needs to happen so that you
mitigate your risk in a certain area you
might just have a very vague objective
that says let's put a firewall in place
let's not talk about whether it should
be stateful are stateless or whether it
should be application-aware and whether
it should have have a built in ids/ips
it just says firewall the teams who
implement the policy may have a perfect
procedure to implement a simple firewall
and they might be managing it well and
yet that doesn't necessarily mean that
it's completely effective in mitigating
the risk that your risk assessment team
had in mind when they said oh if we put
a firewall in place this is going to
mitigate our risk by X and the last
thing on here sort of obvious but maybe
not iscope changes may school with your
baselines so if you you know if you add
a completely new environment maybe you
acquire a company or whatever you add a
new environment that's now being subject
to your security program then that may
be less or more mature than your
previous environments that you were
managing and so that may like you know
mess with your maturity levels and
measurements so if you're doing like
trending and somebody says oh wise our
maturity going down here instead of up
maybe it's because he added new
environment and that's mature those kind
of things does that mean you need to
track maturity of your control
objectives for individual and buy-in
environments individually or not that's
something you got to figure out and
really our last slide here
as answers to your question from earlier
again weird last console application
security what's up and basically yeah we
talked about it be seamless if you're
not familiar with Beeson it's a great
way of looking at the the secure
elements and software development life
cycles across different industries and
what's more common and what not and how
do you level up against that but that
being said any questions comments good
question so the question is when
controls may be more generic or not they
may be impacting how other controls work
and how effective those are depends I I
would say it really depends on how you
manage that and you know like how you
look at taking the results of looking at
your maturity back to us management
program so I have a black and white
answer but it's definitely a good
question to think about yes
it's you know you could even argue that
like well if the NIST cybersecurity
framework isn't one that your company
has declared it once needs to be
compliant with why are you adding just
another yet another layer of controls
framework on to that and so it depends
like you know you could easily like if
you say ISO 27001 is that is the
baseline for my company you could use
the the controls from the the nxi
controls and the mandatory controls and
use that and then map maturity against
that for us the reason why we chose the
cybersecurity framework was you know
it's it's been pretty popular with you
know across industries so it's it's easy
to talk about it and indifferent you
know like butter coats it's really
available this maintain said I think it
also goes back to you having expertise
like David and I deeply understood all
our controls and all the different
frameworks as well so we put that into
consideration even though it did nicely
map into there as well we were able to
kind of think about that yeah yeah
everything was able to fit within there
there's always if some category that's
gonna back back if it depends on kind of
the specific standards that you adhere
to
cool
anything else
I have been here experience in using
this this model of the two-time instils
there what one has been maybe sort of
like response from the recipients of
that information so for any
prioritization and business decisions
that you made from that that's something
that you're trans that kind of like that
and said this is this is a great metric
this really paints a new light on how
much work this control is or be more
like is the number we're doing all right
good question I think it really depends
on your organization it's definitely it
works as having talking points and
something to talk to but then you know
if you look at you know hey we're really
bad at this function or this control and
and you know here's where we are with
our maturity you still again got to put
it into into the perspective okay what
does that mean in terms of the the risk
we are incurring and then it really
depends on you know the story you build
about like what these numbers telling I
also think that using this seven
security framework bringing it to
audience to be able to show the holistic
security program you're not just
focusing on application security you're
just not just so defined asset
management be able to show people that
don't really realize that this entire
program involved I'm gonna be able to
show a metric format and break that down
as well and I think that's a good news
case
[Music]
[Applause]