[Music]
let's get right into it the title of the
talk is your right this talk really
isn't about you it's basically built on
communication and talking about
communication so uh Gover on this side
to distract from all the work over on
that side and you see this comic where
says your big project he's running late
what can you do
and the guy is like people are already
flat out conference calls morning and
night six emails a day and half our time
in meetings I don't see what else we can
do and then she's like what do you think
this is the real problem and he's like I
think it's a lack of communication so
you're gonna see a theme about
communication and how we're
communicating to the end users and in
the industry through this whole talk so
it's like I wanted to that's why I
thought this was a good way to start it
I hate talking about myself if you want
to know more about me go on Twitter cuz
I live tweet my life unfortunately for a
lot of people but it's to help other
governments that keep track of me so
it's like I'm just trying to help them
out they're short-staffed and now you
can also go to my website to see my bio
it's and all their other information
which it's actually true but that's me
on that geo breaking into a bank there's
me on the news but most importantly you
see me stealing stuff it's like people
pay me to actually go in and break into
places and I've been teaching people
individually about security awareness
and about a year and a half ago I got
tired of that and it's like it's like
instead of going in and doing these
engagements and like you know knocking
things out and it's like telling them
what they're doing wrong I decide you
know what let's try to make it expand
that so I've gotten on that little
crusade and decide to tilt some other
windmills and one of those is about
trying to create more security awareness
and enterprise not just from one user at
a time so on the whole theory of
communication I think this sums up our
industry really well these are two
quotes from John F Kennedy the first one
on the left is when written in Chinese -
where Crysis is composed of two
characters one represents danger and the
other represents opportunity Wow
that's inspirational all right I mean
seriously because they've got them on
posters and yoga rooms all over the
place you know usually on a lake with a
with an eagle flying through the clouds
it's like you know that's a really great
quote
from John F Kennedy he's given a lot of
credit to that it's like he's lauded for
that statement they still use it
inspirational speakers still use it to
this day there's only one problem it's
totally false it's like I was giving a
talk inch engine and I used that slide
and it's like and it got something last
before I could even talk about it they
were laughing it's like because they
knew that it was wrong it's like that is
not the correct statement but he is
given credit correctly for that he's
like he saying oh no he was correct it's
like that's a great statement that he
did that was shows how intelligent he
was but he was wrong but we gave him
credit for that
now you look at the other statement to
the right Eichmann ein Berliner right
what an idiot everybody give me
everybody give him crap to this day they
still give him crap about that statement
they make fun about it's like it's been
in the Simpsons it's like you're he's
everybody was saying he told everybody
around the world that it's like he was a
jelly doughnut a president of United
States would not say something so
embarrassing to the world oh wait hold
on so so yeah we get to that point and
he's giving so much crap about that
statement that he was wrong there's only
one problem with that he was a hundred
percent correct when you're from the
city of Berlin and you believe that
you're a part of that town the proper
usage of the word in German is Eichmann
ein Berliner
that is actually the proper terminology
he said it exactly like a local person
from Berlin would say it if you were not
from Berlin it's like you would have
been asking for a doughnut but he was in
the city of Berlin he was trying to get
unity for the city in Berlin he was
identifying with the city in Berlin he
said it correctly and to this day we
still make fun of him so we say things
that are totally incorrect everybody
gives its credit and logs logging this
war it it's like you know and that was
to be okay and then we say things that
it's like are correct and people think
we're crazy it's like so I was like yeah
that's a pretty good justification of
industry another Ducks position of are
going to see another another good way
there are energy industry is and we can
judge it is based on this comic I hate
this comment I totally despise this
comment it's like this comic shows one
of the biggest problems of our industry
you got blue teamers who have an awesome
sock with you know they got their Splunk
and their pew pew maps and it's like all
they're like firewalls and ids is going
up and if something happens blame the
user you got red teamers you know coming
in break it in punching people in the
face is showing it to have a plan or not
and it's like it when the user falls for
it guess what
stupid user why don't we say stupid
information security don't how to
properly train their users this is not
the right way to do a comic I hated this
comic so much and I whined I'm sorry
complained about it so much that my
supervising adult Jason burns or my
manager guy he reached out to the artist
of this comic strip and we explained to
them and we lodged our complaint about
it and you know pay the money and he
fixed it for me that's what it should be
if you don't think that's the proper
usage of the comment you're part of the
problem because every single one of your
users is a asset to you someone to help
you in the situation and if you think
they're a liability you've made them
that way it's like because we always
like to and this one things about this
industry it's like we talked about zero
days day and night we worry about that
we worry about the technology to come
and protect us it's like we're trying to
get the technology to protect the users
instead of getting the users to
responsible for the technology we want
to offload their responsibilities and
still blame them at the same time how
does that work talk about contradictory
it's like we get into this whole concept
that they're like poor defenseless
little creatures and stuff you
who doesn't even know how to like use
the the shift key but then when
something happens they get full blame
for it
how is that how does that work because I
got to understand something for you real
quick it's like if you want to see how
quick and intuitive and resourceful and
innovative your users are take solitaire
off the machines see how quick that
comes back you give them incentive to do
some you will see how quick and adapted
they are it's like and the problem is in
humans it's like we'll accomplish tasks
they they require for them to do to be
employed period nothing else they'll do
what it's required of them to be
employed it's like that was a job it's
like hopefully it's still not because I
feel bad for those people okay but times
are tough in the fifties it's like that
that's that was a job they did it
because that was required of them so why
are we not making requirements for them
to be secure and I'm talking about
requirement with consequences how many
people here have seen at work or has a
job or been in a job where you had
delivery drivers and it's like cool
doesn't really matter because it's like
I'm still talking about delivery drivers
it's like because if you hire a delivery
driver on the first day of the job do
you give them the keys to the car and go
like hey and so you got license it's
like I checked that you got the job
congratulations off on your way here's
your wrap no you explain to the delivery
driver what your safety requirements are
you tell them how it should fire to them
to use to turn signals it's like how
they used a seatbelt how they have
airbags and other defenses the fit
systems in place in their vehicle how
they have to obey the traffic laws in
the areas that they are in it's like you
even go so far as to put a GPS a
recording device into that vehicle to
make sure that they are following those
policies and procedures it's like and
then you are also putting a sign on the
back of the vehicle so people can report
if there's an infraction on that
policy we do that for delivery drivers
users we give a computer we tell them to
read a manual it's like a read the
policies and then let them have it we
tell them all the stuff they need to do
to complete their job but we don't tell
them about the safety parts of it we
don't tell them about the security we
don't go into details we don't make them
responsible for that the delivery driver
is responsible for the accidents he
calls us why not the user on the
computer a delivery driver who wrecks a
car or a delivery van the first time may
have little bit of a problem right
second time later some disciplinary
actions do you think he's around after
the third time do you think he's still
employed at that company after the third
time probably that's a good question
there's a good point but the key thing
is if a computer user jeopardizes the
company security one time two times
three times where are the consequences
why are they still employed delivery
drivers cost you thousands and thousands
of dollars in damage to the vehicle it's
like you work for an HVAC company that's
in a partnership with Target you lose
300 million which one has more
repercussions which has more
consequences we are making the delivery
driver more have more consequences and
more responsibility that we give our
users on that computer when they could
jeopardize and lose millions of dollars
in our company but we're not giving them
that responsibility we're not giving it
to them if not that they're not taking
responsibility for it we haven't given
it to them whose fault is that is that
on them or us that's on us because
that's not showing what their
responsibility is it's like and you have
to understand that humans normally do
not take on extra tasks if it's not
really directly impact their job in a
negative way I mean literally I googled
excited worker all I got were stock
images
I kid you not and I guarantee you after
everything on one of those photo shoots
as soon as that camera was turned off
that model was like God ain't his job
you know it's like so we are not letting
them up you can't say oh this is like we
and if you can make sure you don't click
on links or make sure you're looking at
the source of the emails if we're not
making it imperative to their job
function they're not going to do it if
we're not telling them that they're if
we're not educating them and letting
them know that they're part of the
information security program how can we
get mad when they don't understand that
every single one of your users it's part
of your information security team period
from the CEO to the mailroom every
single one of them is responsible for
the security at the company and they
need to be made aware of that and
understands they're responsible for that
and there's repercussions if they fail
and that goes to the CEO I made a CEO of
a bank one time where a visitor's badge
because he lost his badge that was
policy I was in a hole
that doesn't reflect nice on me it's
like the CEO gets the credit because he
wore it because he understood that the
policy was there in place and he made
sure that he adhered to it and so every
single person that reported to him had
no excuse they had had to hear to the
same policy that's how we do it that's
how we educate our users from the
executives down we let them know they're
part of the securing team and they are
part and responsible for the security
policies and procedures in place and
they're responsible for those and the
reason why we don't just say because it
says in the policy and we explain it to
them we make them part of our team it's
like and we also have to discourage bad
behavior it's like I love this you can
actually Google add or go to youtube
adorable kids call my dad after paying
themselves
you got to love how it's not their fault
you know I don't know what happened it's
a it's like well I'm going I think he
did it and it's like oh what's like I
well I think he did it's like and the
other ones and then brought like what
happened you know it's like and we have
that right
you get in you find someone it's like
there's ransomware going out to your
network I don't know I think it was that
other you know Bob and accounting you
know how he is right it's like no let's
take a responsibility and when they do
show this from their machine it's like
well I didn't know it's like no one told
me that no one's explained to me that
was an issue so you sign the policy with
yeah but I just you know it's like the
Apple EULA you know it's like who
actually reads it
it's like someone does raise their hand
say they've read the EULA stay away from
them there they got issues but but
that's the problem right it's like
you've got to understand you give them
that responsibility you've got to show
them why things matter we can't just
keep going and saying that it's like
this is the positive procedures you have
to adhere to it we've got to show them
why there's repercussions we got to show
them why it matters and another thing is
this whole attitude oh I am thirsty
thank you it's like another thing is how
are we actually doing that it's like
look at I love this because this is like
from a couple weeks ago right wasn't
this funny Kanye West passcode was zero
zero zero zero zero zero and I don't
think that's like insecure it's like
it's only three zeroes instant more
insecure than the nuclear launch codes
that were around in the 70s and 80s okay
because that one was zero zero zero zero
zero zero zero zero zero they had nine
codes it's like if that makes you feel
safer during the 70s we survived thank
goodness it's like but I love PO know
the things response to it it's like he
wrote lots of folks who laugh at this
but I think it's a useful illustration
of how security features fail when
security decisions get offloaded to
users who see them as annoying obstacles
if your users don't understand why the
security is in place or why the
technology is in place then why should
they adhere to the policy they don't
understand it it's like if you get you
can have all the shiny and I I do agree
there's a counter-argument with Benton
did a couple weeks ago where he said
your defenses should withstand a click
and I agree with that also it's like I
agree at the last-ditch effort your
defenses should withstand to climb a
cliff it's like you should have
something it should not be just
dependent on the human because we have
to stop depending on
a human to do everything correctly we
have to have those layers but we need to
make sure that the humans are augmenting
our security system and they're aware of
what goes on so when something does go
bad they can report it as quickly as
possible it's not about the breach it's
about the response it's about how
quickly you respond to it and how
effectively you respond to it because
the breach is gonna breach right so on
this one it's like you see that this
code it's like you show the users don't
understand that they don't understand
why that's important you give them a
link and tell them that there's dancing
gerbils on the other side of that link
and I don't care if that big scary box
pops up and your web proxy saying this
looks like it's going to suspicious it's
like do you want to continue yes or no
well there's dancing gerbils on the
other yes how is that a question where's
your technology now where's your defense
system oh yeah he protected layer OSI
layer one through seven but I'm sorry
I'm not attacking layer 137 I stopped
attacking layer one through seven a long
time ago I'm all layer eight baby all
layer eight the human layer because I
don't have to circumvent your technology
if I can get your users to do it for me
that's where the attacks are evolving
too it's like because at the end of the
day if you still give that
responsibility and you offload that
responsibility to the users without
properly educating to them why it's
there
they will keep failing if you have an
IDs system and you put it in a snort box
and you've got them running this how you
install it get it up and running on the
network got the tap working right and
you load all the default signatures and
go done really are you really done it's
like if you don't fine-tune that if you
don't actually work on it and make sure
that it's actually reporting what you
wanted you don't have anything because
within five minutes you're turning all
the signatures off because they're too
noisy
same thing with humans if you're not
training and fine-tuning what they need
to be aware of showing them what they
need to be worried about and tell them
why the repercussion
are then you have an idea system that's
on a default and that's not giving you
anything you have to fine-tune that
there the best intrusion detection
system you're ever going to have because
they do that job day in and day out they
know when there's a variation they know
when there's something suspicious but do
they know who to call there's know who
to email when something does occur it's
all great that you educate and empower
your and enforce with your employees but
you actually give them the means and the
tools to report the issues do they know
who to contact and quite frankly if they
knew to contact you they really want to
talk to the people that you're supposed
to contact it's like well give it a
little bit later oh by the way I have a
confession to make
this is not really a regular kind of
rant this is sort of like a
choose-your-own-adventure kind of thing
because I'm not going to take questions
right off the bat I'm asking you
questions and someone from the audience
is going to answer it's like I will
spoiler alert because if no one raises
their hand I will run out to the
audience and I will pick someone
randomly and the people in San Paulo
thought I was joking
I was not it's like so and I've been in
the back that does not protect you it's
usually where I go first
so let's start off with some questions
that I have for you guys it's like what
is our biggest challenge in InfoSec when
it comes to the users was our biggest
challenge I'm gonna ask that one more
time that I'm gonna start running what
is our biggest challenge you to come to
the users yes exactly how to communicate
to the users why it's there it's like
why there's a threat it's like they're
not going to understand the DDoS or
ransomware or encryption attacks it's
like they're not going to understand why
passwords need to be salted or hash - or
you know baked or you know cooked it's
like they don't know those things
it's like you have to talk in the ways
that they understand I will talk about a
little bit later but that is one of our
biggest challenge is communication it's
like is there any other one other yes
so it's like how do we actually get them
once they understand it how do we get
them to actually go for it and actually
work with it it's like you're saying is
that what you're saying okay
so yeah that's a big problem it's like
we're gonna have all the policies and
procedures in place then we haven't
taught them what they are it's like how
are they supposed to accomplish it
it's like we'd have everything put in
place it's like you know the funniest
thing is like the Great Wall of China
right huge monumental great testament to
architecture in defense it was never
breached by structural integrity it's
like it was never breached that way it's
only breached twice guess out both times
1 by misdirection and an employee it's
like you know the other one insider
attack from the ball off employee both
of them inside threats I wanna give one
more question it's like truck we got
another one it's like you volunteered
for that one it's like I don't know what
it is
that's part of the surprise so how do we
engage you used to be part of the
security process and not part of the
problem how do we engage them how do we
make them part yes
Leslie whoa really
wait we're supposed to listen to them
it's like we're supposed to listen to
what their needs are and what their
issues are and what things that they
come up with what they find suspicious
or what they find difficult to deal with
that's a novel concept it's like it's
like and that's the one that we also
have a lot of problems dealing with
right it's like but maybe if we listened
a little bit more and said explain to
them what they were doing wrong and
listen to how they could do things
better and more efficiently for them and
meet their needs so we're not a
hindrance to avoid it's like we're
actually an ally to be there with them
maybe our jobs would be a little bit
better but listening to him poop right
yes
exactly one of the key things if that
CEO but he was saying the tone there's
tone from the top it's like upper
manager buying so I guess the SSP
question you know what's like upper
management buying from the security
processes is Integra and intern rule
whatever that word is right is it
important
it's like because at that CEO would have
said now I own the company honestly I
don't really need my badge every person
that reports to him no longer has to
have their Bosch because they report to
the CEO and then every person that
reports to them doesn't need their
badges because their boss doesn't need
their badges and they're doing important
work and you've got no security policy
if your CEO is not willing to adhere to
the same security policy he's telling
the mailroom to have you have to inform
them it is part of your job
responsibilities to inform them that he
has no security policy if it can be
circumvented by one it can be
circumvented by all you have to get
upper management of the process and even
when it's inconvenient now another thing
is how we actually see what are we
securing it's like nothing shows
incompetence since I can the best things
I know shows incompetence and not
actually understanding what you're
supposed to be doing than the TSA thank
you very much it's like a luckily I
drove here but still true because how
does your business make money how do you
make money how do you actually what is
required via the network for you to make
money can your email be down for five
minutes and you still make money can
your email be down for five days and
still make money can your email be up
and your website down and you still make
money if your database is lost does that
ruin your company if your customer
records are lost do you still make money
what is actually required for you to
still make money what does your business
do how they do it over that what is
integral do you understand all those
questions have you talked to every
depart
and figured out what their processes
what their business process is and what
is required for them and what needs to
stay internal and not be breached where
the crown jewels where are they at and
whether the defense is around them do
you know those things if you don't
everybody's got a homework assignment
right because that is a requirement for
you to have and to understand if you
want to actually be protecting your
company because if you don't know how
your company makes money
how are you protecting your company
that's like going through the TSA and
then and I was just coming out of this
last trip and a guy was complaining to
me that there was a hand a little
necklace thing a little charm on his bag
and the shape of a gun it was this big
the shape of a gun yeah he lost it
because they were afraid he'd be going
I'm going about Honduras now you know
it's like turn the play around
I really got a USB grenade confiscated
it it's like because it looked like a
grenade it was this big I still carry a
USB grenade now with me when I travel I
just take the top off it doesn't fit the
pattern so it's okay that's the
stupidity of not understanding what
you're protecting it's like and having
your default go to signatures instead of
any kind of critical thinking if your
employees and your security are not
doing critical thinking they're just
going based off signatures or what
policies or procedures are guess what
you don't really that much of a security
program it's like you have some great
stuff on paper but when it comes to
executions you've got a problem
another thing is I skip pulling or do we
go but nope I didn't okay only it's like
how do we communicate to our users how
do we communicate to our executives
security has to build a rapport with the
executives and the users before a breach
happens when I started out in
information security I was an a-hole I
was horrible I did a lousy lousy job for
my employer I just come from physical
security and law enforcement so it's
like I treated every
users and potential perk right it's like
I was very people didn't learn security
they learned how to avoid me
that's not security they learned how to
make sure they didn't screw up so they
wouldn't have to deal with me if that's
the kind of environment that you have
you're not hearing anything from your
IDs system it's staying quiet because it
doesn't want to interact with you so you
need to build a rapport before something
bad happens that the only time they see
you is when something bad
you're just negative when I worked on
the game times works I guarantee you
I've met people on the worst day of
their life every single day either
something horrible just happened and I
showed up or I showed up and sudden
horrible is about to happen
okay it was never a good thing
because I go to a lot of conferences
people so you still feel the same way
about me but still it's like it's never
the best thing but with information
security it's got to be different
they've got to know who you are and that
you're there to help keep them employed
it's part of your job to make sure they
still have a job because if they get
breached and you lose all your data
people lose jobs if they understand that
you're there to help protect them not
just get them they will help you you
have to teach them that you have to show
them do lunch and learns do classes show
them and your newsletters on how to
secure their Facebook settings how to
watch their children online is to make
sure that they're staying safe and their
privacy settings your said show them
that you're trying to facilitate them to
learn to be better at security surprise
they still won't care about your data
but there'll be more security conscious
and they bring that to work that's what
you have to do you have to teach your
users that you're there for them not
there to report them not there to clean
up after them not there to get them in
trouble but you are there for them when
something goes bad and they will start
talking to you they will be
or available to you to talk to you it's
like you can't just show up every time
something bad happens you know I'm cute
and adorable right now on stage but I
guarantee when I worked at the bank and
it's like I would walk into a place crap
there yes that's that weird hacker dude
it's like this is not a good thing and
it really was it usually but I also
showed up to the networking site and I
talked to them I gave them conversations
it's like I actually tried to make it
where it was like I was trying to go to
rapport with them that's where you're
hard cuz these were networking guys
right but still I did it old wounds
sorry it's like but you know I did that
and that's what built up the rapport
that helped me out in the long run it's
like that's the community that security
must realize that communication is how
humans get patched another really witty
quote social engineering because there's
no pass for human stupidity wrong there
is a patch the problem is you can't buy
a blinky box for it the problem is it
requires effort so instead of having
effort we have jokes instead of a heavy
responsibility we get to shrug it off
and put it to someone else and shift
blame the patch for human stupidity is
education that's what it is we have to
take the effort to educate our users
make them invested in the process and
Vesta and that sucks and that's hard and
that is difficult and that's the reason
why we keep getting compromised and
that's the reason why people keep
clicking on links there's nothing
sophistication of the attacker I tell
people social engineering so easy I can
do it okay I've got into social tearing
so I wouldn't have to be technical
because I'm going after the humans who
aren't being patched and that's why they
succeed
it's an effort so instead of laughing
off your employees educate them then you
patch them so another question time what
is the biggest impediment you're facing
and doing a more effective job there's
the one that usually everybody quiet on
and I warn you I randomly selected one
person their boss from standing record
sitting right next to him it's very
awkward it's like I didn't care it's
like so yes bring out where to start
that's a that's a good one it's like
where did you start to create all this
and you know what you start it with a
newsletter start it with how many people
know about the iOS 6 or that are aisle 6
Wow mold iOS 12 update us half off it's
like the Alice 12 update right have you
send an email out company-wide telling
your users like oh by the way I'll Apple
just came out with the new path because
it fixes some security vulnerabilities
you should patch it because that's
actually effing useful information they
may want to know that's something that
pertains to them when they're when the
FBI sent out last month
everybody should reset their home
routers reducing down an alert telling
you oh by the way the FBI sent an alert
to everybody to reset the home routers
if you didn't know did you send that to
your employees to let them know hey to
keep you more secure at home you're
gonna want to do this and guess what
you're actually giving them actionable
information and intelligence that they
can use for their home light that shows
that you're facilitating them being
secure that you care about their
security really though but still it
appears that way and that's perfect when
you start teaching them to be more
security conscious at home they bring
that to work they're never going to care
about your data stop getting employees
to try to care about your data get your
employees to be more security conscious
at home they bring that to work and
that's what counts
so that's when your biggest things is
starting with just um email alerts
starting up is like you have an inch of
website you know an internet site you
have a page that actually gets updated
I've seen internet websites from users
for security that are like six months
old oh yeah that makes it look like I
care about security right it's like I
better watch out for that in this way 67
that seems to be going around it's like
that's something I've got will actually
you still have to worry about that one
unfortunately but still it's like you
know it's like you have to update it you
have to keep it in Bible and show them
and that
know where it is you don't sit in the
email company-wide saying click on this
link for in security tips okay that I've
used that before an attack it works very
well but you don't want to get your
employees trained on that ok so it's
like you need to educate them and you
need to start off with just by giving
them information that is actionable to
them get them invested in security
possibility let them realize that you're
just not there when something goes wrong
here's another good question
it's like so what is your biggest
accomplishment as it relates to creating
a more secured environment at work
everybody raise your hand at once ok
this is like the easiest one to answer
most people are worried that one like
you know call you out on it but it's
like I'm not using gonna call people out
it's like well you already asked me what
I want to make someone else to have a
horrible day yes users trust you that's
important how did you get users to trust
you woah
okay for those of you didn't hear it
though you see we'll probably don't
believe it she said users trust them
it's like because they're nice to them
that's that's novel okay I guess that's
one way to do it it's like I haven't
heard that in very many environments
it's like that's the first time I heard
that answer you're actually nice to them
it's like you're actually treating them
like they're part of the team Wow it's
amazing what happens when they actually
feel like they're a part of something
instead of the problem and the reason
for things going wrong
Wow that's a novel idea that everybody
should be doing and should already not
be a novel idea in 2018 but still is so
that is a that is a great accomplishment
so another thing is I'm gonna keep going
I got a lot more rant to do how do we
approach to the problem humans versus
tech I've talked a lot about blinky
boxes will not save you period sorry all
the vendors here in the room sorry it's
like I mean they got new blinky boxes
they got blue lights instead of the red
ones it's like it's really cool matrix
II I mean I love the blinky boxes okay
don't get me wrong it's like but that's
not going to save you it's like unless
it is supposed to augment what you have
the best resource you have is to augment
your security it's to augment your users
it is an added layer defense for your
users if you think that's the solution
you don't know what the problem is
that's period that's just the way it is
you have to start giving technology in
there that helps augment your users not
trying to replace them it's like you
have to get the technology in there that
helps them your company should survive a
click your company should also be
advised and aware and relying on their
employees to know when not to click and
if you only have one and not the other
your have a deficit you have to have
both stop saying it's an either/or
situation it does not it is only a both
total sum game how do we show risk and
ways to affect change it's like how do
we do that
how do we show risk that effect change
it's like metrics one of the biggest
problems I get people coming up to me
and telling me stuff with my executive
doesn't understand sometimes that will
magazine he doesn't understand what the
problems they don't even know what we do
whose fault is that it's like do you
know what kind of metrics do you have
available to you to give to your
executives how many firewalls hits do
you get every month five billion
freaking record it
how many IDs signature hits you get 100
million record it
how many spam emails get into your mail
gateway and they're stopped and then and
what ones go through record it how many
systems are passed currently enough
today in your environment record it put
it in metrics put it in a pie chart
everybody loves pie right it's like it
showed that every month year executives
give them numbers that's how they speak
executives do not need to understand how
you think or how you talk or your
terminology you need to talk to your
executives in the way they understand
they don't need to know the terminology
that you understand it's not their job
it's your job and your responsibility to
teach the executives and ways that they
make to make actionable intelligent
decisions based on the data that you're
giving them so tired thinking speakers
coming up here telling me about the
knots LEDs and the end of jump popping
the shells and not using all these great
terms and they look really really smart
if I can't take anything away from that
talk you wasted my time if you go into a
management meeting and you tell them
that what the problems are in what's
going on in the issues and they leave
out more confused than when they came in
you wasted their time you need to be
able to explain the subject in the topic
in a way that the person in the back can
understand it no offense to the people
in the back but it's like you know that
that's the way it works you got to be
able to explain those things in the way
that like I'm a high school dropout if I
don't understand what you're talking
about how am I supposed to implement it
seriously that's what needs to be done
and how do we battle the contest
fatigue with dealing with users it's
quite simple it's like what we do there
is we do one simple thing gamify it stop
expecting users to do the right thing
because it's the right thing
who does that it's boring trust me I've
tried it before it's like no one wants
to do that make them incentivize to do
the right thing
gamify your situation if a person
reports a suspicious email to security
they get one entry into a drawing can
your company afford four thousand
dollars a year one thousand dollars a
quarter there's a prize and everybody
who has reported an incident or done
something security related that's gotten
an entry is eligible for that prize
every quarter for a thousand dollar
price that's pretty good that's pretty
pricey for someone to be able to get
that but it's like you know that's a
good thing it's like if you report us if
you report a suspicious person
piggybacking off you and you stop them
that's maybe two entries you report to
the security and email fish that
actually was an actual fish you get
three entries it doesn't matter how many
entries people get you've got a fixed
prize the only difference is you have
more and more people participating
friend of mine told me how he had a
gamification system and work and at work
where they've got it in place and guess
what happened lady reported a suspicious
email attack coming from a co-worker and
guess what that co-workers system was
compromised
the rooters were actually in the network
and they were trying to estimate their
privilege and pivot off that workstation
does she know that when they asked her
why she reported it her
honest-to-goodness answer was well I
just thought it was part of the game and
it's like I was just trying to get
another inch into the sweepstakes
seriously she had no clue she just
wanted another entry she saved them
millions of dollars because she wanted
to get an extra tree I think she won
that month it's like you know it's like
I would I would let her win that one
it's like but she didn't do it because
she was security-conscious she didn't do
it because she was responsible for the
data of the company she did it because
there was something in it for her game
of Phi your users make them part of the
process make them want to participate
make them want to be more security
conscious because there's next I don't
care about your data but there's
something in it for them
oh and I have one quick confession
before the talks over the whole part
where the title of my talk was it was
not really about you guys well I lied
our industry has to get better it's like
and we don't get better by building more
blinky boxes we get better by having our
users be part of the solution instead of
thinking that they're just part of the
problem and if you go to work and you
think that you're dealing with a hostile
work environment it's like wait till in
other countries in they're playing
around in it so make them part of your
team because they are
it's like period done in Durant
you