so let me start off and ask how many
folks in here consider themselves more
on the development side excellent
excellent
you never know sometimes I give this
presentation and it's kind of more on
the security side they probably won't
get as much from it so I'm glad that
most of the folks in here are on the
development side I do want to start off
with this small disclaimer because this
is about security testing and this stuff
should be used on systems that are not
yours you know there there are some
tools listed at the end that can be
useful to attack various systems so yeah
don't do it unless you have approval as
mentioned I have been a developer for a
while I guess you can say that but I'll
say it I started out as a developer
obviously from running the dalles PHP
user group I began with PHP a couple
years ago I decided to pivot more into
specific area of application security
and you know I'm a speaker predominantly
at developer conferences but more at
security chrome feathers lately and I am
a security advocate in the PHP community
there are very few of us but we're
getting word out and it's getting better
so you know fingers crossed that
continues and now technically part of
Cisco so as of a couple of months ago so
some of the stuff will cover some of the
basic concepts of application security
and the top vulnerability types this is
not an OAuth top ten talk so don't worry
about that
we're not gonna get into all of those
things just some of them because
hopefully if I have enough time gonna
give give some examples some practical
examples and then finish up with some
tools and techniques that you can use to
kind of find these issues
normally this was given as a three hour
tutorial and so the examples I have were
actually hands on so that the developers
in the room could sit down and try to
find these issues themselves but I had
to shorten it obviously for talk length
so if you're interested in the full
version of this you know I can give you
the application that I created that I'll
show you and you can go wild with it
it's not as full featured as some of the
you know CTS stuff that they have
obviously it's not a comprehensive guide
to penetration testing there's really
not any way you can squeeze that into an
hour so hopefully
nobody was expecting that coming here
that's a multi-day course honestly and
this is not gonna be an insurance that
your application is completely secure
obviously there's nothing no such thing
as a hundred percent secure but this
will give you a little bit of a better
perspective hopefully on how you can
test your application and find these
kind of vulnerabilities in your own
stuff and it's definitely not a stopping
place so don't follow these slides and
say oh I did all this stuff that's great
my application is great
no you're just getting started all right
so some of the vulnerabilities one of
the most general classifications is an
injection attack obviously everybody's
familiar with a lot of these that is
everybody relatively familiar with the o
oz top ten I'm assuming if you're at
this conference you are okay so all
these should look pretty pretty familiar
you know they're all different types of
injection attacks one of the ones that a
lot of people forget is just regular old
content injection it's easy to highlight
cross-site scripting and sequel
injection and everything because they
actually perform an action that a lot of
times content injection can be used to
actually put things into the page you
know error messages that kind of stuff
that misson forms the user and tells
them to go do something else it's not
necessarily a you know an action or
something that happens because of it
it's just you know general information
across site scripting the most classic
example you know the script alert in a
parameter URL parameter and it's it's
easy to forget that basically this can
do anything that JavaScript can this can
modify page content it can access
cookies local storage
I saw one attack that actually over
wrote and knew that the images were on
the page for a certain certain
advertiser and so the injection over
wrote those with malicious links and
images but it looked like it was part of
the normal page so you wouldn't even
know unless you knew that it was an
actual attack happening fortunately
browsers are getting a little bit better
about detecting that they have some
automatic stuff that happens usually it
works best for reflective cross-site
scripting but those things I mean if
nothing's foolproof so it's still
possible to get attacked by them so when
you're working on an application some of
the places to look
for the possibility of a cross-site
scripting like if you're testing your
own application look for any form inputs
where the data is just basically then
output to the page you know a lot of
times this can happen in like a search
field you know you put a search term in
and then at the top of the page it says
you searched for whatever now if they're
not properly escaping that that's a
pretty easy cross-site scripting vector
you know to get in get in on sometimes
you can also do the same thing with URL
parameters and don't forget about hidden
inputs as well you know in the forms a
lot of times the you know the ID or
something like that from the URL will be
taken and put into a hidden field you
can use that for an HTML attribute
injection you close off that quote and
then you can put in whatever you want to
include any JavaScript and all that so
you know be sure and check the source of
the page as well once you put that in
there and then sometimes if they're not
actually escaping it correctly you can
get stuff into the database and that's
then output on other pages or you know
like user user profile information that
could be output across the entire site
if there's not a consistent templating
mechanism on there then you know if they
try to do it on every page individually
they might miss one and if you have your
name as you know script alert one then
it'll show up on that particular page so
you just have to be careful obviously
the fix is filtering the output you know
that could be something as easy as a
templating system how many people
actually use a generalized templating
system on their applications okay a
couple of folks all right so do the rest
of you just go in and escape your output
manually on every single piece of data
yes know this yes this is no it's okay
to say no or it's okay to say yes I
guess in this case as long as you're
actually outputting or escaping that
data and filtering it out and then next
up pay attention to the context there is
actually several different contexts in
web applications HTML Javascript CSS
HTML attribute XML and they all have to
be escaped relatively differently you
can get away with somebody aged
they'll stuff too you know escape that
similarly but if you're using you know
user input and output in it in any part
of your application any of those
contexts you have to be careful and
escape it you know appropriately for the
context and like I mentioned templating
layers they're a lot easier than one-off
escaping coming from the PHP world I
have seen a lot a lot a lot of
applications that use HTML special
characters and you know those those
functions that escape the HTML
constantly used throughout the entire
application and there's you know
thousands of them in there
now obviously the chances of you missing
those are pretty high you know you
change one thing and then you have to go
through and be sure that that particular
piece of data is escaped across the
entire application the benefit of having
a templating layer like in the PHP world
they have Twigg which is just one of the
the main ones there's a lot of different
ones but that's the most widely used
it'll do the auto escaping for you so
you pass the data into the templating
layer it manipulates it and outputs
you know the filtered version of it
unfortunately I haven't gotten to be
able to convince them to take out the
raw output type so that you can still
output raw data without having it
escaped but maybe one day
okay next type of injection sequel
injection hopefully everybody's familiar
with that you you know close off that
you directly put stuff into the sequel
statement that's being executed on the
back end there's a tool that I mentioned
later on called sequel map is anybody
familiar with that okay a couple of
folks for those that aren't basically
what it allows you to do is it define
you define the the parameter that's
susceptible to the sequel injection
attack and then it can then use that to
go in and basically extract anything it
wants to you know you if you're doing
manual sequel injections
you know manual attacks you know and
later on and one of the examples that
actually show that I'm not sure if I'll
be able to get to it for this session
but you can use unions to extract
anything you can extract from the
information schema not just the database
tables that you've defined in your
application but you can actually extract
table structure you know
column tight all that kind of stuff
sequel map makes that a lot easier you
just point it at the system and say this
particular parameter is vulnerable and
then it goes in and and extracts all
that stuff for you and it's all
automated and pretty and happy it works
for most things but you know sometimes
it has its quirks and depending on what
the what the queries are doing you can
actually perform sequel injection on
update and delete queries so you can
potentially you know say set this and
then inject comma this comma this come
of this you know an update database
information directly again form inputs
are a great place to look for sequel
injection vulnerabilities if you're not
filtering that any other query
functionality you know the the URL
parameters if you have a query parameter
on there you know that you could
potentially do that directly without
having to worry about you know the or
having to check the post anybody sensing
a theme here user input issues okay and
URL parameters sometimes you can use
these in blind sequel injection attacks
so you you know you stick something in
there that's purposefully made to slow
the query down and you know then you
know it's vulnerable to an attack even
if you can't see directly some kind of
change in the output you know with the
with this kind of thing I mean it's this
is the usual example of a login by past
with sequel injection but sometimes you
want something or you want to be able to
tell if something's happening on the
backend that's not necessarily reflected
directly in an action being taken on the
front-end so if you put in you know
sleep statements or something like that
then you can see oh I can directly
inject into the sequel let's see what
else I can do with it you know and start
dropping tables or dropping databases
and you know all that kind of fun stuff
so not super useful for extracting
information but if you want to just you
know mess around and cause some damage
and that's that's always fun so the fix
the main fix obviously for sequel
injection is bound parameters and
prepared statements is everybody
familiar with what those are yes awesome
good
okay you also have to be careful because
sometimes that data that the user is
inputting is used in other parts of the
sequel statement you can use these bound
parameters and prepared statements like
an aware clause but if you're letting a
user in or a piece of information that's
a table name that's a terrible idea
you know your table names you should be
able to specify those I have seen well
they're very seldom but I have seen a
couple of more management type
applications that use you know user
input for table names because they want
it to be flexible but that's just
basically asking for trouble so just be
careful to that okay next up direct
object reference so the basics behind
this is well there's kind of two
different two different things so you
could have a direct object reference
through you know like users upload files
or something like that they potentially
if their web facing are able to be
referenced directly from a user just
kind of guessing you know file names or
anything like that and then there's also
the idea of unprotected endpoints you
know if you log in and your user slash
one you know then it's a pretty good
chance that if you change that value to
two or three or four or five that if
there's not good security controls in
place you're going to view somebody
else's information and potentially
impact it you know basically if you find
that kind of vulnerability in your app
or you're using this kind of structure
be really careful and insured I believe
that whenever the page loads that you're
not just relying on the fact that
they're on this URL go ahead and pull
the user out of the session or however
you're storing it you know out of Redis
or whatever and then evaluate the
credentials that's a good thing to
follow in general honestly is to go
ahead and pull that user out and
evaluate their credentials every time
you possibly can don't just assume that
because they've logged in and you have
their permissions in the session that
those are going to be correct all the
time a lot of the better more robust
systems that I've seen they'll actually
pull that information you know recreate
the entire session every single time I
know it sounds expensive but you they
recreate that session with the user
permissions and
every single time so that if somebody on
the administration side goes in and
changes a value or changes a permission
that's instantly reflected in the
application you know if an attacker
manages to get in with an account and
the only time you're pulling the
permissions is right at login then
you're gonna have a really tough time
you know unless you have some way to
manually in that user session then
basically they can just keep going
forever and ever and if you even if you
change their permissions it doesn't
matter because they already have them
from the login direct object references
look for URLs with auto incrementing IDs
you could potentially change this and
use uu IDs or some other kind of a you
know hash based kind of thing to
reference these so that basically it's a
little more randomized now obviously you
can still automate you know something
that's a little more randomized even but
if it's just IDs that's that's a pretty
popular practice it's just using the
primary key ID or some Auto increment ID
from the database be very careful using
that you know you you want to make it so
that it's harder for the attacker to do
not just look at the page and say you
know oh well that's easy I can just
start incrementing these IDs and you can
also look for JavaScript calls you know
Ajax calls a lot of times in most
especially in modern web applications
that are you know JavaScript single page
applications when you perform an action
you know you may not see what's going on
behind the scenes it's not reloading a
page it's not doing anything like that
so if you you know pop open that
developer console down there and see
what those Ajax requests are that it's
making if those aren't protected
correctly you know you're not checking
permissions every single time on that
basically you can take that and you know
replay it or you know modify it slightly
how many people are familiar with a
capturing proxy okay cool
all right most most folks zap has this
built-in burp suite has this built-in to
where you can basically have it be the
go-between between your browser and the
service so you capture that that
information modify it slightly and send
it on you can also do something similar
with the chrome developer tools and
think Firefox has something similar how
many people knew you could right-click
in the developer tools on Chrome and
copy it as a curl command yeah okay
that's super handy by the way because it
captures all the cookies it captures all
the session information that the browser
has access to so you don't have to
recreate all that stuff in your scripts
you can just tweak that information a
little bit and it's all command line
which is super great
like I said implement those consistent
access checks
another thing that's easy to forget is
checking access on the data level
because sometimes what'll happen is
you'll go to one page and you can view
you know you're limited on what you can
do on that page but then you go to
another page and it pulls more
information and you're just assuming
that you know the access level is the
same and so they actually have more
content over here than they did over
here but because you're not checking the
data access and the data permissions
that make sense I know so it's it's a
lot harder to do it at the data level
unfortunately because a lot of times
that means going into the data itself
and running it through you know a filter
or something like that but if it's
sensitive enough data and you want to
protect it adequately then you kind of
have to do that you know a lot of times
it is based on the access level of the
actual endpoint that's that's being used
but sometimes you know it's it's a
little bit different especially on an
AJAX call that's returning you know JSON
something like that like a JSON
structure of something because with
ourian's and and you know helpful
functionality like that it's super easy
to just say select all this information
and then spit out all that information
and if you're not you know filtering it
based on what you need to then you could
be exposing a lot more than you you
should like I said consider the use of
public IDs such as uu IDs a lot of times
that will involve storing that that
information right alongside whatever the
record is there are some systems out
there and I forget what it's called
there's a library or a a method where
you can put in an ID or you know one or
two pieces of information and it'll spit
back out essentially a stub value and
it's consistent so that you can take
that and
reverse it back not bei 64 but it's it's
slightly different than that you know so
that you can kind of reuse that and it's
not one two three four or five you know
that kind of thing all right general
information exposure you know you find
those secret secret values you know
whether it's you know incremented
filenames you know if you upload a file
on on your service and you change the
file name or do anything to make it a
little more standardized you have to be
really careful with that because if
you're introducing you know sequential
numbers or sequential values or anything
like that then you could potentially
make it a lot easier for an attacker to
just say oh well I'm just gonna start
guessing file names what I usually
recommend for file uploads is having it
passed through an intermediary script
and then which you can do in that
intermediary script is you read in the
file you check the current user in the
session to see if they have the
permissions they need and then you
basically just stream the file contents
back out so you know it might be file
upload view and then the file name is a
parameter and then it can actually
filter and check those permissions you
know rather than having them be directly
web accessible you can use this kind of
thing to gather intelligence about the
different targets what you're testing
you know if your application has a
robots.txt that's pretty popular for you
know defining rules for search engines
and everything you have to be really
careful that that doesn't also expose
other things in your application you
know obviously most normal people are
not even gonna even bother with a robot
looking at that robots.txt but if you're
saying disallow you know certain
directories keeping the search engines
from reaching it that could provide
information to an attacker or to you as
you're running you know your tests on
the application so you can find it like
hidden files like robots.txt sometimes
what you can do is you can actually
cause errors on purpose like if you know
that something's looking for a certain
type of input and then go ahead and send
it the wrong type of input
you know sin if it's looking for numbers
or if it's looking for you know certain
characters or something like that
send it bad data send it you know random
ASCII characters and see what happens
because sometimes the error messages
will actually expose information that
you don't want shown to the user you
know it's really easy to just say okay
you know capture this exception and then
take that you know that error message
and spit it out the user well if you're
not catching all those exceptions
correctly then the message they see like
PHP loves to do on its default exception
handling is actually a full stack trace
of what has happened in the application
so you get file numbers file names class
names lines that it executed on and
there's lots of information so if you
caused errors on purpose you might get
information like that and sometimes it's
not even the application that it happens
at sometimes it can happen at the server
level as well so it just depends on how
they have it configured and then
sometimes if you're really lucky you'll
find the code injection and you can use
that to expose environment variables
environment variables is a pretty
popular method for protecting sensitive
values in web applications you know if
if they're able to inject any kind of
code or you know run anything on the
system then the chances of them finding
those environment variables goes way way
up so you have to be really careful with
those as well
you know don't put super sensitive stuff
in those environment variables some of
the fixes avoid security through
obscurity ensure that the anything
that's output to the users is clean that
you're not you know exposing too much
information if you have error messaging
in your application be sure that it's
not just catching exceptions and
relaying it everything should be some
kind of a custom message that's shown
back out to the user you should never
rely on something that your language
whatever it may be happens to spit back
out you know and and sometimes I've seen
people even go to an extreme and say you
know the message just says there was an
error and then there's a code after it
and then they have to go look up the
code you know either the user has to go
look up the
where they call customer support and say
I got an error it has this code on it
and it's extra hassle you know don't try
to do that that's that's more pain than
it's worth just make it
contextual but make it custom defined
instead of user or instead of language
output and if possible you avoid the use
of direct column names and identifiers
and user facing content this kind of
stuff is really easy to do on like data
tables or something like that where the
column name might be in the in the query
you know and then that just gives them
information then they can start
modifying that you know you have the
sort on the actual data table so you can
sort it by Ajax requests you could be
potentially exposing basically every
single column name in that particular
table so you have to be very careful
with that kind of stuff so just look for
that and see if there's some way on your
back-end that you can kind of capture
that stuff and say this column
corresponds to this you know this
particular or this value corresponds to
this particular column in the database
so you're not showing those directly
okay cool awesome
I do get to give examples okay so like I
said normally in the tutorial session
this is the point where we would just
start in and start on the application
and everybody would get to hack away at
it and try to find there or try to find
the issues we're gonna do this as a
group so hopefully everybody's not
asleep from their lunch everybody wake
up you know kind of get going okay all
right no cheating
okay hey it's me so let's make this
fullscreen and a lot bigger look okay
all right so these challenges are gonna
be based on the stuff that I just went
over and any kind of knowledge you might
have about the OWASP top 10 there's a
couple of things in here that you know
maybe I didn't talk about specifically
but they're in general good for a
developer to know what we'll do is I'll
actually go through the challenge or
well I'll walk through the challenge
with you guys after you all try to guess
basically and then explain
how that could be fixed on the backend
you know I wrote this in PHP that's my
background so it's it's relatively
simple application so I can show you the
code it it should make pretty much sense
even if you don't know PHP so anyway
alright so first up we make this a
little smaller okay so if this was your
application what would you do how would
you start testing this what's that
right click view source so let's see
what happens when we do that view page
source all right anything looking
suspicious
I'll go a little faster as reasons
anybody notice anything slash admin yeah
look at that
somebody thought that just commenting
out the link would be enough to protect
the admin page security through
obscurity yeah yeah in case you're
wondering yes it is not so if we go to
the admin page that's unprotected admin
direct access so obviously you would
want this to have some kind of
protection around it this does have a
username and password on it which is
good but you would still want to block
this if you don't want normal users to
be able to access that you can do it at
the server level and actually have a
configuration Apache or nginx or
something like that you can have that in
the configuration to say this URL in
particular the slash admin can only be
accessed from inside of our network
something like that when you're
protecting your applications don't just
think about protections at the code
level as you know think about
protections at the webserver level at
the network access level you know I
don't know how many people how many
people are basically a development group
of one ok there's a couple of you well
hopefully you have a couple of other
folks you know around you you know maybe
even a DevOps group or you know some
other their networking group that can go
in and help you set that kind of stuff
up but you know don't forget that
there's upper layers of protection that
kind of idea of defense-in-depth so
you're not just adding one layer of
protection on your application got that
pretty quick good job all right
second challenge
and I have to look at my notes I'm
trying to remember this one you want to
start off with a view source
and being interesting in there that's
the header for that yeah don't don't
worry about the the stuff for this this
is just anybody have any ideas nothing
really interesting in the source
JavaScript console alright let's take a
look I didn't see any JavaScript in
there but we can take a look
console reload no nothing in the console
network traffic a page CSS CSS
JavaScript JavaScript there are there's
the PHP session ID and that's it that's
auto-generated so you know it at least
started a session but think about think
about other things that you could look
at I mentioned some secret things you
might be able to look at there are not
hidden fields
no no not headers wait that's a good
guess though you can take a look at
those if I can't this is really hard to
do on this little podium so if we reload
this and it's so tiny I wish you could
actually increase the size but no there
is not anything special in the headers
but that's a good guess
robots.txt who would do anything bad in
there
see anything any anybody want to shout
it out Wow yes so if we go to that files
directory what did we get now keep in
mind this was kind of a capture the flag
thing so the first thing everybody went
for was the flag txt which you know so
there's a log and some people went for
the photo I actually had somebody
whenever I was doing this take this and
try to like look at the header
information and what is it's stenography
or whatever I forget it is yeah they
actually tried to reverse it that way I
was like cute you're trying too hard
okay so this last one make this bigger
I'm gonna close this okay so this is a
random log file that somebody left in
that files directory because they forgot
about it
notice anything admin passwords yes all
right so what else does this show us
that we didn't have information about
before which one the login path
yep user login you can see it on each
one of those so if we go back to our
application here user login know there
it is you log in with those credentials
oops I guess admin would be better huh
yeah we found the flag our happy little
flag space man good good good good see
you guys I got the hang of this I don't
know why you're even in this session all
right
so we're back to the blog we have some
functionality here this one's not
directly obvious let's just say that
it's not on this page I will give you
that hint so where should you start
looking the source you want to view
their source oops all right so let's
look here make this a little bigger
let's get past the nav there so you've
got some links it doesn't look like
there's anything particularly
interesting in there so let's see what's
next
yep
okay so let me
so you're saying view for like that so
there's no content but also no error
messages page not found which is pretty
much expected but there's not really any
useful information there we can even
view the source on that and see that
there's not any like hidden information
so any ideas okay I like where you're
going put it in the comments field you
like my little memes there I love that
in tanzic spider-man alright so let's
try putting in our traditional oh I
guess I could look over here
our traditional script tag so if we do
that we get a lovely message that says
JavaScript is not allowed so we can't
put direct scripts in there so what's
next to try what's that no no this is
not sequel injection I'll save that
you're getting close with the cross-site
scripting
four oh no that would just so whenever
it outputs it it actually templates the
output yeah so think about some other
ways that you can get JavaScript into a
page besides script tags and then what
now yes in an image so if you do
something like that I think that'll work
I might have to review my notes so if we
do that then we have our image down here
oh I think it's broken because I didn't
quote it correctly
so now we have a pop up very good so how
many people knew that you could do those
kind of on-air
onload all that kind of stuff inside of
image tags
that's yet another vector so it's really
hard to prevent that kind of stuff if
you're not just doing strict output
escaping that obviously that's gonna be
fixed if I escape the output on this
then that image tag is not going to be
displayed as an image tag it's gonna be
displayed as that literal HTML value
does that make sense so you kind of have
to think you know think not just about
script tags or anything like that
there's also a possibility for
JavaScript injection you know where
they're injecting a dynamic value into a
JavaScript string that's on your page if
you're using that directly in your
JavaScript yet another reason to have
your JavaScript in external files you
know separate files and not defined
directly in the page is anybody here
using a CSP content security policy do
you have local eval turned on okay all
right well that makes me feel a bit
better
so the the content security policy lets
you define what JavaScript can be loaded
on the page what images can be loaded on
the page it's sent as a header so you
know that's automatic it's not something
you have to include in the body of the
site but one of the switches you can
turn on and off for JavaScript is
allowing local eval basically local you
know JavaScript executing in the page
that's written on the page versus
another JavaScript file ideally you need
to get to the point where that's turned
off so that you don't have any script
that's not defined in a JavaScript file
somewhere because that allows you to
keep issues like that injection issues
out of your JavaScript directly in the
page you know I know it's inconvenient
sometimes when you have those dynamic
values and you want to put it into that
JavaScript so you kind of have to work
around that a little bit and have it
pull from like a hidden value or pull
something from a session or you know it
just depends on how you want to do it
but abstracting that JavaScript out is
always a better idea
are we doing on time okay doing pretty
good
all right challenge for so we are given
a username and password this is you know
the login for your application sequel
injection hang on let me let me check my
notes here and see if I have sorry
Summit's don't like Dobek crap how can I
turn off mirroring hang on
I'll block that there okay now you can't
see it uh-oh
can I turn off use a separate display
there we go all right now it's my
browser
there we go this would be easier that
bigger okay
so now let me get my cheat to you this
is three okay I will tell you that this
is not a sequel injection issue no I
don't want my contacts so this is
actually this is actually valid
functionality that's I almost said it
it's not an error No
so I will give you a hint I have a valid
user login and there are other valid
users of the system as listed here
default creds for which one admin so
there's actually it's actually multiple
things in this one but yes the default
credentials
everybody's installed software or
they've installed you know an appliance
or something like that's a huge problem
people leave those default credentials
out there if you want to see how big of
a problem it is go and search for the
software that you you're using or the
you know the hardware that you're using
and search for default login there are
tons of sites out there especially for
routers network tools all that kind of
stuff they just have all those default
passwords and so if you leave those
default passwords you're basically
leaving an open door to an attacker so
be sure and especially make them robust
passwords once you change them don't
make it you know admin one instead of
admin because that's super easy to guess
ok so there's actually something else
here what changed between my user that's
not an admin and the admin user
okay all right so let's do up in those
just for use later okay so if this was
your application
how would you investigate what was
happening here
that's a simpler way
you can look at the URL but yes you
can't inspect the element and actually
get that information so when that runs
so we'll delete our test one let me add
another user here I think this is
unfortunately this is gonna be the last
example I can get to you but we'll just
do test test just see that user okay so
we can delete this user using that
address right so if you can't read that
that's slash challenge slash there
challenge forward delete 9 so when we go
in and do that user is deleted
successfully so what should we try my
user test okay so we don't have the
delete button so what are we gonna do
try to delete anyway so let's try I
think it's eight user deleted
successfully permissions are not being
checked on the user delete correctly
that's why I realized the fact that you
need to check those permissions on every
operation so you're not assuming from
the session that they can do that
especially on damaging things like this
deleting updating anything like that
always check those permissions every
single time so okay I unfortunately I'm
not gonna get a chance to go through all
my examples but hopefully that was
useful for you guys I do want to mention
some basic tools oops too fast
I mentioned sequel map already that's
super great for abusing sequel injection
if you happen to find it
Kali Linux is super useful it's actually
a full Linux distribution that comes
with a lot of these tools already built
in and you can get it as an image I
think they might even do a docker
container now something like that but
you can go in and there's tons more
besides just web application stuff
there's lots of other tools in here
completely free so you can download it
running in a
go poke around John the Ripper is good
for reversing hashes does anybody know
why you shouldn't use md5 hashes and
sha-1 hashes what's that they are broken
but what's a super easy way to find out
with even easier than that even easier
than a dictionary attack anybody Google
search yes you can google md5 hashes and
sha-1 hashes and get the the plaintext
string you don't even have to reverse
the hash itself so don't use any of that
and then the beef project is a good one
for just general exploit it actually
runs as a browser integration thing and
so it does the testing as if it was a
user or you know runs the the tests as
it user would through the browser
instead of trying to do an automated
test where you have to have it log in
and do all this other stuff
so alright well that is all I have if
anybody's interested in seeing the other
things there's a fun serialized
injection one there's a JWT injection or
bypass and I think that might be it for
that but anyway that's me on Twitter
enigma I'm usually tweeting about random
stuff sometimes it's security sometimes
it's not and then I write articles for
this website that I started a while back
a lot of its kind of PHP focused but
there's some general security stuff in
there as well so if you want to check it
out and we'd appreciate it
any questions comments thoughts yes
which one not currently no uh well it
might be a public repo I'm not sure I'll
check on that yeah
come up after well I'll take a look at
it mmm anybody else no questions
did you all fall asleep everybody yeah
after lunch you know okay all right well
if nobody has anything else thank you
for coming appreciate it
[Applause]