okay let's get started hi everyone my
name is Jeff Williams CTO and co-founder
at contrast security and I've been
working with
iwasa since the beginning of OS but I
was one of the founders of a wasp and I
was the global chair for the for nine
years while we were getting off the
ground but I haven't really done much
with us in the last you know I don't
know six or seven years so I still love
us a lot
it's one of the best things that I feel
like I've done in my career I'm
extremely excited and proud to be
speaking here today I'm going to talk
about building a dev snake ops pipeline
and I'll just start by saying I think
that DevOps is one of the most
transformative things that's happened to
software since object-oriented
programming came out I mean it's really
like that level of transformation some
of you may be too young to remember
before but we used to do a different
kind of programming that's right so
let's jump into it here a little bit I
wanted to start by giving a sense of
what the average application looks like
now I've represented it here's an
iceberg and what's below the water is
libraries and frameworks you know open
source code primarily and above the
above the waterline is your custom code
and I think it's interesting to just
look at where the vulnerabilities fall
in this in this iceberg most of them are
above the waterline average application
has 26.7 vulnerabilities in his custom
code that is bananas by the way that is
an insane level of vulnerability and
this has been true by the way for the
last 15 years it's roughly that number
of you know like truly verified
vulnerabilities it hasn't gone up and
down very much over that time can you
imagine if we were like the airline
industry and every time you tested a
plane it had 26.7 safety problems that's
nuts we're producing massively
vulnerable code and it's almost all
basic blocking and tackle
I wrote that I lost top 10 in 2002 that
16 years ago and it's still the same
in there I had this idea like oh
well we'll put the top 10 out there and
then we'll do that for a few years and
we'll raise the bar and then we'll add a
few and like over time we'll just get
better but we haven't and sometimes when
you try to create a floor you actually
end up creating a ceiling so now like
the office top 10 is kind of
aspirational for most organizations
which is awful and an unintended side
effect of what I was trying to do there
and a lot of people are talking about
you know library vulnerabilities which I
think are really important but let's
just remember that's like one of the top
10 so you know I think it's it's an easy
to understand problem so people rush out
they're like oh we got to make sure
we're not using libraries with known
vulnerabilities and you can buy tools
that are good at that because it's a
simple problem and you know maybe you
can put some effort into that but really
you're not pushing the ball very far
down the field if that's the only
problem that you solve and you can see
why in the iceberg and in fact it's
actually even worse than this because if
you look you know 79 percent of the code
is below the waterline and so people say
like focus on the big part of the code
right but really almost all of that code
is unused that library code almost never
gets called so only a tiny fraction of
it actually ever gets invoked and there
are far fewer vulnerabilities in that
part so if you're gonna totally says hey
you're using 25 out-of-date libraries
you need to replace them all well it's
pretty good chance that you're not
actually invoking the code in those
libraries at all anyway so there's a
really a weird kind of false alarm
so be careful on where you focus your
efforts in app side the other side of
this is that attacks are out there if
you actually look if you put
measure measurements on your
applications and try to measure who's
actually attacking you and what kind of
techniques they're using you'll see
every application out there gets
attacked every single month this is our
our results from last month
maybe 20,000 applications and you can
see there's a huge level of attack this
is the likelihood that the application
will see an attack in that category
right so more than half the applications
see sequel injection attacks more than
that sees you know path traversal and
reflected XSS there's a ton of scanning
going out on there anybody know what
that that first CVE is by the way that
5638 nobody that's Equifax that's the
breach that took down Equifax and you
got to be aware the day after that
vulnerability was disclosed at an OS
prevent it started getting immediately
attacked broad scale attacks across the
internet within a day and that's the new
reality is that folks are looking for
new vulnerability disclosures they read
the disclosure they reverse-engineer an
attack and then they start bombarding
the internet to try to find
vulnerabilities you know fine you know
folks that are vulnerable to that so you
got to have a process in place for
dealing with these new vulnerabilities
that are coming out very quickly so look
that's a bad situation if we got a lot
of vulnerabilities and there's a lot of
attacks out there that's a recipe for
disaster so we got to do better we got
to do basic blocking and tackling to
deal with some of these problems that
we've known about for at least 20 years
cross-site scripting sequel injection
command injection path traversal and so
on these are not new vulnerabilities so
here's the problem
traditional application security doesn't
really work I'm guilty here I ran a
consulting company for fifteen years and
we did all the services everything
that's in the you know the maturity
models we did threat modeling and
architecture reviews and code review and
pen testing and training and you know
automation and absolute programs and all
all this stuff I've done it all and by
and large I have to say I don't think it
works very well and the results show
that like we can't keep doing what we've
been doing because it doesn't work we're
not getting the results that we really
want ultimately I think here's the
problem is if you've got any kind of
decent sized portfolio of
locations if you're trying to shove it
through a traditional apps tech program
which is built with experts and tools
for experts you're doomed because
there's not enough experts anytime you
do anything that requires an expert
involved in the critical path to getting
code into production you're screwed
because you've got an instant bottleneck
and there's nothing that you can do to
scale it so ultimately my talk here
today is about getting you to see that
we have to get security experts off the
critical path we've got to be able to
push code into production without me or
you in the critical path that means your
job changes you can't be the guy that's
finding the xs/s you've got to be more
like a coach or a tool Smith in order to
help get that pipeline automated and you
know if you've got a bottleneck kind of
process what we see in almost every
organization is that they only focus on
a subset of their application portfolio
anybody got an organization where
they're only looking at like the
criticals these are the high risk
applications may some organizations
they're like well that's just the ones
that are external facing some of the
smarter ones are like well it's the
external facing ones but it's also some
of the internal ones that are really
valuable because that's you know that's
a high impact us but however you figure
it out they're only looking at a subset
of the apps and then what happens is
that's still too much for this approach
to work and so then they have to start
lowering the bar right and all of a
sudden now you're configuring your tools
to not false-alarm so much anybody done
that a star turn it off rules and pretty
soon you've got an incredibly expensive
XSS detector and that's what we're
putting all this effort and work into
building a program that's ultimately not
delivering what we want and I think we
all know what we want if you want to
Matt imagine the outcome that you really
want you want all of your applications
in your portfolio and you want to be
relatively sure that they're not
vulnerable to attack and that they're
protected if they are attacked that's
the goal but we're not getting anywhere
close to that with the current program
so I think dev SEC Ops is incredibly
promising DevOps transformed software
development and dev sack ops can
transform security but it's not just
shoving legacy security tools into
DevOps Larry Mascheroni from Comcast he
calls that lipstick DevOps lipstick on a
pig right it's automating the scan
button is not going to get us there
because it doesn't really solve the
problems with the expert group and we'll
get to that in just a second but the the
big transformations with DevOps we're
taking a software process that you know
as big monolithic and not very you know
not very agile not very many feedback
loops and transforming it they took the
work and broke it down into little
pieces that you can deliver now can we
do that for security sure but we don't a
pen test is like this big chunk of work
right security architecture is a big
chunk of work that we do all is one big
giant thing we got to break that down
the little pieces that we can deliver
all the way piece by piece and as we'll
see a lot of that work can be done
without security experts so that's the
first thing is getting security work
flowing because right now it's not
flowing we do it you know at the end of
the lifecycle it's a big effort it's a
long feedback loop it's all the same
problems your software had so that's the
first step we got to break down security
work into little pieces that are
valuable the second thing is we've got
to ensure instant feedback a lot of the
feedback that we give is way too late
if you ever anybody seen that curve
where it says like you know a security
vulnerability costs X in if you find it
in requirements or development and then
it's like 10 X if you find it in tests
and you know 100 X if you find it in
production that chart is all wrong
because it's not a straight line about
half an hour after that code gets
committed the cost goes up by like
zillion times right because once it's
committed developer
the next thing if they can fix it in
stride while their programming costs
almost nothing but it immediately goes
up so the the curves wrong but the point
is right like we got to get super early
in the process get these problems fixed
instantly and then the last thing is in
for DevOps is to create this culture of
experimentation and learning and that's
also something that we really struggle
with insecurity is most security is done
based on standards that are kind of
backwards looking you know like the top
ten
it looks backwards that like what what
vulnerabilities do you have it's not
thinking about what's the threat gonna
be in three years or five years when the
system is out being deployed we're not
building for that threat we're building
for the threat from three years ago or
more audit driven app SiC is really
about it if so we can build a culture of
experimentation and learning but we
gotta allow everybody to say hey that's
a you know that's a potential
vulnerability comment on the threat
model make it concrete and we'll talk a
little bit more about that so I think
this is really promising this is not
what this talk is about if you're
interested I wrote a ref card about this
a D zone that you can download
intro to dev sack ops and there's some
other materials out there that I think
are good I just want to throw this up
there as III encourage you to look at
pictures of dev sack ops that are out
there because there's a lot of different
you know reference architectures and
pipelines that people are trying to draw
but they're they're all super
complicated they've got a zillion tools
and then they're trying to take all
those tools and shove them together and
orchestrate that process if you look at
gardener's process for instance they're
basically like well you got to buy one
of every single kind of tool and then
you need an orchestration tool to run
all those tools and then you need
another tool to take all the results of
all those tools and correlate them and
you know analyze them so that you can
make get value out that's bananas
nobody has that's not gonna work nobody
has enough people to run all those tools
much less see this little icon at the
top this is app sack analyst
false-positive remover
that bubble should be like 80 or 90
percent of this screen because that's
all the work I know many organizations
have teams I don't wonder if she's got
over 50 people all they do is take the
output of static analysis tools and weed
out the false positives not only is that
it's sort of a miserable existence it's
not a career it's not automated if you
have to have a human in the loop it's by
definition it's not automated so we're
failing it on that so just look at these
pictures with a skeptical eye if they're
I call this tool soup and tool soup is
not a knapsack strategy you can't just
take a zillion tools and throw into the
problem and expect value to come out so
I want to the last speaker talked about
starting with the end in mind and I want
to do that here too so when I think
about a dev sack ops pipeline for me
it's three parts in development we want
to empower developers to create secure
code and checking in clean right I think
we can all probably agree on that to me
that means it's got a it's got to do
significant testing it's got to be
accurate because you know we can't they
don't have the expertise to deal with
false positives it's got to provide them
feedback through the tools that are
already using we can't have them go to
some separate dashboard and it can't
slow them down so that's in development
if we could give developers instant
feedback that say hey you committed
sequel injection on right here and
here's what you need to do to fix it and
they can just fix it and check it and
clean then that's a process that I think
we can that can work I'll show you how
just a second that's that's part two so
the next thing is in the integration
environment or QA environment this is
where I think you want to be a little
bit more formal right in development you
don't want to track all those
vulnerabilities and put in extra work
unless you fix them and get them out of
the way just like any other stick you
know any other software problem but an
integration I think you don't want to
slow down builds you do want to
integrate with normal testing tools and
you should be a little bit more formal
like you might want to break the build
you might want to create JIRA tickets at
this point for issues and track them to
closure so that you can deliver assured
software into production so I I don't
think it's like shift
is kind of the wrong language for me
it's it's a useful analogy but it's not
just about shifting left it's about you
know starting left but you also have to
do more security in QA and we'll
actually talk about in production I mean
apps like doesn't stop when you deliver
the code right like there's a whole
attack world out there and I think
organizations are really lacking in this
I think most organizations don't know
who's attacking them or what attack
vectors they're using I think they don't
know much about you know how how people
are approaching the application I think
they want protection in production and
that's not just for known
vulnerabilities but for new stuff that
comes out you want to be able to deploy
a protection really fast like someone
today some researcher could release some
new zero day in struts or spring and
guess what
half the applications out there now are
going to be vulnerable to some new crazy
attack and most organizations aren't
going to be able to respond to that any
faster than Equifax did they're gonna
have to pull their apps out of
production they're gonna have to get the
new library add it to the application
rewrite the code to match the new
library because they don't patch open
source you issue a new open source
library and then they're gonna have to
do their testing and QA and security and
then push it into production that takes
a long time if you've got 50 apps
written with spring that is a massive
distraction and so we need something to
deal with that in the operational side
of things so if we can do with it if we
could do this I think we'd be in pretty
good shape so now I'm gonna try and tell
you how I see that happening we got to
start with instrumentation so there's a
shift going on in the security world to
not just an application security but
kind of everywhere to move from scanning
and firewalls to instrumentation so
skinny and follows kind of works at the
perimeter right you're looking at
network traffic or HTTP traffic to try
to identify attacks and vulnerabilities
and you don't have a ton of information
about what's really going on a better
approach is to instrument
thing that you're actually trying to
protect so at the application layer we
can instrument the actual app and look
at how it runs at other layers there's
you know the container layer there's
products like aqua and twistlock at the
post layer there's you know things like
carbon black which are instrumenting
even if the the network layer there's
products from AWS and so on that VMware
that can can give you direct analysis of
the thing that you're trying to protect
and so to me the modern security stack
looks like this and it protects itself
you can take that stack and you can move
it you can put it in your data center
you can put it in the cloud you can put
it in an elastic environment the
protection goes with the thing that
you're trying to protect the idea of
having a perimeter around everything is
fundamentally flawed because always what
happens is wherever you put the
perimeter then all of a sudden you gotta
run a whole bunch of connections in and
out somebody wants to run a browser from
inside the perimeter and then you're
screwed one one employee gets knocked
over and now the attacker is inside your
intranet and you know the whole thing
crumbles so this to me is the way out of
that edit Moroso does some great talks
he's the former CEO of AT&T now he runs
a thing called tag cyber but he talks
about this process of offload sorry
explode offload reload and explode is
basically taking the stuff that's inside
the perimeter and blowing it up take
those workloads move them into the cloud
that's offload and then reload is adding
new modern security protections to that
stack so that your applications are
protected wherever they are and then it
doesn't matter
anybody here still talk about like
internal apps versus external apps okay
if there's no perimeter then that
distinction doesn't make any sense there
is no internal and no external right so
I really want you to think about every
app is just out there on the Internet
and how are you going to protect it
because the perimeter doesn't really
provide that distinction so I don't like
when people talk about internal
okay so at the application layer let's
talk about instrumentation based
approaches to security so I'm going to
talk about two technologies here I asked
a rasp who's heard of asks in rasp okay
so maybe half that's great so
fundamentally these technologies are
very different than traditional SAS dest
and woth technologies so I asked is inst
interactive applications to create
testing I actually think of it as
instrumented application security
testing so for me that's a bit more
descriptive and the whole idea of I
asked is to detect vulnerabilities it
does the same kinds of things that SAST
and DAST will do just very differently
and rasp is about preventing
vulnerabilities from being exploited so
this is does the kinds of things that a
wife would do but from inside the
running application so the way this
works is you'll add a Iestyn rasp agent
to your application and you know this
like for Java it could be a jar file for
Ruby it could be a gem it's it's a
application component and what it does
is it instruments the application with
sensors and then those sensors watch the
application run and they can provide
that telemetry to an engine that can
detect vulnerabilities very accurately
and detect attacks very accurately and
and prevent those attacks from working
so let me give an example of a sequel
injection attack so the attacker sends
in an attack maybe it's like you know
single tick or one equals one something
like that and that data it's not trying
to block it at the parameter because if
you try to block at the perimeter you're
always going to be inaccurate you don't
know maybe that was a blog post that had
you know single tick or 1 equals 1 in it
wasn't going into the database it's just
normal data so you know modern
applications take complex data JSON and
serialized objects and so on so you can
never really be sure what's in them so
try to pocket the perimeter isn't a
great idea but from inside the app you
can see hey that data flowed through
ended up in a sequel query if that data
from the attacker changes the meaning of
the query and I asked can analyze that
from raspbian analyze that from inside
the app then that's the definition of
sequel injection right an attacker
should never be able to change the
meaning of your queries
that's what sequel injection is and
that's what rasp can protect so instead
of trying to guess like is this an
attack and having this false alarm
problem
Rask can see exactly when there's an
attack and prevent it from explained so
then then the Rast can intervene and
prevent that query from going to the
database right so defense from inside
the application it's got a lot more
context a lot more information it can be
more accurate now I asked works
similarly and this is a little bit more
tricky to get your head around so now
what should imagine that there's just a
developer just writing their code and
they don't they don't know how to attack
the application because they're not
security experts they don't know about
single tick or one equals one
they just type in normal data like they
might type in the word Jeff
well I asked can track that data like
taint tracing and track that data
through to where it lands in a sequel
query and then the I asked can look back
across that data's history and say hey
was this data ever escaped or
parameterised in a way that would have
stopped sequel injection and if it
hasn't been protected then we know that
that's an exploitable path through the
application it's a way to get data to
into a query and there's no defenses on
that path so you can very accurately
identify vulnerabilities in applications
this way too and again we didn't have to
be experts in security here anybody can
do this any I want make sure everybody's
with me every everybody understanding I
asked and raspier so we've instrumented
this security directly into the
application so we're going to do now is
we're to look at how can we use those
technologies to create a full dev sec
ops pipeline so this is a pipeline for
Springpad clinic and it's pretty simple
it's you know the codes and github will
use norm
development tools like eclipse and slack
and so on in our development environment
we'll build it with Jenkins
we've got bug trackers and sonar cube
and stuff like that
we'll use some testing with selenium and
things like that and then we'll push
this into pivotal Cloud Foundry to run
and we're using you know typical sim we
use Splunk and so on in that environment
so this is our our pipeline and we want
to add security to this so what we're
gonna do is we're gonna add I asked in
the development environment this will
give us visibility into vulnerabilities
instantly as we're just writing our code
into our normal job then in the CIC the
environment we're gonna add both I asked
and rasp and I asked as easy to
understand we want to know if there's
any vulnerabilities that somehow snuck
out of development and made it into the
QA environment but we'll also run
raspier because we want to make sure
that we've fully tested our application
with all the defenses turned on and then
we deploy exactly what we tested ok so
this is a way to get great confidence
that you know security is in place and
working and then in production will one
run with Rassman places will have attack
detection and prevention in in
production and the good news is this is
really easy anyone can do this pretty
quickly so I'm going to demonstrate this
this is the demo portion so I've got
three screens here I've got a
development environment conveniently
labeled with the word development at the
top I got to see I see the environments
and I've got a production environment so
just so people don't get confused I
switch environments back and forth a
little bit so that's that's your
bird-watching guide so here I've got an
application the spring pet clinic app in
Eclipse and I want to get started so I'm
gonna add I asked to this environment so
the first step is to go download an eye
Astin rasp agent I'm gonna use the one
from my company contrast this is the
contrast Community Edition it's free and
full strength for anybody who wants to
try this
so that's but you could use other eye a
sand rasp agents here as well
and the first step is to add the agent
to the environment so I've downloaded
this contrast jar file and I've added it
to my project here and I just need to
configure it so that when we run this
application contrast runs along with it
so in this case this is a spring boot
application so we can add it in the palm
this way so that every time we launch
with spring boot we're gonna add this
Java agent flag to the way the
application runs now Java agent flag is
pretty standard this is exactly the way
that you add tools like New Relic and
AppDynamics to applications on the
performance side we're just doing
exactly that same thing for security
here so we add this agent and a couple
other configuration options here and
then I'm just gonna run this application
normally so as the application starts up
this I asked agent is in the background
it's instrumenting the code as it loads
so when it runs in memory it's now
instrumented for security and everything
happens automatically in the background
it'll just start testing itself like
once I do this this application is now
protected from this point forward and
you don't have to change anything about
the way you build test or deploy your
code here to do this so applications now
start it up so this is the first time
that I've brought this application
online so I'm just kind of starting
fresh here and you can see I actually
have a contrast plug-in in the IDE and
you can see there's no vulnerabilities
here yet so all I have to do is browse
around and just use this application
normally so I'll put last con here and
you can see you'll see slack alerts
start coming in for vulnerabilities as
we use this application so I'm just
going to put in some normal data here
and again this is a lot different than
you know how
to have a pen tester - to do this
because you don't need to know anything
about security ultimately that's really
the key is if your tool requires any
kind of security expertise then you
can't really give it to developers we
need tools for novice software
developers so that novice developers can
write and commit clean code otherwise it
just won't scale so look I'm just adding
a couple little little fields here - to
make sure we get some coverage data and
you know click on a couple links all you
have to do is just use this
functionality than normal way and is in
the background doing the testing so now
if i refresh this contrast has already
identified a bunch of interesting
vulnerabilities and that that's what I
asked can do because it's directly
measuring the running application much
more accurate than traditional tools
like SAST and DAST so here you can see
found a hibernate injection some
cross-site request forgery on three
pages stored cross-site scripting by the
restored cross-site scripting is really
tricky to find because you know for
traditional tools it's one thread that
puts the the untrusted data in the
database and another thread that pulls
it out and renders it so the tools can't
connect those things but because it's
we're running inside the app it's easy
for tools like I asked to see hard-coded
password parameter pollution and and
notice here this is a range of different
kinds of vulnerabilities - tools are
good at finding things that are obvious
in HTTP traffic right things like prayin
or pollution and failure DS autocomplete
and you know you didn't use X frame
options to stop clickjacking stuff like
that obvious - a - tool but very
difficult for a sass tool to find sass
tools on the other hand are good at
things like hard-coded passwords weak
encryption algorithm those are obvious
in the code so that's the place to look
for those and really none of those tools
are very good at data flow problems data
flow problems like all the injections
sequel injection cross-site scripting
XPath injection LDAP injection command
injection is serious object ever
everything like that and so we need a
different solution to try to do dataflow
analysis and all three of these things
are built inside the I asked technology
so we get all different views of the
application so here you know let's drill
down into one of these vulnerabilities
so when I open up this hibernate
injection we get the details and I'm
gonna zoom in maybe this will work
sometimes I can I can scroll in does
that scroll
okay so this tells a little story about
what the I asked engine was able to see
it says here's some of the HTTP requests
we saw some untrusted data come in in
this last name parameter and when I
typed in last con and that data was
accessed on you know this method and
this line of code and it ended up in
this hibernate query without going
through any kind of escaping or
parameterization if it had been escaped
or parameterize somehow the iast engine
would have seen it and it wouldn't have
reported this vulnerability so this is
really good proof that this is a real
exploitable vulnerability because we
saved you can actually see it you can
see the data flow through now I you know
add a stool would only show you the top
line up there a static tool would only
show you you know kind of the method of
the line of code which you have no idea
how to test it and the last line here is
no other tool can really show you that
full query with the actual data in it so
this is much richer kind of finding than
other tools provide and of course you
know the tools provide things like the
details on how to fix it the full HTTP
request so you have a test case that you
can use to verify that you fixed it
correctly and then this events tab I
think is interesting this shows the the
full path through the application for
this vulnerability this shows you know
where the data was read in and this get
parameter values method the full stack
trace for that and all the runtime State
at the end the last step is the you know
the actual create query call that went
to the data
and in between there's a bunch of string
operations here any of these you can
double click on and go right to the line
of code where the problem is so in this
case you can see this is where this can
concatenated query got built and where
the developer would make the fix
okay so again anybody can use this that
the goal here is that I asked is usable
by any novice developer and I'll tell
you story about my son he's in high
school he's building he's in a
programming class and so he built his
first Java EE application this for his
school's Writing Center and he came to
me and said hey it's ready I want to put
it on online I was like whoa let's just
check it out first
go you know grab a copy contrast and and
run it and see what happens he came back
like half an hour later he goes well
dude I had four cross-site scripting x'
and two sequel injections he talks like
that because easy team sure and I was
like all son that's okay it happens and
he's it's okay I fixed it like
that's exactly what we need is novice
developers you can find and fix their
own vulnerabilities check in clean code
that's the key to getting this right in
development okay so I think it's
important to get this data to the
developers through the tools they're
already using I think slack is a good
vehicle for this you can see here's some
of the vulnerabilities we just found in
slack with all the do here's the store
cross-site scripting information and so
that's that's a nice vehicle to alert a
team about a new vulnerability there's
also a way of doing this through you
know right through the the browser which
i think is kind of interesting this case
this is that page that was vulnerable
and you can get a browser plug-in here
to pull down and this will show you just
the vulnerabilities associated with this
page so I think that's really powerful
like this is the page where that
hibernate injection so this is a nice
way to communicate with development
teams is to show right in their UI that
they're using all the time where the
vulnerabilities are so this is this is
kind of powerful I'm not gonna spend a
lot of time on this but if you if you're
interested in
what tools are good at and what they're
not good at go check out the OS
benchmark project these guys built 3000
test cases a few years ago to test what
static and dynamic tools are good at and
it's not a hard test it's relatively
easy that half the test is false
positives half the test is true
positives and you just you know you can
clone the git repository run your tool
get the report feed it back into the
benchmark and it'll grade that report
for you and tell you what they got right
and what they got wrong this will tell
you what your tools are good at and what
they're not good at I do hear people
using you know tools for security like
you know find find bugs with security
bugs the benchmark will tell you exactly
what that tool is good at and what is
not good at and it's interesting you
know you look at things like insecure
cookies and weak random numbers awesome
fun bugs are super at that but when you
get to the harder things like you know
the data flow problems like command
injection and sequel injection and XPath
injection and things like that they're
they're way over it's it's barely better
than guessing and so you know you should
know if you're gonna trust these tools
with the security of your enterprise you
should know what they're good at and you
doesn't know there's no other way to do
this you can't use webgoat I wrote
webgoat by the way 1999 and if you've
used it you can't use webgoat to test a
security tool it's got a very narrow set
of vulnerabilities to test for so you
need to use something that tests a broad
range of vulnerabilities and like I said
this is a super easy test if the tools
aren't acing this test they're really it
just doesn't prove that your tools never
going to find a false positive or
anything but I asked tends to do very
very well against this okay so I'm going
to shift to the the CI CD environment
first what I'm going to do is I would
say like browsing the application to
find vulnerabilities that's convenient
for developers but you also want a
reliable way of checking to make sure
your app doesn't have vulnerabilities
you want to make sure you cover
everything so I asked runs every time
you use the application I'm going to run
a set of test cases here in the
background and it runs with country
actually the configurations in the palm
it this is under the Surefire plugin so
you just add the the contrast jar here
the same way I also add jacoco as a code
coverage agent because you should really
know about code coverage if you're doing
security testing if you're doing a pen
test or a dynamic scan you should
absolutely have code coverage hooked up
so you know really what you got and you
should i mean static tools don't tell
you what they cover and what they miss
but they miss a lot so it's actually
impossible to really know but this means
every time I check in code this these
tests will run and I've got let's see
I've got Jenkins here and so every time
I run and I'll start a build now every
time I run a build all my test cases run
and I asked is in the background testing
every single interaction with the
application that happens so it's like
getting security testing for free and so
I think security should be a little bit
more formal here in in this yes in the
environment you want a good test that
you checked everything so I think this
is a good place to automatically create
JIRA tickets like if you weed out say 80
or 90% of the vulnerabilities in dev
you're checking and cleaner code now
when you find something in QA you create
a ticket track it make make sure it gets
closed and they're good integrations
from I asked right into bug tracking
tools with all the details that the
developer would need so you know really
the goal here is developers should never
be looking at your security tools right
they should get security information
just like they get every other bug right
through the tools that they're already
using that's the least disruptive thing
that we can do and I'll show the code
coverage results here I think this is
really interesting that you know this
says for the most part I'm getting
pretty good code coverage but I've got
obviously one big class here that I'm
not getting code coverage in and I
should probably write a test case for
that you can even drill down here and
get the details of exactly what lines of
code are executed by your test cases and
so on so it you know this can help you
drive towards really good code coverage
and is doesn't mean
full test cases I ask just needs you
know basic execution of the web
functionality so you know a simple
crawler like it Arachne sorry Arachne
you can run without you know running the
vulnerability tests because you don't
need them but you can use that to crawl
the application to get really good
coverage over an application um okay so
I want to show you this in in the
contrast dashboard again this is the
free community ition of contrast and we
built this dashboard since the start of
this talk what this shows is for spring
pet clinic we've started this dashboard
and you can see we've found a bunch of
vulnerabilities and development we're
also looking at what's going on in QA
this is the kind of a sign of an
unhealthy project right because we
didn't shift left we're still finding a
ton of vulnerabilities in the QA
environment so this is a project where
we can go in and maybe do some training
maybe help folks understand how to use
the technology a little better and get
those vulnerabilities fixed in death
when they come up getting this kind of
visibility from other tools will be
really hard like I don't know anybody
who runs static in in dev and static in
QA and continuously compares the results
to see which one's doing better I think
that'd be really hard and I also wanted
to show here the the library analysis
this is really important you should know
exactly what codes are running across
your entire enterprise and that's one of
the things that I asked o students they
can just directly measure the libraries
that are being used by your applications
pull that all together and build a
global database of all the libraries
that you've got in this case you can see
you know I've got a bunch of libraries
here how many does it say hold on open
that up so I've got you know hundred
thirty-two libraries with 15 known
vulnerabilities across ten libraries and
if I want to just filter down and see
which the vulnerable libraries are I
could pull that up and then this is kind
of interesting
remember I said most libraries aren't
you
well if we look at these vulnerable ones
and you can see you know the the C V's
listed here
you know this Jackson has five different
CVS associated with it but we can also
see how much of those libraries are
actually used right so this shows you
the number of classes used out of those
libraries and you know I think four of
these are used but the other six they're
huge they have vulnerabilities where
they're completely unused by the spring
pet clinic application they're just
there because of compile time dependency
they're never invoked so these are
libraries that you probably don't want
to rush out and fix because this waste
of effort
may be you should update them eventually
but you know no rush okay so that's
automated testing in queue ACS see I see
the environment will switch gears and
jump over to production here now
remember this is rasp runtime
application self protection that's
protecting these applications and here's
the data that's you know this is data
coming into Splunk off these
applications and you can see some
attacks are blocked some are ineffective
and some are actually exploited here and
the reason for that exploit a bit is you
can run like a laughs you can run rasp
in a log only mode if you want and you
know you should have a dashboard that
shows you exactly how you're being
attacked and who's attacking you in and
so on so let's take a look at how rasp
actually works I'll go back to dev here
for a minute where I don't have rasp
engaged and we'll just you know we'll go
to this this API you can see it just
works normally but if I do a sequel
injection oops if I do a sequel
injection I can exploit this and pull
all the records out of the database
right well all I did was add rasp to
this application now this is in
production you can see I'm running in
pivotal Cloud Foundry here and now when
I try to exploit that same vulnerability
now rasp intervenes and prevents that
vulnerability from being exploited so
generally you can drop in Wrath safely
into an application and just keep using
it and won't do anything until
you actually try to attack the app this
applies to not only custom code
vulnerabilities so you know they lost
top ten kinds of vulnerabilities and a
bunch more but also to library
vulnerabilities so all the struts and
spring vulnerabilities from last year or
almost all expression language injection
kinds of problems rasp protects against
those those kinds of vulnerabilities and
makes them unexploited so I think this
is really important for every
application to have this kind of
protection because you're not going to
be able to respond to new
vulnerabilities that come out in a
timely manner everyone should know who's
attacking and how you're being attacked
and Rass can enable that really easily
and so you know look that the contrast
one here is free if you've got an
application you want to try it on and
see what attacks on your application
look like super easy to add it and let's
see so I thought what I do is I show the
the actual attack traffic you can look
at it in the sim where you can look at
it in the the the rasped dashboard in
this case I'll show both effective and
ineffective attacks and you can see here
you know the kind of range of attacks
this is you can see here there's you
know expression language injection CVE
attacks coming in sequel injection
attempts and then I'll look into this
one that we just did a minute ago and
rasp is a little different than what you
get from a laugh raft shows you the
attack in the URL here you can see it's
encoded and it flows through into the
sequel query basically a lot like what I
showed you for the vulnerability but no
other you know another attack detection
can really show you the actual query
that was targeted and of course you get
the details like the full stack trace
full line of code even the currently
logged in user because I asked this part
of the application it knows who's logged
in so instead of blocking an IP address
you can go and turn off that users
account or you know make them reset
their password or something because
they're attacking you so you can respond
a lot differently
okay so that's
Iestyn rasp and I think we went through
building this pipeline that it's not
difficult to build an effective deficit
cops pipeline using I asked and rasp you
don't have to change anything about the
way that your pipeline works you can
layer I ass and rasp on top of your
pipeline and and get these kind of
results so I think I did what I set out
to do I wanted to show you that we can
empower developers to fix their own
vulnerabilities and check in clean code
without irritating them we can assure
that build before it goes into
production and make sure we're
committing you know deploying code that
doesn't have vulnerabilities and we can
protect applications whether there are
legacy applications or new applications
we can protect them against being
exploited by both old vulnerabilities
and new vulnerabilities and we can do it
without you know without breaking
software development processes and
without complex diagrams and so on so
this to me is what apps that good scale
looks like we instrument our application
portfolio and we start getting real-time
telemetry we're measuring everything
that we're doing and this is you know
fundamentally instrumentation is
incredibly important everything that we
build in the world that's complicated
we instrument it like factories and cars
and nuclear power plants and so on
they're all super instrumented for
temperature and vibration and sound and
everything but we don't instrument
software software is arguably the most
complex thing that man has ever built
and we have no idea what's going on
inside
all we got is log files there's garbage
in log files we need to know what's
going on inside and so security
instrumentation I believe is the path
towards achieving continuous apps tech
at scale and I didn't want to just
mention that the community edition we're
trying to do something special here you
know there's 21 million developers in
the world and my estimate is that about
6% of them have access to any kind of
application security tools that's that's
a shame we're never gonna get in front
of the problem of app sack with that
situation so we're making the contrast
is full strength analysis and protection
for one application we're doing Java
right now but soon we'll be releasing
the other languages that we support net
nodejs Ruby and Python and so we can
bring great protection to massive
amounts of applications across the world
and make the situation much better so
please check it out
if you have any questions about it don't
hesitate to reach out to me we do have a
booth there if you want to see it we can
show it to you and with that I'll I'll
stop I do want you to go fast and be
secure and I'd be happy to take your
questions for the next few minutes thank
you question
[Applause]
for sure
they are the reason that I started this
company Mustang yes no false positives
are a big problem and if you have grass
automatically blocking what it perceives
as security incidents you run the risk
of blocking your legitimate innocent
customers if you have a bad false
positive rate so how do you account for
that when you're dealing with rats
yeah I mean generally instrumentation is
far more accurate than you know just
looking at HTTP requests so with
accuracy comes better protection it's
really just that simple you know we we
have a hard roll we call it our our
Hippocratic oath that will never break a
nap and so we we work really hard to
make sure that you know the only things
that we block are legit attacks Thanks
yeah I mean obviously there's a lot more
detail there and I can be happy to go
into that with you offline yes so you
might envision that the DevOps the
engineering teams might raise a question
about the performance impacts oh yeah a
pest harassment so I wanted to get your
feedback on what one might expect in
terms of performance feedbacks
interoperability other conflicts that
one might expect from integrating those
technologies in be they other
technologies yeah sure so two things
there
first of all rasp is really fast
contrast adds about 50 microseconds to a
round-trip HTTP request
that's for normal traffic for heavy
attacks that goes up to about 250
microseconds or a quarter of a
millisecond so way faster than a laugh I
suspect it's faster than most
organizations would be able to add input
validation to their code because most
developers will do something relatively
naive like use reg X's or something rasp
is woven right into the code so it's
executing in this the same way that your
own developers validation will work but
it's highly optimized for speed and
performance so I I think you know
performance for most applications it's
not an issue you mentioned conflict with
other things in the environment in in
the first few years we had conflicts
with some of the APM agents because
they've run in the same way but that's
essentially gone now we run right
alongside dynaTrace and out dynamics and
New Relic and a bunch of other stuff in
production and frankly I'm super glad
that those products are out there
because they blazed the way for this
operations teams are open to adding this
kind of agent to applications because
they're used to it yeah so like I said
the the communication is just Java for
now but we're going to add the languages
that we other languages that we already
support and have supported for years we
just were doing one at a time because we
wanted to kind of you know take one step
at a time but that's net nodejs Ruby and
Python yeah and there's other languages
coming even languages like go like
native compiled languages yeah yeah he
plans for nodejs Express you know
something like on the myrn stack react
anything javis yeah yes so no jess is
supported like well I mean that inner
commercial product it's not in the
community edition yet but will be there
and actually it's interesting JavaScript
is insanely hard to analyze statically
because it's a weekly type layer it's
got a million issues but so most statics
holes really are just kind of grep for
you know security problems but because
instrumentation happens at runtime
everything's fully resolved and so you
know we don't have the same kinds of
problems
analyzing javascript so we've got really
the the only technology that works well
on server-side JavaScript yeah does
support legacy applications and also how
grasp learn about 0.0 day exploits as
well as emerging these great questions
no really really great so yeah you can
drop in rascal on a legacy application I
you know it's it's dynamic binary
instrumentation so you don't even have
to have the source code right you can
just add it to a server you can even add
it to commercial products and it just
goes to work right away second part your
questions about you know how to updates
happen for for new things most zero days
are instances of some vulnerability that
a rasp already protects against right so
like if a new spring expression language
vulnerability comes out it's already
been protected against by Rask because
rasp makes expression language injection
and impossible to exploit I could dig
into the details of that but it's you
know we're sandboxing the actual
evaluation of the expression but if
there is something genuinely novel like
some new kind of injection a wasp
injection or something then you want an
update to go out so everything in our
environment everything automatically
updates so new rules go out you can it
can push out across your entire
application portfolio in a matter of
minutes and then you're protected so you
know I think that's important to look
for it you know how does it update over
time yeah any other questions all right
thank you very much everybody I
appreciate the time Thanks
you