[Music]
good afternoon everybody we enjoying
Laska I I'm sorry I hate to this it's so
cliche are we enjoying last con that was
actually lower I think that miss have a
seat
so I originally I had talked set up to
do maybe saw it maybe you're confused
about what we're doing here because I
originally and the schedule there was a
talk I was doing about about password
cracking and I looked at the talk and
looked at the slides and thought well I
can either make that really general not
be useful or make it really specific and
not get past my legal department that
work so instead that even were useful to
have a panel discussion about red
teaming and pin testing so I'm just
gonna start this off it's gonna be very
laid back and if you have questions or
comments raise your hand well you know
addressing during the thing so I'm just
gonna go around here and have people
induce themselves and what I want to
know is what your name is what you do
and how long you've been doing what we
call pen testing or hacking or what you
want to call I'll start with you Dustin
dykes I'm the founder of the Dallas
hackers Association I'm better known
there by the handle wire fall and I've
been getting paid to do penetration
testing since about 1996
hey I'm J Gore it's a handle but that's
how everyone knows me I helped run
Austin 2600 Longhorn lock-picking
work for the University of Texas at
Austin where I'm staff there do regular
pen testing stuff and also we teach a
class there on teaching students how to
have fantastic
hello my name is Matt Pardo I run
besides Austin and
I have been hacking since probably 1990
that DARPA that kind of thing so back in
the early days and have continued for
many many years
hi I'm Cole Otto bender and I'm a
security associate at rapid7 I've only
been being paid to pen test
for the past six months hi my name is
Allison grey my work at children motors
I would say officially I've been working
on application security a little bit
over a year and also delve in some app
testing before that so I I'm David
Hughes I work at General Motors as a Red
Team Lead I've been doing pen testing
and stuff for about about 2005 doing
security before that and mostly IT work
before that a lot of sassette men and
server admin stuff so one reason I would
just say some things about some these
people you actually just met you for the
first time today
and I heard some things about you that
really cool so no J Gordon for awhile
he's of course a lockpick guy and I
remember one time I was I was doing a
talk and I asked I was talking about
burnout and I yell I was asking people
you know what are some things you can do
that aren't from a scream not related to
to what you do that you could use it as
a hobby so you want burnout healed out
lock-picking
yes so which is kind of related actually
but yeah exactly exactly I work with
Matt a lot different projects known him
for quite a while I just met carlota for
the first time and and Alison down here
I work with a GM and the reason one
reason I asked her is because she is so
eager and and and wanting to learn and
contribute that I just feel like you
know this to be kind of like a good
reward for that or or punishment in her
mind
yes so so I wanna start with an
icebreaker question though just to kind
of get things kind of loosened up a
little bit describe for me your favorite
hacker movie or television show and if
you'll have an answer you don't to say
anything but go ahead jiggle by the ways
a movie bluff so maybe he'd have some
yeah good yeah I watch way too many
movies
I basically live at Alamo Drafthouse
I love all hacker movies but I think I
have to go with wargames I would say my
favorite is sneakers since it includes
hacking telephony which you can't do as
much anymore
although digitally you can do some stuff
but it also includes some cryptology
which is pretty cool I was actually
gonna pick Snickers as well um so for me
it's more of a TV show I love mr. robot
probably because one it's mostly
realistic but it's also really gritty
and crazy so yeah I have to say that I
agree with all of you guys as far as the
movies I love all those movies I like
the movie hackers actually that's a fun
movie it's a look it's a variable love
movie those of you who in here on hacker
if you secretly love it
you do you really do deep inside you'll
love the show and you know what I have
to give a little bit a credit toward
swordfish even though it has the most
painful hacking scene of all times how
many I have seen that the Hugh Jackman
hacking scene in swordfish Google that
find it on YouTube and watch it and
you'll not want to watch it ever again
but it's really painful actually think
cool cool and I did a mr. robot you know
I think maybe except for the scene where
she's dropping USB drives in the parking
lot of the police station and handfuls
and piles that doesn't look suspicious
and she downloaded the script from Rapid
9 no my my favorite was because it got
me into it was wargames but one of my
favorite reviews of a hacking or
computer security show was CSI cyber
there was a hacking collective that was
live-tweeting it because though their
their tagline what so you don't have to
watch it and one of the comments was
this makes swordfish look like a
documentary I really wanted to love CSI
cyber I tried so hard to love that show
and I just could not it was just painful
after I saw that actually I was watching
the opening secrets of that you know
they talk about the dark web and this is
my wife saw that and she said can you
get at the dark web but I said yeah sure
would you show me I go ok so I took her
to my computer and we guy used to you
know route I use a proxy and I got the
tour and I showed her that some sites
because that's it that's the dark web II
yeah she walked away it was like was it
nearly as exciting she thought it was so
one more a nice beggar question not I'll
be able to answer this you'll have these
war stories but what's your favorite
pentesting hacking a war story of your
own personal experiences you have could
be an embarrassing one could be a a
victory I think Jake works ready to go
yeah so working on campus we see a lot
of exotic stuff we call ourselves a city
within the city and so we've got like
power plants water chilling stations
nuclear facilities we've got one of the
world's largest laser beams the geology
department got a giant 8-foot globe that
would be it was a dual projector setup I
would shoot projections on both sides
and it would make a live map of the
globe and it had different settings
where you could see like live weather
feeds and stuff we started poking at it
when we saw it and we ended up finding
an exposed USB port where we could plug
in just a regular USB keyboard use some
hotkeys to escape that the running
program get back to the Windows desktop
and do whatever we wanted with it as it
turned out it was running as
administrator and so we had full control
over it in the end to leave our calling
card we just projected our logo the
all-seeing eye onto the world and we
said that hacked the planet
yeah a number probably my favorite
though was I was doing a social
engineering engagement for a company up
in the northwest now that was the
Midwest and they had a warehouse with
forklift drivers they had a standard
outfit and to the local Goodwill of
course got something that matched walk
in and they're having this employee
appreciation like luncheon with cake and
everything and so I just sit there and
I'm eating cake and having a good time
well it turns out they also had their
newsletter person there was taking
pictures and the next month my sponsor
sends me a picture on their wall is me
at the employee appreciation lunch I'll
give a epic fail so I was working now
this was years ago on H it was an
assessment of a server who's for a free
net on the East Coast and they had a set
UID
bash script and so I modified it and
ended up locking out 5,000 users from
this system for about three days so not
all war stories are good but you learn
incredible lessons from right after that
I luckily have never brought down a
system sense because I was so basically
distraught because I was getting it from
everywhere so sometimes you're big
sometimes your biggest mistakes are also
your best lessons
Carlo or Alison have been doing a long
table war story okay so make sure you
have to come back with at least two he's
you have to do two to catch up all right
I got one that really I thought was a
victory but turn out to be a kind of a
kind of a defeat we were doing a
physical contesting for this company and
they had up at an office they converted
to a server room it was the office in a
you know and their offices were like on
the second floor of a building they
share with other tenants and in seven
o'clock in the morning the doors open on
the sides with no badges so I'm able to
walk up to the door of the server room
and they don't know if I could get into
it and I could push the tiles up and
take pictures over I could do that
wasn't about to climb over kill myself
from brick tiles proved that it was
possible to do but they have it on their
Lord at the time their lock on the door
was a simplex lock maybe Jaguar knows
about those the five buttons that are
mechanical and you can only push one
button the Neen combination so it really
limited the combinations are possible
I can try how many the work total and
you can push two at the same time there
were there was a hundreds it was like
two 300 different combinations possible
I took up and wrote them down
I didn't even script I was like old
school I was a terrible I mentioned I
was a terrible pen tester at the time
horrible pen tester and this is last
year though some a little bit I've get
that no it's like this like 2005 so I
what I did was I took a dry erase marker
that was really clever and a pittle dot
h button and then I came back mixed it
and look for the ones were wiped off and
for the buttons right cos there's like
four buttons and the number of
combinations were like in the inlet like
under 30 so no one's up there at 7
o'clock in the morning put my chair up
the door I'm starting go go through
combinations but after about the fourth
one I'm in and I'm just so proud of
myself
I'm just really I take a picture myself
in the syrup mix a server rack you know
posing like I had a big fish you know in
opposing and so I get turn there port in
there like oh thank you that's really
kind of a good good you did a good job
it's next year I come back and they'd
put a biometric lock on the door which
is pretty cool I'm leaning against a
door looking at the biometric lock and
the door pushes open a little bit and I
look at the latch and I see there's a
there's a gap there I think a credit
card pop I open the door I thought great
I got in again in that way blaming this
vulnerability was there last year
it's been sitting there a year like that
and that's the way it beef would get in
they wouldn't do the lock buttons I was
going for the sexy thing and the most
glaring vulnerability was right there I
was actually was totally bad about that
but it's a lesson I take the law by type
of people about about looking over
looking the simple things the easy
things just to go for something sexy you
know it's like a guy breaking it up into
a museum using a grappling hook but the
doors open you know why trained you know
that's a lesson you can learn if you
watch sneakers you're right you're right
at the door with kicking the door open
yeah yeah yeah if you've seen sneakers
add that to your list of films to see
let's cool off for you everyone dies so
let's see how did you get involved with
InfoSec and you do some of you remember
Bob I think from a mentality perspective
you always are at least in the red
teaming always been trying to figure out
how to get into things how to make
things do what I want them to do how I
was professionally recognized was
military then law enforcement that gave
credibility were credibility we have not
existed before but I think maybe more
why I'm I've been able to stay in
InfoSec is because I'm childish the only
reason I get in is because security is
basically saying you can't go there and
you don't tell me what I can do so if
there's a hallway of open doors and one
of them is closed and locked that's the
one I want in I didn't want to until you
closed it in locked but now I want it
and I'm not gonna do anything so that's
why I've been able to stay in security
is because there's always locked doors
yeah so as wire falls I'd probably
always had that mindset as a kid you
want to be an astronaut or a jet fighter
pilot I wanted to be a hacker
that's sounded cool me and I ended up
going the sysadmin route so a lotta
helpdesk and then learning how to
administer machines and then finally I
noticed there was an opening in the
Security office at UT and I forgot to
mention earlier I've been in the
security specific role for about eight
years now I've been at the University
for 10
yeah I just sysadmin who finally got a
shot at a security office so I got
involved I was doing a medical research
at University in North Carolina and my
coworker was on a computer and I asked
her what she was doing and she said I'm
reading Usenet groups I'm like what the
hell is that
and so I she introduced me to it I
started reading Usenet found tons of
info on there found some groups related
to hacking found frak magazine found
bulletin boards which probably very few
of you know what that is and the glory
of a modem connection but that's where I
got started so my backgrounds a little
bit different I have a degree in Emily
science and I got married and I had kids
and I became a stay-at-home mom
my husband was a network engineer for a
very long time and assists admin and I
wanted to understand what he was doing
for his job so I started researching
networking I started learning more about
computers and as I went into it I
started with a lot of the exploitation
and and even I'd have had friends have
their accounts broken into I became more
interested in the cybersecurity and I
managed to I got my nap plus and I got
accepted into the sans women's cyber
Academy and that gave me the opportunity
to gain those certifications that helped
me get my job I'm kind of like her I
started off it was an unconventional
route for me to get to info security
originally I just went to college for
something that was basically exposed to
a South plate athletics all my life and
so I was like oh I'll get my undergrad
in exercise science but then on my
senior year I realized this is not
something I want to do and I remember
being exposed to a little bit of
computer engineering side my freshman
year and I decided to pursue that but
while I was actually going from ICS
degree I took security classes as well
and that's what kind of held my interest
there and so thankfully before I
graduated I was offered an opportunity
to work for a company like you
QA stuff but I expressed to the manager
like hey I wouldn't do security stuff as
well so he also kind of exposed me to
security tasks like dynamic static code
assessments and so now I finally own a
security team and Here I am now well
great that's really good so I guess I
could tell my summers kind of boring
actually I was doing IT work I was in
the computer since I was young kid I
think my first computers at Texas
Instruments tn9 for a we had one of
those Wow they there were classics
anyway so uh yeah I was playing around
with like that the peek and poke
commands and making the screen ooh
strange things even from a very young
age and and so we're not doing that t
work when an opportunity for security
work came along I got interested in that
got involved with our company's side
penetration testing exercises and at the
time there was very little training
available there was actually no
knowledge and at the time and this is
maybe can be our next talking point the
industry was kind of mean I mean there
weren't a lot people at that time 2005
for really sharing information with
other people
ok oh yeah I think they're all working
cool thanks Josh and it was my
information on the internet either about
about security
I mean you could look up YouTube you can
find anything about anything on YouTube
I really upset videos topic that's
earlier the hips tech videos so I unless
YouTube and you Truffaut yeah security
proof of concepts on there there's your
war story what do you tell Alan yeah
real quick yeah so I got kicked off of
the YouTube platform for 48 hour period
until the InfoSec community raised hell
and got me back on two of my videos so
my youtube channel is predominantly me
picking my own locks demonstrating them
on a camera and me showing off the
security research that I do so building
proof of concept tools in this case two
of my videos got flagged the particular
flag I think the wording was privacy
complaint but I think the objection
pretty clearly was that I was showing
off
how to do this type of attack and the
attack in this case was showing off that
those those badge readers that are
installed on your doors have all sorts
of fancy encryption these days from the
card to the reader over-the-air but then
the wire that travels through the wall
behind it almost always goes over this
old standard called weekend which is
completely plain text you just tap into
two wires there and you just read the
bits off of it as it's going back to
whatever makes a decision now you have
the full credentials unencrypted of the
card so I demonstrated how to build a
little Arduino based device so you
unscrew a single screw underneath the
reader pull it forward strip a couple
wires stuff this is a larger we know
back in there and tap it onto the two
wires and then put it back and it will
sit there and silently grab all the
credentials as they go across that wire
and then you come back later and it
shoots them off over in my case I did a
little zig B wireless connection and
just say give me all the credit you got
and now I have legitimate cards so these
I showed two videos of demonstrating my
little Arduino device they both got
flagged it went I got a notice from
YouTube saying we're gonna do a review
because you have multiple privacy
complaints against your account we're
gonna determine whether or not we'll
remove that those videos I got a notice
later that day around 3 a.m. actually
saying due to multiple violations or an
extreme violation we have decided to
terminate your account so they didn't
even want to remove just the individual
videos they completely shut off my
account and said you're not allowed to
create a new account either you're
you're banned from the from the YouTube
service I I went through the legitimate
you call it the resolution process to
say I think this is a mistake and I put
a pretty lengthy description of the full
number of characters they allowed me to
type for the description of why I
thought this might be a mistake they
might have misunderstood why well this
was is a legitimate security research
it's a public exploit and people need to
know about it at this point because it's
a risk and it went to them less than 24
hours later I got a response saying
denied no further information I I asked
can you give me the specifics as to why
you why you banned me which videos and
specific went into this decision and all
I got back was denied so I had exhausted
all my options there I was just kicked
off the platform and I didn't know why
and so I took to Twitter and I got a lot
of friends on Twitter and a lot of
people agreed with me that that didn't
make sense and we and we got we got the
attention of the YouTube team and they
went and riri reviewed my case and said
oh I'm sorry we made a mistake we've
gone ahead and flipped your account back
on sorry about that
[Applause]
yeah and III it's like there aren't
other videos on YouTube of showing how
how to exploit and how that yeah it's
ridiculous
so here's another question for you and
by the way if your questions or comments
feel free to raise your hand this is a
kind of freeform thing I just got some
talking points working a try to cover
but I have no I have no agenda here so
if we don't get to them all that's fine
I'd rather have a useful discussion than
to just get through all my bullet points
here here's a question for you we're all
we all do pentesting work there's a lot
of services that offer automation of a
lot of these types of activities can
pentesting be fully automated can be we
can we be replaced by scripts and by
appliances and I'll just anybody want to
want to talk about that penetration
testing will be fully automated when
code security is fully automated funny
enough that's what I spend a lot of my
day job doing now is automating my own
job away so we used to do this thing we
called hacker happy hour where as a team
we would get together maybe go over to a
bar and just go open up Google and poke
at all the domains we have a Dominion
over and as a public university who also
does a lot of outreach for the entire
state we have a lot of domains so it's
just an attractively huge web presence
but we we want to find that low-hanging
fruit the scariest stuff that's already
exposed to Google and so we would think
of clever keywords to search Google
Dorking in general if you're familiar
with that for example let's say file
type PHP in URL ID so that's a probably
a numeric ID field on a PHP page pretty
good chance they did it wrong and that's
vulnerable to sequel injection so we do
that kind of thing by hand poking at him
one at a time and I started to think can
i automate this process make it a little
bit easier to maybe pop open a bunch of
tabs at once so that I can go click on
them and look at them one at a time yeah
so I started writing a Python script to
do that for me I'm like at this point
why even it opened up in a graphical
browser why not just punt it to a
command line scanner and let it tell me
whether or not it's vulnerable okay I
got that coded up so I could kick it off
and I would run once
at a time I was like okay can I further
automate this maybe make a cluster of
them and do a bunch of scans at once
turns out you can so I wrote I ended up
writing a little framework that we
called dork bot where I can pull from
multiple sources I say Google or Bing or
whatever send it to any number of
command line security scanners and I
just run it on a docker cluster now and
it's churning through thousands of pages
an hour and just giving us back
vulnerabilities of what it finds
everywhere on Google anybody else have
any comments or opinions about whether
we can be automated away yeah I don't I
don't see it happening any time soon
just because we have people involved in
all the processes so yeah if we have AI
that's creating the code and the
applications and everything's encrypted
and there are no passwords everything's
biometric maybe then but it's not I
can't see it happening
in our lifetimes or maybe the next and
whenever innovation stops then then
maybe because they just keep
reintroducing the same vulnerabilities
every time we improved back in the old
days with phone phreaking they learned
with ss7 you know in-band signaling is
bad so then we create data networks and
we put the management in band Wireless
same thing
IOT now as every time they come up with
a new revision we have to make the same
mistakes over and over so so phone
phreaking for those of you some of you
had our phones work we seized these
phones that had buttons on them that
that yeah the long distance was
expensive and so there are ways of
replaying sounds into the phone to skip
around the long distance charges and I
never do that myself but it was
something we you know it was done so I
should have a glossary of old terms like
in art talk I guess okay so this is the
more I'm gonna change gears a little
more useful question again any questions
here so far anybody wanna okay what do
you do personally and this may be
practical for some of you because all of
us and the reason why I chose this cross
sections because they're people here
that are new to pen testing you were and
some of us who've been around for a
while and I what I understand is what do
we do as pen testers as hackers or
ethical hackers I don't even know what
you know the terms we use anymore are
what do we do that improve ourselves to
Train what are we doing to training and
if you have your own like methods or
sources for training that you go to if
you could share with us that'd be great
well as gone I would say primarily
honestly is just keeping up with Twitter
which I was a very late comer my handle
was not available because I was a late
comer because I thought there's no way
you're gonna get content anything useful
in whatever 120 characters but it
doesn't it but it points to useful
information and almost all of the
security peeps are on there now so I
agree Twitter is one way to stay
up-to-date with all the happenings and
for me since I'm a little bit of a new
comer just like at first all the
information was overwhelming I was like
what do I need to focus on because I
mean kind of like you need to know
everything but the reality is that the
anything you don't know everything so
for me individual time so maybe setting
aside like maybe one or two hours a day
and working through a book on a certain
subject and also because I'm trying to
get you know better at pen testing
pulling up vulnerable VMs on bullying
hub authors hack the box as well so just
dedicating time to that
I'm a huge fan of local meetups
so Austin 2600 little self-serving
because I try to run that one but we we
try to place ETFs at the meetings if
there are online ones going on so we'll
get together as a group and will compete
in they CD f's and try all the
challenges I love Austin hackers aha
going there forces me to come up with
new and interesting things just to show
off to that group he's like kidding with
what we're forcing either Aria its it is
compulsory in order to attend the
meetings you have to go give turbo talks
and so a lot of the coolest things I've
done have been specifically so I could
go up on stage there and show it off at
aha
Longhorn lock-picking Club I don't pick
locks I don't I don't practice picking
locks outside of the meetings that is my
excuse to keep good at it is to show up
every other Saturday at Spyder house and
practice picking locks with people so I
love meetup groups so I do a lot of
different things so I CTF I run a CTF
team we're probably one of the biggest
in the world at this point it's called
open to all and it is open to all it's
actually more of a CTF community than a
team I mean we compete in every single
CTF there is that we can get to
including local ones because we have
people from all over the world in the
group and we have a slack channel and
probably have about 500 people on there
and we it's all education focus I'm very
education focused myself that's why I am
involved with a wasp and I help
coordinate the study groups which we
meet weekly in fact we're starting a new
book called PowerShell in a month of
lunches so any of you who are interested
in PowerShell please come join us I also
believe in going to conferences and I
learned a lot of these not only because
of the great networking but because some
of the great talks for example at Derby
con I just learned more about the shadow
brokers dump and something called kill
sue which is this awesome framework all
about data exfiltration and maintaining
persistence
I mean it's some really cool cutting
edge
or at least it was cutting-edge a couple
years ago but it's very it's new to me
and that's the thing about this field is
there's so much to it there's so much to
learn when I start it there was very
little there was frack that was it I
mean a couple other things that you
could find on bulletin boards and stuff
but now there's a plethora of sources
for learning this stuff and what I think
you realize over time as you have this
huge possibility of a foundation in
hacking and pen testing and red teaming
and there's these little bricks that you
can build as you go along and if you
just focus on those and sort of find
something that works for you whether
it's a meet-up or a book or a webinar or
a conference or training which and
trainings are great too unless you
fidget a lot like I do although I do go
to uhm I figure I get 50 percent out of
them but there's a lot of options and I
I I like to go into all of them
personally
things like hack the box and damn from
web apps and such I love hands-on
learning and I think part of it is gonna
be what type of learner are you do you
learn better by listening people talk
watching videos doing hands-on things
and then as a result you know there are
so many resources out there for you to
be able to then use that to learn the
area that you're interested in in the
same way with with the hands-on if I go
to training and there's not much a lab I
don't retain a lot now that training I
might go back to the slides later and go
back and get some things out of it but
just sitting there listening to somebody
else lecture to me regardless else mark
that the person is I need to get my
hands dirty get in there and do it how
many people are here local off from
Austin raise your hand from Austin none
of you have an excuse for a need for
opportunities and maybe you don't know
about them because we have some amazing
opportunities in Austin for training we
have we have OWASP
we have the OU a study group we already
mentioned that we casually meet we meet
on Wednesday nights to do some do some
you know some CTF stuff and it was a lot
of fun so if you're in Austin you want
to know you know what's out there
come talk with one of us and find out
because there's a ton of things this is
probably the most active cities in the
United States with regards to security
security groups conferences we have last
con we have InfoSec Southwest we have
and metal peer is it heads-up besides
coming up this next year there's a lot
of opportunities here in Austin to get
involved and if you're not and you know
about it you're you don't have an excuse
but if you don't know about it come talk
to us for cons I will give you that you
beat Dallas for happenings I'll
challenge you alright great our first
fight
great yeah anybody else have anything
about training talk about I like I like
I like hack the box that's a really good
resource and there's a lot things
available out there there's there's pen
testers Academy there's some things for
cost and some things were free related
to this next question and this might
cause some hopefully some lively
discussion certifications how many
people are at least pursuing
certifications out here raise your hand
everyone always is it seems like right
we're always looking at the next one
right our man is you're always saying
well what's your plan for next year for
a certification you know and so how
important are they what's of value is
their valued certifications or hopefully
get some different opinions here from
this panel but maybe not I would say
it's mostly where you are in your career
or where if you're trying to pivot or
make a change I got my sea-ice CISSP and
I think it was 2000 and I'm here for
CPEs know the cause I'll never take that
test again Oh awesome you get a C PE you
get a CP because after that though like
I absolutely love the training from
offensive security they're osep osce
took those but to get the certification
you have to write a report that's what I
do for a living
so take I'll take all these trainings
but I no longer go after the
certifications cuz I really don't need
to where I am I do think that as you
said it depends on where you are in your
career for me do being a career changer
having certifications is extremely
helpful when I don't have the years
experience to show a prospective
employer
I agree with both of them I think the
other thing that a certification is good
for is that it can motivate you to study
a topic and get some more depth in an
area so like CISSP it's a certification
that a lot of people talk about not
being very technical and after having
gone through that process it isn't super
technical because the the of information
you cover is huge but it is definitely
worthwhile because the breadth is so
huge it introduces you to a lot of stuff
but from a technical perspective it
doesn't give you much to go on whereas
you know oh SCP or osce those those are
fantastic to really get down into the
nitty-gritty and learn how to really do
something so it and like they said it's
great for careers and even some of the
certs that a lot of people make fun of
are good for opening doors but I could
you name one of those and I don't want
to say but I do think that it's a great
way to motivate yourself so if you set a
goal and especially if you because most
of them aren't cheap
I mean OSC peace cheap it's fantastic
and it's inexpensive but a lot of these
certs are not cheap so if you've set a
goal you set a date you buy the test
you're gonna study for it unless you
like burning money which we can get the
bar on the osc ps1 say that I think
offense of security is organization
probably with all the extensions I
bought on labs because I'm a terrible
test taker horrible I freaked out on
tests but all that all the extensions I
bought there's probably some brick at
the office of security offices with my
name engraved on it as a contributor
because I don't go I would think about
much money I spent it had to be at least
a couple thousand bucks in extensions
alone on that exam so
so so Allison studying for osep alright
a skier you thought you find it
rewarding are you are you learning a lot
from it and as an example of I will say
I do find it rewarding because kind of
like what I mentioned before the
lymphocyte field is so so like massive
and it's really hard for me at least to
be focused on one thing so it's nice to
have kind of a roadmap of like how I
need to go forward and learn certain
things so I think it's helpful that way
and also it's challenging so I'm always
trying harder g-iii
I like I like structure too I mean if I
want to sell you a subject the one the
best of ad litem ass point is to it is
to dedicate yourself to actually taking
the exam it's like if you learn a topic
another thing you can do is commit to
teaching it that is you know a
conference or something or you know I'm
gonna do a conference on this in six
months and I don't know about it yet so
you kind of learn or you don't look bad
at you know horrible I've had I've had
live experiences like that so no cool so
what about I mentioned certificate
certifications how about I just come in
general though if if you're interviewing
somebody for a job and I love your boss
student like that how much weight would
you put in there elicit certifications
over let's say that for example they're
they're people skills that's kind of
hard question I guess but but is there
any point where or technical skills
completely basically would cause you to
just ignore the soft skills issues
completely I really only have two
questions that I start out with always
the first one is tell me about your home
lab and if they're excited about it if
they're passionate about this industry
they will have a home lab and they will
be very happy to tell you about it it
could just be their laptop it doesn't
have to be anything like my 42 ureC
server because I have a very very
wonderful wife but
I didn't yeah we got two air
conditioners they run full-time and the
second is tell me about your
participation in that local security
community because that's what drives
their passion if you're here the the
advice I give people trying to break
into the industry is is one yeah you got
to tinker around get yourself a home lab
and the second is you're not gonna get
your job off of the job board you're
gonna get it here you're gonna get it at
aha well I don't know about AHA but
you're gonna get a 2600 or and and DHA
was a spinoff of Ojai actually was
exposed to it many years here when I ago
when I was working for a state agency
and I absolutely loved the format you
know it's not just a talking head for an
hour and a half it's just getting up
those fire talks but even though we call
ourselves a kinder gentler uh-huh and
mophead will will say that oh that's
impossible but you know those are the
two things that are important I don't I
don't care about certifications you know
that may get you through HR so that you
actually see me so I'm not saying it's
not important but that's not gonna be
part of my questions anyone else so
another question that hopefully will
spur some conversation here um this this
term goes back many many years and I
want to ask ourselves a question are we
script kiddies honestly I mean thinking
about that the term in classical
definition and and and which means
basically a script Katie was somebody
who just simply grabs scripts and
somewhere else ran them against things
and attempted to to exploit something
and really care how it works they were
just trying to get results back how much
of how much of a script they are we
today as pen testers and is that a bad
thing
oh I would say we're framework kitties
now we have frameworks instead of just
the scripts but I was a Perl script
Kitty and honestly at first yes you have
an objective you're just trying to get
something to do what you want I don't
care how it works but back then it
wouldn't work it didn't work so now you
have to understand it because you have
to fix it to make it work and I think
that's there's less and less of that
with the frameworks now most of them
just do work and so there is a lot more
of that teaching classes in this now I'm
having to think a lot more about this
being responsible for the next
generation of people who will be doing
this and I really like the approach of
us starting out learning the attacks
manually I'll use the example sequel
injection because I'm gonna be teaching
that on Monday we're gonna spend the
majority of the lecture doing every
single bit of it by hand in a browser
and then at the very end I'm gonna say
oh by the way there's also sequel map
and they'll do all this for you and
you'll probably never do it by hand
again until you run into something
really interesting but what makes a good
pen tester is when they hit that really
interesting thing that the framework
fails that they know how to drop down to
the command line and do it manually and
netcat or something and I think it's
really powerful to start off learning
the those foundations before you get
introduced to the frameworks yeah I
think the I think the idea of script
kitty to guru that whole continuum is
something that we all are based on the
topic and what we're trying to do and so
forth and time and circumstances because
if I can find a POC for the new struts
vulnerability I'm not going to write it
from scratch I'm gonna pull it off a
github and and use that so and that's a
very script kiddie kind of thing to do
but the knowledge to know what to use
and how to use it how to apply it
and what happens when you apply it and
what the ramifications are like clocking
thousands of users out of a server or
whatever that's sort of a more
further down the continuum so I think we
vacillate back and forth depending on
what it is
to continue with that I mean I feel like
while we may be somewhat more dependent
on frameworks and tools you still need
to have an understanding of how what the
tool is doing and why is why is this
expectation happening because at the end
of doing a pen test you have to write a
report and you have to explain to your
client why is this happening how do you
remediate that and that goes beyond just
running a tool yeah I mean I agree with
everything that I've said also just
working with app to use I mean just
being able to throw a script at it it's
not gonna help them as you guys said
like show them we know where the issue
is how is able to exploit something and
also educate them on how known for would
it matter to mediate necessary situation
it's good I think I just might
personally I think script Kitty or
squiddy because it call it's gritty all
right it's more of an issue of an
attitude I think also than it isn't
level knowledge because like you'd like
it's been pointed out none of us are
gurus and everything and actually if you
think about things where guru is in you
always beat somebody along the line
who's more of a guru and you get knocked
down a few steps and you realize you
know you slipped me to learn I'll take a
class on I took a class at our study
group on it was basic Kali Linux been
testing at you something like that
either member the book we had and I
learned a ton of things from that book
because I'm kind of an idiot also but
there were things but they're things
that you know I learned I've been doing
it this way oh you can do it that way
that's a lot easier I've never done that
way before cuz I'm a creature of habit
been doing it this way and I think I
think we're all script kiddies on
certain levels so that's not a bad thing
but I think the difference being is that
is that we desire not just to know to
use a tool but also know how it works
and in no other ways well I could if
you're talking about the the hack the
box the upset videos that if you looked
look for him on YouTube there if sec I
think it's IPP sec and he walks through
these vulnerable systems have been
retired on hack the box and what I like
about him is that he tries he you what
you want on the Metasploit I know people
that fire Metasploit everything you know
I need someone who fired a Metasploit
module it was a witness module at a
Linux box just to see what happened you
know just mindlessly shooting you know
but
but he actually goes to Metasploit last
last scenario it's like you'll that's
the last thing he goes he's manual
testing first before he does before his
Metasploit and you learned a ton of
things that way that you didn't really
know before I think we're all I think
probably for some of us the three words
we have trouble saying the most I don't
know because we think that makes us weak
right it's how we learn though right
it's how we learn from others I don't
know you know well yeah and and and
somebody asked me about the panel what
if I don't know something if I'm up here
but I don't know something well I don't
know you know it's a good thing you say
so so you come along those lines too I
guess last thing you know are there any
questions by the way any any questions
for the panel anybody wanting to get any
pen testing yes come
what are your approaches to using your
offensive skills to fix things or is
that even on your mind I can kind of
broach that beaker Beacon red team we
work really closely with our defense
team I'm not sure this is the way we're
going with this so I consider this to be
kind of like an almost like an arm of
the defense team if we find something
you know we'll do these simulations
we'll try to get in and try to get
around them you know and we just report
out on what we did but occasion we'll
find something and we'll just go
directly to them and say hey guys this
is a problem because when they look bad
we look bad
because if something if someone gets
into our network you know sure they're
the ones that brunt the first wave of
shame and you know and but then it comes
back to us and they ask us why didn't
you find that before before the other
guys did as a red team so it's it's kind
of its kind of like so it's it's up to
us to keep to keep our defensive team
strong you know and they it works both
ways I guess but well I consider us to
be kind of servants of the blue team
more than more than just our own little
cell of red team all-stars you know
which is a lot of people have that kind
of attitude but we're there to make the
company and strut stronger and better so
I do a lot of teaching just in all the
activities that I do not just proper
getting paid for teaching but running
long horn lock-picking and stuff and
being a red teamer feels to me like just
being a teacher you're finding all this
cool stuff and that's fun but then at
the end you get to explain these content
concepts to the developers who have to
fix it so it's it's fun to explain that
a at a high level what sequel injection
is and and see the aha moment in the
developer as they figured it realize it
and then are set off into the world to
develop more secure code you know but I
would like to reiterate that we are not
attackers we are defenders that use a
subset of attacker methodologies but we
are defenders so uh last last more
questions I was good question I saw is
there any word of advice to community
want to give us as maybe someone who is
out here who's thinking about this
career line is there any word of advice
you want to give to them that might help
them along some sort of advice I would
say for me Austin has I mean you
mentioned earlier it also has an awesome
excuse me an awesome security community
like it's newbie I feel like everyone
embraced me if I had any questions no
one hesitated to help me out as long as
you're doing your due diligence I mean I
don't think anyone wants to hold
anyone's hand but they kind of they lead
you to the water so what you're telling
are all the wrong things see what
happens you know
be kind of funny later anybody else I'm
gonna reiterate my meetups add vacations
go go to the awesome meetups they're
here in Austin and I'm gonna
specifically call out Austin hackers it
is I know it sounds really intimidating
that you have to get up on stage to go
there but it is an accommodating group
they I think they respond to the level
of nervousness you have I'm a very
nervous person and if I can do it then I
think anyone can but it is extremely
rewarding just to sit in the room with
the the type of talent that's there and
see the kind of things they're working
on and then to get advice from them just
to chat with them at the meeting
yeah you should definitely check out on
and he's I think under playing though
they it is intimidating I've been doing
this for over 20 years and it
intimidates the hell out of me
they're great though it definitely go
definitely go but it'd be expect to be
intimidated and and that's just it's a
hazing it's it's a it's a ritual it's a
rite it's just and then you're never
gonna have stronger bonds though then
after you've gone through that my advice
would be nothing to do with being
security specific it's uh something I
read recently of a study done on people
changing careers it was specifically for
entrepreneurs and the follow-up was what
is your biggest regret after making that
choice and it was consistently that I
didn't do it sooner I would add that if
you are gonna be in this field you need
to develop in yourself curiosity and the
love of learning if you do those two
things and you are always striving to
continually learn you're gonna be very
happy if you don't love doing that
you're not gonna be happy because this
is not a field where you can you can
learn this amount and then you're done
so you always have to be learning so
develop that I would also say because
Austin is such a vibrant active
community for information security it
reach out to people talk to people
any everyone on this panel I think
except for David is an introvert so we
aren't but but we're here there is a
video that I'll take oh we're here
because we want to help and that's the
thing about the information security
community is everyone wants everyone
else to be successful so reach out to
people who you normally wouldn't reach
out to and say hey how do you do this
how could I learn more do you have any
advice for me because we all want you to
be successful and I guess
last thing and I don't mean to hog the
mic here but I am curious how many
people here like CTF raise your raise
your hand
I can barely see people but how many
people play hack the box okay fewer it's
pretty cool it's a lot of fun and then
how many of you guys go to events
outside of a conference like a meet-up
or a user group or oh ah spur awesome
awesome fantastic so keep doing that
just do more of it those of you who are
preparing for the OSC PE are thinking
about it I was gonna say it's the hack
the box is a great free way to get
better prepared for that because a lot
of there's less similarities between the
boxes in that system and the ones in and
the in the osep environment but I guess
my advice would be also that I remember
Dave Kennedy once tweeted and I have it
saved somewhere about framing it
actually but one of the lines was to
those of us who are forever newbie and
that was how he started off off the line
and that was this thing we need to be
forever newbies anytime we think you've
arrived anywhere we think we've got to
place we're experts and we can stop
learning that's the point we stopped
growing and the way you remind yourself
of that the fact you're not there is to
surround yourself with people who are in
my opinion way smarter than I am
you know and you're learning some
constantly my my little motto that I
came up with and I don't know if it's
original or not but it's do good things
and put them where people can see them
you not to shout it out in the house top
well that look I've done you not to do
good things contribute and learn from
others to learn from the community
because it's the most embracing
community I guess it used to be kind of
jerks I mean we did used to be kind of
jerks and now we're we're bringing in
new people we're trying to bring them up
and train them we're learning from them
as a matter of fact - I I learned tons
of things from people that are new
security they come from like application
development
you know backgrounds and so just
remember we're always learning and
you know we're community here so if you
have questions if you have you want to
know something reach out to one of us I
would follow that up with when you
surround yourselves by all of these
incredibly talented people and come here
was something we didn't cover but you
will feel impostor syndrome but just
know that we do - oh yeah I've been
doing this for decades fraud what am i
doing in this field come on some of you
are liars that's okay realize what see a
reason why I had this for it in this
panel I'd never been on a panel before
I've never been asked to be on panel so
I just made my own they tried to vote me
out earlier it's my panel so they're
decoy we got a couple more quick
questions for questions even if they
have any questions at all please we've
got a lot of people up here not me but a
lot of people besides me they can answer
questions really well anybody come one
more question you have a question this
is my daughter she was my she's my like
ringer here how did you get so to be so
incredibly intelligent daddy
okay um how are you so good at hacking
no um where do you like start cuz I
don't know a lot about computers and it
seems just the whole thing just seems
completely overwhelming like where do
you start you start with code you start
with like what are the wires in there
doing I don't know anything about this I
can't emphasize that enough so what's
like a good place to begin learning
about this I would say that wherever
you're interested the thing is is
hacking doesn't mean computers and we
take a very liberal view at Dallas
hackers Association we've had talks
about hacking your metabolism we've had
talks about piracy which you would
expect but it was not that kind of
piracy was about our piracy
talking about the difference in
communication strategies between
Somalian and Indonesian pirates
I'll never used that information but it
was a really cool talk and this person
was passionate about it they they found
an interest that that's what happening
is is finding your passion and making
things do what you want them to do not
actually what they were intended that's
a question was someone asked earlier
because we're out of time
I wanna thank my panel though everybody
who came up and joined us here they
provided a lot of information feel free
to be one of us have been to talk to
questions uh concerning what we talked
about or anything regarding what's going
on here in Austin or or in the in the
hacking community so thank you very much
thank you
[Applause]
you