all right thanks a lot
morning everyone ha ha ha
so I swear Jason Street and I didn't
like mind meld beforehand or anything
over talking about really similar things
which i think is great I think it shows
kind of the state we're in as a security
industry so I want to keep this super
interactive so I'll be posing plenty of
questions again accidental mind meld
here and so for the sake of the
recording and also for the sake of
accessibility I will try to repeat your
questions that you have either at the
end or during the presentation and also
your answers because we don't have a mic
for people to line up to so just show of
hands who here is currently responsible
for some form of security education for
their employer ok a fair bit of you yeah
who feels like they have adequate
resources to deliver security education
fewer hands cool
so for those of you raise your hand for
the first but not the second what are
some of your pain points there's some of
the resources you're lacking Joe
I didn't get a lot of perfect buy-in and
get a lot of management fine
so lack of buy-in from management like a
buy-in from team maybe yeah yeah you
have formal process for new hires but
past that no good roadmap anyone else
yeah you don't know what you're doing as
an educator or as a person lack of
expertise okay well we can work with
that yeah so there's a lot of roadblocks
out there a lot of things that seem kind
of insurmountable so current state sans
does these reports every year on the
state of security awareness and security
education and a lot of times they look
at where where the pain points are and
most frequently it's time time resources
are seen as the biggest barrier to
devote to security education awareness
and outreach once you get past the the
canned the the new hire onboarding and
the annual refreshers that our
compliance requirement for a lot of
places oftentimes people places don't go
into any more depth than just those two
in the basics and so even for those
training is usually really really
generic rather than any kind of
contextual to employees roles
particularly when the training is
outsourced to some kind of canned
pre-made video or quiz or something like
that and it's really easy to get people
in a room when you're a company of like
20 employees but people run into
problems of scale and scaling a security
education and security awareness
programs often address via just over
automation let's just not deliver live
trainings anymore let's not talk to
people we'll just send them a video and
they hit a checkbox that they watched it
and when you're thinking about going
deeper than just the basics when role
based training does exist a really
common split is just to group employees
into a few groups like upper management
technical teams and everyone else or
sometimes just technical teams and non
technical teams and regardless of where
the
lines are drawn each category usually
receives training separately so this can
lead to further scaling challenges
because you're having to develop
different curricula for each team or
each role and that goes back to
consuming more time and resources than
maybe you have or you think you have and
also important focus areas can be
overlooked because we get these blinders
on about what people's roles are and
what their access is and so maybe
technical teams especially engineering
might receive some kind of wasp
top ten training but nothing about just
threat modeling or basic OPSEC or
physical security things that are still
relevant to them but maybe it's like
you're an engineer you should learn what
cross-site scripting is and just ignore
the fact that you don't have a privacy
screen on your laptop when you're on the
train so how do we address some of these
challenges I think having a lack of
resources can actually make people get
really creative and so we can be
resourceful if it makes a security
education a priority and I think that
starts with buy-in from our own team
rather than like I don't know there's a
bunch of things but we have to we have
to priority have to make it a priority
ourselves so some some ways to think
about it or like start with high risk
roles if you can't get trained everyone
pull multiple groups together and find
ways to deliver common themes while
still making people think about their
own roles build off of concepts that you
introduced in new hire onboarding and
security refreshers rather than going
entirely net new find ways to bacon
interaction and collaboration including
for remote employees remote employees
are most likely to be relegated to
really can't automated trainings and
sometimes they're the people who need
need our engagement than most because we
often have less visibility into what
their attack surface looks like so
throughout this talk I'm going to be
referencing a lot of times the training
that I built earlier this year year for
Robles security education but I don't
want this to be prescriptive I don't
want this to be like this is these are
the exact steps you must follow to do
this but rather want to use it as a way
to illustrate concepts that you can take
and run
with to figure out what works best for
your own organization also worth noting
of this this training kind of came out
of the very challenges we're facing in
security education we identified a need
for more depth in our employee security
education even as a security company
particularly the monk among teams that
were the highest impact targets yet we
we were a sec ops team of two for a
while and we lacked the staff time to
build like ten disparate trainings for
each department and so it's like how can
we say what we need to say and get
people engaged in a way that actually
scales with the time that we have
available and now we do have a dedicated
security education lead Kimber and she's
done awesome things to look for blog
posts from her but I'll let her tell
those those stories and even though I'd
talk about trainings security education
does not have to be limited to getting
people in a room and talking at them all
right
so somebody asked a question in the
keynote in the last talk where do you
start I don't know where to start so
where do you start
does anybody remember what the what
Jason even said he said newsletter why
communication so okay so communication
is good why does that have to
necessarily be a newsletter okay lecture
you said train them on something that
affects them in their lives just not
just work because they will take
personal and bring it in to work with
them and I think that goes both ways too
they can take good work habits and and
take me home with them so I'd rather
than starting with the tactical of where
do you start I think start with the end
in mind what problem are you trying to
solve so what problems are you trying to
solve by building out your security
education and security awareness program
anyone what do you want to achieve yeah
reduce account takeovers it's a good
yeah maintain continuity of business
operations yeah the security triad is
not just about confidentiality integrity
availability is a big piece of that
yeah plaid shirt in the back teaching
people the intrinsic value of security
that's great
blue shirt yeah comply with contractual
obligations and compliance is a piece of
it and compliance as much as people like
to rail against it for some places
that's how you get buy-in for having any
kind of security program is compliance
yeah protect your brand
yeah brand integrity is huge especially
if you do a really strong read
recognition and you want to make sure
that you can actually continue to sell
what you're selling yeah protect your
patients oh you're going to healthcare
yeah so a lot of really good things so
when you keep those strategic goals in
mind when you are building any kind of
security training so one approach that
we took that we've taken before is if
you can't get everyone who are your
biggest based impact targets who are the
teams that are higher highest risk and I
don't mean that in terms of like who are
the users who are most likely to click
because sometimes it's your job to click
and we can't just deliver a canned
message saying don't click but who
are the team's who based on what they
have access to what their role gives an
access to who are the teams who are
going to be the biggest impact targets
and why so who comes to mind who are
your highest risk teams
yeah finance operations IT admins yeah
they've access to a lot of stuff yeah
customer service yeah especially since a
lot of times those support numbers are
public and so anyone can call and try to
social engineer information out of
customer service rep yeah the executive
team they're very high profile they are
probably the most visible members of
your company and so it's easiest to like
yeah pose poses doug song and an email
in my case yeah and mented teams is a
significant influence on availability
like ops and IT admins also teams with a
significant impact on physical access
like receptionist like facilities like
recruiters are often letting candidates
in a lot of times when we when we let
people in who don't work at our company
its recruiters taking candidates around
so it's good to go through this mental
exercise for assessing your own risk of
figuring out who those teams are and how
you can target your educational efforts
accordingly and this gives the security
team more deliberate visibility into the
rest of the organization kind of gets us
out of our own bubble it requires us to
go through the mental exercise of
learning more about each team's attack
surface and this is just really good to
do regardless of whether we ever get
people in a room to train them we go
through the exercise of thinking what
are we trying to protect what do we want
them to be able to try and protect in
case of my employer one could argue that
like as a security SAS company we're all
the high-risk team just like we're all
the security team but yeah we can sort
of target
that so again start with the end in mind
so once you've identified your audiences
how do you engage them so Jason talks a
lot of also about building trust so how
do you approach building trust yeah be
available absolutely yes has very
important anyone else yeah be empathetic
Hey
shameless plug this is Joe Parker my
teammate and he's giving a talk tomorrow
afternoon on empathy and vulnerability
and sec ops so even though I'm talking
about security education and security
awareness trainings and workshops and
getting people in a room I firmly
believe that good security education it
could be the best it could be but it
can't exist in a void if you don't
maintain good relationships with your
co-workers the rest of the time so
really important to keep those going but
getting people in a room can be a good
way to kick off those conversations I
also say lead with listening and
coaching rather than just solely
preaching so rather than leading by
telling attendees of a training why
they're there have them tell us why they
think they're there why are you the
high-risk team why what do you have that
you are trying to protect or that's
worth protecting
that can do potential harm to the
company if it were altered or accessed
so or deleted something like that so
this type of the discussion gets people
in that mindset promotes a better
understanding of the attack surface of
other teams as well when you have people
all across an organization going through
this exercise we start to see outside of
our own work and gives us a little bit
more buy-in if the participants a
clearer sense of the big picture of what
we're all collectively trying to protect
because I think for all the time that
people can spend thinking about
protecting their own stuff they're not
really thinking about what they're doing
with other people's stuff a lot of the
times participants also know more about
their respective roles than the security
team presenters do as much as what
would like to believe we know what's
best for all of you we know what you do
we know exactly what accounting does
what legal does what DevOps does they're
the experts in their jobs were the
experts in ours so we want that we don't
people to talk so when you get people
talking about what they do and what they
have access to then we're listening and
we're establishing a connection and that
can build up a trusting relationship and
Trust leads to vulnerability leads to
trust leads to more connection and so
you get people to actually open up and
it's really important that people can be
open both in in a workshop setting and
then in the future if they accidentally
do so make a mistake and then they can
reach out to us so it also good like I
said gives us more visibility into what
people's roles are what they have access
to and takes the burden off of us having
to do all of that legwork up front of
understanding exactly where where people
are at and what they what they do and
also it's important that we're not
exempt from this when I asked about
high-risk teams
nobody said security we're super high
risk I know when there's been an
incident
I see vulnerability scan reports like
we're not exempt from this ourselves and
so I think it's really important that we
not take the approach that we are above
all of the bad things that could happen
to us Chris had a key one of the social
engineer village guys blog post a couple
years ago about the time he got fished
and like this is world-class social
engineer so important for us to show
that we're not above all of this we are
not exempt we we are just as high impact
of targets as anyone else so once you've
got this conversation going then how do
you get people into sort of an
adversarial mindset um I always liked
the word adversarial but sort of that
think like a hacker when we teach
security awareness we often encourage
participants to think like an attacker
and expect them to know what that means
right away and we rarely put them
through the actual exercise of getting
into an attacker
mindset people don't see themselves as
in the hacker they don't see I'm not a
hacker especially if they're not super
techie they're like that's not me I'm
not a criminal I'm not I'm not a bad
person I would never do anything to harm
someone so what is it important to sort
of at least know that this mindset
exists yeah yeah it's good it's
assessing risk is really hard ever as
bad at not just security so it's
important to like sort of get a good
sense of what's out there so I give
participants a chance to threat model
what they're trying to protect you don't
have to do this by themselves I have
done it by pairing people or grouping
people with people from other teams and
have them devise scenarios where they
hack each other based on their own roles
like based on what somebody's role is
and views their it their access against
them like really good example if
somebody came up with is like target a
recruiter at a recruiting event and
start asking them probing questions
about like oh who did this person report
to what what kind of tools do you use
and all of that and then use that as a
pivot point things like that so helps
them see beyond the beyond the technical
and into just the the fact that anyone
can do this to anyone and again get a
better insight into team's access and
team's roles and people with only
outsider knowledge of what somebody else
does actually come up with really
creative methods of attack and again
it's interacting interaction is more
effective than lecture for retention to
view new information it's less that we
have to talk at people to so once you've
done that it's really important to also
emphasize that attack scenarios that
people come up with aren't always that
far-fetched make sure that you are tying
it back to the realistic which could be
anything so I've had people will share
examples of what they come up with and
then share a few examples that have
actually happened to do oh let them know
like this is it this has happened before
or similar things have happened before
sometimes there are things we can't talk
about or have to remove certain
information that it is what it is but
people really like to hear juicy stories
and so it's it's good to get that into
their perspective right so people are
good and scared now do you leave them
good and scared no because then they're
just gonna go home and curl up in the
fetal position and cry so getting people
into this attacker mindset is only half
of the puzzle you have to tie it to
action so again how do you bring it all
together start with the end in mind
again what behaviors do you want to
reinforce that will further your vision
so what do you want to try to reinforce
to achieve some of those goals that you
laid out when I asked what problem
you're trying to solve what do you want
your users to do what do you want them
to take away yes not click on phishing
links what if they click on a phishing
link also have them survive that yeah
yes if they click on a phishing link
don't make them feel like the biggest
idiot ever when correctly crafted anyone
can fall for a phishing link when I did
security when we're doing security
refreshers this summer if we like I
mentioned that if somebody sent me like
a fish that was for dresses with pockets
I would probably fall for it it's all
about targeting I saw a couple hands
yeah
I love that so the comment was he shared
a security incident that he had caused
and that it can happen to anyone the the
only mistake is if you sit in it and
don't don't ask for help and don't
communicate thank you
yeah I was talking to a friend who works
on the DevOps team a while back and when
I was still kind of new to Incident
Response and I was like this is scary
how do you how did you get over breaking
like breaking a lot of things and
causing outages and he's like I broke a
lot of things and caused a lot of
outages so again very good to be
vulnerable with them
anyone else behaviors that you want to
reinforce yeah
absolutely that collective vision toward
a higher purpose we want everyone to
feel like they are the security team
that we are all in this together that's
really important that collective sense
of ownership not it's somebody else's
problem
yeah so regardless of the differences in
teams roles or their technical skill
levels or their seniority levels and the
information that they handle on a day to
day basis there can be a lot of common
ground in some of these proactive and
reactive security advice for people in
any kind of risk profile of roles some
common themes that I've done are OPSEC
that's one that a lot of people kind of
they they think about in some context
but not in others like not putting your
social security number in a tweet or
something like that and they'll but
they'll tweet pictures of their house
keys and again not only with their own
information but with others information
as well and I think having gone through
the exercise of sort of sort of
collectively threat modeling they're in
a better mindset to be able to handle
other people's information so talking
about OPSEC it's wonderful show people
privacy screens also just open lines of
communication with the security team
beyond just reporting consulting and
partnering with us and keeping those
conversations going especially if they
have like some kind of new software
they're going to implement or some kind
of program they're going to roll out how
to consult with us instead of just you
don't want the only interactions with
your teammates to be helped everything
is on fire how can we be proactive so
they'll hopefully be more receptive to
that after we have led with listening
and coaching rather than just lecturing
so okay what comes next awesome Wow
sorry I had to throw in a Hamilton where
do we go from here so this is not the
end-all be-all of how to approach
building building out security education
beyond the basics
but the challenges of scaling security
get education while adding depth and
maintaining effectiveness are not
intractable we can use trainings like
these as a jumping-off point to identify
additional education and awareness needs
and opportunities for future
partnerships so it's really important to
not only be getting metrics on security
awareness and security education but to
start establishing feedback loops I'm
not a product manager I don't play one
on TV but we need to we can treat this
sort of the same in sort of the same
approach as we are building products for
our teams and we want to make sure that
we're delivering effectively for the
people who are our customers which are
our co-workers and so create those
feedback loops and actually iterate on
them just yesterday we ended up changing
our language in one of one of our
security trainings because of feedback
that we were open to and got from a
teammate about the way we had phrased
something potentially permitting bias so
measure make sure that you are measuring
effectiveness efficacy not just
compliance iterate when you have to
automate think about the absolute
baseline you can build consistent
repeatable processes without necessarily
taking out human interaction you can say
this is how we this is our consistent
process for setting up workshops
trainings that kind of thing so automate
where it doesn't detract from from
effectiveness and rather than trying to
do that look for opportunities to
delegate or collaborate you can not be
everywhere at once people you're in dire
need of assistance to Hamiltons so they
even though you're the security
department I think a logical next step
is look for who your security partners
are and who your champions are across
the organization and figure out where
they can take ownership and run with
things we've had and this has probably
helped with the fact that we're security
product company we have had engineering
and product design teams meet in small
groups and just do a security
show-and-tell sessions talking about
topics in the industry that they've
researched and
purity doesn't go to those we don't
really need to we don't need to be
everywhere at once because this is sort
of like a self-running thing that they
do or like marketing team can work on
like where is it cool like security
propaganda posters that we can come up
with ourselves without us having to be
like be driving all of the efforts so
figure out how to make those a little
more self-running
there's a lot of opportunities out there
for collaboration there are a lot of
ways to get creative with whatever
resources you need and deliver champagne
security education on the lemonade
budget so we've got a little time left
so if y'all have any questions I would
love to take them yeah
security conditions and restricting some
presentation
yeah so the question was how do you
balance when you want to prioritize live
security trainings and workshops but you
may not how do you balance that with
like the canned pre-done ones if you do
have to I would say at least if you can
find ways to make them contextual tear
organization and your organization's
culture so even if you have to
pre-record some kind of lecture or some
kind of training I would say it's
probably gonna resonate more with people
if it's coming from someone you work for
instead of like X random and a made in
person just generically talking about
phishing links so find a way to make it
at least reflect your organization's
culture we've had to do this with we've
ran our annual security refresher
trainings in the summer and so there
were some people who were on vacation or
on leave who we had to send a recording
to I would also stress that live does
not have to mean in person and it's
getting more and more easy to either be
a remote team or a distributed team so
use that to your advantage you can have
like use your remote video conferencing
tools to be able to connect with people
all over the place yeah
bribe them with free food
mm-hmm yeah so the question was how do
you actually engage people who maybe if
you sent a quiz will just click through
quickly or if you have them in person
they'll bring their laptop and that pay
attention if you if you it was a budget
for free food just bribe them with free
food but that that gets them to show up
but doesn't necessarily get them to
retain information so again I think draw
drive back to engagement where you can
we've started having no device policies
for a lot of our big group meetings like
if you're on call of course you can be
on your laptop but generally speaking be
present and I think we have to also this
is where it's important for management
at all levels to be able to stress this
is you doing your job we don't want you
to have any reason to be tuned out from
this because if you're going to be sent
to to a lecture or classroom or training
or anything but you're still expected to
be working then you're sort of serving
two different mistresses and that are
kind of at odds with each other so it's
really important to get buy-in for the
fact that this is part of your job and I
think managers can set expectations of
their employees that we want you to go
we want you to participate and so that's
where it's really important to get
top-down buy-in and as far as engagement
goes sometimes you do have a pretty dead
room but anyway you can build in
interaction and ask questions and get
people talking about themselves get
people to open up I think that's gonna
have a good result and some notice does
depend of your organization's culture -
I feel really spoiled sometimes for the
fact that that work for a security
company and so we've got that a bit of
an easier selling point as to why it
should be top of mind for a lot of
people but also just a really I think a
really solid organizational culture of
open communication and being kinder than
necessary yeah
I think it's something that is going to
become less separated now that we have a
security education program and we can
sort of unify our efforts a little bit
since my job is entirely internal facing
my purview is kind of internal facing
training but we do have sales and
customer success people and product
people and I know that they do go out
and talk about that I did one customer
facing webinar last year on building a
security education program and so some
people who mostly have internal facing
roles do go external facing but I think
you bring up a really good point that
when it's I'm a while I think a lot of
sales tactics are about persuasion
persuading people to take action and so
I think that's something that can
definitely be leveraged for security
education stuff both internally and
externally thanks for reading that up
and who knows and if not I will be I'll
be at the conference all day today and
tomorrow so come flag me down or tweet
me and happy to continue the
conversations anyone else all right well
thank you all for coming
[Applause]
you