about us my name is ma the jump Siddiqui
come here boy ensemble we work for in
Gemalto in the enterprise in cyber
security department well you may not
have heard of Gemalto but it's it's not
a household name because the products we
have is mostly you know business focused
and not not consumer focused but gemalto
is has been you know developing secure
digital solutions for a while for
enterprise for government for banks and
telecom operators we currently involved
in the projects that we involved in is
the you know we have Jomon toes a
safeness trusted access which is an
identity and access management solution
with the wide variety of strong
authentication methods and also we are
involved in DeMarcos data protection on
demand which is the data protection
solution on the cloud so we've been
working on on cloud or developing cloud
solution for a while so we've
encountered many challenges specifically
pertaining to configuration in the cloud
so today we are going to you know use
that experience and lessons and also
done some you know some study so we're
going to share that a few that hopefully
will help you in solving your problems
pertaining to configurations so quickly
on the agenda so we'll go over the
overview of secrets in the cloud and you
know the types of configuration secret
and traditional ways for configuring
secrets and and what is desired of a
secret management solution we'll go over
some of the available solutions that we
studied and finally the conclusions so
first why you know why is it important
to
why is protecting configuring
configuration secret reported right so
we hear about breaches all the time
so as enterprises we understand there's
a strong focus on protecting business
sensitive data right so we have you know
we make an effort to encrypt SSN
credit-card numbers or any other data
which is business sensitive most of the
time the security of configuration
secrets is usually assumed right for
historical reasons because they are in a
you know in a data somewhere a data
center somewhere where it's on a very
you know trusted environment even though
typically configurations are unclear in
the config file sometime due to the
limitations of the tools that we are
using it forces us to to have that
configuration secret it clear at times
it's getting logged in a log file
somewhere but still the the the the
security is is assumed for configuration
secret however we need to keep in mind
that that if we get hold of
configuration secrets very easy to then
you know work towards getting the
business secrets as an example let's say
we have an application that is
protecting credit card numbers right so
it's Java based example so we encrypting
the card numbers in the database right
well we it's we don't have you know that
much money to spend on HSM so you use an
SSM you have a java key store well it's
protected by a password right but we put
the key store you know in the
configuration we put the password in
clear somewhere you know config file and
also the database credentials on
somewhere on on the same system so if I
as an attacker I get access to the
database credentials in the keystore
password in the key store I have all the
information and I need to connect to the
database and get to the sensitive
secrets out so that's why it's very
important to have a focus on protecting
the business protecting the
configuration secrets
so that is one part of it the other is
you know expectations from a cloud
applications right so the expectations
from application have changed quite a
bit right today with cloud application
the expectations are the highly scalable
highly available ephemeral nation in the
sense that because you have an
application throw that away
you can create tens of application
horizontal scaling there is no you know
no configuration which is yeah in inside
the application itself right and then we
have the concept of dynamic
configuration that is coming it that is
configuration like getting services on
demand like you get a data store on
demand so your your credential for that
those data source are the configured on
demand so we have dynamic configuration
and then we have the externalize and
because of this we have the externalized
configuration part and where you know
because of the the the expectation of a
complex application you want to
externalize your configuration secrets
ok now that we understand the business
need as well as the technical
expectations for configuring secrets
let's start let let us have a quick
overview of the configurations ticket
management so they start with a
different type of configuration secrets
that you typically have in your
configuration files so one of the very
common one you'll have figuration is the
service credentials these credentials
could belong to your data services which
could be your databases your cashing
services or some analytics system like
elastic search or Splunk the those
creditors could even belong to some
internal components or services or they
could belong to some external services
like your SME sees your billing system
or your cloud services you can also have
some private keys or speaker keys in
your configuration one of the typical
one is the TLS several keys which are
used to a basic expose your application
on the https depending on if you are
using the client neutral or you could
also have the particulars keys for the
clients over there also you could also
be using the SSH keys or
we've been keys to to the other data
centers or you could be using some
encryption keys to encrypt some of the
pieces in your some of the sensitive
information in your application or you
could be using some keys tools to
basically store any of the keys
mentioned above another common type of
configuration that you typically see
nowadays especially with the popularity
of reconnect or the different API
mechanisms is the API tokens for the
keys so that's another that's connected
to these service credentials but since
it's getting a lot popular nowadays so
we end up putting that as a separate
item okay so now let's also talk about
the what are the traditional ways of
managing those configurations and what
are the typical issues with those like
the the very as a developer you could
embed those secrets in your code okay so
easy implementation but the problem with
that is if you do if you have met your
secrets in the code now those secrets
will be part of each and every clone or
fork
any dual printers or even if you delete
those secrets unless we explicitly purge
those files from the from your
repository they are going to stick in
into the history of the code repository
the problem with that approach is that
it makes the access management for those
secrets very difficult mainly because
the code needs to be accessible by a lot
of developers but the seekers should
only be accessible by the operations
team so you should really avoid that
approach in case you are wondering if
one of your dual pane has already
checked in what you can do there are a
bunch of tools available which you can
use they normally used some graduates to
figure out go through the whole
repository and figure out if there is
some oddity some secrets there or not I
listed a couple of them but again they
are just as an example okay if you
cannot embed the secrets in the code
maybe we can we can embed them in the
bindings
okay but the problem with that approach
is if depending on how easily the
binding is excessive available to the
user
somebody can basically reverse and you
need that and can extract the secret out
of that let's take an example of a
mobile application the mobile
applications are easily accessible to
you guys on the
so imagine a scenario where the secret
is embedded as part of that mobile
application now as the attacker I can
basically download the the mobile
application and then reversing it over
there and figure out the secret out of
that the similar thing is you can
provide the secret as part the build
time variables again at the end of the
day that secret would become part of the
binary and they choose which I mentioned
above are applicable over there also
okay so since we are not going to use
these secrets in the code or we don't
want to embed them in the binary what
about providing them through the new I
already Bill's okay an approach people
have been using for a while but
especially with the with the container
base now the docker containers there are
a lot of issues with that approach one
of the common one is if you do dock
inspect on a running container it will
show you all the in mind variables over
there which means anybody who has access
to the machine should be able to view
the secrets values over there or if
you're using Cuban it is or openshift
okay then you don't even need to have
access to the machine as long as you
have access to the dashboard those will
you the values will be by default
visible in plaintext to you so oh don't
don't don't use those environment words
to provide the secrets over there
another another drawback with this
approach is that all release provided by
through in Winery bills are accessible
by all the processes running in the
docker container again so quite a few
issues with that approach so in other we
typical we the in actually this this
approach is very common nowadays even
that the people provide those secrets in
plain text in configuration files or
store them in the database over there
again even though people know these
shoes with those configuration secrets
but typically that'sthat's the approach
they use because because of the chin
with the with the tools like the example
with Nitin gave about about the Java
Kishore the passphrase needs to be
provided in the in the server I'll again
the problem with that approach is
anybody who get once you get access to
that persisted storage whether it's a
file system or database the secrets are
there in clean tech so they you can you
can extract out from there
so now we talked about the different
issues with the current approaches that
we are using so let's look into the what
are the features we want in our secret
amendment solution so obviously we want
some which has the secure a secret
storage which basically should let you
store the secrets in well in it should
be well protected enough over there at
rest as well as during the transport it
should also let me define who is able to
access with secret even at what time you
should also be able to configure your
applications to use those secrets easily
and should be able to indicate with
those easily over there and it should
provide you probably the usage audit
basically you should be able to figure
out who is who use mice this secret from
where at what times and you should also
have a mechanism to take backups so that
it can it should be able to recover from
disaster situation like the services
down you should be able to get back to
that quickly depending on the what are
the security requirements you are
falling you may also be looking for some
solution which provides you some secret
management renewal management like the
PCI card I'm using that for that the
certificate expires every year so it
needs to be renewed at that time and
last but not least you should also have
a mechanism to be able to revoke certain
secrets in should we delete those also
okay now we're going to cover some of
the you know popular deployment concerns
that are in use and how we could protect
configuration secrets into using those
solutions first first one we're going to
look at is Cuba nation secrets a
centralized mechanism to configure and
provide the secrets to your application
to two containers right we this is a
very simplified diagram but I mean the
idea is as an admin the first step is
the admin would would somehow you know
configure the master keys right so this
is at the time of deploying or it's a
Cuban it this encryption config there's
a config file in specify what keys to
use and then once you have your cluster
running and you know the process is to
create those secrets the secrets are
stored in HDD you know encrypted if it's
configured properly and then when you
deploy your applications then Humanity's
makes these secrets available to the
application typically on temp FS mount
which is an in-memory file system so in
terms of the features it's a central
system that that centrally centralized
secret management solution
it supports encryption for you know text
and files the secrets are protected at
rest and in transport but you have to
configure it correctly and then we
configure at the point for container
secrets are not persisted on the disk
when they are provide and the secrets
are provided to your containers they're
not persisted on test but why did it in
memory temp FS file system accumulated
provides audit capabilities you using
Cuban ATIS auditing
one thing to keep in mind is by default
there's no encryption and the word
secret has been around you know from the
beginning or before
or encryption and over there before it
was just a base64 encoded there was no
encryption so we need to be aware that
you you have to use version 1.7 or later
in terms again you know by default there
is no encryption so you need to be aware
of that it's only May 64 encoding and
Cuban it is provides some some you know
cipher mechanisms secret box it's it's
fast
so it's speed wise it's good but it's a
new standard may not be acceptable in in
in some environments especially if you
have compliance requirements it's
basically a stream cipher and then you
have a s CBC so the recommended one and
slightly slow slower than secret bulk
but it's a well established cipher now a
a SJC GCM it's faster than CBC because
do you know you can do cooperative
operation parallel but requires key
rotation so unless you have an automated
mechanism of doing three rotation it's
not recommended and then finally you
have the you know capability of
integrating with an external kms which
we'll cover so we so Cuba data has
provided a way that you put integrate in
an external kms on external HSM
the HSM over here the hardware security
module so the way it works is that cube
natus encrypts the data with the data
encryption key the data encryption keys
encrypted with a key encryption key
which is in in the KMS and communities
will store the encrypted data and the
encrypted data encryption key on in HDD
also it rotates the key every time if
you know this key rotation of the the
the key data encryption key is rotated
often however we need to keep in mind
that it requires custom plug-in
development so the way I understand it
is cubanía test obviously it's not going
to agree
all the gay misses I say something that
are out there right so it basically you
know called the local service so you
have to run a local service on the
master note that accumulate this would
in in work for KMS operations so I mean
you want to provides an HSM on-demand as
the game is provided up which could be
used you know so in terms of the
recommendations you know don't use the
default no encryption right don't get
fooled by secrets just the word secrets
I use external kms because if we use the
other providers the the master key is in
player still in clear on the master note
right so it's again the problem yes you
if you could get hold of that key then
all your secrets are you could get
access to all the other secrets good on
a CD with TLS otherwise you don't have
you know protection in transport okay
next we are going to talk about the her
she carpooled that is basically a
centralized secret management solution
provided by hi she co one good thing
about this solution is that that is
platform agnostic so you can use that
with any any of your current existing
infrastructure at really high level if I
give you the overview of the
architecture is in this as administrator
I would go and set up the secrets in the
in the world and the vault would store
those in in the encrypted storage over
there after that I can configure my
application to be able to request with
those secrets
what would verify that the application
has access to those and then it should
be able to return those secrets back to
the the application over there so in
terms of features the it provides a
secret secure secret storage the secrets
are protected at rest as well as during
the transport the infrastructure admins
which let's say the open shift or
kubernetes administrators they should
not be able to see the values of those
secrets at all only the vaulted winds
came so there's a difference now between
the infrastructure admins vs. the vault
edmonds now to ensure that only a single
administrator watermen cannot decrypt
the all the secrets
viewdoze you should probably use these
great master keys over here to avoid
that happening what also lets you manage
these static as well as the dynamic
secrets by dynamic secrets it's meant
that you the vault would create those
secrets when application would require
those for example your database
credentials when in a pitchman would
require for those at that time it would
go and create those credentials in your
database server and then would return it
back to the to the application you can
also use walled as a data encryption as
a service mainly what it means that Walt
won't store any encrypted content over
there but it you can use that to encrypt
or decrypt content for you and then you
can store that in your existing
application the way you would a fig
using earlier the you can also limit how
long the credentials would be valid for
in the world you can basically make that
by using the leasing concept of that and
after that the predefined period the
secrets would be revoked
automatically volt also lets you devolve
the secrets individually or you can also
revoke them by a tree like you can
specify okay to both those secrets for
any secret accessed by this user or you
can specify revoke all the secrets of
this particular type what also provides
a very detailed audit log in terms of
any authentication happen to it or any
token creation or any secret related
activity like access to that or a
creation or revoke the revocation
etcetera so it prides detail audit log
for that I want to give you a quick
overview if you want to use vault what
kind of steps are involved over there to
set up that obviously you would first
start the world server when you start
that for the very first time there is a
initialization process would kick in as
part of that you would be asked to set
up the master keys over here as well as
it will give you a root token account
root token that new token is very
important because you'll be using that
token to configure the vault in the next
steps also another thing is whenever you
start the world it will always be in
sealed mode this and you would need to
explicitly unseal that
by unsealing we mean that you would need
to provide the master keys so that the
world can decrypt the content over there
basically the vault will not store the
master keys locally at all so as a what
that mean you would need to provide
those keys on the server starter
once that is done as a root operator or
administrator I should be able to
configure the authentication method
which my applications would be using to
authenticate to the world and then I
would also configure the access policies
and I would also configure the secrets
over there which by applications can
request a later on so once that is done
now I can configure my applications the
application would be able to connect it
to the world using the authentication
method I configured earlier and then
application would be able to request
those secrets which it has existed now I
want to give you a quick overview of the
temptation method supported by my world
again it supports big variety of those
and I haven't even listed all of them
over here okay so but one important
takeaway from this slide is some of
those authentication methods are strong
enough like we studied kubernetes over
there but some of them probably not as
strong as this one like the traditional
username password in LDAP
considering the you are putting all your
secret configuration over there in the
world so it would be probably much more
important to use a stronger
authentication method over here as
opposed to the traditional username
password or LDAP so in our study as I
said we we considered the QBs
authentication so I want to show quickly
give you an overview how does it work so
we see you when you deploy Kuban it is
an application of the communities you
can tell it in the configurations that
it should mount a service account a job
at a particular location of the of the
pot or container and the container
should be able to use that job to talk
to the vault for the authentication
once the world gets that job since it
does not trust that so it needs to call
the OpenShift or kubernetes master api
to validate that once that is done it
should return the tope it's a date of
war token
send it back to the Container as part of
the step 3 and after that using that
wall token the application should be
able to request the secrets and get the
all the seekers which it has access to
in terms of recommendations on the if
you want to use hajikko world make sure
you protect your master keys well enough
if you lose them okay there is no
recovery mechanism available if you lose
them all your encrypted secrets will be
gone okay
you should predict your duty kau token
because that's a full access token you
can use that token to in the existing
configuration of the vault so make sure
you it's well protected again you should
be using sharted master keys or strip
master keys to avoid the scenario via a
single percent gain decrypt the vault in
and view all the secrets over there
again this would make the vault startup
a bit complicated because now you need
to have multiple people available at the
same time to be able to start the server
over there so yeah it makes the start
over but complicated but probably the
kind of stuff it has it's probably not
that big of a big of cost again as I
said earlier you use a stronger
authentication method and one thing is
make sure you don't try to automate the
unsealing of the vault that is a manual
step by design but we understand that
that this makes it a difficult in terms
of automation environment where if the
service goes down there's no mechanism
to automatically start that so that
makes it difficult in that's a challenge
I'm not sure how to address that right
now but that is something to think about
for sure
so that let's look at is your keywords
so if you are in Azure platform this is
a good one too it's a very good solution
for protecting
any any any kind of secret okay so it's
a secure management service from
Microsoft for the assurer cloud platform
again I mean a very simple diagram over
here you have your admin that would
create the vault service and then you
have your developer and your application
then using that word vault key service
to create case new crypto operations and
so on so in terms of the features it
stores secrets keys and certificates
well the big key point over here is it's
HSM back secret storage and one thing
that styled out for sure key want is it
provides certificate lifecycle
management it's not only you know a
storage for certificates at key but it
provides her so you could use it as a C
as well and then manage your you know
certificates for your back-end services
I think it also you could get public
certificates also not so certain about
that point one big point over here it's
a integrated access control with Azure
Active Directory so if you are on sure
then you get access control from admins
applications developers so it's its
built-in also it has built-in
integration with a lot of SEO resources
sequel server for one right so you could
configure sequel server to use as your
keyword and then encrypt all the Karma
encrypted database and it's inbuilt
supports both client and server-side and
client-side encryption suicide what I
mentioned just mentioned with sequence
server it it could be used as you know
and encryption as a service where you in
from in your application you call as
your key wall to encrypt your data and
then store that in cryptid content in
datastore
it provides all written monitoring
capabilities it suppose bring your own
key what Microsoft me
if you bring your own key and Microsoft
within is your key world they only do
crypto operations there is no way for
anyone to view those keys so your keys
are protected and provides a high SLA
microsoft claims on it the highest la
obviously and also thus the you know
typically if we look when you use HSM
there's a performance impact to our
claim because they are worldwide and
they have you know distributed HSN so
that reduces that performance impact
they they have two types of case one is
you know the RSA key volt key that's
basically just like the way it was in
Cuban it is where your the crypto
operations using RSA key volt is
executed in software right and then what
you do is that that key itself is
encrypted with that key which is in HSN
so use the HSM to protect your a King
material and then the other one is the
HSM itself where the key is in it I say
more about all the crypto operations are
happening within the adjacent protected
boundary in terms of access control I
could already you know it's very
integrated with Azure ad they have you
know for for managing oil they have a
management plane API that is basically
used to create the World Service itself
and volt access policies use a surety
for authentication role based access for
authorization and then we have the data
plane API which is a different set of
API is that you are you know that your
applications will call to create keys
you know for crypto operations it uses a
surety for authentication again and also
for the data plane API doesn't use the
role mail access bar to the vault access
policies for authorization that was
created using the management API
yeah can we yeah okay okay okay okay
let's talk about the integral secret
manager in this is the secret management
solution provided by the alias platform
again like the ones we discussed earlier
again it's a centralized secret
management's solution the way the
typically worst is that as administrator
let's say you go and configure create a
new set of credentials in your RDS after
that you would go and configure that in
the 80s secret manager you would also
specify the exes policy over there
saying okay who can exist that like I
can specify this secret is accessible by
my custom app after that the my custom
app would try to authenticate to secret
manager in secret manager once
authenticates that and verifies the
excess policy it should return those
credentials back to the application and
then as a point to a part of point five
it would be able to connect to the
database using those credentials now in
terms of feature it provides again
secure secure storage what it does it
uses the AWS EMS to encrypt or decrypt
the secrets using the keys owned by the
customer so again they also support
bring your own key what they do is for
each secret they generate a new data
encryption key which is basic encrypted
by the key a key encryption key stored
in kms and after that the encrypted data
encryption key plus the encrypted secret
both are stored in the secret manager so
whenever it needs to decrypt that
content it would decrypt that data
encryption key using that using kms and
after that it should be able to decrypt
that secret stored in the secret manager
in terms of access control like all
other services of it appears it uses a
double yes I am
identity access management a module to
manage the policies over there it
supports three type of policies one of
the very common one used is identi based
policies which basically means that this
secret is accessible by a user who
either belongs to this group or who has
this particular role you can also have
the resource waste policy where you can
explicitly space
if I for this particular secret this is
accessible by this person or you can
also have a tag based policy which
example for that could be all the the
secrets tagged with team one should be
able be accessible to all the users who
are part of group team one so that could
be the database policy over here now in
terms of the rotation of the secrets
that's a that's really a cool feature of
it Willis secret manager what it
supports that it at predefined frequency
or predefined time it would go ahead and
change you're getting chilled or secret
automatically for example they have a
built-in support for ATS RDS database
what it means that after every thirty
days it would change your database
credentials over there and the way it
works is it would at that particular
time it would create a new set of
credentials in in your RDS and then it
would pass application to verify that it
is able to connect to to that database
using those credentials if yes then it
would basically permanently change those
credentials in in both systems over
there for other services you need to
implement the custom lambda function it
also provides very detailed audit and
marketing monitoring of secret usage you
can use AWS cloud trail to view the logs
or you can also use the cloud watch it
is cloud watch to receive the
notifications while I email it push
notifications in terms of
recommendations as I said you you can
use your customer master key probably a
good idea you should also protect your
master key because if you lose that no
way to recover your master key over
there one thing I didn't mention earlier
is the application we teach to talk to
the aw secret manager would require some
set of a tedious keys over there so that
it can attend ticket to the to the eight
of your secret manager make sure you are
not using your account keys over there
make a user which has limited privileges
and should only be able to access that
ticket manager API over there
so the solution that we have looked at
till now is mostly a central solution
but because ansible is so popular so we
thought locate ransom and also so the
solution for ansible is a little bit
different it's decentralized allows
users to encrypt secrets for ansible
projects so the way it works is you have
in ansible vault which you can use that
to encrypt your configurations your
playbooks once you have your and then
you persist your encrypted labels and
when you have to execute the playbook
you provide your password to answer will
playbook which would then decrypt
execute the decrypted playbook and
usually it uses an aes key which is
derived from from the password that you
provide in terms of features it's a
decentralized a secret protection in a
symmetric key that's derived from a
password it can encrypt any file and use
by ansible and it provides you told to
to manage the encrypted content so you
can create encrypted content or you can
if you have your name box already you
can just encrypt them directly and then
finally you provide the password to to
ansible label their different ways of
providing the password one is prompt
that requires you know a manual person
to enter the password otherwise you'll
have to you know they have mechanism to
get the password from file input again
go back to you know if your password is
also over there then it's in issue
don't forget the password there's no
recovery mechanism your key is based on
the password so yeah protect your
password be aware that providing the
password in an automated solutions again
you know well that's a chicken-and-egg
problem right what how do you protect
that initial you know secret no audit
capability is limited access control no
authorization
but maybe not an issue because it's very
very specific to answer but right so
you're trying to protect your ansible
projects and trying to protect secrets
if you have secrets within those clay
books so in terms of the conclusion we
started with the business need so it's
important to understand that it is
important it is as important to protect
your configuration data as you protect
your business sensitive data you know we
are possible you should try to use a
center secret management system it would
be mindful of you know some of the
security features they or rather when we
are using it and try to use it in a
secure manner right there pitfalls that
are there if we if because of miss
configuration so we use a strong
authentication limit access to need
bases rotate keys and secrets audit and
monitoring so there's no one solution
that fit all right it depends when your
needs so the platform that your
applications are deployed on we just
listed some of the you know the
highlights of all these it's not a
comparison so I mean you could make a
choice based on on the the the platform
that your applications are deployed on
or you may want a you know a platform
with agnostic solution it's good to look
for a solution which is SS HSM pact if
you want a really good secure solution
and you could use you know Jim Altos HSM
on demand and yeah and if you want to
limit you know if you want to have
rotation limit the lifetime that does
the passwords are available then look
for a solution that had secret rotation
so the question is you know salting a
using salt for the sequences a cipher
algorithm that's what your question is
we didn't cover that I mean that that's
too low level and I mean usually it's
assumed with the cipher algorithm that
we use then it's not more about you know
the ciphers we didn't expect and one
that it's more high level how do you
recommend that we implement a che or
disaster recovery if we're using and
hashey core vault or ansible wall
because it's not automated so so yeah
and I mentioned that in even in my
presentation yes that's an issue the one
approach you can do is probably don't
stew don't host your high sugar vault
probably as part of the your cloud
solution in probably manage that as a
separate VM so that if you're claw cloud
Miam goes down it should not affect that
one thing is I should have I'd say it is
solution over there where you can host
that in multiple machines so even if one
goes down it should be running on the
other one so it comes with the H a will
ability or high availability support
over there out of the box
so yeah it's the option is there but the
problem with that if you for example put
that in something like openshift or
cuban it is if that system goes down
then what you do because over there the
containers goes down keep on going down
and up right any time so that's why we
were saying that ok you probably don't
want to put that on the on the cloud
solution over there and maybe put that
on some separate VM so that that is more
controlled by you and then you can host
that in on multiple machines so that you
can you can take care of that easily the
answer question
and here's a question in that case
thanks Ariel thank you
[Applause]
you