[Music]
one thing I want to say right now is we
are scheduling for a little bit of Q&A
at the end so if you do have questions
which hopefully there will be lots try
and wait until we're done we should have
10 or 15 minutes and or we can do the
hallway and everything else so I think
we're good to go general outline if you
want an idea of what we're going to talk
about beside you hate it feel free to
leave now or whenever you want there's a
lot to try and cover and we can't quite
do everything so hopefully we'll touch
on a lot of really important points
throughout this talk so I am mob head
I'm a senior information security
engineer member of Austin hackers
anonymous might have picked up on that
one
DEFCON security goon general volunteer
junkie including audio-visual stuff for
a lot of conferences one thing I do want
to say though is semi personal
disclaimer I did formerly work for a
vulnerability management company that's
where a lot of this comes from was
consulting with probably over a hundred
different customers so despite that
we're gonna still try and be pretty
neutral on vendors
I am digital grease working InfoSec is a
security engineer a little side note if
there's anybody who's trying to get into
InfoSec and maybe doesn't have like a
college degree or something like that a
little hard work will get you really
really far I used to be a mechanic so
now instead of just can you fix my
computer I get can you fix my computer
and can you fix my car
all right so we're gonna start out with
a disclaimer it'll be one of the few
things we read incomplete we do not
attest to the fitness of any product or
service and we certainly don't attest to
fitness of any kind
we are not lawyers if you don't believe
we're not lawyers ask our lawyers if you
are a lawyer we probably need lawyers
all right so we're gonna walk through a
little bit of expectations just around
the talk itself and again give you an
opportunity to decide you're in the
wrong room and go see somebody much much
better so first we are gonna really try
and be agnostic as far as vendors or
products goes despite my previous
experience I then spent two years
working defense using the biggest
competitors product so at this point
we're not going to try and have product
specific features or functionality and
really make this broad as possible
prerequisites for this talk is you
should have used or configured
vulnerability management product be
running scans and creating reports and
maybe have experienced some of the
challenges of a vulnerability management
program general knowledge similar you
know hopefully you've got some hands-on
work you're familiar with creating scans
or sites templates reports this is not
entirely required but you will better
understand the problems and some of the
goals that we've outlined some common
problems that you run into in
vulnerability management is too many
vulnerabilities and poor reporting on
them lack of upper management support
for remediations and other departments
viewing you as a blocker to what they're
trying to do so general roles is trying
to become a bit more risk focused
focusing on risk versus
vulnerabilities scoped reporting and
definitely things like accuracy and
quickness speed as we get through this
hopefully these should start to become
more apparent than the things we're
trying to address the audience for this
is the people who use these products
every day familiar with the processes
and those people who may be able to
influence change in order to fix some of
those processes you'll find that while a
lot of this is on the technical side
some of it is more on kind of the
high-level philosophical side and so
there are many things you can't
necessarily change unless you're in a
position of influence which is certainly
a challenge all right so first thing
we're going to talk about is just
general life cycle this is very
important because as many of us
hopefully have learned by now there's
not an end goal security is not going to
be done in vall management is not going
to be done it's just gonna keep
happening over and over again I did not
build out your standard life cycle slide
because there's a hundred different
variations on things like discovery and
prioritize and all of that sort of stuff
what I did do is actually kind of my new
favorite starting in the top right of
just plan-do-check-act it is important
to make this a life cycle you are not
done even when something is remediated
it's probably going to come back and you
still have to have that life cycle in
place so maturity level much of this
talk very much relies on maturity we're
gonna say this over and over again and
keep rehashing it you can't do
everything immediately so a lot of this
stuff we may recommend a best practice
or an end goal and you may say well
that's just not possible I can't get to
that point yet just keep that in mind
that you may be starting at a lower
maturity level and working towards some
of these ideas so this is definitely not
a full list of potential milestones for
maturity but having things like asset
inventory and patch man
mint are really going to be important if
you have some of them right now that
will be incredibly helpful if you have
absolutely none of them then that gives
you an idea of where you might be
starting from a maturity level and how
am i doing on the mic it's all over the
place everyone hear me okay
sweet keeps dancing around so we're
going to start this off talking about
some do's and don'ts and starting with
your patching approach um there are
generally two schools of thought kind of
where either vulnerability management
tells you what all you need to patch or
vulnerability management tells you what
you missed after you've already patched
some don'ts that you should avoid is
don't patch things only when they're on
fire you should not patch just because
there's some new named Hollywood
vulnerability with a logo and a website
that is not the only time that you
should be patching things and other
thing is don't chase vulnerability
counts it's not helpful to tell somebody
that there's 30,000 vulnerability is on
a particular system because that is
unmanageable and do not prioritize based
on CBS s it is a valuable metric to use
but it's also a very static metric and
does not take a lot of things into
account like asset criticality or age or
the availability of an exploit some
things you should do are adopt irregular
patching cadence now this may be
different based on your organization
whether it's bi-weekly monthly quarterly
whatever but never never but a regular
patching cadence will avoid a ton of
problems before they can ever happen
another thing that you should do is
instead of chasing vulnerabilities chase
remediations
if you go to somebody with like I said
you know if your server has 4,000
vulnerabilities they're immediately
going to shut down and stop listening to
you because they can't do anything about
that but if you say hey there's two
remediations you need to do that's
manageable and something they feel like
they
accomplished and another thing that you
should absolutely do is utilize risk
score the big vulnerability management
products have their own risk scores
available which is a combination of
usually cbss and those other things like
asset criticality and age and exploit
availability that gives you a more
usable weighted score to sort of
organize things by
all right so a little bit on
architecture and deployment this is kind
of focusing on hardware requirements
number of scanners placement of scanners
this is a very broad topic so we
obviously can't cover quite everything
but hopefully it can give some good
takeaways so for the love of God don't
use the minimum requirements I saw this
all the time and still to this day you
see this frequently from friends that
are telling me hey my system is really
slow my scans take too long so those
minimums are minimums for a reason
don't virtual eyes raise your hand who's
currently got a virtualized
vulnerability console server primary ok
well talk a little more about why in the
do but a big part here is generally
people are not dedicating resources
generally your console or server needs
to be 64 gigs of ram up to maybe a
hundred and ninety-six gigs of ram and
you're not going to be putting that into
a virtualization cluster so this ties in
with being under-resourced so don't
share the system if you run a Metasploit
pro and an expose on the same thing or
you're running tenable and bro network
monitor or whatever it got renamed to
you're gonna wind up suffering from a
lot of resource problems and again
either your CPU your memory or your disk
i/o is going to completely tank and
definitely do not ignore network
topology if you've got DMZ hopefully or
a cardholder data environment the
placement and position of your scanners
is going to be very critical to your
success so you're not punching firewall
holes through 19 firewalls from your
scanner all the way into your protected
network do allocate enough resources
again Ram CPU and especially disk i/o a
lot of people don't think about that one
but for on-prem TVM your disk i/o is
very often the biggest bottleneck even
more so on your scanner or on your
consoles or your primary server than it
is your scanners
definitely deploy enough scanners
frequently I saw way too many people
that had three scanners for 50,000 IPs
and they had 25 offices around the world
that does not scale so if you've got a
large data center with 20,000 systems
you're probably going to need a couple
of scanners if you've got a hundred
offices you may not necessarily need a
hundred scanners but you're probably
going to want to make sure you're doing
regionalized scanners and things like
that tune the OS database application
this applies far less to the cloud which
is why most vendors are going there but
again if your OS can support some kind
of tuning either at the file system
level or generally application priority
especially things like if it does have a
database if it's a database you have the
ability to customize and tweak do so
because once you scale above probably
10,000 IPs if you haven't done this
you're gonna run into a lot of
bottlenecks and then monitor resource
utilization if you're not paying
attention to what your resource looks
like during a scan or during a large
import to your console your primary
server how are you ever going to know
when suddenly your bottlenecking again
and frequently I would see customers
that were simply deploying at a certain
size then growing and having no clue
that they had been bottlenecking on
three out of ten of their scanners so
whether you're using more than likely
some kind of third party thing through
SNMP or IPMI or whatever make sure
you're monitoring much like a sysadmin
would so some important things about
discovery you're scanning and frequency
are well first of all discovery scanning
is critical because you may think that
you know what's on your network but you
probably don't and a secondary to that
is that bone management tools while they
can be used to supplement are not asset
management tools even though some people
like to treat them as such that's not
what they're for that's not what they're
due and
it's really not what they're good at
some things you should not do is assume
that you know everything things
constantly change on a network you have
systems getting decom there's some
developers standing something up over
here to do whatever he's doing there's
always things changing on your network
you cannot at any given time know
exactly what there is without doing some
kind of discovery suite do not blindly
trust your asset management assuming
that you have asset management if you
don't that solves that problem yeah even
a good asset management system is still
fallible it may not get updated properly
it may not get updated frequently enough
and because of that you will miss things
that exist on your network do not do why
broad-reaching discovery sweeps without
notifying people if you're gonna scan an
entire slash 8 in your network you
should probably let people know about
that because it's gonna scare some
people it's gonna break other people's
deployments and you're generally just
gonna cause a huge problem for tons of
people do not rely on ad-hoc scans
ad-hoc scans which may be necessary
every once in a while they will muddle
up your scan schedule they will throw
off your scan windows and they'll use
scan resources when you really don't
need them two things that you should do
our discovery sweep regularly because
things change so frequently and you
never really know what changes have
taken place having a regular cadence at
which you do discovery sweeps gives you
some idea of a baseline of where your
network is you can use discovery sweeps
to supplement your asset management
while it may not be asset management
they will frequently find things that
your asset management system has missed
or did not know about so they very well
supplement each other you should
schedule and notify any stakeholders
before running broad-ranging a sweeps
like I spoke about if there's a third
gives I'm going to be doing Network
maintenance you should probably let the
network guys know and then if that's not
gonna work for them you can
work out a different time to do your
discovery sweep and you should
definitely consider criticality and
resources criticality of an asset can
play a huge role in how frequently you
should scan it for instance if you have
a PCI Enclave you're probably going to
want to scan that way more frequently
than random developers workstation and
kind of a little side note on the
resources side of things is if you want
to avoid using network resources and
system resources agents are a great way
to do that
you completely bypass using air scan
engines resources and any network
resources and all of it is done on the
host
alright so vulnerability scanning don't
build scans for your environment
specifically what I kind of mean here is
that many vulnerability scanner
templates policies will let you do
things like turn on or off certain
plugins or checks the problem is when
you start scanning a list of Windows
servers and you disable everything
that's not a Windows Server what happens
when suddenly in that subnet or by
accidentally in that list of assets you
get an on Windows System now you're
blind so don't use untuned default scan
templates or policies while they'll get
you started you really need to tailor
them for your environment looking at
things like timeouts or retries what
network performance impact it might have
what ports it is or isn't scanning all
of these things are very important and
lastly do not scan static lists of
assets anything that is static in the
product is going to be the devil do
build scans for your environment so
while this is the same as the don't what
I mean here is focus on things like if
you have IOT devices or SCADA or you've
got a portion of your network that's got
low speed connection you're gonna want
to tweak your scans to accommodate those
systems just don't start pulling out
plug-ins that you think aren't going to
be executed or needed because the
products are smart enough to do that
themselves definitely consider your scan
requirements this ties into things like
your scan window blackouts whether
people are in or out of the office
scanning a corporate network used to be
a royal pain before agents because you
had a very small window during the time
period of the timezone the office was in
to catch your employees and co-workers
so think about those things it's one of
the biggest pieces of a deployment and
then lastly scan everything
the motto I've always used is scan
everything all the time how practical is
that do the best you can a lot of things
like the integrations with DHCP servers
Active Directory and especially agents
are making this easier and easier but
the common thing I used to see was
customers that were basically scanning
only my window servers in production and
only this one tier of system in court
and that was only 10% of the network so
authentication versus unauthenticated
stands this is one of the areas I'm most
passionate about but it's also one of
the areas that very frequently leads to
infighting between security and everyone
else who owns the actual systems any
show of hands on who currently is using
credentials and their scans ok awesome
to see so the way I like to explain this
is with a little analogy when you buy a
house you have to get a home inspection
the inspector will go inside the house
look in closets maybe pull up
floorboards if they're really aggressive
look inside cabinets and pull up carpet
they're gonna go very deep and very
thorough so the question I have is would
you ever buy a house where the home
inspection was done by looking through
the window from the outside because
that's what happens when you don't use
credentials you'll never know about
water damage you won't know about molds
you won't know about termites I know
there's a lot of reasons why people
don't use credentials but it makes you
blind to a
lot of stuff so don't skip this I say
this knowing that a lot of people don't
have a good ability to do this agents
are definitely helping but the point I
would make here is fight for this if you
have to fight for two three four years
fight for it and don't ever stop so
don't use passwords if you're doing
credentials we'll come back a little bit
to that as an alternative but you
potentially can expose a credential
that's on every single system in your
environment and now you're compromised
in many other ways yes I don't think
you're safe I ran into many situations
where I'd run a report for a manager and
it would show oh you only have 7%
systems with critical vulnerabilities
that's awesome and then I'm like let me
check my accuracy do we have credentials
on those systems no the credential
stopped working that means it's only
showing 7% because I'm blind to 90% of
the vulnerabilities on this server so
even if you think you're using
credentials don't assume you are safe
and that your data is accurate
definitely utilize agents not everything
can run an agent but a portable laptop
that is used by most of your employees
will greatly benefit from agents because
then even if they're on holiday or away
from the office they're still getting
scanned definitely utilize things like
keys inserts a lot of protocols
unfortunately won't allow this but
anywhere you can use this in place of a
password I strongly recommend it and
lastly much like do you think you're
safe you need to monitor for failures
you need to make sure that if you know
you've put credentials into a certain
part of your network and they should be
functioning that you have some kind of
metrics or dashboards that are going to
monitor for when that failure rate
suddenly increases because the technical
team made a change on the server and now
all of your credentials got disabled
still me pol quick for the audience do
you have a high level risk management or
risk acceptance process in place
very few hands so yep sorry this is a
raise your hand so again high level not
just TVM but I mean for the business
itself yes you have that in place so it
looks like about a third of the room so
follow-up question to raise your hand do
you have the authority to accept risk
for your entire business not a hand went
up short story I like to tell is that
when I used to do trainings on this I
would ask this question and one day in
one of my trainings the CIS o of the
company was in it I still ask the
question thinking it was more rhetorical
and expecting him to say I absolutely do
and instead he said heck no the people I
pushed the risk acceptance to or the
vice-president's
and senior leaders of whatever business
unit the risk lives with this is
critical because you don't want to go
above your paygrade
it's very common whenever I inherit a
new vulnerability management system when
I go to a new company that I see dozens
of exclusions and why who authorized
those what reason do they exist oh we
just got breached and it's because we
didn't know the vulnerability was there
because someone added an exception for a
reason no one knows about definitely do
not use these to silence alerts it is
very common you scan a thousand window
systems you see some minor tcp/ip
vulnerability it's more of an irritant
let's just add an exclusion for that
across the entire product that will get
you in big trouble
if you start abusing that and you don't
follow some kind of high level process
and definitely don't set your exceptions
too broadly if you've got one court or
one service on a class of servers don't
exclude the entire server class I see
that very frequently where it's like oh
well if you scan this vendors black box
product it'll crash so just simply don't
scan it at all
no figure out what's crashing it figure
out if it's a service a check and try to
narrow that down so let's definitely
leverage risk management programs large
amount of people have them if you don't
this goes back to maturity it's very
difficult to do this right when your
vulnerability management program doesn't
have a business program to plug in to
definitely automate the creation or the
process around exceptions and exclusions
ideally what you have is a business
application or system that other people
are putting risk and acceptance into and
when it's accepted by the manager
director the VP that triggers an API
call into your product that adds the
exception we don't want to be doing that
manually and then definitely review on a
cycle so a lot of people that wouldn't
even bother ever reviewing their
exceptions period let alone when I'd
walk in and inherit the product and be
like when was this added I don't know
three years ago so reporting an
ownership is kind of complicated and we
can't get into everything here but um
another quick poll who is either
received or sent a multi-thousand line
CSV report us up was it successful or
useful so bone management can be a tool
for successfully manipulating your upper
management to accomplish some goals that
your security team might have we
apologize if your upper management you
just heard that but what you have to do
is you have to translate a lot of these
useful metrics into financial risks to
the company because that's what they
care about
don't send massive lists as reports
there is absolutely nobody that that
will be useful to it does not
communicate risk or prioritization and
really it's just gonna irritate people
do not focus on severity or Vons
severity isn't a granular enough thing
to focus on and it's usually based on
CBS s scores which as we discussed
previously our static and don't take a
lot of things into account
vulnerabilities don't communicate risk
and they don't scale for remediation if
there's a hundred thousand of them don't
assume ownership of a system if you if
you're just gonna assume that because
this machine is in prod then so-and-so
owns it cuz they own everything in prod
that's not a good assumption to make
somebody's gonna own the OS and then
maybe somebody else owns the database on
there and then maybe somebody else owns
a service that's also running on there
so you have three different owners for
this one system do prioritize things you
cannot remediating that's just not
feasible um use the risk score I spoke
about before which is weighted and takes
a lot of those other things into account
to help prioritize and communicate these
priorities with other teams and
departments to try to narrow down what's
what things are more important than the
other things um scope appropriately you
can use groups and tagging inside the
products to better organize your assets
and define owners of systems and groups
of different kinds of assets and scope
your reporting with a goal in mind like
when you begin writing a report say I
want to fix this problem so I need to
report metrics that are relevant to this
problem and translate that into a risk
and match your reporting to your
business the way you define ownership
and do reporting should be matched to
the way that your organization is
organized if you're going by
Department or server class or things
like that your reporting should match
that you should also work with these
teams that you're reporting to to
determine what kind of data they want
and how they want to receive it maybe
this one developer really does actually
want a huge CSV file and for him that's
okay but you need to work with different
teams to find out what they want
so a major question when defining things
like SLA is and SLO s for vulnerability
management is asking the question are
these for patching remediation risk
acceptance that strategy and approach
will define a lot of what you do around
SLA s and s ellos the biggest point
though is it needs to be auditable I've
frequently walked into a company either
as an employer or consultant and saw
that they gave this timeline for this
thing but it really wasn't auditable so
they had the SLA is sort of in place
they were defined but they didn't really
have a good way of making sure that they
were actually being met
so as we keep saying you've heard don't
focus just on the direct vulnerabilities
we'll talk more about this in the do but
this definitely ties in to maturity a
lot of times when you're starting out
you're gonna have to focus on the
vulnerabilities you're gonna have to
just target a particular SLA for
remediation around a type of
vulnerability a severity for a
vulnerability but that really shouldn't
be the long-term goal we want to shift
to risk definitely don't pick one size
fits all you can't say that everything
that's the CBS s seven and above must be
remediated within 14 days and everything
that's the CBS s 10 is remediated in 24
hours that doesn't always scale if
you've got black box vendors that you
have to wait for patches when does your
SLA start you still have to assume and
mitigate risk so you can't hold for a
vendor patch so you have to make sure
and define these across different teams
across different product areas parts of
your network the one size fits all will
honestly just anger a lot of other
people that are being held accountable
for those SLA s and then don't focus
just on patch availability like I said
if a Cisco vulnerability comes out you
have to wait a week for them to build
something you can't just say well the
SLA starts when that patch
available because if you're approaching
this from a risk perspective the risk
starts as soon as you know that it
exists and it's there in your
environment you have to have some kind
of mitigation or plan in place so just
focusing on patch availability is very
dangerous focus on risk based on
maturity and definitely align with
business criticality your SLA SRS ellos
may not always be the same depending on
where in the environment we're talking
about again this goes back to moving
away from just static CBS s and severity
scoring and really talking about risk
and what matters based on the asset
itself and where it is what its exposure
is and everything else so automation is
a great wonderful thing that can help
every aspect of your DVM program the
main things you want to look for when
automating things are removing
administrative overhead data aggregation
and enrichment and improving the time
that it takes you to come to these
remediations don't depend on manual
processes manual processes means that
there are humans involved in humans are
finicky and get things wrong because
that's what we do and they go on
vacation or go to conferences and they
go on vacation or go to conferences or
they're out sick depending on manual
processes depends on people and it
wastes labour hours there's no reason to
have this developer spending an hour a
week doing this product doing this
process he has to do every single week
especially if he's been working here for
two years and he's been doing it for two
years
don't automate things just because that
same developer if he does something that
takes him five minutes that he does once
a week that's probably not worth
automating
don't automate monolithically and what I
mean by that is if you have a huge
process with a ton of steps and it's a
very important process don't try to
automate the process as a whole because
that does not scale and that is not
maintainable what you should do is
automate your data flows which reduces
manual interaction less humans in the
mix and it also reduces your dependence
on static lists which mom had spoke
about a little bit before static lists
are bad automation allows you to have
dynamic frequently changing lists um
good example of automating your data
flow is you pull an asset list out of
your asset management system and that
goes into your vulnerability management
product and scan zones or asset groups
or sites and then that data then goes
into results and organ organizing those
results and tagging and reporting on
those results and all of that can be
automated when you are automating things
consider the ROI of whatever you're
automating if it's that that five-minute
once a week job but it's gonna take you
two weeks to automate that that's
probably not worth your time just keep
letting them waste five minutes a week
and do automate individual tests instead
of the automating monolithically all of
those individual little pieces of that
whole huge process automate each one of
those individually and then tie them
together that is more scalable and more
maintainable and will cause you a lot
less pain in the future
now notifications and alerts are an
unfortunate part of threatened
vulnerability management and if if you
are receiving them you probably know
what I'm talking about and if you're not
you probably should be the biggest
problem with them is triaging them don't
depend on static emails if you get an
email for anything that your
vulnerability management product finds
you're gonna end up with a couple
emails that nobody's ever gonna look at
because there's a couple thousand of
them or they're on vacation
don't alert for every individual finding
and because that only exacerbates the
email problem if you're alerting on hey
there's an informational alert for some
Boehner grabbing that the product was
doing you don't need to know about that
that does not need to learn it on and
all it does is make a couple thousand
emails into a couple thousand more
emails and don't take it every alert I
have seen where people would for every
single alert that was fired out of their
vulnerability management product they
would have a separate ticket for that
alert which leads to the exact same
problem as the email problem where you
have thousands that nobody is ever gonna
touch because there are thousands of
them do automate automating saves
everything you can use your automation
to ingest all of those emails or ingest
alert data directly from your product
using the API and then once you've
ingested that data you can use things
like pattern just simple pattern
matching can often help you organize and
prioritize those alerts but if you have
the time and development skill you can
also look into things like fuzzy logic
and machine learning to help better
prioritize and score some kind of those
alerts which leads in the next point
which is prioritization prioritize your
alerts based on relevance and
criticality if you have if there's an
unauthenticated RCE
vulnerability that you have that's
probably a little more important than
upgrading java and please tune your
alerts there's no need to receive alerts
that are useless and provide no value
like informational BS alerts that you
don't care about it dress li cuts down
on all that noise before it reaches your
hopefully versioning automation now
container scanning is comparatively new
and because of that it's often neglected
or forgot about or not even considered
and there are options for it the the big
name the vulnerability management
vendors have integrations that you can
use for container scanning and there's
also some open-source container scanning
products do not assume your containers
are secure they are not magical
impregnable little boxes that you can do
whatever you want to with do not ignore
best practices it might be easier
sometimes when building your containers
to do things like this but you still
need to remember to avoid things like
embedding sensitive information in your
container image remember to drop root
privileges when you're building your
container and automating automating the
building of those images via various
tools is okay
but don't blindly trust the templates
that are given to you when you're
building these things and don't scan
like it's a server because it's not
alright don't bother with credential
network scans or agents your container
I'm getting ahead of myself do scan
regularly these are just as important as
your traditional infrastructure
sometimes moreso scan them regularly
don't do though once a quarter kind of
stuff and consider criticality some
containers are more critical than others
and should be treated as such just like
if you have production containers that
are exposed to the Internet you should
probably look at those more frequently
than random container running random
service for a developer do scan your
base images and this is where I was
starting to get ahead of myself you
should you should generally treat your
containers as immutable so scanning them
while they're running should not be
necessary if you scan the base image of
your container that should be all you
need because it should not be changed
that of course kind of assumes a high
level of maturity and mutable
infrastructure takes work to get to but
that is if you are running containers at
any kind of scale that's the goal you
should have in mind is a mutable
infrastructure so this is a fun one that
got trimmed back pretty heavily a few
people might have heard me go on web app
scanning grants before aside from
working for a fall management company I
previously worked for a another
consulting firm where I did manual
application security and so I have beefs
about some of the ways that it's
currently handled if you want the long
version of that come talk to me and
we'll also post our slides the short
version is that there's generally two
approaches to this one is using your
vulnerability management scanner and the
other one is integrating with the actual
pipeline and deployment process these
require wildly different maturity levels
but definitely have pros and cons rather
than doing do's and dont's I'm simply
breaking it down to what a TVM scan
might look like which is just you're
scanning the static web server you're
looking for XSS sqli they're super slow
they're super long this is partially
because the vulnerability management
scanner is not always the most ideal way
to scan a large website especially a
heavily dynamic website that has lots of
forms and fields and values and a big
problem is the visibility frequently
you're not doing vulnerability
management scanning for web apps until
it's already in prod or it's well past a
development lifecycle if we move towards
something like a pipeline and or
integrating with QA we can do things
like scan source code repositories do
static analysis again this is not
utilizing standard vulnerability
management tools but there is definitely
great value and
getting to this maturity level if you're
doing things like looking at your source
code you can also do things like
determine end points so of a
vulnerability management product or web
app scanner usually is just going to
look for what it can find based on a
site crawl or as if you're scanning your
source code you can find unknown end
points that are actually exposed that
might be invisible to you great thing to
do is get involved with the actual
development lifecycle hook get you don't
necessarily have to block but warn
developers in their development process
hey you're doing this thing and your
code is dangerous is using unsafe
functions it's exposing credentials or
secrets again this goes way beyond just
standard fault management web app
scanning and integrating with QA there's
a large amount of this that probably
should just live with QA there's a lot
of products out there that are
specifically built to do that so that
every time a release goes through the
pipeline QA is the group that gets all
of the warnings and notifications for
security findings and they're the ones
that are pushing that back to
development rather than just coming from
your security team so due to the sheer
amount of content we could have put in
here some of the things we had to cut
some of the things we had to scale back
like the web app scanning our intention
is to still release the full slide deck
including some of the other sections
with do's and don'ts that we were not
able to go into this is a huge topic and
there is no single way to try and
deliver as much knowledge as you can
I've done kind of one-off help for
friends before that turn into multi-day
things and in the end I usually
recommend get professional services from
whoever you're Vonn management provider
is they will be able to give you what
you really need questions comments
heckles Josh
every spring loves being down
so the cloud this is also highly
dependent on maturity because even
though the cloud is fully capable of
being treated as traditional
infrastructure you shouldn't the gold
there is similar to containers with the
end goal being immutable infrastructure
so if you're at that point and you're
that mature and you have a mutable
infrastructure then you should do the
same thing you're doing with containers
and scan the base machine images like
for AWS skin that I check the ami don't
actually check the running machine if
you're not there and you are treating
them as dynamic moving pieces then a
solid thing to do is bake your agent
into that base image bake your agent
into the ami before you spin anything up
and then as soon as it's spun up you'll
have metrics on that machine that was a
section we had to kind of scale back on
a little bit just because of time yes
you see
so and actually I apologize we should be
repeating the questions the first one
was dealing with cloud and this one is
asking a bit about are we seeing things
moved to more of a code integration and
away from just static scanning yes just
within the last probably four or five
years most of the major vendors realized
that they were very static static asset
list
static groupings and started adding
integrations for other things like DHCP
and AWS there I I have a whole other
talk I'd like to do at some point which
is basically security is a dinosaur and
a lot of immature companies are doing
vulnerability management the old way
which is the static way the non
integrated way in this case for
containers and applications scanning
those absolutely should integrate in
with the pipeline that doesn't
necessarily mean that it moves out of on
management but it raises the question is
your vulnerability management group
simply a single product or is it a
number of processes integrations life
cycles that you're having to automate
together to try and integrate with the
rest of your your company in all of
those different practices so if security
is a dinosaur we can look forward to as
extinction well in a sense yes because
you could say you know security is
everyone's concern maybe what it is is
that it's not that security goes away
but the idea of a dedicated group of
angry people that scream about security
starts blending into the entire company
and its processes and workflows so that
it shifts its focus from a group of
technical people being angry yeah
evolutionary answer yes yes very bad
okay yep miss
I've heard the argument that if you add
an agent onto a house let's say that it
increases attack surface so is it would
you do anything extra if you add an
agent on there so yeah the the the two
most common put complaints with agents
is either it uses more resources and we
have too many of those which frequently
my experience what that is
they really don't use that much more and
it's not a huge issue but as far as it
being a broader attack surface yeah most
agents tend to run as root and are not
in my opinion ideal and it's where we as
customers need to push back on our
vendors to really be getting them to
build better agents when you do
credential scanning you can choose to
use a regular non-root account but most
of the vendors support utilizing pseudo
or some other escalation but with agents
i think though all the ones I've seen
their route and there's nothing else so
I would say that is not ideal and that
is where you can fall back on credential
based scanning if you need but I think
we as a customer base need to push back
on the vendors to build us better agents
Yeah right behind you
so I'm another question related to
agents you were talking a little bit
earlier about putting agents on
containers as far as products that
you're aware of are there any that like
kind of are smart about the licensing
there and don't like add to your
licensing burden and and that kind of
stuff so this is working yeah okay we
generally recommend against agents
against agents on containers that was
for agents on cloud if
a dynamic sort of cloud environment was
the rest of the questions so with
containers I think and it depends on the
vendor that sometimes the ability to
container scan is a totally separate
license that may be exclusive of
whatever your IP count is for your
volnek you have to look into that with
your your product vendor because they're
not all the same that also plays back
into the the license model is shifting
because of container and cloud so while
I don't think the vendors have fully
figured that out yet for the future
I think they're working on it it's kind
of like with scan engines or Nessus
Kanner's they used to charge you
separately for the scanner and
eventually many of the vendors realized
we can't do that we need to be able to
allow them to have more scanners and
instead license on features or IP so I
can't say where they're gonna go with it
but yeah scanning your cloud
infrastructure of ten thousand or a
hundred thousand AWS instances if you do
have to go the agent route that'll kick
back on your license I'm kind of
confused about is putting an agent on
the cloud host doesn't necessarily get
you anything about the container does it
like that's the thing I'm confused about
it's like let's say your container has
outdated packages for example how do you
protect that from or how do you include
that in a vulnerability management
program so the to at least two of the
major vendors I know of will integrate
with your container platform by looking
at your registry where they're looking
at the images I think not the containers
and that goes back to the maturity model
and being immutable that your container
should be identical to your image so you
don't need an agent on the container
because you should scan your image and
in the cloud for AWS or GCP if you're at
that maturity
it's the same if you're not at that
maturity level you're probably putting
an agent in your ec2 instance or
whatever but the idea is that that stuff
is immutable like he said if follow-on
addition all right the questions I think
that might be it so again we'll try and
release these I'm not sure I forget this
last can have anything any way to
facilitate that sweet so we will try and
get those up as I say we put a whole
bunch of other stuff in here that we
needed to just kind of cut back on and
this is a big topic so feel free to
reach out we're more than happy to
continue this conversation and we're
open to continue to revise and improve
the talk so feedback is welcome we'd
like to still give it to a couple other
local conferences and groups around the
area thanks so much