foreign
through them
[Music]
thank you
I post good morning thank you for being
here bright and early it's an honor to
speak here at Echo party and I thank you
for having me here
so for the past few days you've learned
so many aspects of security threat
intelligence exploitation and
engineering cutting down that path I
want to spend some time discussing
another possible direction of taking a
security career through building versus
breaking and it's a little more about
how my journey and security has shaped
up
so to kick things off a brief agenda
I'll go in depth on my career journey
and how it changed my views on security
my perspectives on the definition of
security in Big versus small companies
the various events that have now
impacted the tech landscape and have
accelerated the inevitable
I'll talk about opportunities to
capitalize on to help build more secure
products and the goal through a lot of
this discussion today is to highlight
various aspects you should consider when
you're trying to make more informed
decisions on how you see yourself
growing and evolving in this particular
field
I personally really like Pokemons so
you'll see a lot of gifs throughout this
entire presentation it's also a fun
morning presentation
so to kick things off a little about me
I studied engineering where I was taught
various aspects of computer science it
gave me a very high level view of
security but not enough to have an
opinion to have a strong opinionated
thought about this field
Microsoft was my first job out of
college and it gave me perspective of
security at scale
the security at Microsoft could mean
many many many things simply because
Microsoft does everything and you build
software and service for billions of
people
from there I moved to Apple and worked
as an engineer in the security
engineering and architecture group and
then I moved uh to becoming an
engineering manager there
Apple changed the way I looked at
security and privacy I learned more
about usable security and to make a real
positive impact to your customers it
doesn't matter how secure your product
is if your customers actually don't know
how to make use of those features to
make themselves more secure so you being
incredibly talented and smart it doesn't
matter if no one knows how to do the
thing that you told them to go to
um
privacy and user trust principles are
often baked into the ground up and the
benefit of working in a big tech company
that has seen it all like Microsoft and
Apple it gave me the benefit of learning
by standing on the shoulders of giants
so often before I would make a mistake I
would have some support system that
would give me some guidance on hey you
probably consider a different approach
than going down this path because many
of us have already been down this path
As I Grew in my career I realized I
wanted to learn more about software
security adjacent Tech Stacks so trust
and privacy being them so I took a
different Adventure by joining Lyft
specifically the Privacy engineering and
the data security teams there
um and most recently I joined notion
security and Trust engineering team
notion is a smaller company a much
smaller company and it does primarily
office productivity software
so what is security at a big tech
company actually mean
um
to talk a little more about Microsoft
and Apple generally and take all of this
with companies that build software for
other engineering teams so for other
software companies
firstly I'm not a spokesperson for any
of these companies so take everything I
say as my perspective it's what I did
years ago and things have probably
changed in the Dell test and so when I
worked at the companies to where I'm
right now
um security firstly at both these
companies are defined by who their
customers are Microsoft is huge in the
Enterprise space so things pro think of
products like Azure and office 365.
apple is primarily a consumer product so
think of iPhones Mac watch those types
of devices so moving on to products then
Microsoft has many many many many
security teams you ask in Microsoft if
one security team knows the other they
probably don't and that's because they
have so many diverse products that are
shipping such different software the
type of engineering that would be
required for Windows is going to be very
very different from the type of
engineering that's going to be required
for Azure and Office 365 because your
Baseline Technologies are very different
uh this often honestly took me by
surprise because I assumed that it's one
Microsoft
but it does make sense a back-end
service or a back if it is a bug in a
back-end service it would take it would
be fixed in a matter of hours you
wouldn't even know that there was a bug
that needed to be patched because all of
a sudden there was just an update
because it's all server side you know
when Windows wants you to take a patch
and it takes a couple of days with all
Engineers on Deck to actually get it out
because it has to go through intense
testing
the next is karia so you understood what
what the types of customers are the
types of products that you need to ship
out
um
a career in Microsoft could literally
mean anything
you take any field of security and it
exists the security design where you can
think about it more proactively there's
threat modeling and response there's
threat intelligence and threat
intelligence could be detecting and
monitoring for the systems itself or
detecting and monitoring for your
customers like endpoint detection
systems or Windows Defender or whatever
you have program management you have
security feature development you have
Hardware software Solutions and then you
have Security based on if you are
developing it for Enterprise customers
versus developers versus in
customers like us
what so response and the reason I want
to call out response is a lot of my
Microsoft career was focused on this but
also because um a lot of people write
security bugs and send them to Microsoft
either for their bug Bounty programs to
get them fixed
um
threat intelligence and response teams
at Microsoft are pretty big they're
about 30 to 40 individuals at least this
was before the time when I left for all
the security researchers who regularly
submit bugs they do look at your bugs
and they do get back to you however if
you'll notice it's not it's the timing
could be very unpredictable and that's
because they get hundreds of emails
every day some of them may be real bugs
some of them not real bugs so you want
to try and front load as much
information as possible to get the most
possible to get the quickest response
but response at Microsoft could also
mean you have an engineering team you
have a program management team you have
a release management team all these
teams need to work together to help
evaluate when the bug needs to get fixed
and then either take a fix immediately
if it's a server side fix or take a fix
eventually if it actually affects
software products so Patch Tuesday and
all of that
on the flip side when I worked at Apple
response was actually a lot leaner there
was a lot more Automation in generally
in Apple's culture so we had to do as
much as we can to make the machine do
the thing for you
um it was also there were fewer security
teams at Apple and again the reason
being is because Apple has lesser
products there's not much of the
Enterprise space there right you've
you've yes compared to like the sheer
amount of things that Microsoft ships
out you've also got lesser versions of
Mac OS and iOS software you to maintain
you have like I think n minus two at the
most and at least when I worked at
Microsoft there was a time when I we had
to maintain n minus 25. so you've got 25
different variations of software so
shipping security bugs for that just
takes a lot longer
either way these are Global Tech Giants
and shipping software for billions of
people worldwide it makes sense to
generally for them to generally have
bigger security teams
security at a smaller tech company is
actually very different when you work at
a smaller company or a company who is
shipping security for a product that is
in software so think like Banks oil and
gas even like
um stores that are things that serve
restaurants your point of sale system
and all of that this Security is to
drive the business it isn't the business
um your definition of security changes
it's less about creating best-in-class
mitigations it's about building a
foundation of security to help push
defense and depth for all of your
Solutions and your most susceptible
assets
it could require your engineers to fix
very critical bugs but it could often be
as simple as implementing an identity
provider internally you need to figure
out what your company needs and then use
security as an enabler not focus on what
could be the best possible interesting
work that you could instead do
um as a smaller company you have very
targeted customers and they will tell
you exactly what they need from you to
get for you to get their business if
security becomes the ask then as a
security team you need to chip in and do
what it takes this could be getting a
sock compliance or a PCI compliance for
folks in the financial industry it could
also mean just making sure you can
attest that the assets that the company
stores in your systems is actually
secure so doing the basics that you need
to do to help Drive Revenue sometimes
that does become the security Charter
and I think it's a very meaningful
Charter because you actually move away
from being a cost center to a profit
Center
um
as your career evolves you'll realize
that working in a smaller company or
working in a company that is not
creating tech for tech will give you a
lot more breadth than depth you end up
becoming the Jack of many trades and
often very quickly they don't know who's
going to go solve this program this
problem you have some subject matter
expertise in an adjacent area so why
don't you go solve it so take advantage
and capitalize on a lot of those
opportunities
um
actually one more thing to call out here
is you are often going to be on the hot
seat of defining build versus buy from
my conversations in the last few days
I've learned a lot more about
uh how security decisions get evaluated
it is interesting and important to
consider Security Solutions that
actually foundationally help you when
you're thinking about build buses by
decisions uh most of them
can are very Point systems so take a
step back and learn about how this buy
solution can actually impact your
long-term roadmap not just the short
term one-year plan
so we we briefly discussed my career
journey and then my perspective of
working in a big versus small company
so let's move on to the observations on
how the security business is actually
still booming despite of the very
deteriorating macro climate
the first change is the pandemic it
changed the world quite a bit and the
past few years we have seen companies
make significant adjustments to
accommodate it the panel the pandemic
brought about fundamental change that
disrupted the core of how people
interact with work systems it now
happens everywhere from very from
significantly less controllable
environments remote work economic
uncertainty and an overall breakdown of
the known societal Norms has changed the
way the world operates it's a lot more
common for you to now get onto a zoom
call than an action and a real phone
call with someone
um
to be fair we were already headed down
this path
um Zoom didn't come up during the
pandemic like Google meets didn't happen
during the pandemic we already took
advantage of a lot of these VoIP
Technologies
um but the pandemic was a forcing
function to accelerate the pace of
adopting these changes and now it's our
job to help keep up with these
disruptions
so talking about the most obvious change
and how it affected security is remote
work the work the move to remote work
has accelerated the move to distributed
networking and decentralization
individual devices and accounts are the
easiest points of entries for most hacks
scaling of remote work has multiplied
Enterprise security risk and has
accelerated the move for minimal Trust
on devices it has also increased
monitoring
so organizations now need a more
scalable way of answering questions that
keep coming up regarding the identity of
an employee this is a recurring theme it
isn't anything new as a part of a
security group you often are already
doing your analysis on like is this user
who they say they are is this employee
who they say say they are
the pandemic has exacerbated all of this
is the person accessing our system
actually an employee what are the
resources we should give them if we
should give them these resources do they
have the right education in order to
know how to interface with these systems
what software is on their laptop what
additional control should we have on
that software they just went ahead and
downloaded an arbitrary Google extension
that seems kind of sketch do you have an
ability to actually control that
when they're at home and not on a work
computer what can and cannot what can
they do and what should they not do
there are lots of things that they
should not do and people have to a
certain extent broken down these
barriers when they work from home
if you finally have to take someone off
the company chart the comp if someone is
to leave your company and you have to
get someone off-boarded it isn't an easy
thing to do anymore you need to go
figure out what sensitive assets
actually live on their machine that you
don't really control anymore and how do
you get that ahead of time
so all of this traditionally falls under
corporate or Enterprise security it's an
area of security I believe most people
take for granted there are there are
plenty of software Solutions out there
and it's also the very Tech jargon heavy
space I personally learn a lot more
acronyms every day in this space or
maybe on a weekly basis I come on to
LinkedIn and there's a new blog article
about this interesting startup they're
doing something with a with a free
letter of highlighter acronym that I'm
hearing for for the first time these are
fundamentally the same Technologies over
and over again repurposed and repackaged
um the other assumption we make is that
we dismiss this area expecting the
internal I.T team to take care of it and
that's not the case because these are
the things that often lead to breaches
and it's going to be a security person
who has to answer for this not I.T
um it also should fall it it makes sense
it falls under Securities prerogative
it's your responsibility to to care
about your digital Kingdom and your
assets
so a few things that I have seen change
in the Enterprise security space as
we've moved towards remote work the
first one is endpoint protection
significantly better detection control
monitoring capabilities have uh the
pandemic has given rise to a lot of
these you have much better event
management systems than you previously
did and they help with effortless data
uh ingestion they also take data now
from very common log sources like you
have identity providers you have your if
you do MFA then you have your totp
providers you have AWS integration that
gets built in you have log normalization
as a part of it and finally they give
you a much better ability of writing
detections on it and they also give you
Baseline detections that you could just
inherit investing in a strong endpoint
protection system can actually help get
you to a more proactive path of ensuring
Enterprise security
the second one is MDM a lot of us have
worked with VPN Solutions VPN Solutions
don't really uh scale when devices start
moving to a lot more remote Focus
because often you need to now ship a
device to someone if they can't come
into your VPN network to go work from
your HQ or something of that sort so
mdms it's given the rise to mdms or
other thinner clients that help keep
sensitive devices off individual worker
devices individual sorry that keep
sensitive data of individual worker
devices altogether but also give you
better control
finally more awareness of the security
space in general I think everyone now
knows almost everyone here has been a
part of a breach as a consumer or is
aware of at least what's going on in the
larger ecosystem
more awareness about overall security
industry is the best defense in depth
because a lot of Enterprise security has
to deal with people management this
people process technology
it is all about people in this category
too
so it's not just Engineers or Security
Professionals who now have to care about
security it needs to be security
education and awareness for everyone
um and it needs to be a healthy dose of
paranoia such that if someone in an
arbitrary team who has never dealt with
that comes across a sketchy text message
saying that we need you to log into the
system they take a step back and think
twice do I really need to log into the
system or is this something that would
am I being the vector of compromise for
my company that is a sort of larger
cultural change that needs to happen
the second thing and personally this is
my most favorite is data ubiquity
data is everywhere and hence it needs to
be considered as a new endpoint and
should be at par with software IP that
needs protecting
traditionally security has always
focused on supporting systems that store
data rather than the data itself and
this will need to change security
dollars are moving towards data which
means that you not only have to create a
more you you not only have to create a
wall Garden around your data but
actually make sure the information
itself is kept in a way that will
prevent damage if compromised
there are so many opinions about data
being the new oil the new gold of the
digital economy it's now a lot of
actually new systems are also built on
data versus code so it is getting in my
opinion even more important than code
itself
and software Engineers are actually
working with data as much as they were
working with code in all honesty you'll
have a lot more people in your company
work with data than code
and it a data here doesn't necessarily
mean customer data it could also mean
analytical metadata collected to help
understand your user your customers your
user interaction with your actual system
it could be logging information on like
how often does the customer log into
your device everything that's pertaining
to audit logs about that it's also
actually audit logs of how often your
employees are logging into the system so
they're multiple there are many many
ways of looking at data
um it also has a lot of information
about monetization a lot of this
information that we collect data
collecting technically Amazon and Google
and all these other companies have made
data storage cheaper than it used to be
but it's still expensive there's a
reason why we don't just arbitrarily
delete everything because there's a lot
of good aggregated information that can
help better your products
the rise of data infrastructure data
science machine learning and data
development tool chain will likely
reshape the way we anyway write software
so if data truly is the company's most
sensitive asset how should we go about
protecting it
um in September so September 2020 not
2022 not too long ago there were
multiple companies that had announced
that they had been compromised so let's
actually talk about LastPass since I
think they were one of the few companies
where a breach actually didn't lead to
entire customer data compromise in
lastpasses case they said that they
didn't actually find any evidence of
malicious actors that accessed any
customer data or any encrypted password
vaults and this was because the
developer environment there was
physically separated from the production
environment the developer environment
did not contain any customer data or
actually any encrypted vaults and
finally LastPass employees itself did
not have access to any customers main
passwords so they essentially more or
less obfuscated this information from
employees which meant that in the case
of a compromise the amount of
information that would actually get
leaked would not dissolve customer trust
in the product as compared to a lot of
other companies where they've gotten
breached and now you have lost very
sensitive private information about
yourself and it's out there in The Ether
data security is not an easy solution to
start off with there because there are
so many different types of data you need
to have a different approach of trying
to secure them because it you cannot
take away from data usability there
wouldn't be any point of collecting data
if it wasn't usable and security cannot
stop that
so data infrastructure data platform and
data Sciences it's honestly its own
massive space of engineering discipline
you can't expect a security professional
to become an expert in that area
overnight
companies such as AWS Azure or Google
Cloud have started providing a lot of
have have always provided a lot of
storage solutions such as S3 blob cloud
storage whatever but they're also
providing a lot more security guarantees
in it than they previously have you have
Integrations with companies like data
breaks and Snowflake and then each Cloud
solution will provide you defaults that
you can go back and configure so they're
giving you the controls but they're
providing you an ability to keep
yourself secure and their infrastructure
if data is secure stored inherently has
less value it means that if it's
compromised if the for whatever reason
the data gets compromised you will have
lesser impact going down to what
LastPass did data anonymization or
pseudo-anonymization differential
privacy anonymity a lot of these sort of
privacy practices actually enable data
security and it's a way a lot of
companies are actually driving data
security
um and then finally adopting a very
similar Philosophy from endpoint
detection it doesn't matter how secure
Your solution is someone will find a
workaround and someone will try to get
access to it so in that case detection
monitoring auditing and alerting has
become critical to capture the out of
ordinary behaviors
um
you need to access two things every
access to user data should always be
audited and audit the types of queries
actually performed and make sure they're
restricted an arbitrary person of the
company should not have the ability to
Star select all records and then export
that all into like I don't know a CSV or
an Excel and then email them out so you
have an ability to build these types of
detections two forms of detections one
is under the actual data itself and then
one is actual network monitoring what is
the type of data that's leaving your
company
um
Concepts like data ownership data
stewardship are often talked about it
becomes unscalable in a large
organization because most people don't
completely understand what should be the
responsibilities of a data owner a data
generator may not be a data consumer and
may not be a data maintainer these
systems become hard to maintain in the
long run because there is no one point
of failure because multiple it's a
shared resource think of it like a park
if not everyone is responsible for
keeping your Park clean then it becomes
no one's responsibility and then a
public property to a certain extent gets
destroyed because of General lack of
empathy about keeping it clean data is
in a very similar boat it's everyone's
responsibility to make sure it's secure
but if it is insecure
it's no one's real responsibility so how
do you own up to handling an area that
could be so complicated
a data ownership system
the usefulness of a data ownership
system goes much it goes beyond security
it helps tackle questions like data
quality which should technically be
important to a company if they are
making Revenue decisions based off of
that it would be nice to ensure that
security is plugged into those
discussions so right the wave that's
already happening for a lot of quality
focused decisions
um finally a lot of these changes are
great for security but they actually
drive a lot of user trust and privacy
and privacy as we know is getting
mandated by a lot more countries than
they previously were so it's always good
to have a bit of a head start than
you've had then at least your
competitors have had
um so moving on to
um the Third change which is distributed
workloads
distributed workloads is interesting for
multiple reasons it's because it
actually reflects the constantly
changing environment that we are in
today
covet has accelerated the move to
multi-cloud so people either have
multiple Cloud environments or they're
stuck between on-prem and off-prem but
cloud computing is past the Tipping
Point in our world and we're going to
see a lot more organizations move their
applications to the cloud in the next
few years than they've historically had
because it was just too difficult to
maintain them on-prem during kobit when
you all can go to work to turn on a
server then what happens
uh most mid to large Enterprises today
use more than one cloud provider and
that's because of reliability issues
Disaster Recovery risk mitigations you
want to minimize dependencies but also
cost if you have multiple vendors you
can always put pit one against the other
to get more money right you want to have
a better contract with all of them
there are two sites of the coin with a
multi-cloud environment the good is that
most Cloud providers have very robust
security practices in all honesty much
better than what you would do for your
on-prem Solutions but they are expensive
you can lean on them to provide
infrastructure support because they give
you Baseline end-to-end encryption they
give you really good monitoring and
auditing they give you good Access
Control
the problem however with that is they're
giving you these Solutions it's what you
make do out of it how do you start
figuring out what sorts of SSO
mechanisms or role-based Access Control
mechanisms now exist you have to develop
subject matter expertise not on security
fundamentals but how security Works in
their environment how would you define
role-based access control for all of the
folks who needs to access AWS in your in
your company should people who access
production AWS have the same as staging
AWS should have the same as maybe some
sort of other logging section that you
have for your AWS store
um it also becomes a mess of fragmented
tools one thing you'll realize is you
don't have one silver security bullet
that exists you'll have multiple vendors
selling you multiple Point solutions
that in some capacity integrate with
some cloud provider how do you take all
of these arbitrary tools that you've now
deployed and make sense out of them that
also gets very very expensive you need
to now hire someone who not just
understands security but now understands
again security as it pertains to all of
these different tools
um
so my call out here would be be very
mindful when you get into your build
versus buy decisions because you're not
it doesn't make sense for you to buy a
security vendor that's let's say a
series a startup because if they go away
you have made a massive business
commitment on them providing you some
baseline protections it could lead to
you maybe losing compliance certificate
which could lead to you losing business
um so again build versus buy decisions
need to go on your technical
capabilities of actually understanding
what Solutions you're buying and being
able to recreate it in the lack of when
you don't have the ability to actually
continue servicing them and finally cost
cost it becomes very cost prohibitive so
think about how much money you're going
to be using if you deploy this in-house
think about how much money you'll be
spending year over year because it's
probably a service agreement
um another change that I've also noticed
is most services are being Rewritten to
be Cloud native that means the move to
kubernetes or other container Solutions
are going to be faster than before
containers enable speed they enable
portability but they can also create a
lot of security blind spots and they
increase your attack surface because
that's now another thing that you need
to go maintain
unpatched or misconfigured containers
are risks that you previously didn't
have to account for you now have to have
you need to have secure defaults in your
containers kubernetes offer secure
clusters but they are not on by defaults
so how do you now help your
infrastructure organization Define what
your organization risk tolerance looks
like to enable the right defaults for
all of these different infrastructure
tools that you've deployed
your security operations response team
will actually be very very important
here and now they're going to be taking
on a lot more work than they previously
have they're responsible for ensuring
that image scanners deployed to help
identify vulnerabilities in your
containers are actually kept up to date
they're taking into account third-party
dependencies vulnerability management
gets a lot more complicated so when
folks talk about moving to the cloud
because you're getting a lot of
guarantees from your provider that's the
case you are still taking a lot of
responsibility for getting it up and
running for your engineers
um
traditionally again a lot of people have
expertise doing the entire stack when a
portion of the stack is handled by
someone else how do you scale yourself
to be able to make the right risk
decision on what your gaps look like now
make image scanning and other Security
checks are part of your CI CD pipeline
your continuous integration and
deployment pipeline the sooner you do it
the better because if vulnerabilities
are actually found you're not going to
ever stop a production from happening
because you found a security build when
you are in the development of your
software so you often a lot of companies
do shift with security risk because
you're like okay it's not a critical bug
it's not immediately the attack Vector
is not immediately obvious let's just go
ahead with it and we will immediately
eventually hot fix it those are very
very expensive decisions so how do you
start front loading and catching a bunch
of these vulnerabilities ahead of time
because of the new technologies that
exist you have the ability to do it you
just need to be aware that you need to
do it now as compared to before where
you probably didn't think about it uh in
all these cases you're trying to get
security feedback as early as possible
in the development life cycle in order
to minimize the security issues from
happening eventually
so
um those were the three changes and I
spoke about briefly my career spoke
about the changes so let's talk about
takeaways what what are the things that
you could probably learn from this
conversation and I'll try to get through
this slides relatively quickly to give
back your morning
um
a lot of this is one of the things to
take away from is these changes are
happening whether you like it or not so
it's best to get on it but also try to
use this to help Define your security
career there's a lot of if you're if
you're interested in financial if you
have Financial motivations or if you
have you want to just be a subject
matter expert in your field the field
itself is changing there's a lot more
money in it than previously was so how
do you take into account a lot of these
things to make the most informed
decision
so the first thing first is take away
one security is moving to Tech and
product development than ever before
security focused on proactive Consulting
secure design pen testing response the
trends have changed and companies are
going further to not just overlay
security as this checkbox it's become a
part of development product lifecycle
and it it should be it's there's a lot
more Focus to it than it otherwise has
been but there's a lot more focus on a
pragmatic way than it has been so
previously if a bug was found somewhere
during sdlc which is software
development life cycle so somewhere
during your life cycle you could then
have a mechanism to eventually patch it
you would go talk to your engineers be
like hey could you patch this then you
would have a risk decision
and eventually it could come out like
hey maybe we should hot fix this or
maybe we shouldn't the problem with a
lot of this is it becomes very very very
expensive the the whole hero phenomena
of security can happen once or twice it
cannot happen predictably and it cannot
happen scalably so you're going to burn
a lot of trust with your internal
engineering team if you keep doing this
over and over again
security fixes can also be very
intrusive and are notorious for causing
regressions and bad builds because they
often happen in underlying layers so you
need to be a lot more thoughtful about
the types of security fixes to take if
it causes a bad build it means you have
more or less lost customer trust and you
are going to have a very difficult time
having an engineering team take your
picks after this
so everything you believe is secure is
is insecure till someone proves it right
and that's a part of our job
and agile and competitive environment
helps you figure out what your security
bugs are ahead of time
we don't have formal release management
schedules anymore because people don't
follow the waterfall model you're not
going to have a specific one week or two
week window where you can test your
product you need to go figure out what
is realistic risk management
uh firstly stack rank your bugs you are
an engineer you're a security engineer a
security program manager you have some
subject matter expertise in security you
should be comfortable enough making a
call of what your critical and high bar
is as compared to what your low and
medium bar is you can punt it over the
fence and have the engineering team
decide to fix all of it you you need to
work very closely with them to make
decisions on okay fixed critical in a
week fix high in a month maybe never fix
median because it's just not important
enough and that is your risk tolerance
help your company Define your risk
tolerance if let's say you're in the
healthcare space right and your medium
bugs could still result in healthcare
information getting leaked then maybe
that your risk tolerance should be a lot
higher and maybe your risk tolerance
should be low bugs don't get fixed not
median you can't expect someone to make
these decisions get involved with how
the product gets developed get involved
in informing what are the bugs that need
to get fixed get involved in informing
how the what your customers should
expect and what the type of security
guarantees your customers should expect
because an engineering team most likely
is not going to be provisioned enough to
be able to make those decisions for
security
the second one is great you you think
you're doing all the right stuff you're
trying to account for risk that's
beautiful uh but let's talk about a very
basic question why should an
organization care about Security will it
help them get more money will it help
them get more customers will it ensure
that your customers are not actually
leaving you it's a very jarring question
to ask at a security conference but that
has been with very organizations I've
worked with and you can't really blame
them for that everyone is in the
business of making money if security is
a cost center be very mindful of how
much cost your cost center actually
takes in in the amount of money a
company has allocated you can't you you
can't come to the drawing board and be
like security is important we've got to
fix it how much money is worth it what
is the return of investment
um so start with being very practical
and understanding who your stakeholders
are and why they care about security if
they don't care about security why
should they care about security
sometimes the right answer could be
maybe they don't care enough about
security because your customers have
historically said that they don't care
um you kind of need to make those
informed decisions you need to be able
to articulate that effectively because
you're creating the security story for
your company
constantly ask your audience
what constantly ask your audience a
question it's Precision question and
answering ask them why they should care
let's say if if a customer comes and
tells you hey I don't think I care about
security I want the cheapest solution
then ask them a bunch of pointed
questions because
sometimes maybe they expect certain
things by default just like you would
when you buy AWS or Google cloud or
whatever you expect it by default you're
not going to pay more for it because
you're like it should be bundled into
the product uh the same way is do your
customers actually expect that from your
product is that why they're not asking
you like explicit questions about that
try to minimize the amount of acronyms
you use only because that makes security
a lot more intimidating often people are
actually talking about the same thing
when you hear the concepts of zero trust
a shift left or at what's it called a
least privilege or something of that
sort it's all about uh preventing
preventing malicious people from
entering your systems identifying is the
user who they say they are if you go to
an engineering team and be like oh we
need to go Implement a zero trust model
they're going to ask you they're
probably going to ignore you because
you're spouting Tech jargon that doesn't
make sense and the barrier of and the
barrier of them to understand what you
have to say has increased as a good
security professional you need to get
your barrier really really low because
you need to be approachable security
needs to be approachable it can't be
intimidating because the more
intimidating it is honestly the less
money you're going to get in order to do
the work that you want to go do
um don't create an ivory Tower of
security checklist for your engineering
team because again you're making it
intimidating
you will be implementing solutions that
will reduce developer velocity you
should be very upfront about that and
you should be very upfront about the
cost so for example
you don't want everyone in the company
to access all your customer data you're
now going to provide it only to explicit
Engineers or they have to go through a
system of checks and balances so that
you know who has accessed what
you are taking away the concept of data
ubiquity you're taking away the fact
that multiple people can now have
multiple people can access certain
things it cannot come as a surprise the
fundamental model that I follow in
security is no surprises you need to be
as predictable and boring as possible so
people know what they're signing up for
predictability ensures scalability which
ensures more money
um more money for your business
be upfront about the cost of develop
figure out what your developer velocity
impedement is going to look like how how
much slower are you going to make
Engineers or product managers or data
science Engineers
um is it acceptable by the business if
it isn't acceptable acceptable by the
business what do you need to do so that
you can come to your Min bar of
acceptability but also security
guarantees
show how security supports the overall
business objective understand real risks
to the company change your metrics to
accommodate that it's very easy to fall
into the Trap of emulating compliance
checkbox so create a create a security
checklist that actually enables Security
in a very measurable way so to give you
an example
we fixed 10 critical bugs in the last
quarter in 30 days we prioritize fixing
only critical bugs to accept the risk
for all others due to ABC product
release what you have done with the
statement is you've explicitly called
out your risk acceptance bar you've
clearly shown why your risk acceptance
bar is to this particular limit because
we had to go prioritize shipping this
product and you have been very upfront
on the fact that this is the data of how
much we have fixed I mean you can go
beyond talking about like how many
Engineers are engineering hours and
customer risk and money and a lot of
these other things but you're trying to
be as measurable as possible with your
business and the reason you want to be
very measurable is performance
reliability they all follow the same
model as security
people assume your service is always
going to be performant right like if if
let's say uh
xyz.com is not reachable you're probably
not going to do business with that site
anymore because it doesn't have a few
milliseconds load time
um security follows a similar model if
your customers expect something from you
the business performance reliability
again specifically those two help figure
out the right sorts of metrics to talk
about why people should spend money
supporting this security should probably
learn from those businesses
finally as an industry we don't really
have a formal path to progress in our
careers and careers in security are a
relatively recent occurrence and there
are a lot more specializations people
often get exposed to domains or
subdomains of security through work
through colleagues through friends
through mentors through a lot of Discord
or other slack groups and all of that
um
I came across Marco lanchini's mind map
on various security careers and honestly
I couldn't have put it any better which
is why I put it up here there's a link
to there so please feel free to check it
out but it actually provides you a very
good perspective on the breadth of depth
of security
it also provides you a perspective about
the fact that security is not this
bubble that you actually expect it falls
under compliance it has a lot of
correlation with privacy and trust and
safety it actually has a lot of
correlation with uh services and
software development so if you look at
application security infrastructure
security uh devsecops Cloud SEC mostly
if you if you're not a good
infrastructure engineer you wouldn't
know how to write security for
infrastructure so you have fundamentally
changed the way what you would you would
you fundamentally change what security
actually means because it's now getting
subject matter expertise in different
stacks
um there are times when security can get
really hard and it's very demoralizing
knowing the fact that you are the one
making prioritization decisions for a
company's risk can also be very very
intimidating and exhausting it's the
decision fatigue you're constantly
making these sorts of trade-offs and
calls off you constantly try to convince
people why they should or shouldn't care
about these things and you often do not
have a safety net what if you make a bad
call it isn't easy but I think we're all
here for a reason right I mean it keeps
us busy it keeps us challenging no pun
intended it gives us job security
but it also gives us the joy that at the
end of the day our users Trust and
Believe in our product and we're
shipping good code and yeah thank you
for giving me this opportunity to
discuss my thoughts today morning and
thank you for being present here bright
and early on a Friday morning uh that's
it for me
[Applause]