foreign
[Music]
okay in this time
let's see hey yes
thank you
hello
everybody
is it
is the mic on
okay perfect
uh my name is Claudio Theodore rescu I
represent binary and this is my talk
blasting event driven Cornucopia with my
colleagues Andrea nigor
so what is wmi wmi stands for Windows
management instrumentation and it is
used to manage Enterprise devices both
locally and remotely
uh
various tools enterprise
software endpoint Solutions are
leveraging wmi to get performance
monitoring and device
device uh
Telemetry get gather Gathering and use
this to invoke a little bit about the
security posture of the of the device
but as we'll see through the
presentation uh this uh wmi is very
easily uh attacked and bypassed and
disabled disabling this will blind all
the Security Solutions that rely on such
Telemetry and this is very important
topic because as a security researchers
we need to know about this and also make
sure we understand the the risks that we
have by allowing this type of attacks to
go unnoticed
so a binary team myself
Claudio Toyota Esco with Andrei and Igor
unfortunately Andrea Nicor couldn't be
here but their role in in this research
was instrumental
so let's go a little bit in the agenda
of this talk so we'll talk a little bit
about the Windows management
instrumentation
about the architecture and features
touch on some of the forensics on wmi
also link the wmi and how is it used in
the firmware to do policy orchestration
then we move to the the part that is
more interesting for the attackers we'll
go and see how wmi used in the wild to
do evil introducing a wmi threat uh
threat model
a template of attack which is very very
easy very easy to implement and it
applies to most of the uh the attacks
that will uh will present today and then
we'll present for for Echo party will
present four new attacks on wmi service
data
with demos we'll switch to another type
of attack on LPC communication channels
uh and it will present a user mode
attack and a kernel mode attack plus a
demo
so let's move forward
so the architecture so wmi actually is
the windows implementation of two
standards the wbm which is a web-based
Enterprise management and cim which is
the common information model so wmi it's
available in all Windows operating
system from since the Inception and it
offers a standardized way to
consume and produce events uh as uh
using com interfaces so in short wmi
architecture consists of uh actually
Implement wmi implements the structuring
querying and transmitting of double Mi
data which is represented as wmi objects
and as part of the WM architecture we
have the providers which provide device
Telemetry
using com interfaces that implemented as
a com dlls
uh then we have the consumers that
consume those uh those uh that device
Telemetry produced by providers uh and
one of the very used
client is the Powershell that can be
used to interact with wmi both locally
and remotely next we have the uh Sim
standard consisting on of
of the query language which is wql to
filter events uh the repository the cim
repository that contains the
class definitions the namespace
definition as well as persistent wmi
objects and then we have the move format
which is an object oriented uh language
to be to be able to extend to specify WM
artifacts to be able to extend the
standard and uh to remotely connect and
transmit the
W transmitter receive wmi data uh winner
win RM or decom can be leveraged and
last but not the list is the wmi service
which is implemented as a as we see host
the service dll in the net svcs group
called winmgmt
so wmi providers as we uh as we I
mentioned they are implemented as com
dlls another each com interface it's
identified by a class ID with uh the
information related to to the com dll
into the registry uh and as you can see
there are more than four thousand even
four thousand wmi providers in Windows
11 covering a lot of device components
such as the ones in the in the table
then one of the benefits of double Mi is
the ability to act on events that cover
nearly any uh any operating system event
another great feature of of wmi is the
ability to register permanent event
subscriptions that survive reboots which
is uh
something that is used in in the Wild by
attackers to obtain persistence on the
device there are two types of events
intrinsic events and extrinsic events
I'll not go into detail so I leave this
definition as a reference
wmi filters it's an instance of the
underscore underscore double event uh
double my event filter is an instance of
the underscore underscore event filter
uh standard class uh that specify which
um
which event should be uh sent to the
bound consumer
so the the main uh the main class
properties for an event filter are event
namespace the namespace where it
operates the query language mostly wql
and the query itself that specifies
which which are the events and when
should they should be uh when should
they should be sent to the bound
consumer and uh a simple example of the
syntax of the wql it's very very close
to SQL queries and two examples one for
uh for a filter that for a intrinsic
events that
triggers whenever notepad exe is
launched and the second is an example of
a filter for extrinsic events that
detects uh
detects persistence via the Run registry
value
next
so w my consumers
we specify
they are linked to the event filters and
what they do they they perform the
action whenever the filter is has
triggered and in the standard cim
standard they are defined five standard
event consumers
to do basic things like save to a log
run command lines or scripts then send
notifications and we mentioned about
persistent event
registration and how it's implemented
create a filter
to specify what is the field the event
you you want to trigger on
create a consumer to specify the action
that you need to take when a filter has
triggered and then bind them together in
a instance of filter to Consumer binding
perfect let's go to forensics now
so WM repository or cim repository you
can use it you can use both terms the
location is found in the registry and
consists of three types of files
index BTR objects that data and mapping
that map in the in this repository I
mentioned before but uh it was
mentioning again
the class definitions the namespace
definitions with their qualifiers and
properties as well as persistent objects
are stored and it's important to be able
to parse this because there is a lot of
information
that you can use from there one of them
being the the permanent uh event
subscription
which attackers can use it as a way to
persist
so yeah as part of flair team I reverse
the the format of the of the
um cim repository and wrote some tools
to forensically parse this uh this
database with my good friends uh Willie
Valentin and Matt Graber
the links are in there so let's go a
little bit into some details about the
forensics so I said there are three
types of files index BTR mapping that
map on object that data so index BTR is
a B3 implementation that consists of
search strings
so in order to
Parts a certain uh to to find a certain
the data for a certain instant of a
certain object you have to first uh
create the search
string which is created by uh by
concatenating the identifier for the
namespace the clock the identifier for
the class and the identifier for the for
the instance uh as a hint uh the index
identifier is just the hash of the name
of the class namespace and the instance
itself
using that search string the B3 is
searched on the the record for the in
for the for the index from the index is
identified uh first there are two
numbers three numbers in there the first
one is The Logical number of the actual
data in object that data for the for the
particular instance the second one is
the record ID and the third one is the
size
next uh mapping the map is used because
the logical page number needs to be
translated into its physical
correspondent so mapping map for that
reason consists of uh two d words array
one for the object that data and one for
the index.btr that contains this
translation mapping so the The Logical
page number actually represents the
index in the array and the value of that
index is the physical number physical
page number so now that we have the
physical page number we can go in the
object date that data get the offset of
the page because the page has a certain
size
now we have the page offset we iterate
through the page through the record in
that page to identify the the record
would identifier from the index record
once we find it we are we validate that
they have the same size and once the
same size is validated then we have our
record and then we can we can parse the
uh parse the wmi object properties
next uh the same thing applies for the
parsing the index BTR because uh the
pointers to the next because I I said
it's it's a B3 the pointer to the next
uh
nodes in the in the B3 are actually
specified as logical page numbers
so with this in mind knowing how to
parse the database looking into a on a
Lenovo system
um into the root that wmi namespace we
have a list of functions that starts
with the Lenovo underscore prefix and if
we look there are some
classes with very distinctive names
such as Lenovo biosetting Lenovo set bio
setting Lenovo set BIOS password if we
look at the definition of the set Lenovo
bio setting on the right we see that it
has four properties and one which picks
our attention is the current setting
property
looking into the database for persistent
objects
of this type
leads to empty results which means
these are not persistent objects these
are the dynamic objects that are
generated on a fly by a wmi provider
that is implemented by the vendor by
Lenovo
so for that we can switch to Powershell
use Powershell to actually get the
non-empty instances of the wmi current
Uh current setting that W my BIOS
setting current setting property
so this is
one of such instance and if we go a
little bit magnifying on it we see that
there's some some bios related settings
such as uh trusted text trusted
execution uh bios update and the TPM
type type
settings so which means
we can alter this from the user land
I mentioned the Lenovo underscore set
bios setting that's exactly the class
that can be used to alter these
functions these settings
so
in short
Lenovo provided the interface below the
operating system in the firmware so that
the the provider the the Lenovo provider
the wmi provider can talk to to be able
to read and alter this these settings
so
from the management
perspective or for setting uh easily
setting the BIOS policy orchestration
this is great but uh
exposing such functionality in the user
land
it's a little bit tricky so and this is
and this is why
so in September 2022
a Lenovo vulnerab advisory has been
issued
and we have an update that has two
um CVS that Identify two vulnerabilities
in the SMI Implement SMI handle
implementation of that interface below
the operating system that the W my
provider is leveraging
so one it's uh it's a buffer overflow
and the other one is a information
leakage and if you notice there the SMI
it's set bios pass or smihandler so this
is the Handler that provides the
implementation
which the
Lenovo underscore set BIOS password
class instance is operating via the
win32 provider the provider that Lenovo
provide
so
this is one reason to pay attention to
this type of things and
it's good to have usability it's good to
be to to be able to easily manage your
your Enterprise but understand the risk
of doing that
another class 132 bios is part of the
standard you can get basic information
about the system
so you can get information about who is
your manufacturer of the device uh the
serial number and then the the bias
version
so double am I used by both Defenders
and attackers and because it offers a
great visibility at the device level to
a lot of endpoint Solutions but it all
it provides also a great living of the
land infrastructure to execute malicious
attacks and this is a list of uh
comprehensive lists of ways how to use
wmi to do evil but to do it better it's
just was I thought that it's much easier
to give you an example
so
this is actually
close to something that happened in the
in the wild remember that the fire I
named this uh C daddy the uh the malware
so pretty much it was a persistence via
wmi
the trigger was supposed to execute
and execute the the bound consumer
between uh 240 seconds to 300 seconds
after the system power up
and what was executed so it was executed
the Powershell command with an encoded
um
command
and after decoding it
it
invoke it was executing invoke
expression
by executing the script that is stored
in the description
property of the option class
going forward
we have the evil class double my evil
class in the in the cimv2 namespace
which has two string
properties name and description
description is the one that contains the
script that is run through the consumer
and looking a little bit over the the
script we just see that it extracts the
second stage from the name
base64 decoded store it to a to a file
location in the in the configuration so
this is a c Windows 6 wealth 64 UAV tray
app.exe and then launch it
so we saw that we have persistence data
storage through the wmic option class
and then execution
it's a full cycle
so now let's go in the into the meat of
the discussion the thread model so the
wmi thread model that we proposed
consists of several several items the
windows windows service communicating
with uh
providers and and clients via alpc ports
Advanced LPC ports then we have the wmi
files on on disk the con the
configuration in the registry and also
the wmi data in the in the address space
of Windows service
So based on that we have
bucketed these attacks into five uh big
groups the first one is Attack on the
inside wmi inside the data in the the
text on the data inside the wmi service
process the next is the attacks on wmi
uh alpc Community connections third is
the one on files and registry
information
fourth and fifth is the sandboxing of w
mice service both using a user
mode attack and a kernel mode attack
as black hat I presented several attacks
on on the first and last uh three
buckets
then a labscon I touched on
more attacks of data inside the wmi
process and against the wmi pipe
connections
and for Echo party I'll go further into
into the research and present four
new attacks on data inside the double my
process and uh and to uh one more attack
on the pipe connections
so why those attacks are so dangerous is
because these attacks are in there since
the Inception since the first version of
the wmi
wmi has not been created and the wmi
service is not has not been created with
Security First in mind and the double my
service is not considered a critical
critical app
and the problem is like nobody can
detect those uh those uh alterations of
the address space of Windows service 32
there are no security alerts
another thing is
these attacks are executed from the user
land with the same privileges as the wmi
service
and uh
one of the most important one why is
this so dangerous because this is not
viewed
as a vulnerability this these are
architectural flaws
wmi has not been implemented
to be used in security products wmi had
the only purpose of wmi is just to offer
visibility into the device telemetry
so let me present a template on
attacking wmi data so
pretty much there is a wmidll that is
loaded into the pros address space of
wmi service
usually you have a global flag that is
initialized to its default value in the
init function it is set to the the value
that you need to be in each initialized
to
and when a new wmi connection request or
for adding a new filter or the wmi event
some dispatch routine is called
the global flag is checked if it has the
right value
then
the the event is processed and success
is returned if not then the event is
dropped and then another a certain error
code is returned so an attacker can
find the address of the global flag
patch that flag
so that in the dispatch the error branch
is taken
is returned very simple
way of attacking it
so this is the list of
Flags available in these dlls that are
loaded into the double my process
address space
we presented this six at the blackhead
the next two at labscon
and the following four
will be presenting details today and
show some demos on how to
um
how to attack wmi and blinded
so let's start with the first first one
it's the a pointer to EAC route member
of the city repository uh function C
repository class in wbm core
so as you can see one of the LL wmr core
dll is loaded it is set to null
the pointer is set to null in the init
it is set to the output parameter from
the logon function
and in the shutdown it is released and
set to back to the to zero
and then when a new wmi connection comes
in
we have this uh
call stack and the last one is open yes
ESS
function which will take a look
it's a simple check to save the the
pointer is not null
if it's not null then it's return no
error if it's null it means it returns a
critical error so a clear attack find
the address of the pesc route
set the value to zero in the address so
that open escns
takes the error branch and returns
critical error so
what's happening
after the attack new wmi clients cannot
be started
and the error is always wmae critical
error
so now let's see the first
demo
so we have the latest windows 11.
WM test is a tool that you can use to
interrogate wmi
so right now we're getting the instances
of wm32 processes and their handles
and we're running our attacker app
and then just run this attack that I
described
and you can see there we found the
address of the ESC root we set it to
zero
and then we're trying to run
again wanna test and we have the error
critical error exactly as described
next the P ARB
same same template this is again a
pointer in the cwmi arbitrator class
in the initialize function function
The Constructor is called and then set
set that to uh so this is not c c
language it's it's it's just uh a pseudo
code
from the decompilation
so so we set in the by by calling the
Constructor in initialize class then in
the shutdown it is released and set to
null back
the same thing when a new connection
comes
we have this
call stack the last two the universal
collect which connect which calls the
create instance if we look at them
going backwards in the create instance
the uh the pointer is checked if it's
not set which is when which means when
it's null it returns zero going up
into the universal collect instance is
zero then it's going and returning out
of memory error same thing
new clients cannot connect to to the
service and then
the the current clients
still
can receive events
but the targeted uh the target you want
cannot
next
demo
so now we are getting the running
services
everything goes fine in the latest
version we're running our attacker app
and then go over this
PR disable again where I find it in
memory and set that pointer to zero
and let's see what
happens now
we'll get out of memory error
foreign
flag offline in the CD wbam install
object
so when the dll is loaded
it's set to false
there is a function
mem there is a member method in the CBM
cwm install object to set that flag to
the uh based on the input
when a new double Michael connection
comes in we have this call stack and the
last one is go get class
object if we look at it
very simple one just check if it's not
set
if it if you are not offline then you go
and do some processing if it's if you
are offline
then send this
wwbam if failed genetic error so
the attack is obvious find the address
of MB offline and set it to true
and uh the results are presented same
same results
previous running wmi clients continue
receiving
new clients cannot
connect to the wmi service
next one
you can start using the
wbm tester app
running the our attacker app
finding the address of MB offline
and setting it to true
and as expected
we get the genetic failure
next attack it's the global value
gtls context
in the when this in the initialize
function when wbam ESS
uh is is uh loaded into the address
space of wmi service this function is
called tlsr log
is set into into into this uh
the word file d word and represents the
index to the TLs for the thread for the
current thread uh
if it's not if it's -1 then there is a
failure in the destructor uh the TLs
free is used to um
to free the
the TLs storage
so one of the new wmi callback
request to to be installed comes in we
have this uh call stack and then let's
focus on the last three uh
functions in the AP in in the in that
list the last one it's it's the the C
implementation uh C plus plus
implementation to the TLs so it's a
wrapper around the TLs apis so as you
can see that get actually calls the the
get value TLS get value API uh when it's
if if the the index is uh the global
index is uh equal with -1 which means
it's not set then uh zero is returned
and then going backwards to the color
function in the get current ESS thread
object
the the value of the object returned
from the get function is checked if it's
not zero then additional processing is
happening v0 it's returned to the caller
the prepared current ESS thread object
so when it's if it's zero
if it's not if it's not zero then it's
doing some more processing if it's zero
we get the uh out of memory error again
so let's move
to yet another demo
so we also wrote Our
application to receive events
so we are getting every uh launch up
launch process and display to the com to
the command prompt
and then you can see we have Notepad
and I must paint processes logged
and we're running our
attacker app
found a global
the address for the global
TLS context and then change it to -1
and now you cannot install a callback
anymore
next
now we're going into attacks on wmi
against the alpc channels
so the user mode
so this is describing the the
communication on llpc channels so uh
there is another PC channels between the
service exe and the uh wind energy
service the the wmi service that
connection connection uh it's a it's a
name connection uh Port called a net SVC
and then the the wmi service
communicates with the with the wmi uh
clients via the same type of alp6
channels the only difference it's the
the connection Port is different it's
RPC control backslash OS star so it
starts with all star all a prefix so
the events are exchanged between
providers and clients via these alpc
channels
so a simple attack first we can attack
the client the client handle on the WWI
client side
which means the targeted client
cannot communicate anymore with the
service so you cannot receive events
anymore
the client can reestablish the
connection or relaunch itself but the
attacking attacking app can act as a
watchdog and close the that handle on
the clan side every time
same with that
can be applied from the
server side
so instead of closing the the
client-side handle of the alpc port we
closing the servers server LPC Port
handle which is in the uh wmi service so
the same attack but now
no client can connect to the wmi service
then the only thing uh it can be done
is just to restart the wmi service so
that new connections can start but again
the uh attacker app can act as a
watchdog watch these handles and then
close them whenever they become
available
and uh
now moving to the kernel mode so we have
uh kind of the same on the on the user
user space same same approach
um and we have an app application
attacker application
on the Kernel side we have the alpc port
kernel structures
which uh through the owner process know
the e-process of the client that to
which this alpc port belongs to
so an attack
is just the attacker app installs a a
driver
that uh
through the owner process
you can pinpoint the targeted
double my client through the e-process
and the attack consists of zeroing out
the completion port
so the wmi consumer stops receiving
new events
so let's see and
demo on this this is the last demo
again windows 11.
latest version
we launched the
client W my client
to receive events
and show that WM test has been launched
by running the attacker app
and then disable the server side
alpc port
so as you can see no logging into the
so the client doesn't receive any events
anymore
new clients
you cannot connect to the
wmi service to receive events
so this is the error
you cannot establish a remote procedure
call
so now a conclusion
the whole talk the purpose of the talk
was just to raise awareness
so people that or or companies that are
using wmi as a sole source
for getting device Telemetry are aware
of these limitations and how easy is to
attack uh wmi
and the thing is that
15 to 20 methods of disabling
wmi that I presented
none of them issue any security alerts
and most of them are just as you saw
based on a template like one bit change
attack
and this is because there is an
architectural decision that was made
long time ago about wmi
only the purpose of wmi was to just be
used for the device Telemetry not to be
not to offer information
to uh
this decision making information to to
uh security uh endpoint Solutions
so as a conclusion
use this Telemetry but make sure that it
the the wmi has not been tampered with
and another conclusion is just
this all the attacks that I I presented
can start from the firmware which is a
big plan a big blind spot for the
industry
thank you very much
[Applause]
no questions
ah okay come
can you please talk a bit about which
type of thread actors are using this
type of techniques
uh threat actors you mean yeah
um we didn't see anything in the wild
like from from the from the things that
we presented we didn't see anything in
the wild yet
uh
there's some hints so actually to get
back uh backtrack a bit
we've started with our research with etw
first and present ways how to disable
edw and that etw is more mostly used by
you know the Windows Defender and other
endpoint solutions to actually get
threat threat intelligence through
through their sessions so
we notice something related to the the
talk that we had last year in in uh
black at Europe
back to your question we didn't see any
uh any attacks on wmi yet
thank you
more questions
no
okay
thank you very much again
[Applause]