We welcome Diego with a big round of applause [Applause] Well, now I was watching the nice video to see if something else good happened.  At home the talks are a source of pride to be present here My name is Diego Freijo I work as a security office in April and every so often we do pentesting and from time to time we do some research projects like what we are going to show you here  What we were talking about is what I'm going to tell you about, what we've been working on is ways to defend yourself against phishing attacks from websites and well I'm going to tell you so briefly But you haven't entered sleep mode let's go to sleep  That's right, briefly, who am I, security office in Ambil, as I told you, I used to be a web developer and I'm still a web developer, I used to be  game developer and I am a militant of the organized mind because I think it is the best side taste that exists well what do we talk about when we talk about fishing what is the problem we face with what is fishing from websites not because we have fishing for  phone by mail etc. We are only going to talk about websites here. You will have happened that a relative at some point a friend told you guys that you understand a little bit of this about security computers Look at this I clicked on a link and it sent me to this form that is  the Gmail form so you can see it but it shouldn't be something strange I suspect of looking at some bad guy wanting to do bad things to me no Usually you use those concepts as good security connoisseurs what are you going to do are you going to approach the form are you going to  say Well I see that this is a Gmail form, everything is fine But they know that the domain may not be from Gmail or Google, what do they do? So they approach  they look at what the domain is, they see that the domain is google.com, as in this case of the formaler that they are seeing and they say, well, everything is perfect, I know that Google is one of those that controls Gmail, so this must be a Gmail trainer or is it  perfect Now what happens if instead they see The domain I swear I'm the dotcom I suspect they're going to say maybe they're trying to steal the odd password from me So they're not going to give you the username and password so happily There you go  Now, how can we automate this process? Because these relatives may not always have you available to ask these questions and we also admit later, maybe one day they catch us off guard and fit us a login, they break our password because we had a bad day and  We didn't realize that well he was talking to I swear I'm gmail.com to start seeing how to automate it let's think about this flow that one did in the head and  This is what we told him that he was just briefly telling us what one processes in one's head so that later we can translate this into the automation that we do, not starting from the top left, one looks at the form and says I recognize this site, that is, I recognize it, it is  I know I know what it is or it's the first time I've seen this site if I don't recognize it this site I don't know what it is I assume that everything is fine on the bottom left because well It's the first time I'm entering this site if the  The first time I'm entering there's nothing that can be stolen from me because I don't have a user I don't have I don't have anything I'm new here I'm a guest So if I don't recognize the site Nothing happens now the issue is what if I do recognize it as the case of  Gmail and I see that the domain belongs to the site we go to the right I say everything is fine also like what happened at the beginning I am in gmail it is google.com everything cool but if the domain does not belong to the site there it is  Yes we are in the red case of being caught Or at least we suspect that they are asking you and I don't think they will happily give this guy the password pay attention to these two little squares, both green and red because These are the three results of the Analysis  What are they going to do? Not what they say to the family member? They can tell him. I assume that everything is fine or everything is fine or everything is bad.  tell us now how we recognize the site the first step How we recognize that a site is a site that Gmail Gmail for example not the first thing that one can think is good Look at the html I already have a database of I say Well Gmail I already know what the  html from Gmail I see if I swear I'm gmail.com it has the same html I compare and see Ah It's the same html it must be a fake site that is posing as Gmail not the issue that they are beginning to see how to implement this they are going to  realize that it falls off quite quickly because it is very easy to obfuscate an html so that it is completely different, seeing only the text, let's say, but for the user, for the human who looks at the site, it looks Exactly the same, different libraries cannot be used, different libraries can be used  javascript can be used different variations in the gift of html, that is, it is easy to skip this, there is also a fundamental issue that the fishing attack is an attack on human beings, the attack is based on what a human sees and if  We are analyzing the html html Humans don't see it, usually only browsers see it. So it would be nice to be able to do a recognition that adjusts to what a human being recognizes, so we say, well, let's compare the images, we'll capture the screen of the  forms and we can compare the photos, the screenshots, the png, whatever we have and based on that we see Good to This photo is very similar and  This form in this game is very similar to the Gmail post form, it must be that they are trying to pass themselves off as Gmail Now there is a problem that if you change a single pixel, the image will no longer matter to you and it will jump like that  It is another site Although in reality a human being is not going to notice when a Pixel changes nothing else and when a Pixel can change. For example if the language changes, it will happen to you, it should happen to you that from time to time you enter Gmail in English  or in Spanish, according to their taste, they changed the regional configuration or Google just wanted to change a little button in a place, some margin, etc. and one as a human does not realize these useful changes, but if you buy images Pixel by Pixel, yes, the comparison will  be pixel to pixel and it's going to fail and no you're never going to have a comparison a post recognition you're never going to be able to detect that one site is impersonating another so we were thinking about this and the so  The solution that we came up with is to use perfectly the hashin, the hashes, perceptual algorithms, I think the translation in Spanish is a very good explanation that I found by Diego Esaya in a Taringa blog that was using it, which is a very silly algorithm but it works very well.  and it is very fast it is not very demanding for the cpu what you do is take a photo as they have on the left Adobe take any photo not and they take a lot of quality, the second step is to take quality, reduce it to a very low resolution like  In this case, 16 by 16 pixels, if you get more detail, that is, you pass it to black and white so that each pixel has only one byte, it is a value of 0.55 and then you normalize it even more, making the values ​​greater than 128 be  a 1 the low ones are a zero And so you will have a matrix of one sincere as you have on the right Yes then simply It is a representation where there is a one is where there was a color m  stronger and a being where there is a less strong color basically now that this algorithm is so beautiful Beyond that, as you can imagine, it can be implanted with a pair of shorts And a little bit of operations massage bit what is good about it is that yes  the image changes a little, it will change a pixel and probably the signature will be exactly the same because if a pixel changes its color value a little bit, like here we are also comparing very roughly the final signature will be the same. So what does it mean?  This is that I can have two very similar images even if they are not exactly the same but with the signature it will be the same so if I compare signatures I will be comparing to see if two images are similar even if they are not exactly the same now Very good We can get a signature  image here to be able to recognize to see if it is a fishing attack or not and what we do with that signature the first one that one can think of is good to send a  central server a kind of virus database as it could be but centralized from some server that she says Well gmail.com for example is the Gmail form has this signature So when someone wants to see if they are getting caught they send the signature to the server  Google wherever it's hosted and it says Che is signing the braid the database this signature Which domain does it belong to or should it belong to but we didn't like this idea because it's unfriendly to privacy.  it can be quite sensitive information because it is basically a record of all the sites you visit and the information that appears there Although it is encrypted It would be nice if that never leaves your machine do not send it to any central server so we said good How can we do a similar solution  but have more privacy and we said it Well we've been doing it for decades ssh did it decades ago and  it works so why don't we do the same ssh as you already know When you connect to an IP it checks if it already has a signature of the certificate that the server sends it looks like IP and if it doesn't they save it the database ASSUME that everything is there  well the first time and then the next time you enter the same site Sorry to the same server to the same IP verify Che the signature is the same that I have the database if it is the same everything is fine if it is not the same it is that it is  something bad happening Here is someone in the middle making a mess so we said great we can do something similar to ssh but with the signatures of the images that we are taking from each form And finally all this that I am telling you we said Good and how can we automate it and  let's make a browser extension to see what comes out and well it came out in case I wouldn't be presenting it here it's a pretty small simple extension But at least it convinced me that this can be done with the tests  As I did, I hope to start with you, there are also mainly two parts, as you will see, on the one hand is that little button And where you open and the list with your databases appears, that is, it tells you for each domain that you have the signatures of the images that you have  saved in that domain you can also clean the database And by chance you need to do it and then you have three possible notifications simply as notifications from the operating system because it was the easiest thing to do in any other way but well there are the three notifications with the three results  What can happen that we were talking about before, which is when there is a new domain when you have already visited it or when it seems that they are signing you up So we come to the demo so that they believe that this is true here we have the extension the database is empty  You'll see that we're in Gmail, I'm going to refresh the page. You'll see that the screen blinked. Now we're going to talk on the phone.  what did that blink do And if we see in the notifications it will tell you another old one it will tell you a new domain was added to the database Yes, that is, it is the first case of I do not recognize this site So I assume that everything is fine and  if we come here now we will see that the signature of accounts.google is already there yes I mean I already registered it So if I refresh this site now another notification will appear But it will say this domain you have already visited it you have been Here it is all  well nothing happens and the signature well it didn't change compared against that signature Now what if I go to visit I swear I'm gmail.com and we see that it's exactly the same form I refresh the screen and it's going to throw me a notification that says Oops this  It looks like Fiji I have a similar signature in the database for The domain I swear I'm Gmail that actually belongs to accounts.google.com Yes, I mean, it showed you that these two forms this form looks a lot like Gmail's but in  real  ity you're not in gmail So be careful don't put passwords right So we're going to go into detail what it's doing inside on each page it does these five steps So we're going to go into detail so you don't need to look at them  now first shrink the window that what I was saying about the blinking to this yes because small the window this was the biggest technical implementation problem I had you know browsers have this problem that they don't like to always have the same size no and what do they  Those who design websites like to make them responsive to make them flow according to the size of the true window and it is a problem because imagine we are comparing images and look at these two it is the same site look I am in the same browser in the same site everything Exactly the same but  the images are very different And it is more so in the case where the screen is maximized I have some giant white margins that do not add information and have  This makes me noise, that is, I am leaving very little space in the screenshot that I am taking. I am leaving very little space. What matters to me is the form that is where they can file me, no white margins, there are many forms that have white margins along  On the sides there are many solutions that we thought of with this, the one that seemed easiest to me to do the proof of concept and make it work is to reduce the window here with the browser to 360 by 640 because the guys is solving first because it was a super arbitrary decision, the truth is that  I would like to lie to them and tell them that there was a rigorous scientific analysis but there was not, it just worked I tried it I said ok This is like the lowest denominator let's not say good This is also designed to work on devices a tiny tiny mobile device that can have this resolution  well ready the least common denominator and it works notice that when I was a boy  The window is so small, in the case of Gmail, I only have what interests me, there are no white margins, there is the information from Gmail, period, I tried this in a couple of other well-known login sites such as Instagram, Linkedin, etc., etc. and more or less.  always have the same result. I mean, I focused a lot on Google because it's well known, but more or less I tried it elsewhere. Let's see if it worked and it did work. There are other solutions that occurred to me that you can see on the blog. I wrote a blog for Android  then I leave the link at the end of the talk where they will be able to see the other solutions such as injected javascript to open it on an iPhone and things like that but when they start to see that way they will see that there are cors problems and well others  details that are irrelevant if you want to find out more later come talk to me with pleasure I'll tell you everything I'm doing well once I check the screen  I already have it in a resolution that works for me I have to capture it now and for that I use the browser iPad the browser footer is the one that firefox gives you Chrome When you make a browser extension it's quite simple as you can see you put capture me the Tab gives you a  String in base 64 that's an image period No, there isn't much more secret there, then I calculate the signature and as a good javascript development you can imagine that I didn't start programming the algorithm from scratch with my own hands, but I went to npm and said Che exists  a fish one of these algorithms exists it works perfectly I sent it npm install it came in it works perfectly this library that I used you will see that it supports several types of hashin algorithms there is not only one variation what I showed you was a simplification but you have from Hash to hashtag  W of Hash this use of Hash is one of the most performant again They are implementation details are not very relevant but to keep in mind the calculation of d  e the signature is quite silly it returns a String with ones and zeros again here There is not much to turn around in the fourth step verified the signature This is interesting when one verifies The Signature what it uses is the haming distance is this let's see  Said Simply, what you want to do is subtract habit bit from the two signatures Yes and see how many bits there are differences in, that's what Poza does with only one short, it's quite simple and that's the Instant, it's the subtraction of the two signatures Yes, that is, it's  How far is one image from the other and when one usually uses these algorithms what many use is the concept of hamil tolerance the haming tolerance which is good up to how many bits of difference will I tolerate between one image and another to say yes  yes there are two three videos difference but they look alike I was testing with some values ​​if I put less than 10 I started to see that there were many false negatives if I put more than 10 I started to give many false positives I found that 10 and  It's a good balance in the most again not very rigorous that says by hand in 5 or 10 known sites so good this this hamil tolerance works but it could be interesting to review other hamil tolerance well finally notified the user I put him back to the diagram with  the variations I put it back with The variations we were seeing look if I assume that everything is fine it will throw you there is a new domain if they are following you it will tell you this looks like Fiji and if everything is fine they tell you you were here all calm  Nothing happens Yes so again these are the five steps that he does in each refresh in each refresh of the page conclusions So here we come with this we found a solution So that can be easily implemented in a browser to detect attacks on sites that  they are alike they don't need to be exactly the same again because we are the attacker is trying to trick human eyes that don't recognize  Pixel for Pixel perfection they recognize an image as a whole it's 100% private in the sense that nothing leaves the machine my database It's there where you were viewing it locally in the browser and it never goes anywhere no no leaked  nothing I did not choose anything I do not consult anything it works on sites without public access This seems to me something very interesting imagine that in many companies there is an intranet certain some internal application that you develop internally or that you need to access through a VPN etc. In those sites you could not  trust a company like Google to scan these sites and tell you if they are catching you not because it is just something internal Google any other public provider does not have access to those sites So we think it is great that you are only using the information you have  you in your browser based on the sites that you can Browse from your credentials your access to networks etc.  And finally, it is efficient to use the phone, as I was saying, the calculation of the signature is quite simple. Even in javascript, which is not one of the most performant languages, it works very quickly, so it can be easily used on any phone or device that is not just a  computer future work improve the problem of checking the window the most important thing is quite annoying if you start browsing all the time it is annoying it breaks the Flow the flow of use can also be made to only run forms with passwords this so that if by  You are bothering the user for some reason. Also, say Well, I'm going to bother you only when I see a password field because that's where I'm interested, if you're looking at a site where they don't ask for information, why are we going to be checking if they are  Fichadon can not improve the notifications the report so that only the notifications do not appear is  as on the side try others hamil tolerate to know if for some sites you need more tolerance less tolerance when comparing the signatures and then there is another problem that I was thinking is what happens if you have a stained database I call it stained imagine that instead of visiting  first to Gmail post to the real Gmail he visited I swear I'm gmail.com he's going to say Ah well I don't think I know him so I keep the signature and I assume this is the post and then when you go to Gmail I'll say no  No, this Gmail is they're messing with you because you really wanted to access I swear I'm gmail.com and no, you didn't get confused, you have the other way around So you have the database stained with the fishing attack as it is the real site when in reality  It's not. I don't think it's a very important problem because, well, you're going to realize, you're going to say, it's telling me that here is a Google point, Gómez fishing, it's not, but hey, it's something interesting like p  To think about it I leave you a couple of resources first the repository is in github in the ambil secure account you can download this demo you can run it they should give everything perfect I leave you the article with details it is in the ambil block there is also my personal blog Now  I put the address you can read I began to write a lot in English of all these problems that I found the solutions that I proposed to not check the window etc. etc. and there is a very interesting discussion on the Internet that I like because people were interested I received good reviews  and bad I liked it because it means that people were interested in putting criticism A pasta in Red it is not difficult for them to make you make bad criticism But they did it anyway, they were taken over and were constructive for example there is one that I liked the most  What does it say, why make so much trouble if you have a password manager already directly embedded in the normal El Paso browser, I will already  enter the password when it is in a posta domain and it will not include it when you are not in a domain as I swear to you.com no and I say it is true you are right but I do not like to use it to play in the Suzuki pass browser for example  and well, the truth remains for much more debate So it was interesting So that's all I leave here my Twitter linkedin my email my blog you will see that I am Diego in all things everywhere send me emails send me tweets send me whatever you want Ask me if  They see me in the corridors, they want to ask me questions, come and consult, I'm going to talk and I'm not going to let it go and I'm going to keep talking to them
until they get tired. So
you can come ask a question
and I think we have time to  one or two
questions true if anyone has any
questions regarding the talk
you can raise your hand or ask into the
microphone in the middle
if no one has any
we clap goodbye again
say  o good Thank you very much
and we are preparing to
welcome Lautaro Lombardi in a few
minutes