[Music] [Music] [Music] [Music] We welcome you with a round of applause to Federico Pacheco, let's go Well, thanks, it has been many years without being on the Eco stage, so I'm really happy, Thanks for being here, we'll be chatting for a while.  A little bit about him, let's go back, a little bit more is not coming out for me, there it goes. Well, let's talk about something that he has been doing for a few years that seems to me a super interesting process after having been there for more than 20 years. I don't know who was in the talk.  from Ryan today but all the things that were more than 20 years old and someone says remember Back from 2001 we all raise the old ones raise our hands So being more than 20 years in the subject it seemed to me a very interesting topic to work on these  times in the largest companies in the world it is quite a lot the smaller ones are not so encouraged and I want to invite them to do it in their own organizations without having the need to buy anything simply with the g  entity that is available and trying and Learning to do well So let's go there Hello hello it's difficult This good it seems that the title did not make sense because democratize What's up this this facilitate for everyone no because how to facilitate access simulation exercise means that  We seek to do something similar to what would happen, well, it's not that we're talking about emulating, we're not trying, we're not alone in the process, but rather the result, something like what we're going to see for a little while, and on the other hand, response to a cybersecurity incident, basically what we do  to get out of the problem when something puts the business at risk when an inconvenience is mostly technical But it can be non-technical puts the business at risk something like that then why of course exercises tablet the word or ttx is used a lot or it comes from English but it is not used much  in Argentina or in Latin America but it is a mixture of as if it were a Purple teaming that is, we practice ens  Let's train, it's not real, but we do things, but at the same time it has to do with more things than decision-making processes So it's a mix between several things What is this for a lot of things we have to choose so that yes for  what we do that is useful in our organization But mainly to see if everything we said we were going to do in an incident we really know that we have to do it not if the playbooks make sense if we can communicate during an incident if we treat each other with respect  in teams if we know the scaling processes if we have a good decision-making process and we make decisions by consensus There are a lot of things we can get from practicing like anything else like any sport as good as what you practiced in the  moment you had the opportunity like the day of the marathon like the day of the game like the day that anything happens in reality  dad So it's useful for a lot of things eventually I needed to put a little square there so I added something else because it said sweet, can you think of something else for what it's useful for, it would help me to put it in the client when we told him about it, he can't imagine something like that, no  the company, the organization, the government, whoever it is, can imagine Wow, simulation, I'm far away, I'm already wearing my biears, and I go with things like this, with the oculus, and I put this flight simulator on Microsoft. Come on, let's do an incident response simulation, I loved it, the reality is that we are on our side  We say no, but look, it's more like a game, people interact, it has to be used to learn as well, not just for. Well, we're going to do it like this, two, re serious, all the traffic and tie doesn't exist anymore.  that ends up being how we have really looked like this people end up killing themselves wanting to make decisions one above the other interrupting more in Lati  noamérica interrupting itself a lot so it is difficult for us to really explain why it is worth investing time money effort resources etc. In something that there are no classes left for people to fight so what am I going to do so how is the dynamic these exercises I am going to tell you  There is a little bit of a group of participants that represent their areas, well, these areas can be business areas, communications areas, legal press, that is, non-technical or technical areas, they can be technology, development of cybersecurity, information security, Jersey area, although that is in the middle.  But it can be technical areas, on the other hand, an event is presented, an event is designed to be presented, and it is actually a scenario that is in the form of various events that unfold over time so that people can then react based on the  information that people receive can exercise their decision-making and can see what they would do in the face of that situation.  situation, that is to say, such a thing is happening Well, what do we do? Well, according to what your playbook says, according to what you have written, what would we do here? We will have to do such a thing. Well, we would do such a thing.  things are clear If we depend too much on the documentation and of course there are several key figures that I am now going to tell you about, the key to all of this is the interaction of course the interaction between people because there are many problems that are communication and not problems  technicians we realize Generally that technicians know how to solve things but sometimes the part of communicating between areas between people is a little more difficult or something There is a turn they told me it would be type choose your own adventure and neither Because the reality is that we try  that the scenarios do not vary their flow of execution let's say for all an analogy with this system depending on the decisions  isions that are taken but are linear and go in the same direction but at more advanced levels of maturity in organizations with these processes there it can be done, it can be done that before certain decisions the scenario changes a little well to chop it up a bit or  to lower the turbo a bit according to the decisions they have made So it's not so much about deciding and what happens but rather deciding and it gets more and more complicated because eventually that's what you want to test well It's like when we do a test of  Disaster recovery is o When we make a plan we say we are going to try suppose a meteorite fell but a meteorite is not going to fall let's not suppose a meteorite So why do we have to start thinking about what we would do if everything falls apart it doesn't matter from your meteorite an earthquake or  whatever is right then doesn't have as much to do with decisions based on flow as it has to do with decisions based on what  It's going to happen at all times and now it does. Well, there are different types of participants here, of course, we call active participants players because I like to consider it as a game. In its interaction aspect, the game has this more playful thing that it serves to learn.  because it is a psychologically safe environment to make [ __ ] to say something to make plays and not to be challenged for that, that is, we consider it as a game Even though it is something that organizations go through and I am not going to be reading any comeback  my boss to respond to an incident that yes, even if it was simulated because if it didn't turn out badly Well then we call him the players it is the people who will actively participate in the exercise there are observers there are people who do not participate in the exercise who may not  I know I can invite an audit, for example, we can invite another area, another company or someone who can simply look to see what we are doing.  doing to make a board here and then in compliance so we check this that we are doing a perfect simulation exercise I saw it I was there there are connectors also called secretim the people who are on behalf of the company or organization helping to create the scenario that  everything happens as it has to happen if the exercise is internal to the company there will be a group of people who know the film or who, like the one who already knows the book from the Aventura institute, already knows which way to go Then there is no point in playing  read it well and on the other hand the coordinator who is the most key figure in all this because he is the one who will be the conductor of the Orchestra let's say in real time of the entire scenario of all the things that are happening and he has to manage that dynamic  If they are very calm, chop it up a bit. If it is very complicated, lower the turbo. Try to get people to talk and it will come to a good conclusion. If there are things that do not appear, I don't know.  Well, it's good to highlight them a little more. The coordinator is the key figure in all of this, but the design The exercise is more complicated and now I'm going to tell you a little about what it's about. Well, of course, you have to create scenarios.  some type of known threat we seize the ranson I'm going to seize service generation some can be combined it is not convenient to be so complex with that but it is also necessary to delimit the field of Industry it is not the same scenario for the financial industry as for the government as for  Critical infrastructures are obviously scenarios that can vary As much as the logic of what happens is the same, it ends up being reflected in something like this. Excel is much bigger than this, it has a lot of more columns and of course hundreds of rows where  each little thing of this has to be reflected later or in a Power Point or in a software that I am going to tell you about. Now you have to take some  Design decisions, for example, the modality can be traditional, which is what has been done for a long time before the pandemic, based on platforms, that there are several tests on this and what I am going to tell you about now, or a combination of both, it could be that the  profile of the audience or the players are more technical or more executive or more decision-making or more management or you can do a combination of both we always do a combination of both has the additional complexity associated with that combination and finally the interaction that can be  virtual face-to-face or also hybrid obviously before the pandemic there was no, it was not done virtual Generally during the pandemic it was made virtual all the times that it was in and now good combinations are made and very interesting things are really achieved so I will explain to see so that you understand  my aunt Rosa for Give me a diagram I'm in engineering So I need any little squares with f  little milk I say Good night little square with little arrow there to see if the little squares appear little arrow every time I leave this is out of sync There it is good sorry sorry sorry There goes then little square with little arrows a stage with events a coordinator who gives them one by one traditional modality  I'll start with a Powerpoint I'll tell you I'll put you Bullet this happens what would this happen what would it be good empty but it lasts a lot on the other side the teams that interact with each other internally and externally all in the same place and outside connectors and observers the connector too  he's going to be taking notes to see and then make a report things like that the platform-based model seems more complicated because it has more colors in the little squares and arrows But it's easier believe it or not because the interaction of where How they appear  the things inside the platform are handled by software So it is more reliable than ourselves  s passing a Power Point look at myself doing a single task monotasking credo passing a Powerpoint goes wrong imagine in an exercise where we are simulating a crisis so memory is going to be a platform is what I am here to tell you particularly today for more that can be done  hybrid things, well, each one has its advantages, one is not really better than the other, but the truth is that since they come in order of time, the ideal is to go towards a more hybrid model where there are instances where we interact by chat, as it would be like a slack, as we do  In everyday life, in instances where we have to be in person or at least be in a type of office in a World room like there with almost an incident or crisis, well, there is an organization, a company, a penalty, a university in the United States in Wari, the Institute of  norwich annual applied research that with the funding of the department of homeland security of the United States of almost 20 sticks  green for more or less 10 or 12 years they put together the first software of this style that ended up being quite a big thing, it is only closed for the industry, for the government, the United States, etc. But since I was lucky enough to work for several years in an American company, I was able to do it.  try it from within try it as a user try it as a configurator and administrator of the platform there are also the pickford ones of course the big consultancies have their own software I am not going to talk about quality comparison shopping because it would look bad with everything I mean I can say one  One thing and one type offends a lot of people because I have friends from all the consultancies. But hey, the pioneering platform decides a lot of money towards the eighth quite well and we looked at each other with my Argentine friends and we said why would an Argentine think in any situation that you contributed with  papers this foot review papers well what else after we said let's open it to  the community alumni colleagues we did something else a little more open and then after a while we said let's really test it as a service for a real customer who pays for this well what would that process be like is what we try to do well I know it's  well, Mati, many know it, it's also what's under, it's me, the version we put it on later, we gave it to each other. We don't know how much version I was going to see now, I say 0.8, it's easy, not good, as far as I know.  of incident response simulation in the world in history and we did it last year because we wanted it to be open, everything that the whole world sees is that we raise the bar, expose ourselves and receive so that they are going to hit us, it's all good. So,  We did it thanks to the fact that a lot of people participated, I know, so it was the main version where we did it, it was a copypage of the events within each of the channels.  It was a mess and here we have people who also did that for us. There is a previous version but I won't tell it because I'm ashamed so the next version is there with the contribution of a former student. We said why don't we do something that throws things at me  automatically into the discord then a python bot that basically solves things and the scenario exported a Jason that I can cohere it and I can throw it into each of the channels with the things that happen And that ends up being this scenario that people read  within their own channel, that is, you are on the slack channel, you would receive something, the other receives something else, each one receives different things when we simulate an incident and we reach the final version, which is what I am going to tell you about now.  the minutes that I have left in a moment tell me the actual number of minutes that I have left Poor thing, I'm really dying Eh then we put t3r because it's like that I had  to a beautiful name and we can present it and we change the name from Spanish to English also so that it looks beautiful and we can present it in other places and what's more we made it more modular In other words, instead of being discord, it is also for slack for WhatsApp  for Telegram for any means of communication that we would really use on a daily basis to work and to contact our fellow colleagues etc. In case of an incident that we want to point to this So we proposed this this this this this more modular system and it was done as it was  What does this look like in slack or in discord? If you're used to the platform, you'll see otherwise I'm going to tell you a little more later on Telegram to my WhatsApp. The good thing about WhatsApp is that WhatsApp is complicated because we did this before it was released.  the Api with which it has much more merit was like discovering we had right now said the mosquito I had nothing Joaquín la franconi had to h  do everything so many here know about him So we're going to thank him huh So there's only one step left to convince the CEO of the company I work for that this has to be offenders because if I don't find out on my own and this is going to be  well for me and no one else and that's how communities don't work and in security we know a lot since that's important on our own validation from my industry colleagues if I don't believe it, I just how I look at myself  navel So we had to make it open, it worked great and I'm very grateful because this could be so, that's why this is open, we have a much deeper documentation than a project that comes out in version 1.0 because obviously people who don't like to document it understand  but we did not focus on that and it is also there in the github of base 4 Security you can wait for your pool request your feedback your things to really get something out of all this well u are missing  A little more that I want to show now is that there is something in this for each one of you, what do we do with it? With all of this, good to try, try the organizations, we want you to try it because incident response simulation, if you want to use this, great, if not, we get together broken and  I'll tell you how to do it, you try it, that is, we as a security follower need the ecosystem to be more secure because I am safer, you, not you, yes, you don't have a hole everywhere, and we need a safer ecosystem, that is, and this is  I think it's important for everyone Even though we started by ourselves, then testing in your organization implies a scenario Thinking about a scenario Putting it in this type of box I showed you before Choosing a platform Building the teams Thinking Who is going to participate in this Setting up what needs to be done  configure the platform of course run it and then always learning feedback lessons learned etc.  The methodology that we use is actually quite generic as how anything would be in a process from a planning to an execution But of course there is a stage of planning dates and who and how and when and the Ok and the sponsors etc. a stage  of design a moment of execution that is two three four hours at the most is not like a parking lot that can last a week this is generally two three hours at the most good and we have to have deliverables that reflect what happened So that they give me  information about this process to be able to make better decisions later, improve my playbook, improve my documentation, improve my communication between the teams, etc., etc., to close conclusions. The truth is that incident response simulation exercises in general in Latin America are not as well known as in the countries  as in Europe with the United States but they are beginning to be done a lot and the idea is that c  hen we get into this before, it's an interesting process to do, it doesn't have a cost, it may have other things that have to be paid for, it can be done anyway, it's a process that takes time, it takes effort, of course, but I think it's worth getting into it like this  that can improve abilities after breakouts with practice like i can improve my ability to get less dead at the end of a marathon if i practice more if i run more and train more then Exactly the same the day you are there in the incident you respond with what  that you can with what you know with what you remember You are not reading the playbook everything is catching fire and you have to do something and one responds there from fear stress and it is complicated if they had situations of incidents that escalate the crisis is complicated then one  platform allows how to do some things with greater realism by combining what would actually happen in receipt of alerts through the same channel or a  or similar, we don't use the same one, it doesn't make sense, we make a similar channel to receive alerts as you would in the case of a real incident and combine it with the more traditional way, say Well, a Warren with yes Level with the directors of the company with the  management of the company that is for the highest level decisions, for example, we are leaving social networks Because someone said that we have a database linked somewhere and it says a lie but we have to manage it anyway if they are saying that on Twitter and it has 20,000  this retweets something has to be done with that information so there are decisions to be made that have to do with executive levels that don't have so much to do with technical levels the technical level has a limit of course and we have to practice both and finally we want one  A free and open tool can help how to facilitate all this, that is why we want to make it accessible to everyone about democratizing.  r of course you have to build good scenarios for the trick we use the good scenarios how do you grab metasploid you install it I don't want to compare things please understand but it is important that you understand that there is a lot of work in the construction or adaptation of exploit exploit or the  building one like in this case there is a lot of work in adapting a scenario of a story from a narrative to a series of injects to a series of bullets and things that are going to happen that have to be realistic for this to really work because yes  We don't all get together to play the game of life, playing chess or whatever they want and we're left a little laughing but it's not because it's not there, you have to really believe what is happening and with this the latest of all  I want to do is thank the people that I was mentioning Joaquín who was the Main developer who breaks it by rubbing elbows in anything that you give him the age no he does not manage something and he manages it every week  Na next Mati and Gas from the team of the team in which we were working with this, especially at the beginning when all this started with the design platform that I was telling you about and that finally ended up being the ones who put the Snow House in importance and if you want to see a little  more this tomorrow we are going to do a demo this in the room next door we are going to do a demo you can you can be a free observer if we have a place you can participate we will also have to do with your laptop and nothing else so we invite you  come over there tomorrow at
11 in the morning if you want to see a
little more of this and thank you very much
for all of your time
[Music]
we thank Federico Pacheco