[Music] we welcome Gerardo Fernández Navarrete [Applause] good morning everyone and thankful to be here in the coparti I really wanted to for many years and I'm glad to give here the talk that I'm going to speak will be about an investigation  that we did at the beginning of the year in total virus on malware camouflage technique how malware can be camouflaged to go unnoticed to go through the legitimate application and how to deceive users or defense systems I'm waiting for the return of the slides ok Here we are  what the chala was saying before is about a technique of abuse of trust, not like Mauro uses techniques to abuse conscience so that it passes through a perfectly valid or reliable application or simulates it is a valid application we did the study based on the contribution  of our user total virus in the end feeds on all the information we receive from you from the user more than two mi  Millions of files per day from 232 countries for 16 years This has not allowed us to have a huge malware file database, the largest on the planet.  Here below you have links to access both the report and a blog post that we put up explaining how part of this research can be replicated, not how you can Search for information on the topics that I am going to discuss below. First of all, one of the things that surprised us was finding  that approximately 2.5 million malicious files malicious means that it had at least five antivirus detections were hosted on legitimate servers to more legitimate servers from the Alexa ranking in the top 1000 there we found those files here is a graph that shows which ones are  servers that stored a greater number of malware files did not and note that this technique is  very common and it is usually used above all because if I am a malware author and I want to insert a malware file, the easiest thing is to insert it into a legitimate domain in a domain that is authorized in the firewall that does not raise suspicions, in addition, it has another counterpart and  It is that by using a legitimate element or a known trustworthy domain, I do not have to deploy my own malware infrastructure, I do not have to generate my own servers to host files, nor do I have to distribute it using my own infrastructure.  that by not having our own infrastructure to distribute the malware, I cannot be attributed yes yes that infrastructure yes that IP yes that domain is not linked to me because it is an Alexa ranking domain Well, well, until we see where that comes from, not that  it has that added value and another one on top of it. Another interesting aspect of this is that the user is seen to be more confident  on executing a file or downloading a PDF if it's hosted on a known server rather than a hyper rare a strange domain No that's one of the reasons legitimate domains are used for weapons this information Was released in June has now changed  but basically, well, it has changed, it has rotated a bit, but the main players are still not here either, then another interesting thing is a certified magician. What does that mean? that means malware that uses valid certificates; the signature is correct and clear;  operating system will not raise suspicious alerts or good in the event that it is not a certificate authorized by these operating systems, the fact of having a certified file with a valid certificate also reduces suspicions to a certain extent, not when we did the study we found that more than  a million files were legitimately signed and those suspicious files had at least  Less than 15% of antivirus detections 15% Right now we have 72 antiviruses to get an idea that among six seven antiviruses they said that the file signed with a valid certificate was malware if we look for that if we investigate a little in that million-odd files  and we focus on which ones have a valid certificate, a revoked one that has a chain, a valid chain of certification, etc. If we start filtering what really has a valid signature, we do not find that 950,000 samples were signed by the certificate something at the moment of the moment.  in which the graph that you see here was received in total virus, what it shows are The files that were sent from January 2021, 2021 and that have been seen for the first time are files new employees 2021 that are legitimately signed by malware this list  that was on the right are the certification authorities that have signed the most malware to date that asset appears in what I asked for  I explained it in the list, it's the old one that came out in another chronicle report a long time ago and it seems that it still has this problem with valid certificates, well, and the peak that you see in June 2022 caught our attention because suddenly  a huge peak appeared of a bunch of samples that were signed and the certificate was valid And that belongs to a winzip installer that was labeled by the antivirus as Open install, that is to say, a magician of the type not to put advertising or spa the same and things like  that guy and the firm was for Open install worth 80% of that peak belonged to that campaign of windfit installers then speaking specifically about a case that drew attention that came out in the press it had quite a stir it was the theft of envy certificates about  March March 3 March 4 At the beginning of March it was made public that envy certificates had been stolen Then we were curious How do you use that cer  Stolen certificates At the time the certificates were stolen we could see a first wave that appears on the left of the use of malware that used those envy certificates posing as drivers etc. No, but in the end it was malware that incorporated the stolen envy certificates  and then a second wave appeared when it was made public when they already knew what the certificates were, etc., etc. and the second will talk about people who used it when they were already revoked, but look, not everyone checks that the certificates are revoked, people check that the  certificate says that it is envy it seems that it is envy and well the revocation chain is an additional check No that I suppose that explains the big thing that happened between April Mid-April approximately then I already say that they were revoked then another interesting thing that we were  investigating is malware that employs similar icons and similar icons m  I mean when I downloaded an application from the internet without the browser you see in the file browser you see that an icon appears No, there is a lot of malware that pretends to be that application and it pretends to use the same icon but it is really malware it does not try to deceive the user to  that you click because you are seeing Skype, well, the Skype logo you are seeing the Telegram logo but really what it installs is malware, well, here in this graph what you can see is good to say a pre-selection of 25 most downloaded applications and of those 25  most downloaded applications we start looking for malware that exists that uses similar icons that search is not exact, that is, we use the fuse to identify icons that are identical or similar to the top 25 files downloaded from software and here you can see one thing that did not worry And that is that  since last year there has been an increase in the use of This technique of using stolen icons icons if  thousands of legitimate applications if we focus on the bulk of whom I mean which malware uses more icons we see that Skype is the first there are many more websites that use the Skype icon Adobe blcs cleaner There is the list of which applications  the icon is used more to pretend to be malware something else that we are considering is good Ok, we have the list of the applications that use the icons the most and so on But what is the radius of infection, that is, what is the amount per  percent of malware that we found with respect to the number of legitimate files yes The more an icon is used to create malware that is what it could give us as indicators and the tendency is to say which legitimate application is more interested in the malware authors to mimic the icon  no And what you see in this graph is one of the results that are different from what I presented previously Adobe acroback appears here That practically 9  0% of the files that we have in total virus are malware, there are 10% of files that are legitimate from Adobe and everything else is malware, with which it is clearly one of the applications that attackers have the most intentions to try to camouflage, then another interesting topic  also talking about icons but now not in applications but in urls is to see what malware uses the same web icons the fabys Not that that presents another paradigm many times when we are in a web browser we locate the tabs Looking for the icon and the bank icon or  the Google icon or the icon of such is the one that takes us to that page, no. So we considered and really that is used a lot to simulate malware in fishing campaigns, it is used a lot that is something that is known and everyone has seen it as the  web page icon appears fictional campaign no But how much of how much is used that is to say how is the use that is made here you see the radius of infection again radius of infection  ón is the number of malicious URLs with respect to the total number of urls that we have for that, for that website it is worth And of course the first one is almost 25% 27% of the urls that we have from Cloud are malicious malicious and Well there you have the complete list  if we focus it is not on the radius of infection but on the total number of malicious urls that we have WhatsApp is worth a head That is the first Instagram Facebook and of course as you can see they are applications of social network applications Not here what is hidden is an engineering attack  social tries to take the user to a Facebook page to an Instagram page and they use a similarity in the icon as a claim, for example, that is something quite common and then another way of looking for camouflage techniques that we have seen before is using malware  or looking for malware that hides in installers in a legitimate installer sometimes malware is embedded so what we start looking for is how much it installs  Legitimate developers had to embed malware inside, that's okay, that has several readings. The first is for that to happen, the attacker had to have access to the software distribution web server, or to the certificates, or to the source code, whatever, disaster, and those three  things what it shows is a good attack production attack in the chain the results we had are surprising 80 suspicious files out of 80,000 Followers of files since 2020 0.1% of The files we have came from installers that include malware then from another  side we consider well we have the legitimate installers I do not have the Telegram installer the Skype installer all this illegitimate installer how they are used by the authors of evil so installers means imagine, for example, a malware that runs a Telegram installer With what objective would it have  a malware author launching a legitimate Telegra installer  m Well basically because it needs to disguise itself as a Telegram installer no I create a fraudulent Telegram installer I do all the furniture that interests me And then I install it I run the legitimate Telegram installer no then we start searching based on malware relationships that run installers  malware that is included in compressed files that contain legitimate installers malware that is embedded in the resource segment of the resource section of a p-file and malware that appears sorry and legitimate installer that appears packet capture malware and they had more results first the  installers that are most used to camouflage are the ones that appear here Google Chrome window day zoom brave firefox and Telegram that are the top of the installers that are used fraudulently on the other hand 1816 samples were distributed through 268 The different Hot is worth  so we have another way of representing malwa  re within legitimate installers frames camouflaged with a legitimate installer here you have a graph of Which were the games that distributed the most malware Cloud from appears at the beginning and Well here you have some Sorry some legitimate games Ok and another that are common to host files this is  a screenshot of a legitimate Telegram installer is worth we take the legitimate Telegram installer and we see that malware has been executed in Total virus that is executed is legitimate installed and what we get is that several malicious files appear that if you see the name it simulates Well nothing pretends to be a  Telegram installer pretends to be Telegram, okay And it's because of what I told you before, not because the malware pretends to be a legitimate installer. I install all the malware part and then install, sorry, execute the legitimate installer of the application, this would be the timeline of how much we have  found this guy over time from 2020 to now and if i see  s again appears as a growing curve, it is becoming quite common to use this type, however, let's see the advantage you have, it's simple, I don't create normal malware without much complication and what I do is that camouflaging the packaging comes out packaged.  It requires little effort and the distribution is simple, which is why they are becoming more frequent, so another option is a smartwatch that is embedded in the resource section of the P file, in the P file section, that is, malware that includes a legitimate installer in the p cement.  We saw that a lot of years ago with a Cry that included a Thor client and it's not the first time it has appeared many times but that time it was quite loud that seems very frequent and what we have found has been 200,452 samples  malicious that include Zoo Spotify installers and then finally malware that is included in compressed files that are included in compressed files  os that contain a legitimate installer, of course, I suppose that more than one scenario occurs here. No, I have a compressed file that has malware and a legitimate installer that could be, and what we found are 2,218 samples distributed throughout 180 domains, such as  For example, so that you have not fallen into this, you have to have a legitimate proton VPN installer and then a known medicine to crack it, okay, that is quite frequent, what happens is that these crackers are often claims to install more software, in this case randomware this cracker  de proton VPN that as an example Then if we focus on detection or anticipate some of the things that we will not expand on tomorrow in the workshop that we have at 11:30 and here you have for example How to find a legitimate site that distributes malware this query  that you see here this here entity file as well as a search is built within our service to find malware that is  distributed through Google, for example, on the other hand, search for similarity, search for similar icons, you must have a search for similar icons with at least two detections And here the results appear to you: 132 malware files use an identical icon and then three  files use a similar icon ok using And finally to the last example of use here would appear a Microsoft certificate you can obtain What are the parameters of the serial numberger the footprint and we can Search for malware that uses those parameters in the certificate chain No, here you have  For example, this search in this search shows 65 files legitimately signed by Microsoft in a certain part of the agreement signing chain and Well, nothing else basically if you are curious and think you know a little more
about How to hunt Wizards of this type
tomorrow  we have a workshop in which
for two hours we will see this
carefully and beds and nothing else Many
thank you
[applause]