[Music] [Music] [Music] Come on, okay, people, welcome and welcome to ecoparti 2022, thank you very much for coming so early, a huge room, a great challenge, and the first thing I wanted to say is we're going back to the Eco in person, so please give it a go so we're back  In your face, the pandemic seems most important to me, that seems like nonsense, but now we are all here again doing what we enjoy and what we like. So, well, thank you all very much for coming, I will be here.  teacher of Héctor the dog Peralta basically as coordinators of the space of aguanty here with Adri javo it seems let's say it almost that we pushed him and we were encouraging him to present his talk because it seemed to us that what he achieved was really something incredible In such a short time with such dedication  and good with all with all the genius of the dog So not soon we are going to move on to the technical part that we like everything but first of all  I'm going to give the pass to Héctor the dog, in principle he's going to tell a little about his personal story How he came to achieve this bounty of 150k that are not bytes and well I'll leave you with Héctor the dog presenting his talk on  breaking teams for 150k applause but [Music] good morning everyone thank you for coming before starting with the technical part of the report what I want to do is tell a little How to start this activity since it was almost by chance In fact it's been a while  I don't know that eltie existed for three years. In 2018 I lost my job. I spent a year and a few months looking for a blank job and in fact it was quite complicated for me since I was 30 years old at the time and my only work experience was working  in the cinema and in a telephone company, so the effects of human resources have not passed and in fact the few interviews I already got, they would not have called me precisely because of the issue of age and little experience  Labor science, so in December 2019 I remembered the news about Santiago López that came out yesterday in the nation where he commented that he had won a million dollars doing it. And I began to investigate, it seemed to me that it was a lie that there was something strange behind that.  but but it turned out that it was not true that in fact Santiago commented that he learned on his own so I began to investigate the activity where they could be among these reports as the process to learn and find an error in a company and reading about it  information I realized that many people who also learned on their own not only had a title or a lost experience but starting from scratch so I started reading and after seven months I was sending reports periodically every month yes or yes  I had at least two or three valid accepted reports And from that moment on I began to make a living from this activity and what I want to comment on is how  It was not my experience to enter the world of the County, not only in computer security but specifically in security regarding the technical part and many resources on the Internet. In fact, they are all free. What helped me were the public reports on  the hacker One page the subject of blogs many people who share their research or their approach to certain vulnerabilities that of Twitter also very important following the right people on Twitter is a very good source of information since out there in a  comment from Twitter that one can extract that and achieve something much bigger than reading an entire book, for example. And finally, the documentation, the documentation is also key because it is the source of all the information, although it can explain an error or error to a person.  a type of vulnerability with his words I like to always go to the source where it came from how he is how this person learned that  how did that reasoning arrive?  information that the only thing it does is cause more confusion from the outside When one starts everything seems complicated not only because one does not know things but because it is also promoted from within there is a lot of keeping many people who had a path to get where they are that they had to  have a stack of certificates or years of experience or university degrees and that's perfect but many people try to impose that on new people and that discourages them and the reality is that this was the path of each one to do what is precisely offered by the possibility  that each one make their own way if one copy repeats what another did because that person was consistently successful  I think that it was successful, one is only going to produce more of the same and in this activity at least that doesn't work in the long term since the errors are already there the code is written in the kitchen it is in how each one sees it yes  One sees it in the same way that the developer had done it or because I follow the years that a person x or because another person told him to do such a thing. It will be the same as another person to kill nothing instead when one can apply his  vision to what you are doing is when the errors literally begin to appear because as I say they are already there it depends on one seeing it in a different way and well what I suggest is that one take the path of others or people are  Here it says yes, you have to do such a thing because I did it as a suggestion and try to find your own way. What I like to do is question things. If I make a report or an information or a classic, the classic example is a  blog that the person writes 200 pages with definitions that are copied from Wikipedia and When one arrives at the error itself it turns out that he put admin to achieve and one does not need to know how a database works or be a developer programmer to know that a vulnerability is  that it comes out by default, you just have to click it and that's it, then it's up to you to develop the criteria at the moment you're reading, you don't read the report or read the blog, and it says Well, this is fine, but what's good that it doesn't match? So it has  to see all this with the result and well, as one applies it, the criteria will develop precisely to give him the information and he develops his point of view and eventually the errors begin to appear another difficulty that I find is the issue that one  there is a lot of uncertainty one feels offended by the computer and says OK I am going to play an error but many times he does not know how to look for it he does not know how to em  It's not a matter of just dealing with it and you know that uncertainty will always be there, not like nothing was ever guaranteed, it's not sure if you're going to find an error, the question is that one is already there.  predisposed to look for it anyway, this is closely related to the issue that new people are encouraged to work in public programs which do not offer monetary rewards, they only give points so that they have access to private programs, which I think is the private test  Public of That difference is irrelevant one does not have an advantage because it is a private problem in fact the Microsoft Team application is published the competition in which you participate is public and from the same report that the same prize that I obtained was received by four more people, that is, there were  five different reports to reach the same goal in a super well-known application that does not have any kind of Secret of  done even the application the code is public what one can access from your computer so the issue of worrying about invitations or public programs is something irrelevant and exactly what people are encouraged to start because they are already basically self  demotivating by saying I'm not going to read this public program but I'm sure that everyone already did it, it doesn't matter because it's related to what they said about each one, apply your vision if you don't review it in the same way as others and if you obviously don't  I find nothing but if one sees it applying their knowledge and their way of approaching it, they will surely find things like what happened here after the issue of frustration one sends the report a critical report I expect an amount of reward x and the last word is always with the company  You can send the report with all the explanations, the details, whatever they ask you and the company says no. Look at this, I don't know, it's known.  internally or not for us we consider that the severity is lower because we reserve the critic for circumstance x and the reality is that although one can claim the platforms offer mediation OR can send corn to the company [Music] it cannot be more than  That if the company says we don't want to pay you, they won't pay you and that's it, the only thing I recommend in those cases is not to work with that company because they clearly don't care about security, much less about the work that one does for the effort because one  you spend time and they just try to find an error based on the promise or what is written in the application policy and when you come across the answer that is super arbitrary you say Ok that's it move on to the next application and don't waste any more time with  that And finally Well the same thing about the edition of the reports the same thing just after all the companies will continue forever but good enough to close this  This is the introduction. What I suggest is that you don't worry about the circumstances. If one day, if today you don't understand anything or things appear complicated, it doesn't matter because you don't know what will happen tomorrow, maybe today's report will not be accepted.  But one keeps looking and the next one is accepted and it is a matter of finding, as I said before, the path of each one where they are comfortable with the type of connectivity that comes most easily to them, there is no single path, there is no  There is only one way to do it, they can hack web pages, desktop applications, blockchain, there is a fairly large field to choose from, and so that each one can fairly develop their vision in this regard, regarding the competition, I participated in May of this year, it is a competition.  of hacking is normally held in Canada, what is done is to inform in advance approximately four months before the scope, that is, the applications that are several to participate and  what the participants have to do is find a way to execute remote code either through a software application or on a phone, for example, not iPhone iOS or Android as vulnerabilities that are not previously known what the company does This is  Through this competition, a little encourage people to use the legal path or as they say and not to use these good skills for something malicious, for example, and the monetary reward is offered fairly. In my case, they participate in the communication category.  business had the zoom and Microsoft applications and I went for the Microsoft one the feature of this application is that it is developed with the electron framework basically what it does is display a web page in a desktop application so it is subject to it  fundamentals if something you should in web applications as a scripting process in the electron application can be found  the same difference that in the context of the application this vulnerability can be used as an entry point to access the operating system instead in the browser that is much more difficult before starting with the technical part I am going to define some concepts that are necessary for  explain the development of the error web preference refers to an object that stores the security characteristics of each render process the render process would basically be the application window within those preferences the relevant ones are Note integration in the case these may have a value  true or false in the event that this is true, the web page has direct access to the main process, which is the one in charge of the system path, that is, if we have a way to execute the code on that web page with this feature active, we automatically have  a remote code execution that is a critical error installation context It's something  Similarly, when the render process remains, it has two instances: the first, which is the process creation part, precisely where the internal modules of the Electron Gold frame are loaded, and the second step, which would be like taking out the document, that is, our web page, the installation of  contexts Depending on how it is configured in true or false, it can allow these two instances to work in the same context or separately. Ideally, what comes by default is that it be separated since we can commit the render process with the context information disabled  we can access again the critical functions that run in the operating system the sandbox attribute is an additional security measure in the event that the other two measures fail and can be accessed by proceeding and can be compromised if the attribute is both active modules  Available are limited, that is, there is no module that can access the operating system.  vo one can modify the page and other things but they are superficial things If we use it is extractive as I said it is an additional measure In case the other two do not work And finally the k attribute that what it does is give access to the document to an element  special that works similar to an iframe in a web page but has additional functions in this case the main functions I want a new process and if you do not have control over this element You can create a process with arbitrary characteristics and in this way for example you could create  a new element with active nauda integration and executing code in the operating system Even if the superior document does not have it And finally the ipc communication system and that basically what it does is allow communication between a document has a frame window the  post month which allows communication from the iframe to the Superior and the superior of the iframe to send information and the message  aje ipc works in the same way the difference that goes from the render process to the main process, that is, it is something internal to the framework, it is not exposed by default like the system, the Book basically consists of taking advantage of application features in a different way. In fact  there is only one vulnerability that is an evasion in the security measure the rest is to combine that with these characteristics to turn that into itself No it is not a bug or it cannot be exploited but combined with what the application offers you can reach the  critical error the first feature is the integration of external applications what Microsoft teams allows is precisely that a user develops an application that is basically a web page and delivers it to his organization or for himself to use it the implementation of this method is  through a View web element which has valid security measures since each content and  xternal so it must be contained since the content is arbitrary precisely the application is allowing you the option to put external and arbitrary content because that has to be contained in some way and here we have a priming scheme would be the following we have the main window  which will be the main process the teacher render main when we create the external application even the new processor through the View web element within the main window process in this in this process dry a URL from Microsoft steams which loads within an iframe the  external application note that the application is quite contained the attribute the live water element has San true false the other attributes are also valid so they are reduced to those two that are important but the main process does have access to the View element So  if I can somehow get from the external application to the process  From the main window we have one step forward to activate the water element. Analyzing the application integration, we find that the application offers a method of communicating with this process directly through the post-month communication. What is the application? This month a message is sent  message to the parent document the parent document receives this message based on the format of the information it is forwarded by the main window process through the ipc message and the main window receives this information again based on the format of the message two things can happen  that this information passes from the main process and some X action is performed at that moment or if not directly connected to the main window it never goes through the process analyzing the application code and drawing it what I found was access to all the methods that  are available through the post message most are to add applications c  change words and so on But there is one that is interesting that allows you to create a new window when I don't want the new window within the application which is creating a new render process so what I did was analyze this event since there is a new process It is  a possibility of a different security attribute in this case we can control the URL of the new window or a message with the following format what you do And open a pop up from where identification of third parties with a barrier And that we control Because returning the scheme  We have sent the message required to access that specific function in the API This goes to the main process, the new window event is emitted and the interesting thing here is that the event is emitted from the main window, that is, the green box, so when it remains  the new window would be the event attributes of the process that emits it if the event were emitted from the iframe or from the webview ser  Instead, the attribute would be set to false as it is emitted from the main window, so we give it the true web attribute, so we have a new process, we already came out of a different one that was contained and not only that, but we have access to the View web element  In other words, we are already one step closer to reaching the error when I find this element what you see that comes as an additional security measure that is implemented by the teams application since the frameworks what it offers as we saw before the attribute true false  one has access or not now if it is true and there is no access it is something particular to the application for which it was developed separately and it is possible that there is an error in that implementation In fact here is the error when one creates the element in the process  New, what happens in the main one is that the edit of the event emitter process is verified, that is, each render process has a value, hence it is a numerical value that  e is generated automatically At the time of creating the process if heredy does not correspond to the value 1 which is the value of the main window this is impossible to modify them the only way for this to be true is that the event comes from the main window if this is false the  element is removed so if we find a way to bypass this check we have full access on a water element the internal logic of the framework I find out that the check was started when the emission of this event being from this event backwards you can find the point where it was  starts since it can't first find it where it came from but if they found it determined then going back from there one can also go back through the code and see where the event came from what I found out was that one can create the View web element and instantly  to create it, it is not destroyed, it is only destroyed when one has the value source or src, so between one step and the other one has  You can only access it and you can interact with it when you access the value, this part of the code is executed, note that at the end of the line is the return of the functions, the emission of the event, but nevertheless, before, two verifications are produced and both end  in an error this means that if we can get into any of those errors, the execution of the codes is interrupted and the emission of the event is avoided and possibly giving us access to the element, the first verification we can control it since we cannot Modify the internal element of the element  web View but the second Yes because it interacts, notice that it says the point contains Windows now we are going to see that we have access to that element to that element from the document when one creates the element you do not have direct access to the web Bio but you have access to the internal element  which was the one we saw in the previous positive version But what happens the maintenance object is not defined however  or when one attaches This element to the document the element is automatically generated counting Windows which corresponds to the iframe window having the defined object cannot interact with it even before triggering the rc values ​​the error consists of the following if one modifies the location  of the element counting Windows to an invalid URL what it does is initiate a navigation attempt this navigation attempt what it does is a modification of the element found in Windows no longer wants by default as used in the previous verification simply  loading a URL that cannot be loaded in an eframe because we can configure the header externation the Night when it is assigned the content location variable is modified Windows the error occurs since this Barrier cannot be change of race or frame we assign rc values  at this point the error occurs in the second If block causing the code that l  The execution is interrupted since note that the Windows content of our object defined in the document is the same as that used for verification and if, having modified it, the web function cannot obtain a result because the result is minus one, the IP connection 0  and the error is produced once we produce the error we assign through rc values ​​with a valid URL And at this moment the code related to the src is executed again the important thing here is that in the second If this verification is going to be false already  When we assigned a value the first time, what happened was that the create Quest function was executed, what has assigned the value of 10 ID, triggered the event of the main process, and so on, when we assigned these false ones the second time, to which I already told you  is assigned, it avoids the emission of the event since it does not enter grages but passes the last line where our URL is loaded And at this moment we already have full access to the web element  View and we were able to completely evade the security measure by forcing an error, this not only makes us only elements, but since it has not gone through the main process and due to the security measures implemented in the original process, it is created with default attributes, we have the obligation  false order sanction up to this point this is also not directly exploitable since we have installation and we can't access internal pen but the combination of sandbox and context consideration allows us to be able to scale this in some way what we are going to see now we come back  to the scheme of the next step was to force the error and create elements with the vulnerable properties once we have access to elements and we will see how to exploit the combination of sandbox and context titling remember false and we were able to compromise the process we have access to internal functions  and the installation of context what allows is that the two codes  the internal logic and that of the document are executed in the same context when it is false this can also be exploited that what we are going to see now with the process all process was wanted render in electron the following function is executed the argument r is the name  of the module to be loaded can be module 8, the electron process, or module x, the first thing it does is check if this module was previously used, since the first time the module is loaded it remains stored to be able to use it efficiently if  This was not previously loaded through the call function of the module itself, the module has to be loaded and then when it expires for later use, all the modules are downloaded and this happens before the document is loaded. The listener is added to the window to the event this  event is basically executed when the document is finished loading what's interesting now that this code belongs to the internal part of the brake to internal logic  a of the framework, but it is being executed after our document has been loaded, that is, if we modify any native javascript function, we can modify the internal logic of the framework. First, a verification is made to see, to achieve no security measures, the result of that block. If It Depends  from the following in this case we see variables that can be defined in the application configuration within the c object or note that in the second verification if there is a window or a document and seeing this document you already get the variable innabel or desable one  you can control the result of the If block simply by defining the variable however you like in this case we want the If block to be entered so we define the variable as Trump which executes the following function This does several checks and the important part is the following when  try to run this function run javascript note that an  You have to Access the Prime web object to load this the webframe module has to return to the beginning of the initial function that we saw in the render process And at this point where we have the possibility to enjoy the function in webware which allows  execute the code to briefly explain what is the modification of prototypes in javascript each data type has access to native functions automatically make declared in this case we declare the test variable with a String data type with the value dot file exe what to the  functions of the String data type, for example, the function is with, what it does is check if the variable ends with what it receives as an argument. In this case, we check that it ends with an exe point, which gives the true if we modify the prototype of the functions this  For example, we can make it always false and this is valid even for a change that was previously declared.  that the same variable as first true god after Modifying the prototype we execute it and the result is false now How can we use this to exploit it or turn it into a security flaw if we had a function for example verify that based on the file extension it allows  to be executed or not If the man ends with dot exe It is not executed if it does not end with dot exe it is executed in this case the same thing we define the test variable with the word file dot exe we execute the function and as appropriate it is not executed it had already finished with dot  exe we modify the prototype so that the result is always false and automatically execute the same function in the results, that is, with that line of code we were able to evade the security measure and we can execute any type of file in this case by transferring this to the electron hour frame lo  What we can do is modify the goal function since when the WiFi mode is loaded, it was necessary  for the previous step we put the same initial function But what happens in this case the check is false so the module did not put it previously which takes us to the end of the line and through the function with the module to be loaded being call  one of the native functions of javascript we can use the method that we saw previously And filter the function to execute the code that we want our document consists of the following there are very few lines first we declare the variable required to control the result of the If block and that is  run the failsafe function what we do next store the original prototype of the goal fusion since once you modify it you have no way to restore it Unless you have stored it previously and these functions needed to run the code afterwards so  that the only thing we do store a temporary variable we declare our function as modified and what we do  s here is to check if argument 4 corresponds to the function This is inside a block three since sometimes it is not the first the first module to load is the frame it may be that another is loaded or it may be that argument 4 is not  the function that interests us and if the execution is interrupted we have no way to return to this point so what the trail does is continue until it is until it is the function that interests us when we find the function that we need what we do Is  restore the original prototype delete the Temporary variable and simply export the argument 4 which is the require function to a global variable and we can use it at any time outside this point of the document this happens only at the beginning of the document when it is loaded if we can't  if we don't wait for it to know it's good we have a way to do it again instead with the global variable we can access it permanently once we have these functions here  ntions it is possible to load modules from Note since no integration is false and sandbox is also false we simply have to declare an empty object use one of the methods to fill this object with the function that loads modules and inside that function just choose  the module that we want to use in this case the process model is the one that allows executing the code in the operating system we can simply as an argument of the code that we want to use and this code is executed for example of a calculator execution So up to this point we already have the  The last step would be Modify the prototype in the last render process that we obtained and we can already find things an external application a user simply installs it accesses the application element that accessed the application its operating system was compromised So at this point I say Ok ready Send me the  competition I'm going to notice I'm going to participate I already won 250 here and he tells me  n Well, yes, but look, we still can't because you have to meet a lot of requirements, the ocean has to interact, it has the error, it has to have a certain characteristic, so they send me an email with 15 questions, which is exactly what you have to satisfy all the conditions to be able to  participate in the competition in this case the one that I was not complying with is the issue of user interaction because they tell me well it is in the application you can do this but how do I get to that application it has to come through a link you have to install it If the  You have to install where you are going to get it from, it is not something so simple and it is not valid for this type of competition, so investigating the application regarding another feature that allows you to share the same external application but in meetings the  difference that in the context of the meeting one can share this application to others simply add it choose the share option  rtir and automatically the other people receive on their computer there is no way to reject what this is the key I would like to accept to receive the external application It would not be valid either but by default one shares it and the other person receives it As much as they do not want to  simply connect in the call having to be implemented in the same way through the web element uses post message and ipc communication but the difference is that when the call starts you want a new window And if I want to use the same method that I used in  In the previous Step, the issuer of the Windows damage event is the call window and in this case we have a fake web and the rest of our Xbox depends on this, so we have to find a way to avoid this other obstacle to do it. You just have to  use it I have features and no application No there is nothing else, nothing strange Organizations can create teams or channels common to all  The users simply stay, the channel is configured to be public and all users can access it automatically, they do not need to accept the invitation to the Channel or any type of additional interaction if we can somehow redirect the main window is  this public tab we can avoid the issue of user interaction in the call by analyzing the main tabs I find that each application, each tab has an individual link when opened in the browser, a tripling is executed, this means when one puts the link to the tab  In the browser, for example, in Chrome, you will find the following notice, which when you accept what you do is execute the protocol, the society, the spatial application to the protocol, the intimate http protocol, which is the basic, the classic Internet protocol, when you open the  page runs through Microsoft's custom protocol the Deep l  ink And if the application is installed one finds this message again and user interaction Even if from the call I execute the URL the browser opens But you have to interact again and this was not valid either so we used the other feature that  it offers the application which is precisely the execution of dipling from the from the Microsoft teams application basically works the same as in the browser one calls the Open function to create a new window but instead of putting the http protocol put the protocol associated with the application  who wants to execute the difference with the web browser It is that from electron by default the external applications are executed without warning to the user in the browser as we saw before you have to put accept or not On the other hand, if from the Microsoft teams application we execute the diplink the user  no nothing is notified And if the associated application is directly executed if it Exists at  guna This is precisely what we use to satisfy the requirement since from the external application in the call we can execute a Deep link to the public tab, redirect the main window and this way of executing the code without any additional user interaction for this, we simply do it  What we do is to convert the original link to the tab to a diplink, we only replace the domain and the protocol by the word MS teams from the shared application we use the functions to execute external applications we simply call the Windows open function and finally we have the code distribution  in the operating system now we are going to see a summary of the entire process and then a video demonstration the attacker in this case the only thing he does is make the call once the people enter the call it is shared by the external application to the  share the application to calls is called through Windows Open the p  rotocolo the custom protocol with pointing to the tab with the vulnerable application at this point the flow that we saw previously starts it is used for two months the upper document is sent it is sent to the process of the main window the new process stays in a new window dry our  document which we forced the error to follow the element returned with the default configuration we filtered the internal function And finally we have the code execution in the operating system only Having accepted the call and now we have the video on the right would be the attacker to the  left the user first the person is invited the call or the meeting the external application is added note that we have the option to share and automatically in the window of each member the uniframe will appear with the external application now the blink one is executed note  that even the main window is automatically redirected to the vulnerable tab  The new window stayed, the internal position and the person were leaked, that is, we automatically accessed the victim's computer. Applause, please, the first calculation of the Eco Party. Thank you, total crack, dog, total crack.  the talk broke it All for me the dog a total genius I make a small summary about everything we have just seen basically mainly from his personal history that is, he had another job two years ago he had the bad luck of being left without a job and a  little thanks to the community and to everything that we already know that the world of backgrounty gives us, he began to get involved in developing systems, learning a lot of things and taking advantage of everything that the community in general in the world of hacking  it has to give to everyone and two years later after a lot of trial and error learning nothing starts to get a few bapt  is and find a weakness in a very particular Niche as that electron begins to find a skill that is critical The truth is that before pound to One you had already been working with the Microsoft application a little over a year ago, so when it came out  the competition was good for me because I was already familiar with one of the valid applications so I decided to give it a try Exactly So he starts pulling out all these amazing bountys that we all got wide-eyed pleased thanks to that Microsoft approaches him you can see later  the talk is going to be uploaded you can see on the Microsoft research blog they made a whole note about his life story and others this and well thanks to those bauntys he qualifies no to the pound which is one of the most Hardcore and strict competitions that  It can be known from the world of hacking in general, in fact, he came out second in power, only the first, the team that came out First, I want to acl  plow that it is a team of researchers many times there are many researches many companies behind And here Hector the dog alone with his computer and his brain he managed to reach second place So a big round of applause for him thank you very much thank you very much now let's go  open to questions I don't know if you have any questions, you can think about them I'll pass the microphone on anyway I have the first question, yes it precisely comes to the topic of how because I don't know if they saw that I had already forged a kind of Mini work of art  which is a Remote codexecution in a program like teams but it didn't qualify for the competition, that is, it was a very succulent bounty, no, but it still didn't qualify for the competition.  It was the competition in which he had qualified thanks to everything they had been posting and so on and they told him again pum pared Don't worry, this can be done  in a viable way let's call it then he had to go back a lot of steps to start to understand the application again not only the hack he had achieved but how to use the application so that it can be done no basically then it seems to me that there it is  another great example of the try harder and go back and review everything again and there he had to get creative again to find a way with a Deep link to be able to do it with the least amount of interactions by the user now well tell us a little how is the  triachi de la pauntuba one, that is, how do they check that your ex Play is yours, they have not stolen it from you, they have bought it on the black market, etc.  since it is not the same as running your exploration at the moment if you have to modify something you already know what is already finished but I had to send  Send everything by email with all the detailed information so that someone else can follow the steps accordingly, since you don't see everything here, the back part would be because you don't have to confirm the local server, you have to have a domain x to load the web page, you have to  configure certain local configurations on the computer and verify that everything works at the moment. So I was on the call. In fact, I had to start the first demo at 1 in the afternoon and I was having all the technical problems when the person opened the host machine to  Grabbing in the teams application didn't work the virtual machine didn't read the flash drive they couldn't copy the exploit they spent I think 40 50 minutes going around to see why it didn't work and you also have a certain amount of time because one of the key points  In the part of the questions, it is said if one is aware that they have half an hour in total and a maximum of three attempts each of about 5 minutes and  the three fingers have to be within half an hour, that is to say, if in that time you could not demonstrate your desploid No, it's already there, you can't participate in the competition, so say no, you don't win the prize. Even if it was valid, it was somewhat complicated, that is.  Obviously they told me that the time it took was not going to be deducted from my participation time when they wanted to connect to the local server it didn't work either they had to make a change there in the code at the time but well once everything was programmed and when  It ends, they tell me, well, we still have to verify more things. First, the people from the Micro Train Organization open up and they ask me. Well, how did you find this? How did you come up with it? Where did you get it from?  that error more than anything also so that they understand it Because if there is in it, for example in my case there were five participants for  the same category if the errors are similar in the explanation of how one found the error, it allows just to differentiate so that the two are different or not Because if the two are similar and it is not clear what is the root of the error, only the one who wins  the one who participated first participated so they ask a lot of very specific technical questions once they finish verifying that the error was valid and that it is fully understood there are the people from the product in this case Microsoft who also ask questions but basically how long was I  How long did it take me to find the bug? How long does it take to get everything ready and then do you have to check both Microsoft in your database and the organization if you don't have any information related to this bug to confirm that it's just a unique variability and only after?  from that point of all those subsequent questions It is confirmed that the university  dad is a 0 from there and at that moment one is already confirmed as the winner of the category, he came out genius Thanks for the answer for the doubts that's it we believe that he is already suffocated no yes yes That's it they no longer understand a call it seems that he is already suffocated  I don't know if anyone has any questions, raise your hand I don't see you I'm kind of like here with the light in front of you there's a question I'm going to come over. Good, first of all, congratulations Thank you very much, very good life story of overcoming and nothing  Given the frustration, it was quite cool and I calculate that it was inspiring for many. You had commented that you had been working with teams for a year already. Yes, more or less, and other vulnerabilities could be found. More than anything because not long ago I had read layers a post in the middle and I don't remember  who was just exposing team vulnerabilities but always focusing on the fact that it has many design problems and that for more precisely what is being reported  ban, they lowered layers of criticality or others But well, showing that technical part a bit, I don't know what a good time you had found before with this, yes in my work as Microsoft, in fact, it was quite good, the majority of them came back, I think it was two or three  critizing crosses and the rest were all from this same category critical errors discussion of remote code in regards to the design is something very particular to the y of the companies out there one sees that someone gave you a direct Open radio for say one way x y  They paid for it and another report did the same thing and they did not accept it and when it goes specifically to Baconti, design does not usually have much impact on companies. Rather, companies do not usually accept it. Even though the impact is great, this is not with what  what it says at the beginning is subject to the last word if one starts a critical error it is most likely that they will not accept it unless it is I mean it already has to be very  and allegorous saying no I don't want no because we don't want it like there is no justification for change when the errors are design they are a little ambiguous things companies as soon as they see the opportunity they grab hold of anything to avoid paying you or paying you less great Thank you very much for the  ask someone else some other short question yes I'm reviewing something in that yes classic classic yes never stop trying bypaces on what you reported because it's another guy basically in fact the report This is a third bypace an error that they call from previously there was  I sent an rcd they fixed it I sent another one they fixed it and in the second bypass which would be the third report for the competition it is also one of the advantages of electoral applications to have access to the application code simply when there is a fix to an error that one  reported you can go in and see what the rule was and be able to look for a bypass you have children to Microsoft they can't want a  Well I don't know if there are any more questions I don't see anyone more perfect then Thank you all very much because Thank you until the end Thank you very much thank you for those who want to see other super
interesting bags like this one
can join us in the  space
de So thank you very much everyone
Thank you very much everyone
[Applause]
[Music]