ok we welcome the first presenter of the Eco day 2 Josué rojas with a loud applause [Music] Hello everyone thank you for being here early at 10 am some still haven't woken up or still haven't slept well also thanks to the Eco for  This is this paper that was accepted is the second time that I am here and counting a little less as dense as the previous time but for me it is very satisfying Because 15 years have passed since I started reverse engineering and basically I want to count  how I started and like any of us any of you can start in this yes it is not so complicated As some say that this talk is not this talk is not about how to bypass anti chips yes but what it is is about how  I began to infer how the game was internally written in c++ but program the chips in assembler so you will see my reasoning a bit as was the scope of all and what  e how we can all learn together and start in this So I'm going to tell a little of My story very quickly for reasons of time this is radio echo 133.7 worth a little volume while you see the demo of a chip that we made with some friends not  I know about 11 or 15 years, I don't remember well, but basically, when I started I went to an internet booth in Peru, we call it that way because, since we don't have enough resources, most of us there in those neighborhoods, what people did is they bought computer machines.  They put them all together and then they rented them for a while. We love internet booths or cyber cafes without coffee and when we went to play Generally and do homework but you're going to play One day someone comes with a USB where they had a chip for this game  rakion and everyone wanted to use it everyone wanted to know how it was used where I got it from and well I also wanted to know how it was used but the difference is that while it appears  I also wanted to know where it was used I wanted to know how it worked So that's where my journey more or less begins, not understanding how that chip, which is a dll, a library, worked because it was a file that you clicked twice with another executable that  I didn't have the slightest idea what these things were doing and overall they were like magic for me, I mean, I didn't have the slightest idea how it worked and there's more or less How my journey begins in this So let's see a little about the  agenda we are going to see a little about the creatures, all that was explained to him by a program further advancing the first chip that I made, which are the entities that are the most interesting. I think that it is the reconstruction of c++ objects and Well, a little of my reasoning to do  my first boat not from this game well then at that time the big problem is that being things from Game Hawking they were very closed why because there was money involved So it was like very elitist and you didn't  Many things came out So I was quite thick asking questions I was very very very exposed so that this guy who brought the chip gave me Where did he get it as soon as I found out Where did the forum get it that was used a lot at that time I went in  and I began to ask everyone Nobody wanted to tell me anything they treated each other badly it was As I told them it was very elitist however Sometimes they told you one thing or another they don't learn Olie sower from vader and how this one works but heard but no and  someone at one point published this code in dolphin I couldn't get it so good I put my assembler code but basically what this this this line of code does is that it looks for the properties of the creatures because each each player has some creatures that  can be invoked and what it does is Look for the object in memory why because there is a reference So it can be found in memory and once you find it what you do is t  ode all all the properties of this creature of lower level or lower Rank and lower that does less damage and overwrites them within another of the properties of a creature so you read one of a higher level and overwrites it in a lower one  level making you able to do what is going to be seen, that is, making you able to use very simple things Well, a little let's see, it doesn't seem like it won't let me get ahead Well I'm going to put Play and well no it won't let me put Play but basically what  we do here is to do that is not to copy these things the properties of the game and with that I could, for example, I had a spider that was very simple and could summon another much more powerful creature not within the game and for me it was almost I mean not  I had an idea what it was I knew more or less that they were bytes that were a little bit of memory addresses these are the objects that you see in the descriptions column you see what are the objects and basically what they  It is without knowing that it is so, the only thing I knew is that that byte array was copied and the byte rule of, for example, the spider was copied into the other, and when instead of a spider what it did directly was spawn another  not a creature as you can see there and for example you have minotaurs or event things etc. But if you notice it's a spider then This was something that basically opened my mind a lot because I saw that interesting things could be done and I learned a lot about how  chickenjing works because one of the first when one enters and sees the tutorial the first thing they do is Search for data and the data that changes for example we all have in a player have 100 life to put a number and it would be 64 in hexadecimal  and when it receives damage from one, it decreases so one Searches all the time, it searches for changes in memory that are relevant to the player, no. So when this happened, what I did was Bus  load the changes and I could get the addresses where these changes were and well basically in this in this video that you see there what I'm doing is finding the creatures that in this case that spider I find how do we do this that is like  I sit down and go to the computer How do I find something specific in the game? Well, depending on what you are looking for. In this very specific case, what I did was take out and put in. Take out and put in. Why? Because when it was put in, I understood that it was established  a value and when that value was taken to null and like that all the time then I played all the time with it and like that at about the age of 15 or so I started doing these things So when you went to the internet booth while everything  the world was playing I had the computer with my ID programming an assembler the image was super super curious but it was interesting because while a  everyone everyone caught my attention that caught my attention this kind of thing not good so what I do is start looking for them all the time I do I do that that game pulled put put put put until I can find the memory address  and if I advance it The problem is that it doesn't let me advance but But later it is seen that I can make changes in the in the in the in the creature it doesn't let me raise well don't worry Well then then every game must have like a  entity, that is, all the beach players have to have some references to their data in memory. Yes, for example, the name, the armor, the life, the items that the creatures have, if you can use creatures or pets or whatever, no, then the entities are  Those are large structures that contain this type of information, no. And in this game there were two, one that was in the game, that is, when you interact with other players and in the lobby, because  in the lobby because inside the lobby there is an inventory and in the inventory you did not have things So this game called rakion which was an mmorpg had this type of two entities not as mentioned So as we saw in the previous one in the previous video I did it  What it did was look for the memory address of the spider creature, for example, and then exchange it and I could put minotaurs or whatever. So I understood that this means the game has to know somehow how to access this data.  I mean, it's not that all the time it's Dynamic because when you restarted the game that address where you found the spider the spider's identifier I wasn't there anymore So the game has to understand at some point where things are, they have to  see specific non-relative references of references to that place so I more or less started looking for information about it, and what I started to do is Search for d  fixed addresses not what I know nowadays to be known as global variables but fixed addresses Like the one you can see there not and why Because the address of the creature was in higher addresses and I was looking for lower addresses to see if I could find a  pointer that adding an offset to a displacement and found the specific byte that I wanted So searching by looking was basically open in Oliver Hey and start looking Look look Look look and see what I find good ranking God which is another is a Clone uses an implementation But  We can see that this was interesting because it's once that I got I knew where I was I could use two functions in Windows I found it by reading The msdn is getting the name of the function called in game plus two I got the address of this pointer  So the change of the version dlr didn't matter, the updates didn't matter, nothing mattered because I knew At least what  That they change the entire implementation there, yes, but I already knew that it would be there, so making a chip of this supported me many versions without problems and well, as you can see, they programmed all of this in an assembler, it was not, it was not easy, the truth was my  First, it was the first language I learned, but it was taken from the Internet. I put it, I put a few things on it, and I mean, it didn't even fit well, it was terrible, but well, it worked and it helped me a lot, no, and  Well that's in the lobby But how is that how we do it in the game well in the game there are two functions you can see we can see the C class Player get local Player and within that it has its implementations that Player get feeling info and info get local  Player does not return a pointer to that class, that is, it does not return a new object if they do not return the previously created object of the character's game, no And also  something that was very good is that you could also obtain the entity of the other players so that you can do very very very cool things.  start doing these these things there are things that you want to do first you don't want for example to have infinite life yes you don't want to die you never want to have infinite armor you have to have Excel points which are the points to be able to summon creatures no and there are three functions as you can see  They are methods of the C Player ztps http class and have as argument an argument that is of float type no which is basically life or armor or points no So I have to do these more yes So if I didn't know more  more this we said more willing I have put it now that is, I did this exercise I did it now but I without knowing more more without knowing anything that is, I had barely read or  n a little bit of Sembrador and I started doing things in this, how do I do this, in assembler because I didn't know, that is, it was my first language, I was learning And that's where we can all start doing reversing, how can we do that? Well, I have to tell you that it could be that  It was a set of coincidences, coincidences that I had just gone to this internet booth, coincidence that this person brought this chip and that it interested me a lot, coincidence that the rakion burned game has many decorators, yes, that is to say, they can give you information  of the function that is what the function does as you can see there zhp c Player what you see below that chain below [Music] and this set of coincidences were great because that's how it can start so if I have the left column I know more more  How do I do this, as it was good, as we saw, there were two functions that returned the pointer, so what we do is we call two functions in Win  dows that is using using using the previous function that we saw to be able to obtain the entity of the player that returns an object to you is Player, that is to say that doing what you see in the square can be done has the two worlds I know plus plus one side in Sower to  another to the other side then Ok Very well I have the object But what else do I do well when one feels seen that when we see we begin to see patterns What things can we identify What things can we take out What can we understand what I began to see were patterns patterns  of how many things were moved to the sx register they were moved to the sx register they were moved to the CX register and I didn't understand what it was so I searched on msn and there it explained that what the this object is was moved to the sx register So this this object  I had been registered I understood that when an object is created Yes, what Visual Studio does is that it internally builds this object and uses the sx register in a relative way to acc  Edit the members, for example, or the methods, or the virtual functions, and well, we're not going to go into that because it's not objective. So once I got the object, what I did was move it to the sx register and we simply called the function, as you can see  there was no Push of the argument called the function and of course this for me was, that is, it was like they were like discovering things that were behind the scenes and that they worked and the truth was that he had a great time, not while many stopped  spend money playing and I began to adjust the money programming things so I did all these things and the truth is that they seemed great to me I think that what I am telling you can be useful to you if you are not starting and want to start in this  It's not as difficult as it seems you just get on and sweat a bit very well so with this we have easily learned how to call methods of classes in assembler then but not only  It doesn't end there, but we also have to, for example, if I want to use an object and then I want to use that object. I don't know how to establish a certain state. Yes, how do I do it, for example, chaos Mode is he is he is a mode as you saw in the first video that the  player kind of changes its appearance and is usually stronger is the chaos mode Yes and inside is this that what you see there in assembler I don't know a menu It is a class that inherits from another class and has two values ​​chaos and no chaos basically then another  Maybe what I needed is to do what you see there in that line, not to do Chain Mode and the same chaos, that is, one.  we do a little more I didn't have much idea about that and I understood that there was something called constructors and the consultants what they do is initialize things Yes when they say when you initialize things Generally what initializes the sue classes  len be the since members of the class So when you see the constructor you can know what the class members are even if you don't have the name Because it says there this + 2 10 + 3 + 4 you don't know what it is but at least you know that  how many how many members does the class have so once i was able to understand this i didn't say ok ready i have a constructor what do i do now what do i do well i explain this so that it can be understood yes as you can see there in this month more when building a  object there is a layout if this depends If it is one if they are if it is inheriting virtual functions if it has base classes it depends on many things yes but in this specific case you have a virtual Pointer function but then at offset 8 is just the Mode how did I know that  How did I know that the exact mod that I needed to move the value 01 was there? Trial and error, it didn't have much mystery.  It worked but and testing you can do this so if I have, in short, I have what they sell in the Left Colony and I need to do something I didn't know I didn't know for a long time, the only thing I knew was assembler at that time so how do I do it? How do I do this?  in assembler, well, one understands looking at the code is that basically what it did is like this I didn't know it was 10, that is, it had come out a little bit but I had no idea because I had never programmed on it, more so than what I perceived  what I understood is that it was like a buffer where things were initialized so what I did was OK Yes it is a buffer I give it a buffer as you can see there you don't say it is a local buffer I move it to sx I call the constructor it initializes the Data  that you need to initialize later with disma 8 which is where the chaos mode is, it moves the value 1 0 depending on what I want and then I sent you the second part this second part because I know good mir  I check the Cross references basically I saw that this was done and I said I also do it I copied it and it worked but basically what it does is as in the previous case it returned the object already from within the game in this case not in this case it is a  new object because if you realize this is a local variable so for that I need that it be committed so without it it is for the change to be effective no But well no there is not much mystery in this the constructor was called and then it moves  that value 1 to 10 + 8 and then eax is this Yes because I could use eax or it says it doesn't matter because the slice returns the same value as the address of the buffer you are passing so it's the same Hey x6 in that case In the box  yellow very good Ok so I could do this chaos mode not that was seen in the first video but there is something interesting that I also wanted to do is that it is like being able to move the player in different places or how to do  I knew that, how could that? Well, what I have learned at school is that they only taught me that there were x and I didn't have the least that I had no idea that there was a Z axis. So I had to talk to a friend who was  the university and he explained to me a little how these things worked well and you can see the truth that in the first instance when I had at that time you used a little, that is, it was doing flashback Yes, because I wrote this a few weeks ago, that is, just  Today when I started to look again I understood that this is the code that is the most, but let's see, I didn't know how to write this code, you see there, I didn't know how to write that code, I learned it now, not now, but I mean, I did it now, no, but  at this time I didn't know that So as someone who doesn't know anything you can use a template you can make a class you can doing starting initializing constructors well basically testing a bit in this case to be able to do this  there was there was a function or this class called simple placement 3D Yes and but in this case there was no constructor So as you saw in the case of the constructor that tells you the members of the class in this case a life then what is it  I was doing well I began to look and I began to see that there was something called operator, maybe look for little information and they are called overrights Yes and basically so as not to get into this a little more basically what it does Is that I can put I can do  I can use the equal using using class objects c placement 3D no then obviously to do this overright of the equal what happens is that it has to be able to copy the first value the value on the right the Ray value the left value is called the value of  the left because there was one is equalizing so in order to do that you have to be able to access all the information and effectively copy it to the left value to the left value then  look there life was looking for me basically if there wasn't one thing I was looking for something else and so then I understood that overrights exist and that thanks to that I could know that there were two members in this class if the positions and angles how do you see that they are positions angles are not  I didn't know, we started putting fruit in and seeing what came out and thus deducing deducing you can understand and I think it's basically what we all do nowadays it's not like sometimes we don't understand things and we fight and well I'm going to put them in to see what  It comes out And sometimes it explodes and sometimes it does great things well no, it doesn't change much today I think Very good So I have placement position value and I have to have this on me more How do I do this again well as I told you it was a set of coincidences  The truth is that there was a function called get placement within the Player object and I say that it is a reconciliation game because everything had a decoration and that helped me.  to a lot in the reverse and I think that if it hadn't been for this, maybe I wouldn't have continued so much but well then Calling get Place I got the placement object Yes and then I knew that in the offset as you can see here 048 you can get the positions The  The x and z axes are not complicated, so you can see how the values ​​began to change, for example, the Z axis is changing, it does not go down, it goes up, it goes up the same Yes, but then other things occurred to me because they saw that at the beginning I showed them that it could also be obtained  the entities not only of my player but also of the other players I thought it could or could not be what Good thing to obtain because in the end when obtaining the sanctity in other players in the end it returned an object makes Player Yes so obtaining the object  c Player you could do the same thing we were doing here today so I was able to do this I could read I could read the positions We have to follow and this from the other players  It is Yes and I could do two things I could cross them out as you can see that I was chasing them like a stick figure or it could be that they came towards me well And that still needs to be optimized a bit but and they came towards me all the time then  I'm going to do these fun things where I could move players put a loop and move them to the side and not make them move or they all come at me like a vacuum Yeah and kill them there Hold on I have low battery alright alright  then another very interesting thing that I wanted to do is about being, they saw that all the characters have stats so how do I modify the stats yes How are they modified This good This Windows is Windows ranking changed it because before it could be modified in a file they had  on the disk it changed it, it was no longer there yes So when I first started searching what I did was Search for the name of the character having watched it change and know what I found then  s this character is Machine you can see there and then there are some values ​​that constantly change all the time and these values ​​caught my attention a lot I didn't say but I mean why do they change all the time something is happening there so what I did  It was basically how I had a detector from The Wagners, an anti-chip, what I did was very clumsily disconnected the internet from the virtual machine, I activated the value of [Music] and put a Breaking on this, an Access, there is a Hardware Access to know what addresses were  they wrote there no, as you can see, it came out saying who is writing and then there was a function that makes a class called Genesis as seen there in the eye then searching I realized that there was a two functions called set and get  I spend time I was more or less 16 years old and I had started the Institute in Peru the Institute is not like a university but it is in the middle is finishing school so they were in  Teaching a little algorithm and such and such and more or less I knew that it was a setter and that it was a getter, yes. So when I found out that we already want to be with eternal, it really caught my attention, but as they realize, it's like you look at them and  For the first time it's like I don't understand anything the same thing happened to me I don't understand anything anymore I didn't understand anything what is a thing What a thing these things were I knew it was a pointer because I had already read that it was that I knew that something else had to happen I knew it was  a Dish because I had already done things with it but I didn't know many other things so what I began to look at were the references to know what things happened there. So it is interesting that the way in which those places were written  that they changed all the time it was not it was not usual how to write a value as in a variable in this case it changed a lot and you had to follow this that that way of writing it you have to do a short it was super  strange Yes but basically you have the value where you want to write the address where you wanted to write Yes and then obviously you pass them as arguments as you can see there but then this address plus 4 the content was sorted Yes with Yes with the same air with the with the  address that is the content of the erosion plus 4 makes a short with it with the address and after doing that the function was called it was very strange but it worked magically it worked then obviously those 999 was not 999 if not that you do not realize  account I was programming there in the internet cabin while I was programming vital because Even while we were at the Institute we had no way of buying a computer in my house and while I was programming these things and I was testing and such and such I grab while people are playing  We program, I inject the dll, it works and it starts to scream and all the people look at me, what's wrong with this madman? Well, this happened to me that I caught and could  do this kind of thing not that that and that it not only worked with the with the games he said with with the values ​​you see there you see the original values ​​but you could also do with the with the items if you know you could also change the values ​​like this and it was super  interesting for me because you can start to discover things very How things worked inside How these worked And how how could I modify them and this brings me to my first Bot and the first Bot that I made I'm going to tell you a little bit quickly this is about  the stages the States Son are like missions girl mission depends what things are done that mission in this mission is specific it has a death counter that is, every time you ride a creature the counter tells you and what I did in this in this  case is that I developed my own scanner that is to say because because because each game this is a Data Setup point xfs is a resource file within the game that had, let's say, informatio  ion of each scenario as you can see there you are not some two three four give information with example the creatures the positions the creatures in the game etc. no so what I did is that since I didn't know how they found a long time ago I didn't know how to find those those those  routes in memory what I did is create my own scanner I programmed all assembler my own scanner and what it did was look for that route and replaced all those stage 0203 all to one Yes because it did that good because the fact that that counter is there me  It illuminated because, as we saw at the beginning, if I have a value that changes constantly, you can find it with the Chinese engine like this. If you change three, then four, then to 5, it is a value that is being compared and then it remains as with the address, then there was the maximum value there.  is 100 and you pass the mission with the maximum Range so I knew that if I moved I found the memory address and moved the value 100 I could reach that or that is  That is the maximum value if I am going to reach 100 then Knowing this having this premise what occurred to me is that what I could do is to move all these values ​​that is to say that all the all the all the scenarios are like scenario one modifying  that memory yes and finding that thing that you see there that number 3 in memory and modify it and well This is a little from my scanner I learned a little It was great because I learned a little how it worked a little inside the exceptions no and well and the  1-0 obviously because Little indio is there you have to write it backwards but that's 01 not from the stage and of course the problem The problem with this is that I'm going to put my video this you're sorry for the quality but I recorded it a long time ago No  I think it's heard But there's a lot of noise behind it Even at one point they asked me if I rented another half hour because my time was running out but what I did was the problem at this beginning was that I had  I have to kill the creature so that it gives me level number 100. Yes, the problem is that I had the textures of the game that I was creating, but the coordinates of the creatures from the game in scenario 1, so each scenario obviously has different coordinates because they have  that this is obviously because the scenarios are different So the problem there was that I had to find a scenario big enough for at least one creature to appear for me to go kill it and be able to get the range the maximum Range no then testing testing testing testing  I found that there was a scenario that creates 49 and that you couldn't do that. So I go jumping there is a creature I kill it and this is the maximum Range So internally what I did was move that value 100 to the counter but this this scenario doesn't  It was the scenario of death counters, but thanks to doing that, that game could get there by doing this, we don't believe  s very good but the best thing is because I realized that there was like a Loop that accessed that field all the time Yes then if I played that function that is there and moved the value 100 directly Then I didn't need to kill  the creature because there was a look that accessed that value all the time I don't know why but it did it so I got to do it doing that and how I learned to make a Hook Well thanks to chickenji the chickenjing in one part has a tutorial that is  it calls coldcafe or code cave that explains how you can do this So when I knew you could do this and I started looking at making tutorials my mind lit up it said Ok those things I can't use here which is basically like we could almost say how  It works a little Frida how these things that are used a lot today don't work.  we could take it and well you put music on it too so as not to get bored and it sounds like an improved version no but you say Ok you are great what I wanted to do with this is that everyone can start in reverse engineering everyone is not that difficult they just need a lot of desire because more  At once I wanted to leave it and thanks to that today I work on this I have been doing reverse engineering for approximately 15 years and now I dedicate myself to making exploits for the carnal Windows among other things but basically that and that it is available to everyone is not  It's so difficult to do it, it's just to put on and keep going and sweat a little because these things are not easy But we can do it and well now that I show it and you'll see how it works Well that's what we did there was record the coordinates of the mouse with a key  to make the boat much faster, so what you did is that you pressed a single button, it created the scenario, it doesn't matter what you believe in, it doesn't matter, a single button was enough for you  s and the Bot worked by itself so there it will enter the stage and once it enters it dies and wins and so on constantly in all scenarios and thanks perfect if anyone wants to ask a question the microphone is in the middle they can come closer if not  you can raise your hand I can bring the microphone closer to you So nothing personally I have a question to ask you If you started programming in assembler Yes I personally learned to program with javascription two very different languages ​​what would you recommend me to do what did you get Well  by learning to assemble first Well I dedicate myself to that basically, that is, to do, for example, exploration, malware analysis, basically, we see assembly code all the time, so it depends on what you are doing, what you want to do, did you see, for example, if you are going to do  web developer I don't know if you use tremor clues but if you want to dedicate yourself to doing reverse engineering it's mand  to know assembler Thank you very much does anyone have any questions How are you Good first congratulations because what is explained is wonderful and I have Well actually two questions the first is mechanics of doubt How did you come to know what value to put so that your little spider asked me  also when they gave it in an internal chat Yes, the Data Setup that I showed before was eligible before it could be read and inside were not only the scenarios but also the resources of the game, such as the items and also the creatures and the identifiers were there  So I knew, that is, because I was already doing things before, these four values ​​were specifically from the spider because I already knew it before. So when they made that patch, it worked for me to continue doing and Show what views and the second one would be I understand  that this works for applications that run on the same installed system not like a  native applications I think they call it in case if it were a game in the browser it would also be the same idea Or it would have to be in a clear way Yes yes if it were the browser in theory it should be a little simpler because that is me what what  I must understand is that they must use, that is, code on both the server and client sides, and the client is probably using Script key, probably after Script years, you will have to look at the functions, yes they are implemented And the good thing about the key is the good  the browser is that it has a built-in debagre So you don't have to go and to make an antichip as it was in this case you see having where they go to built-in you can call functions modify things modify various global views so that's the great advantage of it being a  game in browser having a built-in debate is basically having to leave the door open for you thank you very much well we say goodbye The talk With a big
hug thank you