[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Applause]
[Laughter]
that's all I got
um hi I'm Maddie Stone and this talk is
all about a Samsung in the wild exploit
chain
so as I said that's my name that's me
um I am a security researcher at Google
project zero and we are a team of
offensive security researchers so the
majority of our team is focused on
vulnerability research exploit Dev to
show what are attackers likely doing to
find the same bugs
Etc but my role is focusing instead
first off on the zero day exploits that
are actively exploited in the wild so
the ones that the attackers are actually
using not the ones that they could
hypothetically be using and as a
refresher a zero day vulnerability or a
zero day exploit are those
vulnerabilities that Defenders don't yet
know about so there's not the patches
available for them we don't realize
there's a hole there that could be
exploited only those attackers know
about the hole so that's what I focus on
on a day-to-day basis
and so my whole role and my job and goal
is we learn from all of these zero days
that are discovered in the wild that are
detected and make sure that we learn as
much as possible from them in order to
make it harder for the attackers to come
back write another zero day and use it
against folks
so that's what this talk is about
specifically it's about a sample that
was found in the wild which involved
which targeted Samsung devices and
involved zero days
so this sample was obtained by the
Google threat analysis group
um and they attributed this sample to a
surveillance vendor commercial
surveillance vendor so this sample in
particular was a native library for an
Android app and it involved three
different zero day vulnerabilities that
were zero day at the time of the
discovery of the sample the sample was
discovered during a testing phase or
during a texting practice so we did not
we were not able to see or study the
whole chain from start to finish this
sample is also from late 2020 so that's
an important thing to keep in mind when
we sort of evaluate the state of the art
what was vulnerable what was not Etc
so let's walk through what we're going
to cover in this sample we did not
include or we did not there is not the
initial attack Vector included in this
sample so the sample is a native library
that would run within an Android
application so that means that the
initial attack Vector could have been
some vulnerability in a common app where
they knew they could then load this
library to run or it could have been
something like campaigns we saw earlier
this year where attackers were able to
have apps install installed on their
targets phones but either way we know
that we're starting in sort of the the
least privileged app context which is
called untrusted app so that's where our
exploit we're analyzing starts from
so the first thing it does once it's
running and loaded in this untrusted app
context is it's going to use a
vulnerability to get arbitrary file
system read or write
then it's going to figure out how to
load its next stage in a more privileged
than untrusted app more privileged
contest
a system app
then we're going to use another
vulnerability to leak information from
the kernel
finally we have a privileged escalation
through the display Processing Unit
driver
and whoa then we're going to talk about
how it got root from there so we have a
lot to cover in 15 minutes
um all three of these vulnerabilities
were patched in March 2021 and the
Samsung March 2020 2021 release
um yeah
so the devices that were targeted with
this chain were specifically Samsung
exynos devices so if you're not aware
Samsung devices sort of run on two
different CPUs devices sold
predominantly in the United States and
China as along with a handful of other
countries run Qualcomm CPUs whereas the
rest of the world largely runs on the
Samsung in-house developed chip the
exynos specifically this chain could
only target those exynos devices because
vulnerability 2 is triggered using the
GPO the GPU driver that is specific to
the exynos chips and vulnerability three
is specifically in the driver that only
runs on these exynos and lastly it
targeted phones running kernel versions
4.14 and so in late 2020 when these were
zero day and the sample was found this
would have included phones like the
mid-tier A50 A51 along with the flagship
S10
so
why did I think this was interesting
enough to share about this sample
first off I think anything in the wild
is generally pretty interesting there
aren't a huge number of those samples
that we get to discover and get a ground
truth of what our attackers actually
doing versus what do we think attackers
are doing so that first off
but secondly all three of these
vulnerabilities are in manufacture
specific components
as Android vulnerability researchers
this is talked about but it doesn't tend
to be the focus of a lot of
vulnerability research who are
publishing blog posts generally just
because then your exploit will be
specific to the manufacturer so instead
the Upstream Linux kernel the AOSP is
what tends to get a lot of the looks and
research done so that's interesting here
and also as you'll see our first
vulnerability we're going to cover is
sort of the foundation of this whole
exploit chain and it's in a Java
component which is interesting because
vulnerability researchers were usually
focused on memory corruption bugs which
will exist in compiled code
so let's jump into it here is our first
vulnerability as I said it was patched
in March 2021 and it is a arbitrary file
system read and write via a clipboard
so this yellow box the one in the bottom
left is the one that we are starting in
so we're running in our untrusted app
context
and before we jump into this we need to
understand a little bit about what our
content providers in Android so they are
a component that basically allows for
the storage and system-wide access of
data because Android has sandboxes that
you know tries to separate data from
each other so the content providers is
what says let's one app contact or see
your contacts because that's stored in a
separate context provider and so this
data is stored in you know sort of like
sqlite tables
and a key aspect of it is that according
to spec content providers are required
to implement these six abstract methods
the first five the all of them except
oncreate are called by a client who
wants access to the data
the other key thing to note about
content providers is that by default all
applications can read from or write to
your content provider even if the
underlying data is private
so when you create a content provider if
you do not go through the necessary
steps for Access Control and permissions
it is going to be device accessible
across the board
usually these permissions will be set
via the app's manifest file
where they can set you need this
permission to read or write Etc
but this is where our bug comes in
our content provider doesn't actually
exist inside of an app it's running
within this server or the system server
which is a jar file
so it's required to do all of its own
Access Control
one more foundational step before we can
really get into it is Android file
permissions so Android uses a
combination of Linux file permissions
you know read write execute along with
SC Linux and so the system user on
Android devices is the most privileged
user on the device besides root
and the system server SE Linux context
is very privileged because it manages a
whole bunch of services critical to your
device think of connecting to Wi-Fi
location stuff so it has to be
privileged to do all of that
and so one thing to keep in mind as
we're talking about a lot of access
stuff through that throughout this
presentation is that to have access to
something a component needs both the
requisite Linux file permissions as well
as be in an accessible SC Linux context
so in our case this clipboard provider
which is a custom Edition by Samsung
um runs within this privileged system
server so here are some of the variables
associated with it we have the database
name clipboard image the table name the
URL to access the content provider and
then the table
and the key part of this that sets us up
for this arbitrary file system read and
write is the name of this column here
underscore data
because underscore data is a special
sort of nomenclature and means something
specific in these Android content
providers it allows direct access to
files on the file system so if you have
a path in a column named underscore data
then you can use this helper function
open file helper to directly open it
without having to work with all of these
underlying operating system internals
so this is the insert method within the
Samsung clipboard provider provider
and what I would like you to note is
there is insert and then the function
just runs it just runs insert there is
no access checking before that first
insert call
and because this is not an app and
doesn't have a manifest that means
there's no access checking at all
because it would require some sort of
vetting at the beginning of this
function for there to be any
so this is how you trigger the
vulnerability so what our exploit did or
not my exploit the exploit analysis I'm
probably going to mess that up and say
that a lot it's going to get me in
trouble here
um is first we need to create the
content values and so this is just you
know the Java object that's going to say
hey I want to put this value associated
with this column or key so in this case
there is the column the underscore data
a special one and then this file path
data system users xero new file bin
then we have the URI to this special
clipboard provider
and then we call insert so we are adding
this new value to the table saying this
custom file path goes in as data and
then we receive back a URI that points
directly to that row
that new URI
is the only thing that needs to be
passed to open file descriptor
with whatever mode you want to run in to
then receive back a parcel file
descriptor which is a Java object
for whatever path you put in there and
finally then
a parcel file descriptor defines a
function or method called get FD so you
can get back the raw file descriptor
so pretty straightforward using that
underscore data column
but how do they use this so they
ultimately use this vulnerability four
times throughout this exploit the first
time here was to drop the stage to
exploit and so we drop it at this path
the dropped elf at that path will now
have a SC Linux context of of user
system data file so the key here is that
apps do not have access to create or
open those files but system server did
so the exploit proxied that create and
open functionality to through the
privilege system server process got back
a raw file descriptor and then they were
able to read and write to that file
so how was this bug fixed
basically just adding an access check
they added this check at the very
beginning of the function that says what
uid is calling me and they verified that
anything that is calling this function
is also already running a system
so we now have our stage 2 elf on the
file system but how do we load it we're
still running in this unprivileged
context but we want to start running in
a more privileged one
so this dropped as a background this
drop file is another app native library
and we know that because its starting
point is a function called jni on load
which is a built-in aspect of java
native libraries
and so the exploit ends up using this
app that's pre-installed on Samsung
phones called Samsung text to speech to
load and execute stage number two
so the Samsung Text-to-Speech app is a
system app running on all Samsung
devices it's pre-installed part of the
system image and it is not quite as
privileged as system server but is still
much more privileged than the untrusted
app context we're running in it's
running as a system app and so there
were many versions of this application
that would read a settings file
of this application and then just load
whatever native or whatever path was
there in the settings so the exploit
took advantage of that because they had
this first clipboard vulnerability that
allowed them to write and read to
arbitrary files on the file system
so by changing that they were able to
get their stage 2 Library past a
system.load which would load it and
begin executing jni onload
so what this looked like is actually
pretty straightforward they ended up
using the clipboard vulnerability to
write it to two different settings files
because the path was slightly different
based on the device version so the user
de so many people have thought that
meant it was targeting German users it
does not de stands for device encrypted
so just to clear that up off the bat so
it wrote to both of these files just in
case instead of checking which version
it was running on and it just changed in
the XML file this highlighted bit of
what is your engine path and it changed
it to their stage two
so now we're executing as a more
privileged system app
and this is when they jump into the next
two vulnerabilities the first of one
being kernel information leak
so what they're going to leak is the
task struct address and assist call
table address the task struct address
will be used to access the address limit
um member of the test truck because the
adder limit is important for the kernels
functioning and will be how they end up
getting arbitrary kernel read and write
the syscall table address they used to
break k-a-f-l-r
and basically all they do for this info
leak is abuse a worn on worn on Macros
are used in the Linux kernel to debug
kernel failures and because they're
supposed to only be used for kernel
failures they include a whole lot of
information in their logging when
they're hit including a full back Trace
which included stack contents
so this is the worn on that they were
abusing in the exploit this is a
function within the Mali GPU driver the
Mali GPU is one of the generally two
common GPU drivers that are used in the
Android ecosystem and so there was this
worn on right here
so basically what this is is this is an
eye octal call and if the ioctal is
passed an invalid command number one
that doesn't actually exist within the
driver then we hit the worn on
so this is all they had to do to trigger
that is they get a file descriptor
handle to that specific ioctal driver
and then they pass in this invalid
command and now they've hit the worn on
after hitting worn on a few different
times to make sure you got the good logs
they then turn on a bug report
um oops
so they end up calling these to set
build properties for First a full bug
report from dump State and then they use
CTL start to initiate the bug report
ctl.start property looks in this the
operating systems init to try and find a
service and start
so this was a little funny because we're
running in a system app context
at least on AOSP you know the Baseline
open source version of Android
apps can't call CTL start because it is
a basic sort of aspect of the
initializing services within the
operating system
so I ran SC search on the device to see
huh how is this able to do it and lo and
behold there was a whole lot more access
to this CTL start property than what I
was expecting and so including system
app did in fact have permission to start
and set the property and that was how
the exploit was able to initiate a bug
report
so then I opened up dump state which is
the binary that this bug report service
would call dumpstate is an aspect of
AOSP but it had been modified as a part
of this Samsung device specifically for
this line right here at the beginning of
the dump State function which
copied all of the contents from proc
seclog to this file datalog seclog.log
proc seclog is also a special
customization for
Samsung devices that have more sensitive
security logs and usually apps would not
be able to access contents like K
message which is where things like worn
on are usually lobbed but through proc
seclog to data log seclog they did get
access
and so specifically here this was an
example of the back Trace printed or
logged whenever the worn on was hit
we have in this raw stack contents our
test struck address as well as assist
call table address and so the exploit
had hard-coded knowing that it was
looking for the values at b60 and BC 0.
so how did Samsung fix this first
dumpstate no longer writes to seclog log
log because the other thing was this
seclog log had very permissive SE Linux
permissions so that apps could widely
read it they also removed this bug
report service from dumpstate.rc because
this service was a customization not
found in as OSP but there also had been
changes made in Upstream components that
would prevent this type of vulnerability
in the future so the first one had been
in February 2020 arm Who develops the
Mali GPU driver changed that warn on we
were looking to a PR worn which is a
much more appropriate sort of function
or macro to have there because it does
not print a full back trace and secondly
in April 2020 Linux did remove printing
the raw stacked contents in back traces
for arm64 because they realized like
this is sensitive and doesn't have a
huge amount of actionable info
now we get to our previous
so along with the other two this was
also patched in March 2021
so here we are we're still running as
our system app content context but we've
linked two pieces of information from
the kernel
what now
so the vulnerability is a use after free
of the file struct
and specifically it is in Samsung's
version of a driver for the display
Processing Unit which they called in an
upstream commit Decon to Stanford
display and enhancement controller is
the new IP and exynos 7 sock for
generating video signals using pixel
data so that's what we're looking at
that's where this use after free exists
and so this use after free will be
triggered again through an eye-octal in
the Decon driver but first the exploit
needs a file descriptor to be able to
call an eye optyl on that driver and
that's not as straightforward as a sound
because the full path for this driver
can live in many different places so
what the exploit didn't know is that the
path would include Graphics slash fb0 in
the path but that leaves a whole lot of
different options
so instead to figure it out they've made
a three-step approach
first they wanted to find the paid of
the process that's running that driver
or find a pit of a process that they
knew would be running that driver in
this case that's the graphics composer
process which is the Hardware's
abstraction layer on Android devices for
the graphics
then they it once they find that PID
they iterate through the processes file
the script or table and using read link
to find any of the full paths for each
file descriptor that is open in that
process and then finally they will use
our vulnerability number one to open the
FD again
so first how do they find the PID so
they actually connected to log reader
which is one of the basic sort of
Android operating systems that sort of
you know controls logcat in a way so
that's what it's similar to and so they
connect to a socket via there say they
want you know a whole bunch of logs
including the system logs and the Crash
logs and then they just wait and read
and look for the term display
and when they find the term display at
the beginning of a logging message they
then look at what PID was printed along
with that term and that's how they find
the PID of the graphics composer process
so now we have a PID which means we can
iterate through proc PID FD table and so
they literally start at the beginning
and open up each one called read link on
it to see what the full path is check if
that full path contains graphic fb0 once
they found it that was the path they
would then use with vulnerability number
one to open a file descriptor to that
path which is the Decon display driver
so the use after free was also a pretty
common pattern that we have seen amongst
Colonel drivers before
so first the driver required acquires a
file descriptor an FD for a fence we
don't really need to know all about
fence internals but the basics is is
that a fence is used in kernel drivers
for sharing buffers and synchronizing
access between different drivers or
processes
so first it's going to acquire that FD
and then it's going to associate that FD
with a file struct in this case it's
sync file in the file pointer member of
that
then the driver is going to call FD
install
FD install makes a file descriptor
accessible from user space so before we
were just sort of access all operating
in the kernel so now the driver has said
hey userspace you can do operations on
this FD now too
and when FD install is called it
transfers the ownership of the reference
to the FD table
so in this case if the driver had the
only reference to the file struck that
it's associating here and passes it to
the FD table
and user oh I'm jumping ahead and the
user calls close
then that closes the only reference or
freeze closes the only reference on that
file struct in the file struct is freed
but the driver does not realize that and
assume that that file strict is still
accessible and legitimate and will
continue to access it and that's how we
got our use after free
so specifically in this case looking at
the code from the driver we have this
function Decon set when config which is
accessible via an eye-optal so the first
thing it does in this highlighted
portion is it calls deconcreate fence
which is going to acquire that file
descriptor for us and assign it to
retired fence so I know it might not
sound like it if you haven't but retire
fence is actually the file descriptor
then we're going to call FD install so
we're saying hey you can associate
retire fence FD with this file pointer
in the sync file struct
or yeah
and then we call deconcreate release
fences with that same sync file
and
sync Decon create release fences will
acquire its own FD and assign that to
relfits
and then it calls FD install this time
though they do take an additional
reference out using that git file but
they're using that same file pointer
again the one that was just freed by
user space
so at the end of the concept Wing config
we have two fds retire fence which is
the closed FD that pointed to our free
file struct and Rel fence which is an
open FD with an additional reference
taken on it but still to our freed file
struct so that's our use after free
so the exploit strategy of that use
after free that was taken was that we're
gonna or the exploit replaces the freed
file struct with a newly controlled file
stuff you know one that they fake and
create and set different members of
they're going to set the private data
member that's within that file struct to
point to the adder limit
we're going to then use signal FD to
modify the adder limit and that's how
it's going to gain arbitrary kernel read
and write so that's the overview of what
we're about to cover now I'm going to
get into the details of what that means
and what it looks like in this case
so to back up what is the adder limit
it's the address limit as I said before
it's a part of that member of the task
truck and it sets what is user space or
user space is able to write to any
address below the adder limit so when
we're in user space you know that's
usually user DS
which is set to seven ffff
for arm 64. and then for kernel it's set
to negative one here being you know the
highest value so the kernel should have
access across the board
signal FD which we're going to use to
write that outer limit is a syscall
um that usually is for creating a file
descriptor if you want to Monitor and
accept different signals that are being
sent to your process
and but the key here is that we're not
actually going to open it on and ask it
to open a new file descriptor we're
going to call this on one of these fake
ones that we create
and when that happens it only updates
the eight byte mask
oh yes see I really emphasize that
so this is the signal FD function from
this kernel and the key Point here first
is that the syscall expects you to pass
a mask of the signals you want to accept
but the kernel stores masks as the
signals that should be blocked so if
you're first say using this later on
just keep in mind that first it will
mask out the Sig Hill and the six stop
bits but then it's an inverse so when we
want to have negative one or ffff
written to the address limit we will
actually pass zero into the signal FD
because of this flipping
then there is this Branch where if you
pass in a file descriptor of negative
one you're telling it to open up a new
file descriptor and create a signal FD
file descriptor but we're going to
follow this else Branch here
so first off a part of this signal FD is
it has this struct signal FD context CTX
CTX is a pointer to a signal FD context
struct which only has one member which
is the Sig mask which six set T is also
an unsigned long
to keep in mind so we're going to set
that to our private data member of the
of the file struct for the FD that is
passed into the syscall
the man page says that whenever you use
signal FD and you're going to specify
your own file descriptor but it must be
a an existing and valid signal FD file
descriptor the only check for that is
checking if the F member of the file
struct equals signal FDF Ops so that is
something we can get around with our
fake dropped
lastly this is where we do our right so
we're going to set the context Sig mask
Into the Now knotted mass that was
passed into signal FD
but because we set context to the
private data this is equivalent to us
saying file private data Sig mask
equals Sig mask
which we will get to in a minute here of
why that's interesting so these are the
different members set in the
exploits fake file strikes that they
sprayed all over the Heap to get their
replacement the first one wasn't really
used I think they were just using it for
maybe identifying their own file structs
the second one is we're using the
syscall table to calculate signal FD
epops so that we can pass that check we
just talked about
then they use 7f as a reference count
and that's basically being used to
identify when they have successfully
replaced the freed object
um unfortunately there was not enough
time to get into this but there will be
a blog post published later this week if
you're interested in the internals of
the Heap spray and how they do the
replacement
and then finally they set private data
to at our limit pointer
oh okay I forgot
so since now private data equals the at
our limit pointer
that means that when signal FD updates
the Sig mask we're actually overwriting
the outer limit so we have this pretty
strong primitive now or the exploit does
of a repeatable stable right to the
address limit
but not so fast it's not done we can't
just say great we have arbitrary kernel
read write done because there have been
two mitigations added to Armed CPUs and
most modern Android devices now use the
rv8 CPUs which include these exploit
mitigations called user access override
and privilege access never uao and pan
so pan protects against the kernel
accessing direct directly accessing user
space memory
whereas user access override works with
pan by
allowing unprivileged load and store
instructions to act as privilege load
and store instructions when the uao bit
is set we'll talk about what this looks
like in practice now
so this is an example kernel write
function that myself and Jana horn used
in an Android exploit from 2019.
and so the way that before uao and pan
that you could do this arbitrary kernel
read and write is you open up a pair of
pipes
to do a kernel write for example you
would write the address of the buffer of
the content you wanted right written
into the kernel to one end of it and you
would read it into the into the kernel
address that you wanted to write to on
the other end
so the reason why this no longer works
is first if pan is enabled because at
our limit is set to Kernel DS
then we cannot do this right because its
buff is in user space memory and
privileged access never permit
prevents the direct access to user space
memory but let's say we set kernel DS to
something else so pan wouldn't be on
that's when uao comes into play
uao will not be set if kernel DS doesn't
equal or if the outer limit does not
equal kernel DS so then this call will
fail because we're trying to access
kernel memory with unprivileged load and
store instructions
so this is what the exploit did
basically they just switched the outer
limit back and forth between user DS and
kernel DS so I don't really call this a
bypass because they're just working
within the way uao and pan are supposed
to work so walking through this
first we have two rights to one end of
the buffer it's the buffer we want to
write into the kernel as well as a
pointer to the user yes value
then it cause this function set at our
limit to Kernel DS which sends a signal
to another process in the exploit to
tell to do the whole signal FD
process to send the adder limit to
Kernel DS
it then does a little bit of a sleep in
there to wait to make sure that that set
occurs and then it can move on to the
Reeds so now that we're in kernel DS it
will read the contents from the other
end of the pipe into the kernel address
and now it's done it's kernel right
and so it will then set everything back
to user DS so that it always enters
these functions as user DS reading back
to that pointer
so I think this is especially really
interesting just because yeah they
didn't need a bypass for ual or pan
because it the Primitive was so strong
for the outer limit that it just sort of
works exactly with uao and pan toggling
that Adder limit back and forth they
didn't have to use set FS which is
usually the function that folks will use
to change the adder limit and but set FS
includes mitigations of like making sure
that
um
that at our limit is set back to a user
space address when returning to user
space and things like that so the the
Primitive that they got really is what
enabled them to get around uao and pan
without really having to bypass anything
post-exploitation
so they've gotten their arbitrary kernel
read and write what do they do to root
honestly it's pretty boring
they follow exactly what we've seen many
many Android exploits do for years is
they overwrite the current processes
cred struct to get root privileges and
then they overwrite the current SC Linux
context to voldi where Vol D is the
volume Daemon and while it is a user
space process even in Android's
documentation of sort of security
boundaries they treat it as if it's
kernel because it has a lot of access
um unfortunately this sample did not
include the final payloaded implant but
based on it being attributed or believed
to be associated with a commercial
surveillance vendor I'm guessing it
would likely look like the surveillance
spyware that has been we've been seeing
over and over again
so final thoughts
first
I think as much as we can see and talk
about and publish about these real world
examples of what attackers are doing is
really important because it helps us
know as Defenders where what is the best
return on investment in terms of
um
where we want to put resources is it
different fuzzing are there attack
surfaces that are being exploited that
maybe we need to focus on more are there
are mitigations that are not holding up
and need changes to them and things like
that so I think this is important in
that way
but
Earth and of those considerations of the
real world Tucker to me some of the most
notable is the example of
only targeting manufactured specific
components this is what we generally
assumed was happening this is what we've
heard anecdotally especially with the
increase in fragmentation across the
Android ecosystem but it's always good
to have that tangible example and in
this case also seeing that two out of
the three bugs are logic bugs there's
been so much focus on memory corruption
which I think is rightly so like memory
corruption is largely how all of the
zero days are happening right now you
know I think it was like 67 last year
but it's important to remember that we
can't just say hey write everything in
memory safe languages and things are
done from there
lastly remembering that Java components
are really good attack surface
but overall a lot of times when people
write about in the wild exploits and
zero days they're like most
sophisticated ever great attacker like
mind-boggling amazing
but really this exploit's pretty man
it's using a lot of techniques that
we've seen in public work before
none of the vulnerabilities were all
that awesome
and that comes back to us as attackers
because
attackers are having success with meh
types of exploits and so even if we
readjust our mind to oh this was found
in zero day two years ago still even in
that concept
even in that context these techniques
weren't were in use long before that
and this also highlights to me another
thing to keep in mind is transparency
around these in the wild
um zero days and it is something I have
been talking about many many times over
and over for the last few years of
studying these because knowing what zero
days are being actively exploited and
knowing the exploit techniques are in
use is how we can really then make
decisions of what types of steps to take
next so for example performing root
cause analysis to figure out what bugs
are the attackers going after performing
variant analysis to see are there
additional bugs that the attackers
likely know about that the vendor only
fixed one of
doing patch analysis to see if the
patches are actually sufficient what
types of detection techniques should we
invest in that may actually work because
the testing zero days is hard when
you're trying to detect something you
don't know what it looks like
lastly
it's not the end of the game when you
patch a vulnerability a vulnerability is
only useful if you can exploit it so
looking at exploit techniques how could
you block that and make sure they have
to come up with a new one instead of
being able to plug and play with a new
vulnerability and other hardening and
systemic improvements
and so all of that uh oh I think I lost
one oh I meant to say it somewhere else
oh it was in the mess section we can go
back to meh
um one thing that was interesting about
this exploit as well and especially
focusing on the Java components is that
they probably could have written this
exploit to only have to depend on that
first clipboard bug
that had system server arbitrary file
um file system access and so maybe they
didn't because they had this other other
infrastructure expecting kernel read and
write or something for the payload
but that really highlights to me how it
may be very worthwhile to do more
looking at these custom components and
things like system server
um even when they're Java and you're
thinking there's not going to be Memory
corruption because
yeah there's probably more they're
probably could have been some pretty
interesting ways to just leverage that
single vulnerability
um to meet their goal
and yeah so my goal is always to try and
learn from these zero days and I'm
always happy to chat and talk about zero
days on and on and on so I'm at Maddie
stone at Twitter or we have this email
address
for things and I keep a public tracking
spreadsheet of zero days in the wild as
well as we have a private not private
public repository of root cause analyzes
for that we're trying to cover all the
in the wild zero days but there tend to
be a lot more than there used to be when
I started that goal of covering them all
so yeah we also accept pull requests and
that's it thank you any questions
Guerrero
[Applause]
Savi
question
yes oh okay
so from what you described it seems that
this
exploit or the chain of exploits or the
overall program it's a quite reliable
meaning it works all the time so it's a
hundred percent reliability it doesn't
depend on uh but there's a uh user after
free maybe but it doesn't
the mitigations the current mitigations
do not seem to have made any dent
all right is it do you have any
reliability
um considerations or numbers or metrics
about this
um
so the question is are there
do you think or have you measure if this
exploit worked all the time 100 each
time you run it
um
I do not have metrics I do believe it
would be pretty reliable because each of
the pieces of it as long as you know
it's the right versions of the device
um were pretty reliable vulnerabilities
and of itself the clipboard right is
going to work every single time
the loading the exploit which wasn't a
vulnerability but loading it being a
Samsung app like that's straightforward
the kernel leak might be the one place
where you have to do it a few times but
there's not really then an issue with
running it a few different times because
it's not like you're going to crash the
device from that and then it seems like
the use after free was pretty stable as
well
thank you
hi congratulations for a fantastic talk
it's really honor to have someone from
Project Studio here Echo party so please
keep click keep coming and my question
is
um you just um basically like burn a
full exploit chain from a surveillance
webinar which is fantastic but what are
your thoughts about doing the exact same
thing maybe for the US government
[Laughter]
um I do not know when we see exploit
samples you don't know if there are bugs
in something they're being exploited I'm
gonna get them fixed
thank you
thank y'all