[Music] [Music] Let's welcome Roberto Fresca with a round of applause Hello, listen, How are you? Good afternoon, welcome, I'll introduce my name to Roberto Fresca. For almost two decades or more, I've also been part of the emulation and  preservation I am a member of the dumping Union and recreacionales org which are two organizations dedicated to preserving old Hardware through dumps and preparing things for future emulation Oh and I forgot I am very proud I am one of the developers of mami de  It's been more than two decades now and I have more than 500 games and platforms between platforms Already emulated Many thanks to a lot of honor Because I'm very proud of this I think that everyone already knows mamen what it is to multiply Machine emulator and it is the emulator par excellence of  these little arcade machines that are those pigeons those those little machines that we played when we were kids at least when I was half old that they handle with  Everything is small coins and whatever, but over time it didn't change and other types of devices began to be emulated, such as computers, Angel consoles, even washing machines.  more and more with this, emulation versus simulation, many wonder what emulation is and I am not going to go into much detail on this because a technical talk in 45 minutes imagines that this is flying and the content is extensive. So I am going to try to summarize  everything and to the extent that you have any questions then later you can ask and I am going to answer all the questions and for having the emulation itself to do it in Creole and in a few words It is simply the simulation of the components of a Hardware creating  a virtual environment this virtual environment this framework actually what it does is after executing the original program that goes into the Hardware haciend  or believe that it is in a real Hardware then we can have in a computer today practically the system working as if it were the real one I don't know if it was understood But well it is so easy we are going to try to explain a little because it is very difficult they are  extensive the complex part that emulation itself has that we are going to try to talk a little about forensics and the methods in which we acquire that data and then in a second part we are going to talk about the stages more or less of how it is done  reverse engineering to be able to emulate a game here what you can practically see is an old-style Hardware that like everything that is Even today it has its own cpu that can have one or more Ram ROMs it has microcontrollers there can be devices of  input without outputs sound devices video devices that are of different types Because at that time the Hardware was very custom there was no such thing as a PC that was all ig  Everybody, when they had a platform to make a game, to make a computer, whatever, they designed their own Hardware. So what we need is first to do an analysis of that Hardware, what else do we need to see the bus it's running on and the clocks it's running?  It is essential to know from those of the crystals How much is the clock that enters the clock that enters each of the components to be able to emulate like the people and then to preserve everything else that comes in  the equipment, if it is a computer, will have its media with floppy disk with hard disks with whatever there is flash memory and the little pig dhs tapes tapes and a lot of countless things that must be preserved to be able to have that system running let's go to the  Forensically, these old hardware actually contained all their information. Within this type of device, you can see there that they are iproms, which are chips, a  The integrated ones that store information, so everything that was a program, what was graphics, what was sound and other data, actually, what did they do?  guaranteed that the information could be kept for up to 30 years and that they were going to worry if they were going to go ahead because they thought that after 20 years nobody was going to activate those games those boards were going to end up in the trash they didn't have emulation So how  The information inside that chip is read very easily with that little device that you see up there, which is a diprons reader programmer with the chipa up there and connected to that device, it reads the binary that contains it, you can verify it and it's great, we already have everything, no.  More than 30 years have passed. So we have little problems with these types of chips that generally suffer from what they see up there, which is bitrrot, the Root bit is the degradation comes  of bit rotten, that is, of how to go, being practically a rotten bit, comes from the degradation of the material, as you could see in other media, such as old CDs, which are sold by many things that in magnetic media that cannot be read, time goes by  hatching and breaking down, the media degrades to the point that it cannot be recovered and the content cannot be read, and that is where despair comes, how do we get that information out? Well, we also have as a second possibility that the device is damaged, that it is  damaged in a physical or electrical way and it cannot be accessed in the case of the Beat, there are ways to change the physical forms such as temperature, pressure, etc. sudden changes in temperature that make it possible to have a reading more or less  constant and being able to recover that binary so so so so exquisite that we need for the emulation that is necessary is critical but many times it fails too  Also because in reality the device does not allow for more, so that is where reverse engineering comes in, where you have the best of the dump, a kind of curve is made and an average of the majority of the bytes that there are for each offset is maintained in order to have  let's say the best probability from there if it's a program we're going to find that we have illegal instructions and a lot of things that seem like they're not going to come on that side So it's about looking for which instruction should go that has a grit more than one  a certain way that is similar where there is a difference of one or two bits and it is a question of recomposing the program in such a way as to be able to have, let's say, a reliable copy of what it would be in the event that there are graphics once the graphics have been decoded  At the moment of demonstrating them, you will see the little dots that are lost that do not belong to the original Graphic and it is easier to rebuild it now, what happens when they are damaged  With the devices, for example, in an electrical way, it becomes more difficult because what we do there are solutions that are very expensive that are from high-level laboratories and others that sometimes one has to improvise. This that I am going to show is an example of a  board that they brought me many years ago that was unique, came from Eastern Europe and had a problem in the graphics, one of the graphic ROMs had the dressing 8, that is, the leg that belonged to 08 was totally burned, so to speak, and he answered us, no matter how much he asked.  change the temperature whatever we always had the same problem having Andrés without 8 dead makes you have the first 100 exam with the original Data And the second 100 already with repetition of the previous one and then you had a good strip and another with  repetition of the previous one well and another with a repetition of the previous one because precisely the 35 didn't work there what happened my friend Gabriel who is a genius of discreet electronics appeared  and he told me I have an idea Why don't we hack the ROM hack it seems to you that we could hack a device with these solid state characteristics that did not have a backdor Antonio had nothing where to enter it there was no way we had to look for a solution precisely and that's why  dealt with we tried first to see where the problem could be each leg of this device goes through a diode in this case we thought the diode was dead and what can we do to do this because we need to bypass this to hack the ROM and be able to  read the real and good content, it occurred to him to make a device in which it is a current Booster in which we can inject a certain current that replaces the programming current to be able to read and I put a strong current that would be more or less equivalent to the polap  that they have inside the board the project was quite ambitious because we needed to change the information of this iprom without t  having to alter the hysteresis of the circuit, which is quite difficult, but when it came to the realization that the short was not a total short and that we had about 18 ohms, something like that of resistance, a calculation was made more or less with five or six more or less  with 5.6 volts to be able to have the almost 300 milliamps that we need to confuse that device and be able to read it at the moment. Therefore, we designed this device that here we practically have the schematic to be able to achieve this prototype where Calzada La ROM was going and then  it was getting that specific current injected into it and it was trying to read at the time we were confusing the system would it work i don't know we tried it the first time and it didn't work it was a total disaster we had the same problem the same the same dump problems and it didn't work quickly  We corrected a lot of parameters of this and we were able to have a more precise dump with which we were able to recover those stripes of graphs.  things that we did not have and we were able to emulate the game correctly Colorado we saved a game from death with a Made In Argentina hack that for us has a lot of leverage as we went out to leverage at home and with what we had This is the second case of a problem  electrical that we can see this is from one and from naughty Boy Deco which is a bootlet that was quite important but as you can see the micro wire that is in the middle is like burned it does not reach the leg So how could this be fixed this already needed  a slightly denser solution which is what we do well time is short for me well here what you have to do is like a kind of camping take out the lid and try to find something like this what is this it looks like a sewing machine  They don't see the spool, yes, it's like a sewing machine, it's a Weber bonding, which is a device that goes with an electronic microscope. Once you took the cap off, you can't see it here, but there's  a command that is like a joystick that makes it practically move micro servos until reaching the axis with the hcz reaching where the short is and then with that reel that is a golden thread to be able to make the patch and with a heat method  to be able to seal it what happened well it's a matter of laboratory and expensive but we were able to achieve this this was done by recreational org there in Spain we were able to reconstruct that filament and it was put in a biprom reader programmer and we were already able to read the game which also  It is a very, very invasive and very, very difficult forensic method. What else is there to be able to dump bipolar prons into the plate, which are the ones that contain the information with which to make the palettes of the graphics that we are going to decode later and the  Others are pldés, which are chips that contain a series of equations in which they make transformations between the inputs and the outputs. They are generally used to obfuscate to be able to ca  change the lines of Andrés ungrateful and that it is not easy to copy a Hardware among other things no obviously another problem that we have is this I have had to emulate this that the cpubrics that instead of having a cpu have an epoxy brick that  it's hiding everything then by chemical means or physical means it's about melting a Mel down the epoxy revealing what's inside where one finds there's a cpu there's a program ROM that's hidden and other logic let's say logic devices to obfuscate can  be like in this case that instead of a ROM there is a Ram with the program and it is powered by the battery that the system has with the battery.  We don't have to do anything there anymore, the system is dead. But the idea is to try to melt it so as to be able to take the data from there in the event that there is an iprom and to be able to save the program  to later emulate it what else can we find microcontrollers and other custom chips that have nothing customes that are empty do not have marks and we do not know what there are then what is done in these cases what is called decaping is done the lid is removed  with different chemical or physical methods and then where the dae is, let's say the platelet, it is about micro-photographing to later find where the eprom and the content are and then by hand go making a map of those bits that you can see up here are the  ways to decap how to remove the cap on Day, which is the central part where you will see the Halo on one side, the e prom, the Flash, whatever until you find Where are the ipron data, which are these here once  found, you can see it here how they are interpreted as ones and zeros and then it is a matter of decoding and wrist to find it. What is the logical and boolean relationship to be able to rearm the binary that it has  Inside that good microcontroller, among these, there are other types of readings and things that I am not going to put much emphasis on, but everyone knows more or less what forensics are like to recover hard drives and other things that are more than good, we already know a lot about that here.  With the Eco Party, which is the only place where you can give something precise and strictly technical in the case of diskettes, I happened to see a person who was an expert in Europe when they asked him how they were going to preserve the diskettes  From that of a certain system, the chancellor became and said we have the original Hardware with an original Hardware How are you going to read floppy disks from 35 years ago? I remember when I had floppy disks a year later, they already had errors and could not be read, imagine  35 years later, forensic techniques are used in which, for example, the blogs that take the complete magnetic flux and then a Boolean assessment is made to be able to extract  r of tracks and I'm going to put together the structure of that diskette, we're not going to go very far talking about disks, we have this one, I don't know if you know it, but you've seen it at some point, here it is.  the size of the old vinyl Long Plays are laser disks Even though they have little mirrors and have lasers, they stored analog video Look how it can be analog And yes, they had an rf car that took that signal and then transformed it into video How could it be done  preserve and well at the beginning they tried to capture with capture cameras but it was not precise because there was what is down there which are the Philips codes which are some codes that looked like binary that appeared in the non-visible zone So they could not be captured and those codes  they are commands that said where the game had to go or where to which frame it jumped to etc. there were commands and they had to be preserved which one it was So there was no way h  until the approach appeared which is the dumpsday duplicator this is practically a development that a giant hack was made for the system that they did it precisely for an encyclopedia that the bbc published at a time that was called precisely that Tom save and the idea of  This thing about preserving those discs was not to capture the video but to do a Hack in such a way as to be able to take the rf signal from the pickup laser, hack it from there and bring it to expand it up to eight times the number of Nike Shannon, which would be the threshold of where you have to  Digitizing so that there are no losses is actually a highly complex system and with that lasers from both movies could be preserved. Only the game ones were comfortable, and those of us who were interested in some of us have heard of Marbella Vice, but not the one from GTA.  we are not talking about that way we are talking about something even worse much older it was a detective and police game starring Santiago se  gura and by Catherine fulop when I was young yes the Catherine fulop that we all know made this game that was an interactive game also based on the servís but you had to somehow preserve them and recreational org was able to preserve that laser video using all the techniques this forensic  that I just described now we have everything ready and now that we're doing it we put everything in the blender and whatever comes out This is not where everything that is reverse engineering and the technical part really begins You have to create a virtual memory maps  where they go where it is really going to be mapped Where are the components the cpu the ram the ROM the peripherals etc. we are going to take as an example in this case the most popular 8-bit processors that we already know what the bus is like and in this case a z80 or  We are going to see later a 65 02 and all its family in the case of the z80 everything, both one and the other, we know that it has a 16-bit address bus.  from 0 to ffff hexadecimal Or 65,565 if you want let's talk about now exa store and obviously It's 8 data What happens once we have it we start building a cpu because mommy it's made precisely by objects and we add the interruptions we put what  that we have to take into account how we map this because the z80 by itself luckily architecture has to have the program ROM at the beginning of the memory because we have in 66 and in 38 exactly the two pointers to interruptions  from nmi of the non-masked interrupt and from normal resources and then interrupts by Software that start at zero 8-18 10 18 20 28 exa and so then they have to go right in the lowest part of memory and we map Ram the working ram Generally  at the end of everything, which is where it operates. This is the case of the z80, which has different interruption modes, etc., we are going to see another case, which in this case is the 65 02 family, which is another ot  As a processor with different characteristics, in this case we have the pointers to the vectors at the end of everything, so the program ROM must be mapped at the end of this map, that is, against fff, because both the non-masked interrupt pointers and the reset pointer that  It is the pointer where the program is going to start and we have to follow the code such as the one for the interruptions.  the end of the memory and from the architecture we know that we have Ram in the first 800 where the first 100 exa are the famous zero page where the registers are what do we have to start putting together that memory map as that is where we start to see the  code we start the code where the reset vector goes and follow the code see what it normally does the first thing it does is try to initialize  ar some peripheral or another and there we go understanding what it does Where it writes and what it writes and to interpret each of those things out there grab a large offset and write a lot of things and verify we already know that there is RAM there and we treat it  as such as you can also try to get a pointer from a String of a phrase a word anything and try to write a character on one side and then in that guess what I know at address 2003 and then at 3003 try to put a  another character like this and another with differences of a thousand, so we know that in one he puts the String and below in the other he is putting the attributes of each of those characters that these attributes can be the color codes or they can be the bank of graphics to which  I'm writing down anything that remains then later we're going to it we're going to clarify what happens with all this Well we're going to see an example in this that this is a Hardware that once they brought me we didn't know what it was  The company is called Chang You and we didn't have the slightest idea what was inside. We only knew that it had a strange chip here, which we later realized it was. It made sense. We had an mcu, a microcontroller that has its internal ROM, so we couldn't get it out.  and we have a processor here with a microprocessor from the 65 02 family with its program ROM next to it and we said well, let's see what we do here in some way or another we have to see that it is listed we did a data survey of each of the things  and we said Well once we have Here we are going to see what we do with the memory map we start I'm leaving Sorry Here goes the first thing we do Is decode graphics because because we have when there is something to Show we have to Show something that is eligible so we take the  graphic ROM and we tried to make the different connections so as to be able to have something eligible as we did here that there are graphics of a single plane and there are graphics of three  bit Plains once the graphics are decoded, let's say good, cool, I start to follow the code to see what it does that writes, they do this offset that they do the other one and we can have I could get to have a data survey there are the cpus closest to being able to achieve a  memory map like this where I know where I have Ram Where I have the ports because this is handled by interrupts where I have where I have the crtc which is the controller of the cathode ray tubes where it will really give me what the grid and matrix are like  of video and the two the two video rams here one for the characters another for the attributes we have a guacho that is for resetting normal working memory and the program ROM here I am going to show you a video at this moment in which practically  I'm running for the first time this is this mapped to see how far it goes what can we do let's see let's see let's see I'll show you and this this what it is this is the first time I have  ne audio that he sends to a friend so let's see it totally gives technically there let's say the vectors are pointing to 8022 exa that would be the beginning of this what LD xf does the first thing it does is put the hexadecimal ff value inside the register  x transfer it to the stack after Clear tenth what it practically does is delete the decimal flag to be able to do certain operations 6 set interrupt here Put the interruptions per se load the register to which is the accumulator with 0 I don't know if you are following me with  practically zero and puts them and saves that zero the ideal content was achieved in 13 8 13 9 13a 13c3cv is practically cleaning those records because they are going to be records and that they will be useful for something later the same thing he does later loading c0 and they put them 3f and  in 828 and then the flow continues But hey, this is how you can practically follow the thing, we can follow each one of the things so that you will realize how you see how things are going and the  idea 00 in a no no does not change anything in the window on the left because a is still 0 they are put in all these directions and here it loads there it loads 0 So you can see it there that practically the record already has zero and  it transfers them here practically now it will load ff nothing Look how it changes now to the side where it says PC 8048 has aff and they put them 12 0 0 which is another registry let's say or initialization of another component they put three ff is doing registry cleaning no  it does not operate and with this it returns and decreases to x, but it is making a time Loop to wait for some peripheral to respond and then it decreases again and look at xsfa now f9 now f8 F7 and so on until it reaches 0 so how will it go  practically follow the list of this let's see we are there No now we go here and we are going to make a direct jump there that is already x reached zero and we go to this routine this routine loads x0 lda the value the value that is in 888  3 in that offset comma x and it puts 838 39 in 838 the value of X which in this case is 0 And in the one of n and it puts the one of a that is the one that is believed of the one of the offset 8.883 puts them in 8.39 what is  this then Ah [ __ ] increments X now x is worth 1 compares if I get to 12 exa which are 18 decimal values ​​and since it is not returns now x is worth 1 then it will read in a not 8.883 but indexed in x wanted 8.884 and puts x which is worth 1  here in 838 that before it was worth zero now it is worth 1 at 8:38 and 839 puts the new value that it read and thus increases the one that is now worth 2 and returns to being like this what is it doing here it puts 8:38  nes offset 838 the values ​​0 1 2 3 4 5 up to 12 hexa that we always speak in hexadecimal and in 839 the new values ​​that are read one after the other that are through the 8.883 that we have in 8.883 Let's see let's look for 8.880 80  81 82 83 from here onwards to here to here doing the whole line not the whole line and from below to here Read and  gravel in that what are these five nine forty-eight four f07 they are crtc records I already know them randomly when I see them from when I see them from touch and the way in which it records it records in the 838 the dressing and in the 839 the value of the  registry that is what it is doing well it is so that you have an idea of ​​the complexity of all this even after this it will obviously continue trying to initialize other peripherals I close here and you will see that I got to have interruptions that I already put  from nmi it comes to me as a kind of intro although the graphics are not correct the graphic banks are changed but it is for you to see after doing all the civilizations and all the ball you see what it does and I said and this the graphics are not  I'll tell you again, you have to find the right graphics to put it in. But look what it does, it's erasing part of it, it puts there something wrong and then I realized these are cyclical, so this is an intro.  or what it is doing is an intro with other graphics and there is another graphic availability but see if you pay attention it is an intro but with another one with Well what I wanted to show itself was practically that something was running that was like an atractra and we say good  It was all disorganized, which is what I did was try to fix the video to something else, realizing that what was missing was a video matrix and here in this short video I'm showing the same thing but organized with another  Note that the video matrix is ​​different, it already seems that there was an organization and that now you will also see that it appears as if it were part of what is giving cards. So we already had an idea that we were working but there was still work to be done here  there were a lot of things that are practically missing and I'll show you in the other one if you let me close this thing that won't let me.  and differently we run it and here we already have an improvement in which we already have not only the video matrix but also the size of the video Ram as it has to be to make it look clean and what we are seeing here is  the robbery that would be a title It just has the graphics changed because the graphic banks have to be changed But that would be cards and that they are being given that is, the game is working but there is still work to do on reverse engineering to be able to fix the graphic banks that  that's what it's about let's go back now what we did next with the graphic banks that have to be with real graphics where are the ones that have to be once decoded and know where they are we already have a title that I later found out is called May No  Neither I nor One and him so far I'm telling you this is an unpublished game because it's still not that bad, we're simply turning the Hardware around and there we realize that it's a game of 21  or Blackjack type but here the thing does not end It is still necessary to note that the beams are blue the colors do not fit so something had to be done with the colors and work with the color prom to try to have a more appreciated color and something that has to  being relative to the game, which is what I already achieved in this video where you can already see that the colors cycle cyclically, it is not appreciated very well in what is the title and then later in the cards and in the rest it is noticeable that  there are other colors that respect the colors of the cards. So we already knew that we were within the right step but now we have almost everything because we had, except for the sound that is handled by the microcontroller, we had almost everything else.  The microcontroller is missing here, what do we do with it? It's a big problem. So we come back to this again, this is the story. That microcontroller is what was killing us.  When we didn't have the binary of that microcontroller, what could we do to be able to recover it and that's what happened? It was stripped as we saw in the previous one and looked for that little square that you see with an arrow. It's the protection fuse. So we had to mask all that and  With a special microscope, see that fuse, point a special laser at it to be able to unprotect to be able to operate on that fuse and have the device unprotected and be able to read it.  microcontroller that we used later to get the game running one day in Mame because it's still in Walking progress but there we also did a huge reverse engineer to get to this What else do we have what more can we ask for this this It takes this looks like nonsense but it takes weeks  sometimes emulating a game can be a matter of days but other times it can take years.  a platform that was stopped for 12 years and just with a gru logo we saw it later and we were able to walk it out that it was the one with omega heat and like that there are a lot of other things here there is another one I have this game here to explain a couple of  things that are tremendous this strong carder was a card game that didn't work they gave me the board and I don't know or it depended on a leprom series or a device that has recorded data that could not be read So what did we do nothing we emulated the Hardware  and then on that Hardware we built a Trojan yes, ladies and gentlemen, we not only emulated the platform but we created a Trojan for that platform for what? Because that Trojan and having the video outputs could read what was inside the weirdo and put us in  screen the numbers that it contained then from there we were able to get the Data to be able to start it up another reverse engineer of those then we were able to find the English version but and  That binary wasn't useful for that, so we had to put ourselves together for weeks analyzing the code to see what it did that it didn't do and rebuild that binary from scratch to be able to have the game running. Let's continue with the reverse engineering stuff, this is a very strange thing  when they gave me they gave me the dump of that plate they wanted to remove the content of the aliprom series and they tore it up the serious book there was no other this these plates have no replacement they do not exist So there was no way to make it work we spent a long time with  We wanted to die from this, we couldn't find a way out, we had to do reverse engineering to be able to recreate the content of that one there, but we all knew it and listen well This, the Hardware is from 91 and the game is from 97 but the Hardware is from 91 and it did communicate  sorry yes from 81 of 81 and it communicated somehow with the alipron series by a strange bus until we realized they remember the square  or c that phillip patented two years later well it is exactly the same but with a changed clock Philip patented it two years after that Hardware was built and the communication is clearly and square C with that we were able to turn it around and with the changed club we were able to turn it around  To be able to rebuild according to the calls, that binary that I needed to be able to even realize that they were two games in one and that they came from factories already set in one way or another is another of the achievements that we were able to do in reverse engineering. I run with this  Because the presentation is gone we have practically two minutes left and almost nothing enters a Steel game is a Front game that hides a Back game Generally it is a normal little game that hides a casino or betting game that was played because they were prohibited in that  moment the police came and you saw that overcat that is there he went to the police and we discovered on that plate that there is a ra chip  gave frequency that makes a series of inputs that when they are made, what they actually do is trigger the game that card game that is down there the police are leaving pin is the schoolboy we have the casino game the police are coming pin from that radio frequency of the ejidos already  we have the breakout again and they actually suspect us that it is a casino game that is undercover loki 74 This is another another hit to be able to tell you it has a brick there a cpu brick like the ones we talked about that has its battery up there and  a Ram with data was dying there was no way to extract it we had to do a lot because it even has three Customs chips that you can see there one was easy to remove which is a programmable Cloud divider because it was removed with the logics and then two of these that  they are they are programmers they are video controllers that one does the background and the other alground and then the two are mixed to output the video that is tremendous and the other manages the Champion Sy  stem decrypting the samples that is, what the sounds are and instructs loki 5 5 to pass the digital sounds look at this you see something strange here nobody took it out Well I have this graph on April 1st, 2011 on my site on my site  web Why Because that cockroach that you see there was not in the original but I did put it in a graphic hack and I put it now I don't feel like opening the module two hours had not passed and a Chinese collector Japanese conditions Sorry send me an email  telling me that he buys me the cpu, well, as you can see, there is everything I had to explain to him that it was a joke about Apple full day, etc., etc. But hey, that was left for history because collectors immediately went to buy it because there is a cockroach inside the Mel down, which  never existed These are sil game too but in a different way you can see that they are like a kind of Space invaders that use the same graphics to a different input game to po  To send a disguised poker game is not a poker game, it is the latest and then when touching another tequila he returns to do the space invader of Always in the one below is a Pacman that if you play pac-man and a different set of keys  it transforms into this Cherry Master-style slot machine and when the police leave they return to the same thing again with their accounting All different names are that's how we baptize them because they are hidden inside another game anyway well ready are you ready we're here we're going to round up  this This was something that I was 22 years ago about this missis Pacman Twin is just an Argentinian hack of missis Pacman that two players play simultaneously that it was impossible I couldn't get the board until we got it we said it's Pacman hardware you're going to go  easy emulation lie clubs what we see there that plate that you have here we see the detail that chip that is there or look for data and addresses but not only from di  Instead, the M1 line of the z80 uses the M1, so they make different critations depending on whether it is an up code or an operand, or whether it is Data or if it is an instruction, the encryptions differently, so we had to do a lot of things and reverse engineering  for weeks to be able to find the algorithm to decrypt this and there you have it practically and have the game running as we have it today mommy it took me 22 years but we have it running the Argentine hacker who has the devil's encryption is working today  in mame from now on I thank you from the soul in all this presence but you have to understand the importance of preserving the heritage for future generations what is it that moves us is the engine that moves me at this moment and later it can move you  anyone who can add without being part of this story here I leave mameder links which is the original mame page of the developers of  Mames the part of Quito where the recreational shorts are hanging, it appears that it is this Spanish group that the preservation work is incredible and mine in robertofresca.com where you can see the working progress of what I am doing One thing should be highlighted and I say this  Before I finish and being in the acknowledgments, I appreciate that you have participated and I tell you that next year I will celebrate 25 years as a mommy developer, so I really believe that it is time perhaps to take a little step to the side and  I hope there that you fully like the production and the eco-park that has invited me for this, possibly I can officially say goodbye to the scene. It does not mean that I say goodbye to mom, perhaps giving a training or doing something or moving or saying goodbye directly to the scene in  a talk in Spanish for my people So I thank you for being here thanks to the organizers for inviting me and thanks to you  for being here and for wasting this time listening to me Thank you very much and have a great Show we say goodbye to Roberto fresh
after the launch break we will meet
here at one to two
[Music]