We welcome Salvador Mendoza with a round of applause [Applause] Hello, hello, thank you, perfect, hello, everyone, it's really a pleasure to be able to echo One more year after this pandemic, today I want to talk to you about a new technology that Apple implemented in  the last two years and that has revolutionized in a certain way the way in which we can locate things objects inside even inside buildings houses or outside of these not talking about appler tags is more than anything this talk is not to solve doubts  It is to give you more concerns about what is happening Out There, not to talk about privacy issues, to talk about issues related to these devices that can know the exact location of objects or people in a very precise way, it is extremely important related to privacy Not if we  Let's go to the related terms of privacy It's related to how I already authorized a certain person to know certain things about me  no no that information is simply there and everyone can get it there was a South African writer named Luis limemberg who talked about the art of tracking that basically his hypothesis in this book was that the science of tracking was really the first scientific form related to this  type of situations when in ancient times food was sought or animals were not sought and here we are going to combine it a bit with the privacy part how important is it for me to be able to control what other people can know about me and likewise  What is the exact place where I am positioned using different types of devices everything that we are going to talk about here you will be able to find in this repository some examples that we are going to be presenting are not yet in the repository but eventually during the week I will be  adding Well I am Salvador Mendoza I am director of the research and development team of the company  At the Metabase Club company, I have given different types of talks, including here at ecoparty, related to payment systems and digital wallets. We have talked about relays and replay attacks on this type of technology, and I am part of the offensive team of the same company. I am also the author of the book.  from the editorial ceroth Word that I probably shared there they will be selling in the future so let's go into detail what is the agenda for today basically we are going to talk about the technology of the Apple aartags that are the athletes that that guy  of technology What is the functionality and technical aspects and also a bit about the reversing on this type of technology and finally What are the concerns related to privacy with this type of device we are going to see what type of instruments we can use for, for example, to  scan these devices near us when someone for example can plant  keep one in our backpack Or maybe in our car or things like that not to open I want you to imagine in a scenario where you have a sister let's imagine and your sister received a notification on her phone that she is being tracked or that  there is a nearby device identified that has been with her for a period of time no her sister can't find this device because it can be anywhere no and they are extremely small devices basically this size if they can't see from behind  It's that they're just about the size of a coin, so what her sister does is go to the police to find out where estertack can be found. The police find that the read tag is taped under the car and the police extract the data from  this truth that basically has an identifier related to the Hardware when the police bring this data they realize that they can put  a court order to Apple so that they give this information of who Esther tag registered and they realize that her ex-partner is her sister's ex-partner literally no but the worst thing is that the ex-partner is a police officer and it is a true story come on  Let's see what ends up in the slides, but basically this happened in Miami about six months ago, Air tags are usually implemented to subtract important objects or normally that we don't want to lose No, this type of object can normally be a backpack, it can be our pet, it can be  our wallet or it can be any other type of device that we want to have tracking on it we are not even starting to see wallets related to how we can have this type of art inside our wallet to be able to know exactly where it is we are going to talk a little about  of the internal technology of this device a little later on some important features  Before the Air tags is that they are very low cost and they work anywhere in the world one of the most important things is that they use the Apple network basically the Apple network if we put it in context let's imagine that I have  an Air tag right now here is probably disconnected from my device but everyone who has an iPhone here is reading the advertising Or the information that mirthack is sending and you are passing it as a gateway to Apple services and you are updating the location  from where this artag is located in a transparent way and without friction towards the user you really do not realize this, they do it in an automated way one of the important things about technology is that it basically maps you where it has been found That is the tag during  a period of time and it is extremely precise due to the fact that it has three types of technologies and one of the most important is called  ultraway Band that helps you to know exactly in meters where this device is located by making a small signal triangulation You could say at the level of size we can compare it with a coin and internally it has a coil the coil imagine that when we want to make it sound  This coil moves using a magnet that hits the magnet and basically generates a sound. It's a very slight sound. Basically this happens.  move because it has an accelerometer it also starts to make a sound but since the sound is very soft it is very difficult to hear a lot of the time and it is very difficult to be able to find them because of the size and what they are they are very easy to hide internally through  technical level uses a nordic in rf of the family that has integrated ble and nfc uses Apple 1 technology which is basically Ultra technology  way Band that is useful for that part, not to know in meters how far we are from that device, it has an accelerometer, the accelerometer is quite useful when, for example, we imagine that I have an artag with me or that someone planted me and it starts to move and  doing the tag gives you an alert instruction it's been a while for it to start beeping literally and of course you have an audio amplifier that basically isn't much use at the moment and they're waiting for updates to make a louder sound so they can detect it inside  the news in recent years well in these last two years that it has come out we have begun to see different types of scenarios more than anything in the United States that have been implemented to be able to track women most of them that basically a woman bombing to have a drink  beer and a person puts the tag in your bag or in your car or right now because of your situation to know where you live or  to track the route it takes, no, and one of the important issues is that the notifications that Apple gives you at this time are with a time of approximately six hours before, they were 24 hours, they began to reduce the 6 hours when the person can give  Noticing that there is an Air tag nearby, a lot of time has passed and the attacker already knows where he lives or what is the route he takes, for example, in the morning or to work, for example, no, and of course, apart from being very alarming, we also have the part  that they are using it to steal valuable things, such as cars, sports cars or very expensive cars, not that it is extremely interesting, they do not know where they park them, they arrive at night and well, they start to steal it, not this is the story that I told you at the beginning  basically a Miami cop uses air tags to track his ex-wife or ex-partner and the ex-partner arrives at the police station and realizes that it's what  They are being tracked by a person from the police station that is extremely sad and alarming at the same time, no, and what tanks have is that they are easy to hide;  in different types of containers, for example, this was a rancher in the United States who normally used his trailer to move cattle once a month and realized that one of the main qualities was hidden inside his electrical connector for the trailer  It is the precision to track people is one of the most important issues and of course we have been making this call Apple to do different types of things to be able to mitigate this situation in a certain way and they have begun to make different types of changes one of the most  important was how long it took alert to make a sound when it was disconnected from the registered person  strada this device normally previously it was 24 hours it was reduced to 12 hours and now it is 6 hours that still six hours is a long time for a sound attack not normally a mobile device in this case an iPhone gives you the notification automatically if  you have the bluetooth system turned on normally this is extremely important to be able to detect it is close Not now for example that I have this device here if all of you do have an iPhone for example this questioner tag advertising is arriving automatically it is is here close to  you guys and normally some time passes and if it's true it's still with you you're going to start getting notifications on your mobile devices and of course the question here was how we've been seeing on the internet how to remove the sound part very many attackers are selling the Air  tags without the coil part so that it does not make sound when it is moving near the  Not the victim basically to prevent them from finding to be able to find an alert that is close to them no Well, although an alert for example is worth 28 or 35 dollars without the coil you are selling it for 55 dollars they are not taking away Hardware but they are even giving it  a more expensive price that is interesting basically remove the metal part in this case the magnet that is in the part attached to the base and with that more than enough so that it does not make the sound since the coil will not be playing with anything  no more but let's go into more detail How these celtics work basically they have three technologies they have nfc technology ble technology and Ultra way Band technology we use nfc a lot for when we want to register our device know the phone knows basically takes the data through FC  and it mounts them to the Apple service or when we find an Air tag for example we can read it through npc and see who  belongs or if the elta that is in lost mode, for example, to know who to contact or in the following way is that I can connect to a web page through npc if I have an Android phone and it indicates instructions on how to contact that person or how to remove  the battery so that it does not follow me continues to send us this signal the bluetooth part is very useful for the part where that device is located basically right now [ __ ] that is sending this type of advertising through bluetooth at 2.4 gigahers any iPhone that is  It is located here in this 30-meter zone, it is detecting this signal and is updating where mierdak and the Ultra way Band part are located, as I was telling you, it is to know exactly in meters where I can locate it. For example, I can open my Apple application and start to  navigating can give me in meters you know that he is two meters from Tino even inside buildings or my house where where  have it is extremely interesting the part of the three technologies in such a small device we do not have three antennas here as I told you the nfc is basically to register it the Bluetooth part is to basically update the location of where the device is located through  from another iPhone or iPad device, for example, Ultra WiFi is basically to know in real time where this device is located in any type of place. Not one of the important features that Apple uses to be able to do this technology is to use the bluetooth stack  The most important part is the vertizen The bedticen part is extremely important due to the fact that the Air tag does not need you to connect to it to be able to make this update of where the bacon is located, basically in this case, what it does  is to always be sending this advertising page all the time any iPhone can detect and update it  r the occasion without the need to connect to it, that is one of the very important characteristics of this type of technology, and it does not use three channels for this, which are the three most important channels of advertising 3738 and 39 that the other channels are really used for the  Other types of features are not, for example, when the owner already wants to connect, alertac And make a sound, for example, not being able to write in certain features What is the advertising page What is sending the Air tact of time no basically it is a package that  it indicates different types of characteristics such as which company it belongs to, not within the bluetooth stack within the regulations, any company that wants to sell a product must have an ID related to this stack, in this case the 4c00 belongs to the Apple company  But there are extremely important characteristics, not number 12, but number 12 in hexadecimal indicates that it is a device.  vo that is used to find my, which is basically the technology that Apple uses for all types of Wireless devices and the final part is basically a public key, we could say it cut off, an internal technology that Apple manages in a certain way to identify whose device this is without  yes basically distribute or make the registry known or yes the manufacturer number or the device number yes Inside the board no if we compare with an arta that is disabled we begin to see that there is the find my becomes 07 which was before  12 So we began to see certain characteristics within the packages that allow us as researchers to begin to differentiate arts that are enabled and certain that are disabled for what, basically to be able to scan and filter information and to be able to know, for example, if an art  is close to me using a scan is not one of the extremely important issues  It is clear within other characteristics for it It is that we in the company developed a project that is Open source, you can still find it in the repository that I told you that we call mini well, you ask a lot why mini in Nahuatl means hunter of mini  beasts So come on we are very related to that with this part within the characteristics that the card has is that you can find the disabled taxis Because it is important to be able to find the enabled taxes let's imagine that I am an attacker I plant an art where you live and then I  disabled I disabled it because I no longer want notifications to arrive to you from Junior is close to you so the idea of ​​being able to find the disabled touch is to know if maybe someone already planted a tag on me and really not  I noticed no And as an alert that the Apple notification system is disabled, it no longer indicates that there is a  the tag near you internally we use a rack basically to integrate WiFi bluetooth on the same board we have programmable buttons and we have leds the leds Well a little later you will see but basically the leds are not good for knowing how far away  we are close to an Air tag using light through the intensity of the signal we also added an external connector for an antenna in case you wanted, for example, to have an extra AC with much more amplitude to be able to read the signal much more in case of  That the antenna that the board contains is not enough, it is not important to mention that for example this antenna can be a custom mate or it could be that you buy it specifically for the bluetooth part and within the programming we begin to see how we can begin to  filter information from the bluetooth part we begin to filter the type of company and then we go to the task of filtering the part  from Ok this artag is enabled it is registered because And then we can do filtering today is this one that is disabled And it is close to us what it basically does the tool that starts to do a scan and starts to filter you or to see the type of information that  you can find within these of this scan in this case it begins to check all the Bluetooth systems that are near us and finally it gives us that it finds one that is registered and active near us in Bluetooth range no that can be around  20 25 meters away and one important thing is that it gives us the distance in decibels minus 44 to know how far or close we are from that device, not within the important thing about the decibels is the example that I was commenting on, no.  we have the tool that tells us that there is an Air tag near us but how to locate it how to find it as it is a small device  We have a wide range to be able to locate it, which is why we undertook the task of generating a tool with LEDs that basically when turned on indicates that there is a device nearby and depending on how close we are, these LEDs will start to light.  or they will start to disappear no the main idea is that you use it as a heart scanner to be able to identify where it is or how close we are using the intensity of the alert signal at the decibel level for example here when it starts flashing  the leds indicate that it is super close alertac and basically we can locate it it is not the important features another important issue within the Air tags is that it has a feature hardcoded where you can connect alertac and force it to make a sound let's imagine that I find read tag no  i can locate it i know it's near me i can try to connect alert and write on this page  characteristic one bytes for example and do what sounds In case we cannot locate it, it is the same characteristic for all the Air tags, well, those of the approximately few days that we can collect and of course, basically as I commented here here in the code we are only  writing the one in the feature And it is more than enough for the alert to start providing a sound all this code of all these issues they have in the repository that I told you from the beginning not to be able to write this specific feature basically what does the  device is finding freedom tries to connect saves a log of alertac try to connect but need to spend 10 minutes is the time we have recorded 10 minutes to reconnect and write the byte to that feature if I connect to that feature  I connect to the device and try to write to that feature at that  moment no it will not emit any sound, that is, it allows you to write but it does not emit any sound so 10 minutes have to pass after the first memory record and then send the characteristic or they write the characteristic and now the device starts to generate the sound no  For example, in this example, 10 minutes have already passed and basically we indicate it with a button to write about the feature so that it emits the sound and to be able to locate it in the mini. The mini project is basically not only based on generating a board and generating a  repository is basically not to give the tools to those researchers who want to continue researching this type of device and who want to learn more using this ideology related to Apple technology, many of us probably do not have the ability to print a plate or develop one  board but what we did is develop the library of this board  here specifically to arduino technology so any arduino velee board is compatible with the library that we are handling if you have a W order you can mount the examples we have here and you can start scanning to see how appler tracks technology is handled See  about the packages, what are the classifications and so on, and of course, not only in arduino, not this is the part of arduino that I told you that the repository already has support for arduino, but we can also use Linux, we can't use Linux, for example, to do different  types of things What happens For example, if I realize that someone is following me freely, what I would love to do is be able to take that data from Albert and be able to go through the other devices and make him think of an attacker who is still following me but I already sent that  device on the other hand not maybe in a car what do I know basically make the attacker believe that I do not  I have realized that it is following me, it is not the spuffin part, we call it, no, the spoofing part is to take that data from reading the original tag, mount it on another device and send it to another device in another direction, for example, not for the attacker to  think that we are in another place we can do this from Linux using this configuration basically the 08 indicates that we are talking about the ble family and the 00008 indicates that What is the information that comes in the part of the truth within this question many people ask me  You have been asking about Why don't we put the type of features in the flipper no that here has flipper a very good tool well the issue of the flipper is extremely interesting because of certain important features not even before starting to get into the code is the stack of  flipper bluetooth It has certain specific characteristics, one is that the stack is not complete, there is only the client part  Basically the part of the client is that someone can connect to the flipper but I can't scan or I can try to connect to someone else and of course if we imagine that I want to pass this device off as an Air tag I need to make some changes within the code  one of the most important changes at the bluetooth level is the name the name covers certain characteristics within the part of the truth that we need to be able to make an expofeo of data and the also extremely important flags that are found within the part of the flipper within  from the code at the code level there is really no documentation on how to remove flags and things like that basically it's trying to understand a bit what was my counter that was used and what are the official semi-controller libraries not related to flipper basically related to my controller  and see how it is handled internally Not if I do not remove any flag That's how  or the flipper would be seen It is actually occupying different bytes that I need to be able to send them 31 bytes for my advertising deck so we need to remove those two flags to remove those two flags at the code level These are basically the instructions or the functions this does not allow us  remove these flags and of course we need to do other things like the Discovery part we need to clean the local name part which is basically this device name and does not include the uides that are being used for the flags no that is also extremely important Now the code at a general level  How it would look like we clean the flags we add the loyalty part and we update the orbital sindeira of the bluetooth device this at a general level how could you how should you do it at the flipper level many wonder Hey but how do I compile and how do I basically need clones basically  repositories recursively to have all the  data the file that I am modifying is called gap.c basically and at point c there are those instructions that I was telling you of course it is only a long code but you can focus on that part and basically it is to compile and it generates the firmware again to be able to mount it  towards the flipper no basically to mount it you have this button called starphone file and you select where the firmware is to be able to mount it and it automatically updates it in a very highly automated way no what can we do with the flipper Well what can we do  with the flipper there are different things, one of them, for example, is to generate a lot of being tags or sponging a lot of being tags, not what can this be of use to us?  to be a friend that they are walking with him no basically we lack the part of knowing how to know a little more about him  e the notifications that Apple generates for this type of technology and of course that is why in this talk we try to provide these tools so that not only we continue investigating but also you who like this type of investigation or privacy can continue with this type  of issues not in this case I am good in this case Monte 11 but it really is a cycle that generates different types of artags or makes the Apple system believe in this case it is an official Apple application that is detecting the Apple toads around us  The research should not stop there. We have other types of devices that are widely used to track things using Bluetooth. The main idea is that we have this project and that we can feed it with different functions that allow us to find these devices, not like the  Samsung technologies not taiga technology the main idea is that we can nu  Remove the repository of certain functions or programs that allow us to detect these types of devices near us using any type of device in this case, for example, arduino, another type of instrumentation, some recommendations if you have Android, use rf Connect in order to detect any type of device  near you or you can use the text tracker from the Apple company that basically what it does is a scan identifying using your ID as a filter and I began to track what is near you to detect some kind of deartag  If you use Apple technology, activate the Bluetooth system, which is basically the notification system that tells you if there is an altar near Tino, which is extremely important. Finally, he has commented that if a strange device is found near you, then resort to legal distances  and that the courts have a way of being able to tell that di  specific device to give it that air of the device to be able to take information on who this device is registered with, with whom it has been paired, not even Apple has the ability to indicate exactly the places where this device has been located before, it is not important to have the tools to be able to know  what can we do in matters related to privacy from me that's all thank you very much Celín you have questions to ask regarding the talk you can raise your hand or ask into the microphone How many questions or ask into the microphone in the middle to see that no one has raised first  I have three questions. The first is for a particular reason why you decided to generate your own prototype instead of using open source like the cat snifer, for example, what happens is that we don't have control of the Bretazing, you don't have control of the  resides in this type of device even the part even in arduino had  the part of the truths at the bld level Ok another question I have is when we are spitting an artag sure I can control this later but is Apple doing something for when it shows you the map or the information of the Air tag to maintain integrity If you have  two Air tags in two different parts, how Apple tells you which is the real one or it only gives you the two data, that is, how do we make the spoofing really reliable? Until now, we still need to investigate that part, we are in that part now, since we have not investigated the  part of the inside of this we are in that part Thank you and the last time you spoke when after the initial connection to the artag before writing the feature 10 minutes have to pass that was commented you reversed it How did you come to that conclusion yes we reversed it in the application  Android from Apple Ok thanks excellent I don't really know how it works really no I have never had one but my question is does it exist  the remote deactivation of the Apple tag and if so, how is the deactivation carried out only by the means of there is some authentication in between, that is, from the phone that is nearby, not the phone that owns the hospital How does this process work  deactivation really can not be deactivated remotely you have to remove the battery directly alertac to be able to disable it so they are the official instructions of Apple if you find a tag that you do not know if you do not see If you do not know whose it is if it is not  yours basically remove the battery and it is the easiest way in this case to avoid the tracking type the owner can disable it remotely the disabling is done by Apple by means of another iPhone that is near the device Yes please not the warning part But  I imagine that we sent another signal in the Tyson part. In other words, right now the iPhone is only used as a gateway  not from the part to update the location of the device but when disabling the alertc the alert has to be done it has to be close to you to deactivate it through if the art is not near you you can only put it in lost mode  They just tried to start the bluetooth of van Energy with a tool like Bill yack and see what information is being sent by the one that does not belong to the hospital that is doing remote deactivation to see if the attack can be focused, could it be  I think it is the question of the community side, not having the tools to be able to do it in us, we still lack the research part, we only have the part of this depophy and the filtering part, but we still lack a lot of things related to the investigation of  Apple artax what happens all that is all at the rivering level no I mean we don't have any type of technical information related  to the device we have only reversed the signaling part we have reversed the part of the apk for example of Android we have basically what we have done currently and from there we have taken these these issues but yes I mean there is a lot of work to do in that part we could  using the air in reverse, that is, pivoting towards it and those around it are not ugly and being able to identify the people who are there or the devices.  possibility of yes I leave it there Now it will only be a matter of course to make a dead River dolphin and try to understand a little of what is happening No but in theory I would allow it I don't know It would be a matter of not as we have not seen that part so deep at level  firmware it is impossible to say yes Good afternoon, I wanted to know, that is, we here in Latin America, not everyone walks. That is, the use of d is not so frequent  Apple devices because of the cost they have and especially in a place, for example, that is not a big city like this but far away where there are much fewer devices around that use tags they need Yes or yes from the Apple network or Do they have some other way to communicate  and another question do they have their own GPS or do they need Yes or yes two or three devices around to know let's say one to be able to do the triangulation this good basically that I think the second question answers the first one does not have a GPS it really needs the Apple devices  They are close to be able to do that detection There is no way that you by the device is the device is there and no person with an Apple system is not going to update the location, that is, someone with a device has to pass by  Apple for this update to update well the devices have to be yes or yes the iPhone or iPhone or Apple computers It also has  n this technology ipads and iphones can be registered up to now because they use through nfc either the registration Thank you very much and congratulations thank you how are you I have a question besides the Air tags There are a lot of other devices that work with  blnfc it is possible to reverse the firmware and inject it into other devices to make a mini King of an art and generate an attack out there with another advertising identifier there is a guy who did the reversing basically dumped the firmware from undertag and mounted it on another  It was basically cloned, the two attacks were cloned, basically it was what he did if he can because in the tests he did it was clear that he was in one country and the other was in another country and he is a very technical guy and well, only no no  It has made ruiles, for example, the part of the firmware but it is feasible, yes it is true, it is one of the issues that they have in rrf that can be basically made a glit  ch to be able to do the dumping and to be able to do that type of cloning Yes, thank you very much I'm having a very good talk, thanks Thanks for the talk Salvador, I have a question, do you have ideas, and the iPhone, the iPhone or the ipans respect their bluetooth settings, in a matter of whether I have it  off do not contribute to this network to identify them the tags do not respect do not respect thanks Hello I have seen transmission that the public key is possible to impersonate an ertec if you copy the public key for example yes basically the expofeo part If you take exactly how it is shown  the public key or in this case the part and you mount it on another device with the same Bluetooth Mac it is possible to splurge that this is the original tag in general it is not basically how Apple's implementation is developed thanks no thanks for the chat  Have you tried reversing the part that communicates with the Apple server when it sends the location of the artag if there in the apis?  The latitude and longitude is sent, try to change it, put it in the record, that in another country, for example, No, not yet. Basically we are in that investigation process, thanks, thinking about the malicious side. If at any time I know that someone has right now that they are tracking it, it could be spoofing.  of that device to make, that is, make that person or that object lose in different places and they will believe it, that is, they will replicate to the user how it appears as several equal arts or whoever recognizes it, have you done that part the part  What I have done is turn off an Air tag, choose it in another place using the same Mac as the device and if it has worked, if it appears in the mapping part and if you have it on, yes, both if you have it on, sometimes it appears, other times it does not appear, I think  something out there that should be half composed in the part of Apple Ok a second question No it is not true perfect very interesting questions We ask Salv with a round of applause  ador Mendoza thank you we meet again after lunch
break in the room at 2:10 p.m. with a
talk by Gastón Ares