we have some questions or comments on
root zone scaling and some of the the
data that we've been provided and how
this may relate to the the early warning
process and GAX role in that so are
there questions or comments on that
netherlands please our basic question I
think we discusses beforehand in in in
plenary is the fact that we have a kind
of different expectations different
wordings different signals in this
during this meeting then we had I think
in the Brussels meeting with the board
and basically what we heard and we
didn't hear it in our let's say anything
not in the presentation court gave to us
but it was in other in other setting
with Gina so that it's probable its
thinkable that the I can can accommodate
it will accommodate let's say more than
500 or more than a couple of hundreds of
applications in the first round and I
think it's of course it's admirable if
you can have all the systems and the
processing the services are available on
time but we still have I think to
concerns one concern is that we had a
kind of understanding in Brussels that
after the first batch of we had a
thinking and understanding in a couple
of hundreds that will be a kind of
evaluation about what's really the
impact of them let's say the first
insurgents in the root zone after a
while and that second round would be
deferred until there's something coming
out out of the
evaluation of how the root zone system
works or e acts on this so in case in
the first round there is not a kind of
batching but we have a let's say an
explosion of thousand or 1200
applications it will of course interact
it will have repercussions of our own
let's head on route scrolling route
scaling agreement we had I think in in
Brussels on this and the second thing is
will basically it depends also on how
the batching is going to be arranged and
if you plan this introduction will this
be batched will this be one round and
then if the applications come in after
certain time will be in one time posting
of all the applications being in because
that's basically the trigger point for
our early warning within the cake and
our early warning is of course and we
have us all restricted resources if we
come up with a list of 1200 it's a
little different than a list of 1 150
new applications so that's these two
questions we are struggling with and we
would like to have some answer
indication thank you so I think there
really are two quite different things
that we're talking about here the early
warning with respect to strings is a
process for review of those strings and
you're asking a question I believe about
the capacity from a personal point of
view within the GAC and within the rest
of the administrative processes to
process those applications to do give
due consideration to those strings and
what the time frame is for those
responses perfectly fair question
separate and apart from that is the the
terminology that you've used is the
impact on the root server system which
suggests that the name servers
themselves
would show some evidence of stress
because of the addition of new names
into the name servers that's it there's
seems to be some persistent confusion
and misunderstanding in my judgment
about that the the name servers the few
hundred anycast instances around the
world regularly process on the order of
10,000 queries a day per second this is
huge huge numbers the variation on a
second to second basis on a minute to
minute basis and during the course of a
day and at various you know changes on a
seasonal basis are very large changes in
those numbers the addition of a new one
or two are a hundred or a thousand names
into the root server system almost
certainly will generate no measurable
change that you can that you can see
because of the ordinary changes that are
ordinary variations that are taking it's
fair to look at that if you wish and and
there will be people who are monitoring
things very closely and I'm given to
understand there will be a report
carefully documented the before and
after and explaining all of this but I
think it's important to set the
expectations here that the relationship
between adding new names into the root
zone is almost completely if not a
hundred percent decoupled from anything
measurable in terms of the performance
as seen by the users or even for that
matter seen by the internal distribution
processes within each of the roots of
our operators I I suspect that there is
a misunderstanding that has taken flower
and seems to be spread and I'd like to
find a way to settle it down
and as I said I think some very careful
documentation structured in a way that
is readable not only by technical people
and by gac personnel but also one that
can be shared with broader audiences or
more senior people in government would
be very helpful in laying this laying
out this very clearly and laying any
misunderstandings to rest as you may
recall the board passed a resolution
that stated that the maximum number of
tlds that could be delegated into the
route under the new gTLD program on an
annual basis is 1000 and the number may
not exceed that unless there's a formal
review or a new decision by the board so
that was the limit that was determined
and established by resolution and we
will fully respect that thank you yeah i
would like to echo what my colleague
from from the mandamus was raising the
issue because the the really the amount
of nudity of these that's going to be
launched that's going to come to it's
also going to end up in our lap in this
early warning system of course is going
to be huge different to deal with
thousands or maybe a couple of thousands
or strings and if it if you compared to
to a couple of hundreds and actually
when we listen to Curt preach who made a
very good presentation in early in the
week we we got impression or we
understood that that I I can hazard I
can stuff and I can board as a very good
dialogue with the technical community or
the experts the root server system
stability committee and the security and
stability Advisory Committee and so on
and another of course expert on in the
technical community and that is very
reassuring from from our point of view
and it's also very very important
because we are governments we have
concerns but we have not really the
experts but I would like to say another
thing what I what I got the impression
of them hope I understood it is also the
our sec group had some kind of proposal
of our level warning not an early
warning in the in the gac early warning
at an early warning actually from from
the from the technical perspective from
there from the root service system and I
don't know whether you are working on
that one or or or or also have you have
some dialogue on that one maybe you have
but that is also out of interest for us
actually to know because that has
implications on our policy public policy
and our concerns and issues and I think
it's very very important we have this
early warning whatever it is the systems
in place before things starts and it's
going to start very soon now because I
think I think it's very important is its
accountability for 44 ik and it's
accountability for us as an advisory
committee that whole this whole systems
in which we are all of us involved right
now is actually going to work so it's
not going to go go down the drain so we
need to make sure that it's going to
happen and that's what also and I feel a
little bit like a parrot I saying the
same thing every every meeting when when
we have the opportunity to meet you for
the ICANN board that I really hope that
we could I really hoped and I still do
it we could have a limited first round
and have a good evaluation from all the
perspectives this is necessary and then
take into account the the information we
got foot and then could move on to the
next step to the second round thank you
we love live the word to the board if
they want to react immediately to this
point and i will take the water
afterwards two points the first one is
related to the question at Thomas asked
the first one and the and the answer of
Steve there is indeed a distinction that
is important that Steve as are lighted
and maybe one way to to highlight this
distinction is to say that the stress on
the root servers that are distributed
are more related to the number of users
that the number of tlds this is a very
important distinction overall on a daily
functioning the stress on the root
servers is related to the number of
users that are actually query
it will increase a little bit because it
will take time for the mirrors and all
the cash and all the replications to get
all the addresses but overall the load
is not fundamentally related to the
number of tles but more to the number of
users the other stress which is
different is the number of updates to
the database that come from changing the
servers from changing the address of who
manages the registry and so on but this
is a completely different type of load
and I'm trying to express that in a way
that marks the distinction it is very
important in our discussion that we are
completely clear about that distinction
because it's a very important element in
relation to the root scaling and the
dangers and it is extremely important in
particular that you have all the
elements to report back because this
question is going to be asked over and
over again and if we are not clear tell
us and we will clarify we will try to
find the arguments that you can use the
second point is regarding the workload
on the early warning it's absolutely
true that the workload on the early
warning will be heavier if there is a
thousand two hundred and five hundred
this is true and we all know the problem
of bandwidth I would like to share and
maybe make a methodological suggestion
because one of the dangers for everybody
both for the board and the staff the
structure as a whole and for the gag is
if you want to provide a one single
early warning why is that because you
will have to wait until you agree on
every single potential problem on tlds
before you provide the output I would
suggest that you explore something along
an important distinction among the list
of tlds hopefully there will not be too
many that will be problematic but we
don't know there is an important
distinction between those where there is
a problem from the gac points of view
regarding the string and to be
caricature
there may be strings or applications
where the gac as a whole or some black
members will say we don't even want to
explore who is applying for that string
that string is a problem this is
different from a situation where there
is a problem with one particular
applicant for a given string that in
itself doesn't pose a problem because
then the early warning is much more
directed towards the applicant himself
like saying you didn't contact the
corresponding local authority or you're
missing appointments so i would
encourage to maybe do a sort of to pass
system to try to narrow down very early
on what are the strings that you believe
are causing a problem in itself in
themselves and identifying among them if
any hopefully there will be none but if
any those where there is a real obvious
consensus on the gag that there is a
problem that needs to be addressed and
those where there is a problem for some
countries and and others but i would
encourage to try to design something and
maybe we can discuss further on how to
make it efficient that will be a
flexible modality so that you can
produce early warnings on an ongoing and
state-by-state basis instead of waiting
until you have an agreement on all the
early warnings you're going to provide I
hope this out and we all crossing
fingers that people will be smart enough
and respectful enough of this period of
the program not to make applications
that are really probably mad thank you
very much to the board members for their
insides al Rosen scaling I think that
dr. Crocker I mention a report that is
going to be published on the matter I
imagine it would be very important to
have that report as soon as possible and
it is important to have policy summaries
that will certainly simplify our work
when talking to our political masters so
to speak but the commission would also
like to have the full
report with all the technical data all
the methodology explanation or
methodology that we use because we want
to share that report with our own
experts to and be able to be to help you
to be confident all together on the
resilience audio system on the early
warning the commission would like to
thank Bertran de la Chapelle for the
suggestions we should certainly be taken
into account by us we are internally
discussing how to streamline our work I
don't want to go into detail as this is
a discussion that is still ongoing but
one thing that the Commission is already
raised with the I can start with whom we
have met a couple of days ago and I
raise it again with the board we will
need n sorry we understand that icon is
building an internal system to handle
the new applications on your side it
will be very important for gac to to
have access to have an interface to that
system in order to be able to consider
how to automate our work as well so the
Commission is hopeful that this can be
this discussion can proceed as quickly
as possible and then on again on the
early warning and new gTLDs thanks to
the CEO to mr. bextrum for specifying
for reminding us of the limit of 1000
new gTLDs my question is did I cannot
base their calculations on the deadlines
by when they will provide us with a full
list of gTLDs on which we are supposed
to provide possibly Eddie warning did a
calculator deadline on this maximum
amount or in other words the deadline
that you set for yourself to communicate
to us all the gTLDs with all the
beautification done with your said at
that stage is it calculated on 1000 new
gTLDs or 100 and 200 and if you
calculated it on 100 what happens if you
receive one thousand applications are
you confident that they're going to
respect the deadline that you
communicate it to us and if not what's
going to happen thank you i hope this
last point was clear enough is not I'm
happy to elaborate in May approximately
one month after the application window
closes we will be publishing all the
strings publicly so it's known what has
been applied for and that will be the
total list of whatever number
locations has been received during the
application period firstly secondly the
current plan is to process the
applications and batches of 500 so I
think that we've taken that into
consideration when we looked at the the
early warning period but I'll check into
that in more depth and come back to you
thank you thank you rod so Suzanne first
I want to reinforce a couple of the
points that have been made particularly
by Steve the first of all given the
limitations that have been committed to
as rod just mentioned and has previously
discussed there's not an urgent issue
here there are concerns that are in
there it's probably third there that do
need to be addressed and have been
committed to be addressed but this is
there there is more there's more to be
gained by taking the time to have these
conversations and make sure that we
fully understand given that limits have
been agreed to that are conservative in
the minds of everyone who's looked
carefully at this for our sacks
specifically I believe was Maria made a
reference to some work that's been
undertaken there has been some work
within the committee on a shared set of
metrics as much in the interests of
transparency and facilitating research
frankly as because there are specific
concerns for the root servers about rid
scaling and also I believe Steve made an
illusion I'm losing track of who
mentioned this but there are good
working relationships in place and the
technical folks outside of ICANN are
looking forward to working with staff on
making sure that the technical issues
are addressed it does make sense though
to also reinforce the distinction that I
believe for tron particularly spoke to
between policy issues and technical
operational ones and I believe that one
of the benefits of the long discussion
that
we we all had on this issue was that
there is a reasonable set of clear
separations among those things and
regional plans for tackling all of them
so I I think we're in a good place on
that but we need to keep moving forward
in and we look forward to working
particularly with the staff on them ok
Germany I just want to come back to the
presentation made by petrol in this
respect on the evaluation process and
early warning system I just I think it
seems your comment seems to be rather
sensible to have a distinction between
as a aberration of the string on one
side and the other side revelation of
the applicant having said that from a
practical standpoint that might be
rather difficult because imagine we
receive on the first of May or second of
May or 29th of April a complete list
with strings okay a string of evaluation
is rather easy to be made the rather
easy just to say but an evaluation of
the applicant and in particular it's not
only the name of the applicant you need
to know what is the model he is
following what are the registration
policies what are the restrictions I
think this frankly speaking is not
possible within a time frame of 60 days
this is something I I would really be
hesitated to have such kind of
evaluation during this period and having
said said I also would like to second my
colleague from the European Commission I
think we we only need to consider what
will be the possibilities for the
government for the early warning system
if say is really a significant decrease
of application we had considered up to
now
something like 500 if it really is
significantly more than these 500 then
it would be also a capacity problems for
us to proceed these 500 CC's
applications because yet we as
government have not privileged to extend
at a time we are bound by a 60 days
thank you thanks who burped for your
question we will publish the
applications which are essentially
questioned the information in questions
1 through 13 so and and then more so
there'll be the string and then the
applicant and the purpose of the
application and the answer to many of
the questions so that the gap can use
that to make its determinations now what
might be helpful for the GAC and what
we'd like to hear is a way thank you
I've you know so maybe there's a way we
can sort the data so we're planning as
rod mentioned we're going to we're going
to publish that the information on a
date certain after we received the
applications if you would we could give
that information to you now what's going
to be published and perhaps you could
get back to us with a way that we could
sort that data so it'd be more helpful
to you so you can kind of run your
finger down it easily Thank You Curt
switzerland in principle it would be
useful to be able to express an early
warning first on the string and then on
second level on the applicant and/or on
his business model but something that I
start to realize which is in at least in
my head slightly reducing the value of
this whole early warning system and I
put it as a question due to the board is
my perception write that in case we
would realize that there is a string
with that we do not think it's
problematic we look at the applicant and
then we look at his business models
already registrar conditions whatever
and and then realize that something is
not applicable to our law in our country
and then you issue an early warning
saying like basically everything would
be fine but we have a problem there we
cannot accept this what is the use of
this if
if i get is right that if the applicant
cannot modify is application he can only
with with droid is that right that's the
only answer you can give unless this
exception with geographic names and
seeking government support but if if you
for instance in an early warning detect
a minor flaw which would cause you to to
to file an objection against the
applicant can only decide I go
nevertheless or I withdraw there's
nothing in between is that right and and
then yeah that's you thinking Kurt
please so that question reflects a good
understanding we're we're loathe to
allow applicants to fully change their
application because that would allow
applicants to abuse the system get an
application in as a test and if that has
sort of fails they can sort of get
around the system by amending it but
there are ways an applicant can address
government concerns for example in the
case of a geographic name McCann secure
the approval of the government or there
may be conditions at government would
have before would otherwise approved
delegation of a name so it can put the
applicant on notice that the gac will
probably give jack advice or encourage
an objection in some way so there are
ways for governments to use the early
warning effectively and then the of
course the other use for gac advice is
to put the applicant on notice that
there is going to be gak advice or an
objection to it and give him or her the
opportunity to withdraw early for a
higher refund and so we're trying to
encourage the applicants to heed the gac
had early warning in that way Thank You
Curt patron want very quick comments
both on Herbert and in Thomas's
questions what way of trying to put in
place is a communication channel and and
the whole discussion we had during the
elaboration of the applicant guidebook
is to identify
tools for interaction not box the
capacity for the gac in particular to
make a comment at one moment and not
later and so on what was attempted was
to provide a way for intervening at
different stages and there are as thomas
has said there are different types of
problems that may emerge i think that
the proposal that andre are made of
having an interface or something that is
facilitating the interaction is in this
period of what we're trying to put in
place identifying as early as possible
and the early warning bears its its name
very well identifying problems as early
as possible is beneficial for everybody
including for the candy of the
applicants and so there might be cases
where there is a general problem with
the string there are cases where there
is a specific problem for one or several
applicants because with that type of
string them should have done something
more than what they've done for instance
and they would be anchorage to move
forward and that can be cases where one
or several specific countries have a
particular problem that can or cannot be
addressed and where the applicant will
or will not withdraw in the end but what
i would like to highlight here is the
notion of a continuous process that will
move all along the evaluation the
objections and all those components that
have been put in the program as
protections as a general remarkable what
we've all attempted to do is to find
something that combines two very
difficult things to combine one is
openness and the other side is
protections and the whole process of
dialogue with the GAC and the early
warning and the advice the various level
of advisers isn't are intended to make
sure that there is always an avenue for
interaction when there's
problem I think that's the best answer
we can give at that moment and the
questions that you are asking we need to
keep asking them in parallel with using
the process so that we improve it as
much as we as we move forward you said
in case there would be more than 500 you
would divide this in batches of 500 that
you would proceed kind of one of the
other in case you receive four thousand
applications how do you decide which
ones up going to be in the first batch
and which ones are going to be in the
last batch will there be according to
the date that they actually hand in the
replications or those from A to G and
then those from g what is that what is
your reflection in how to divide these
into batches thank you rod please we are
still working on this issue there's some
complex legal implications and also
there's some technical or operational
issues but we haven't locked down on a
specific batching algorithm yet but we
will be doing that and when we do we
will be sharing it Thank you Thank You
European Commission when when you say
that you're going to process batches of
500 application does it mean that you're
going to how can I put it does it mean
that you're going to present to us only
500 applications and then the next 5
under are going to come later or would
like a clarification because that's
quite unclear to me the application
window will be open from January 12th
until April twelfth there's no limit on
the number of applications that may be
submitted in that time frame if the
number of applications that is received
is over 500 then we will have to look at
the issue of how do we handle or how do
we process those applications in batches
and the current intention is to do that
in a number of around 500 per batch so
it depends on if there's a higher number
than 500 then we will need to do some
batch processing if the numbers lower
than 500 then we will begin the process
yes they'll all be buck sorry they'll
all be posted at the same time so all
the applications receive we will publish
the information in May on the date
certain as Kurt mentioned with the the
publicly available information
the Netherlands please know that Cortez
a telephone oh sorry the microphone just
one I think very essential question
about remediating an application I
understand that you don't want to have
applicants gaming the system and
changing their application but in
certain cases which are not only
geographic but also others like dot
sector an example of whatever sector
imagine just to be very had to have a
concrete example imagine that after
talks with with gang members after an
early warning that the registry would
then maybe make a stricter policy and
say for example that on the second level
there is organization dot sector and he
would say ok I want this to have
stricter for example a registered name
from organization on the second level
but with a minimum of ten countries
existent origins my question basically
it's on and on what extent do you have
the possibility of having a stricter
policy which will then alleviate
concerns of them of some governments or
the whole gig thank you so what the
guidebook says is that an applicant
cannot materially change their
application and it's interesting to talk
about specific examples like this but I
don't I don't want to give an indication
whether a certain specific example of a
change would be allowable because we
want to maintain the goals of making it
not gay mobile but we also understand
that you know a registry might want to
further restrict its its application
make it more now in order to bring it
into into the the goals of what the
government has so there's some limited
opportunity to adjust how they're going
to operate the registry without amending
their application so as long as it's
within those guidelines of getting to
the goal of not being able to gain but
other than that I don't want to really
comment on a specific application that
people might rely on later on