I can meeting 42 has just concluded here
in dakar senegal we're here with rod
Beckstrom president and CEO of I can and
Steve Crocker chair of the ICANN board
who have agreed to answer a few
questions for us rod let's start with
you it's roughly about two months before
the new gtld application window opens is
I can ready we are ready and we've got a
operating process we've set up to to
handle them in batches anyway so we're
ready to handle whatever a number of
applications comes it'll just be a
question of how much time it takes to
process them Steve does the governmental
advisory committee so called early
warning system mean in a de facto sense
that the governmental representatives
will have veto power over new gTLDs what
it means is that they will get a solid
straight forward list of the strings
being applied for have an opportunity to
comment on them raise any issues and
make sure that they're heard it's not a
veto power but it is a high quality
channel so that we have no
miscommunication rod based upon
questions asked by some of the
governmental advisory committee members
there appears to be some concern over
the practice of so-called batching can
you explain what that is and is there a
cause for concern for I can hear sure we
can receive any number of applications
in the window the application window but
we're only going to process them in
batches of 500 so we have to decide how
we're going to order those applications
that come in in those batches and
there's a complex set of legal and
technical issues involved and we're
going to come up with a solution pretty
shortly and announced that so the GAC
had some questions about that and the
other thing they were interested in was
whether their early warning was going to
be done in separate batches of 500 each
or whether they be asked to provide
comment on all of the applications when
we publish the list of strings in May
Steve what did the board do about trying
to assist potential new gtld applicants
from emerging economies developing
countries those in need of assistance
well you may recall that we previously
allocated
fund of 2 million dollars to be put
forth to assist applicants we didn't put
precise specifications on how that would
be used we this time they were the joint
applicants support so called jazz
working groups submitted a very
thoughtful and very heartfelt report
with a whole list of recommendations the
board received that report and is
committed to putting something sensible
in place that meets the twin conditions
of being responsive to that community
and at the same time fits into the
what's practical to do with the program
so does that mean you're the board is
endorsing the recommendations of the
reporter you're trying to figure out how
to implement the major themes that run
through the ribbons closer to the latter
want to be a bit careful because the
group that put that together did not
have all of the business issues and
business process issues at hand weren't
part of the rods team and and all of his
employees so we definitely take the
themes who definitely take the intent
and now we want to find out what's the
best way to get to as close as we can to
that idea and still not break things
like ask both you gentlemen this was a
subject of a lot of conversation not
only if this meeting but in the last
meeting of seeing of that Singapore why
is this so important I can I think it's
part of broadening out who we are and
what we do and there's a recognition
that we just want a lot more
participation from emerging markets
emerging countries around the world and
developing countries are really
important and it's wonderful to have
events like we have here in Africa but
we want to see them fully participating
in this program Cohen commonly said you
know there's two billion users on the
internet that's not evenly distributed
and there's quite a lot of attention not
just within I can but broadly around the
world of how to increase that
participation in the developing
countries and so I would view this as
our part of how to participate in that
general thrust
why is this so important this particular
subject matter and how important is it
to those potential applicants that may
exist here in the African continent for
example sure well as you know we have a
slogan called one world one internet and
that means we want to keep the internet
open and unified globally and that means
we really want people from all over the
world to benefit from this unified
domain name system and so we want to see
applicants from developing countries as
well as from others and it's important
to them to feel included so it has a
great psychic benefit and political
benefit for participants around the
world to feel like they're going to get
a hand to participate in this program
extending the internet and increasing
the participation in the developing
countries is a major theme for the next
period of time it will take quite a
while and program that we're rolling out
new gTLDs is a sort of our contribution
to how to extend the reach one element a
new gTLD program will be so called
internationalized domain names ID ends
and that will make the internet
accessible help make it accessible to
large number of people who don't speak
English or any of the Western languages
as they're as their native language
everyone in the world counts and as
Steve mentioned there's 2 billion users
of the internet and the world but
there's many more of those in the
developing world than the developed than
in the developing world and that's
beginning to shift and we want to do
anything we can to help make sure that
the domain name services and choices and
opportunities are available all over the
world so because everyone everyone
matters it should be defined by
inclusivity yes exactly Steve one of the
controversies that has arisen over the
past few weeks is conflict of interest
or perceived conflicts of interest with
current or former board members what is
the board doing to deal with those
concerns well we have always had very
tight conflict of interest policies
nonetheless it's been opportunity to
take a close look
at the policies at our ethics policies
to see if there's areas that can be
expanded or pieces that can be filled in
and then equally to look at our
practices that follow those policies and
to sharpen those at the board level we
go through an ordinate amount of testing
about conflicts on in given situations
whether a particular board member is has
business relationships that might be
perceived to be related to something
we're currently voting on we're in the
process of tightening things up even
more than drawing a kind of wider fat or
lying around so that there's just no
issues rod what's I can't doing at a
staff level to deal with these same
types of concerns you know is continuous
education that we do there's a lot of
tightening that we've been doing since I
mentioned this issue in June and my
speech and Singapore that I thought that
launching the new gTLD program with the
economic power behind met was going to
put new pressures on the board and on
the staff we started tightening up
internally so it's about education and
it's about drawing new lines such as at
this event we educated our staff that
they were not to accept a free meal or a
free drink from anyone in the industry
that might be a potential applicant for
the program and some people consider
that draconian and I thought it was
pretty clear and concrete and it was I
was really pleased that so many people
this event called talked about how you
can't even give an employee of coke and
that's right so I'm glad that the
concept stuck but it goes farther than
that we also decided that we would not
have any staff members participate in
the new gtld Roadshow if they were
involved in processing applications we
also decided that staff members should
report any contact with potential
applicants for new gTLDs who were
talking to them and asking questions
about it so that we have a really clear
documentation trail just to show how
fair work we are in processing these
applications and how independent it is
because we do have an important role in
a quasi regulatory manner in some ways
and we've got to be absolutely fair
absolutely objective
extremely clean and everything that we
do and I think we've got a long way to
go to keep educating and improving our
practices both on the board and on the
staff you seem to be saying objectivity
is not simply important in fact it has
to be perceived broadly we got to change
behavior so I mean because of you
because as I mentioned in Singapore
we're moving from having crafted the
program and in crafting the policies and
the guidelines there was heavy
interaction between the board the staff
and the community now we're moving to a
phase where we're in the program
execution and that contact between the
board and applicants and between staff
and applicants has to change because the
applications have got to be treated so
independently and so fairly because some
of these new gTLDs can be worth many
millions of dollars and we can't have
situations where those applicants are
lobbying board members or lobbying staff
members seeking to gain benefits for
themselves Steve there's been some
questions raised as to whether the
internet root zone can handle the influx
of new TLDs well I wouldn't want to say
it's a not a valid concern but it's for
those of us who actually understand the
dynamics and the how the root zone works
it really is not a concern at all the
root zone is a very very small when
we're talking about expanding it it's
still going to be quite small compared
to all of the other zones that are
common across the Internet the root zone
is a tiny tiny fraction of what any of
the major top-level domains are for
example so from a technology point of
view expanding the root zone is a really
very minor manner what are the biggest
things that came out of this particular
meeting into car so certainly one of the
primary and most interesting aspects was
the focus on Africa who had the African
regional at large organization had a
summit had a showcase had many people
from around the region participating
also had interest in participation from
the government level we have African
ministerial meeting three days leading
into the icam meeting and
the same location and is very focused on
not only general ICT and not only
general internet issues but also focused
very much on what I can could do that
would be helpful in this region the
African Minister ministers put together
a communicate with 12 very specific
requests that showed a lot of knowledge
what they weren't they weren't
superficial they were very pointed and
it was pretty interesting engagement so
we're quite interested in that so that's
one whole focus and a number of other
things that were maybe less visible
along the same lines that I think we
learned an awful lot about what this
region could use and would find helpful
then the other themes of course were the
interest in the conflict of interest as
you say there is considerable interest
in the process that we've set in motion
to look for the very daunting task of
looking for a successor for a rod
Beckstrom here and the other things
related to the gtld launch process
including of course support for
applicants from developing areas rod let
me put the same question to you what
will people remember about i can4t to a
number of things I mean as Steve
mentioned the ministerial was fantastic
and I think the communique that was
delivered by the ministers do I can very
constructive I think people are going to
remember the President's speech this was
the first time a head of state spoke to
I can and went so in depth on the policy
issues of the domain name system he was
clearly very well briefed and interested
in animated in the issues because he's
got an interest in the internet so I
think that was a highlight plus just the
beauty of Senegal the physical beauty of
the coastline here the people the music
the great events it's just it was just a
fabulous fabulous experience and our
first event ever by the way in French
sub-saharan Africa gentlemen thank you
very much thank you thank you