bienvenue à la vida reunion telecon
dans une deca on soleil ye welcome to i
KN 42 and to sunny dakar as you will
have discovered the senegalese are known
for their hospitality a hospitality so
warm that it rivals the sun that shines
on the beaches and the city there is a
wall off word for it taronga we are
deeply grateful to the government of
senegal's Ministry of Communication and
telecommunications and ICT and to the
regulatory agency for telecommunications
and posts for their generosity and
hospitality and hosting this meeting
they have shown us the true meeting of
taronga we welcome our special guests
who honor us with their presence today
His Excellency President wad of Senegal
and Minister gavazzi we thank Madame
Japp director of ICT at the ministry of
information and communications
technologies we also thank the
organisation internationale de la
Francophonie and in particular Franco
Pole and Federico go of the circuit a du
Quebec for organising an outreach and
awareness session for senegalese law
enforcement on dealing with cyber crime
and I would like to recognize Africa's I
can and internet leaders including ideal
a plugin CEO of afrinic for joining us
today I'm glad to see so many of you
here today and equally glad that so many
more are participating remotely there is
another West African tradition for which
Senegal is well known and that is
storytelling storytelling is done by
griot who have kept West African history
alive for thousands of years through
words and music the griot profession is
passed down generation to generation and
requires years of training and
apprenticeship in genealogy history and
music Creole literally give voice to
generations
of West African society having a voice
and being heard is a fundamental human
right creo are important members of West
African society because they are living
history books they hold the stories of a
society in their hearts and minds but
each of us holds our own stories
opinions and ideas and we share them in
discussions with each other through
articles and white papers through
lectures music art videos and through
social networks and through meetings
like this one here today a few days ago
I had the opportunity to visit the Ile
du go vague it's a picturesque island
but one with a tragic history as a slave
trading station today it is a museum and
a UNESCO World Heritage Site reminding
us of those terrible events and the
millions who cross the threshold of the
door of no return and who lost their
freedom it struck me that the internet
represents exactly the opposite it
brings freedom and connection to
everyone from any place anywhere at any
time it allows us to connect to anyone
opening up new worlds and building a new
stronger society and helping to unite
our world the internet is another door
and now that we have passed through it
the world will never be the same not for
us and not for governments Senegal like
most other nations is experiencing the
rapid growth of information and
communication technologies that growth
brings the potential for innovation
increased productivity education and
greater competitiveness it connects
people in new and exciting ways it
brings more voices into the chorus more
voices that enrich our discussions
and more voices that foster innovation
the internet advances economies through
innovation it provides a global launch
pad for ideas that will generate
tomorrow's great economic opportunities
it empowers creative thought and
risk-taking and never has the internet
had a more fertile ground to grow in
here in Africa there has been tremendous
progress towards greater connectivity in
10 years the number of Internet users
has increased 25-fold this is rapid
growth yet it still represents only 11.5
percent of all Africans the stage is set
for greater growth thanks to a phoenix
distribution of ipv6 addresses as Steve
alluded to according to AfriNIC more
than half the continent has received
blocks of ipv6 addresses so nattel
senegal's telecommunications provider
will speak about ipv6 at a roundtable
session this Thursday as they are one of
the leaders in this area African ccTLDs
including Nigeria Senegal South Africa
Tanzania Tunisia and Uganda are adding
security to the main name system by
working to deploy DNS SEC so many others
who are taking advantage of the
three-day DNS SEC security training this
week offered by the network startup
resources center Nick Senegal and I can
I also hope that many of you will
participate in sx meaning on DNS SEC
this Wednesday your voices are stronger
than ever and the Internet's potential
for greater growth and influence makes
ICANN's role even more relevant than
ever yesterday I had the honor of
addressing the opening session of a
capacity building workshop attended by
representatives from nearly every
African at large structure after lo
vice-chair to Johnny Benjamin and chair
Fatima Tazi asilah have built a five-day
training program to give African civil
the tools and the knowledge to
participate effectively in the ikn
policy development process as we move
steadily closer to truly connecting
every person in the world our collective
economic future will depend on
maintaining a stable domain name system
a stable and unified DNS provides the
foundation for continued innovation I
can must ensure that this role is
understood and advance our common goal
of a secure stable and unified global
internet that is job number one for I
can I mentioned a few moments ago that
everyone has a voice and a right to be
heard and I can those concepts are a
part of our DNA the internet is a global
resource that belongs to everyone we
believe that everyone with an interest
in the Internet has an equal right to be
heard in its governance I can is built
on openness inclusion trust and
collaboration these very principles are
woven into the multi-stakeholder
processes demonstrated here this week
the entire ecosystem collaborates
Internet service providers domain name
businesses local internet communities
governments internet standards bodies
regional internet registries individual
internet users nonprofits and businesses
around the world engagement with
governments is also fundamental to
ICANN's role and to the very future of
the internet in representing governments
that I can the governmental advisory
committee or gac makes its voice heard
in all of our work the GAC significant
role and I can of course complements
many other groups this constructive
international engagement including the
series of intensive board gac
consultations was demonstrated
throughout the development of the new
gtld program it demonstrates once again
that the multi-stakeholder model is
alive and working
operating a new gtld as many of you know
is a complex undertaking and applicants
from developing countries may need
technical or financial information or
assistance to facilitate the
establishment of a new registry icann's
global community is already taking steps
to help needy applicants for new gTLDs a
Joint Working Group has spent many many
hours working on a proposal that the
board will consider this week on how
best to provide that support details may
still need to be ironed out before the
application window opens in January but
the voice of the global community is
clear on this issue support for needy
applicants will help ensure that we
receive a diversity of new gtld
applications and that these are not just
domains for big organizations in the
developed world ICANN's global community
is rich with talented and experienced
people who may be interested in helping
as well part of the support available
includes an online gathering space to
facilitate cooperation among those
interested in establishing a public
interest gtld registry and entities
willing and able to provide pro bono
assistance this part of the microsite is
now up at ICANN org I encourage each of
you to think about how you can help
could you offer pro bono services
in-kind support or grants assist with
application writing technical
requirements registry back-end services
or DNS SEC consulting whatever means you
choose you will be able to help bring
more voices and more people to the
internet new gTLDs are an important
initiative and communicating about the
program has kept me and many other I can
staff members very busy in early
September several of us hit the road and
scattered around the globe to spread the
word when the board approved the new
gtld program in Singapore in June it
charged us with informing and educating
the world
about new gTLDs that plan includes an
ambitious series of organized visits and
events in many countries this is the
first key deliverable of the new gTLD
program it represents phase 1 of
operations in recent weeks I can
representatives have explained discussed
and debated new gTLD programs in Ankara
Beirut Berlin Buenos itís Cape Town
delhi Doha Dubai Helsinki Istanbul
London Munich Nairobi Oslo Paris sao
paulo and warsaw and we were planning to
take parts and events in beijing jakarta
moscow Sofia Tokyo and beyond in every
case we have met members of this
community government officials business
leaders academics and students the media
innovators and entrepreneurs we're not
done yet but I wanted to take this
opportunity to provide an update on our
progress and to acknowledge some of
those involved first let me thank the
many staff board community members
who've spoken and taken parted events in
numerous countries as a part of these
outreach efforts there are far too many
of you to mention here by name but
please know that your contributions to
this awareness-raising effort are both
noted and appreciated the message we've
been delivering is that the new gtld
program offers unique opportunities but
that applying for and running a registry
isn't for everyone anyone who might be
interested needs to do their own
homework develop a solid understanding
of the program and then determine if the
new gTLD is right for them the clock is
ticking judging from the media coverage
we've generated the roadshow has been a
success we've been interviewed numerous
times on television radio online
newspapers allowing our message to
spread far beyond the auditorium's and
conference halls across six continents
to reach potential applicants
international news outlets such as al
Jazeera BBC CNN have carried stories as
have major newspapers in every country
we have visited in India alone no fewer
than 15 english-language newspapers and
many more in other languages carried
stories on new gTLDs based on our visit
the people we've met and talked with
have many questions and they've come
away with a better understanding of what
new gTLDs are all about and more
importantly they will have a better
understanding of what I can is all about
and a deeper appreciation for all the
work that we collectively do
representatives of more than 100
countries are here in dakar today I ask
each of you to help us carry this
message to your communities whether that
means distributing materials organizing
events sending a web link or sending an
email to your networks and your
associations whatever steps you take
please do so soon the new gtld
application window opens in 79 days
that's just a little over two months
away and it's before we'll meet again
the next time at our i can meeting in
san jose costa rica we can we can bring
more voices and more people to the
internet through internationalized
domain names I dians make it possible to
access the internet in scripps other
than latin-based characters and their
adoption has been one of the community's
great collaborative efforts maybe you
only speak Arabic or Chinese or Hindi I
d-ends will make it easier to join the
conversation and to tell your story I've
spent much of this speech on the value
of hearing from the widest possible
range of voices on internet governance
and that is true no matter what your
view in a multi-stakeholder model it's
important that everyone be heard since
we met in Singapore i can has opened
more than 20 public comment periods on
topics such as expired domain names and
how to expand participation from
developing countries in the new gTLD
program but i had to smile when i saw
the title of a public comment period
that opened at the end of august the
announcement said that we were seeking
public comment on our public comment
process if that doesn't sum up I can I
don't know what does we have to be one
of the most open governance structures
in the world when your organization is
built on a foundation of accountability
and transparency as ours is you wind up
seeking public input on how you see
public input and that I think is a good
thing how we receive public comments
matters because it's a bedrock concept
in a bottom-up model like ours ongoing
community review cycles are built into
icann's foundation through the
affirmation of commitments as we
implement the ATR T recommendations the
who is and security stability and
resiliency review teams are developing
additional recommendations to improve I
can right now there are multiple
organisational reviews underway
simultaneously roughly nine in total
having trouble keeping up with them so
am I so we built a website that includes
a simple visual graphic depicting the
status of each review with links for
more information to help all of us
follow those important initiatives I
also want to give you an update and
where we are with the IANA functions
contract those who have followed its
evolution recall that back in the late
1990s the US government laid out a
vision for ICANN's rapid transition to a
fully independent international
organization this was clearly stated in
the white paper approved by the US
government as official Department of
Commerce policy we're not there yet
instead we see
a series of short-term contracts
overseen by the US government in
response to Commerce's request for
comment on the anna functions contract
many have argued that this structure is
no longer appropriate for the
organization responsible for a key
function of the global Internet nor has
that process achieved the level of
transparency that we feel the global
community has a right to expect we are
pleased that the department shares our
concern as evidenced by their commitment
to include greater transparency
requirements in the next contract we
hope that the department will permit us
to publish data related to root zone
change requests so that every major step
in the process will be open to public
examination the spirit of the ATR t and
the affirmation of commitments demands
no less we also hope that commerce will
support publication of the detailed user
documentation that i can has developed
over the past two years which will
increase the confidence of other nations
and stakeholders that the process of
roop updates is fair and predictable
many submissions to commerce
specifically requested that i can
structure be more international the
feedback from many community
participants globally was that the
current unilateral structure of IANA
functions contract should evolve to meet
the needs of the global community we
hope that progress toward the vision
articulated by the US government's white
paper will be made in the next agreement
and we hope and we expect to see a road
map for the realization of this vision
in the future as I work through the
remaining year of my term we have many
challenges and opportunities ahead of us
we need it we need to negotiate a
successful evolution of the ANA
functions contract that expires at the
end of March we need to successfully
launched the new gTLD program the
largest and most complex program and
icons history we need to continue to
implement the 80 RT recommendations and
support its community reviews
we are a complex organization and our
complexity increases with every new
review working group or policy
initiative that adds more requirements
and processes to what we already do
pressures and I can are growing
political ethical financial geopolitical
and operational the complexity of the
geopolitical landscape the risk and
unpredictability of a new gTLD program
the mounting concerns over cyber
security the need to coordinate so many
diverse institutional and organizational
tasks present an enormous challenge to
an organization of just under 150 staff
members covering activities across six
continents given the increased respect
in stature for I can around the world
and as witnessed this morning we're in
an excellent position to recruit a
highly talented individual for the CEO
position a skilled manager respected by
the world and able to lead a complex
international organization in transition
we are currently operating with an
annual budget of 85 million dollars and
with the new gTLD program this could
perhaps double ICANN's next CEO may be
from any country in the world working in
any organization but must have the
courage to manage and in some cases
stand up to the many pressures and
special interests the CEO is subjected
to every day the person who succeeds me
should be a person of integrity
experienced talent skill intellect and
leadership qualities someone with a
strong international background and the
judgment to make tough choices under
enormous pressure the board recently
adopted a resolution about the CEO
search it states that no current or
incoming member of the board or liaisons
may be considered as a candidate for the
role of CEO it was intended to assure
the community that the search process
would be fair and impartial and avoid
the appearance of a clue
your conflict of interest I feel very
strongly that the board members
interested in the position whether they
have applied in the past would like to
apply now have expressed an interest or
may apply in the future should state
their interest publicly in addition the
board Governance Committee identified
three of its members to review and guide
staff efforts to revise the conflicts of
interest policy and the ethics program
my decision to leave does not mean that
I'm going to take my foot off the gas
pedal I don't know how to I plan on
driving us to accomplish two years of
work in the next eight months I am more
focused than ever on the execution of
top priorities I will also do my best to
ensure an efficient and effective trand
over hand over at the end of my term and
I hope that the person who replaces me
will be the highest integrity and has no
recent or current commercial or career
interests in the domain industry because
I cans fairness objectivity and
independence are of paramount importance
to the future of the Internet we are not
here in the domain name business we are
here to serve the global public interest
if we can continue to manage the
challenges I've talked about I can is
poised for future success to lay the
groundwork this fiscal year we put into
place a new financial management system
this should give the board the community
management and staff greater insight
into budget management and it will also
further enhance our commitment to
accountability in transparency we have
also just receive our 12th consecutive
clean audit we have a 100-percent track
record in this respect our financial
house remains in order we will continue
to exercise the budgetary discipline
needed to keep costs low and to be good
stewards of icons resources working with
verisign and NTIA we have completed a
multi-year automation project that
streamlines the management of the root
zone and this year we will
transfer all of our marina de rey staff
to a new facility to enhance the
productivity and to better accommodate
the technological needs of the
organization and we'll also continue to
bring new voices into the I can multi
stakeholder process at every level thank
you to those of you here who are new to
the ican family and attending one of our
meetings for the first time we are glad
that you're here we welcome you this
fiscal year was the first in which full
remote participation was used at all
three international public meetings with
stakeholders in every country in the
world I can strives for world-class
remote participation services that
enable internet users and their voices
to the discussion from wherever they may
be remote participation supports ICANN's
commitment to maintain and improve
robust mechanisms for public input and
transparency this is what bottom-up
consensus-driven policymaking looks like
those remote connections are enabling
people in beijing Johannesburg and
Montevideo to participate in this week's
meetings here in dakar without having to
be physically present technology
connects all of us in New in complex
ways breaking down geographical
boundaries and creating a virtual
gathering place for the world to share
ideas and tell their stories in my
recent travels I've seen people
accessing the Internet in the tea rooms
of Delhi and in the shisha bars of Doha
I've heard of Internet buses crossing
Africa and Baneen in Rwanda that are
bringing computers and connectivity to
children and villages allowing them to
use the internet for the first time in
their lives technology is woven into the
everyday lives of people around the
world and the world is a better place
for it there's a wonderful African
proverb that I will leave you with this
afternoon I am because we are and we are
because I am
this beautifully expresses our new new
life and our new world of connectedness
each of us exists in community with
others like the West African griot who
trace their lineage of their people and
who keep their ancestors alive through
storytelling and past these stories on
from generation to generation we are the
keepers of something just as important
together we maintain a global community
built around the operation of the
Internet's domain name system each of us
is a part of that whole the internet is
the doorway to the future and now that
we've gone through it there's no going
back I want to extend thanks to the
ICANN staff whose diligence has built a
foundation for our good work here in
dakar this week a special thank you to
the meeting staff for seeing to every
technical and logistical detail and
thank you to the global community those
of you here and those participating
remotely and all those who leverage this
technology for the betterment of people
everywhere together we are I can we
accomplish so much together we bring new
voices to the discussion we maintain a
stable internet we are poised to launch
the new gTLD program successfully what
happens next is up to each of us and all
of us thank you