we have to celebrate the people who have
worked to go through the challenges in
the hacking village and collect Sam's
and be active and try out their hacking
skills so I have quite the list of
winners here and we're going to go
through them one by one we have some
awesome goodies and prizes to kind of
recognize those who have made an effort
to show their skills to learn something
new
hack devices infrastructure ATMs do
ariadne's thread and many other
competitions so I'm going to start one
by one and I'm going to invite on stage
some of our partners to give out these
prizes as they've been so generous and
helping us really award those who have
made an effort
so the first winners are those of the
Deaf can capture the flag competition
and I'd like to welcome on stage
Christiane petechiae from orange Romania
Cristian please join me on stage
this is your mic we have three winners
so please go ahead and call them out so
thank you very much not so fast
okay first of all congratulate all of
you it was an amazing event I hope that
you enjoyed that today's it was an
amazing speaker lineup so I guess we
need to thanks Andre and his team for
this so please enjoy meet them okay
so please rise your hands the connection
the wireless was okay no no no connect
the Wi-Fi connection because we had mic
before the wireless connection we had a
mobile operators orange we provided a
connection it was okay or not sure
because next year maybe just think of
all this okay actually we will gather
all the information from from our letter
because we did also some capture
together with Mike we put together maybe
with Ixia data Emily tried to to have
some nice information for you the kind
of bulletin after the event okay let's
see okay I will start with the third
place hacking force stones you from
Sweden
please join me
[Music]
I'll support guys please line up line up
for the group picture
[Music]
let's give them another round of
applause
[Music]
awesome work guys now I guess it was a
tough decision
tough night okay second place P for
Poland
[Music]
okay and the winner for this they've
come eighth edition is DCU a from
Ukraine
[Music]
okay thank you congratulate the winner
please now I will invite Anatole which
will tell us a little about the
technical specificity of the CTF hello
everyone how are doing yay okay so as as
we have everywhere it was an amazing
event and I'd like to thank first of all
for the organizers for the nice event
the guys in the DVF team that helped
with the challenges everyone thank you
and of course the participants in the
winners as always it's a it's a great
event we had we had in that much sleep
but it's worth it
let's be fair it's worth it how do you
feel guys sleepy tired
are you happy well yeah ok
I want to just ask a couple of questions
real quick about the challenges about
the Romania about the event what do you
think final challenge with kitties like
kittens huh there was a task with some
kittens and they spent a lot of time on
it oh hang on what do you guys think of
the competition this is actually have a
third time that we actually deaf camp
and every year is actually even better
you know so it's actually progressing
with with each year I mean we hope that
we actually will be able to come here
next year and it will be even better
than this year if it's even possible
entirely possible don't miss the
qualification round waiting here what do
you say guys
how it was for you yeah we
it was a it was a bumpy ride ups and
down but there was a fun and educating
experience I'd like to know everyone to
know that sorrow is an alcoholic drink
they're hacking for that first source
don't be seen it's totally cool thank
you guys once again thanks everyone who
participated from all four all the
thanks all the teams from the far Canada
on the west and to Taiwan and Korea on
the east it's an amazing experience
every year to see so many faces so many
people and so many cultures here
together hacking for something awesome
thank you awesome thank you guys we're
about to receive the winners for the
next competition and for that I'd like
to invite on stage Adriana de from Ikea
to help us give the words to the next
contestant for defend the castle thank
you so hello thank you all for being
here today first of all big thanks to
the organizers of this great event we
had a small competition of writing ideas
signatures we had a number of eager
participants and we would not like to
give prizes to the best so third place
and new Alec smart SDR device goes to
Adrienne to door
[Music]
okay second place and the Wi-Fi
pineapple nano goes to share Barbra Jean
[Music]
and now up first place the winner of
this year's competition mister you're
nuts chair Nika
[Music]
so thank you all again and hope to see
you again next year thanks for that a
lot more where that came from so next on
we move on to the winner is a very
honest red city of 2.00 words presented
to you by Andre or done from SecureWorks
Andre please join me on stage hey
everybody the first thing that I'm gonna
do
I'd really like to invite on stage with
me the two guys that helped really drive
this competition please welcome chipra
and daniel come on guys come on alright
it's it's the second year when I start
to see a pattern it's the second year
where nobody managed to capture that all
the ten flags so guys if you have your
Rotten Tomatoes and everything hold for
them for a little while unfortunately
it's also the second time when we kind
of lose the person that's one of the
main drivers so I'll see you back in a
while
so thanks guys for helping drive this
and now I'm going to reference my
screenshot from a quarter to four and
I'd like to invite so we have a tie we
knew that hence the two devices or
something so please help me welcome team
brain come on team come on guys
sure like the one-man army okay cool so
this saves me because if there were more
of you I'd say well one if it takes this
one of you takes this and then you
settle things between ourselves but no
issue there
congratulations how was it it was hard
because it was two competitions
simultaneously but it was I've got so
I'm glad we do we publish everything
else okay we don't publish will you
leave it running okay you can break your
teeth in it later and the second team
it's team bad rabbit I think black
rabbit yeah
see a pattern see a pattern
hey any thought well I think it was
sexual in a CTF like I don't know I was
playing it after the camp sir was kinda
see me dead so it's hard to say how hard
the task really were but well very nice
I like it thank you and we promise we'll
be back here for the next year with
something even more difficult
thank you everybody thanks so much
congratulations to all the winners where
we're about to meet the next ones from
the IOT village and I'd like to invite
respond Mauritian from bit different
nose up in polka both okay now we have
to so rez one Sabine thank you I'll do
the talking he'll do the handling every
time I get here so to this year we had
only two devices that were correct to
say we had a lot of teams and I would
like to thank first of all deaf camp for
helping us organizing again the arity
village and thanks to all the sponsors
specifically that wolf shapin behind
reservoir and without further ado let's
invite the winner so winning unsecured
mass western digital my cloud bla bla is
pawel hopefully I will pronounce it
right crazy Levitch and his name
[Music]
I wouldn't store anything confidential
here to be honest the box is very light
because it doesn't actually have the
device in it the device is back in the
RIT village we'll see you later
yeah and the big winners they actually
were very close to get the second device
but ran out of time and also the first
blood which comes with an additional 50
euros right I think from us is Maksim
cotton we and his team congrats guys
again I wouldn't print anything that
dubious on this
[Music]
few words thank you very much he was a
great fun to participate his content
contest so thank you very much for
Bogdan Andre for everybody who assist us
during this great event thank you
gentlemen it was a real pleasure to be
here and participated this contest and
Thank You max awesome Congrats everyone
now for more good fun let's see who was
the best at hacking critical
infrastructure Alexandre so detour from
an AVO it will join me now on stage to
introduce our winners hello everyone
actually I forgot to take something yeah
so first of all want to thank deaf camp
for the wonderful energy generates about
critical attack infrastructure we
simulated a couple of control processes
one of them was a substation that was
powering actually the train system that
was next to it was the table with the
transistor was running around and was
cutting it short a word to Ricardo
petricka is somewhere around here
[Music]
third place goes to Alexandru choker tow
hang on for the picture in just a second
second place goes to units that are gone
II unfortunately he's not here because
he had to take a flight to Natalie - we
still can give him a big round of
applause please and also really fun a
nice fact about him he actually
developed his own his own script his own
exploit for for one of the plc is
actually devoted for another one test on
this one and it's still new first place
goes to Alexandria Chu who again is not
here he's round of applause this guy
lost his credit card and had to go to
the bank to change it so thank you
everyone and please a round of applause
for my team who actually made the whole
event possible and did that table in
such a short time it was amazing please
thank you
awesome thank you so much Alexandra now
time to find out who won the ICS
homeless EDF are on money from PR ooh
please join me on stage
hello guys this is my first time in deaf
camp 8 and really it's Def Jam is
rocking
really and I really thanks to Andre and
his team so my the CT up is related to
ICS some simulators and some hardware
related so you need to come some
firmware you need to tap some
communication between two ICS this stuff
was there so I would like to announce
third the third winner his name is Marty
and
and the second winner is it's really
difficult to pronounce the third first
he's not here actually he he left
because he want to try out his home so
his name is Eunice Dragoon II so let's
see see you next year thank you so much
thank you it's awesome to be involved in
the same project with so many passionate
people next up we're going to find out
who want the heck Dabangg competition
that idiom certainly drew a lot of
attention so Olga coach Aloha and Alex
AOC bow from kaspersky please join me on
stage
hello everyone we are very glad to be
here and many things for organizers for
all sponsors partners for everyone who
made this event so awesome and he likes
keep silence yeah and we are ready to
invite our winners and the third place
is for Georgia dragon
thank you very much we should drink more
beer that's definitely my moto so yeah
thank you thank you for this chance to
participate and yeah hopefully we'll do
it but better next year thank you thank
you
Georgia got some prizes from organizers
and from From Russia With Love some
small not vodka small price from
Kaspersky Lab and the second place we
are welcome to Tudor Georgia
it was very fun to participate and it
was definitely a challenge but I'm glad
I could overtake it thank you and the
first place is for retiree odeon Andre
[Music]
cheers guys it was an amazing challenge
quite difficult at first and pretty
interesting and thanks all the guys that
participated because at the end we kind
of old managed to put all of our
findings together so it's been a
teamwork stuff so it's no 1st place last
place or anything it's just us all
winners thanks for all the guys who
managed to do this who are participated
there are a plenty of interest in ATM
security we hope so that you will be
aware of that there are some problems
that you will be aware that there are
some issues with ATMs and these
particular devices are also should be
secured and we try to do it we try to
make things better and save the world
thank you
guys one more time thanks for everyone
you are really cool but be aware and be
careful don't do any event the things
around you on the real life thank you
thanks everyone now it's actually my
turn to give us three prizes for target
John so I'm going to start with the
third one pet rutila please join me on
stage
some cool recognition for you would you
like to see a few words
okay cool congratulations
now for the second place heiress Nicole
I'll come up here congratulations
[Music]
and now the winner of target John is
Adam hora - you got
[Music]
huge congratulations
so thank you guys we have two more
prizes to give out the next one is from
amigo I'd like to invite bok-dong Kasich
on stage to help out to draw some this
price I hope you just pass by their
booth also enjoy the coffee
haibach done it's on hi guys I don't
know if you had the chance to taste the
coffee but it's freaking awesome
especially in the mornings when you had
several hours of not sleeping so this
thing is actually sealed I try to find a
way basically to find them back door
didn't happen so I'm gonna brute force
it
[Music]
and look the lucky winner is
Zamfir Teodoro
[Music]
what no she's not okay I've been
instructed to let you guys know that she
will be contacted by the guys from
Strauss so basically this is it I'm
sorry I know someone back there who
wanted that the tablet but this is it
sorry sorry she's quite lucky and now
for the last prices of the day I'd like
to invite on stage fluorine atom
attracted a very very awesome Florina
which we all know and love who is such a
big part of this event and bok-dong
pegado from a sec oh please give them a
big big hand
hello everyone there were two intense
days of cybersecurity and now it's time
for the passport surprises tombola I
will pick the first winner how many of
you participated could you raise your
hands all of you that's good
so first when you let me 1 2 3 4 5 9
stamps is Bach Tamra's van woo
congratulations
you just want a Fitbit charge
hello everyone I will pick the second
one second second lucky
okay I'm sorry for the name but I don't
know how to read it it is something like
Bach 917 ski
[Music]
how do you read it
waha dancer at Natsuki thank you
okay next winner
next winner is Luciano Pasco
congratulations
[Music]
sorry this is damn lucky doesn't have
all the stems
another one
expect us from hackers right yeah
expect it to be more times not only one
how this is valid this is little
Christian
next we have the contacts here so it is
valid he will receive an email
next winner is Vlad loop wire
[Music]
the next winner is Katalin Dumitrescu
okay we'll keep it contacts okay next
winner
we have Raluca Constanta now too bad she
will receive an email and then the yard
the next winner is Diana Thomas cool
[Music]
and the last winner of the evening
mihaela boo
[Music]
thank you so much for your participation
and I'll see you next year I leave you
under awesome guys don't leave just yet
I think we should really gather the deaf
cap team here so Andre come up here
Florina don't go anywhere I know there
are not all of us here I'd like to say a
big things to entrada increasing as well
who handled everything
moderation wise in tracks 2 & 3 there's
a lot of work behind this event some of
it you can see it and feel it some of it
you don't but what I can tell you is
that there are tons of people who have
worked to make this happen and have show
their passion so let's give them a huge
round of applause and to our sponsors as
well
orange Romania the main partner Ixia
SecureWorks BitDefender Amazon and Ewa
Beach Sentinel KPMG Pierrot
PricewaterhouseCoopers DeCecco and amigo
and a special thanks to the Austrian
embassy
and its commercial section for
collaboration I hope that you'll take
the inspiration and the energy that you
got in these two days and go make
wonderful things happen it's been an
honor to be your host thank you for
having me here and we'll hopefully see
you again next year thank you
[Music]