hi everyone I'm here to talk and I
wouldn't call it the dreaded GTR if you
ask me it has a thing for people who
actually care about this and I see
there's quite a few of you here through
this could actually be an opportunity
and hopefully by the end of my talk
you'll also see why now I'm not going to
talk a lot about myself I'm in security
and legal hacking so basically I have
people in companies that they need to do
it and in this context in the past year
and a half or so I've been looking into
GE PR and we've been looking into
offering this as a service company that
I will also be on again Eastern will be
our protection officer we'll see what
that means now just if you've ever sort
of reveals what we're going to talk
about I will do high-level overview but
45 minutes we half of this talk is by no
means enough to cover a lot of the deep
details on on the EPR but at least
hopefully we'll get you the general idea
of what it means and what you should be
able to god we'll take a look at some of
the articles and I've chosen to
highlight some of them more interesting
or he or some of the B points were for
some companies out there that start to
address some of the changes that we
needed in companies all over to be able
to
handle the requirements of gdpr I'll
leave you with like a top ten list of
things to do if you want to start
working on this today or tomorrow
now let me said GPR is quite a complex
topic and there's a bunch of items and I
will talk I think about all of them most
of them over the course of the next five
minutes but it's just to give you an
idea of the sort of concepts that you
should be able to understand and be
comfortable with if you are dealing with
geography and with that I will start
with a show of hands how many of you are
hearing about DEP our first time to date
okay so not a lot of you how many have
heard about you Garrett no have for more
than a half of the things on that belief
all right so that's about half worth
little over half coming up you know that
the companies they work with or four are
already doing stats and are quite
confident that they will handle gdpr by
the time accompanied by a while you know
what there's no fear requirements of
watching EPR compliant these so the ones
that raise their hand
are actually hulis about what it
actually takes to be - you gotta plan so
what smarter than that
[Music]
GPR as opposed to directives in the EU
GDP art is a regulation was that one
here the panel
that is pal are here before lunch now a
lot of you so that's where they
discussed that this directive basically
the difference between a directive and
regulation within the EU is that the
directive is something that he needed
decides that should be implemented in
the Member States and then the Member
States have to pass a law to align who
the directive as opposed to that a
regulation does not require a lot to be
passed for it to company to in fact it
is recommended for you to start blinding
your local law to some of the new things
that are new regulation might ask of you
but it's not something that you have to
do for the regulation to come into
effect so this means that whether or not
our local government does anything this
will happen and this will happen to all
the Member States of the EU and not only
that it will affect companies even
outside you that collective store
process or deal with anything out any
personal data related to citizens of
European Union so that includes a
Facebook and Google and whoever if
they're not a new company but they do
collect store process data from EU
citizens they still have to comply to
this regulation it gets a bit more
complex and how they get fined and what
not but usually if a country has a
bilateral bilateral agreement with the
EU they will have to comply with us as
well now but what the GPR brings is
actually not a bunch of new things but
it just changes or enhances existing
personal rights dealing with data
privacy it
pieces and puts more pressure on
companies to better protect personal
development because it comes with
significant faculties at all and it also
includes mandatory reporting so if your
company has any sort of personal data
and if you're a company that has one
employee you are affected by this
because that one I believe he said uh
citizen of the EU you probably have an
employment contract the one on contract
has his personal data so from that point
on since you have this personal data in
any sort of digital or written form you
have to protect it according to the GPR
so the mandatory reporting means that if
your company goes with the average and
any of that personal data gets
compromised made public to be it'd
change anyway you have to report it to
the local or supervisory reporting in
the country or in GPR so the regulation
was published in April of 2016 and it's
mostly unknown people didn't really care
much until I think this summer is when
people actually started getting more
into it and learning more about it and
the nice show of hands employ more than
half
the room of people that have heard about
it a little bit about VR is proof of
that
however it's not too long before it
comes into effect so they they gave us a
little over two years it will come into
effect in in May of 2018 essentially
what it does like I said is to clarify
where responsibility lies when it comes
to privacy protection and it affects in
companies who like I said collects or
manage analyze process and sort of
personally identifiable information and
as I mentioned before whether your
company with me you or not if you do
this perfective it so it needs to
replace the current directive remember
interactive matriculation so there's
this directive that is curve being in
fact and the member states have passed
laws to align with that directive this
needs to replace that and it sort of
also complements that recently
introduced misdirected but one that was
briefly discussed and up at right before
lunch
GPR contains if you anyone here read the
entire thing also compared to the more
than half of the room raise their hands
I think that they know what GPRS about
the four people that raised their hands
that
reddit that's also a sign of the current
state of things it consists of 99
articles which is basically this should
be done and then there's 173 recycles
which are just best practices
recommendations and basic principles
that are easily interpreted and will
remain at the sole discretion of the
member states on how they pass any sort
of launching is within their countries
to align with the geography since we
don't yet have such an updated law this
means that we don't really know how this
will happen in Romania we sort of have a
big future but you'll see when we browse
the GPR that is a really big and fuzzy
picture there's no clear definition of
the bunch of things in there so
answering to we need specific questions
of how does this word tell you some like
we doesn't look like this piece of black
tea is hot period it's very possible
what's my fuzzy is that if you go
through the average you could get line
and the finds are as you can see down
there for any major breaches they can go
up in 20 million euros or up to four
percent of the global animal turn
or whichever is heist and my global
turnover means that if your company is
part of a group or in say multinational
company of any sort
they will take the global term where
I'll be tired company and not just a
country that got affected by the breach
for less important reaches is happen now
from our experience so far like I said
we've already started with this with our
customers and we've got a bunch of new
customers we partner up with a couple of
law firms so that the legal aspect
because we're not really legal people we
don't talk people these as well as those
people do so we partnered up with
companies to try and help our customers
align their processes procedures
technical investments and solutions that
we cover the process and technical side
I want to not all great experience has
shown us that if you are to actually do
something and be efficient about it you
need to have at least four entities in
the room what any gdpr discussion takes
place you need to have the legal side so
you know the company lawyer or lawyers
or their law firm that they work with
somebody who will be most likely present
you need the organizational and
procedural side so why do you want
covering governance in management and
also policies and operations and you
need the technical people in the room as
well it's not a technical thing it's not
a legal thing it's not a process thing
it's all of them putting together so you
know these people to talk to each other
but they very rarely to do and just work
thing up beyond that you also need to at
least involve in some
the process of people in HR marketing
finance customer service basically any
money in our company that deals with
customer data that deals with that they
are coming in or going out
and in fact dia is personal information
they need to know what they are exposing
the company to now I told you this is
not you think it's by a vital accounts
it's some somewhat of an improvement of
the existing items and this is specific
to the two mania for this case but it
also sort of applies to a lot of other
member states the current law dealing
with personal data is that there's a
seven seven four two thousand one that
already gives you some rights you're not
getting those rights right now you have
those rights before you might have not
thought about it
anyone here then read that long it's a
50-plus year old law dealing with how
companies and the government has been
tweaked your perspective ever it's
probably that if you haven't done it so
far but these go through the GDP army
because it covers those things as well
but it also introduces a bunch of new
violence and a bunch of you a rights
that you have for one the right to be
forgotten the right to go to and in
company or if we are to put it into
e-commerce and data controller
any sort of company that the galactic
forces mint processes but they now and
you can ask them hey if you've got that
data as pertains to meet my personal
data I want you to delete it from your
system and there are cases where this
might not be possible because there's an
honorable or requiring though
and store that information for a
specific period of time for instance
you've bought something from the store
somewhere and they had to give you an
invoice that employs to meet your name
from the earth security number and other
data the law when it comes to invoices
and Finance and whatnot says that you
have to store all the data for 10 years
you can't delete all the invoices from
your system in order to delete the data
so there's things that you might have to
do because of other existing laws that
will prevent you from leaving all that
data now if you have also collected the
color of my eyes moisture shots shoe
size when I purchase something from you
now that's some data that you might have
to delete because these models some data
that are worse to collect buy than
existing while you're collecting it
because you want to sell me more stuff
maybe so in those cases you have to be
able to comply as soon as possible as
soon as the request comes in to that the
right to restrict data processing you
will have to both notify or make it
easily available to all the people that
collect it out for or from or the bottom
what sort of data you're collecting and
a lot of purpose or purposes this means
that if you collect my information to
both able to send me the order that I
just placed on their website to my home
my children also black begin before you
because you want to say yeah the
newsletter or next month or you want to
process that data
on your site I need to know about all
the purposes that they've got against
reflected in process and I need people
to marketing or odd for any one of these
purposes so it's it gets a bit tricky
then there's the right D Network
building not only do I have the might
come to you and ask me what sort of data
do you have about me and I need to know
especially if you've got something on me
that I haven't given you personally and
you need to tell me where you got that
data from that's one - you have to give
me that data in a machine-readable
format you don't give me some speech
outside the PDF file and then a sub file
exported from three four or five
different systems I mean that they've
got to be a machine readable format
because I need to be able to take it
from you that they have control or to
another be nothing for say I want to
change my welcome subscription I want to
be able to take the day off of the
current supplier and give it to the new
one that I want to get into and tell
them hey this is not my day out this is
what they asked me so do whatever you
want with the data it's in machine
readable format it could be it like an
XML file or JSON or whatever how many
systems if they can do this right now
there's a bunch of other items here I
will give up the mandatory data breach
notification so you have to notify the
local authority within 72 hours from the
moment you have found out about it now
you could have been hacked a few months
ago that's under discussion or problem
that by betting paints on average
anywhere between six to nine months for
a big a breach to be discovered that's a
mr. maverick so that's how long a hacker
stays in your infrastructure
before you find out that they're there
now the moment you find out we have
something for hours to reporters and in
some cases you also have to notify the
people affected as well
there's also the DPO the data protection
officer we'll talk about that in a
moment
that's semi mandatory there are some
specific cases where you have to have an
appeal and all the other cases it's
recommended to have such a person with
data documents or inside your company or
that can find it on the market and pay
someone to access even a temporary EPO
to cover all the requirements that EPA
has to cover but there's the talk about
explicit and implicit consent covering
about a minute the introduction of
concepts or requirements on the a
minimization and student position what
this means is basically don't collect
more data than you actually need and the
data you collect make sure that it gets
stored and processed in different
systems you only transfer the data
that's needed in ab c randomized fashion
you can transfer an ID and all that they
how about that ID so you can't help who
that person is you have data about the
person you process it and bring it back
you don't have to take all the thing
that you have here and put it in that
system over there simply because you
need to use three of the seventy fields
that you've collected to process the
data in that other system so make sure
you only collect what you mean and
especially when it comes to transferring
data between systems or even within the
existing system make sure that it's as
hard as possible for people to get
access to that system back
who identified although they have
watched then there's the mandatory PPI
AIDS data protection the impact
assessments basically if our tomorrow it
was a nice thing to sort of do risk
analysis and pen testing and stuff like
that every now and then now it will
become mandatory when it comes to the
risk analysis and the risk impact
assessment for any sort of incidents
related to personal data breaches so
we'll have to do this and you'll have to
prove that you've done listen you have
to provide these reports to the local
authority to ask for by the DWG person
the privacy notices should be way more
robust transparent and understandable
and they must explain like I said the
sort of personal data that gets
processed the purpose intended retention
the the rights that the subject has the
source of that data especially do not
get got that data from the actual person
and you've got it from somewhere else
you get what a list of emails on the
internet as you want to spam people with
your amazing roof protection thingy
right and you get all these emails with
all sorts of services and products
because somebody just bought up was to
be most injured and there's some
addition to what personal data means and
they progress things like online
identifiers and deities and cookies and
the positive sensitive data which now
includes exclusively genetic and
biometric data as well the guys that you
will be for me out or digital marketing
will be the ones that are going to be
hit first
because GPR effects have you collected
enough customers having MMR
the constant validation is a sensitive
point here you need to be able to easily
apply that right to be forgotten when
somebody asks you to leave the day of
your system you need to be able to do
that and the explicit consent I'm
talking about on the next slide and also
if you do any sort of behavior tracking
you need to clearly state that so right
now you know there's a kooky one or
Englander website tells it that you've
got cookies you're gonna have make me
want work to do pop-ups telling you that
they're tracking you and they're
collecting some other data as well
they'll have to complete for a bunch of
those it's going to be interesting
somebody really thought this through but
at least you know and you're going to
click through it like you play from
anything so see now on the topic of
explicit consent and this is a section
from the GPR text it says that any fruit
Lee given specific informed and I might
be to us indication of the data subject
wishes and which your sheet and the
oldest statement is biased England or by
a clear affirmative action so that
consent needs to be a clear informative
action and sort of the pre-taped I agree
boxes no they won't work anymore you
have to take the IRB box yourself but be
clear
affirmative action or if you want to
apply this one existing list thank you
send all your customers an email and
tell the page now this thing PP PR
department to get your consent
please say yes and if you don't tell
justice you plan to say yes silence is
they need explicit consent appear action
to exist and you need to be able to
prove I need to be able to prove that it
might take that or sadness or sensual
development said yes work converting to
a phone call or something so that's
gonna guarantee however you can still
process data without that consent in
some cases if you have a contract with
the individual that says that you will
process that data if you need to comply
with a legal obligation some other law
saying that you need to collect that
data grid like up send out an invoice
vital interests and public tasks and
this is more of the talk for them for
the be noticeable because it really
depends and there's no clear answer
definition on what vital interests are
or how they apply to personal data and
where that line gets drawn or even like
public tasks that's also a bit fuzzy
however if you talk and this is also
something that you will have to improve
or discuss in case it's needed
what's all legitimate business interests
going back to my example you've got a
shop online they're selling stuff to
people if you want to send them the
product at home you need their attackers
you don't need it for other services
about in order to ship and you need the
name and address that they need to ship
it now you don't need the explicit
consent of them of the person saying
that yes I agree that I give you the
data to to from you to shift the the
stuff to me however I you need to be
able to tell that if I only use that
address to send to that shipment and I
don't send Christmas cards as well
that's okay if I want a psycho Christmas
part all happen explicitly state that
they will descend to a Christmas card
every month on that's a different
purpose you need to agree to that
also leave illegitimate business
interest means that at some point during
this process I might give this to the
courier company that will deliver the
package it's not me going to that's
going to deliver this is going to be a
third party so the data that you meet
will not get transferred to them for
them to bring you the packaging this
would also go into this legitimate
business interest and you will know you
will be told that by filling in this
form you're giving me the permission to
send this to a third party for the
marshal to be delivered just thinking
that definitely required them to
explicitly agreed
dpl's like I said having the dynamic
connection officer is mandatory if one
you are public authority so I need
coffee before tea will be required to
have a person who will act as an EPO if
you are performing much ill constant as
systematic monitoring activities
involving personal data so even if
you're not a public authority but you do
perform a sort of large-scale stop
button holes that day I also need to
have a mandatory habit or a part if
you're processing any sort of large
amounts of sensitive paper for instance
if you're a private hospital you're
processing sensitive data such as help
me out you need to have an EPO
it's the recommended happen
the local authority in Romania which is
a MSP DCP anyone heard of it
oh but that much about this they get up
and talk about dead Bassam
he got protection Bardo right nobody who
really heard about them on gdpr
shut up so it's it's there but don't
mean I was giving out the fines they'll
be the ones making sure that things are
going on okay and right now their point
understaffed so by the time you are
having to defect I think that's only
gonna get worse the rolls these are the
roles that the PPO has to cover is he
and the recommendation is to not have
someone in management doing this it was
very important because he's the one that
also is supposed to be monitoring that
things are being done so if you're both
accountable and responsible of the thing
you are not just gonna say yes it's done
because you're also accountable for that
being done and only responsible for
implementing it and quite as much out
there the DA needs to inform and advise
the
bunny the operator and the temple is on
what gtp areas he needs to mind her that
compliance and that the company does
something to become a client he needs to
be able to advise the operator regarding
those data protection impact assessments
and also to oversee their execution he
doesn't have to do that but he has to be
there make sure that they get done he
also needs to be the one that does the
notification in case of the averages
this is I think article 34 that says
that if the date of each involving could
be on that can put the person at risk
not only are you might notify the Data
Protection Authority you also need to
notify the people themselves so you need
to find ways to notify all the people
that get affected in case that happens
and of course that's the person
operating the DPA
now why should companies here here well
currently with a current law the maximum
fine is anywhere between fifteen hundred
to five hundred thousand later right
the GPR comes with much higher clients
and 40% giving to be breaking article 28
31 34 33 definitely impact assessments
you don't notify the supervising
authority above the breach or you don't
have the records for they can get fine
why do you do the reading backstop by
compiling that the basic principles
relating to be about security which they
help define in the regulation it just
said the best thing you need to abide
those basic principles but they don't
the basic principles are which makes it
funky then they can't be they can't find
you with even higher size now from our
experience of course in dealing with
companies out there
most companies either have heard or not
very little about champion even the ones
that think they know the emerging PR
they know it's something to do of data
processing and they deprive data what
not that's not enough because for one
there's no clear process in place
internally within those companies right
now to deal with data governance with
formal data ossification in order to be
able to protect personal data you need
to know where that personal thing is are
you collecting it what sort of things
like where it doesn't get sporting who
gives access to it for what purpose you
need to be able to do that and really if
I were that's the case because usually
you don't even have formal data
classification you don't need a
discovery or it's very hard for you to
know where all the data gets stored and
processed and transferred it just is
it's video right now it's got to be a
town that personal data any me and you
need to be able to tell the difference
anywhere inside your organization need
to be able to look at a stack of papers
this high right all the archive and you
need to be able to tell this is a piece
of paper that have personal layout and
this one is a piece of paper doesn't
and you need to be able to do that for
both printed or digital data regardless
of whether whether where it's ordered
there's a lack of proper the lack of
processes when it comes to
dehumanization and civilization shadow
by team who knows my shadow right he is
so shadow my team is all the stop the
people in the company use that's not
mandated by the company say you use
Dropbox to transfer a file from the
company file server to your personal
account so that you can work on it while
at home or in a hotel or at a customer
but the company doesn't have a company
Dropbox account that you use use their
personal one nobody binders that the IT
guys probably don't even know that this
is happening and this is happening a lot
especially when it comes to transferring
files who here has never used a
non-sanctioned file transfer solution if
the people drive Dropbox has forgotten
or whatever right it was not mandated by
the company so this stuff happens this
is how information gets out and it gets
out in the way that I think that doesn't
have any control over explicit consent
rarely obtained now it's going to be
mandatory
there's little or no laws of any sort of
personal data processing you will need
to know who has access that sort of
personal data when and what purpose if
you've got a CRM and you've got some
contact information for a company and
that person has his phone number and his
company email that's personal deal first
of all they got is any sort of data that
can
you identify indeed first so now we need
to be able to tell which one of your
sales guys has opened up the contact
details for that first and when and why
there is insufficient employee awareness
and a huge lack of skilled people
dealing with wide live EVP our needs and
what needs to be done and there's lack
of unity body designed by equal fighters
so let's just jump through a few of the
items in the GPR article for instance
deals with definition so if you go to
the Vepr and look at marble floor it
defines a bunch of stuff including why
the person data is while processing is
and what's a person to do application to
something's up personally I was
basically anything that would identify
you it doesn't have to be our main email
than others it could be anything it
could be it's a made-up age 25 to 35
living in that city and driving a blue
BMW and burning this amount of money per
year if that piece of information leads
to I have to find you that's personal
data so it gets straight when it comes
to personal data there's a layer on top
of that the size of India the stop that
can put you at risk where the operator
in schools will notify you now the GTR
doesn't contain any explicit list
personal data that would fall into this
category but the Supervisory authorities
have already published some guides all
over word including our guys they
publish the guy that's a few pages long
back in September saying some stop on
our DVR
and what the PPO requirements are but
that's about it that's about all they
really did if you look at some of those
best practices there's a bunch of you
know that is clearly identified as
having increased sensitive like
biometric genetic data financial
economic situation usernames passwords
or data that the bbc's were identity
from fraud or special liam what
specialty huh it's the part of the
person gave us certain prohibited for
you to collect store and analyze unless
you have a very narrowly describing
scheme or a very specific reason for
doing some and this is a list of such
enum identified talks about the
principles related to processing
personal data and one of the points
years of one app says that mercifully
national be processed in a manner that
it shows appropriate security of the
personal data now GPR does not come to
define what appropriate security means
so the first count again and giving even
files they will tell you what
appropriate really means what they think
appropriate security and whatever you do
it might never be enough or appropriate
because obviously it wasn't appropriate
if you've got fourteen average was not
enough so it's available but it says you
need to protect against accidental loss
destruction or damage how I got asked
couple much bill well it's the hunger
comes in and deletes the data of the
personal data why do I even care
deleted the data it doesn't get breach
or be opting for anything right problem
solved deleted the data example well yes
FL
think of cases were deleting the data
might put that person eating there think
of any medical institution that has
information' about their patients
somebody hacks it deletes all that data
one of the patients comes in the next
day he needs to get his treatment
there's no history so the doctor might
give him a prescription that puts you in
danger because there's no history
because it was bleeding so even the
deletion could be could be dangerous are
limiting the rights of access of the
data subject so as they are subject you
need to be able to ask the controller
the data processor the data controller
all this information that they will have
to tell me the purpose of the processing
that integrity so they are concerned the
recipients where players over cvn to
whom the personal data has to be or will
be disclosed by price to that store
giving you giving your data to the
courier company and where possible the
period for which the personal data will
be stored or if that's not possible the
cranky I used to determine that period
so any company in some cases they want
to tell them to B's for in for three
months but they will have to tell these
for a bobtail acts happens and they will
have to give you that break you this is
this goes on ye they business of the
right to request the controller a
rectification already ready you can ask
for the data to be corrected or erased
the right to lodge a complaint with the
forestry authority where the personal
data collected property
I think you need to tell them any
available information as to their source
and if you all need to know about the
existence of an automated signal making
including profiling and at least
meaningful information about the logic
involved and should be able to object to
that and he sort of automated processing
that will have the system take a
decision that regard that affects you
and this we automated you can object to
that if you think that maybe it's Bobby
maybe the programmer that wrote the code
of the logic behind it put a zero or
didn't put a zero software and the whole
logic went they were article 25 defines
data protection by design by people and
this basically states that the
controller to the company doing the
difference between the controller and
the processor the controller is the
entity that besides what sort of data
gets collected the processor is just an
entity that stores the behind process of
data on behalf of the controller even
think of this in the terms of cloud
providers like Amazon and Microsoft
below would be data processors they're
just selling you compute power they
don't have any sort of influence over
what data you could in those portions of
the evidences but the data will still
reside there so they are the data
processors they have some
responsibilities protected that they
have powerful rizal's human they have
controller now hasn't had before you
need to implement you know protection
principles such as but they don't need a
list of the data protection principles
if you don't do it however that's gonna
be problem by default only personal data
for a specific purpose to be processed
and you also need to demonstrate
compliance with the three distant points
article 32 account when it comes to
security processing the mentor and
processor shall implement appropriate
technical and organizational matters
what does that mean
we don't know so this is to the people
that think that their company is going
to be compliant well let me know what
you're getting there because I surely
don't don't really know exactly what's
gonna be acquired I know some of the
best practices are recommendations and
you can start with those but you can
tell if you're going to be a hundred
percent compliant you can see that soon
advising encryption the CIO right now
that you have integrity availability
regular regularly test be assessing and
evaluating that so you need to be able
to do that's mandatory so actually it
asked companies to do basic security
mandatory if you need to be able to
prove that you comply to that because in
case of a data breach that's going to be
alpha that you can use to prove that hey
I'm at least on my vest I've done this
about that and maybe just maybe you can
get away with just a smile
the rest are not twenty million euros a
pint article 33 when it comes to
notification this is the notification to
the data protection covering this should
be done no later than 72 hours
article 24 I have included that back
filled with the sensitive data or they
are
with people at risk but you also need to
know by the people as well so no later
than 72 hours without God you delayed as
soon as you become available and
hopefully do you have to just doubt that
they are learning oh my god we've got
that document the DWP to include the Box
waiting - that is defects and then you
remedial action taken or they are
currently taking
you're not going to discover the process
with it no 72 hours you can have that
process in place beforehand now if you
look at the main actors like I said it
only happens ans BDCP you'll get the
spikes this one goes to their website
that's data protection about our own
this interconnection Authority is the
one that keeps in touch basically
whether being a processor that they are
controllers the BPOs within each company
and also all the citizens that I have
therapy as the one compromised or worse
now when it comes to the changes - some
things are on the changes site for what
individuals have the right to access
their personal they have to correct any
narrative erase that where it doesn't
interfere or go against any other
existing laws - objective processing of
personal data so you need to be able to
tell the exact reasons why you're
processing that they have to object on
and export that data organisations also
will need to protect by using
appropriate security and this is where
the DPR leads us to notify authorities
open data breaches to obtain the consent
and to keep detailed records when it
comes to being a processing they also
need to provide a clear notice
the election to outline the purposes in
these cases when that BIA when the data
is provided and to clearly define the
retention region policies and also when
it comes like and training they need to
train their have their people they need
to audit and update thanks Orton
policies they have it's recommended to
employ that BPO and to make sure that
any sort of vendor or supplier contracts
are updated to include or to cover for
this when it comes to the journey
getting started basically needs you to
go through four very simple steps you
first need to discover where and how
that personal be on what's what personal
need on your collab and where you have
then you need to take them forward and
to be able to easily modify it than
needed and things like that so that's
the manic side you need to be able to
then protect it to be able to push in
the security measures and controls to
prevent detect and report they sort of
all abilities that become breaches and
then reporting side to keep any sort of
documentation that will be required
because it does 72 hours you won't have
enough time to do all of that and I will
tie the flood like ever set up a bullet
points for each of these four things
when you stop learning sort of the other
thumbs job that's by person and this
gets caught in all sorts of places so
it's all you need to be able to find it
anywhere he giveth management policies
all these possibilities whatever let me
up is addressed in process in transit
processes being archived where's where's
the bad company to protect the backup
that includes all the day as well you
need to be able to organize and label so
they have classification appropriate
security right sort of physical
protection Identity Management
encryption all the things that people
have been talking about for years when
it comes to security actually have to
stop doing that and you have to start
monitoring and detecting intrusions need
to be able to tell as soon as possible
that you've been breached
and you need to be able to report that
include all the data that's required and
in summary a quick checklist for one
you've only got six months it's not
enough in we need to start yesterday is
still enough right
but even so you can think of gdpr as an
opportunity and not a threat if you do
this right you will have an edge on the
market and these sort of services you
provide your customers are going to be
gdpr compliant you don't be able to ask
for more money from our customers or
you'll be able to just sleep well at
night
if you've done this it's an easy
decision if you they're doing or you
know you do it and it's got to be a long
road or you don't and you just a month
risk you can offer that as a valid
business pursuit
it might be a business decision but
least your business going out of
business independence of
this decision you need to get an
inventory of the current government's
frameworks and practices and here my
recommendation is to look into coded
five as sort of like a 90 governance
framework and to point the DPO also have
that resistant down launch of
unawareness program internally you need
to have those incident response plans
that shouldn't be just oh my god we've
been hacked what can we do that's not a
valid incident response plan you need to
focus on the information don't forget
this is all about a personal deal and
that's it
and if you need to do that continuously
to continuously assess and see where you
are and where