so as markets first of all my uncle's
gypsy researcher at its young I spent
most my time recognized didn't find
nutritive our modern markets researching
new malware and imaginary parts of mind
which is a bit of a handful so fast but
fitness so moving forward intuition
about women's a bit of an analysis about
the works of the teaching works and then
we're going to see how we can actually
go about attracting the CCS and some
stats from research so first of all what
is mirai giving a cuz there's a number
of people here are pretty funny so
that's a little security was attacked by
mistress Rizzo did us six gigabytes
which was after the steel-stringed
obscene what was before that what was
really interesting from the top is that
they said it wasn't the usual
DDoS 10 standard DNS amplification were
still burning or dissident hat
let Sheila get requests for the British
University which given the condition
that the muddling with fluid standard a
standard EMS work he said they said it
was most likely that in dealing with a
very very large lot of devices so after
the cooldown probate a week and a half
later the source food was about to did
not did you didn't jump from a sickness
Davis well this was actually a group
this research because we normally we
have optical mystery to start analyzing
to this look a little but was also bad
because didn't actually have chance to
actually have people start to do this
system we've seen an increase in the
number of attacks against severity
devices so a specific comparative about
self-destructed that resides in Europe
it affected the vice president has
supported our pictures it's myths art
six this one there's a murder which
basically harvest a successful market
once Department was the past that's
really start scanning for new portable
devices when fast device takes that
the other said the traditional
combination usually and password and
sends it back once that happens it
clicks to the device does the best are
supported so that's way that we receive
a huge network of devices that are doing
not stop enforcing the default
credentials of editing the rest the
website posting the power dissipated
when they infect a new device they login
this be justified me David run and
lastly one of the most it reads the city
city server what's this in fact it was
outstanding
it automatically connected to the server
and Wipro commands what commands DDoS
but with us
the since she also has an operating
manual which is just basically a
repetition of infidelity devices which
Turnitin boot was your position DVR RL c
CB devices once the managed planet if
the credentials to login at that machine
internal the report results what happens
the loader collapsing on the machine
fingerprints this to know what
the system works ass with it know what
exactly what planet to download little
button from the website and then they
just miss between the and what's that
happens the seriously about the operator
of the sensitive business a that's in
point start the video see some targets
all the machines informations are out
there there's an interesting features
from this when you run it it actually
can only run it if you use that a
specific file into the battery isn't
called DPR run it with dot slash
variable it will automatically stop it
with disabilities about this first and
it just stops if you use that particular
part of the video directly it works to
just a process they say to do PS travel
to that process work if you are a burden
on us anything it is interested you can
see hundred percent the sockets a
biscuit opening up a server and you'll
see those cannot find the processes
running for instance its server which
recommends in the same time it continues
start standing rib roast effect and that
was that
naka so the but has an obstacle in Swiss
be absurd initiative travel stream Zion
worship they were seen much information
I use the extra key which was generally
used as 0x10 beef blood should be able
to extract the permission about the CC
the reporting server reports used in
everything like that
even the default the user agencies for
they should be requests so as I said the
neck surgery is actually only one bite
it's reserved explain to that was in
some time that you start seeing some
changes with being won by experts but
it's pretty to write a script that would
open up it try to find the key you can
just no person-specific strings that you
know that we needed for example if you
look for is ragin see if you can't do
this but the script stated we finally
put on the user agents or somewhere no
information in there just you know we
found in the tea and the other state
binary as I mentioned the pot has ten
capabilities in order to discover a lot
other devices that can infect and use
four different words it basically when
starts the Stanford for new tablets were
23 23 23
once it finds machine that has no status
port open it will automatically try
mister before using password
combinations to love
that's was actually such as not there
were like 16 conditions and later on
after order of monastic they actually
updated through Singapore that their
capability with the newer new is rated
the users and passwords what they did
basically is something that most of us
do without actually but she thinking
about it when you get resentful was when
it usually did the same the route or a
DVR or something you try to set it up
first thing you do is search google
default username password with this
device so what they did was this big
compressor Fitness stuff this root user
passwords put in the hydrated tries
those those combinations
another interesting let's see
item in the the products up is that when
he start scanning it says the TCP
sequence number equalling the
destination IP address so if you if
you'd like to example to set a monitor
on your device exceed if you're dealing
here you see there's a tense on me I
understand you were good for you the
quickest way is to just respect those
specific numbers if it's equal to your
public IP address it's a pretty clear
sign interestingly enough this was also
used later on in India achieving burden
a lot of important was published armed
every birth initially the worse there's
there's a big hype then kind of quiet
down but there's a lot of similarities
between the energy we put and the bride
for example in if indeed if you look at
the curve of the body you can actually
see photographers there was a liberal
youtube link to a liberal property you
say Packers in the beginning - it was in
ripple in the river as well the
differences was that the real
performance will start standing trying
to infect the devices did didn't see
before potentials have to start using
some known vulnerabilities in DVRs and
that's gorgeous in water-related
abilities and uses those long after the
other words when it first started at
hazard supported open it starts using
qualities its particulate manages
together
foothold it also when partner start
standing and it actually supported first
it does something a print for the
business is about system which is
looking for if the target is actually
vulnerable device or not if you are
losing doing this in an iPod or students
machine these commands was up in this
box another word but if you respond with
for example arrived at the background
it's necessary okay passing this check
moving on moving back to the loader
basically what happens is it reads from
the standard a pollutant and connects
data to the RT devices and after that
once it has the photo uses classic TT
dollar 50 P sometimes artistic
represented use
glued to the down the battery to the is
about discovery and another interesting
feature is that uses it runs cat our bin
slash Perl to discover the architectural
system so it might actually pass when
this
fingerprinting techniques but if you
don't have the correct occurred binding
on your machine you might not know work
and this is information that she goes to
the website listing the binaries and
dance the one that fits that particular
architecture and of course as mentioned
the changes that the link to the DVR
have been executed this is a replay of a
lot of artists in the binary everything
other steps from fingerprinting all the
way to double death is becoming the
boundaries renaming changing permissions
and then HP this visit develop but this
does not run this way with automatic
fail so in terms of little computing
what it does not communicate with the
sincere misfit since it's pretty easy to
accidentally since you just have to send
initial sequence and then it's all
hardened Smith which is 0 X 0 0 0 0 0
you'd have to do this every 60 seconds
and is a sophisticated the body if you
listen to whatever is going on there the
alert message format learnt the original
DDoS
it's a chiral center of a super mode
sample steer the options we have some
examples for from work a lot targets
duration at PI PD P what else educated
people in HTTP what the main target is
so on they have actually but in the path
types what was interesting is that this
particular on that list that was for my
personal it's called false religion
greater this is basically the company
that developed Lucy or contrast right so
this this one actually interesting
recently provisions of me they're
actually trying to include you notice
gaming servers and small a lot actually
we've seen that the track example to hit
the we called an authority nuclear
fallout game services on some other the
recipe hosting server side and other
things other than that you did before in
DNS simpler interruptions which stage
during routing encapsulation HTTP which
can use and to basically even either get
best for most requests with data so
second arrive which was per se the
biggest biggest name in this field last
year in this year
welders there are other threads as well
some of the ones that we be seeing was
this did
- tsunami are sicker than healthy weaker
somebody most of them pretty much work
the same way they were first potentials
didn't tear down enemies and the server
and infect other machines in the process
the differences doesn't have difference
in see for was it communication purpose
instead of me right has this specific
for logistical tell others use some sit
down
IRC servers others just tell it you can
just connect daily once you did was do
the tenant of the server talk about this
is since the command to start Stan looks
at what religious experts so for example
this is a script but only used by the
acted publicly be down boundaries in
London this is an interesting thing
person aside difference being is that
Iran tries to pick up with the system
and in the fight which finally to
download and execute in other cases they
simply just spray and pray to download
every finally forget architecture and
run which rather one runs as fine one of
the nice interested in that also found
in our TV press was in erisa third the
city rural when you run it if you try to
run to buy name is mark the other
they'll actually actually students
killed the initial process so there's
only one instance of the running
to run multiple places in a single VM
for example it's not about any one of
them is going to be alive at a time so
we did to the point that let's see we
want to start checking the CNC once what
they're doing what attacks that worth
the attack and so on so what we did was
extracted or else we know from behind
pellets downloaded the binaries and then
started into them there are two options
here we can either running in the
sandbox or you can write the chapter for
this and with others the thing is with
the substitution is you need to be very
careful about firewall immunity and
because if you don't do that you end up
having a VM which is basically brute
forcing other devices across the
internet and you don't want to do that
the advantage here is barri changes its
behavior to actually you know I actually
worry about - Darius they were supposed
to do it with Bosnia updates
it will continue working however we
found the comedian's management using
samples for this purpose and that is
killing a performance being able to run
only one battery at a time is little
drop every stream the number to see
exploit attempts and the number of items
that we receive so he chose to join
Authority the spirit tracker which
respectively the magician purple the
variety and item
about you just start plating to each of
these servers as you find them and see
and you can actually the same confirm
them by the commands division first
if the same for example to stand on that
we know you're dealing with yeah it was
ample because that's the matter start
telling tourists and the bench here is
that you know women in resources for
this can basically have a script so
piece of software that connects to the
servers and just have to interpret the
protocol and it was good to love them
simultaneously working just deployed on
multiple machines across the internet
blacklisted and this was the behavior of
the system changes the protocol changes
you always have to go back and update
your curves we don't stay behind because
otherwise we'll just be taken out so
here we have some info some sort of most
interesting stuff that we've seen what
monitoring of these indices so if you
see this busy here twist we started is
ordering the bath two stars Chandler
Bing Bingbing to put keep alive citizen
VDP flooding and then we see people chat
you see that disgusted they could work
they have to sleep slightly wrong so on
ESMA bystander and
interesting stuff also
you cannot receive this chance that
these people were posting their vote
counts so when you see this there's
havoc like 10,000 or CC that had 10,000
Watts was the worst travel mm mm boss
also operator scheming try to steal
other operators was this big around a
trend there speaking of senator what
their apartment to somebody else and
then other interesting stuff that we've
seen actually a lot of people some of it
some of the cities actually had Twitter
accounts of tied to them you head to the
CC it could actually see from posting
their to accounts or Instagram accounts
so this is this is a permission I think
it's very good because it's a process
that these people honestly very
professional they're not real careful
with the data
what they're doing their job somebody
might actually listening to them and
from the research that we've done
afterwards we found start a sentence
with this video account most of them
were just the teenagers that used these
parts in order to see
giving servers because they got this is
in the scope in culture simple works
that's collected four thousand unique
wineries over a six-month period of time
we've identified them confirmed over 20
C and C's and we've seen just over
700,000 attacks against assigned us some
statistics about the past themselves the
most of the attacks are coming to the
United States which is but see that
Venus Christ through the device today
then the Netherlands Russia always
present France and China a policy the
topic and as for targets again leading
by three big distance in the United
States Germany Russia as well while
looking into these people interaction
point them base been this guy has
arrived the box keeps to actually in two
kernels how to install and run these
buttons on the right item two variants
of these and so on even have people to
defy the polos easily and also clear
this is actually shot there from one of
their posts can't simply worship adapt
to the operation have had
for the ride and during some other Chad
they have my Twitter they were somebody
was that me upset that they super
happening and taking down some point so
that's that's it for me for this dietary
is help this project really smart guy
and it was a lot of interesting stuff
out there Oh John