hi everyone i am
oxford
and today i'm here to talk about the
problem of computers and randomness
um so a little bit about myself
a little bit about myself
i am a software developer and a security
enthusiast
um
i am currently pursuing my b tech in csc
from bennett university
i like to make and contribute to open
source software in my free time and i am
not really an expert on this topic of
randomness it's something that requires
phds and phds but i just happened to
walk into a couple of nerds speaking
about randomness and that's how that's
how this park started and that's how i
started researching on it and that's
that's me thanks atomic for putting that
as the official picture
um anyways
so here is the problem statement
computers are deterministic machines
okay
so
if you
want your computer to add one with one
it will give you two right
it's efficient at doing exactly what you
asked it to do but at the same time it
it's not smart enough to come up with
things on its own but then how the heck
are we able to generate otps randomly on
when we require it or cryptographic keys
when we require it so such such this is
what i want to address in this talk
about how we move forward
um
for reference uh the spoiler spoiler
heard a little bit about about a lot of
things that are going to come i want you
to think of
of the of coming up with randomness with
respect to a function
um a mathematical function itself
so let me lay down some ground rules
first of all we're going to use python
for reference because it's easy to read
and everyone in the security community
must have used python that one place or
the other
ground rule that i want to lay down is
that when i say random here i don't
really mean random random it's actually
pseudo-randomness because whenever it
comes to computers you cannot actually
come up with pure randomness right
um
[Music]
well if you think about it nothing is
truly random but let's not go there
um so
the talk is more about pseudo randomness
rather than randomness
um yeah so let's begin finding a
solution to the problem that i laid down
um
i would have wanted you guys to pull out
your terminals if you guys were in front
of me
but really think about it how would you
come up with one function
which would output a
random number every time you run it it's
a it's a great question that would spark
your curiosity in this topic
um
to the panel uh
do you guys have any guesses
make make light guesses okay
i mean if i was going to put something
random oh
we all know the correct way of doing it
let's let's try to find a way that's a
little bit more creative
um
i don't know um
the
power drainage from a cpu
like
a cpu is going to do a various number of
operations per
second
that's a good idea that's a good idea
good
number of threads or power drainage or
uh things like that
that could be interesting
um
what else
the problem is that it's uh it's not a
compound value right so you're going to
get something in a range that is
somewhat predictable depending on
i don't know um even you have any ideas
okay
so sorry
it's fine it's fine
um we're talking about something random
that
i don't know yeah i have to remember to
unmute my mic sometimes so i'm sorry if
there's a delay in what i'm speaking but
something random
um
no i've got nothing
i was actually just about to to whip out
um my code editor and see if i can
generate something without using a
pre-written function
so i'll get back to you in chat when i
when i finish up
okay we we've had one person suggest
something
uh so observing a physical phenom
phenomenon
so for example using a camera that would
detect if something is happening or not
that could be an idea
that's a good idea i totally forgot how
smart the invisible community was
[Laughter]
these are really good ideas i never
thought of them
anyways
these are really good suggestions um
somewhat true uh i wait
well
we'll get there we'll get get to how
it's done as atomic said
the correct way
um but
let's start from the start okay i want
to uh since i was talking about the
since i was talking about how python how
it happens in some python libraries
let's start from the start so i want to
use the reference of the random module
you guys must have used the random
module somewhere right
it doesn't really give you again it's
that the name is a bit misleading there
is it's it doesn't generate something
random it generates something
pseudo-random
so um here is how the random module does
okay so the random module uses the
current unix timestamp
as the seed to generate the output the
random numbers right so um it's actually
when i found out about it initially i
thought it was pretty smart but at the
same time i i wasn't satisfied by it
because come on it sounds a bit weak
somewhere right
so um
[Music]
fair enough so it uses the unix
timestamp to seed the random generator
and then it accordingly produces the
random numbers
um
so i want to talk more about how it does
work right like give you some brief
some a brief abstract of how things work
in in in the random module so it uses a
an implementation of an algorithm called
the mercen questo so the mercy investor
is supposed to generate random numbers
it's a prng which sounds for which
stands for a pseudo random number
generator
and it it it is able to generate a
sequence of random numbers
uh when a seed is given to it from the
seed itself and the seed of course in
this case is the by default if you don't
see it you you have an option to seat it
but if you don't then by default it uses
that unix timestamp and uh
that seed from that seed it generates a
sequence of random numbers
these random numbers um the catch here
is
that uh even though the algorithm is
pretty pretty tough
uh
the thing is that these random numbers
would eventually start to repeat itself
after a point
that you generate from the seed okay
and for one given seed uh the random
number the sequence of random numbers
generated are the same
so if you gave this information to
someone who is really into cryptographic
they'll probably have a heart attack and
because of that uh
because of that you must have heard
people say that okay don't use the
random module for for things which are
cryptographically sensitive right you
must have heard them ask you to
specifically use the secrets module now
the secrets module is another library
provided by python uh you can check
check out its code base from c python's
official github repository
um
which
is able to uh
which is able to generate the random
numbers according to itself
which is able to generate
cryptographically secure random numbers
so uh pseudorandom numbers so it's a csp
rng
but then the question arises what is so
different about the secrets module right
i mean it was already pretty smart for
the random audio
to
to come up with random numbers on its
own
but then how does the secrets module
come up with with these random numbers
now again i didn't give you time because
i think i've put the answer somewhere in
the slide itself okay i haven't that's
nice
um
so the secrets module
uh it uses i won't go into the depth of
how it happens uh but i scrolled through
the the code base
all i would say that it actually uses a
class from the random module itself
which is called the system random module
the system random clash
uh this the secret module uses this
class and this class is responsible for
fetching the entropy from your opera
from your operating system
now
how your operating system comes up with
these with with the with the entropy is
something that depends on the um
operating system we're talking about if
we're talking about unix systems then
it's of course slash dev slash random if
we're talking about uh windows then it's
it's it's probably some win32 api right
um
for for the purposes of finishing up
this talk i want to look into this uh i
want to look into slash dev slash random
um
because i'm more comfortable with unix
systems and i as far as as far as i've
understood when the windows also does
the same thing more or less
so it fetches the entropy
from slash dev slash run
fair enough
uh
but how does slash dev slash you random
a file in in your linux system well it's
not a file it's a device but
continuing uh a file in your linux
system come up with a random numbers
sorry random bytes
you get it right how does it come up
with this entropy
um
again the answer is in front of you
because i'm putting in this slide
but uh
it's still interesting to think about it
right
um
since the answer is already in front of
you i'll i'll i'll brief up more on that
it uses entropy that is generated by a
system and this system and then and this
entropy is
generated by the in so basically every
time you move your mouse
every time you use your keyboard every
time a drive is red uh all these
functions they take different amount of
time right i think someone in the chat
also said that we can use some physical
hardware
but more or less
it happens here more or less it's it's
not as smart as you were talking about
but more restless there is something
like that which happens here and uh
um all this uh because of the of the
random entropy uh because of of of the
factors involved here we are able to uh
use this information to as a seed and
then we are able to uh to to generate an
entropy pool
which is then
further used for for the secrets module
right
so that's
pretty much all i wanted to talk about
here
but still before i end this talk i know
this was short but before i end this
talk i all i want to i all i want to
leave you with
is the fact that
to mimic the most basic of things
something like coming up with random
numbers
which which you can do on your own at
the top of your head
uh to mimic the most basic of things we
had to come up with algorithms
smart algorithms and we had to
understand we had to come up with
creative ways to to get to get entropy
to get to to get to get to get the seats
for our for our csp rngs for our prngs
um
just to make the most basic of things
which is which is coming up with
something random on your own
so it's it's almost beautiful how how it
all comes together and how we try to
do these things
that's that's mostly it i think my talk
i i did
i think i've covered most of it if if
you guys have any questions and answers
i'm open to them
um but again as i said i'm no i'm no
expert
i am just someone who loved who was very
curious about this topic and thought you
know what i'm going to give my first
talk and it's going to be avoid this one
topic that i loved starting up on
so go ahead ask me questions
no we have no problem
we've had a few suggestions uh in the
meantime uh one which is a bit recursive
but uh we'll get to that um
right observing a physical phenomenon
such as a coin flip so using a robot to
flip a coin and then observing uh the
the coin flip
okay but you cannot do that with me
dude that that's a good suggestion
but uh usually
your computers and your mobile phones
don't come with coin flippers
[Laughter]
it's all about getting creative
theoretically if i were to build one
would that uh would that work
i don't know i think you've just
inspired my next project
um okay
we've uh
right are
our coin flips truly random uh i don't
know um someone suggested a kind of
recursive approach uh using a random
sample of a random number
which is like hmm
okay
it's like the chicken and the egg
but you what the random number has to
exist first right
true um
and i had an actual question uh
less than a suggestion but you mentioned
devue random
and would a less powerful computer let's
say a raspberry pi
or something on a very small device such
as
an esp32 which runs a very uh
lightweight version of linux such as
what we can see in the iot world
uh have a slower generation of entropy
uh than let's say and
i don't know an ibm z
uh
uh mainframe
like is there a difference in speed
dude there must be but legit i don't
know
that's fine
that's yeah that's
that's that's the question that's like
hmm could you could you if you knew the
device
be able to then generate a slice of
random uh like of you know the entropy
values and then attack based on that
that seems that seems kind of impossible
i don't know man uh it's a good question
that i might have to look into myself as
i said i it's just something that i've
started up on my own for the for the for
the sake of
for the sake of fulfilling my curiosity
but that's a good question i don't think
it should be possible but
since something like a
raspberry pi
doesn't have these other physical
[Music]
well i think i think i think it should
be
well it's something that i have to study
up on my own and i think it should i i
think it should be safe enough
yeah
i mean it's uh
to have the idea of actually going ahead
and like enumerating debut random to
then do very like micro second specific
attacks sounds a little bit overkill
in the voice revolution
random
interesting topic
indeed
yeah and thank you so much for
presenting it for us honestly i think
that's gotten a lot of people thinking a
lot of brains going inspired to new
projects
um
is there anything else you'd like to add
elliott or nicos
um
not really
nothing else you guys can follow me on
my socials it's everywhere any you can
find me anywhere with with my username
being 0x00 elliot
other than that i would like to thank my
friends who are just sitting right there
in front of me
wait
[Music]
that's amazing
thank you so much for coming on and
thank you for your time it was so much
appreciated