thank you nichols
so uh hi everyone i hope you all are
doing good
uh today i'll be talking about api pen
testing and a few vulnerabilities
related to it so let's just jump into it
okay
a quick introduction about myself my
name is abhinav khanna and i'm currently
working as an application security
engineer at not so secure
before we get started with the
vulnerabilities just a quick disclaimer
that i do not endorse the tools and
platforms listed in the slides
and uh these are not the only ones
available in the market there are tons
more
okay
so again before jumping on to the
vulnerabilities let's discuss
a little little bit of of what commonly
apis i used to do
the first would be rest apis rest apis
are based on rest architecture
and they work with json and xml booth
now when it comes to soap apis they are
relatively older than rest apis and they
only work with xml format
the third one which is graph quality
apis they are a bit more flexible than
rest and show
as we can access a lot of resources in
just one single request
all right
so
let's go to os popped in
we need to take care that oh my stop 10
is considered an important part when we
are working on the apis because today
apis are a very critical part of the
business
for today's talk we'll be discussing
about four vulnerabilities one is mass
assignment the other is improper asset
management the third would be excessive
data exposure and the fourth would be
lack of resources and trade limit
sorry
so whenever you start with any of your
ap projects or api assessments there are
a few things that you need to take care
about the first would be that
go through the documentation before you
actually get started
when you're going through the
documentation you might be able to
understand what is the business logic
behind the apis and you might be able to
find business logic laws related
the second would be always ask for ebay
collection which includes the positive
response
by positive response i mean that
when there's no manipulation
being done in the request what would be
the right response
and the third would be that do not stick
to automated rules for vulnerability
identification see when it comes to apis
i i've always found out that the manual
approach is the best one because we'd be
able to find a lot of a lot of logic
flaws uh if we go using the manual
all right so we'll be discussing the
first vulnerability
that is called as mass assignment so
mass assignment occurs when a user or an
attacker can manipulate the objects
which should ideally be not accessible
to them in the first place
when we when we talk about mass
assignment the concept of object binding
comes into the place
i've written a one liner here as well
let's lie and check if we can get caught
so we try to understand this
vulnerability
using a non-technical story before we
actually jump onto the demo so let's see
what the story is
consider this a catholic
and a person walks in and says that hey
are you guys serving pizza
and the waiter comes and says yeah we do
solve the pizza for ten dollars
now the person in return says that okay
hey i'm the only friend
and the waiter without actually
identifying that okay if he's the owner
friend or not would straight away give
him the discount i would say that okay
we serve the pizza for two dollars to
you so that is something similar to mass
assignment where we're actually not who
we are but we can still uh
access the resources
that do not belong to us for example
if we are not the admin but we inject
the parameter that okay is admin equal
to true and if the application accepts
it we might be able to access all the
admin related functionalities
all right so let's try to understand
this using actual demo
so for demo
we have used the contrast free exercise
so what we'll do
we'll go to the forget password page
here
we'll enter our own email address
and we'll wait for the password reset
link to be sent to us
okay we have the link
now let's try to open the link
i will try to enter the new password and
then analyze the request
now this something called as it is admin
faults
so what we'll try to do here is we'll
try to change this to true and save the
application accepted
all right the application accepted is
now we'll just try to log in with the
new credentials and see if we are able
to access the admin functionality
you are able to login access everything
that admin can access so this is what
mass assignment can do give you a lot
more functionalities than you actually
need need to take care of
all right so let's move to the next
vulnerability which is called as
improper asset management
and according to overall apis tend to
expose more endpoints than the
traditional web applications and that is
why documentation becomes very important
see
if the documentation is properly
implemented we might be able to uh
mitigate the risks related to the
retired or depreciated versions of the
aps
again i've created a one line of that
okay you made a very secure new new
version but did you forget to disable
the previous one so what happens is for
example uh you have a v2 version of your
api which which has everything
stored in an encrypted format which is a
good security practice
but at the same time
v1 the version one of the api is still
accessible to everyone
and all the data there is there in plain
text it might be your password your ssl
number or anything so even though you
have good practices implemented on v2 v1
is vulnerable
so again let's try to discuss this let's
try to understand this with a
non-technical story
and and see how this can be exploited
okay so consider this an office
and this is an ex-employee that works
here
and tries to enter the office with this
old id card see if the employee has left
the organization his id card should
ideally be expired it should not be
valid
but what the person here tries is he'll
try to log in
he'll
try to enter the office with his old id
card ideally he should not be able to
enter but what happens is
he'll be able to enter the office
why
because the assets were not managed
properly his id card was still active
and in an ideal world that should not
happen
now let's try to understand this on a
while variable
we'd be again using the contrast
vulnerable free exercise for this
so what we'll do we'll go to the one
variable app
we'll go to this project password
and here we'll inject the victim's email
id
okay now we don't know what is the
verification token we'll just enter
anything randomly and we'll try to
analyze the request and response
we are using the version 3 of api
to analyze the request
all right so the token was not valid but
we got to know that there is a rate
limit implemented there and after four
attempts we will not be able to check
for the token again
so
let's try to enter in the random token
again
so now what we'll do is we'll change
this
v3 to v2 or v1 and see what happens
okay we are again under authorized but
we got to know that there is no rate
limiting or no group brute force
prediction available here
so it basically means
we'll be able to uh will be able to
brute force the token and log it into
the account of the victim
we run a python script here
okay we found out the correct token
let's enter this token
all right so now we are able to log into
the victims account see
this is what asset management can do
even though you have rate limiting uh
implemented on version 3 there's
absolutely nothing uh preventing through
force attacks on v1 and using that we
were able to log in
alright so let's talk about the third
vulnerability
which is called as excessive data
and it normally occurs when more than
required data gets shown to the end user
accidentally
it's just like
you're exposing your secrets to every
person you need
so ideally you know you will not go
around and tell your secrets to everyone
right
just that just like that
you you should
take care that
the data that is shown to the user is
dependent upon their role
let's try to understand this with an
example
consider this request
uh consider this request of a dating app
usually on the front end a few things
are available one would be the name the
second would be the age and third would
probably be
the city
but if someone captures the request say
this is a request and they try to
analyze the response
so in the response we can see that this
name this age
there's the exact address
there's the mobile number and there's
the email address
according to the business of the dating
app this becomes the very critical data
and if you are able to enumerate the id
it becomes an even bigger threat
so that is how excessive data exposure
becomes a huge risk when it comes to
apis
let's try to understand this with a demo
we have again used the free exercise of
contra here
let's go to the forget password page
now we will enter an email id and we'll
try to analyze the request
all right
so we got to know that the password
reset link is available in the response
itself
using this link will we we can change
anyone's password and login into that
account
so straight account takeover is possible
so now what we do we enter the victim's
email id
and we we got the password reset token
here
we'll open it and see
if the password reset page gets opened
cool so the page get got open
we would be able to change the password
and novel into the difference account
so it's
it potentially led to accounting
excessive data exposure
you should take care that your pan
number your ssn or the reset password
links names emails depends upon the
business these things should not be
there in the response itself
all right
so now we'll be talking about the last
vulnerability for today which is called
as lack of resources and trait limiting
one of the most commonly found
vulnerabilities when it comes to apis
and basically what happens here is that
there is absolutely no control on the
amount of requests that a user user can
make in a short frame of time
it can potentially lead to doors while
the other scenarios can range from group
force attacks or flooding attacks
consider this it's 5 am in the morning
and
you start getting a lot of sms like 500
sms in 2 or 3 minutes and those are all
the password reset links to you from
your favorite e-commerce
website
one
your obvious uws me very irritated that
hey why am i getting so many messages in
the morning and second would be you'd be
scared that hey someone's trying to hack
my account
so if there's no rate limiting in place
this this can happen
now
let's try to understand this again using
a demo
all right
so for this we'll be using the ova
security knowledge framework
and we'll try to see if we can bypass
the rate limiting on spook on this logic
page
okay so we don't know the dimensions
we'll try to view the source of this
page
we got something written in base64 let's
just try to decode it
so we found the username
let's just try to enter this as username
and password both and see if we are able
no we are not so now what we'll do we'll
just try to analyze the request here
cool
now we have the request with us what
we'll do is
we'll send it to includer and we'll try
to see if any sort of rate rate limit is
implemented
let's create a preview list
we're using a very small list here
just for checking your fate limitation
it is there or not
so we'll just quickly start our attack
and see what happens
all right so so there's absolutely no
rate limit in place
and
[Music]
so we have a different response for the
19th attempt let's just try to see
the response to it
cool
so we were able to solve this challenge
because there was no rate limit in place
and since there was no rate limit we
were able to prove for secret engines
so these were a few vulnerabilities that
we wanted to discuss today now coming on
to the next thing the tools that can be
used for testing
one is worksuit and verb suit is the
you know it's one of the most hacker
friendly tools when it comes to dynamic
testing
things like intruder repeater decoder
makes it the first choice whenever we
want to test
web application mobiles uh
the second is postman postman comes into
picture when we are working with rest
apis just like postman there is
something called as soap ui and soap ui
comes into the picture when we are
working on soap apis
the next one is sky travel kite runner
is a very widely used uh content
discovery tool the other one is astra
astra is an automated scanner you can
quickly just run this cam to see if
there are any issues that you can find
quickly with this
scanner
the other one is arjun now arjun is
again a very widely used tool for
parameter discovery
just like i mentioned previously there
are other tools available in the market
itself these are a few tools that i use
when i'm working on influence
all right
so
let's talk about a recent high profile
vulnerability related to apis
this vulnerability was found out uh in
coinbase and what happened was
this vulnerable api allowed unlimited
trading of cryptocurrency it was
categorized under broken object level
authorization and what happened was
it allowed the attacker to give a
command to sell and convert bitcoin to
usd without in fact owning a bitcoin
so what happened was there was a
parameter known as product id
that was going into the request and its
value was uh product id equal to dodge
point to usd or ethereum to euros so
what was happening
what was happening was it was converting
the value of dodge coin to euros or
ethereum to dollars
but what the attacker did here was he
changed the dot dodge coin to btc and
try to analyze the request
to his shock
he was he was able to make the
transaction without in fact owning a
bitcoin wallet the transaction took
place from an unknown bitcoin wallet
so he changed it
from dodge coin to usd to btc to usd and
the application is separated
at the time it was reported it was uh
considered super critical and it was
fixed like under five to six hours of
reporting so uh so think how critical
the bug was back then
all right
so
that was all
before before i leave i just want to
give a quick shout out to contra move
ass and security knowledge framework for
the for their amazing free content
related to papers
all right so that's been my time guys uh
thank you for listening and if you have
any questions feel free to reach out to
me on my email and on the linkedin uh
url sharing
thank you guys
awesome
and thank you for that awesome
presentation