right i'm told we're live and i can see
us live so
welcome to the panel
uh nice improv chaotic panel just chat
away i've got a few questions to throw
at you and then we will just blather and
fill up time after that if we have any
so
let's kick off with a simple one first
you know really easy question for both
of you and let's go in alphabetical
order but why did you choose to go down
the route of cyber technology security
in particular
well
i was very lonely
and i found lots of friends on the
internet
i
see i messed around with computers a lot
and
i got a job messing around with
computers
because it was fun i got to learn stuff
and i didn't really have to get outside
much which was nice and easy for me
then
i looked at the pay grades for security
and i went yeah sure i'll do that
very much motivated by money going into
it but then i met a really nice
community full of people i wanted to
stick around with and that's why i'm
still here instead of like hopping jobs
every six months
again i've always been kind of really
interested and drawn to computers and
also how they work and like all the
stuff behind it and then that kind of
developed
as i got older into programming um
learning how that sort of stuff worked
and then it
went into how
that stuff was then secured
and it kind of just kept going from
there
so
brilliant
and since we've had the job hopping
mentioned let's go for a
non-controversial question next
do you think security is compensated
fairly do you think people are paid
properly there's
a lot of conversations around pay
there's a lot of companies trying to
crush any conversation about pay
do you think it's a discussion worth
having and how do you actually have that
conversation
so let's go in reverse order this time
just to throw it off
i think it depends where you're working
some places will pay fairly but then you
get the other places that don't or
there's long hours and they don't pay
you enough for certain things
um and also public versus private sector
there's a big difference in pay there as
well
so
and i am an advocate for discussing pay
rates
um
when they are particularly egregious
so i did a year in the public sector
where they paid me 18 000 pounds a year
to train
an incident response team
and to in my spare time also manage
social media for that organization
because
that's how that works for some reason
but it was a lot of fun and i learned a
lot of things unfortunately
it probably should have paid a little
bit more
but this is a this is another problem um
pay geographically is very very
different obviously if you go to london
you have a massively inflated pay grade
because the cost of living around there
pretty high
and then where i live in cardiff
people don't pay anywhere near as much
for people who are local because the
cost of living in cardiff is really
really low it's like one of the cheapest
cities to live in really nice place by
the way
so
with remote working
we've now realized that you can go and
get london pay
and live in cardiff
so
yeah geographical pay is really really
unfair sometimes particularly if you
look at
even bigger disparities like if you're
in the us
and you're getting paid like 200 000
a year
and then you look at say a job in india
you could be doing exactly the same role
and someone will be being paid half of
what you're getting
so pay in the industry can be
some of the best around in tech
and it's fantastic and it's really like
something to aspire to and get up there
but uh sometimes you get trapped in this
little hole where people are like oh you
live in the wrong place
and because you live in the wrong place
it doesn't matter what your skill set is
we're going to pay you this super low
wage which is like scraping by in
comparison
i just i don't know how industry is
going to kind of meet that with remote
working coming in
i was actually going to ask about that
because we've got things like digital
nomad schemes coming in we've got
various ways that people can work not
just remotely from a different city in
the same country but halfway around the
world
i know i've seen some companies having
to adjust to that because they don't
have a choice
but are you finding anything if you're
currently working looking for work
seeing people being hired are you
finding people
being more scattered across the world
and demanding the same rates of pay
i mean i'm not seeing i'm not seeing a
hell of a lot because i'm not obviously
a hiring manager i'm not really
particularly involved in the hiring
process
but i am seeing
as i kind of
move around and go up the chain i'm
seeing a lot more people from different
places all around the world
and
while i'm not 100 sure what their pay
grades are we should be working towards
that kind of parity and
you know if managers won't do it then
you talk to your friends in the business
you talk to your friends in industry and
you start sharing some of that
information maybe that'll help you
even the scales a bit it's a win-win
situation when you do that
it's like it's not the person at the top
with the most amount of money sat there
like i have to hoard the information
so that no one else can like ask for the
same pay grade everyone wins because
what happens when you get paid fairly
is you don't burn out as much i know a
lot of people who like hot jobs because
they want the experience
but they can't afford to live on the
amount of money they're being given for
it
i think also so
i haven't been actively working with him
for in within him for i always keep an
eye on the different jobs that are going
because i'm in university at the moment
but i have definitely seen a difference
recently after clovid and everything
that's happened in more remote jobs
going
um
so i think it has definitely changed
because that you can see that there's
more going than there used to be
thank you
okay so you you both know something
about instant response properly quite a
bit about instant response and we've got
a question from lady b
how do you think cyber threat intel can
play a role in helping instant response
get ahead of threats
so i am a senior threat intelligence
well i'm not friends
i get my own job description wrong i am
a
senior
cyber instant response
team analyst
so
we work really closely with our threat
intel team
which
you know
ebbs and flows as things go
but
threat intel feeds in a lot of the
information that we need to prepare
things ahead of time we can have an
incident plan
ready for something weeks even months
before there is actually
a known instance of that in our
environment
so if you get things like log4j
if we get that information ahead of time
even by 24 hours by 48 hours
our response plans look so much more
professional and so much more well put
together
because no one is scrambling and no one
is panicking
or the panic is like halfway subsided
by the time we actually get around to it
so
threat until it's kind of essential to
our jobs
it's not all just reactive on the back
foot
i don't know what you've done with that
chloe so
um i don't really have a lot to add to
what you said to be honest
yeah i mean
and do you with the stuff that you do on
the side and stuff that you do
kind of in your time do you find perhaps
that threatens intel would be
like threat until this kind of
helping lead the way
yeah definitely
um
and i think also
we're seeing
a lot more happen within it and you can
i don't know
sorry
because i think
i think one of the things we can get
from that is maybe
when we get that threat intelligence as
well a lot of things follow similar
patterns
so if you see
like if you see an apt do it like
hitting
two businesses off to the side of you or
like starting to hit your suppliers
and it's not come around to you yet you
have that extra time to prepare it's
really useful
i'm going to
give a question for chloe you to have
more to say on this one
yeah so
brace yourself
you're obviously a student so you're
studying but you're quite involved in
the general
let's call it security community so i
don't get into whether it's cyber
information data whichever security
how are you finding the
overlap between what you're learning and
the skills you're learning is with what
people are talking about you needing in
the industry
i think some of what we're taught is
slightly outdated but
some of it also overlaps with things
that we do actually need to know
um some of the software that they use is
outdated or they don't have
um
certain things
like new open source um software and
everything that's always coming out that
other people speak about within the
industry
um
isn't always used at the universities
but i think also
a lot of it can be
used no matter what it is
so
say something from one tool could be
used from another because it's all about
how something works rather than
just using a tool if that makes sense
if you could get the university to buy
one software license for all students
what would it be
i think it depends in what module as
well for the ethical hacking probably
burp suite pro purely because
it's got everything in built within it
good choice
yeah
i love the pet you've already learned
the most important answer in security
okay
general question about security as a
whole again you're both
not new but
still early enough to be optimistic
about the industry
do you think organizations do you think
countries are improving in their
security posture are there common
mistakes that you see made or hear about
whether it's being made by security
people being made by companies ignoring
security people that could easily be
prevented and let's not with chloe on
that one because i'm interested in the
perspective from
your course and what you've seen and
then we'll go to abby's
actual painful experience of it not that
it was painful
um i think
there's always going to be people within
a company who don't listen to advice
from security teams and
a lot of people don't actually know what
they're talking about so
you might give them advice and they'll
be like oh no it's fine brush it to the
side and then something will happen and
they'll be like oh why don't you tell me
um
but
i think also it's becoming more people
are becoming more aware that security is
definitely a massive
risk factor within
the companies with all the new data
breaches and passwords getting leaked
every day and
i think
it's become people are becoming more
aware of it and are starting to listen
more but
it's still not where it should be
i mean that's
that sounds about right for me for
particularly like a lot of small and
medium enterprises
one of the things i will say is actually
i'm going to go and plug one of
yesterday's talks we have greg berkland
did hack your boss
very good talk and has some relevant
points on this one actually because the
landscape has moved and people are
getting better at things there are less
grumpy guys in it who are multitasking
as security and sat there like oh well
you know what's the point if you're all
just going to break it and i'm blaming
users for everything we think we're
moving on from some of that blame game
that we used to play before
um but we still have this massive
resourcing issue
i can't say the same for my current
company because uh we are kind of like
on top of things i'm much more happy
there than i was my previous one don't
go looking at my linkedin however i am
going to slate my previous employer for
20 minutes now
no um my previous employer had a couple
issues with the fact that they didn't
quite size the team correctly
and the budget didn't match
so because there wasn't this kind of
element like greg will talk about how to
get your boss to buy into things because
we didn't have the buy-in
and a lot of small companies don't have
that buy-in they're like oh you know why
should i spend 30 000 pounds on and you
know on a sock analyst why should i
spend 40 000 50 000 pounds on people to
like build help build out my team
and
no one knows what they've lost until
they've lost it
so everyone's like oh there's no way you
know we'll lose a bit of data what's the
worst that could happen and then the ico
comes along
and issues one of its very rare fines
for breaching gdpr and you're stuck
there with like
a massive portion of your income just
gone as a fine without all the other
things you had to do to get your data
back in the first place
so
i think we i think we're moving in the
right direction
we're very very far from being where we
need to be
particularly with
smaller companies with smaller workflows
and
kind of more hierarchical structures
sometimes
where the person at the top doesn't
understand the value that's being driven
by security
because we are always a cost center
rather than we are
rather than being seen as defense and
protection of assets i find
thank you and leading on from that
because there could almost be some
relationship between these questions
uh it's not often that a week goes by
without someone in the security twitter
community burning out and saying i'm
going to quit or quitting or wanting to
quit
even more often if you talk to people in
reality so
have you come across peers who were
stressed either in industry or during
your course or just
socially and
have you picked up anything on how
people could manage it or whether there
are
ways to manage it or how do you manage
it
i quit for six months
[Laughter]
infosec twitter was getting a little bit
too much for me
a few too many people were having a few
too many spicy takes
so i decided that the uh the extra intel
and the community spirit that was going
on wasn't quite what i wanted i took a
break got my head down did a little bit
of work
um
honestly one of the best things you can
do i find personally obviously it's
gonna work different for everyone else
one of the best things i found was just
turning off and resetting
if you get to that point where you're
like oh
i can't deal with this anymore someone
has crossed a line or someone has gone
beyond what they should
just
shut it all down
carry on with your job keep talking to
your co-workers keep talking to your
colleagues
and people that you trust
bring that circle back down to something
more manageable
and then you can creep out again as time
goes on
i find that that helped me a lot but i'm
not 100 sure if that works for everyone
though
yeah i agree it's i think it's always
important to take time for yourself as
well because absolutely
where
everything's always changing within
infosec and you're constantly having to
learn and
keep updated i think it can be hard to
make sure that you also keep time to
yourself right and
not just constantly
be within the community or talking to
people
and constantly learning um but also find
some time to
sit down and relax
yeah
so i think a lot of us are kind of
introverts or ambiverts like at best i
don't think there's a lot of us who are
extroverts who want to go out there and
constantly absorb energy from the
infosec community in whichever form that
takes
i'm not sure i'd want to deal with
someone who actively wants to absorb
energy from the twitter into a tech
community
there are good places there are
definitely good places and good people
one of the things i find is quite good
as well is branching out beyond your
security bubble
because infosec twitter can be quite
insular and
it likes to obsess over things that
perhaps aren't that big an issue or
aren't that big a problem
like we had these and we've had critical
cves that have come out and everyone's
gone into panic mode because it's like
oh you know we're all gonna die everyone
give up all your weekends and afternoons
to make sure that this gets fixed in
time
and
then we've actually looked at it and the
rate of exploitation for those
vulnerabilities as dangerous as they
might be is effectively zero because
it's only running on devices that are
well behind the dmz
and no one's really thought to take
stock and think about where all of the
threats and all of the big panic of the
day is hiding because it's a popular
thing and it gets you likes to say
everybody panic
i think also what you were saying about
branching out within
like your infosec bubble it's also good
for going to like in person conferences
and things
um because it's a really good way to
meet new people that you might not have
met otherwise
yeah absolutely
on on the infosec bubble i mean we use
the words infosec and cyber security and
security pretty much interchangeably
but i'm interested in whether you've
had any experience or spoken to anyone
in the security community but outside
the technical security community
so physical security biosecurity food
any of those whether you
actively look to have those
conversations
in breaking out of your bubble or if you
just want to go i want to talk to normal
people not more security people please
know more about risk management
i get along quite well with a lot of
people in risk management
but that's also because i am
an outlier and i love paperwork
i love documentation and if i could have
been a digital librarian
i would have been a digital librarian i
think
um it's really fun and it's something
that i enjoy personally so i've got a
personal stake with that and that side
of things i've had a few friends who've
been in physical security as well and
it's just really really helpful
to talk to people and contextualize
things in a way that you don't get from
a pure security view
also always talk to your developers
developers love it when you talk to them
about security
i think it's always really important to
spread out and learn about all the
different area of all the other
different areas as well rather than just
staying within
the whatever
job role or whatever it is that you're
in and
if you're
um only speaking to people within the
same infosec communities and stuff as
you you're not going to be learning the
stuff from other people as well
i think it's always really interesting
to know what other people are doing
because it can also help you improve on
what you're doing then
yeah absolutely because like if you talk
to um you know security people do a lot
of ctf wow
a lot of security people do a lot of
ctfs it's kind of like a big thing in
the community
but
you do need to talk to people who
understand systems administration you
need to talk to system administrators
you need to talk to people who
run like containerized
at like containerized assets
containerized like everything you need
to talk to someone who knows docker you
need to talk to someone who knows how to
run hypervisors
you need to talk to programmers
to get to a point where you can deliver
that kind of thing in the community in
the first place and you learn so much
from those people who are outside what
you would consider traditional security
just to do real basic things in the
industry
so
while everyone can go on about patching
and
the latest cbe on the market yeah you're
absolutely right
it's
super useful
to get that input from people
who have other technical and
non-technical skills
because you know
how to hack your boss isn't
necessarily something that's a pure
infosec talk how to hack your boss is
something that could apply to any
workplace any time it's about
stakeholder management
okay on that because we've now talked
about branching out
the whole specialization versus
generalism or generalist debate
where do you both fall on that and
what's your reason
that one's rough i'll let chloe go
faster now
so do you mean like specialized within
cyber security like a specific
so for example uh
pen testers doing ctfs doing the box
doing try hack me and focusing on those
areas
not to the exclusion of all else but
i think it's always good um
to branch out your knowledge because it
means that you'll have more
understanding of what you're doing
and say
if you were doing hack the boxes and all
that other stuff you might actually come
across something where you need to know
the
um
other
say different types of programming or
different
um
[Music]
i don't know different scripting
just so that you know how to use it if
it comes to a point where you do need to
so i think it's always important to look
at the wider picture rather than just
what you specialize in
yeah absolutely because if you um like
for instance if you're in security and
you need to de-obfuscate some code if
you can't read javascript
you're a bit stuffed
but
you're not going to exclusively be the
security person who reads javascript you
know some people might you know
drop
powershell might drop bash scripts on a
system and being able to read powershell
being able to read bash being able to do
those system administrator tasks
are really helpful i'm very much like
i'm kind of with you on this one in the
more generalist camp
but that doesn't mean there isn't a
space for specialists because i rely
very heavily on people who have the
specialist knowledge in the field and i
need to know who to go to
so i think
if you if you personally on the other
end of the conference want to do either
feel free because there is a space for
you
there is a space for specialists and
there is a space for generalists yeah i
think it's just a preference to be
honest
absolutely and i feel like it's kind of
our job as in the more generalist fields
to
bridge
the skills that they don't have
it's like we enable a specialist to do
their bit really really well
because we can help take care of the
things that they don't understand in a
much more broad sense
and then they enable us to do our jobs
because if i'm like hey i need this
really really in-depth splunk query
that like cross-references three
different sources and has like 17 nested
if statements
then i can ask the guy i know who's used
splunk all his life for like as long as
splunk's existed
and he'll just pull that report for me
and just hand it over and be like there
you go
and that's super useful
okay and keeping them with the
controversy then
non non-technical roles in security
yes or no
yes
question over done
where do they fit in
i mean
i think
right yeah and also non-technicals can
sometimes be better at communicating
than
um
some technical people so they can also
bridge the gap between the technicals
and the
non-technicals um
because there's usually someone who
works between
both of them
and they can
basically translate the technical
people's
um
gibberish to some people
yeah um and a good example of that
actually
um so i used to work at a company that
had basically no documentation
um and then we decided we were gonna
have some documentation
it was written up by people who were
just a little bit more specialist
in nature um specialist in the
elitist kind of way they were like i'm
going to be in charge of technology and
people are bad and i will never do
people because people are a bit too much
for me
um
which you know is it's if that's how
they work that's how they work it's just
we kind of needed someone to
tie that all in so they would draw up
these big documents that were 25 pages
long
completely incomprehensible defined
every term with six paragraphs of
technical data
and we kind of had to go in and we had
to rewrite some of that
um
communication is one of the most
effective like one of the best skills
you can have in security even if you're
a specialist
even if you don't want to deal with
people effective communication skills
are essential because there will be a
time when you need to there'll be a time
when you need to communicate with
someone
that where there isn't
you know the people person in the
department around
so
yeah
guess some people skills
right i will find something
controversial at some point which will
actually work rather than get an
acceptable answer so
sticking along the same sort of thing
in the uk we've got the dcms doing
consultations at the moment about
professionalising the industry
and you've mentioned elitism already
is there such a thing as good
gatekeeping
and what would it look like if it is or
if it doesn't exist then why not
i might have i might have a spicy take
on this one but um i'll let chloe open
no you're welcome to go first on this
one
no you
so
there is
a massive
shortage
in the cyber security industry for
professionals
now i believe that shortage is primarily
driven
by gatekeeping
and it's absolutely
dreadful
so we are a in this particular country
at this particular time at this
particular maturity stage for the
majority of businesses
i think there is no such thing as good
gatekeeping
there is you know for security there is
no such thing because you can train
people and people learn on the job i was
very fortunate that i took a leap from
junior to mid
quite early on in my career
and
that leap
was someone throwing me a lifeline
basically they were like you know
you can deal with people so come on and
you know be our people person for a year
i did that
and i learned so much
that you don't get taught
in indus you don't get taught in like
industry approved university programs
you don't get taught in your college you
don't get taught in your secondary
school you don't get taught in the
comptia books
none of that
helped
in any meaningful sense when i moved
into industry and i started using
industry tools
because
it's a different world
industry and education aren't matched up
right now
so you can ask for 30 different
certifications
and sure someone who's done those
certifications might have a solid
understanding
of how to begin to understand those
industry tools
but also someone who's had none but is a
really good learner
can sit in front of those industry tools
and in six months time
they will
accelerate past that person who had
those certifications those you know
those degrees that kind of thing so i
think
we should be
accepting more people
with more diverse backgrounds into the
industry because we need the bodies
but also
because we don't have an education
system fit for purpose and security
and until we have that until we have a
system where we can teach people
good security practice
how to use tools
and how to
run you know how to run your sock how to
run
your application security team how to
run your incident responses
we should be letting juniors in and we
should be training them up
and we should be having reviews like six
months we should be having reviews
yearly and we should be like okay you
were a junior
it doesn't look like it anymore you've
just grasped all of the concepts we've
thrown at you in a really short period
of time
that's my take
also if they've got a more diverse
background they'll have different ways
of thinking so they might find things
that other people wouldn't
yeah i mean if you get an army of red
teamers in the chat
and you have them all talk about how to
get into a box you'll get a very very
different set of responses to having
like a group of blue teamers in the chat
yeah
then
put them together see what happens share
some ideas
okay we've got about 10 minutes left and
skelly's been wanting to ask this one
for a while so
have you been impacted by tokenism and
forced diversity in tech and what are
your thoughts on it and do you think
it's beneficial or harmful
this will be fun
so um i don't think i've been affected
by tokenization in technology that much
if at all really
um i have had people be incredibly weird
to me
which is less tokenization and more just
the fact that everyone accepts
discrimination in the industry
super common
uh i believe it is a third of employers
in technology
will turn around and say we are going to
break the equality act by um simply
not
hiring people who are
too
diverse for us
so
we have a little bit of a problem there
i don't necessarily think we're getting
tokenization
i i don't think we're elevating voices
above where they should be i think what
we're doing is we're reaching a point
where
voices that used to be suppressed
actively
are getting less
so
people are seeing that movement upwards
to an even platform as tokenization i
think
chloe do you wanna
drop in you haven't any experiences like
that i don't know what it's like in
university anymore because i know that
there are a lot of like girls who code
and women inside the things guys yeah
there's a lot of that sort of thing um
and you can get different opportunities
and stuff specifically for women to try
and encourage them to
go into tech
um
but again i think that's also because
there's yeah on my course there's a lot
more guys than girls
so i think they're trying to bridge the
gap between that still at the moment
yeah do you think that i don't know what
it's like for you as well do you think
that
the problem is that we can't
get people into the industry or do you
think the problem is like whether or not
they stick around like do you find that
over uni there's a drop-off rate or
something like that
um
i think there's a bit
the problem that i have is that i've
moved university so i wouldn't know
do i do the same thing
i did the same thing i hit i hit second
year and i did my third year at
different universities yeah that's what
i've done
yeah well
yeah
close enough yeah
that is
i do i do think that part of the problem
with keeping
we're going slightly off topic here i
think part of the problem of keeping
like wanna say minoritized groups in
security is a lot of us just
quit
because in my last job i had a guy who
would come up to me and we were remote
working he would like come into my
team's chat and he would call me on
teams and he would start doing the
absolute weirdest things he would start
showing me
comic books that he read which actually
that's kind of cool right you know
show me your special interest we can get
to know each other and be friends the
problem is he was showing me comics
about a torture novel
oh
and he was just trying to like
constantly do like the most gross things
to like freak me out and i'm like
i'm not rising to this bait but like why
are you doing this
i mean i've had people message me
inappropriate things
yeah and that was before i'd even turned
18 so
there was a lot of dodgy stuff going on
but
i think that's also
a lot a lot of women in tech or women in
general
find that it happens a lot to them i
think i think because like obviously
when you're in infosec you have certain
you know you have usually got like a
skill set that allows you or enables you
to do
bad things if you want to do bad things
and
some people take advantage of that maybe
not as many as you might think but it's
enough for it to be a serious like
annoyance like a thorn in your side when
you're in the industry and you're
constantly exposed to people like that
and i think um
maybe if more people took a stand
against them
rather than you know if people took us
down against them then after a few years
when things catch up and the buffer kind
of
hits its end we'll start needing
less and less of this kind of signal
boosting for uh like keeping us in
technology
because
instead of like advertising for everyone
like please stay please please stay
we'll actually have like communities
where people will want to stay
i've i have noticed one particular thing
um just to you know insert my
underrepresented voice into this
there's
almost a thing in security that i've
seen come up a lot where people are very
against demographic surveys as part of
hiring
and say that they're being intrusive
they're privacy violating why do
companies need this data
i do think there's a problem there in
that the reason companies need that data
is if you don't measure you don't know
you've got a problem
if you don't know you've got a problem
you can't stop looking at solutions for
that problem
and nothing gets better so while
there is a take that it's intrusive that
seems very much weaponizing security
concerns to try and stick heads in the
stand and say there is no problem we
don't need to do anything wrong
diversity people just don't want to go
into tech
and just to stick my own as i said
underrepresented taken there as well
right we've you say it's an under you
say i was gonna say you say it's an
underrepresented um view and actually
you say it kind of ironically i'm not
sure that it is underrepresented
um
although it isn't underrepresented
rather because
you're kind of right
there are
i will say to anyone who does think that
if you are watching the chat right now
just remember that demographic surveys
are
optional you can simply choose not to
reveal that data and like the company
that wants to use that data for any
reason do so it's a it you know it's
your personal data
you do what you want with that also
try not to force other people
yes
all data if you are giving away
demographic data obviously you do need
the legitimate cons like security
concerns of it being fully anonymized it
being
preferably like preferably in such a way
that you cannot trace it's not like
pseudonymizing fully anonymize data if
you can
always there are legitimate security
concerns but you can't weave things in
like well i don't want to give my
information across because i don't
believe in
you know insert your own political take
on what you think of diversity in the
workplace
and that means that no one else should
it's like you can have your views but
try not to force that
you know try not to force data away from
people who need it to make a positive
change
right we've got one minute left so final
hot spicy take from each of you
certificates yes or no
i think it depends
it's more personal preference to be
honest
because i know people who have gone into
info cycle security roles and they've
had no certificates
yep
so
sometimes it can help be
a shortcut but it's not necessarily
needed
yep
at risk of um a risk of burning bridges
um
ec council please stop
no a lot of certificates are checkbox
exercises
until your certificate stops becoming a
checkbox checkbox exercise
no
there is no need for them
however
i will caveat it for the certificate
holders in the crowd i have a cloud
practitioner with aws
those checkbox exercises can actually
get your foot in the door so
does it build your skill set
maybe is it a good place to start maybe
does it help your prospect in industry
if you're struggling absolutely
so i don't think we should need them
but i guarantee you if you're struggling
to get a job and you add a certificate
on to the end of your you know resume on
your cv
you will have a better prospect
of getting a job
thank you and with that i think we've
come to the end of our time anyway so
thank you both including for the hot
takes and for the
more sensible answers