yes thank you uh
first of all before i start i want to
thank uh eden and atomic for putting on
such a great conference and i want to
thank the volunteers and the mentors um
for organizing everything and for
helping us speakers uh prepare for this
conference and now
getting into the main conference hi
uh
my name is ahmed and i'm going to be
talking about offensive security welcome
to the dark side
so who is this specimen who is this
creature in front of you today um well
like i said my name is amateur and i'm
18 years old i like to play basketball
i participate in the trace labs ocean
search party in my free time
my team came 20th place just saying just
saying uh i'm passionate about
everything cyber security and uh i got
my ejpt which was my first certification
um at 17 years old so that's about about
me i do like to um
create content on youtube i have a
youtube channel uh that i'll link at the
very end of the slide and
throughout uh
as we get on with the as we go on with
the talk i'll have time for questions if
anyone has any questions for me
um so let's get started so i want you to
picture this with me okay i want you to
to to really imagine this with me you
have a castle and it's filled with
riches and gold and so much wealth
you have a lot of security measures uh
to prevent any kind of theft
but one day you you wake up and you find
that this person stole from you and your
riches and your gold
now
similarly but in a more digital form
think of your organization as the castle
and think of your riches
as the company's data or profit your
security measures is your password your
antivirus firewall intrusion detection
system and maybe also have intrusion
prevention systems
now
is the thing you have all of that in
place
but you still fall victim to a cyber
attack and
what happens now so you had your
security measures in place the cars were
awake and didn't see anyone conducting
the highest the cameras did not pick up
anything the question is what do you do
now where do you go from here
so
here is where i want to present
offensive security
offensive security is an approach to
better secure your systems networks and
assets by hiring what we call a white
hat hacker to try and break into your
systems as if they were an adversary
so
we as the good guys as the white hat
hacker it's
pretty much us
pretending and kind of simulating a
break-in
to uh
kind of see where your where where your
flaws are at what assets or where you
might have an issue
and then from there we go back and we
reported the security team and then uh
give feedback on how we were able to do
this and this is what we call a
penetration test so this is a simulated
cyber attack
attempt to expose and test any potential
security flaws
of an organization company etc now i
know i know what you're thinking before
you judge me i know what you're thinking
i know you're probably saying how is
this legal let me explain let me explain
there are kind of three characteristics
that i would say uh define the fine line
between ethical and unethical
you have intentions which is our
intentions to improve a company's
security or are your intentions to steal
or harm a company then you have your
scope when you're conducting a
penetration test engagement you have a
scope where you're allowed to kind of
play around and test and
and work your magic on that kind of area
but
if you go out of that scope that would
be unethical
if you stick to that scope if you stick
to that defined area of attack where
you're allowed
to go and play
and this is given by the company so the
scope would be given to you by the
company the company will tell you i
alright this is my scope i want you to
just test these um assets
that would be uh so just sticking to
that kind of scope would be ethical
and then lastly you have permissions so
do you have valid permission do you have
valid um consent from that company to
conduct this attempt a simulated cyber
attack do you have uh permission or are
you doing this simply with no permission
no one knows about it you're just doing
this on your own so that's kind of the
three characteristics that define the
line between
ethical and not unethical
and we really want to stay on that side
so
let's break it down um
when i think of a penetration test um i
try i narrow it down so some might say
there's more but i narrowed it down to
four stages you have reconnaissance
scanning gaining access and reporting
now with reconnaissance that's the first
stage of a penetration test is you're
gathering information you're going
around and you're trying to see what
information you can gather kind of
trying to paint a picture of the company
that you're trying to break into so see
what you can learn see who's the
who's the uh ceo who's the head of
security
where the
what the company's goals are what the
company's uh
you know what the company is based on is
it is it an it firm is it a financial
firm
kind of get a picture just get an idea
of what you can learn from this company
uh that's available to you
and then from there you go into scanning
and you start looking for potential
areas of attack so here you would start
looking see uh maybe there's um
a vulnerable web uh website that you
could maybe take advantage of or there's
an open port that maybe was left open uh
accidentally so you could abuse and and
use that
from there once you've kind of figured
out okay this is kind of the path i want
to take this is kind of the area that i
want to start um
attacking from you go into the third
stage and this is the main stage where
you actually gain access
um you start you break you conduct that
break-in and you try to gain access to
that uh
to that system from there once you're
successful you'll go into reporting
you'll write a report back to the
security team and
uh back to explain okay so this is how i
conducted it i was able to learn that
you had maybe an open port that was uh
left unchecked and i was able to get uh
access and from there you kind of just
write how you were able to
kind of like a summary of how you were
able to conduct that temptation test
and comment oh no who who sabotaged my
who know uh who sabotaged my my
presentation no okay we're gonna ignore
that
uh
no okay so
common tools that penetration testers
use to kind of assist them uh during a
pen testing engagement you have record
for reconnaissance you'll have google
and social media so you'll go under
social media see where you can learn uh
um
see
what you can find out about the company
google is a very uh great tool as well
and uh it's part of it as well
so once you kind of use google use
social media see or maybe the the
security team goes out to drink uh for
drinks
somewhere or
they're
uh or or you know they go and
play uh maybe hang out somewhere or they
go on the weekends to for a run together
whatever it is
you kind of just learn about the company
you learn about everyone in the company
you learn about the employees and you
just build an image a greater image um
and these are some of the tools that can
really help you do that
from there you would have scanning which
is the second stage and of a penetration
test and then you have nmap which is a
network port scanner and they can help
you identify open ports so this can
really help you find if there's a
potentially uh open port that's been
left unchecked that you could maybe uh
use their buster is
a tool that can
reforce web directories and this is a
vulnerability scanner so a bunch of
tools that can really help you um in
your engagement
from there once you've kind of figured
out okay so there's a vulnerability here
or there's an open port there that you
want to kind of uh start
conducting your attack on you actually
go and gain access and some of my
favorite tools are metzploid netcat and
hydra so metsploit being um
a framework which can spin up
it has so much it's so it's so fast and
big but there's so much functionality
you have
metsploit uh which can uh
it what it does is it's a framework that
can you can spin up exploits you can
have backdoors you can uh listeners and
there's scanners in it if you want to
scan for uh open ports just like just
like nmap it has so much functionality
and uh it's quite it's honestly stable
it's one of my favorite tools um and
then you have netcat which is a network
utility um
and they can help you set up listeners
in your engagement then you also have
hydra which is a direct which is a brute
forcer in general and it can brute force
many protocols ssh
it can ssh ftp a bunch a bunch of uh
protocols and then lastly you have
report the final stage which is
reporting and these are some
dradis magic tree and metagoofil are
some of the three um
tools that come pre-installed with an
operating system uh called uh kali linux
which is basically a distribution that
has pre-installed tools for you so
you're just there and
it's it
you have all these tools set up for you
including and map under buster analysis
and exploit netcat and hydra all of
these tools are just pre-installed for
you
ready for you to use so that
being one of my favorite tools
getting access in the end is no use if
you cannot write a good report
the whole point of you conducting that
pen test is that once you gain access
you write that report back so that the
security team can identify the issue and
can fix it the whole point is that
you're improving you're trying to
improve security and you have to
understand that
sometimes
this report won't just go to the
security team it'll also it might go to
the board or
heck it might even go to the ceo but so
when you write your report you have to
make sure that you're writing one that's
both
that both the technical side and the
non-technical side can understand it has
to be well written in the way where both
sides can understand not just one side
has to be fully technical to understand
um and and fix the the issues when you
that you've mentioned in your report
now speaking of distributions uh there
are two common penetration testing this
uh operating system there's a bunch more
but these i would say are the two most
common ones there's kali linux and
parrot os both open source both great uh
i've tried both personally i just just
saying i'm just saying i prefer cali
linux i'm that that's the team i'm on um
but that's just personal preference of
course um
and yeah they both have many many tools
installed that you can uh use during to
start your engagement uh
so your penetration test engagement um
so you don't have to
go through the hassle of reinstalling
all of those tools uh and map their
buster
all of those tools come pre-installed
with that distribution you just have to
spin it up in a virtual machine and
you're ready to go
now another thing i want to talk about
is
the tools that i mentioned they're all
open source so they're all available to
the public and you can approve them
and uh
but sometimes
if you're in an engagement and
you're in an environment where you don't
have access to nmap or metsploit or you
don't have access to these pre-built uh
pre-installed or pre-built tools
sometimes it's a good idea to create
your own
uh some to further you know move to
further
and
to further go along with your engagement
so
uh a great uh
scripting language would be python uh
which is the two is the blue one is the
blue yellow snake uh right
facing uh offsets each other so that's
python and you can create your own diy
and map with it you can create your own
um port scanner with it
there's also go and bash bash being one
that that's really useful for automation
so if you want to automate the task bash
is really useful for that
some there are really really there are a
lot of different assets when it comes to
penetration testing and
i know it's
i know it's a lot but just bear with me
pen testing engagements can be conducted
on different assets including web apps
networks iot devices which are internet
of things
and android and ios mobile applications
and physical buildings so you can
conduct a physical penetration test on
the building steve
if you can social engineer engineer your
way into a building into a restricted
area and
sometimes it's really useful to conduct
not just conduct
you know technical
technical uh penetration tests but it's
also good to conduct physical ones as
well
now
when i have to say uh training providers
there are
these two uh
these are the two most common trained
providers i have to say that give you
consent and you can
train yourself and and practice your
skills in penetration testing uh for
free and
you have consent to play around uh and
and practice your skills with
so one of them being a very famous one
is hack the box and this is a
this is a platform that is
a ctf based and they also have an
academy where they'll teach you
different uh
different fantastic uh skills so you
could uh they'll teach you the basics of
web they'll they'll even teach you how
to uh exploit a bunch of things um so
you can go there and you can start
learning if you're interested you can go
and start learning how
this world works and
dive deeper into the subject matter and
try hack me has what they call rooms and
you have two kinds of rooms i have to
say is one of them are
educational ones so they're made to
teach you uh concepts so they'll teach
you uh concepts on how the web works or
how um assertion tool works
and they'll have another room which is a
more ctf capture the flag uh what we
call a capture the flag and this is
where you'll it's more of a challenge
and
you you're conducting like a simulated
test in a gamified version to try and
reach that like final piece of flag at
the end and once you get that flag
that's that's kind of how the game ends
once you find that flag
so it's a very fun way to gamify cyber
security and penetration testing to
actually
you know you're not just learning but
you're also
playing around in a fun way to which
both teaches you and um
and you're having fun during the process
so you're not just learning um you know
theory having to write down everything
pen and paper style no but you're also
doing it hands-on you're on the keyboard
and you're learning and you're having
fun
so now let's solve a business
you spent years
years creating what you think is the
most secure unbreakable system for your
organization so you have everything in
play you have you think you've done the
best possible job
but you still wake up the next day and
you're still fall victim to a cyber
attack and it can be really discouraging
and really um really rough
now why is that
so you see
it's really not a question of
if i will be attacked it's a matter of
when will i be attacked so once you have
that kind of concept in mind
no company is ever
100 prone to uh
cyber attacks there's always going to be
some way where you would fall victim to
a cyber attack
so it's
it's almost like it's inevitable
sometimes all an attacker really needs
to do is send one fake email just one
email imagine
you like dogs or cats
and you there's an email that says you
can get your cat back uh
a voucher one to for example have
your cat
checked up on
for free
and you just have to click this link to
sign up
all it takes is that one click to steal
your uh still credentials of the
organization if you're accessing it from
an organization
computer to steal credentials to the
organization or for an admit to just
forget
a sim
and we're all humans we all forget so
sometimes politics is just one person to
forget to change the default password
and then that's an open door for an
attacker to abuse that and harm the
company
so the best way to kind of go about
dealing with this issue is to conduct a
penetration test every 12 months doing
that will help you see that maybe what
you thought you when if you thought you
changed the default admin password you
really didn't or maybe
something you didn't know existed an
issue or a vulnerability that existed
that you didn't know about you would
find out because
you've had someone try to break in and
try to see where kind of
where are the holes in the castle that
you can kind of go in and and
and try and
steal
those riches and those um
and that data and that profit
anyone can fall victim to a fishing uh
to a phishing link anyone can public
them to a social engineering attack
we're all humans and
needless to say i've probably
fallen for one uh
one for many actually um
but
it's important that the company that
you're working on that you're working in
also teaches you how uh security
awareness training so security awareness
training every once every um
every year just once every year you have
security awareness training to remind
those employees of how to spot a
phishing link or how to uh you know
read and and verify this this is the
the the right uh sender who's sending
you this and it's not some
uh
you know someone who's with malicious
intent trying to harm the company
and
on that note i want to move on to some
recent cyber crimes that have happened
last month and i want to just bring this
to light
of the cyber attacks that have happened
uh in march so the the two uh the two
separate crimes i'm going to be talking
about today have happened in march 2022
so the first one being morgan stanley
which is an american multinational
investment bank and financial services
company
got uh many of its client accounts
breached in a social engineering attack
and this happened through a wishing to a
wishing attack and this is when the
kind of
the threat actor or the
the the malicious user will will go on a
phone call
and they'll start
pretending
that there's
there's someone of legit who they say
they are and try to extract information
through the phone
and uh you know luckily the company was
able to deactivate those accounts and no
harm was done besides the
you know the credentials and the being
leaked to the
public but besides that
any you can see that this is a really
big company and
it still fell victim to a cyber attack
through a social engineering attack now
a massive cyber security budget this
just goes to show that a massive
security budget won't stop you from
being hacked it it really just because
you have such a
a large amount of money and you invest
so much money and time into um
into taking care of that technical side
that you forget there's also a human
side when there's a technical side
the human side is just as important to
secure as the technical side
and another one which really shocked me
if i have to say this took me by
surprise
uh lapses which is what a really big
cyber crime organization
um and just
for some context here they're
responsible for breaching octa microsoft
nvidia and samsung so all really big
companies
and
just in march they found out that a 16
year old from oxford was the was accused
of being one of the leaders of the
organization so you can see that
a cyber criminal can be any young um
teenager
to a more experienced adult there's no
age limit to
that says oh you have to be at least 18
years old to attack a company that
doesn't exist so
make sure that you know you have your uh
good security measures in place and
this can be more
and
a way to prevent this would be doing a
penetration test if
if you constantly do penetration tests
at least once every year you're more
likely to see those vulnerabilities that
popped up that the hackers were able or
the
attackers were able to use
and the views
now this this brings me to my next point
which is benefits of a fantast when you
are conducting a pen test you can really
reveal where the problem is in your
systems um a pen test should not be
conducted just once it should be
conducted at least every 12 months and
if for whatever reason one of your
employees needs more um
uh
is not really aware of
is security aware
providing providing security awareness
training again one at least once every
uh
once every uh year is really important
to prevent that to prevent not just the
technical side but also the the human
side of security and in the end you're
you're really not just hardening systems
but you're also hardening personalities
too
and before i
kind of uh go up and leave here i want
to leave everyone with a quote and
that is you can't learn how to defend
against an attacker if you don't know
how the attacker is conducting the
attack
with that being said some of the key
takeaways that i want everyone to go
home uh with today is being offensive
can be used in a good way and to reveal
accompanying security flaws anyone can
learn the documents of offensive
security so
i'm
18 years old if i could learn anyone can
comment training providers that you can
sign up right now and practice
penetration testing legally are try hack
me and hack the box and you can build
your own scripts and tools using uh
scripting languages such as python go or
bash
and the biggest advice the the best
advice i could possibly give anyone
who's really interested or
fascinated by this is never limit
yourself and
this isn't just insecurity but in
general never limit yourself to
sticking to one methodology or one
approach or one technology to learn
explore
different engagements will require
different
uh approaches and sometimes you can't
stick to the same methodology all the
time so
think outside the box and
don't be afraid to
you know leave what you're used to and
that maybe that
four-stage
penetration test if you have your own
methodology don't be afraid to try out a
new methodology maybe that will work
better in your penetration testing
engagement
and if you would like to reach me i'm
that there's my email it's
ahmad.rushfound outlook.com uh my
instagram is at rsasec0x01
which is just rsa being
rushed once
my name backwards with security
concatenated to it um that's also my
twitter handle ahmed r60x01 and my
youtube is ahmadrishwan
um i hope you learned something i hope
this was interesting
and i hope you're a little fascinated by
this and i have time for questions if
anyone uh wants to ask questions i'm
ready to answer them
oh boy i have a few questions uh
actually
um i'm ready
okay
so uh first question um so you recommend
um
so you have
okay no someone else i'm gonna start
with someone else's question because
otherwise uh i'm gonna get lost okay uh
what do you recommend uh doing to
practice making scripts uh was there a
site that helped you a lot in learning
to create scripts
so
i would say if you really understand the
basic um
the really basic fundamentals of a
programming language so you know like
what a variable is or uh what a loop is
how to use a loop
that can really help you kind of so you
know for example if you're trying to
create a script brute force or something
you
you as you try and
think if you understand the core
concepts really well you'll understand
that okay maybe this is a loop that i
can do and it can
you could maybe use bash to read a list
of um let's say directories and you can
use the while loop to kind of
test that
those different directories by sending
web requests or whatever it
really to to just help the best way is
just to try and
get a lot and a lot and a lot of errors
in the process but it's just to keep
trying and having that um
uh
trial and error process
when you're creating your scripts
awesome
um so now on to my questions uh so you
mentioned doing a pen test every 12
months uh there's a few questions uh on
that end mainly uh how do you deal with
people that
do pen tests in a
uh checklist manner so if you were more
on a company side uh you know checklist
pen testers people that go through a
baseline set of tests and go then go
drop a report and poop that's it how
would you deal with them
okay
so
not i'm not going to say it's
necessarily
a bad approach
but
going through a checklist
may leave out what's in the middle
so if you if you're going by so if
you're going all right one i want to
check first the networks and then i want
to check maybe um
if any of the machines are vulnerable if
they if they're all if they all have
antiviruses you could miss out what's in
the middle between point one and point
two and that's why
it's not necessarily a bad idea it's not
a and it could work
but it's better to not stick to kind of
an organized um checklist manner
when you're uh connecting a penetration
test because the whole point is that
you're trying to see what's in between
those in between those two points so if
you have a checklist and between point
one and point two
the whole point of a penetration that's
this you're not trying to check if
they're secure you're trying to check
what's not secure and to do that you'd
have to read in between those points
no so yeah i would say is it's not
necessarily an idea but it it's better
to
read what's in between those points
okay
and uh i guess i'll continue with um
like 12 months uh
questions um so imagine yeah
it spawned a few questions um
if you add infrastructure let's say uh
you're spinning up some new uh
kubernetes clusters on your internal
infrastructure uh would you recommend
moving the date of your pen test to like
right after you've spun up all this
to check that there's no gaps in your uh
infrastructure security okay
uh i'm gonna need you to repeat your
question just one more time okay if
that's okay so
if you uh use um kubernetes or whatever
to spawn up some infrastructure
would you recommend moving the pen test
time like when you're doing the pen test
to right after you've done this
i would recommend doing it when you
think it's ready to go out to the public
and
it's ready to uh be shown to the public
i would recommend doing it right before
that because then you know that this is
what would be going out to the public
and you would see okay so maybe there's
certain infrastructure that's vulnerable
in a way that you didn't take into
account so i would suggest right before
you maybe push out to the uh if you're
on an infrastructure and
you know maybe that you have a web
server running
make sure that
just right before you're pushing it out
you have
um and conduct a penetration test at
least at that time uh to check that both
the infrastructure and the assets are
going out to the public are both secure
okay
and uh the final one uh that i had and
then i'll let eden take
the others
um
so imagine once again from the
perspective of a company you um
contract a pen testing company or a pen
tester uh to do
okay you know a test
would you be recommending switching
between these uh different uh
i don't know entities
to see if there were so you're saying is
so you're saying
you know uh
going with
a company that's that's uh
that's assigning the hand that's uh
assigning the pen tester as opposed to
just a single pen and tester uh
is that am i getting your question right
is that kind of what you what you're
talking about not exactly so um for
example if you're a company and you
contract a pen tester or a pen testing
company so to do a pen test on your
infrastructure
okay um
would you recommend switching between
who does the pen test so to see if the
results change
i would recommend so
uh
you know typically the penetration test
would it's it's good to have more than
one pair of eye when you're doing
fantastic because um one pair of eyes
won't you know necessarily find
everything
uh that's wrong with the and you you
you really can't find one 100 everything
that's wrong because there's always
going to be something that maybe is
overlooked but that's that could further
be um you know
that
issue can be fixed if if you do more
than if more than one person goes
through uh
goes through a contest
on that same company on that company uh
assets
so i would recommend sophia
awesome
awesome all right yeah next question we
have is from binary sleeper what are
your thoughts on scoping tests
okay
depending on the scope you're given i
i say
try to
search everything that's in that scope
and obviously try not to go outside of
that scope
um
sometimes maybe there's something that's
vulnerable that's outside of the school
but that's not what
you're there to do you're here to stick
to just that one section and that one
area
where you're uh
of that scope so
make sure that if you're stick if you're
going to stick to uh if you're going to
be assigned a certain scope make sure
that you try and
explore that scope as to the
to its uh to its max and try to see what
you can really find um and go really in
depth in that defined scope
awesome thank you
and from ghosty thank you
uh how would you deal with checklist
clients the clients that are just doing
the test for a checklist requirement and
have you void critical results from the
report
i would say
try to bring to light how
the critical um the critical points are
that are being made that
that company is trying to overlook
try to bring to light how that can
really damage and impact the company
uh
whether that's you know by
not necessarily but
you could uh
if it's possible to show them a demo of
how
it could really affect the company
then there there may be more likely to
actually understand uh
why it's so important that that point is
being made and why it's important to
look not just overlook that point
awesome
and a
question from ray great talk what made
you interested in this topic
thank you
okay so
uh
a lot of searching into that so we all
know cyber security is a really really
huge field to get into but
at 16 years old 17 years old when i just
started deciding to get into my career i
wanted to find something that was both
fun that i wouldn't mind doing
all the time and that was interesting
and i could constantly learn so i wanted
a balance between something that would
be fun and something that i would be
able to have a lot of learning
opportunities from
and more
the more i search in the different
domains of cyber security the more that
i found that this was the one that
suited me best i like being on the
keyboard i like trying to
conduct that break-in and uh
that was personally what i enjoy doing
so that's kind of why i've
that's why i kind of pursued it
makes sense thank you so much your talk
was awesome and thank you for answering
all these questions you had a lot you
did a great job of presenting the
information thank you eden uh thank you
atomic i really appreciate it uh thank
you for having me on thank you for being
on it's uh it was fantastic to have you
and thank you for your awesome talk it
was so like informational
yeah thank you uh i'm glad i'm glad it
was it could inspire and be informative
uh it's a few uh people out there
because
that's that was the goal that was a goal
to to make to kind of inspire and
get people interested in this topic
awesome i'm glad
i think that is a rousing success it is
definitely yeah