hello everybody
uh thank you all for being here uh and
uh i'm really very happy to be here uh
i'd like to thank the organizers uh
organizers for uh for this opportunity
to tell you more about the next
generation of peace builders but before
i do so let me tell you a few words
about the cyber peace institute
the cyber peace institute was created in
2019 in geneva switzerland by our
founding partners microsoft hewlett
foundation
mastercard among others
and
assist them we now count 27 staff of
different nationalities and coming from
various backgrounds
and our mission is to build cyberpeace
now how are we doing that
the way we do this is uh i apologize
the way we do this
is by working together across three main
teams here at the institut the
assistance analysis and advancement team
in assistance we assist humanitarian
ngos with their cyber security needs
when we do so we collect stories stories
that we then share with our colleagues
in analysis to document to research and
to analyze to then inform our colleagues
in advancement who work to create
policies policies at the u.n and
international level
now
why are we doing this like what's the
rationale
behind doing all this what's the need
actually so as some of you might know
before covid 740 million people lived in
extreme poverty
now with kovit with the pandemic this
number is going to
rise by 150 million people
these people
encounter huge barriers in terms of
social economic sanitary uh political
life due to conflict natural disasters
and the least so long it can go on for
the rest of my talk um now
these people they depend on the critical
services offered by ngos by humanitarian
ngos who in turn they depend
on donations donations coming from
different institutions private public
from government and from private
individuals
now
we did some research and we realized
that humanitarian organizations actually
raised around 30 billion dollars
annually
now i do not know if you knew that
but cyber criminals do
several criminals also know that only
one in 10 ngos train their staff on
cyber security matters
only one in four ngos monitor their
network for any kind of suspicious
activity and only one in five has any
kind of cyber security strategy or plan
now
you see attacks on humanitarian ngos are
not something new
however since there is no protections
his protection is so low and there is
nothing really put in place these are
easy attacks that imply very low risks
for
uh
for for for for the perpetrators for the
cyber criminals and also a big payout if
you refer to the slide before where we
saw how much money this humanitarian
ngos raised annually to help vulnerable
people
now according to our research
around 500 attacks were committed since
2016.
each one of them are different
intensity or severity as you can see
depending on you know the money or
the data stolen and the damage
now because of this we realized that
cyberpeace begins with the most
vulnerable the most vulnerable being the
people this humanitarian ngos help
but
in order to
in order to be able to support them we
realize that it's important to protect
this mantra and ngos to be able to carry
out their their job to deliver critical
services to these people
and that's how
the cyber peace builders came to be
that's our solution to this challenge
now what are the builders
what do they do what do they offer
now the cyber peace builders are cyber
security experts coming from all trades
and they are employed by local and
international companies
uh thanks to them we can offer um three
different types of services three
pillars
the first pillar of services that we can
offer are pre-incident uh we can do
security assessments of ngo systems
we do cyber security training for all
staff to render them more aware of all
cyber security threats
we help them with their security policy
cyber security policies and we also do
vulnerability scans of their emails and
websites now let me give you an example
last year
in summer end of summer 2021 uh one of
our beneficial organizations the union
for international cancer control got
their instagram account hacked
um
they
they got it they got this account hacked
because they received a phishing email
claiming that um um
they had some sort of copyrighted
infringement and of course when you see
something like this you say oh no this
is serious let's you know take care of
this we didn't want to do any kind of
copyright
but they fell in the trap and then two
days later on the cyber criminals
contacted them via whatsapp
telling them yeah we have your account
and if you want to get uh access
if you want to regain access you have to
pay this many thousands of ranks in
bitcoin by following this link
uh the union for international cancer
control or uicc they did join the
therapist builders and we managed to
help them with this issue but we also
managed to improve the overall
cybersecurity infrastructure
the second pillar of support
that we offer is a
post incident
um here we can we can do open source
intelligence as we recently did actually
not in the context of the cyber business
part in the context of the ukraine
conflict where we developed a ukraine
timeline of cyberattacks
we also do darkway monitoring to inform
attack notification but we also do
recovery and investigations to be able
to properly notify our beneficiaries the
humanitarian ngos we work with now just
to give you an example in terms of uh
investigations
um in december last year um the
institute has discovered this
um this uh phishing campaign that uh it
was targeting specifically ngo
humanitarian ngos by working with some
private partners we realized that the
cyber criminals they were leveraging
a gap security issue in outlook and they
were sending phishing emails containing
malware
after all this research after all these
open source intelligence uh
dissemination gathering uh my colleagues
informed all our ngos all the all our
partner ngos
that not only about this trap
um the last pillar of support is just
general support
where we do uh coaching uh for managers
um more precisely how do we talk about
cyber security
um
how do we talk about
a cyber attack in case especially in
case if we get one
how do we position ourselves is cyber
security only managers responsibility or
is it everybody's responsibility and
it's everybody's responsibility we do
tend to take a very human-centric
approach when it comes to this
the other services we offer legal advice
in terms of data protection and data
privacy uh marketing and design of
publications related to cyber security
issues or creating resources for these
ngos
to be able to access quickly and
implement them themselves easily and at
no cost whatsoever
now going back to what i said before
about the builders who are cyber
security experts employed by local or
international companies so these
builders they volunteer between 20 hours
to 40 hours a year to protect ngos
online
on the side of the ngos after we connect
with them we discuss what their needs
are then we create missions missions
that are listed on our cooperation
platform
the purpose of our cooperation platform
is twofold let's say
on one side it's for this humanitarian
ngo to have a safe space to be able to
share their experiences their worries
and to get the necessary help they need
but also on the other
is to ensure that the builders get
access to a community of professionals
they get access to training and they get
access to uh to concrete
help to improve their skills and to
maintain their certifications as well
now
just to give you a quick
overview of where we stand
we launched the program in october 2021
since then now we count more than 40
humanitarian ngos
uh to be more precise with you we have
around 44 right now uh from almost all
over the world actually um and uh this
far we managed to create 87 missions
out of which 52 are completed or about
to be completed
and um 35 are still open now new
missions are being added weekly um the
demand for this service it's for this
partnership actually it's it's big and
we're very happy to see that that uh it
it adds such a huge value to the work of
the humanitarian jobs
now
just to give you a quick overview of uh
the company supporting us
you will certainly recognize some of
them such as microsoft uh telefonica
probably logitech spelling team
and um here is what our ngos have to say
about us
now
um
we got these testimonials
at the end of each mission actually what
we do at the end of each mission is to
create a survey that we share to measure
satisfaction but also to see what we can
improve in the program
and these testimonials actually show the
added value and the impact of the
program and we are very happy to
continue to work with our beneficiaries
and to expand even more
now to be completely transparent with
you
the server piece builders is free for
ngos and it's going to stay free
but the program has fixed and various
costs and that is why we run on
philanthropic and corporate donations
from the companies that you have
previously seen practically the way it
goes these companies they do provide us
with financial support and also people
the builders when we um
when we look for builders these people
must have been working for the company
that we are talking to for at least a
year before being able to join the
program but when they join the program
they represent december peace builders
they they are a cyber peace builder
working for mentoring new jobs
um
that's
all on my side
um
i hope um it was it was clear and um i
am open to your questions thank you very
much for your attention and
awesome thank you so much for that
presentation i think nikos has just
dipped um but you do have some questions
in chat
so uh first question is what are the
first steps that ngos should do to be
more protected
well the first steps an ngo should do to
be more protected is to literally take
the time to invest in the training of
their staff
cyber security it's on one side about
technology and on the other it's about
people
and people are at the forefront
of most of the cyber security issues
ngoc counter
uh so what
so and humanitarian ngo the first thing
they can do is to really invest into
training people and developing their
security and protection
measures
awesome thank you so much and another
question just came in and it says
uh
also can anyone become a builder is that
like uh something that's open to the
public
uh as a matter of fact uh just as i
mentioned at the end of my presentation
um
well the person who like to become a
builder has to be employed by a company
and they must have been working for that
company for a year unfortunately we
cannot um we cannot work for the time
being with people who are self-employed
or working individually
um i hope that answers the question
that it does and someone else followed
up with what scope is there for people
to get involved
well
if people get involved into this program
let's say there are two benefits on one
side is the benefit of actually helping
humanitarian ngos working in different
fields in health education peace
and so on to actually strengthen their
cyber security posture
to improve their systems and then to be
able to deliver their critical services
to the vulnerable the vulnerable people
i i mentioned at the beginning of the
presentation and then secondly you see
the builders are not in a position just
to give
we designed this this program in such a
way that the builders yes they do give
time
um they do give their knowledge that we
give their expertise but in return there
is a community they can tap into they
can access a community a training um
training let's say on diversity and
inclusion on victimology on this whole
universe of humanitarian ngos and how um
how they work and how they operate so
there is another benefit and scope to
that
awesome thank you so much uh miss root
asks do you have to work specifically
for cyber security company for a year or
can it be like another company is there
any like uh
like leniency around that
uh there is there is a leniency for as
long as the job is actually in cyber so
it doesn't have to be necessarily a
technical job it can be on cyber but on
the marketing side on communications in
legal so we are open to
a lot of profiles because that's what
actually going to
make the whole experience that make the
whole program richer and to be able to
actually provide more more support and
help
awesome thank you
and um another question came in
which is what could convince ngos to get
more involved in cyber security training
any opinion um
well first of all ngos when when we talk
about cyber
the first reaction is what
so they they just don't know they they
they need to probably be more
uh exposed to the topic first of all
um probably uh um
they need to be first okay so first of
all they need to be more exposed to the
topic and the topic has to be maybe a
bit more bulgarized if that's the right
word to be more accessible to
these people working harmonious ngos who
just to give you an example we will work
with ngos who have five or six or ten
staff but they have no i.t person and
they
they realize cyber security it's a you
know it's a serious matter but they just
don't understand
and the way we do it on our side is to
make to have a very structured concrete
approach
that we explain things we don't just do
things without uh you know explaining
them and also we do it at the face of
ngo
um so i think to to answer the question
to sum it up it's very important to
render this field maybe a bit more
accessible to ngos and also to
that the industry invites ngos to
conferences to talks to to open a bit
you know the gates uh on both sides
yeah awesome thank you and then um yeah
another question has come in to look
back on the previous point can any kind
of ngo join
uh
yes so um the most
the most important criteria for us is
that the ngo
is uh delivering critical services it's
a humanitarian ngo
what does this mean
delivering critical services such as
health
nutrition education
peace
sometimes it's a bit difficult to
distinguish uh between maybe a charity
and a human ngo a charity probably works
more locally they do an amazing work and
it's it's it's very important why they
do but maybe they don't have that
international reach or they don't have
that critical services aspect to it
and that's why we focus right now only
for my own humanitarian ngos at the
beginning i hope i hope it answers the
question
definitely did thank you so much for
your time it was a fantastic
presentation
atomic any other closing remarks
i quite enjoyed it um
it's also quite uh quite fun you know
that we're literally like i think what
20 kilometers away from one another
so it's
pretty nice
one more last minute question came in
how can people support this project
well first of all people can start uh
sharing
the cyber peace builders on their social
media
in an individual capacity
start the conversation a bit about what
we're doing and how we're doing it and
then if
in terms of a company they would like to
join just drop us an email at assistance
cyberpsinstudio.org and then we can have
a discussion um see what we can put in
place and how you can support how they
can support the program um
and and and to help united ngos
thank you so much for this entire
presentation this was well put together
it's fantastic
many people loved it thank you for
answering the questions too
uh thank you very much it was great
having you here
yeah same for me and
great great conference thank you for
organizing it again
and yeah all the best to the next
speakers