thanks for that um yeah i just want to
before i even start say thanks to the
digital overdose um team for providing a
platform for us to have talks like this
and
to share my experience my first
physical ex
physical assessment experience as a
redeemer
so just a quick agenda what i would like
to go through like a quick overview
is i'm going to quickly tell you a
little bit about myself i don't i won't
waffle on about that too much i'll go
into what the assignment was actually
and then i'll explain the fishing and
the machine
that we performed on the client
the recon that i did of the premises how
i eventually gained access there and
then just a couple of mistakes
and listen so
mistake from my side and from the client
side and then obviously lessons from
both sides as well
so just a a little quick run through of
who i am i obtained my first dc
when
i was eight years old from there i
learned
too basic at when i was 11 years old
the first
you know so my first unofficial hack if
i can call it that and i call it
unofficial because there wasn't really
permission
granted or i called it a um
unofficial
unexpected penetration test which
resulted in me
taking over isp basically i was young i
was 13 at that age i mean
i'm sure
i won't get into trouble for mentioning
that
then due to my interest in computers
that i carried on
i started the it business at ages of 17
from there i carry on with the business
obtained my computer science degree
and then at some stage my
it business
transformed into a software development
house um and then recently i got into
ctf
with the with the hack south crew and
check them out on discord quite a nice
bunch of guys and then i eventually got
into my first official penetration
testing job so currently i'm employed as
a penetration tester slash red teamer at
checkmark cyber
i've over the last year now i've gone
through a bit of a spate of obtaining
certifications through offensive
security so i've gone got my own cpo set
o sweo said osc3 and i've also done the
pn
in pt from tcm security and also
recently faces from princess academy if
you're looking for me anywhere
chris meister basically on all of the
social media twitter linking wherever
i'm always open
me
um if you want to discuss anything um i
like i love discussing
um acting stuff with anybody and then
i've got a blog running
chrismeister.edu.io and you'll actually
find this whole
talk on the as well that i wrote down as
a blog post
a quick disclaimer i'm relatively new in
the official hacking scene
so i've been a hacker all my life but
officially only for a year and a bit now
so what i might be saying
might come across wrong
please i'm open to corrections anytime
that anybody has
perfections or suggestions and
whatever i say
go go and research do your own research
before you just accept what what i say
okay so getting into the actual talk so
the assignment that we got was a full
black box
um penetration test for the company
basically what that meant is they gave
us the company name and said go and test
the security see what we can do
so our goal
well first of all i was quite excited
for this i mean it took about what four
to five months for this to actually
materialize from hearing about the first
time
so i was quite excited when it
eventually came because
in our country i'm from south africa
there isn't a lot of opportunity for or
tests like this um just based on the
fact that it costs a lot and i've
actually spoken to a lot of penetration
testers after the fact
when i started sharing my story and a
lot of people are actually scared to go
and attend doing these things just based
on the um
the
our security guards and with the crime
rate in the country which is probably
not which is probably on par with the
rest of the world i just think maybe our
security guards are but figure out the
year so people are very
wary of attempting physical assessments
but anyway i was excited for it so our
goal
was that we
we had a feeling in the team that we
would
gain
full domain
control if we could just get access into
the internal network and we based this
on the fact that they haven't done even
a white optic test internal test before
so we knew there would probably be a lot
of opportunities for
us to be able to escalate our privileges
once we got onto the internal domain
so the goal was the main admin and in my
mind i wouldn't wouldn't accept anything
less
so then
so then yeah at the start of it we
started performing ocean on the company
um that meant going on to twitter going
onto linkedin finding employees of the
company starting to build email
email address lists
and employer lists trying to find the
interests and all that just so that we
had a base of
things that we can attack if we wanted
to
uh for example do fishing or wishing
which we ended up doing anyway but we
didn't need to do like a spirit that was
what abroad for all the tech that we
eventually did so anyway then we found
all the external facing infrastructure
did enumeration on it find found open
ports etc etc so we were looking for
like low-end food initially um i must
say i recommend this company they are
quite well secured in terms of the
external stuff
besides
one web application that i've found a
vulnerability in that allowed me to
purchase
airtime for a sim card and data
without actually paying for it so i was
able to
basically cost them money by
just loading vouchers onto my own sim
card
which comes into play a bit later so
besides for that we were quite happy
that the the internal infrastructure
sorry the external facing was quite good
so then we decided okay we now need to
to find a way to find credentials if we
can't get get through a vulnerability on
the external side so we decided to do
some fishing first and then fishing
after that
the fishing
uh we we had about 40 email addresses
from our ocean so
i went through my normal procedure of
what i do to set up a phishing campaign
we got everything set up i hit the same
button and not absolutely nothing
happened there wasn't a click and
nothing absolutely nothing
so i just left it for a couple of days
carried on with some of the external
testing and then i decided to just go
back and look at the logs and lo and
behold the at the exact time that i
clicked to send out permission there was
actually a problem with the mail server
so none of those emails went out
so that at least gave me a
little bit of a hope
and we sent through a second second
phase of the phishing attack and through
that i was actually able to
get a
one credential out of the people um
which was in it's it's normally enough
um normally i have a better strike rate
but anyway so we got this credential i
logged into the
email the first thing i started looking
for was the nd dells which i found
but unfortunately they had to form
two form factor
um available i've activated on those
accounts so i couldn't i couldn't log in
without that
two formal authentication
pin code that would be sent to their
cell phone
so i sort of gave up on that idea
i found a lot of usernames and passwords
that would be connected to external
services that they make use of which we
didn't touch because that was obviously
not within the scope
then i also noticed that the i.t
department
detected our phishing attack because
they sent out the email to the whole
company and say there's a phishing
attack happening if you're if you
clicked on the link provided your
credentials contact the i.t department
so that your password can get reset
so i just quickly deleted it out of this
user's email box and they weren't aware
that something had happened
and
thank goodness for that because i could
until the end of the engagement these
credentials
stayed active and i could use them and i
actually use them eventually to do
the final takeover of the domain
then okay so with the
fishing being successful for us we
decided to go into the vision
would be that's basically doing phishing
through the
um using telephones
so
you would phone up the
people
try and get them to give you some sort
of info this was the very first time
that i've had to do something like this
so
i struggled for a couple of days to just
like wrap my head around okay what is
the end goal going to be
when you do this vision what do i need
from it
eventually i decide okay you know what i
can't wait any longer so i decided to
just start phoning up the branches of
the company and sort of just see what
happens
to add insult to injury i made use of
the
vouchers for the sim card that i
actually was able to pull off their site
that i didn't pay for and i used that to
to phone them so we were making use of
their own infrastructure not
infrastructure their own money if i can
call it them to phone them and wishing
them
so
my first attempt at that i phoned up
said listen i'm x from head office id i
just need to speak to someone about
computers
um we're seeing that the antivirus isn't
updating and we're just worried that
something is going to happen
and you're going to lose all your data
so i'm trying to prevent that
and the the first lady that i spoke to
she was quite happy to
give me anything that i need from her i
got passwords from her i was able to get
her to run commands on her pc because i
was trying to do rebound to see all the
computers connected to the internet
which they weren't
um but based on the proxy
message that was coming up i thought
maybe it was just a proxy setting that
would need to be set up because i need
to needed to gain info on what i could
expect when i actually gained access
physical access to the to the offices
and from from
the discussion with her and a couple of
other stores that i found with a sort of
similar script i was able to determine
that they had a
a password pattern full of that so
they would so i would easily be able to
guess if someone gave me a username i
would able to sort of figure out what
their password would be and it turned
out the administrator password said the
same pattern
just a side note on that i actually
still feel quite bad about it uh one
lady actually had a genuine i.t problem
thinking that i'm from haiti and i told
her that there would be someone that
comes could come out to the premises to
come and sort it out so i do hope that
someone did come and sort it out
otherwise she still still has an issue
there um
the commands that i had the people run
it was typical ping come on that would
sharper error and
that just let me
gave me the opportunity to say okay
listen something is wrong on your
computer we're gonna send out a local
guide to coming out because we don't we
obviously don't fly someone down from
where we are from your office so just
expect someone and
um yeah that gave me the
opportunity to to
have a
story of when i actually go go there so
the first
time that i
decided to go to one of the stores i
just went to go and do some recon just
to see what is in the store i needed to
see what type of security they've got
how
vigilant are they
how do they secure the security interact
with the clients of the store how busy
is the store what are the where are the
high value areas and the areas of the
computers and the servers and that
so i needed to establish all that
and again i just went to the store open
mind
pretended i'm
one of the shoppers there got a trolley
walk through the place
so the the
things that i noticed they were like the
security guard was more interested in
checking that the people are wearing
mosques and sanitizing there's a store
in the
cover times
and then you would randomly check people
that went out the store they would
actually use like search their handbags
and whatever backpacks and things that
they had there was cctv all over i
didn't know if someone was sitting
monitoring them
there was a vacant network jack that i
found
that actually had a power source
close by as well so that provided
perfect opportunity for me to to build
and test
at dropbox for the first time dropbox is
just a little computer and i mean it's
as big as a cell phone that you can plug
into the network have access to
and from there you could basically be
connected to their network to do
enumeration and try and
compromise them
so i also found where the offices were i
saw that there's no like physical
barrier to enter the offices to get to
the server room so i could see them see
all of that through the corridor leading
into the office
so
having gotten all the infra that i
needed to and i've already formulated
the exact plan that i was gonna do when
i go there
i headed back to the office and started
preparing
my little tools so i built a little fire
box with um kelly on there as a dropbox
you look on my blog
page you'll see uh website you'll see
that i actually wrote what a detailed
article on how i bought the box
and on exhalt i actually did talk and
explain to you guys how i do it so
um have a look there um i'm happy to
also get suggestions if you guys have
any um
comments or suggestions on that for me
so then i also added like a usb drive
that i loaded up some tools like mini
cats um built a custom reverse shell
that had antibodies bypassing in case i
could get a pc with an uh internet
connection that i could call that the cq
server
and just a bunch of enumeration tools
just a side note like if you ever do
this just zip up the
the tools with the password because
otherwise as soon as you plug in any
defender or any antivirus is gonna pick
it up and kill kill your tools and then
you sit there with anything without
anything then i'll just add like other
random stuff with me as well usb
charging cable i had another laptop that
i had cali on that was set up to connect
to the dropbox file wi-fi and i even had
kelly on a lock and a live galley on a
usb drive in case i could plug in and
then from my old ip business i still had
my company id badge which clearly
indicated that i'm an iq support person
so i made sure
i wore that
that day
funny thing is um i was taking my kid to
school that morning having breast
already and even he noticed that oh
something something is different because
i'm not he's not used to seeing me in
jeans and then button up shirt and
things like that so and then i explained
to you the five year old what i'm going
to go and do so
i'm
quite
i was quite interested afterwards when
you kept on asking me about because i
explained to him we're gonna go and try
and see if we can access the people's
bank account that was the easiest way
for me to explain to you and afterwards
the afternoon he wanted to do
when he was he saw that i was sitting on
the computer he wanted to come and sit
you want me to show him okay
how can i see the people's bank
statements for example
so yeah it was quite interesting the way
that he grasped that
okay then okay so the first time that i
actually went to the store with all my
tools and okay i'm gonna i'm gonna do
this now
i
stopped there i thought i was relatively
gone as i was walking up to the door
like a million things ran through my
head that could go wrong
and
it's a good time to note that during
these assessments you normally have a
what they call a get out of jail free
card which is a letter from the company
to say
this guy has permission to do what he
does if he does get caught then call the
cops call this guy we will
confirm your old story
four reasons that i can't go into now we
didn't have this in place yet but we
were running out of time for the
assessment but we did oh we obviously
had the position we just didn't have
that official later so i took a bit of a
gamble and decided okay
hopefully i don't end off in the cop
shop
today
as i got to the security guard
my mind was completely clear and i was
relaxed i just had told myself just just
pick him that you belong here i went up
to him i greeted him i
explained to him who i was what i was
doing there and i asked him if he could
point in the direction of the
of the offices which he was happy to do
and i think that that was the important
step for me because i want i didn't want
the security guard to wonder later on
who is this guy what is he doing that
are you i wanted him to know exactly
this is why i'm there
and don't even worry about asking me
again
so
as i walk through the offices i had
another little brainwave i thought lego
just pretend that i'm on the phone with
the ita office
and i pretend that i'm speaking to
someone um i did it loud enough so that
anybody within earshot could hear me and
i just said listen okay i just got here
i'm going to see what's going on uh give
me 15 20 minutes i'll find you back now
at the u.s site report to say what we
can do to fix the problem and that
little
trick worked because
i hadn't even pretended to put the phone
down and the lady came out of her office
and said oh are you that it guy that the
i was already in no one had any
suspicion of me i was i could walk into
any of the offices
um like just just abandon things that
caught my attention in people's handbags
cell phones everything was lying all
over i could have easily if i were if i
were a malicious person i've caused some
financial damage there go by stealing
stuff
okay so anyway i was part of the
furniture there and they let me into the
server room the server room is just a
little a little
small little room that looked like it's
actually supposed to be for like storage
of
cleaning products and things like that
the
handle wasn't even a proper handle it
was a broken angle so i could get in
there to the server access everything i
could close the door behind me side full
privacy to do what i wanted to do
i got
my dropbox out connected to the network
that worked perfectly i could access it
from our laptop i could access it from
our sorry not yet from our c2 server so
the first little hurdle that i had to
cross there is that there was no dhcp
on a small hurdle so i just had to set
up a static item but then i realized
okay but there's no
in internet i can't access the internet
from that
network sub
subnet
i tested for
proxy servers couldn't find anything
so
the dropbox idea wasn't going to work so
i tried the tools um mini cats don't
want people because they were running
windows 2000 windows server 2003 and xp
so the version i had was for later
versions
um
so but
bonuses for me is that
all the workstations were locked in as
admin
local admin users the server was logged
in as an administrator not locked so i
could see stuff on the server but even
from the server i couldn't access
access the internet so i decided okay
when an hour passed i thought okay that
was my limit let me get out here go and
regroup see what i can do
to come back and and get to get a bit
more success i went back to the office
brainstormed a bit
realized okay let me just put a
3g connection
on my dropbox as well so that would
connect the dropbox directly to the
internet connect to our c2 servers and
let me allow it to do everything that i
wanted to do initially so i was quite
annoyed with myself for not thinking
about that the first time
anyway so i went back
this time when i walked into uh onto
their premises we had cash and transit
guys that were busy loading money from
the atm
so that was quite a
a little bit of a scare thing and seeing
these people with guns and all that
so
again i had permission to be there but
for me
guys like that um
in our country they get targeted quite
often if not daily so i i knew these
guys would also be
quite sensitive to anybody acting
strange around me so i had to once again
tell myself okay calm down walk past
them don't even
think about it just just get get through
it
so yes i got into the property no one
shot me uh
went straight to the
to the manager again told her that's not
back i think i've got a
solution to the problem now
so got back into the server room
connected to dropbox tested that the 3g
is working all the connections that were
perfectly
tested from our c2 server okay i thought
that was it i walked and walked out got
back to our office connected to the
dropbox great i could still connect to
it started enumeration and basically the
box died without within a couple of
minutes of demolition and i realized the
heat that i felt in that little room
that day was affecting the dropbox and
obviously
freezing it up
so then i was i was super annoyed it was
hot i didn't want to go there again but
i just just decided okay listen ah they
have given me free rain there now i'm
just gonna set up a spa laptop that i've
got and use that as my dropbox then i
went out for heat issues i've got a nice
powerful machine there
so set it up i went there
again just told the lady i've come back
doing xyz
went into the server room hooked this
thing up and it just tested everything
is working got back to the to
our office i was able to connect and
start doing enumeration and everything
was working perfectly
so then i was able to
see that the their network is actually
connected throughout the country to all
the branches i could access their head
office i could access absolutely
everything
so i was able to make use of kerberos
attack and and the old me17 exploit to
actually just take over the the whole
network there so that was a success so
just a a summary of like
mistakes i assumed that there was going
to be an internet connection there
wasn't i built a failover but the
failover just wasn't enough i didn't
take into account the heat even though i
felt it it should have registered with
me this little device isn't going to
work and then eventually i just decided
to think big get a laptop in there get a
proper computer and make sure i've got
all the connections and everything
running and yeah that that gave a
success at the end of the day
then just the lessons that i learned
quickly is
i just be prepared for any anything try
and roll with it don't get too upset sit
with it and just also just
act like you belong at the place
and then just a main thing that i can
maybe do to companies to prevent
something like this is the segmentation
of the network make sure that one
computer one computer on a network that
is compromised can't access your your
whole network and then provide training
for for staff um
ongoing training about the physical
threat to the
experience at the offices training about
their fishing
uh trading but train them about fishing
and all that
so yeah that's that's my talk um
thank you guys for listening if there's
any questions or anything like that
please feel free to ask me i'm always
open on social medias
awesome that was a really fun talk
uh
someone actually remarked uh that was
kind of funny you know when you said i
was a good engagement because i didn't
get shot
that's a good one
anytime that you don't get shocked and
you engage with this good
yeah
i mean you
does this often happen that you have
like a similar consideration like you go
somewhere you're like i hope i don't get
shot today
well let me tell you
we went through a split of a lot of
these caching transit hijackings taking
place in our country and locally even so
whenever we at a shopping center and you
see these guys walk through they it does
play on your mind so that's why there's
even more people than building that
engagement for me that i'm sort of doing
something illegal here now
i don't want these guys to be nervous
around
and with and i understand why because
they you know they're not the the best
paid people and they do what
right
let's see if there's any questions in
chat
um
not that much um right
so when you introduce yourself to the
security guard did you introduce
yourself as a pentester did you
introduce yourself as someone who is
here to you know uh
perform some operations
oh yeah okay or maybe i wasn't too clear
on that yes
my whole persona there was i was i t
support person that had opposite
subcontracted down to me
so anything that i did i'm united like i
said my old
i.t support
company i had the badge there that save
computer services with my name and
everything on there so
yeah no i didn't go in there and say
there's no
i'm here to hack you
yeah
i don't think they
understood if i said that i might still
have gained access
i don't think it would have raised too
many questions
awesome
what uh
i believe that concludes
uh yeah the time for this talk
someone mentioned in chat that most
americans can relate to not getting shot
as a born and raised american myself i
can tell you that resonated personally
with me
um
when i started sharing the story and
they are all of their opinion as well
that they do not like the physical side
of them and if they can they actually
won't do it and that's i think that's
why there's a lot
there isn't a lot of opportunity for for
engagements like this i mean i've been
with it now for just over a year with
this company and it's the first time
that the opportunity like this has arose
and i don't think opportunity like this
will come up very soon