hello my name is jennifer gomez i am a
cyber threat intelligence analyst at
bechtel corporation through my career as
an analyst i have mostly worked job
fraud cases but i've had the opportunity
to work on some very interesting other
types of fraud such as romance fraud
so today i'm going to talk about romance
fraud and it's recently been gaining a
lot of attention it has a lot of people
asking the question what is romance
fraud
so well okay
sorry
today i'm going to take you on a journey
of romance fraud from beginning to end
we're going to discuss all the stages of
the fraud what preventative steps can be
taken to avoid falling victim to romance
fraud and how romance fraud can affect
your company's brand and reputation
so as i mentioned there's been a lot of
attention on romance fraud with
documentaries popping up on several
different networks such as netflix
showtime national geographic and that's
just to name a few there's several
others out there some of them showcase
in real life romance fraud where the
target actually meets the fraudster in
person
they build a relationship sometimes they
even get engaged or get married and the
other type is where you get to take a
look at the romance fraud from the mind
of the criminal
now on this slide i've highlighted three
of my favorite documentaries on romance
fraud
if you haven't seen them you should
check them out
so i'd like to start with the definition
what is romance fraud
romance fraud is a fraudulent scheme in
which a threat actor pretends to have a
romantic interest in a target
establishes a relationship and then
attempts to collect money or sensitive
information from the target under false
pretenses
so next we're going to take a look at
the fbi's internet crimes annual report
data as you can see here
this has grown significantly over the
past few years
with 2021 accounting for over one oh
just under 1 billion dollars in
financial loss which is approximately
thirty nine thousand dollars per
individual
so as you know as you can see and this
is just what's reported because as with
a lot of fraud
it's not always reported sometimes
people are embarrassed or ashamed that
they felt victim to the fraud or they
just think it's not going to matter
anyhow it they're not going to get their
money back or you know it's not worth
their time but whatever the mat whatever
the reason is that they don't report it
either way these numbers are staggering
so next we're going to take a look at
the stages that i've identified in my
investigations
so it starts with that developing a
persona
who they want to be this time picking a
career creating their social media
presence selecting the images they want
to use and then they develop their story
then they go live
they look for their target on social
media sites maybe dating sites possibly
looking for individuals with profiles
that say that they're divorced or
widowed and once they identify their
target
they send a message
and they just wait for a response
once they've connected they try to get
to know their victim they want to learn
as much as possible retaining any
information that can be leveraged later
on
they try to get they try to start the
relationship and build a trust with
their victim
let me tell their story lie after lie
possibly a sob story about their family
or losing their partner tragically
whatever they think will gain the
sympathy of their victim
once the relationship has been
established and the trust has been
established the financial requests begin
and they're always extremely urgent
usually they start small
and if their victim starts to make the
payments then they increase in value and
the actor will do whatever it takes to
convince the victim to come up with this
money
so the victim does whatever it takes
pulls to pull this money together to
make these payments
and at some point the victim does begin
to doubt the requests being made they
start asking more and more questions
they start searching for answers answers
which usually will lead to the discovery
of the fraud
so as i told you in the beginning i'm
going to take you on the journey of a
romance fraud case from beginning to end
this is an investigation i recently
worked and it gave us a lot of
information about how the fraud is
carried out
it also shows us how quickly this type
of fraud progresses because it takes
place within a time frame of just under
two months
so now we're going to take a look at the
involved parties
the actor was a wealthy american widower
who was an engineer working on a project
overseas
he claimed that he had two children
still living in the u.s but no other
family
the victim was a recently divorced
individual who was seeking a
relationship online
so our story begins with a connection
made on social media the conversation
begins with small talk it's exactly what
you would expect of two people who are
just getting to know one another however
the infatuation builds very quickly
and you start to see the actors saying
things like i think you're the one for
me or that they hope that this develops
into a serious relationship
now it only takes one day but several
hours of conversation but just one day
for the actor to claim to be falling in
love with the victim
and the victim does seem very receptive
to the actors advances and compliments
but shows that they're a bit reserved
and guarded
because they don't want to be heard
again
the actor uses all of this information
to further guide the conversation
and gain the trust of their victim
so the conversation continues for a few
more days and at this point they're both
proclaiming their love for one another
they're discussing their future plans to
be married where they're going to live
what a wonderful life and a beautiful
family they're going to have together
at one point you see there's a shift in
the conversation from mine to hours and
finally they begin discussing sharing
finances and who's going to pay the
bills once they get married now this is
only day two of their conversations
a couple more days pass by
and you see another change in the
conversation the courtship phase has
ended and they now are in a full-blown
relationship and at this point the two
have only been talking for four days
shortly thereafter the first financial
request comes in and of course it's
extremely urgent
there's an emergency that requires a
payment and the actors having banking
issues
now remember the actor is wealthy
however the actors having trouble
accessing their funds because of the
location that they're working on the
actor assures the victim the money would
be paid back by the end of the month
this victim is not in a position to be
helping out anyone financially but the
victim borrows money from family to make
the payment
this continues on and on and the
financial requests come in and each one
is greater than the last
so you might ask yourself how does this
progress so quickly how does this happen
well these actors are masters of their
craft they find ways to convince the
victim how much adoration they have for
them they make them feel special and
safe they use endearing terms like honey
darling my love sweetie
they make them feel safe and secure it's
all part of their grooming process once
they have their victim hooked that's
when the conversation begins to change
and the actor shifts gears into the
financial requests
once the money starts coming in a new
urgent situation will arise every couple
of days
when the victim does become suspicious
or ask for something to reassure them
that this is a legitimate relationship
or
a real person the actor will provide
family photos pictures of themselves at
work or at restaurants or even exploring
in the country that they're working in
all in an attempt to prove to the victim
that they are who they say they are if
the victim
continues to be suspicious of the
financial requests that are coming in or
asks for some sort of tangible proof
that some money is due
the actor will provide falsified
documents or bills whatever the victim
is asking for whatever it's going to
take to continue this fraud
finally after almost two months the
victim began to investigate calling all
the places that the payments were going
to
gathering as much information as
possible and finally reached out to our
company to see if the actor was an
employee working on a project
so once we confirmed that this was not
an employee of our company nor had they
ever been the realization set in for the
victim that they had been defrauded
the embarrassment there was fear and
panic that now i'm going to be stuck
with all of this debt
and it was really unfortunate for this
victim because
this victim did have the instinct to do
research and investigate but it just
came too late it was after the victim
had already incurred a significant
financial loss of tens of thousands of
dollars
so most people think i would never fall
for this it could never happen to me
victim shaming happens all too often in
this arena
but this victim did question everything
this victim appeared to be very
intelligent and logical asking all the
right questions
but remember this is what the actor does
they purposely seek out individuals who
are emotionally vulnerable they use a
very high pressure tactic
matters of extreme urgency if this
payment isn't received something
catastrophic is going to happen
they don't give the victim time to think
or make logical or informed decisions it
has to happen now
another tactic used by the actor is
guilt
if you don't make this payment and this
catastrophic event happens
can you live with that it'll be your
fault
so with these different tactics the
actors able to convince the victim over
and over again
to make the payments
the victim as i said was not in a
financial position to help anyone out
but this this victim borrowed money from
family took out bank loans
used money intended to pay their own
bills and support their own family all
in order to pay the requests that were
being made by the actor all along going
further and further into debt
to help the person that they thought
they loved that they thought they were
going to be married to
all with the assurance that they were
going to be paid back
so next we're going to talk about what
the victim could have done to protect
themselves before engaging with the
actor
so put your dating cap on for a minute
oops i think i went too far
oh i lost my way
okay sorry about that
so put your dating cap on for a minute
and ask yourself what could i have done
to protect myself in this situation
if the victim's social media accounts
had stricter privacy settings the actor
would have had a more difficult time
finding them on social media the victim
could have been more cautious about who
they
chose to connect to and could have done
some research
before engaging in conversation
now once they were connected the victim
could have continued with that guarded
mindset and done continued to do
research as new information from the
actor came in there were several warning
signs that at first the victim seemed to
ignore
this was
the perfect match the perfect person in
every way shape or form and usually if
it seems too good to be true it probably
is
they were unable to have phone or video
conversations now these were all
explained away
but
it was still suspicious
and it was it was overlooked
but the biggest red flag of all was how
quickly that this
romance progressed and also the
financial requests coming in
the victim could have taken some of the
images that were provided by the actor
and done a quick google image search and
would have found that the images that
were being provided were that of a
public figure
now the victim did do this eventually
however it was after the
financial loss had already been incurred
so next we're going to discuss the
impact romance fraud can have on your
company's brand and reputation
why would the actor claim to work for a
particular company why do we care and
what can we do about it
so we see quite a bit of romance fraud
reported and it's all by individuals who
are inquiring about their friend does
their friend work for our company and
the first question i hear is why would
somebody pretend to work for your
company
well bechdel's a reputable construction
and engineering company with projects
all over the world so this makes it easy
for the actor for a couple of reasons
first it explains why they can't meet in
person
it explains why they might be working on
a remote project with spotty wi-fi so
they can't have face time conversations
they don't have cell service so they
can't have phone conversations
and the second thing that it does is it
provides the actor with a sense of
stability and security with a good
career
and this is enticing to the victim the
victim as i said before was an
emotionally vulnerable person who was
looking for love it's emotion over logic
so they're always going to be very
enticed enticing
so sometimes the actor would even
provide falsified documents on company
letterhead
um
counterfeit badges to prove that they
were that they worked for our company
sometimes their social media profiles
would indicate that they work for our
company or they might even provide an
email address that's
impersonation email address
so what can be done
once we verify that it is in fact fraud
and this person was not an employee of
our company nor have they ever been we
instruct the
victim to cease communications with them
immediately
we tell them to report it to their local
law enforcement if they feel that
they've been a victim of a crime and
then we encourage them to file an
internet crimes report with the fbi
and if they are unsure of how to do that
we would in some instances we would
assist them with that
then we gather as much information as we
can to build our brand abuse case we
document all of our findings we conduct
research we read through any
conversations that are provided to us by
the victim we're always looking for a
connection to our company
we search at the after social media
profiles we do google reverse image
searches on the images that are provided
and look for any actionable items and if
there is actionable items we work with a
third-party company to disable the
adversary infrastructure
so we're nearing the end here and i
wanted to cover just a couple of other
things the proactive measures that can
be taken to protect your brand and why
that's important
impersonation of your brand can affect
so many areas of your business from
business development to your industry
reputation which can affect winning
contracts or bids really can affect your
revenue and that's why it's imperative
to protect your brand at all costs so
these are a couple of things that can be
done to help with this effort
create a group for this purpose
identify a group of key players within
your organization who can meet regularly
to discuss fraudulent practices that are
affecting your brand
it's a really good idea to ensure that
this group is made up of members that
have varying backgrounds this way each
person can contribute by providing
guidance and input in their area of
expertise
additionally if at all possible
it's a good idea to allocate budget to
outsource the monitoring and disabling
of fraudulent infrastructure to a brand
protection company
brand protection companies can work to
disable fake email addresses remove your
company's information from social media
profiles sometimes they can even
completely have social media profiles
disabled
but brand protection companies do come
in many different shapes and sizes so
you absolutely want to do your due
diligence to ensure that you're picking
the correct company that fits your needs
so the last thing that i wanted to cover
was a couple of high profile arrests
that were made in 2021 now as we saw in
the beginning of the presentation the
slide with the
stats
this is an increasing problem it's
gained the attention of hollywood with
the documentaries and it's also gained
the attention of law enforcement
the first case i'd like to highlight was
from september of 2021
33 individuals were arrested across
texas they were part of black acts which
is a transitional organized crime
syndicate originating in nigeria but
they operate worldwide
authorities stated they engaged in a
wide range of fraudulent schemes such as
business email compromise investor scams
and unemployment insurance fraud and
online romance scams
there was 17 million dollars in
financial loss and over 100
victims the second one i'd like to
highlight happened a month later in
october of 2021 eight nigerian men were
arrested in a decade-long scam that
swindled seven million dollars from
their victims
this was also linked to the arrest made
in september of 2021 and the black acts
organized crime syndicate
so as we can see this is a growing
problem
but it is getting the attention of law
enforcement and there is action being
taken
so as i'm closing out here this slide
i've provided links to some of the
resources that i mentioned throughout
the presentation
that's all i have for you today i hope
you have found this to be informative
interesting and enjoyable
are there any questions
there are indeed
um
uh
right so actually i had a question for
you
um and
i'll get a sec i should just load yes
um so
the
engaging in one of these scams does
require you to know
how someone from a certain country would
speak
for example or the country you would be
impersonating from
and
is it more frequent for these actors to
be in the same region as their
you victims in the cases that i can only
speak obviously to the cases that i've
worked um they generally
claim to be in the same region
but i would say from victim to
actor no
okay
awesome i also i had a question myself
um
so on instagram there's often a lot of
sugar daddy and sugar baby scams
is this considered romance fraud as well
well i guess it would depend on how that
went down i mean i i think that it could
be considered romance if there's a theft
of
personal information or a theft of money
of some sort without any
i mean if you have a sugar daddy sending
gifts over that could be a whole
different situation
but you know i think that it it comes
that down to uh is there lies being told
in order to gain the finances or
personal information of the victim
awesome thank you yeah that makes sense
nicos any other questions
uh i don't have any and i've not seen
one in chat
so
that
that's pretty much it i think
uh yes there is another question it
looks like
um it says does internal teams work with
brand protection organizations or does
the partner organization handle most of
the work
um i'm sorry could you repeat that one
more time sure and i'll slow down too
okay
does internal teams work with brand
protection organizations or does the
partner organization handle most of the
work
um the internal team we work we work
directly with our brand protection
company
we meet with them monthly to go over
any
anything they see that they monitored
for uh we so we work direct and then we
work with them on takedowns when we're
working our cases if there is any
actionable items
awesome all right
thank you so much sorry that i speak so
fast by the way okay i feel like i kind
of speaking pretty fast too
it's all the the conference jitters
everyone's got him except for nicos he's
just got the caffeine jitters from those
nine coffees he drank
uh guilty
right well uh unless someone else has
questions i think we can close it up
yeah that looks good yeah
thank you so much jennifer your
your presentation was fantastic i've
learned something new today
well thank you so much for having me i
appreciate i appreciate it
really fun and enjoyable