hey
great to meet everyone i cannot see
everyone but just say hi to everyone and
uh thanks for uh
digital over those provide this
fantastic opportunity thanks for the
organizer for your efforts
i'm peter lowe i'm the the uh
i'm the co-founder of deton me and
i used to be to be the
lead security analysis for microsoft
offices five where we predicted hundreds
of thousands of
exchange servers sharepoint servers and
onedrive servers
uh i got my phd in computer science um
so today i'm going to talk about the
security automation which is loaded raid
uh if you don't know the red and you can
quickly google search it
it's a very popular uh no code
automation platforms and we are
basically embossed
[Music]
so here's a
here's a rough agenda um
so i'll talk about a couple of use cases
that we
we had in manchester operation centers
and work with
different teams on managers of secure
operation centers
and uh later i'll talk about the high
level overview of node raid and i will
i'd love to give a demo i will i will
provide a couple of demos interactive
demos to show how how it works and uh
and then we can deep dive a little bit
into little red it has been
lots of features but i will i'll try to
provide a comprehensive these features
that we think i
that will get you get started with with
notary
um feel free to ask any questions if
there's any channel um i look i look
forward to interact with everyone in the
uh
in the room
um
so um
so i'm i'm a determining guy i'm so uh
so i i'm i'm more focused on how to how
do you run defense how to run data
operations of course there are lots of
things we can do on the rating side uh
but here i think the uh these are the
tasks like we are seeing very common in
the uh in the blue team
um
so for example like uh we have been uh
looking at like how to monitor the dark
web right if you if you uh
if you come across best ping you can
cross ad hoc uir you will always want to
look for you look for to monitor those
kind of
data exchange uh in those kind of
website and see if there's kind of
things relevant to your companies
um uh i've been doing this kind of
insulin response every time i have
insulin response i always want to enrich
our enrich the informations right like
the original ibs which
um you racially threaten intelligence i
always want to
learn lots of tedious works right like
if there's a email phishing email my
analyzing i always want to
parse those kind of emails if there's
any kind of communications i always need
to write emails to address different
things different dlps different
different phishing scenarios um so
there's i mean the uh
we are used to working microsoft and the
way like we deal with otherwise we have
to write down all those kind of steps in
the in one note we love one note by the
way uh we have to write all those kind
of steps and we have to do all this and
those kind of things manually um
and um
uh compliance and audience is always
well
takes time consuming it's always like a
takes lots of our efforts to
differentiate them
so especially in this kind of cloud a
year there's uh when you have users when
you manage like thousands of hundred
thousand users you want to
uh autism you want to make sure every
every user has the right password policy
you want to make sure every user have
the part uh have the right mfa enabled
you want to make sure the password
was
designed to rule out every three months
or those kind of things there are lots
of policies you want to make sure they
they they are they are strongly enforced
um and you and i don't want you to learn
manila
i i i
i i it's it's going it's it's probably
impossible to deliver newly um
let's talk about the security controls
let's talk about like a dlp
verifications let's talk about this kind
of email phishing uh training
simulations right and so
um you want to make sure those kind of
the ap are always uncontrolled you
always want to make sure whenever
there's a phishing and your system was
able uh
your system will design to catch it you
should be able to catch it and you
should always make sure that your secure
system is secured as you expected um you
know administration so we have been as
as as a stock team like we have you
manage different software's like even
like a small companies you have uh for
example you have a uh
we like you have new users
it's very new employees right you have a
you need to assign them to different
systems right uh different software
different tools for example your team
using the sims you are two teams you're
using like microsoft offices five
defenders if that team is using like uh
uh
using um uh using like uh maybe like
virus totals you need to assign those
kind of people uh into those kind of uh
uh
system granular permissions right and
you play limitless teams you always want
to make sure they they got off uh
completely from your systems they got to
cut out from systems completely so as a
as i was managing team i always feel
like dd is like i have to
manually add everyone i mean i have i
have a checklist i have to go through uh
this is a google data this is a google
this is the g suite uh this is like uh
uh this is like a developer tools like
bit bucket or something i go through
every tools and add them one by one uh
so this is not my main job to as
a blue team
my main focus should be focused on the
the different people rather than like
managing those kind of data tasks about
reporting right reporting uh
i mean security is a lot of aspects of
the building that's super important um
um better one one very important thing
maybe not a relevant to uh how you
defended people but this is a relevant
to how you uh getting your funding
getting getting you guys funded from
your upper management how to get
uh get a visibility across your
organizations how to get availability
across the
world across community right the
reporting so as we have mentioned using
different tools edr tools in er tools
you are using vulnerabilities and
lots of details in the security
university teams and that as i know like
elixir teams and every security people
security analysis has to deal with lots
of things but uh
no matter how complicated like why we
need to be able to like uh create a nice
report using like popular power bi tools
uh popular like data data uh data and
that analysis tools like power bi like
do their studio or whatever uh to
showcase to uh to all others to sell
what you have been doing you can
communicate the values that you have
been uh working on to them i mean those
kind of things it takes time uh it's not
it's taking this takes away time like
for us to focus on how to uh better
detect how to better respond to those
kind of
issues
and
what if we can ultimately i mean not a
lot unless you automate everything but
what if we can quickly ultimately
as much as possible so that we can focus
on the most important things i mean
automation is a
important task and then one thing when
we talk about automation i mean probably
everyone can talk about like
uh using like a uh writing writing code
right writing python script codes or
those kind of things i think i think
it's doable i mean like using bachelor
scripts or using a powershell scripts
using uh uh using whatever scripts uh
you know python script or whatever you
you like it right i mean it's doable i
think i think the chinese there is that
uh
there's uh um
let's definitely time consuming and
they're definitely lots of these lots of
things it's time for me there definitely
is a lot of uh there's a little bit more
skills right you have to learn how to do
programming uh
and write programming is not as
it's not a it's a fun stuff but it's not
like the most the easiest job for
everyone to do um there are different
challenges to get things right right um
um
uh uh plus like unless you if you write
code you have to you have to maintain it
right you have to make sure it's always
right side runs correctly um so there's
a lot of challenges like doing this
writing uh scripts uh uh but i think as
as um as a from the education point of
view i do encourage everyone to uh to
write or to write to learn how to write
programming uh
but now we have
we possibly have a better tools like uh
like enable you to write less code not
like a it is a little bit ambitious to
say no code but
but we will
with the help of the community with the
help of the uh um
of the technology probably you can write
this code i mean this is a this we find
already which is open source uh
uh uh open source automation tools uh so
no real was meant for like uh
iot iot automation i mean it has been
there for like over 10 years over 10
years it has a lot large pop large
community it's already have 33 more than
3 thousand integrations and people are
actively contributing to you due to this
kind of tools
um
from what we see is that so it's brought
the best editing you have flow editing
you have the you can get the flow you
can
i'll show you guys in demo in a couple
of minutes very
engine on high level you have a browser
level um
flow editing and it's built on node.js
based on their popular even loop
architecture
so and it's easily shareable with with
between different teams between
different
uh and contributed by community so you
can you can leverage whatever uh it's
already there
um
so
this is a little high level overview of
the of the of the way that you have all
these kind of
uh integrations on the left side and
that you have uh you have a you have
your
your lovely canvas where you can create
your automations and you can have a you
can create your automations from here
and you have you can have a detailed
instructions like what's input what's
output and how to use these kind of
integrations and you have you have menu
you can manually kind of work those
um okay speaking with that i think i'll
just quickly uh quickly get you a demo
uh uh to just to should let you guys
know
what i'm talking about here
um
can you see my
see my
browser
yeah okay great so this is a quick
example so let's say like we i want to
do some
uh
so on the left side there's a bunch of
functional integrations with different
subsequent tools us
let's say
let's say aws let's say arju claustra
crosstrack
uh
hybrid analysis uh jira those kind of
things
so
what i'm showing here is uh is this
canvas uh so what i'm doing here is that
i basically uh showing you i i include
an ip ip is called is a google defaulter
d4ip 8.8.8.8
and i want to go through a a note that
we call like ipg
uh fpga uh
information like at least one is
basically a parcel
parser ip uh and extract elective
information and then
i'm going to show you how to uh when i
run this one you will see the geo
information get outputted
uh on the right side so you can see
i uh basically at least take the input
of the 8.81 and then go through the go
through the the building integrations
and give you the information about this
ip versus what's the geo information of
this one
um
so this is a
a quick example of the geo i mean
there's lots of things we can do with
eyepiece for example especially in your
investigations right like you go to 3g
you go to survivor total you go to
through hyper analysis you go through
maybe essence you go through
um
abuse abuse ipdb right i mean lots of
things i can kind of quickly get like a
setup let's say let's just say let's put
your verse photo
and uh
and let's say
this one and
then uh
and uh for versus though you want to get
a versatile uh key right and you can get
a free premium uh version of keys
and keep yourself and then you can run
it and it will automatically create a
rush total
give you information about this these
ips has been detected
and who what are the engines are you
detected and who is the owners what's
the resolutions uh
so and so forth
all the hosts like result to this ips
let's say let's say i want to go to
abuse ipdb and i can go to abuse ivdb
and then i can
go to this one
so you see like it's give you errors
like api keys is not existed so i need
to make sure i have api
key here
uh so you can just go through uh abuse
ibdb and it's give you all the
information from uh builds ipdb give you
the hostname uh yeah there's definitely
some overlap with uh with other
information on authorizing invasions
let's say if you want to using a
crosstrack
thread thread crop you want to put your
three crowd and you can check the story
clock here
and you can do this one i think this one
is one
and if we write
uh
you can see you can see this crosstrack
at least a stray crowd they give you
information whether it's deny or
malicious
um
yeah so let's uh just give you a
first impression about the movement
so
let's get a little bit deeper into the
lure stuff yeah so so movement has uh i
think you have seen a similar notes
right uh the the notes here uh some
nodes have like uh uh
we call like four types input nodes up
nodes utility function node and
third-party action node
so the input node has uh essentially
there are two two types of input so one
is once we call like uh
injector node one is the http endpoints
and
this inject knowledge enable you to run
like things periodically or enable you
to run uh or run adhoc and http is http
endpoints so you can uh you can quickly
create a rest api endpoints that can
connect to any kind of platforms you
have and then after they have the debug
or http response correspondingly so
uh
so
so for example this one is this one is
the inject this one is inject nervous
so this one is the inject node injects
best trigger you can see this one the
trigger has uh uh you can specify in you
can input different things input like a
timestamp or uh or content and you can
repeat you can repeat them at uh extreme
interval so you can specify like it runs
everywhere once a day or or runs uh uh
or at this time like
tuesday monday tuesday hour and uh at
different different different um
fine
and then you can use like a http uh
http endpoints so this http endpoints
get you you have you can see all kinds
of methods uh get poster put a deleted
patch you can quickly set up this one
you can give a url something some uir
and uh they have a
and uh and as a as the output you can
correspond is set up after you can go
you can do all kinds of things uh in
between and at the end you can set up a
response like is that the 200 is that
400 and based on your
uh your
your
requirements so this is the input and
output so two ways one is proactive one
is possible for proactive ways uh you
can you can schedule them you can and
for passwords you can uh you can build
up quickly quicker speed up uh api
endpoints and for any kind of systems uh
to connect with you for example you have
a servicenow team i know and lots of
companies have a uh servicenow team uh
if you if you want to
connect to the to the new raid i think
that's just super easy
um
so a little bit deep like uh down
here is uh how it works in within the
red so essentially anything anything uh
any node that basically is taking input
and output
adjacent format
in the the json format
the json values is getting passed
between different nodes
uh so whenever the winner operand
is basically json
just some type of uh
content and use with the default value
like payload
default value
default values payload msc dot payload
so that's the that's the main like
information carrier but you have other
attributes that you can you can specify
um
so and the fold
it has so
when you when you write automation you i
mean you probably have to write a lot of
other functions you want to like
flexibility in terms of pilot functions
you can just like javascript only so uh
if the nodes if the integration is not
here i uh so you probably probably want
to uh run some kind of
write some kind of your own functions so
it's also have integration with
javascript or you had integration with
uh with python um so that those kind of
functions enable you to uh smoothly uh
or even like a reuse or ui existing code
for example you have you already write
some code would write like python you
know to do some uh scraping or or
scanning i think those kind of things
you can always
fit in fitting here that combined with
them compute your own your own new logic
um
and in terms of logical functions either
already have a bunch of things like give
you like a split joints which uh uh for
example is like a parts like getting
data like getting one by one switch is
that that you can do if else right you
have multiple conditions you can have
multiple conditions
if something happens something happens
and let's do this if something happens
as you let i mean that's very common
logic
uh in in the data operation data
operations and then no really have all
this confidence building
um so and also it has like a third-party
third-party integrations and lots of
third-party third-party integrations uh
with different different security
different security tools qualities rapid
saving and
service now so and so forth uh so those
kind of things basically is api based so
you have a uh all this platform they
have api and now you have you can
connect to their you know connect to the
apis and um
uh
connect connect to the apis and uh and
uh and
and you complete your your tasks like
for example you have a crosstrack and
you can always pull data from the
crosstrack whether that's detection
without the instance or whether you want
to close a crosstracking instance or
where you want to uh analyze getting the
host information of the crosstrack and
so
the api is already there you don't need
to rebuild the viewer wheels and the api
will get you to do the slow stuff
um
and then and in terms of workflow
management once we have the workflow in
place we can we can we can save them
into the we can save them into the
playbooks we can save them into the uh
we can save them into the playbooks a
variety of different kind of playbooks
you can drag and drop and if you have
already reviewed a bunch of things
this is a somewhat complicated some of
uh some are easier uh so you can always
save them uh the good thing is you you
can you can because you can
share them with the community and
leverage whatever community with build
so you can yeah you can share them with
is essentially just some format you can
share them with with your colleagues
like just copy paste this kind of json
format and then they can they can import
it into their environment center and run
as well
[Music]
so
uh so i'll i'll get two demos i'll get a
two more demos uh why is let's see uh
uh so besides i can look at eyepiece
let's see like there's some uh
um
there's lots of time-consuming part is
really like a part of the data data
parsing uh so we have uh
it's a little bit more like uh
um uh the utility functions like the
target for security teams like for
example extra urls especially like when
you analyze something like let's let's
just write some
random text here uh so it's getting
parsley
random text
something else
and you want to so there's some tasks
you want to analyze these these emails
right like analyze these urls so
uh so you can you can always go through
this kind of automation and and get you
back the page back the uis do the ioc
abstractions uh you have the host name
if you have the ips if you have urls and
those kind of things or can go through
these kind of utility functions and
let's get to the last demo so we have
the we have ip enrichment here and we
have the uh we have the parsing here and
now let's go to the phishing and you if
you remember phishing when you have the
emails and you you need to parse the
headers and you pass the urls you get
attachments you need and then you need
to correlate it with uh with virus flow
you need correlated with hyper analysis
and you based on different information
you will need to send out different
different notifications
so here this this automation basically
is taking you taking the personal emails
and uh and go through parsley parser
email read emails parse emails and uh
and go through the
aristotle and you have two conditions
you will check if also give you
information if it's malicious if it's
malicious let's send the email let's
send an email to say oh this one is uh
this one is the phishing emails if not
let's send it let's send an email saying
there's nothing no you should find these
emails
so and in our testing environments i'll
say i'll show you
uh that we have uh
essentially we have a
uh
we have two we have two emails here uh
anyways
two emails
we have two two emails here uh i'll
quickly run this one so and then you can
you should expect to see the we can send
emails here notification here let's
quickly run this one
so now it's it's connecting to the
emails uh and
you can see we even have red red limited
control here there are two emails it's
doing uh so why is uh so why it's
parsing now and then once it's done uh
you can see it's connecting to the web
api so it's text time uh but these kind
of things already once you once you see
the result you start automatically
and you see like it's give you status
it's done
is done and then let's look at
the inbox here
so you can see i received the email
phish email was detected so you can see
it's getting it run automatically
um okay
so
um yeah i think that's yeah i have 25
minutes uh done um so this is all i have
and uh i'm ready to take any questions
yeah thanks for the time thanks for
organizers organizers again here
so i think skelly had a question
i did and i remember to unmute this time
yeah so um question for you peter how
difficult is this to learn and what are
some other use cases that it could be
useful for
um
so how
okay that's that's a good question here
so
so it's uh so getting started it takes
like uh one second probably it's taken
one second you can get started with your
first uh first baby workflow um and the
use cases as i mentioned all these kind
of use cases is doable we have been
using them and we have been
working with different teams on this
stuff yeah so
uh all these use cases we have we have
hands-on like implementation stuff yeah
it's it's almost i mean it's almost from
all these kind of aspects yeah even like
going goes beyond the blue teams to
rating stuff here
awesome yeah yeah
thank you so much that was great um
mikos do you have any more questions for
peter
i mean
i was wondering a little bit uh how one
could extend it for example okay so we
have some
some form of uh
automation could we eventually hook in
uh elastic as a service for this to then
perform operations on an elastic
yeah so yeah so you actually we have uh
uh the let's the platforms already have
uh have you asked this integration uh
you know talking to the talk to the
index and that is this goes beyond the
usage goes to uh raza goes to uh you
name it spanx it goes to uh
yeah how well goes to every opposition
another the exam being all those kind of
things here
awesome
we're just a bit curious so yeah
fantastic
um
we don't really have that many questions
uh
actually in chat
as uh
i'm actually uh
uh pleasantly surprised um i think the
word is
excited that the live demo worked
perfectly
that's always a challenging part
[Laughter]
oh we did uh just get a question aha uh
would it be possible for the workflows
that you showed to be designed in the ui
like you did and then be
executed from a command line interface
exactly in command yeah so i think the
the way to do that is really like you
have you set up a workflow with
api and api endpoints and you rather you
you just call your api inputs from your
command line okay
awesome
that sounds
interesting
new perspectives for security automation