ahoy there
call me crappy
and today i'll be delivering a talk
titled mind the gap
where i'll be helping you get a better
understanding of what your security
control framework might not cover for
your organization
let's get started
at times security is a kind of sailing
in both cases
you are
assisting with
steering an entity towards its intended
destination safely
whether it be an
organization or a ship
in the case of sailing
you may be
on the lookout for dangerous conditions
that could affect the journey
things like
stormy weather hidden rocks
and of course
kraken attacks
before you see security is akin to
sailing when sea monsters are thrown
into the mix
and for the ill-fitted ship that doesn't
have the capability to spot these
dangers
or
proper defenses to fight back
or even
the escape plan
if things goes out they may find that
their journey will come to
an abrupt end
so how does
how is this similar to securing an
organization
well
for organization that does not have the
proper procedures in place
they too may find themselves not
able
to
defend against attackers
if they are sought out as a target of
opportunity
and the attack vectors are several
from things like insider threats
to
software variabilities to
phishing attacks
and similar to how a ship it may be
doomed if it suffers a
major breach in its hull
an organization may be doomed after
suffering one or several data breaches
so what is an organization supposed to
do
to stay afloat
and try to navigate these treacherous
waters
well
one thing they can do is be
strategic
and the security data to implement
within your organization
this is where control frameworks come
into the picture
simply put they are a collection of
recommended actions
that aim to reduce the frequency and
impact of harmful events
and such one example of a control would
be something like establish and maintain
detailed enterprise asset inventory
by doing so
an organization will gain a better sense
of what
devices do they own
and what they can do to limit
the amount of exposure they have
and
oftentimes
organizations are driven by necessity to
adopt a framework
simply because it might be something
due to
legal contractual regulatory obligations
let us broadly categorize the types of
control frameworks out there that might
be of interest to security
industry
there are frameworks that are
used at a federal level
these would be documents that are
maintained
and
distributed by government
and for organizations that are looking
to
work with certain
sectors within the government they may
be finding themselves having to meet
these
frameworks um
requirements in order to continue to
operations
so one example would be
cyber essentials over in the uk
another example of a control framework
that has a federal basis will be the
cmmc over in the states
which is short for the cyber security
maturity model certification that one is
more relevant for contractors who seek
to work with the department of defense
another broad category here would be
industry based control frameworks
this would be
documents that are
meant to with a
keen focus on a certain industry such as
finance or healthcare
here's one example being the pci dss
which is short for the payment card
industry data security standard that one
is focused on
how
credit card information is handled
within an organization and processed
another example of an industry based
framework would be the high trust csf
which is short for the health
information trust lines common security
framework and is meant for
organizations that deals with health
care data
another category would be frameworks
that have a contractual obligation
these are frameworks that might not
necessarily apply at a federal
or industry level but they're simply
frameworks that an organization can
adopt and get certified with to show
that they are
have meet a certain baseline and to give
a form of assurance to other companies
that
are looking to work with them and
entrust them with their data
so this would be
two examples will be the iso
2701 framework which is a document
that is maintained by international
organization for standardization
with that is
that has a collection of information
security management standards
another example would be
the sock 2 which is short for system
organization controls to first
and then we come to
the fort
broad category of control frameworks
which is those that have community bases
these are would-be frameworks that are
kind of
driven by community effort
and
to give a collection of recommended
actions that may not be adequately
addressed in the other three categories
so two example here would be desist
controls which is more
oriented towards technical
recommendations
it might be of interest to it folks
overall
and then we have the ccmm
which is short for the cloud controls
matrix and is maintained by cloud
security alliance
and if you or it took a guess you can
probably
recognize that this framework is more
oriented towards cloud security
and so while we would hope that an
organization would be proactive
in trying to implement and adopt the
framework to help secure the
organization
and in certain cases they may be driven
by the fact that they realize oh gosh we
have an incident we have to do something
about it and then they kind of
choose and adopt the framework to help
them
secure to gain a better sense of
security and you know regain control of
things
all right
and this is where i want to discuss how
control frameworks are kind of like maps
if they were maps from like the 17th
18th century
the thing the key thing to keep in mind
is that since every framework is
different
and has different objectives they all
kind of have a sense of what an
organization do to be secure
but they also are each different in
their own ways
different enough that they might not
cover everything
that an organization
needs to know
and the reason why it's is because each
organization is different
and have unique
security risks that they care about
that
a framework might not be able to meet
keep in mind security control frameworks
are not quite one size fits all
so
and also and a few other things how
control framework is like a map
from 17th and 18th century
it won't help decide for you where to go
that is simply something that the
organization has to decide for
themselves
it won't tell you how risky your journey
will be or how much is the acceptable
amount of risk for
the organization
those are questions that has to be
answered in conversation between the
security department along with
board members in the organization and
those who
are at a c suite level
and of course these maps won't have all
the information that an organization
will need
there will be gaps
and
so how can we go about identifying these
gaps
well
here are three broad recommendations
one is first
help an organization catalog to security
risks that are relevant
second would be to help
organization review and monitor
what controls are implemented
for and how to implement it to see if
there are
if they are implemented correctly
or if there's something that has to be
fixed
and lastly
you should try to understand the
relationship and dependencies between
your controls
because for an organization that does
not adequately recognize the security
risk that they care about
or that is not checking the controls for
incorrect implementation
or that perhaps doesn't doesn't have a
good
understanding of how these controls
relate they may find themselves having
gaps within a security program overall
okay
let's try to
address the first recommendation
security risks
so
just to be clear
since risk is one of those words that
are kind of used in
security industry
in a lot of scenarios it's kind of best
to try to define what i mean by first
because otherwise we get sentences like
that is a high level of risk for that
risk
where it kind of becomes confusing what
is meant by risk in the first place
so when i say risk i'm not referring to
it as a probability
i'm simply referring to risk as an
uncertain event that can affect an
organization's ability to achieve their
objectives
so this would be something like um
like a data breach
or
something like
a
maybe the destruction of
data on a
asset or ransomware you know what are
the
events that the organization
are
is um concerned about
and keep in mind that every organization
runs on a certain level of risk because
you know that is they taken off they're
taking opportunity to invest
time and resources to achieve something
that is uncertain
so
for every organization they have
a different
appetite when it comes to risk about how
much
they're willing to uncertainty they're
willing to accept
and of course when it comes to risk
there are four primary ways to deal with
it
you can either accept the risk you can
try to remove the risk you can try to
mitigate the risk
or you can try to transfer it
in a case of mitigate
it would be something like
perhaps
you implement policy for encrypting data
at rest so in the case that if
data was stolen
it is harder for intact access simply
because it is encrypted data
in a case a transfer most of the time
that would be
you that would be related to
security insurance just
things that help transfer risk off to a
third party
okay
now let's talk about identifying
security risks
in this industry you will hear about a
model known as the cia triad which deals
with confidentiality integrity
availability
of certain assets
so
but one key thing
here that might be missing from a
conversation that might drive better
um discussions about security risk is
first talking about
the value
think thinking about what is valuable to
organization how do we create that value
in the first place
and so
by bringing in the idea of value and the
process used for value we can start
thinking about more directly what are
the
bad events that could have happened to
these
assets
and start thinking a little bit more
clearly about security risk
so things about like how can data be
destroyed how can facilities how can
people be denied access to facilities
things like
how can
certain technology if
not properly handled become
unusable over time things like this that
helps
the organization clearly understand what
security risks they might be concerned
about
okay so let's try
applying this kind of way of thinking
towards risk when we're trying to select
controls
here in a box is an example list from
iso 27002
the most recent one actually from this
year
and 48 controls under people categories
if you were to go and simply try to
implement them without thinking about
the risk you may not be as effective as
you were if you had the risk in mind
that the organization cares about and
then you can tailor these controls to
best
um suit and address these type of risk
so let's say if we talk about
the risk of when it comes to dealing
with people perhaps maybe the company is
concerned about
limiting the amount of workplace
violence prevent so trying to prevent
co-workers from harming another employee
or perhaps they are
concerned about whether about insider
threats how to detect whether somebody
is trying to
steal
propriety information and perhaps
sell it to a competitor
so by having the risk
first in mind you can help that helps
you better understand
what the controls might be helping to
achieve
so
next let's talk about proper control
implementation what does it look like
well for one policy
because without policy
certain controls might not be
implemented at all
policy helps the organization understand
what exactly is it trying to achieve
and try you know set a certain baseline
of an appropriate level security for
them
an ideal policy should you know address
what type of risk is in it is this for
the assets that this control and policy
applies to
the owner asking who is accountable for
the implementation of this control
and then of course the custodian which
is simply referring to who is
responsible for monitoring and
maintaining this control
and then when it comes to
documenting what is done it is important
to record it it's because
for people who
are new or new and brought onto the
organization can recognize what has been
the process
and keep
building upon that process
and it's also important for simply okay
so if you recognize something goes wrong
you can go back to documentation and
update
so ideally control documentation should
have an objective statement simply that
quickly summarizes what the control is
or what i will achieve
and then maybe a few notes about
dependencies does this control
it depend or it works in tandem with
another controller
and this will become a little bit
important later on where we talk about
the and on ontology that can be used to
categorize frameworks
or categorize controls within the
frameworks
let's start talking about that ontology
so
there's a group called the fair
institute that has a
certain
um
ontology that helps with
categorizing
broadly how controls are
and there's three main levels
at a high
um overview of how where controls fall
into
this would be controls an acid level
controls at variance level and controls
at a decision-making level
for acid level that's simply something
as simple as like applying a firewall to
an asset these are the controls that can
be applied directly to an asset
for something like variance level
controls that would be the two key
ones there would be policy and security
awareness training controls that help
the organization
limit too much deviation from an
appropriate level of security for them
and then when it comes to the decision
making level this is
more
about making sure that company is able
to make
informed decisions
about security risk management
and do it repeatedly
okay so when it comes to acid level
there are
two
broad categories for this you have
controls that prevent loss events and
you have controls that detect and
respond to loss events
so an example is trying to prevent a
loss event would be something if you
have like a web application or firewall
for short
that tries to monitor for malicious
traffic that comes to a web server and
drop that
those type of traffic
but then what happens if something gets
passed well you want ideally you want
control to help you detect and respond
to
if it's some if let's say someone was
able to
try to
trigger and
vulnerability within one of your web
servers
so
it's key here to know that you need
have a combination of those
of those control categories if you don't
have a control that helps prevent a loss
event and only detect and respond you
might be
you might be you know overloading your
security department with
work if they're not if since without
that percentage
preventive control
and on the flip side if you have
controls that prevent
and but don't have adequate controls to
detect and respond to loss events
then you are simply relying that hope on
the hope that nothing gets past that
first control
now let's talk about controls at a
variance level
this also is broadly defined into two
categories controls that prevent too
much deviation security levels and
controls that detect and respond to
conditions that permit significant
deviation
and prevention we already discussed
about this policy and security awareness
training are key here making sure that
people understand what is expected and
making sure that they understand how it
can be done
and then when it comes to detection
response
this can be done in a couple of forms
such as something like audits
or it can be done someplace sometimes
with something like
having well-informed people who can
detect
um when
the
conditions around the organization has
changed and requires you know
changing the level of appropriate level
security and sometimes it can be not
just condition inside your organization
but sometimes affected by conditions
outside like for let's say an example of
log4j
that that was an
event that many organizations realize
okay
we are we are likely have deviated from
our appropriate level of security
because now we recognize that there is
this vulnerability that probably affects
us within an organization and we have to
do our best to regain sense of control
and
and you know address that
and finally you have controls at
decision making level
so this would be things and here the
three components are key you need to
make sure that the appropriate people
are unable to make informed decisions
based on repealable processes and
reliable information
you need to make sure that you have the
the ability to detect when poorly made
decisions
about regarding security risks are made
and
that this could be simply meaning that
you have
people informed on who to
notify and who to get involved if this
these cases occur
and most importantly you have to have an
organization that's willing to learn
from these mistakes and respond to them
and document lessons learned so to
prevent these kind of mistakes from
happening in the future
okay in short
your control framework will not cover
everything your organization needs
there may be gaps in your security
program as a result
and to help you find those caps it helps
by trying to first understand the risks
that the organization cares about
continuously checking and verifying
controls
and lastly recognizing how your controls
relate and affect each other
if you want examples of
controls that perhaps might not be
included in one or several frameworks
you have i would recommend checking out
these free resources
that
are mainly compendiums and controls from
several frameworks by doing so you can
probably get a better coverage of what
your organization
might not be addressing already
that's all for i have for today
i hope you have a wonderful time with
the rest of digital overdose
and i hope you all have
smooth sailing in your security careers
to come thank you very much