[Music]
thanks uh great to see everyone I love
hack a day let's see if I can figure
this out all right cool
so when I was 10 years old my mom spent
everything she had to get me this
computer it's the best day of my life uh
immediately because she was going to
University I was able to dial up into
the university get on the internet and
immediately I did what anyone would do
and I searched for The X-Files
and I want to chat with people about the
X-File so I found something called IRC
Internet relay chat I downloaded MRC
yeah you guys know IRC
I download IRC I went into a chat room
and I said who wants to chat about the
X-Files and someone immediately said get
out
so whoa uh we don't we can try to chat
about something else like what's your
favorite TV show and they said you have
10 seconds to get out
and I was so confused by this and I
remember like should I be worried about
this person
um and I remember my mom told me you
know don't ever give out your name and
don't talk to you know strangers on the
internet I saw this tweet recently don't
get in strangers cars and don't meet
people from the internet today we
literally summon strangers from the
Internet and get their cars
and I was thinking well back then I
didn't actually give this person any
info so they can't do anything to me I'm
invincible so I said no
10 seconds later the brand new computer
that my mom spent everything on
did this
I got a blue screen of death this is
1995 running Windows 95 and I freaked
out I pulled all the wires out
I turned off I I pulled them away I
waited 20 30 minutes I figured the
longer you wait the better it'll be
it'll it'll heal and I plugged
everything back in unfortunately
everything came back up but with the
adrenaline just rushing through my veins
I thought that was the coolest thing
ever how do I how do I do that I don't
do that uh after a couple of certain
weeks of searching I found this win nuke
95 written by this author uh Mr burnt
bogus of the Dem
and I thought this was so cool and all
of a sudden I have this super power I
can do all sorts of crazy things and
Windows 95 Service Pack 2 came out and
my superpower was gone now I'm not
malicious I don't want to like crash
people's computers but there's something
pretty intoxicating about being able to
control some type of system that you're
not supposed to be able to right
something you're not supposed to have
access to I figured could I make win
nuke 96 could I make the next version
and that's when I got into reverse
engineering understanding memory
manipulation reading things like frack
and 2600.
and I've then spent the rest of my life
trying to figure out how to do that how
can I exploit systems and how can I
patch them and how can I exploit that
and that brings us to hack a day where
I've learned so much from all of you
um in fact it was oh actually uh I threw
the badge in the my x-ray machine last
night thanks Sam for the recommendation
on the X-ray machine so this is the hack
a Day badge from uh that you're all
wearing and it was a few years ago 2019
I was talking to Sam zuluf Adam zaluf
what a coincidence last names and the
same domains weird
um and also Alex Whitmore who's doing a
talk right now in fact actually you can
kind of hear in the other room if
everyone cheers so let's cheer for Alex
and then afterwards I'll just tell him
that was for you let's go yeah go Alex
yeah all right
she's gonna ask why were you guys
cheering it was for you
what oh my God hi Alex
[Laughter]
oh well I hope you enjoyed that that was
all for you
okay so we're
um I
we're just chatting about different
projects that we're working on and one
of the the concepts I had I have many
Concepts very few finished projects and
one was this thing someone handed me and
they said this was a USB condom or like
neuterer so what this thing does is this
is a device
that you plug let's say you want to
charge your phone in the airport you
don't trust the airport charger so you
plug your phone into this with a USB
with USB and it cuts off the data lines
and only allows power so you're only
charging like okay that's a good idea
but how do I know that this opaque
device actually is not containing
something else like a chip that's doing
something crazy so that'd be a good idea
if I made transparent ones and I gave
those out to people but that's not that
very very fun really what I want to do
is I want to make a transparent one
where there's two wires for power two
wires for data you see the data lines
stop because they're copper fully
transparent and then I use indium tin
oxide a transparent conductor to
continue the traces for the data
and because USB is actually high speed
when you have a high speed line and you
put another let's say just wire coming
out zigzagging you now have an antenna
so you'd actually have a fully
transparent USB neuter that's really
just radiating all the information but
um so I thought that would be cool so I
got this stuff from Ito um on plastic
sheet pet from at a fruit I tried
cutting I tried making a couple versions
it was just super obvious that there was
something really really fishy so I
thought okay how do they make a Ito like
I don't know how can I just make it
myself can I make it at home and then I
can make a really nice version
um so I Googled how to make Ito and I
was like why why is Google tell us how
fast the search is like we know you're
the best Google like no one's saying
let's Bing it we say we Google it so and
then I realized oh applied science that
guy is Amazing Ben krasno um he has
everything you know a lot of these
things I search is usually just him
um coming up with how to do this stuff
at home so pretty incredible here's a
talk at 6 pm today I'm excited for and I
watched this video and and he has this
thing called the vacuum chamber and a
vacuum pump where he's sucking air out
so I'm like okay I gotta get one of
those I go on eBay I get this thing this
is a dual stage rotary vein we'll figure
out what that means later I had no idea
I just
got what he got
and I turned it on and I started having
oil just going everywhere in my kitchen
like what is this so I look up what I
need I need this oil Mist filter so
okay Amazon 157 so I just use a toilet
paper roll which this was actually early
covid so the going price of a toilet
paper was about 157 if you recall and
I'm now trying to figure out how does
all this vacuum stuff work I see all all
these videos on Sam Zulu's Channel I
started recently watching this guy Nick
pool I know he's here and I've been
watching his channel recently really
amazing stuff there as well and I also
continue watching Ben's videos and he
does something really cool he makes
freeze-dried ice cream like with a
vacuum chamber I'm thinking okay some of
my projects will take me a long time
will take months years whatever
so I try doing that so I actually get
like a vacuum chamber I mean do I have
like a
um so I have my vacuum pump going into
this four line trap that's just a stop
let's say water and things from getting
back and then I have a cryo trap this is
like propylene glycol it's just it's the
stuff that you get in those packs of
cold when you get something in the mail
um and then that chamber has ice cream
um and I'm heating it a little bit and
what's really interesting about this is
all right so we know water water
generally boils at zero degrees Celsius
and generally freezes I'm sorry freezes
at zero degrees Celsius and generally
boils at 100 Celsius but that's only
true in atmosphere and what that means
is really this is called a phase diagram
so really there's water and how it when
it becomes a solid when it is a little
liquid and gas but there's also pressure
so if you change the pressure you can do
some cool stuff so you can actually go
solid turn it to ice and then you can
lower the pressure and then get down to
a gas and that's called sublimation so
you can turn a solid into a gas without
ever going into water or liquid if
you've ever seen dry ice you see it just
gassing off right that's sublimation so
that's one way that you can actually
make freeze dried ice cream I thought
that'd be really cool and you may hear
different things like atmosphere or tour
but normally it's really easy to figure
out all this pressure stuff all you have
to remember is one atmosphere is equal
to 1.0132 bar which is equal to 33.895
feet of water which is equal to 29.9213
inches of mercury particular 406.7825
inches of water which is equal to
101.325 kilopascals
um which is equal to 14.695 psi which is
760 torr or millimeters Mercury and
1.0332 kilograms four squared
centimeters unfortunately everybody uses
all of these different things so it's
really hard to calculate but just
memorize that you'll be good
um
so fortunately I made some type of
freeze-dried thing it looks gross it was
absolutely amazing super super rich
unfortunately in that process I then
destroyed my vacuum my vacuum pump so
now there's all this water I'm like okay
I need to open this up figure out how
this works and they have security screws
on this on the vacuum pump like they're
trying to prevent people from opening
the vacuum pump around the same time my
friend Stan had said hey I have this um
uh Mill that I'm giving away if anybody
wants it's just in the back of my trunk
hardly used like new uh unfortunately
that's a mill
so like yeah I could use a mill so I
take it home and I try a couple
different methods and evapor rust is
absolutely amazing I don't work for
evapor rust but that thing like I put
stuff in evapor Rust I took it out the
day later there's nothing
um really beautiful uh did a great job
and this is now the mill unfortunately I
was left with a couple of Fasteners I
still don't know where those go
but then I use the mill I have a small
lathe the grizzly g0765 took a piece of
Steel
um cut a little bit and just tried to
cut into that security screw and
fortunately I was able to just generate
something to actually open that thing so
I opened it up I cleaned it out and
that's when I learned what a rotary vein
is which I think is kind of interesting
here we can actually see what's
happening so I'm just manually holding
this with a drill those two white things
are the veins and rotors need rotation
what's happening is like if you were to
take something and push a balloon you're
gonna push that air out well it's like
pushing air out and while that other
side is expanding it's just like if you
were to breathe in you're expanding and
that air will just go go into your body
for example then I start getting closer
and closer to sputtering so this is my
attempt at a magnetron sputter so I'm
now copying more of Ben's videos and
other things and now I have high voltage
I'm using a microwave oven Transformer
I'm using Auto Transformer from the wall
so I take 140 volts and I control that
zero to 120. then I go into a microwave
oven Transformer which upset like a
people 70 times I go through a high
voltage diode and then to these two
sides that's a steel plate that's just
some like npt I don't know connectors
and I'm pulling vacuum on this entire
thing up there with high voltage and now
it's spraying metal or spraying
electrons hitting it hard enough that
it's spring metal and sputtering this
this thing unfortunately it's still not
doing Ito indium tin oxide
um I need better vacuum for that but
anyway I go back to all right this USB
thing
see how we're on time all right cool
um
so let's understand first why are there
two data lines with USB and that's
because the USB lines are actually
differential and what that means is that
you have if you have using Arduino you
might set a pin as high which let's say
5 volts or maybe 3.3 depending your VCC
or Ground Zero but really now if there's
electrical noise if there's like
interference somewhere then what you
might end up experiencing is a slight
variation might be 4.8 volts but the
Arduino the transistors inside don't
care they'll still see that as one or
high
now the nice thing now if there's a lot
of interference it might actually go low
you might be able to take a floating pin
and go high or a ground pin and go high
so the nice thing about an inverted or
differential signal like in twisted pair
like an Ethernet is you have you have
two voltages offset by something and all
you're looking at is the comparison of
these two voltages and then if there's
interference they both will get
interfered and the difference between
these two is still the same and we can
actually kind of see in returns I
remember a long time ago I was sitting
at my desk and I had these speakers on
my desk I'm not sure if this will work
but it will test real quick
and I remember I got a text message and
the speakers on my computer were making
noise I'm like wait why is that
[Music]
time to hear that
um so these are not connected to
anything so that's called interference
anyone from the FCC here
just curious
uh so that's interference I thought
that's that's actually pretty amazing
that you can produce sound on a speaker
that's not even connected to anything or
if it disconnected anything you're not
actually you're not actually touching it
you're literally wirelessly emanating
sound into this thing you're not using
sound you're using RF I thought that is
so cool like what else can I inject
sound or noise or information onto and
thought about keyboards those really
interesting keyboard so I started taking
a look at some general wireless
keyboards at first
a few years ago several years ago I
created this project called key sweeper
it's basically a stealthy Arduino based
device it looks like a charger it's
actually inside of an Adafruit charger
it has a phono board which talks to GSM
and whenever it's near a wireless
charger it sniffs and decrypts the
keystrokes and then produces an online
interface you can go to and you can
start typing on the keyboard wirelessly
fortunately the FBI released a notice
saying there's this Wireless keystroke
logger this guy is USB device charger
and they have the excellent additional
best practices to prevent a compromise
limit which Outlets are available for
device charging all right so don't let
people plug stuff in know whose Chargers
are currently being used
and immediate removal of an unknown
charger so I think I might make a new
one with a banana like put it inside of
a banana what they don't realize is the
circuit inside can go in anything it
doesn't have to be a charger so soon
it'll be limit which bananas are
available uh no whose bananas are
currently being used and immediate
removal of an unknown banana from the
office
uh okay so I thought all right wireless
keyboards that's interesting that makes
sense if you can attack the wireless
communication there's already RF between
your computer or a USB dongle and the
keyboard itself but what about a
physical keyboard inside of a keyboard
you have something called a scan Matrix
basically if you have 100 keys on a
keyboard you don't want to have 100 pins
on your microcontroller so it's best
better to use the scan Matrix where you
can actually share pins and the
interesting part about this is that
there's also diodes on every pin that
that prevents key ghosting uh so I
thought okay well in a keyboard if you
actually look at the keyboard the wires
are all different lengths so could I
just measure all the wire lengths and
what is the length of a wire well for
one all wires are conduct are all
conductors are antennas and what is the
wavelength of an antenna or the
frequency it's related to a physical
length of a wire so if you measure all
of those then you actually now know the
wavelength the resonant frequency of
every single key on a keyboard so could
I inject that I'm not sure if that would
work and just to learn a little bit more
about RF
so I started doing this I found it was
not working I got a little bit of luck
on on a mouse but once I got to let's
see where we're at all right cool
all right
um once I got to
trying to inject on my keyboard it
wasn't working so like okay I don't
really understand what's happening if I
touch my oscilloscope to the keyboard
itself I now change everything about the
way that I change the impedance and I I
can't measure it that way so I actually
have to really probably just understand
RF better so one thing that I started to
learn was RF this is a highly scientific
chart from XKCD about the
electromagnetic spectrum so radio
frequency RF is just one part of the
electromagnetic spectrum and I think
it's actually really helpful to
understand because visible light the
light that we see is also part of
electromagnetic spectrum it's actually
helpful for me to think about basically
all radio waves as all radio waves as
light right I can now think of
everything as light and all waves have
the same properties they have reflection
they have absorption refraction
diffraction
and as I'm learning about radio waves
they also have very clever names like
low frequency medium frequency high
frequency very high frequency extremely
high frequency I'm sorry ultra high
frequency super high frequency extremely
high frequency
and then far infrared and that's when
you use it infrared and then light
visible light ultraviolet x-rays gamma
rays Etc I don't know if there's
anything after that
but that's pretty interesting
so I'm trying to learn about this and
okay I want to understand if I want to
understand how a packet works or if I
want to change some networking I
understand how packet works if I
understand ethernet then I need to
understand or CAT5 I'm just doing
voltage so here I need to look up how RF
Works which is how electromagnetism
Works which is how light works so I
start looking up what light is and that
just starts talking about photons on
Wikipedia like hey what's a photon and
then I start reading about this thing
called wave particle duality and this is
just like blowing my mind so apparently
like I always thought of light as these
particles right these little dots that
you can fly and send this is called uh
this right here is called the double
slit experiment so this is a double
slides which is my living room I took a
plain laser green laser I go through
this double slit here I would expect to
see two lines on the end on the other
side of the room instead we see this
like up down up of the high low high low
high low that's called an interference
pattern so literally the laser going
through that two lines creates this
pattern what does that mean and now
another way to thinking about this and
people have done great demonstrations of
using water like if you actually have
water a water wave go through a dam and
you have two slits in that Dam now two
new waves will come out and then they'll
interfere and those waves they have
Peaks and troughs right so now those
Peaks and troughs will interfere their
potassium did a good job of explaining
this so here's a video that you can
check out
so now I'm just I'm fascinated by Optics
and that this stuff can actually work so
I start looking online like how do I do
opposite experiments at home I find 3D
like you can find optomechanical
equipment you just 3D print at home and
start building yeah buy buy your lenses
or mirrors from Thor Labs
admin Optics online eBay wherever you
want
um and I'm really curious now about this
Photon thing because there's another
thing with the double slit experiment
with like let's say we have light like
let's say we're sunglasses and let's say
they're The Aviator type or very
reflective and 50 of light goes through
50 of light reflects off
what happens when you send one photon
to your sunglasses does it go through or
does it go or does it reflect that's
that's actually a pretty interesting
question so there's actually a lot of
research that's been happening 30 40
years ago about what happens with single
particles like photons and electrons
what happens when they interfere when
they do one thing and apparently
supposedly they do both they actually
this is called the quantum superposition
now this is blowing my mind even more so
what actually happens is supposedly it
will go through both it will reflect and
it will go through and how do you know
that and you know that because according
to papers when you reintroduce them
through another let's say beam splitter
sunglasses you can then learn you'll
learn you'll actually see it on one side
of a beam splitter if one side is
blocked you'll actually end up seeing it
on the other side of the beam splitter
if the actual Photon went that direction
there's papers on this we won't get into
this if you can't unfortunately there's
lots of open papers that you can access
online but there's something called the
elter waveman bomb tester experiment
which also was first a thought
experiment around this and said that you
if you created a photosensitive bomb
that would explode when it detected a
photon you can in some cases detect that
there's a bomb there it will explode if
the photon ever gets sent and you can
learn that that is there without ever
having a photon actually hit it this is
pretty amazing because this could mean
that could you do the same thing with
that tray if an x-ray is a photon then
couldn't you Double Split couldn't you
split an x-ray into hit a human with a
superposition the X-ray continues down
another path you re-merge them and then
you now learn information this is called
the witch path information did it go
this way or not so I'm like all right I
have to try to understand some of this
Quantum stuff
um I don't know if I can but I'll try
so I start looking what experiments can
I do at home and I find this book called
exploring quantum physics through
Hands-On projects like that sounds
amazing and I look at the authors David
perucci and Shani prucci and I find that
Shanny Shawnee excuse me uh
it did a supercon talk actually there's
a couple super gone talks so I just
tweeted I remember I was like oh my God
you're a biggest fan
um and we started chatting and I got the
book and I just started going through
some of their experiments like this is
actually really cool I really do suggest
this book
um because you can do a ton of stuff at
home and so it's really really
incredible because if people are doing
quantum mechanical experiments 30 years
ago 40 years ago think about how much
technology has progressed since then and
what we're able to do at home
um so now I'm learning about photo tubes
photo tubes are actually super
interesting because they're a they're
extremely simple all it is is you let's
say a piece of glass and you have two
pieces of metal inside and there's a
vacuum and if light of a certain energy
hits it so if you have let's say blue
light or ultraviolet light hit something
like zinc it will then emit electrons
and those electrons will hit the other
piece of metal and then conduct a
current and now you have a current and
if you send let's say red light instead
you get nothing if you send a thousand
times the red light at the same time you
get nothing and that just showed that
light was also at times quantized so we
saw it as a way when we did the double
slit experiment but now we see it as
single particles with a with some amount
of energy so this is like this is
absolutely crazy I want to make one of
these
how do I make a photo tube so it's glass
it's metal well I can just make pieces
of metal like I can take pieces of metal
and cut it or bend it but I don't know
how to mess with glass so I start
googling how do you make how do you make
glass like how do you actually I don't
know make the photo tubes so I find this
book called building scientific
apparatus and amazingly it's on
archive.org for free so you can access
the full book there there's a full
chapter working with glass so this is
very exciting the properties of glass
what you need tubings rods Etc and the
glass doors tools so I get the very
basic tool set so this is a national
torch and then you need a fuel I use
propane you also want oxygen for
borosilicate you want borosilicate glass
like Pyrex and the reason for that is
that you're going to use a lot of heat
and you don't want the glass to break
it's like
it's easier to use in some cases and
harder to use in some cases anyway I was
like I'm not going to pay for oxygen
like I breathe oxygen every day
um can I just like take it and
apparently most of the air is actually
nitrogen so I'm like 80 nitrogen maybe
90 oxygen something like that so you can
actually get one of these uh oxygen
concentrators so this if you have
emphysema you might have one of these or
you can find them on Craigslist
um and I was looking like can I just
produce the oxygen myself and I found
more more actually people on a Discord
called vacuum hack sores helped me and
said oh this is all you need to do get
an oilless compressor so that you're not
spitting out oil which takes in the air
compresses it and then you put it
through a couple of things you put it
through a silica gel like a desiccant
that gets rid of the humidity then you
put it through a couple of particulate
filters just to get rid of any dust or
anything and then you put it through
something called the molecular sieve and
this is actually the same thing as the
silica gel that you might find in your
vitamin packets right that's silica gel
how does that work it's really just
these balls of silica and they have
holes in them on the outside kind of
like a golf ball and those holes are the
size of water molecules so it's really
adsorbing a d not absorbing but
adsorbing and you can do that you can
get other things called other sieves
like zeolite and there's various kinds
that will actually collect or absorb
different gases so you can say I want to
get I want to collect nitrogen I want to
adsorb nitrogen so the oxygen then
continues to go out and then you can put
that in a buffer tank and then you can
compress that further if you want and
spit it out too whatever you want so you
just make oxygen at home or nitrogen
so now I have everything and I have made
fire it's absolutely amazing uh so
now I'm continuing and I'm trying to
make I'm just trying this stuff at home
I'm trying to make these different
connections and like teas and ring seals
and every time I make something like I
kind of kind of got it kind of got it
half an hour goes by and I hear it break
my kitchen like okay what am I doing
wrong and I try it again and I try it
again it just keeps breaking so then I'm
like okay well maybe I maybe I need to
go take a class or something and uh
uh after after literally weeks every
weekend I would just spend trying to
make some glass I just went chapter by
chapter by chapter in this book and the
second to last chapter says annealing
even when a seal is carefully blown out
to give it a uniform wall thickness
harmful stresses or inevitably frozen
into the glass work glass must be
annealed by heating to a temperature
above the annealing point so I learned I
was doing it wrong the whole time I need
to anneal so I continued now I tried
annealing and I still found that a lot
of things that I was doing weren't
working so uh I then found a local class
on on lampworking and glassblowing um in
La so I went to this class unfortunately
they're doing soft glass I had trouble
finding anyone who would teach how to do
borosilicate or scientific glass so I
went to this class anyway I learned a
few things but my stuff at home still
didn't work so I can you just search
online scientific glass blowing borrow
silica glass blowing can I find anyone
who's doing this kind of thing that I
could just pay to teach me for a few
hours right it's the same thing as a
class I found this guy on Instagram he
has a lot of beautiful glass work he
also had like a lot of oregano or basil
or something in a lot of his images I
think he likes uh yeah not sure but uh I
asked him as like you know you can't
really come to my shop
um I just started messaging more and
more people on Instagram on Google on
YouTube
um then I just went to LinkedIn I
searched scientific glass blower and I
just started messaging literally copying
and pasting my message to everyone
people didn't respond um some people
like you can't come to my work and I
can't like teach you right I have a job
like the scientific Glasper and finally
I get someone who responds this person
works at Sigma Aldrich owned by Merck I
mean legit company it's been assigned of
a glassware for a long time and she says
oh I see that you're in L.A we're
located in Milwaukee Wisconsin this is
something that you're thinking you would
travel here for
it's time to check in
and the great thing is that tickets to
Wisconsin in the middle of winter are
super cheap I think I think they paid me
actually
and I arrived I was very excited to uh
get to this place and now here's the
thing she's I think she was very
suspicious she was like okay well is
this kind of legit like you're gonna
have to send me you know six hours up
front pay me pay me after I was like
that seems sounds reasonable so I sent
her the money via Paypal got the ticket
flew out there I show up knocked on you
know if I get an Uber I stayed at a
hotel and I show up and I say knock on
the door old woman comes to the door and
says hi is Katie or Ian there she's like
nobody here by that name I'm like what
I checked the address I'm like is this
the address you're like yep that's the
address like oh no
and I call I call Katie I have her phone
number we've never spoken before I've
just given her money on the internet
and like I met this address it was like
oh oh I have the number switch sorry uh
hold on come outside and I see her like
10 10 houses down like okay
it was so cold
I was so cold I live in you know I live
here in L.A and I thought okay I'll just
bring four layers and that's just that
doesn't do it like it's the wrong kind
of layers I guess you need a windbreaker
or something I don't know
freezing so I show up at the shop and
I'm like I'm so excited so these two
guys Ian and Katie and they're actually
they're incredible so they're teaching
they've this is Ian's Workshop this is
home workshop and he has this glass
lathe um absolutely amazing makes it
really easy just a few pictures of their
lab here
uh this is a pretty sweet uh
this is a torch that Ian made so this is
fully fully glass besides the two needle
valves so one needle valve allows you to
put in something like butane and then
one allows it to go go out and then use
the Venturi effect to add additional air
through the back and you get this torch
and that's super sweet and this is uh
Katie in her lightsaber and you're the
the blue or the Purple Haze that's
actually basically the geodimian glasses
that you wear to a c much better and it
removes all of the yellow sodium Flair
when you're working so when you're glass
blowing or lampworking you really want
to wear that so hey you can see better
so this is a if you ever want to reach
out to them if you want to fly to
Wisconsin they'll they now teach
personal classes
and while I was out there I realized you
know I was actually I've been talking to
this guy on Twitter um Michael Katz he's
a professor at and I realize oh yeah
he's in Wisconsin so I said hey he's an
Optics Professor he's an Optics lab out
there I'm like can I take you to lunch
he's like yeah you know come by also my
wife is Jennifer you know Dr Jennifer
Troy Professor Jennifer Choi and she has
a Quantum lab I'm like wait I'm gonna go
visit an Optics lab in a Quantum lab
um so I got to go hang out with them and
of course Professor Toby
um and just I blew my mind I I haven't
gone to like a school or university so I
haven't seen the types of stuff that
they're doing this is a Magneto Optical
oh man a Mott not a microwave oven
Transformer Magneto Optical trap where
they're actually able to cool down atoms
neutral atoms with a laser and trap it
that blows my mind so I fly home really
and reinvigorated on this like
glassblowing stuff and I'm thinking I
need to do little projects as I'm
working on progressing on larger
projects so I thought it'd be cool maybe
I do a little art project I make like a
little neon sign or something
um because I can I think I can do that
now um I think I understand enough about
vacuum and gas and glass blowing and
actually neon signs are really they're
called gas discharge tubes so neon signs
what that means is that there's neon
inside most of the tubes you see don't
actually have neon inside so some are
helium or argon or Krypton or Xenon so
typically the noble gases and sometimes
you can you can add things like mercury
vapor and that will also alter the color
so we can see a couple of the colors
here so that's pretty interesting like
that'd be cool to have a neon sign on my
wall like it could actually just be the
the noble gases like argon neon
Etc
and how does that work I was just
curious so the way that's what my
understanding is when you have a neon
tube you have two pieces of metal two of
metal electrodes and then you're putting
High volt high voltage on those um I
assume it'll work with these with both
DC and AC but I think AC will actually
look better and what it's producing is
this huge electric field not huge
electric field like electric field if
there's ever any electron in there that
electron is going to get pushed by that
field or pulled
and if that electron hits a neutral atom
like an atom of neon that neutral atom
is not doing anything it's just hanging
out and if it hits it hard enough well
what will happen is an electron will fly
off and if that electron flies off and
hits and then joins another atom that
has already had an electron fly off
light is produced that energy base gets
converted to light now you need that
electric field you need the vacuum
because you need enough space for that
electron to actually Traverse so I think
of it like if I'm if I'm in a parallel
parked car and just slam on the throttle
I'm just going to hit the car in front
of me slightly but if I'm on the street
and I have a lot of space and I
accelerate I'm going to gain more and
more speed right force is equal to mass
times acceleration my Mass is the same
but I'm accelerating so I'm going to
have a lot more Force when I finally hit
it and I'm going to eject the person
from that car and they're going to hit
another car and as long as they're a
magnetic field and they're wearing like
a steel suit they're they're probably
going to eject someone else and
the whole thing will keep going so I
thought well it'd be really interesting
if I could actually have this on my wall
and not have wires because I don't like
wires so I try to remove any wires on
the walls like you know my TV or Xbox or
whatever wires so I remember that I saw
a fluorescent tube light up a long time
ago and those from a Tesla coil so I got
one of these like little Tesla coils on
Amazon
um and I might start googling like how
do these work what's a Tesla coil and
how can I make my own
um and as I'm Googling I actually see I
find out this guy Jay
um who I had the opportunity to meet
last night so check out his channel he's
also doing a talk tomorrow at 11AM so
I'm pretty excited about that so
learning a lot about Tesla coils from
him also go on to a Discord for Tesla
coils talking to a bunch of people
um I meet uh this uh someone named Tate
and he we're chatting oh hell no I did
not just get the plasma Tour on let's go
dude oh my God
so Tate's here so he recorded this in my
home he's trying to like he's working on
Tesla coils like crazy Mad stuff like
this
um and he needs equipment I'm like just
come over whenever you want and use my
equipment
um don't destroy my oscilloscope and
still scoop still works uh so he's doing
crazy stuff so I'm just I'm excited to
just be around that type of energy this
is his channel check it out as you can
see he's doing incredible stuff
um also a shout out and thank you to
Scotty for pushing me to actually do
this talk here because I wasn't going to
but uh we hung out and he convinced me
to so excited uh for his stuff so I
started learning about something called
a Slayer Exciter circuit and this is
actually really really interesting this
is a the simplistic circuit so that's
very helpful for me I'm not an
electrical engineer
um so this is my Slayer Exciter it's no
different than many others um this is
just a bypass capacitor that's a store
energy so we can ignore that for now and
just understand like briefly what's
happening basically VCC that's our
voltage there are 10 I put in say 12
volts 12 volts uh
can go through this resistor R2 and then
go through the base of that transistor
that's an npn and npn transistors is a
switch right it turns on or off so going
voltage going to the base turns it on
which allows voltage or I'm sorry
current to go from BCC from our battery
or whatever through that inductor L3 now
whenever you have current when you have
a Charged particle moving through
something it creates a perpendicular
magnetic field so now there's a
perpendicular magnetic field like going
around this inductor inductor is just a
coil like this
so now that that happens the same thing
it reverse happens with L4 L4 now says I
feel this magnetic field and produces a
current
um and that current actually then shuts
off the base and which then turns off L3
which then turns off that field and now
you get this oscillator this natural
oscillator which is really really cool I
thought okay maybe I can put like a
Tesla coil in my wall and then I can
light up the neon sign and I won't have
electrodes in the neon sign it'll just
be like they'll just be lit and then I
asked uh Sam someone I work with
um hey do you know of like any way that
can do a flat Tesla coil and he's going
to link me to this thank you Sam that's
him hard at work
uh so I get this so we'll find this flat
test like one that makes a lot of sense
so this is called the pancake coil where
you essentially have your primary coil
on the outside here
um and the secondary which is here I
have about 140 turns to one um so what
that means is if I put one volt in I'm
going to about approximately 140 volts
on the out on the outside I used Eagle I
found a ulp to create spiral coils it
only got up to 100 turns so you just go
into the code and you literally make it
200 and now you can go higher I tried
producing them at home I tried ferric
chloride I use like spray paint on pcbs
and that wasn't working and it's around
this time that I'm messing with this
project that uh crash space had a
wearable Wednesday with our favorite Liz
here she's also doing a talk today 5 p.m
here excited for that actually that's
wearable Wednesday is where I met
Deborah geek mom projects and she's a
machine I don't know if you've seen her
Twitter it's just so many so many
amazing projects um she is absolutely a
machine like literally uses a cybernetic
organ ISM with living tissue over metal
endoskeleton uh so I was like it would
be cool to have some type of a wearable
thing for wearable Wednesday so thought
okay instead of you know I could put
that PCB inside I don't know I could
like have a have a Tesla coil with me
but could I make it on a flex circuit
what is a flex circuit well a flexor
could have just capped on tape
um not Capcom tape but capped on tape
and kept on tape with copper that's
that's all really Flex circuit is and I
started messing around can I make this
at home I started Googling like what is
like actually what is tapped on tape
it's a polyamide tape and this website
says that the polymer tape has a strong
taste and a sour smell
the polymy tape is likely to be fake
so that's how you know if you have fake
polymide tape by The Taste thank you
hopeflightcn.com
so I tried a couple things but finally I
went to pcbgo.com I sent them my board
they sent me this
um actually I think I have one
so this is now I think as far as I know
the first flexible wearable uh Tesla
coil
um
then I now need to make like an actual
ampule or something to actually carry a
gas so I've now been improving my vacuum
setup I'm using all these npt gauges but
I have a ton of leaks and then I've now
switched to KF so MPT these are just
like things you use for pipe fittings
um KF is quick flange it's just a it's a
better higher vacuum connector for all
all these connections basically this is
a scroll pump I got rid of the the oil
pump uh I just didn't like dealing with
all this oil uh so now scroll pump I go
through a valve I can turn on or shut
off the vacuum it goes through this like
four-way T this cross I can bring it to
Atmosphere I have a valve that's now
going to that balloon that's my breath
so just blow into the balloon put my
breath in there I have desiccant there
to remove humidity from my breath and
that way I can now pump my breath I can
pull vacuum from a piece of glass at the
bottom here the mks-91p that's just a
pro it's a pressure gauge the pressure
sensor and then I just break out cereal
and I have a little analog voltmeter on
there so I can see the voltage so I can
basically pump down pull out all of the
air from this glass tube then I can turn
off the vacuum or actually prevent
anything else from being pulled out and
then I can open up that needle valve and
allow my breath to go into this and I
can control the pressure because there's
a needle valve and I'm monitoring the
pressure there and then I can use the
Tesla coil near it to see will it light
up and once I do that
here's the full setup and so I have
basically I have a scroll pump I have
the book right next to me I have very
little space to cook eggs anymore but
that's okay who needs a kitchen this was
the first successful actual ampoule and
uh I think because I had put my breath
in there Sam insisted that I had blew
myself
I'm not sure that's entirely true but
yeah that's what he says and uh that's
actually let's let's see if this thing
works
don't mind the Giant heatsink in my
pocket
um so here we have like the actual uh
ampule as you can see
and here's like a different one
not too hard to see on the uh
[Applause]
right no batteries nothing else just
piece of glass different uh different
gases will produce different um
and I know you'll really want to see
what's down there
so that's all you need a little coil
and uh just some quick things
um here I take a little clear camera I
was just curious to see like what it
looked like um you can actually see this
torb oil or donut shape it pretty what's
interesting to me is that it really only
lights up at the edges
um so you can kind of see like in the
center it will not but down here it will
um I thought that was pretty interesting
and also uh this is just while making it
so here another you can kind of see the
shape a little bit of that field which
is which I think is kind of cool just
the rest of the components used I just
took three lithium cells the 18650
batteries put a battery management
circuit on it because I kept putting
lithium cells without battery management
circuits and I'd wear it for a couple
hours the voltage would go down to like
2.5 volts and then I'd destroy the
battery just kept doing that because I
was lazy
um I use a voltage regulator as a buck
regulator
and that basically takes my voltage
let's say you have three cells you'll be
at I don't know 12.6 volts or something
like that that brings it down to
something like I bring it to town to
about 10 volts because I unfortunately I
have to have this giant heat aluminum
heat sink with a transistor on top so
that's in my pocket and it's just
getting hotter and hotter and hotter
and that's uh that's the rest of it it's
just a Slayer Exciter with these three
components and thank you so much for
coming
all right
[Music]