[Music]
thank you
how many people in the room have a ham
radio license
pretty good pretty good showing kind of
what I'd expect
how many of you that don't have ham
radio licenses know what ham radio is
okay
so
um
I'm going to talk to you about the ardc
and its Grant making process
also at the end we'll be talking about
some of the things that we're working on
this year my compatriot here John is the
head of our technical committee so you
can grab him if that interests you but
I'm going to talk to you about grants
Okay so
you can read this but so can I uh the
mission of amateur radio digital
Communications is to support promote and
enhance digital communication and
broader communication science
and Technology to promote having to
radio scientific research
experimentation education development
Open Access and Innovation and
information Communications technology
it's a mouthful
basically we're promoting ham radio and
also certain uh forms of digital
communication
um
we're a 501c3 that's a non-profit
foundation in the U.S
um 501c3 has some different categories
of foundation is
tightly managed and doesn't necessarily
reach out for funding for multiple
sources
um
and we have to operate under a certain
set of rules and we'll get into that a
little bit
we have an endowment which we can
distribute approximately five to six
million dollars a year out of in fact we
have to
give out a certain amount of money each
year because we're a foundation
and uh
so we don't say how much is in that
endowment but we have to give away five
percent a year
uh so all the mathematicians in the room
know that we're somewhere around
that about 20 times that amount
that endowment was created because back
in the early 1980s packet radio was a
thing a a new thing and a gentleman
named Hank magnuske who actually still
is a volunteer for ardc uh went to John
postel anyone here hear of John Postell
before
he was the god of Internet addresses
back then you'd go to him and say I'm
IBM I need some IP addresses and he'd
give you 16 million of them okay it's
called a Class A Network so Hank went to
John and said hey could we set aside for
amateur radio some addresses and Johnson
sure here's a Class A 16 million
addresses well
that's a lot of addresses and
a few years ago well a little bit of the
history there
um
it was passed down the the stewardship
of those addresses through a series of
individuals and then about 10 12 years
ago ardc was formed to be the steward of
the address space because
unfortunately some of us die over time
and so it's good to have a foundation
there that that carries that on
and then
in 2019 we took the step and said hey
we're not using 16 million addresses for
amateur radio uh maybe we could sell
some of them so we sold 4 million of
those addresses again to a company that
I cannot tell you who it is because the
contracts say that but if you go check
out our 990 tax filing you can find out
who it is so uh anyway uh they bought
them and they paid a market price for
them at the time
the market price has gone up since then
we could have gotten a lot more money
holding on for a few more uh years but
uh
so given that we have this bank money
that we need to give away and we want to
find people to give it away to and
that's my job is to find people to give
money to it's a tough job
I've spent 42 calendar days this year
going out meeting with groups like this
to educate them on how they get their
hands on that money there are some
qualifications
uh we also do not actively do
fundraising we've we've got this
endowment we operate out of that
endowment
um
however we you know if someone wanted to
be Quest somebody or something like that
we have a way to do that but we don't
actively go out and fundraise
um we don't have members there's no
membership to ardc we we operate as a
foundation we have a very small staff
there's six of us John's our newest hire
we're a california-based foundation we
had no california-based employees so we
had to hire John because he lives here
in California I live up near Seattle
our main website is
www.ampr.org anyone know why it's ampr
yep that's where it comes from
um
and we have a board of uh uh volunteers
uh they're all very senior very
experienced people like Phil Karn and
John Gilmore who you may have heard of
Casey who's an academic at UCSD and and
some others and they do an excellent job
as a bunch of volunteers
so we have some requirements if we're
going to give you money and most of
these are governed by law so that's what
we do so there are
three basic groups that we can give
money to
501c3 uh non-profits those could be
Charities or other foundations and so on
or their International equivalents
because we are an international
organization we make grants
internationally
um
there's some complexity to doing
International but we're willing to do
that if you happen to be International
um and you apply and we accept you we
have to go through something called an
equivalency determination where a bunch
of lawyers look over your documents and
the laws from your country
to make sure you're equivalent to a U.S
501c3 we pay for that if if we pick you
so you don't have to come up with the
processing fees non-profit educational
organizations universities schools so on
we can do that governments sponsored
projects that align with our goals we
can give money to the government I've
never known a government to turn away
money
actually they do because there's some
reporting responsibilities and that also
includes tribes the tribal governments
we've done a few grants into tribes
um
so
if you are like in many cases you have
an informal group that is an amateur
radio club that hasn't become a 501c3
you you can go to
an existing 501c3 and have them fiscally
sponsor you
um if they're also a foundation it's
tougher they fall under the same rules
we are if they're a charity or an
educational institution then they can
sponsor you and they can handle the
money and and hand it out to you as
needed we do allow a small amount of
money less than 20 percent of the value
of the grant for someone providing that
service to you
there are also independent organizations
one based here in California called open
Collective you can go to them and apply
if they accept you then they will be
your fiscal sponsor and they take a a
nominal fee of like eight percent or ten
percent uh on top of and we're okay with
that
all righty whoops did I bounce ahead
okay so we have a few categories that
like to fund
support and growth of amateur radio kind
of what you would expect for it if
you've got a project that will add to
the growth of amateur radio whether
that's
teaching classes or building out some
infrastructure we've done a few
microwave IP networks that are
specifically for amateur radio some
other things I mean one of the the
things that we have is we still have
addresses that we can hand out which are
fully routable IP addresses so you know
you can
talk to them from the internet and so on
community outreach things support type
infrastructure some emergency
communications projects we seem to have
a whole bunch of people that thinks it's
really cool to buy a trailer and put
some equipment in it and let it sit 360
days of the year when we put money in
something we want it to be used and we
may do those but you better come to with
the plan of how you're going to do more
than let it sit park somewhere
you know you got a regular schedule
going around to schools and exposing
students or other things like that
um
I guess I keep touching the pat here
accidentally okay so education is the
second one we
it's not hard and fast but we
basically give a quarter of that five
million dollars to scholarship funds so
awrl
um we've done the Society of women
Engineers we've done some we're really
interested in increasing the diversity
in the amateur radio community so we're
really looking for opportunities that
help us do that so we've done some
historically black colleges and
University scholarships and and some
others the scholarships need to be for
STEM related type activities so about a
quarter of the money goes there we also
do for K-12 type projects
um
I don't know that we've done a
fellowship that we consider a fellowship
we've funded
um
a lot of different educational
opportunities out there
research and development this is one
that's near and dear to my heart and we
want to see a lot more of these
collectively which is where you're
extending the art
and this is where the hacker space
Community can really come in we'd be
looking for things like one that we're
funding is called the m17 project which
is a digital voice system that competes
basically with d-star and DMR and and
fusion but it's a hundred percent open
source including the vocoder
and we're funding the development of
that there's some others out there like
that if you have a project that will
advance the art
new applications that might run on uh
digital Communications that kind of
thing that are ham radio related uh
don't have to be hem radio related but
they tend to get more of the attention
um
and and we'd just like to see more of
those and that's why I'm here besides
listening to a bunch of cool
presentations uh one that was
interesting to me earlier was the uh
open source Asic project that they were
talking about nothing I say says you're
going to get approved but we would look
at something like that as long as it was
being done on a non-profits basis and
open source
in fact anything that we fund has to be
okay so to apply for a grant
uh you can apply for Grant anytime
it's done online
we collect them review them and select
grants that we're going to fund four
times a year
the next review period starts February
1st
so anything that's submitted between now
and February 1st will be in that batch
once it's gone through our internal
process which can take
unfortunately two to four months
sometimes so don't
come to us and say we need money in
March in February come to us in February
and say we need money in July okay kind
of thing
um
and basically again we have a small crew
so once you're submitted don't call us
we'll call you if we need more
information because people say I put in
my application and you know we won't
know until the whole process is done but
we'll notify you as soon as we have a
yes or no for you
and like I say if we have questions
we'll reach out to you so
and the application is done online
um
anyone here written a government grant
or an educational grant before
okay you can forget that we're much
more friendly than that
basically there's a couple of ways you
can apply we have a series of questions
in the application you can just fill
those out
the level of detail is probably directly
related to the total amount of the grant
so if you're asking for two thousand
dollars we don't need a big book about
every little detail but if you're asking
for a million and a half we'd like to
understand why uh so
um also the reporting on it is a lot
lighter as well we're not looking for
monthly spreadsheets of how you expended
the funds and stuff uh at the end of the
project you give us a report we said
we'd do this we did this this is we
spent the money you sent us to do these
things uh if your project runs over a
year will last for one at a year and
then again uh later
okay and that's the website
so
um I won't go through everything but
here's some things to think about if
you're going to do a grant request
be sure to re review all the information
on the website first I don't know how
many times I've gotten an email tell me
what the website said you know well go
read it and then come back and ask me
pertinent questions
um
most of our projects are what called
several ready you've already planned it
out you've figured out what you want to
do what your metrics are going to be
um as you do the project and so on
we tend to like one-year projects but if
it's two years it's no big if it's
really long it has to be something
um really significant an example of that
would be uh we gave funds to the heiress
program I think a million and a quarter
or something like that five-year program
we fund up front typically so they got
the money up front
um part of the reason for that
particular formula is uh NASA doesn't
like projects that they don't know where
the fund is going to be so uh the
heiress folks we worked with them and
made that happen but in general we're
looking for uh
let's go
another one is
if you're going to be working with uh
with other groups or facilities and
stuff have it all lined up we've had a
proposal before where oh we're going to
build this great Network and we're going
to put all these uh microwave links on
tops and mountains and they hadn't
negotiated the the sites they knew what
sites they wanted to use but when they
went back there well you know if you got
money we want more money you got nothing
you know so have that all lined up when
you put together your budget include
everything taxes fees any permits that
you need if you're going to need
Professional Services like a tower
climber or an electrician have that all
in the budget right at the beginning
and as I said 20 for indirect costs
um
also the other thing is a lot of times
we have a few hems in the room
they like to be frugal and we like that
but if we're going to buy equipment
to support
a program we want it to last a while so
we'd rather spend
say three thousand dollars for a new
repeater then you get Fred to give you
his 20 year old repeater for 900 so
find good functional equipment but don't
gold plate it you know don't buy the
nine thousand dollar repeater because
your buddy gets a good commission off of
it
um
and have a project plan again the detail
of that project plan is to probably more
directly related to the size of the
projects you're working on and and the
cost of that
foreign
really make your project stand out when
we first started when I had that chart
of money we gave you the first year you
saw 9 million instead of five we were
doing some catch up
and so basically if you'd applied in
that time frame your chances of getting
it through as long as you met through
quiet went pretty good uh now we're
getting uh well this last quarter just
closed the beginning of October we had
an
total number of applications that
exceeded what we give away a year
and so some aren't going to get approved
obviously
so
provide some previous accomplishments
that you've done so that you know you've
got a little bit of a track record if
you're a brand new group explain that
but maybe
tell us a little bit about the people
that are going to be doing it and some
of their accomplishments
um
we're really big on Outreach and and
building Community around the project
that you're doing uh you do need to
adhere to our uh Open Access and open
source policies and Open Access includes
things like
if you came to us and said we're going
to build this great repeater network and
everybody that's going to use it has to
join our club and pay 200 a year we're
not interested in those projects
there's nothing wrong with soliciting
membership but it shouldn't be a
requirement if we're paying for the
equipment okay
um
anything that you're doing that is truly
Innovative tell us about it tell us how
it's innovative
uh but understand what may be Innovative
to you someone else has already done so
um
you know it may be new for your group
you know you just discovered FM okay but
that's not Innovation that's just
it's just getting there uh inclusiveness
and Equity are really important are you
reaching out to a broader Community not
everyone looks like me old gray and
ready to kick the bucket uh
use particularly
um
you know fighting the grain of the hobby
we don't need a book but be complete in
your description
uh
also included if you're doing any other
fundraising you know if you come in and
you ask us for thirty thousand dollars
and you say but we've also raised ten
thousand on our own that's going to
carry more weight than well just give us
40 000 because you got money right so
um keep those things that's right and
finally a statement of how your project
will make a difference make the world a
better place
uh so catch me I'm only going to be here
today I got to get back home I've gotta
uh child that's got a medical situation
right now so I'm leaving first thing
tomorrow morning
um
that's my direct number
uh or you can use that email address
um or in general you just email the
giving at ardc.net that comes to both me
and the grants manager so once your
Grant is approved Chelsea who's
wonderful takes over
and you'll be interacting with her and
that's a good address to have and be
familiar with
we couldn't do this without a bunch of
volunteers and and we have uh two
standing committees
um and we're recruiting uh
volunteers right now we
we recompose the Committees ever for
each calendar year and so we're at the
end of this calendar year so we're
trying to build up the list
uh if you
apply it are accepted as a volunteer for
one of these committees
you can serve up to three terms and then
you have to step out for at least a year
and what some folks do is they just
switch committees because they really
love what we do so what do the two
committees do well the technical
advisory committee which John is the
staff representative for
sets our policy and manages the
remaining IEP address space and
um
does technical Innovation kinds of
things it's really a good place to share
your knowledge and expertise on
technology and networking
uh the grants advisory committee which I
the staff representative that's my
second hat for we decide to get well we
recommend who gets the money so uh when
the applications come in that committee
reviews them weighs them against each
other we have a ranking process we're
trying to get the best uh uh proposals
in each class and uh pass that along
to the board who generally takes the
recommendation of the committee there's
a couple QR codes if you need the URLs
um
so consider if that's something you'd
like to contribute back to the community
by volunteering
um
we're actively by November 12th we need
your application if someone slips a day
we probably will let it in anyway but
we're shooting for November 12th
and finally
q a
that QR code will take you to a a link
tree with a bunch of urls
foreign