thanks for staying or coming everyone
will just continue pretty much right
where Natalie left off I do want to
spend two minutes explaining this
vulnerability it's again like a cycle
issue ordering NS an archiving again in
the shared key dictionary so basically
what you have to know is there is a
shared key dictionary that at the top
right you can see it it's basically an
area of values and a pointer to a shared
key set in a shared key set itself is a
linked list so I can have sub sub sub
key sets and then they have the number
of keys they store then a rank table and
then the area of keys right and so the
way the lookup works is you take the you
you want to look up k1 maybe okay let's
go with k3 so you want to look up k3 you
go to the first shared key set you hash
the value k3 basically and you said AZ
index into the rank table and then the
rank table gives you an index into the
keys area right but that index is bounce
checked against num key okay and so in
this case it wouldn't find the key K 3
in the first he said it would go to the
second key set do the same thing fine k
the key K 3 and then that that's the
index for the values area in the shared
key dictionary why is this important
well really the only important thing
here is this one invariant that Nam key
must be equal to the length of this
array if that's not the case then
there's a big problem because then this
rank table stuff can index out of bounds
let's see how this ended with coda looks
like for for this kind of object it's
fairly straightforward really what it
does is like take all the values out of
the archive right this is like this
decode so decodes the num key field and
the rank table field then it decodes the
sub key set and then the first if
statement that's where it makes sure
this invariant holds right there like
key length of the keys area must be
equal and then interestingly there's a
for loop where it tries to look up every
key
just to make sure that it's like useful
that it can actually look up all the
keys looks pretty much okay but let's
see what happens when we try to mess
with it so we start with an empty shared
key set at the top we start decoding
these values okay Nam key let's put in
some some interesting values ffff and
four one four one four one and then we
go and decode a second one here and we
do the whole thing again right we start
from the top we fill in all these values
and now we actually make a cycle and
this is like not not how you're supposed
to do it and you make a cycle back to
shared key set one and this actually
works there's handling less logic in the
key to an archiver to make this possible
okay and then we decode the keys and
this is okay right like dumb key and the
ranked the keys length is the same and
now we try to look up every key and so
in this case we are here we decode away
we look up the key and shared key said -
and it isn't being found because the
index is 42 it's not that's not the
right one so we recursed
to share key said one and now all of a
sudden here we have a memory corruption
because now this invariant doesn't hold
right it's Nam key is hex ffffff so it's
things this keys area is gigantic but
really it's Niall pointer and so we can
access an arbitrary address and have
that be used as an objective-c object so
that's the bug it gives us an arbitrary
address dereference and that's what
we're going to exploit now right so this
is just a summary again our bug
primitive so how do you exploit this
kind of bug um basically what you need
to do is to create some kind of fake
object and have that object be used
right so this pointer that's being read
this absolute point is that's being
treated as a pointer to an object is the
object and it will call methods on it so
that should be exploitable if we can
fake these in particular I think it will
call like dialogue or is nsstring on
this thing and so what you would have to
do is like fake an objective-c object
I have a class pointer that
points to a fake objective-c class and
then that Objective C class has the
function pointers and those will be
called so once you have control over
that you can get code execution now the
obvious problem we have here is a SLR so
we don't actually know where anything is
in memory we don't know where our fake
object end up when we put them in memory
and we also don't know where libraries
are so we don't have code point us and
we'll take a this problem in two parts
part one is will do heap spraying which
is an old technique but it still works
and so what you do basically is you
allocate maybe 256 megabytes of memory
this is fairly easy over iMessage
actually due to the an archiver and once
we have allocated that much memory then
at this one address the hex one one
seven zeros there will be control data
our data and so this is how we can put
fake objects into memory which is spray
to 256 megabytes and then our fake
objects are located at a known address
and it's pretty good the second part is
more complicated so the problem we now
still have is we don't know any code
pointers and so because we can't like
inject executable code into the process
we have to know the addresses of
existing executable code so we need
library addresses and this problem I had
two different approaches for that for
taking that problem and I kind of
followed both but then I I didn't really
get the first one to work but the second
one worked but I still want to go
through both of them because I think
they are kind of interesting the idea
for the first one is basically to work
around a SLR and and like deal with not
knowing these addresses so one typical
example here's a partial pointer over
writes all right if you like have a one
buy it over right into a pointer then
you can do some interesting stuff
without actually knowing where the
pointer points to this doesn't work here
because of the bug the bug is like an
absolute address D ref but maybe we can
do something similar where anti second
ideas to properly I guess break a SLR
and get addresses through then yeah
fake objects and so on start with the
first one so the rough idea I had was to
to do a heap spray without knowing
library addresses but instead having the
the application itself put in some
pointers into the sprayed into the
contents of the heap spray so maybe it
makes it more clear with this image so
my heap spray is at this hex 1 1 7 0
Edwin's and what I want to put there are
fake objects that have some valid
pointers in them that the application
itself puts in there and then I have a
pointer maybe to some interesting global
object and since that's part of a faked
object maybe I can make the process do
something interesting to it like that's
the really vague idea that I had one
example how this can work in our
scenario here is the the nskeyedarchiver
it allows decoding C style arrays like
well just fixed sized arrays you said
I'd like give me 10 an area of 10 or
decode me 10 integers or so and actually
it also supports decoding class pointers
for I don't know why and it seems like a
really absurd feature but what what this
lets you do is it lets you create a
linear array in memory with pointers to
classes and then if you look at
objective-c objects and in memory and
Objective C object is just a pointer to
a class and then the fields that it has
right and so with that we can suddenly
create somewhat valid looking
objective-c objects without knowing
addresses so it makes this more clear
the picture at the bottom the archive if
we put in pretty much just has the
string NS array in it where it's like
this is an array of classes and each
entry is the class NS array so I just
need the name of the class and then the
keyed an archiver will go ahead and like
look up the name of this class look up
the class object and put in the pointer
to their class into this memory buffer
and so I end up with this memory dump on
the right side
and now this suddenly looks like a
legitimate NS array because the first
quad word is a pointer to a class
the emissary class and so now I've been
able to fake objects without actually
knowing any addresses I pursued this a
bit further
I guess the farthest I got was I I was
able to basically free some object and
then make the application lower or
decrement some ref count now that that
ref count would also be appointed to a
class I would like that the thing that
would be whether refcon would be
decremented was also pointed to a class
and so it just so happened that if you
look at a class object the first quad
word is again appointed to a class I
made a class and the second quad word is
the pointer to the super class right so
Objective C has inheritance and these
class objects the second quadrant is
always the pointer to the super class
and now due to this reference County
command it was I was able to defer meant
the second pointer to the superclass
which is kind of hilarious because it
lets lets you change the inheritance
hierarchy at runtime because this is
writable but it's not immediately useful
at least I couldn't really see something
immediately what we are to do with this
so I kind of gave up on that idea but I
still think it it could be done there's
probably more you can do like more
primitives we can gain by by faking
object in a similar way or doing other
clever things so that's why I wanted to
include it here the other option that
ended up working is well properly
defeating a SLR which which has two
steps or two parts to it the one the
first part is we need some kind of
communication channel to leak data back
and the second part is we have to
exploit the back in in such a way that
we get some info over this communication
channel so let's deal with the channel
first here's a screenshot of iMessage
and here you can nicely see the three
different states a message can be in
the first one is red the second is
delivered and the third is none of those
and the way this works is through
deliver or I guess received a message
received
and so there's read received which say
yes I got this message and the user
actually read it
and the second type is delivery received
and those are sent automatically which
makes it very interesting by this I am
agent process that Natalie mentioned and
and so we get them automatically once
the message arrives in I am agent and so
this is going to be our communication
channel because now we get some kind of
information back from the process so
let's build something cool with that are
an Oracle on the Left there is some
rough pseudocode about how this this
message processing and I am agent works
and the delivery received sending and so
the key point here is that the NS an
archiving happens before the delivery
received is being sent and what this
gives us now it's basically a crash or
occur because if we can trigger a crash
during the on archiving then we won't
see a delivery received and if we don't
crash then we see a delivery received so
all of a sudden we have a one basically
one bit information leak did it crash
did it not crash and now the remaining
challenge is to crash when some
condition is met so that we infer some
kind of some piece of information from
that okay so that's the communication
channel let's go to exploitation before
we do that um some some iOS internals
there's this thing called ey LD shared
cache the idea is to take all the the
majority of system libraries and you pre
link them into one gigantic binary blob
which is around one gigabyte in size so
it's pretty gigantic and that is shared
and mapped in all userspace processes on
iOS and there's three things about this
that are very interesting the first is
it's always mapped in this address
region of four gigabyte between
one eight and two eight seven zeroes the
second is the randomization granularity
is four thousand hex four thousand bytes
because of large pages in iOS but the
third is the most interesting one the
shared cache is actually mapped at the
same address in every process on this on
the same device so it's only randomized
per boot is what this means which means
that for example if we crash I am agent
we know that when it responds the next
time the shared cache is still at the
same address
okay so let's build an Oracle um the the
bug that I showed that gives us the
arbitrary address D ref primitive can it
basically gives us this Oracle function
so we put in some address and it will
only not crash if the address is mapped
and then if the value that's at that
address is either 0 or if it like looks
like a valid objective-c pointer which
means that kind of the most significant
bit said then it it looks like a tank
pointer or it actually points to a valid
objective-c thing so only if these
conditions are met will it not crash
when we give it an address otherwise it
will crash and now we can observe this
crash because we either get a delivery
received or we don't so that's the idea
so what do we do with this part off line
so that this doesn't need network
connection we will basically compile a
profile of the shared cache given this
oracle function so this is really simple
you you take that wire shared cache you
get it from IPSW whatever so you have
this huge binary you take the Oracle
function and you just run it over the
entire shared cache and the result is
basically like a bitmap right bit 1 bit
0 a bit 1 depending on whether this
function returns true or false and so
here at the bottom you can see an
example profile and maybe the white area
means this is where it wouldn't crash
and the black area means this is where
it would crash when probing
in practice there's a search state
because for example there's a writable
area in the shared cache and you don't
know if that at runtime what what will
be there but it makes it it's easier to
explain with a true state I'm sorry I
was a true state profile so the next
step is then to do some linear memory
scan we know the the possible region
where the shared cache is mapped you can
see it on the right in this image and so
we just go in like for example 256
megabytes increments and just go over
this range query this Oracle and at some
point it will return true or like we
will get it
delivery received and then we know okay
we have found some address somewhere in
the shared cache like maybe this 1900
seven four zero zero zero okay the next
thing we do is again offline we have to
now compute all the possible base
addresses sorry that would lead to us
not crashing on this particular address
that we just probed and this is again
very easy and we just go in page size
steps over our shared cache profile and
now every where every in this picture
every white region is now a potential
candidate right because this this is the
the the eight bytes that we could have
just probed in this case and so in
practice I think this will leave us with
maybe 30 to 40 cells and candidates
because the share caches gigantic it's
like oh well like one gigabyte also in
size okay so we have all these
candidates last step we need to
eliminate them until we have just one
remaining and I think this is either
best to explain with an image so suppose
I just have five five candidates left
here and there they are now all mapped
at different addresses that's why they
like shifted right and you can see the
initial address that we probed
it like goes only through white white
space because it didn't crash right so
that's the initial errors and now we
pick another address to probe so that
roughly half of the candidates will have
a 1-bit and the other half has a zero
bit and so this way regardless of what
this this Oracle returns we are able to
roughly discard half the remaining
candidates right so in this case if it
crashes then we know we either have the
first or the last profile right because
there's that this is why the black areas
and if it doesn't crash we have one of
the three middle ones and so we just
keep doing this and in every step we
basically have the number of remaining
candidates and so this is really fast in
practice this takes like 20 or so
queries to go from 30,000 candidates to
just one okay so and this will then tell
us the base address of the shared cache
right so I think I have just about
enough time so this now this is what it
looks like we have all the addresses and
this is good enough for any device that
doesn't support pointers indication
which is every device before the iPhone
10s on the 10s and you are Apple has a
new feature called point authentication
half-minute idea is that you take
everything that's a function pointer can
be any point in theory and you sign it
ID process startup for example and so
you do this with a specific instruction
as you can see in the bottom and then
you have a signature and you store that
in the top bits and then before using a
pointer for example for jumping to it
you are CENTAC eight and make sure the
signature is actually valid and if it's
not then you crash and so this prevents
us from doing like directly gaining a
control over the PC program counter
because we we are not able to fake these
these signatures so we need to bypass
back so this pretty much what I said
right we cannot
make these code point us anymore the
idea for the bypass roughly is that why
we cannot use what we cannot fake
classes we can reuse existing classes
and so here in this case I have a fake
objective-c object but it points to real
existing class with signed function
pointers and this will ultimately give
me some form of arbitrary objective-c
method called primitive where we can
call any method or almost any method
with pretty much controlled arguments
and this is powerful enough this is all
that necessary okay so we cannot execute
arbitrary objective-c methods also
outside of the same box because this was
on iOS 12.4 whether the archiving still
happened outside of a sandbox connects
this user data etc we don't care about
that we just want to calculator the way
to do it is you call this one or one way
to do it is you call this one
objective-c method to launch an
application name the calculator and
let's see we can get that to work
[Music]
yeah okay so this is the iPhone I'm
using it's still on 1234 right so this
is the last one a bit version like at
this point more than half a year old and
[Music]
let's start this I hope it works
okay so what what you can see now okay
it's recording it's kind of unnecessary
anyway what you can see now is it's
going to do this linear scanning phase
right and it's nicely telling us what
it's doing at this point
and so it's probing these these
addresses and I think this step is is
128 or 256 megabytes increments and so
it's testing these addresses and it's
not getting a delivery received back so
it assumes okay it crashed and now this
for this one address the hex 1b it did
get a receipt back and don't know us
okay it has found a valid address and it
has it did this this candidate
computation thing and figured it had 32
thousand candidates and now it's going
to roughly half that number in every
with every additional additional message
so you can see it already went down to
fifteen or sixteen thousand roughly and
it will keep doing that and I think I
can actually take questions now while
this runs this will take like another
one or two minutes so maybe it's a good
time to take questions if there are any
at this point all right there no come on
make me run through the room idea I
thank you for it talk first of all I
guess that only works because I miss
like restarting in the background all
the time because it's crashing exactly
right so and this is really important so
the I am agent is just restarted every
time it crashes there's
one ones one thing happen that happens
is if it crashes too quickly there will
be a respawn delay like there will be a
penalty and it won't be restarted for a
couple of minutes and so I always have
to wait about 10 seconds between two
consecutive crashes and this is why I
can only will probe the Oracle every
once every 10 seconds roughly but it's
like it's really not a not a big issue
and this is probably something that
should be fixed if it's not already
fixed that this demon just restarts all
the time you know okay almost through I
think I'm also almost out of time let's
see if it finishes in 30 seconds I don't
think it will but yeah so it has found
the base address now it's 1988 Ruby four
zeros and now it's doing a heap spray
and this is also really really happy
right now I think so I'm like doing this
unless you can say well in 24 steps I'm
very certain with some better
engineering you could do the whole heap
spray in one single message and like to
one sing a message that this heap spray
+ trigger the Bach but I am doing this
in like 25 or so yeah sorry Stefan I I
hope it's gonna work it better okay
okay so let's see so when it triggers
actually the phone freezes the UI
freezes for a couple of seconds I don't
know why but I think that's what
happened now because the second on the
clock the seconds don't move further yes
yes
awesome just just quick quick at least
yeah there is a chance that it fails and
if so do you know why is it possible it
fails so it's possible that it fails but
not nothing that can be that can't be
fixed so one reason is if the there's a
srr bypass if it finds a like writable
page and find something where actual
pointer is then right now this
implementation handles this incorrectly
and also the heaps phrase it would be
much much better if it happened in one
message because now like some allocation
happens between two of these then it
could failure