what we're gonna be talking about today
is self-driving self racing cars and the
awesomeness that you can build on your
own so without further ado let's get
started so first things first in case
you guys don't know I'm the founder of
hack in the Box one of the guys that's
responsible for answering most of the
emails if you've ever sent an email to
Tom Prince in for a hack at the box at
all most likely I think the guy who
actually replied if you guys want to
follow me I'm on Twitter beep dog and
little bit more I use the right code
long long time ago now I write emails
mainly but I'm also an AI and m/l
enthusiast so I spend my days in
Victorian writing emails building models
screwing around with machine learning
stuff and some AI stuff I also live in
Malaysia in case any of you guys are
wondering I have two cats they're more
famous than I am they've got more
Instagram followers anyway if you guys
want to follow them they can't null and
void because well hacker you have to
have cats that have hacked their names
right so the twin cats not in void they
drive me crazy they ruin all my
furniture which is why I have hardly any
furniture and so when we talk about AI
and self-driving cars pretty much these
two papers are like quote unquote
state-of-the-art right there's one
people they came out if I'm not mistaken
in June of this year which is the deeper
car and both of these papers while
they're essentially what we would call
therapy are they work essentially on the
same principle thank you
they're essentially taking input from
various sensors that are on the vehicle
then you train your neural networks on
those things and then you know it drives
itself so if you want to get into
self-driving cars self racing cars I'm
guessing most of you guys don't have
like a whole 100 K just lying around not
doing anything with it so what can you
do
so my case suddenly becomes so is to
look at this project called the donkey
car project this is what it looks like
the little picture on the left there is
a Raspberry Pi with a small little
camera on the front of it and it's
behavioral cloning so while it is
machine learning and it is artificial
intelligence to some extent they're very
basic right like a real self-driving car
like a Tesla for example has numerous
different sensors lidar radar cameras
obviously all around the car as well
this has one camera so it's not like a
super complex self-driving car but it
allows you to experiment and it allows
you to learn the principles that would
be needed if you wanted to get into
autonomous vehicles and you wanted to
start building your own self-driving car
so how does it work essentially you are
steering it and it's taking the camera
input which is what the car would be
seen and so the camera that's on the on
the Raspberry Pi is got like a very
limited depth of field feel of you and
is looking at for like a centerline and
the two white lines on either side it's
taking the input from as you are driving
the car or its behavior including so
it's pretty much trying to follow what
you are doing
so as you drive it along it's taking
your total input it's also taking in
your steering angles and with those two
things you pump that into your neural
network and hopefully the car will drive
itself right and so on a more technical
level it's a competition network
basically episode you've got like a 120
pixel high image by 160 you've got three
RGB channels so it that forms your
vectors and any pump that into a
convolutional I think it's like nine
layers maybe ten years so it's not even
a neural network as what they would call
right I snidely and Euler network man
it's not that deep but most of the state
of VR papers are all essentially doing
the same thing right
in a nutshell obviously some might be a
little bit more technical they might do
some kind of like sub models on a model
and maybe they have to
generative episode of networks trying to
like learn it from each other but
essentially the all convolutional
networks anyway
so it's that one take a picture right
you take that from the camera input you
pass that over as your user input so as
you're driving the car the car is using
shoulda brought the car it's actually at
the AI village
guys can come over and check it out in a
bit but it's taking you have like a
PlayStation controller that's on
Bluetooth connected to the car and it's
taking the input from that via HTTP
posts on a web server that's running on
the Raspberry Pi so it's like I said
it's taking your shuttle values as well
as your steering angles as you drive it
around it's recording all of these along
with images that are coming from the
camera and then we use that to update
the servos so all the RC cars are using
PWM so pulse width modulation and so
those signals are actually translated
from the Raspberry Pi to your servos and
that's actually controlling your actual
car and use that save it into a data
frame so you've got your pairs of data
so you've got the actual images that are
coming from the camera and then you've
got the steering input and the total
input and those two things is saved as a
JSON file and any Pompton seen new
neural network and so it all runs on
chorus tensorflow how many people here
are familiar with that okay cool
hey Lisa some people in here that into
chorus I love chorus having chorus is
the Bob because tensorflow if you've
ever tried if you clear off in your
networks a tensorflow
likes up one point zero or one point
zero between one point one all the way
to one point six it's like a pygmy ass
because it's very very very low level
the amount of code that you need to
write just to get a basic functionality
working makes it quite tedious to build
models and to experiment but chorus
abstracts a lot of that away from you so
you don't actually need to know about
the actual tensile values you have a
high level you can just pretty much this
is like the actual code from from the
autopilot itself and you can see it's
not that difficult to read I mean it's
like human readable you can kind of
understand it you're building like you
know combinational layers of various
sizes with the strides and then you
flatten all of that you've got a dense
you do some drop out not usually the
best idea but in considering this is a
Raspberry Pi this is like really very
small compute power you can't do too
or to complex computations on it and
basically with this model you would have
a card I can follow a line at least
you'll follow the other line in the
middle of the road and it's looking at
the two side lines and is trying to
clone your behavior so if you were to
build itself a track it could be a small
track could be a big track you'll need
to drive it around the track probably
between eight to ten times to get enough
training data from that and then you
pump that into your neural network and
train on it
so when you talk about the hardware it's
not expensive right a real self-driving
car real test love with all of its
hundreds of thousands of dollars of
equipment is beyond most people's budget
but you could build yourself a donkey
car for three hundred five US dollars
which is pretty good it's quite cheap
you can actually get all this stuff
online so if you don't want to buy it we
can buy it as a kid if you wanted to or
you already have some of these parts
this is like the the cost breakdown of
what it would take
there's actually a store that you can go
to and it will ship you the actual car
plus the Raspberry Pi plus the camera
plus the 3d printed the chasis where you
can mount the camera onto it comes with
all the nuts all the bolts and it's
quite easy to put together
I mean it's essentially already built
and you just have to tighten the nuts
and then on the software side if you
already have Raspberry Pi then this
helps a lot because you can actually
start experimenting that's an actual
simulator which I'll talk about in a
little bit but if you really have a
Raspberry Pi and you don't have the kit
but you just want to play around and
learn a little bit more about neural
networks you can download like a
prebuilt binary it's a simple image
basically just like download that
classic the Raspberry Pi and then on
your host machine side you set up your
virtual environment and install all of
your tents off so stuff if you ever
tried to compile that from sauce like
it's gonna take a day and a half so use
the pipe installer really helpful saves
a lot of time and so as I mentioned as a
simulator and it's built in unity if any
of you guys are gamers you'll definitely
be familiar with the Unity engine and
the simulator
helps tremendously because you're gonna
crash the first time you compile your
mirror on that welcome to the guide you
like self-drive it's not gonna end well
it's pretty much gonna end in disaster
so I would strongly recommend
downloading the unity simulator if you
really want to get into this as a hobby
there are teams all over the world in
fact the docutel project if I'm not
mistaken it's all at the US but they've
got a local community group in Hong Kong
also in Europe so check out the slack
channel and if you have your Odin kit
obviously it's no fun playing video with
yourself racing against yourself so join
the slack channel because there's a lot
of other guys that will probably
encounter the same set of issues that
you would have liked you might find that
the car doesn't really do what it says
it's supposed to do a trade Nate I've
driven it around like whatever two
hundred times from the track it still
crashes it still doesn't follow the line
join the psych channel download Beauty
simulator allows you to experiment more
so you can actually start playing around
with like I don't know let's just say
you set your dropper at 0.5 doesn't
really work so well that it 0.3 try 0.7
you know you can experiment a little bit
more and that helps tremendously because
trying to compile the model on your host
machine and then transferring it that
over to your little car takes a lot of
time well we have a simulator then you
can just compile it move it over to the
model running this simulator see if it
works and so what you can do with all of
this stuff right we're actually putting
together a challenge for next year's
Amsterdam conference and we're gonna
provide hackerspaces hackers enthusiasts
students who ever liked anybody in this
room Bay City and can join this contest
we're still formulating the rules of it
so I I forget you know we'll probably
give each team two batteries and we'll
model it after like the Formula One
style of competition basically well we
have maybe two or three days of open
practice
we'll build a track we'll probably go
and we wanted to build it outdoors but
then being that it's Amsterdam and
always rains we thought mmm not such a
good idea
electronics what the doesn't really go
so well so we're trying to find a space
that's indoors where we can
set up a track and you can bring your
cars with you if you already have a
complete car kit bring it along and if
you don't we'll provide you guys the kit
so we obviously can't provide kit for
like a hundred teams so we're inviting
people to register if you wanna join us
the competition is going to be running
at the Amsterdam conference which is on
the 6th to the 10th of me excuse me so 6
7 & 8 will have your free practice and
then we'll probably do a qualification
round on the 9th and then the top 10
teams will move on to like final race
tape and in addition to that how many
people are familiar with the more videos
neural compute stick from Intel it's
pretty much like a little USB thumb
drive that lets you offload a lot of the
neuro computing power that would be on
your Raspberry Pi to this device and
that allows you to go faster go harder
go better I'm still hacking along with
it and it sort of works but there's now
a new more videos and C 2 version 2 that
has just come out apparently it's
attracted a lot of the api's out and it
makes it a lot easier to implement it
because the initial version for more
videos from Intel they have an API but
it's like completely not documented
which is kind of strange for Intel and
there's not really a lot of peyten
integration going on but we'll give each
of the teams move idiots so the guys who
actually managed to train the neural
network and get the car to run around
our track and not crash we will give you
guys some videos so that you can
hopefully go faster and then in Dubai
next year so literally a year from now
we'll be back again here in October and
obviously this Formula one in Abu Dhabi
right so we thought hah what can we do
to like make it even more interesting
that's actually a project based out of
MIT called race car J it uses a jetson
which is a small little embedded
computing platform and in this
particular instance of what by
competition were opening it up to any
engineering teams any university
research teams to build themselves a
mighty race car J all the documentation
and how to build it and all the hardware
stuff is online but it's a little bit
more expensive like the donkey guys like
300 bucks the MIT race car J if I'm not
mistaken with the lidar plus the jetson
the base car and all the modifications
need to make brings it up to around
three thousand five hundred US dollars
so it's a little bit more expensive but
it'll be fun and we're inviting any of
you guys who are interested in this
the 1/16 scale cars are going to be in
Amsterdam and then the 110 scale cars
which are slightly larger will have an
outdoor track we're actually thinking of
actually using the outdoor area of the
parking lot here because it's like lots
of space and it never rains in Dubai so
they'll last two days in difference but
it generally does not rain in Dubai so
that should help will not limit you guys
on sensors or hardware so we want to put
in you know to light us then light us up
to you man I mean really have at it we
probably might put in some limitations
on batteries just to make it fair
because you know people are going to
come up with like I don't know 20,000
mAh batteries that have 50 C discharged
which means the cars can go like
lightning which will not be very fast so
we're still formulating the rules but if
you're university research team you're
encouraged to apply that QR code if you
scan it takes you to a Google Form for
the Amsterdam conference so if you guys
are interested in signing up and you
don't have your own kit sign up pass
because like I said we only have 20 kids
to give away so the first compass of the
teams that register will get it if
you've got to bring your own donkey car
or some then no big deal this little
form there you can fill it and say I
have my own donkey car I don't need the
kit so you won't deprive other people
from having a chance to play that's it
pretty much
sorry like once again that we don't have
the right speaker here for you guys but
hopefully this was a little bit more
interesting and if you guys want to see
the cars and actually see the hardware
that's on it and you have any further
questions I'm at the AI village which is
if you go out of this door that map go
all the way down to the end you can't
miss it it's like the last booth it's on
right thanks guys hope to see you guys
in Amsterdam enjoy the rest of the
conference is going to be fantastic I'm
quite excited have a nice day thank you
Dylan