what we're going to talk about today is
basically the evolution of
telecommunications threats it's not a
technical talk we don't have time for
that is it's kind of a historical review
of what where we came from and where
we're going with telecommunications
security so we basically have an agenda
that goes through a generation of of
telecoms and I'll just go through that
briefly so where where did we start we
actually started in China 1800 before
Christ so this is a long time ago and
the Chinese they were already at war
they already had a lot of conflicts and
need to communicate about those conflict
and to their generals remotely and they
were using smoke signals to do that so
it's quite interesting to see that the
first telecommunication technology
started in China because basically
that's where it ends as well and
nowadays the major telecommunication
vendors are Chinese what was interesting
about the smoke signals is that they
suffer from the same threats to their
security model as modern communication
technology as we are going to review and
after that we had in Greece still before
the Christian era some evolution of the
smoke signals they use a more
sophisticated way with basically with
with fire and same principle they would
have they would use visual indicators to
communicate their messages when we
evolved from that we of course hid the
telegram which was invented in 1844 you
know what it is I'm not going to remind
you and followed closely by a telephone
and all those technologies share the
same threat model which we're going to
discuss also historical milestones in
telecommunications are the semaphore
another form of signal to communicate
messages so Telegraph
wireless telegraphy by Tesla was an
amazing inventor as you know and
invented that in 1893 the first radio by
Marconi which is really a huge
breakthrough in telecommunications fiber
optics were invented in the 1920s even
though most of us didn't get to enjoy it
until almost a century later the first
cellular telephone was actually used by
the Swedish police in 1946
now Scandinavia has always been at the
forefront of telecommunications
development they also created the first
mobile networks etc the first
communication satellites were put into
orbit in the 60s and the real first
mobile phone was the 1973 Motorola we'll
have a picture of that later and the
first cellular network was in Japan in
1979 what's interesting about Nikola
Tesla is a guy I mentioned earlier he
that it was quite a visionary and if you
read what he was writing in 1926 was
talking about a device where we could
hear one another as perfectly as though
we were face to face despite intervening
distance of thousands of miles and this
would fit in our pockets I mean this one
in 1926 I mean could you predict
communication technology in year 2100 I
doubt it but this guy he was a visionary
so let's go to the first generation of
mobile telephony and we'll also briefly
talk about the fixed line telephony
because it's also part of
telecommunications not you've got a nice
picture of the phone that was called a
brick which is a very first generation
and the basic security problems as I
told you were the same as the early
generation of communication technology
including smoke signal is we have a lack
of authentication you don't really know
who sent you that message
I mean someone else could be putting up
a fire and making smoke signals right
it's very difficult to protect against
interception because your smoke signals
or your semaphore what
they can be seen by somebody else so
they can be intercepted and messages
could be replayed you know there's no
integrity in the message so all those
technologies were suffering from that
including as a fixed line telephony but
with a subtle difference the thick line
telephony is what we call the walled
garden model which means all the
infrastructure is privately while at the
time state-owned and it wasn't reachable
by the public the only way you could
interfere with the telecommunication
network was to do what's called blue
boxing in the early days of in-band
signaling you can see a blue box on that
picture blue box was a device that would
send some frequencies that would mimic
the frequencies used by the operators to
control that network now they were able
to do that because the signalling was in
band in band which means the same
channel as the speech so because it was
on the same channel you had access to it
telecoms are always controlled by
signalling from the first moment they
they existed and the blue boxing was a
lot of fun I mean there are some very
famous figures including for example
Steve Jobs who played with the blue box
it was a very fun device you could
basically tell the switch to well first
you would dial a toll-free number so you
wouldn't have any charge on your phone
bill and then you would tell the switch
well just clear that call and then you
would send the dialing sequence for
another number and then you would be
connected to the other number but the
bidding system would still believe you
would be calling that toll-free number
so because of that you were able to do
not only free calls but also calls that
could not be traced because if they were
Trace they would they wouldn't have the
proper billing record so they wouldn't
be able to find where the call
originated from there were other forms
of boxing cluding red boxing beige
boxing in chess tries they all involved
mimicking tones
that's a networks use for signaling and
other issues with fixed networks where
subscription fraud this is a classic and
do it in everywhere your register line
was a fake identity run up charges and
then you disconnect all you would
connect to your neighbor's line etc and
PBX which is still happening today I
believe there was a talk about it in ith
ITB and this year here PBX are basically
a mini switchboard used by companies it
can be abused and then you can do free
calls etc but this was mostly for the
old days so one very important landmark
that involve fixed network which I have
to mention because for many hackers of
the older generation this was a stunning
point for them it's a movie wargames and
I in the movie wargames was the first
time the public was introduced to what
is known now as war dining and reward an
income from the movie name which is
basically dialing number after number
with the modem and waiting for it to
answer and when it answered you would
try a low-key name password you will try
all sorts of things and you would
discover a lot of things that this was
very popular in the 80s obviously after
the movie was released in 1984 and in
the 90s nowadays they're not so many
systems connected to modems but they
still are some so I suppose some people
are still watering but you there
wouldn't be much because nowadays in
internet and also technologies to
connect systems so the fixed network was
pretty secure mean apart from those
little cases I described because it was
closed and we will see later that this
is also the models at the mobile
technology used and it worked for a
while
and eventually it's sort of caught up
with seven so let's review those mobile
technologies so first really so what we
call 1g which is analog technology it
was started in the in Scandinavia in the
Nordic countries and MT no-dick mobile
telephony and in the US they developed a
similar version called amps which was
analog and the problem with analog is
that well first you can intercept the
calls all you needed was a frequency
scanner
pictured here and you would intercept
communications because they were not
encrypted that's a very that was quickly
a big problem the other issue with
analog systems is that they were not
properly authenticated the only thing
that would attenti kate was a serial
number that she would have on the phone
as you can imagine a serial number is
not a really strong security measure
especially that it can be you could just
find out easily about it and once you
had it you would be able to clone the
phone well just reuse that serial number
and you would make free calls based on
someone else accounts so that was a
problem and the lack of encryption
basically made everything impossible to
secure other limitations of analog
phones was they were of course using at
the time basic and proprietary firmware
which was by no means secure they had no
data capabilities whatsoever which in a
way was good for them because no data
means no hackers would use it for making
hacking the base man and the main CPU
were not segregated which is the case in
in modern phones now so the part that
controls the radio and the part that
control the phone where I'm the same
processor there was no secure and clave
to store cryptography keys because there
were no cryptographic keys there was
absolutely no integrity mechanism you
couldn't run any custom software there
would be no roaming so they were not
really a target for hackers I mean
hackers were busy at the time with a
fixed line with internet that got
started and with x.25 etc so to counter
those problems with first generation of
mobile phones GSM got started right it's
a it started as a European consortium
with major telecom vendors and
manufacturers and was called group
special Mobile which is a French term
and eventually they because it became
international they renamed it to GSM
global system for mobile
telecommunication and it was a very
serious and successful at
at building a secure Network first they
dealt with interception by encrypting
over-the-air with protocols called a
five and a three and they had
unfortunately semi proprietary algorithm
when I say semi proprietary means they
were not disclosed to the public but the
operators had access to them because the
operator said airwaves we don't want to
trust you we need to know what you're
doing sure the algorithm now anyone
who's been dealing with cryptography
knows that it's a bad idea to have
private algorithm as the only secure
crypto algorithm is the one that has
been reviewed by peers that wasn't the
case and we'll see what it's a problem
it led to the authentication was really
a breakthrough they separated the
identity from the phone itself so the
SIM card you carry in your pocket in
your phone it's actually a secure device
that store your cryptographic keys and
you cannot extract those cryptography
keys I mean the secret key cannot be
extracted from a syn SIM all you can
tell the same is do those computations
calculate that challenge response
calculate that cipher etc so because of
that you couldn't steal the secret key
needed for decryption or for faking
authentication so this made it very very
secure some other interesting
development of that technology was
caller ID which at the time was the
breakthrough in mobile communications
you could see who was calling you and on
the infrastructure side very serious
developments advent of ss7
which is what we call out-of-band
signaling now remember what I said about
in ban you could control a
telecommunication network by you know
you know replaying the tones it was
using to control it but with ss7 the
signaling system number seven this is
not possible anymore all the control is
outside of the channels you have access
to so you cannot reach this a7 network
and therefore you cannot abuse it and of
course this very successful technology
had a huge growth in worldwide
deployment and that's what we are all
using today
there were other competing technologies
in late 90s early 2000s but basically
GSM and it's evolutions remained so for
a while there were absolutely no
security issues
no one knew how to break the GSM model I
would say up to 1998 there was
absolutely no security witnesses no
reported vulnerability is no abuse
nothing only some academic research into
radio protocols that could denial of
service attacks sort of sort of stuff
like that
however in 1999 and 1998 some of the
crypto algorithm leaked someone at an
operator I decided that it would be a
good idea to for the public to review
that so eventually people got their
hands into the comm point two eight
which is the hash algorithm and to a 5-1
and a 5-2 which has the encryption
algorithm and there were some
interesting results the first security
paper on GSM security was published
published in Asia in 2001 at blackhat
Hong Kong in Singapore by myself
actually so this sort of raised interest
people to study more in this field at
the time the security model of the SIM
card was still not broken the
infrastructure was still not compromised
and the signalling was completely out of
ban there was that was the test of
freaking which was you know freaking is
a term used to to characterize the
hackers that were abusing the early
phone systems so because of this script
analysis research well the security
model became under threat now when
people knew that there were
vulnerabilities in algorithms they
started thinking what can we do with
this what can we how can we abuse the
discovery for doing nasty stuff so let's
see what they started doing first sim
cloning was made available by a guy
called Pacino
that through the algorithms that was
leaked so because of that you would be
able to clone SIM cards make free calls
etc then more research by the same guy
on the a5 algorithm which at the time
was able to break the cryptography but
it wasn't really practical yet the
security model was broken he could show
how to do the to decrypt the traffic but
it was really computationally intensive
so it wasn't practical yet that there
were more crypts analysis by biryeo
cough and Shamir you know she Mirza s in
RSA and vise man in 1999 and then the
hackers started to get interested in
that so at the CCC event you know the
cows Computer Club which was the oldest
hacking group in in Europe they do an
event every winter which if it's very
technical it's a very good event and two
guys caster Knoll and Tobias Engel
started publishing how to abuse those
vulnerabilities in a more practical way
and of course this meant this was the
open door to abuse on top of that people
working inside the mobile operators they
started to say hey wait we have access
to those systems what can we do and they
started to abuse it and you had a lot of
insider fraud cases that were being
developed and because of those
vulnerabilities and the publication by
at the CCC etc people started developing
what we call emcee catchers now emcee
catchers abuse those vulnerabilities to
allowed interception man-in-the-middle
attacks and EMC tracking MC is an
internal number that is associated to
your phone identity well to your to your
account ready and law enforcement
agencies they started using that because
even though there is a lawful
interception system in every mobile
network the problems that you need a
usually a court order or some sort of
warrant to be able to use it so
the police and the intelligence agencies
they say wait if we use an MC catcher we
don't need to ask permission from anyone
so of course this became very popular
and the next thing that got very
interesting for hackers is that at the
beginning there's GSM was wasn't really
doing data very well I mean you know
just showing you the early GSM networks
they had V sorry to be small M I mean
you have to be very old to remember what
that is they they were able supporting
facts and dial-up connection and x.25
networks but you know at the speed of
9600 there's no way you would actually
use that for anything serious and there
was a really disconnect at the time
between the telecommunication operators
and the Internet guys I mean I could at
the time this early 2000 I was working
with telcos and they most of them didn't
even know the internet existed but just
going back to the drawing you can see
that there's a whole lower part is
basically the evolution of the GSM
network to speak tcp/ip and to
interconnect mobile phones to the
Internet and because of those elements
and you could use your mobile phone to
make internet connection and that really
changed a lot of things on the handset
side still I'm looking from a hacker
perspective how interesting is it but
the first handset they had proprietary
operating system they had low bandwidth
high latency they had very small screens
black and white they were not really you
couldn't really use them to do anything
and there were many attempts early early
attempts to things practical like web
which hopefully you don't remember and
still people say ok I'd better hack from
my computer and this started to change
when we move to the third generation now
the third generation the data speeds
they they became finally usable and
practical I mean on a 3G connection you
can you can do some work you can do you
Brow's graphical websites the terminals
they started to have larger screens
better resolution and they would have
more CPU resources you could run custom
software so suddenly it became
interesting as a hacking platform and on
top of that the IP stack which at the
beginning didn't exist in mobile
operators they all had their proprietary
protocols even they were still using
x.25 very late but finally everybody
started to move to IP now not only the
IP connectivity for mobile data but also
the infrastructure connectivity the
management networks were on tcp/ip and
then the signaling networks ss7 was
being transported over API through a
protocol called sigtran which is just
layers that replace the first stack
protocols so everything is transported
over IP and guess what hackers love
tcp/ip that's what they used to they
couldn't really hack mobile networks
because they didn't understand those
proprietary obscure undocumented
protocols that didn't have access to but
as soon as IP was there they were able
to go and play and this is at that time
that we started to see some very serious
attacks on the network infrastructures
the operators themselves so most the
most bizarre and fascinating story of
all happen in Greece in 2005 and just
this is just a reminder or how an
interception and normal interception
system works
you've got the cell towers you can see
the guy talking here's the cell towers
relays a signal to the switch which then
you know redirects are called to the
other guys etc and inside that switch
you've got some modules that allows
lawful interception now this is a
standard way to do things and remember
to do lawful interception well first you
have to be authorized obviously only is
the law enforcement and Intel agencies
can do that
obviously only the one of the country
you operating in but also you need court
orders warrants etc in Greece what
happened and it is believed this is a
nation state because of sophistication
of the attack but the attacker was never
clearly identified basically what those
guys did they broke into the operator
Network maybe they had some complicity
inside it's not 100% known because the
guy who could have answered that
question as was was killed and they
modified the switch itself now it might
sound like something easy modify a
switch but when you know how a switch
operates it's extremely complicated a
switch is massive I mean a medium
networks I switch would almost feel a
quarter of this room because it's you
know dozens of racks and proprietary
hardware and proprietary software
running all the time with you know
real-time operating system it's
programmed in a language called Plex
which probably most of you haven't even
heard of so for someone to go and modify
a live switch in that bizarre language
that was really amazing and then they
really compromised everything else
around the network they allowed it to
basically exfil data and to do a silent
interception that no one knows about not
the operator and not the government
nothing so just to show that the
sophistication of attacks has increased
and of course because of the the way we
use phones in our lives well the
government's are interested in that and
hostile governments you know so we don't
know who did that things in Greece but
there's only a few players that have the
resources to do that I'll let you guess
who anyway moving on to 4G which is
basically the technology that we most of
us are using today the architecture has
evolved a lot
if you see on the left hand side you've
got the GSM infrastructure which is
using proprietary signaling protocols
like cap which is cam an application
part I nap
map mobile application part and all
those you know those proprietary
protocols that was there from the start
of GSM and they're replacing all that
with more open protocols for example sip
I'm sure most of you have heard about
sip sip is a protocol using voice over
IP and they do the signaling with
something called diameter a diameter is
very open it's fully IP based and it's
going to replace as a seven which was
obscure and difficult to access a lot of
the network elements are being replaced
by open systems like well historically
is a lot of them were running on Solaris
but now it's more and more running on
Linux the terminal you know your phone
and the network element they are talking
sip and using encapsulation protocols
like gtp and all this is fully IP based
fully documented and very easy for you
know bad guys to get documentation on so
the attack surface has massively
increased and of course now all your
data communication are intercepted by
governments is nothing wrong with that
but technology made it a lot easier so
now they can correlate all your you know
cold data communication the websites you
access etc etc so this means sorry this
means a lot of opportunities for hackers
to to abuse the technology everything IP
means easy to understand and to connect
with signaling becomes open a lot easier
to abuse sip is a protocol that's easy
to understand and you can encapsulate it
into gtp to to have hostile payloads
internal networks are increasingly
interconnected to the outside to other
operators service providers to a lot of
things and this made it a lot easier for
people to have access to
infrastructure so so when you know that
the ITU is recommending some shred model
that have absolutely no relation to
reality you have a recipe for disaster
so where is this going
I mean if you see the evolution of speed
you can see that it's getting a lot more
practical to access and use those
networks and when you know that in 5g
you will be able to have super low
latency super high speed and billions of
devices connected I can tell you one
thing that no one really knows what's
going to happen with 5g you cannot
anticipate what will be the impact of
that technology people saying oh yeah 5
G's just the next evolution is faster no
it's a lot more than that everything
will be interconnected super fast and
this is going to create a whole new
generation of security problem and this
is going to be great for people working
in the industry because it's going to be
a security disaster in my opinion of
course people will tell you and my
vendor is secure my infrastructure is
security try but that's impossible
really it's too complex growing too fast
and they won't revenue before security
so that's it like concluding with a few
seconds late what started as a closed
garden that no one could access evolved
into a worldwide digital network that
people could interconnect with it's used
everywhere all the time by everybody
it's increasingly hacker friendly
security as always is the last thing
well not the last thing but it's at
least the second thing to deployment of
services and a large attack surface and
expanding perimeter means operators are
going to have a lot more problem than
they used to that's it thank you for
your attention thank you as well I'm
Anna Wahl