thanks for coming my name is Jeff oooh I
come from 360 hacker Research Institute
360 technology this Maspeth name is
Hardware scripty mode multi-dimensional
attack and different to set in this
topic I want to tell you about the
design methods and principles of common
hardware security tools and you can
learn these things learn how to use
strong electromagnetic technology to
unlock doors learn how to user remote
NFC reader how to design or - to prevent
NFC reading how to design a ultrasonic -
to attack electronic devices and so on
I hope after this speech you can master
these skills and perfectly choose so you
can design your own hardware security
platform first let's talk about NFC NFC
security you may have heard NFC just
like Promax free chameleon yes they are
very powerful and you can use it to too
many things sorry
there are something wrong under about
Hecky FC was designed by three-sixty
unicorn team it's our team it's my team
I'd like you to I would like you to
watch the video below to see what hack
we devised a diva says i hack a mess hi
KFC as you can see put one device on the
roll it and use another device to pay
the bill so what happened
Hecky FC is NFC repeater it'll be later
signal from the car from Catarina and
his bank are to complete education
something so watch your game use the
device you can't do manage evil scenes
like stealing other people's money and
zing but is in your every sin to present
but I have to see that a design such a
repeat is not a very simple it may need
you to know know where params
communication protocol and also near you
have the hardware design ability and if
you really want to make here I'm here to
give you some clues you can you can
search men in the AFC on the internet
internet to get more information about
hike in FC this device was designed by
p7 462 it is a powerful airship and it
has many useful libraries you can
download many AFC simple programs on the
web search this group these programmers
will have you tooling every protocol
quickly anything you can develop your
own hack tools
and our mission as as our mission on the
screen nf2 for arrow 0 1 this chip is
used for in Indy meteor to signal
transmission but you have a lot of
chance you have a lot of options for how
to how to do well or transmission
between two devices not only in may have
device the development of this project
about this heck FC is about three months
to six months so that development hm is
very long and if you really want to if
you really want to do this device I
suggest you buy the development part
this this this development boat this is
the picture of the ensign for six do
controller development kit and as the
price is 250 and $59 it's a little
expensive but bad I'll pay it or not you
decide I think it's a I think this
development kit brought will greatly
speed up your development in the channel
and Zenit talk about how to emulate or a
high frequency curve
in my opinion milling is a good choice
maybe you'll maybe you have her this
commit this device commonly it's it's
very famous on github in NFC is pretty
area it can be a good choice to practice
writing code and have a you to learn
more about hardware designs you can
download the PCB and reserve SCS PDF on
the website
when I were designing the camilan iPhone
as a melee functioning amulet function
was easily to mplet it means you can use
this car to open you it means you can
use this chameleon device to open the
door as an affair car
you just had you just had to follow the
official bomb to solder the PCB to
solder the components and zing register
where as a quarter to into the MCU it's
very easy but I found a spin see the
chameleon can't employ to read function
it means that you can I use chameleon to
read it's me fare card number at first I
saw I were doing something wrong and a
zing I wear did several PCB brought it
with me a lot of time I I was exhausted
at Eva and after arrest I decided to
figure out where I'm wrong I haven't no
choice
under this is official PDF you can
download this circuit PDF on there g-dub
of chameleon sorry this problem -
Camille took me a very long time so this
problem
I mean how to complete the read function
but I think I'm more qualified hardware
engineer I carefully studied as a
circuit of hardware design and is in
family cadet the values the values in
the yellow box are wrong I don't know
why there is a measure here so maybe
maybe you know I want to see that open
so scenes really have deep pitch maybe
under since people are not so much here
today but I want to see if you are NFC
if you like AFC hacking so you are lucky
because now
you know where the problem is problem is
it can save you a lot of time when you
want to complete to complete read
function next I want to introduce you
more Fanny sing from the picture you can
see this is a tennis racket but guess
what it is
actually it is a MC reader when you
design a MC have to you may consider
these issues how to do mock conceal me
concealed hider
has their coins has a circuit boards how
to design how to get a long way the
distance what feature do you want to add
in your design like reading like reading
the pencast number or stealing sir thank
hot money
it depends on you here on the screen yes
you can see the tennis racket the
hardware the hardware board was hiding
was head in heading in the bandage and
you can see the coin yes was design on
the tennis line of su tennis racket so
this is the radio I recorded before as
you can see I used to tennis racket to
swear to swap subhankar and as a tennis
card and a tennis racket a transmitted
as it did to the PCs receiver and a zing
the message displayed on the screen
watch ok this is a head
concealed device you can't go too
crowded at places like suburbs fishing
or other crowded places reading the
reading distance of this device is about
10 centimeters this is a feral farthest
distance of standard NFC protocol if you
know MC protocol yes the frost
resistance is 10 centimeters I have to
see if you have drawn hardware skills
you can imperat and as as as far as I
know the furthest road distance is about
20 centimeters but you need but you need
to modify the circuit of its relative
code but here I want to eat I want to
teach you how to achieve a reading
distance about 10 centimeters if you
master these skills it will be real
simple yes mass mass queues you can't
design you can design your NFC - to
achieve far as the distance on NFC
protocol 10 centimeters yes
it's very easy under this skill is is
the first time I share in public
yes you ask you lucky and listen
carefully
maybe you know there are a lot of AMC
chips in the market on the screen is a
circuit of pn5 3 to p53 - it can reach
and emulate me fare cuts an inserted
blue box is a demodulate emotive
demodulation circuit which is very
important the value in the blue box can
affect the car reading distance I think
you should know it and remember the
circuit and
z MF I see five five two five two two
another NFC chip
he said that blue box is a demodulation
circuit of MOS m FR c v 2 2 and a next c
RR c 6 6 3 maybe you found out that in
the blue box they looks they look very
similar right
check ok they look very similar similar
yes we have the same we have the same
the modulus in circuit so they must be
have the same depart function so use the
same debug function you can't achieve
father's reading distance right so how
to how to do this how to do this the
first step is the first step
power current power current am
monitoring power current am running like
like this you need to download the data
set of AF chip and a checks are T V DD
check the T V DD supply current I marked
it with a blue box so it's easy first
downloaded it dear sit and as a fan of
the T V DD supply current what you need
to do it to keep through device current
or something weather pattern 70 ma to
100 ma 100 ma is there tap is a tab
where you me P 19 ma it's very close to
it's very close to tell value because at
this current consumption that is this
current consumption state you can't get
the maximum reading distance and
you may have questions how to change
their current consumption how to change
the device current to do something so
here is a way what we should do next
into optimizing optimize the parameters
in the blue box this is a demodulation
circuit when you change the values in
the blue box
maybe c1 or c2 your fan is occurring the
key something will change maybe it's
getting bigger
maybe it's getting smaller so let me
repeat again when you change CY I'll see
to the whole device current consumption
wear chains what used to do is to change
c1 and c2 to mix device current if you
Samson to rate 100 ma and as if family
your care is a maximum rating business
and you do not in you do not need to
change L 0 and s and C 0 because they
are flitters adjusting adjusting arrow 0
and a 0 giant increases or distance so
and I said I think it's very easy don't
change arrows arrow 0 and a C 0 just
change C 1 C 2 okay so next how to
change see you Ayanna C 2 as I say
before do now to change the value of L 0
L 0 and a c0 and another scene please
here TC here nor too teensy one on a
seat to add a symptom for example if you
change c1 if you change diva and you fan
as a device current the best current is
about 13 ma you must remember that you
must remember that the tap current is
100 ma do you remember do you remember
is please yes 100 so if your device
current consumption is inserting ma
wrong you need to change c1 or c2 so
what you should do is to change c1 and
c2 and test man champs below me
Faneuil value of c1 c2 to mixer current
okay something to raise bar 100 ma you
will get a good business okay another
thing
please remember play member that there
are antenna antenna value air in the
attend a value between 1 to 2 Mac Harry
want you to make Harry it's very
important so let's make a conclusion
conclusion let's make a conclusion how
to gather the longest EFC reading
distance do not do not change arrow 0
and a 0 just change c1 c2 and mix aren t
2y and a 2 to 1 or 1 to 2 Meg Harry make
Harry and change c1 c2 to make the
current device cue Samson to 100 ma and
zing ureters longest father's files to
read in distress
okay I think it's a little harder for if
you are know the hardware hardware
engineer sync we took it a lot of
measures about how to make a fc2 so how
to start and we are else should we start
in my hardware I used to digital
projector or sorry in my heart where I
used to this jitter Harbor project as a
reference and I recommend you write and
I recommend it to you because this
project is based on our two new ado
knows code is simpler and more suitable
for beginners so when you complete this
project it and then you can you can try
to design hi KFC or try to design your
own chameleon yes and maybe try to
designs or tennis racket yeah me too to
be a hardware hacker if you want to
design your unique Hardware hardware
tools by yourself you shouldn't know
some electronic circuit it is a software
software bears
mm-maybe automated Zener maybe it go
piss clay you must you must know how to
use one of them it's easy you can
download many documents about this
software responsive web search I think
it will takes you about a wine make or
to make so you can control how to use
the software it's it's not hard
okay so now
we just talked about the medicines to
how to steal other people the
information how to steal people's money
how to tell people's information like a
bank has a number now let's talk about
how to block a of the communication how
to make an AMC defender and a low
frequency 125 defender and this topic I
my team had at his speech and a black
hat I think now let's watch her video on
the reader on the on the AFC reader you
can see you can see the ESD defender
it's blocky and the way you took it took
a device away so the reader is working
now it's it's reading the bank card
number information so now let's like to
learn how to design this NFC blocker and
a low frequency defender yeah high
frequency defender and a low frequency
defender how to design this device the
picture so
texting and a protection circuit of high
frequency and low frequency this is a
circuit designer piece they espouse
their communication protocol it's very
simple and it's easy now let's talk
about as a principle first let's talk
about how to detect yes detect the first
thing you should you should detect
through am Sarita
or low throaty Sarita and a zing you can
protect your money right so first how to
detect rings there is a radio frequency
signal come close to the device for
example when the AFC signal if this
thing don't come to the device it will
generate generator voltage every one
that we want zero and zero on the left
of the Sprint you can so when you when
you get a voltage at v1 you can come to
a conclusion if the reader is tummy and
seen seem at the low frequency this one
we to seem at the low frequency when low
frequency radio is closed
through that to this device it will
generate to vote each other way to so
you can come to a conclusion
125 frequency radio is coming so now the
protection now is the now the problem
problem of detecting is solved yes you
can't detect the voltage everyone or you
can't detect voltage every - now how we
resolve the detects problem and is in
how to protect
how to implant protein protection pounds
there are high frequency antenna we
generate to the square we generate a
square wave signal of 847 frequency
which can effectively blocks a
communicating of sir nearby MC MC reader
if you really want to if you really want
to figure out why why 847 your suitor
ladies you should read it
MC a protocol document and on the low
frequency antenna we generate the square
we have skill of 100 and training file
industry which can effectively blocks
the communicating behavior of the near
Bell low frequency reader so now I think
it's clear how to detect and protect
losing what do you to do is to choose
one simple adjud arduino to simple anna
to do and aus ego or ultimate designer
and use this simple circuit and design
your holding AFC defender and a low
frequency defender I think it's very
easy ok let's finish about her RFID and
talk about Wars what boys do in the area
of hacking let's let's look at let's
watch the radio frustrating so
you can see with with the sender the car
was driven yes the cat is a the palings
camera driven the principle the
principle is is that any emitting a
certain power a certain power of sin the
chip of the machine
Lucy is a balance of judgment I think
it's very easy to understand them and so
now it's clear our job our job is to
make a sender transmitter right make a
center transmitter make electronic
device speech adjustable frequency of
sound wave but when sing but one thing
you shouldn't know fan is a frequency
found as a frequency to make the device
feel it may it will take you in a will
to give you a lot of time you need to be
percent okay so now let's talk about how
to design a device to to attack the
balance car on the screen is it's a
simplified circuit our design but but it
works well it works various image
ultrasonic nutrition was another thing
as you can see the circular bar is very
simple but an a seeing you should pay
attention to the speaker you need to
look at as you need to look at as a
response with response frequency of the
speaker if the speaker cannot emit zero
CN observe ultrasonic frequency so this
device cannot walk where and is in the
last scene as you use the MCU use the
MCU to generate a chair for you to send
you to send frequency
and so the ultrasound hacker is finished
so now you know I think it's it's easy
okay now let's talk about our power
glitch in my opinion this is a low freq
it's a low success rate of the master
and here are the Oh brief I will briefly
explain explain here about how it is so
what is what is the power glitch attack
generally it sorry to make the processor
power flop flat rate and the mix program
mix MCU program excusing Ezzor program
purpose or you can use it to program by
us all decryption and here I also give
you a simple circuit what you should do
is to generate very fast square wave
signal as the power control and change
the period of signal and the zing test
again again to fan as a specific
frequency that are caused a program to
ran ronald attractions so let's let's
speak again change the park into square
wave change superior and make the mix
superior as a very fast very process
period
okay the last topic circular system
breaker yeah you too strong lecture
electromagnetic theory security security
system breaker okay let's watch a video
first
from the video you can see is added a
door was open ambassador device no
matter which apps of a door no matter
what a tabs of a door freak a
fingerprint lock all possible lock it
can it can it all can be opened by this
device so what does it here it is
yes what are the hair it is okay let's
talk about what is the devices and how
it works
this is on the screen is a device
circuit when you open there is a switch
when you open we open the switch the
long coil the long coils that
continuously image em energy out world
yes
the long coil will continue continuously
emits energy our outlaw so we open the
switch the trance transistors will ting
on wilting own and the first coin the
first column has has a very big current
and a second corn will generate very
high we will generate a very high
voltage but as in transistors changes
through a chain of second corn Lu Lu's
voltage so this is a circle
raise the transistor on and off the
second corn will affect the second coin
will affect the surroundings electronic
electronic devices so there is the
electronic devices produce injection
current effect the working speed of the
surrounding electronic devices
so now you know why so now you know why
it can open the door now
the longer the longer the long choice
real image image their energy out world
and effect perfect as a working state of
the Sirona electronic devices and zingy
will open the door I think it's it's not
hard if you have any interest II you
can't assign this to us by yourself
Oh as in let's talk about how to make
amazing artificial lightning in our
lesson to make this beautiful lateen how
to it's very easy I think what are you
to do it to make the second coin
workload to the back corner and you will
fan as a legend yes makes the second
coin close to the back one to this place
and your rear fan is allotting you yes
thank you very much and my topic is
finished if you have any questions you
can come to you can come and find me I
will be there about your king or two to
thirty minutes
I hope and I'll be happy to have a talk
with you and since they are still on
sale champs I wanted to make you maker
conclusion yes in the slicing artist you
about how to use strong electromagnetic
technology to unlock doors and I think
you already watch the video how to open
the door and they're soaked it is very
simple you can't design their circadian
and how does a designer removed a fc
reader the introduced chameleon hecka FC
the parks the box about a chameleon you
can complete to the
zuri focusing right there is a deep
hitch in gym bag and if you really want
to design the NFC repeater you master
bath AFC pn7 462 development kit it will
help you to speed up your developer -
term and the most refinishing eye and
the easiest thing I think is I teach to
you how to prevent the AFC reading
prevent is a low frequency reading and
also introduce you how to design their
ultrasonic choose to attack electronic
devices I think all these things thank
you thank you very much
[Applause]