herschel optics holders are expensive so
i made a holder and ring system using a
laser cutter and some common hardware
the holes are threaded take cap head
screws and they stick to magnets in the
Rings this works pretty well you can
adjust the aim up down and left right
and the ring doesn't slide around or
fall off you can put magnets in the
holders for better stability all most of
the time these aren't needed the kit
lets you examine and prototype all the
common optics functions such as
projection magnification and even
advanced laser effects such as the
Michelson interferometer shown here so
just that this project is instructions
and files to create your own optics
bench using a laser cutter so trying to
make some high-end experiments fairly
accessible to anyone who has a laser
cutter for me what was really neat about
this project is that it's incredibly
well documented it was easy to read all
very well photo documented but a lot of
effort was put by this team to show
their full process and the pros and cons
it left me wanting to run over to my
laser cutter and make an optics bench
which wasn't something that I really
ever had on my to-do list which is sort
of needs anything for a project to leave
the website thinking on out now I can
either have those tools I can make this
so the new thing is I take a lot of
classrooms that wouldn't normally think
about this and I say classrooms I mean
it loosely I'm this to be your
makerspace this could be a college
classroom this could be something that
you're doing into the high school
physics class really acknowledging that
this is typically a a pretty pricey set
to tools and the prices that that this
project are quoting really do come in
under hundred dollars and create this
we introduce assault a cross swords
fabrication pipeline to how blind people
independently make physical interfaces
accessible blind users capture a photo
of the inaccessible interface with a
dollar bill for absolute measurements
these labels are then used to generate a
3d model for a layer of tactile and
principal buttons that fits over the
original controls the printed overlay is
designed to be easily aligned and
attached to its appliance using
adhesives so basically it's to help
people who are blind or partially
sighted generate tactile interfaces for
appliances by themselves which I thought
was a really good innovation so
essentially you stick a dollar bill on
the next your microwave keypad was
example or anything and you scan it with
an iphone app and it goes off and it's
crowd-sourced for people to suggest all
that interface should look like as
Braille or as other symbols and it
basically generates using open source
software as well they're using open s
can or variant of it with I believe with
JavaScript plug-in or something to
actually dynamically generate a 3d model
that you can 3d print and then stick on
that interface and then you can
obviously feel it to use it and it's so
basically the person you can't see as
long as they can hold their phone and
they know roughly where the appliance is
they effectively can get this thing
generated by themselves I think one of
the things that's going to make it
really cool is that they're going to
develop a library of created interfaces
for a specific appliances that people
can just download and print
poke zero is easy to use just plug it in
the USB board of your smartphone or
computer Louis the software and your
workbench is ready Bob 0 provides
affordable access to an oscilloscope
signal generated power supply spectrum
analyzer sensor interface we all time
data loaded and many other tools there's
a lot of ways in which you can now
replace what used to be really expensive
to a leg an oscilloscope like you you
have similar processing power available
now in inexpensive microcontrollers
right but those aren't necessarily
products that Agilent or HP or who
tektronix are rolling out like they're
still making like high-end stuff and and
so there's like a real gap there i think
for to be able in a low-cost platform to
provide like a lot of kind of
introductory tools that each controls
lab courses as an engineering professor
and our equipment is is ridiculously
overpriced and we're running into
constraints with number of students that
we just can physically put into the lab
situation so if i can say by this open
source hardware widget and plug it in
your phone and who the lab remotely i
think it would have benefits and more
than one way because students get to
learn on their own time in that way and
not just kind of a two hour lab you know
fake hands-on setting
never hold an object at an angle to the
light tilting it back and forth to see
subtle surface details you can't see
when you're looking straight at it
you're taking advantage of the way the
light interacts with those surface
details to make them more easily visible
reflectance transformation imaging RTI
for short is a digital version of this
technique photos are then processed in
software to create a virtual lighting
model so that using the viewer you can
set the lighting ankle to a desired
position to reveal details in the object
with my design up to 64 LEDs are
installed on the inside of a plastic
dome the system sports automated
triggering of the camera shutter in
synchronization with the LEDs for many
different makes of cameras so this
project I was so taken I've never really
thought about pictures museums and how
to get these detailed images and and
seeing the photographs this was really
exciting and I can see I just got back
from a weekend of camping I can see how
having a lot of fun you know looking at
rocks differently using a device like
this this is a neat project that now
opens it up Stu a lot of others science
and art application so um yeah this
seems like really good application of
the technology that's our key out there
and there's some stuff out there that
you can combine in an awful way and add
some software and and now it does
something really amazing and and even
more so I see this as being you know a
unique offering from the kind of open
source world so you wouldn't you
wouldn't really see this from industry
and if you did it would be
astronomically expensive it wouldn't be
accessible to everyone so yeah I feel
like this is one of those projects that
is both kind of intellectually and
practically interesting and is just
really well-executed
you