test test
sound test check
hello
one last
so start I think
hey here's Rasmus Jensen yeah thank you
for coming to this talk so this is going
to be about an architecture and just a
quick introduction so this is my name I
did a master's in computer science from
the outback university in 2006 and I've
been working on this secure scuttlebutt
project for the last two three years and
it's a bit of a fair warning this is
going to be a bit opinionated this talk
so there's going to be both technical
things and also like there's a more of a
more of a different kind as well but
don't worry they're going to be plenty
of technical things as well and so I
wanted to start out with a quote but
instead I wanted to show this pitch in
instead I guess it sort of sums up
pretty well what's going on
yeah so this is a pretty clever little
figure so when I'm going to speak about
more clearly here's application
architecture and software and I'm going
to divide it into three key points so
one of them is the infrastructure
meaning that computer that actually runs
all this stuff and the other thing is
going to be the data that's going to be
sort of part of this in the second is
the view on the data or the use
interface like how can you actually
interact with this data so if you take a
traditional architecture you have
nowadays like some server somewhere
connected through the internet to
different kinds of clients of various
kinds and we didn't look at the standard
architecture you have some features like
one of them is that the server can be
hacked it can be down or it couldn't be
shut down like Google that's a lot and
one of the other things is that this has
really often centralized in these
systems it's stored on the servers and
that's where it lives and you have this
UI tends to be standardized and and the
power the power in the system lies in
deciding how you can actually use the
system when you look at this kind of
system online you often get some kind of
one-size-fits-all use it or moderation
and when you look at it in a more of a
traditional company settings it tends to
reflect the existing organizational
hierarchies that are in the organization
so let's switch a bit to to talk about
machine learning look at how how happy
they all look and this small network but
I'm actually going to talk a bit about
more about the dark side of machine
learning
so back to the first slide so this part
is going to be talking about the data
and the use interface like how you
connect with this data and when you look
at these machine learning recommendation
systems it's like anywhere where there's
large quantities of data like YouTube
Netflix Amazon whatever and Facebook of
course and even if you're not one of the
2.3 billion people on Facebook you're
probably still there I mean a lot of the
apps running on your Android phone will
connect to Facebook and and will tell it
which apps you log you you're now
opening in this X gives you a pretty
good profile of the person so let's say
you are opening the King James Bible app
or the calorie counter or the peeler
tracker for that sake get a lot of data
here and when you look at the the user
interfaces in these systems you have
this personalized feet and and one of
the interesting things is that when you
look at the u3 when you look at YouTube
when the way the YouTube interface
actually works 70% of the view time on
videos are generated from these
recommendations algorithms and you have
the self-reinforcing system where you
have the data generates the UI the UI
generates the data and so on you get
this like loop which actually tells you
how the system can be used and then
there's this really depends on how you
look at the previous light this is from
Facebook data science team 2014 where
they look at the data and and they can
sort of say that well love happens
around here right
so when you look at the features of
these kinds of system you give the power
to the data and this means that you give
the power to anyone who can generate or
buy the data and really when you look at
it this is like black boxes which are
like attack vectors for any kind of
people that want to misuse this system
really in the same way as we had
provides our software back into 90s so
one way of influencing this system is to
buy ads and most of these big companies
now have online repositories where you
can actually go in and look at who
bought which apps or ads and the people
that they are targeting with the ads
that's at least some kind of
transparency in this but the problem was
that is you can see here that actually
the software is just riddled with both
like identical searches returns
different results I mean come on one of
the other problems with this is that it
sort of creates this money almost like
money laundering system for buyers
meaning that bias is is the sort of
attributes that you have in the system
which is the data that it is trained
upon elect it really hard to see what
kind of biases you haven't these machine
learning systems another one of the
problems is they have this degenerate
feedback loop like you get to filter
bubbles and echo chambers as well inside
these systems which manifests itself and
in the way you use the system because
it's recommended you videos for example
so you probably all heard about this
take a tie a I that was a part on
Twitter which would look at the date and
then actually trying to learn it took
exactly 24 hours to turn this body into
like full-on Nazi but so what I mean not
necessarily all of this this is bad I
mean it is a system and the same way
this is that the system has can also be
turned into opportunities so this is a
quote for how Taiwan combats
misinformation so one of the interesting
things that that you can see is that the
people that want to target them with
like propaganda campaign and
disinformation and actually start
testing these in the wild in order to
have the most effective spread of their
viral content and this means that the
Thailand government can actually go and
look at these signals when they start
happening and what's interesting here is
that each of these Ministry land has a
team which then has like 60 minutes from
when a viral post hits to do like an
equally on more convincing narrative
that they post on the same media as the
people trying to to break these systems
work we have more of a volunteer-based
which I like the Athenian Elves so they
also have a lot of Russian trolls that
goes and writes all kinds of
misinformation in news articles and
various social media and really it's
sort of like resistance fighters about a
21st century right like they say that we
don't want to be the propagandist in
Reverse we just you know want to expose
the it's a really low-key and
really mean went in mark now and you
look at the Danish election which just
happens and advertisement on TV is
illegal by law from these political
parties but advertisement in it's an
Internet is not regulated I mean it's
just I mean it's really just ridiculous
when you when you think about it like
what kind of situation or what kind of
system do we really want to end up with
here so when you look at this machine
learned a lot of ethical questions
that's quite often than not like a dress
like what values does the trade Algren
actually embody like is a study like who
determines what these values can be and
and so actually leaves like a whole
question just set aside to whoever runs
these algorithms or the engineers that
runs the algorithms
so in summary you can use machine learn
to individualize and it's sort of like a
propriety of data and algorithm stack
and it's a constant battle for the
people that tries to to use this for
good as well
okay so let's switch again a bit so I'm
going to talk about a different kind of
architecture and this is a peer-to-peer
architecture and this is where I think
it gets a bit more interesting
so one of the ways you could do these
centralized systems is in a federated
system so this is like we've known for
email for like ages it's like different
access can run these servers which have
different objectives and different kinds
of of ideals and it's also what's used
for Samba for Mastodon which is like a
big decentralized system and when you
look at some of the feature and this
again you can see that the power is is
then again centralized at the service in
the same way as it was before
so in the same way you can have them
hacked and down shutdown and it ends up
being like a benevolent dictator
moderation system and of course compared
to like only one system you get more
diversity you get like local governance
as well you can start up an instance and
do your own kind of governance of this
but one of the problems with these kinds
of systems is that they have a tendency
to to go to what sort of an eventual
centralization like you've seen with
email and Gmail for example a different
architecture is fully distributed
architecture where the computers running
system are also running the
infrastructure as well we've seen
different kind of systems using this
like that and skull port for example
and when you look at these architectures
you have the power is at the edges
instead and this means that you have
used to control over the infrastructure
the data that runs on them and the
software that you used to interact with
the data so this means that you get
bottom-up governance instead of
centralized or pseudo centralized and
then there was a really great article by
Inc and switch which talks about local
first software and some of the tenants
that they look at in these systems is
that they really want systems which a
fast multi device can work offline
we can still provide collaboration
between the between the users of it you
want in conductivity and privacy and you
also want user control
so one of these local first systems is
skull apart and this is actually an a
real image of the network so you see the
red part down here's the old guard of
the system people the nodes have been
here the nose and as you go to different
colors these are newer nodes in the
network and skull but it's a identity
centered system so this means that your
profile it's is what is central in the
system it's not your post for examples
like it is in the forum and I could call
a social network but it really has a lot
of bad connotation so I'm going to call
it a friend Network instead it's really
like there's the there are really no
gatekeepers in the system's all the data
stored locally and you get the user
interfaces embodying local values and
the way it works like these identities
is that you have a scuttlebutt feat
which is your identity and so these are
just messages that you put in and the
first one has a pointer back to to
nothing it has an author field which is
the person who owns this piece and then
have a hash of the message as well and
then you sign the message meaning that
nobody else could produce this message
and they get like a long chain of these
messages one for each
of these feats and this means that you
get nobody can sort of put in a message
in between here or look as if it's from
this author because all of them are
signed with the key that only the author
has so this is an event sourcing system
where feats are these mutable change of
messages and has like an ache a limit on
the messages so you can store them
locally it has no global lecture
consensus so it's not like not like any
kind of Bitcoin or or something like
that where I feel has this global
properties in them and you could do all
of these messages that you saw before
you can either do them public or
privately and and the interesting thing
is that you could do any kind of message
as a private message so this this would
mean that you could for example when you
follow someone you could do that that's
a private message so nobody else can see
that you're following that person for
example or I block them large files are
saucers as blobs whose five megabytes
off limit and the really important part
here is that only you store a product
and you are your private key so it's not
on any other service anywhere it's only
you another interesting thing about the
system is that because you have this
signed and linked messages by has this
means that you have no URL where you can
find the stuff everything is location
transparent because the only thing you
need to find a message is the hash of it
and then you talk to people and try to
get the message you do this by gossiping
so one of the ways or lat like like
there's plenty of ways of some of the
things that are working is like local
network it's in local network they would
gossip between them you can have pops
which are Internet connected machines
like any other machine which just relays
messages between different ones we do
onion hidden services want to run over
tor or you could do sneak and it's like
you can actually do your messages put
them on a USB stick and hand it to
someone that also works and the way it
works with these feeds is this when you
are you
here in the middle and you start
following people like in any kind of
these systems and that means that the
people that you follow are inside this
hub one that have one hop away from you
and the way it normally works is that
the clients are set up to have to
download messages from two hops away and
then put them into your local view of
the world so this is all the messages
that your machine contains and what's
interesting is this kind of from a data
perspective is that you can have like
long-running connections from your
machine through a different machine and
then you post like I'm interested in
these feats and then you could use these
at the epidemic broadcast reach which
are quite efficient in actually pushing
out updates you can actually have
somebody in the network assuming they
are all connected porting messaging just
acts is just spreading out just as the
as the messages post and you could do
this because you have this ordered locks
identity-based pure messages I'm just
not going to go into very much detail
here but you can also block people
meaning that if you have in the network
here you can see let's say that you have
these friends who connect you in this
person is really annoying so you can
block them so they don't they they are
not in your network where you can
increase the hub meaning that that
person's follows you not get unless you
have someone else that can connect to
those people so that actually stops a
lot of these attacks then you have on
these kind of systems and this means
that it's easier to guard against spam
and harassment because you only pull in
the messages that you're interested the
Pops are are also problematic if you
follow them but we have PN Box rolling
out very soon which is going to make
this really a lot better and one of the
other interesting things in this system
which is not used very much but is that
every network here has a caps and the
caps is it's sort of like a key meaning
that every message composed or
written in this caps exist in one of
these universes and this means that you
can choose the different caps and then
you have everything else working all the
clients everything works but you are in
a different universe in these universes
don't interact with each other at all
and this means that you have the
possibility to actually run like
parallel systems you could do like one
locally for example for a system that
you don't want anyone else to to get
access to and even if you connect with
these ones if you don't know the captain
you cannot get the messages or validate
them so if we look at the the software
side of this there are different kinds
of different implementations so one in
JavaScript want to go one on the way in
trust and see in Python as well you have
multiple interfaces that can interact
with this data which brings the nice
kind of diversity into the systems we
have like patchwork patty a pattern ooh
you also have mobile Android apps like
many of us for example so it looks like
this it looked like any other kind of
like system where you can see that the
post over here you can see the people
you are connected to and you can see
some of the people in the system as well
and you can build apps on top of this so
for example this is a book app and we
can see you put in and you put in the
books and the way it works it's like
like any kind of an in sorting system so
books are just messages that you post
with a specific type and then you can
edit them in revenue as anyone can do
that and they just do this by actually
posting messages and then you can
correlate them and then actually hydrate
the state of these messages and that
will be your book app and because you
only get data from your friends and
friends of friends slacks it works
pretty well
and in general for these apps you can do
more local filtering if you want to as
assets these blobs are like normally
with the way we we shall push bigger
data like images for example but it's
also support for that which is super
cool distributed system
as well that you can use for
participation and one of the interesting
things is that you can actually then
starting playing around with actually
getting sort of some of the community
things in this like you can have like
these pups which is this long-running
note can actually start seeding these
files from your friends and this means
that you actually have a system where it
can exchange data which stays within
your network and it actually helps the
network it actually grows by the number
of notes that I earn and this is not a
really interesting app that element of
it is called a crystal so the ideas that
you can have a secret that you want to
share words or that you want to say for
example and then you can choose some of
the most people that you trust the
secret with and the and the way it works
is this mystical sharing so you so then
send it so we then send a shout to each
this person and any choose how many of
these shots that you need what a quorum
of this and this means you can put
secrets into the network that that that
you can then get back again and these
ones can then be from trusted friends
that you know for example in the in the
real world it can run get on top of SSB
like you just really just you get in it
at SSB create and then you can see here
get like a repository which which has
idea of this and then it actually pushes
these changes as blobs we can have like
the whole system actually running and
and you could just pull in updates as
well and it works exactly the same as
any other kind of message that we've
seen here and which is the interesting
things was that one of the Linux
Foundation people came into the network
about months ago and wrote this article
arguing that the Linux kernel should
switch to sort of an SB protocol because
then you'd have the messages in the
source code and coexisting let's see
what comes out of this but it's really
interesting to see these kinds of use
cases from people
so as you can see this like really very
very simple basic building blocks and
you can build all of this kind of stuff
and toughness a lot of these things that
I've shown are just things that people
just build on top of these primitives
it's really fascinating see it's almost
like a Lego from when you were kids
some of the things that are they worked
on is new message format which is going
to roll out soon which going to be a lot
more efficient has some really
interesting properties private groups as
well so right now we have these private
messages but we also want to have larger
private groups it can be a part of this
is not a trivial problem to solve so I
want to do this right another thing is
like it could be interesting to have
full peer running in browsers like right
now that JavaScript emplaced and runs
the notes and you have these electron
based apps on top of this but it could
be lint interesting to have it like
running this way and another thing is
that it could be one of the things that
have worked on are these safer spaces
like abuse audit moderation tools as
well ok so I'm going to do a small demo
here of one of the things that we're
working on and this is this being a
browser so this is all of this is
running in the browser you can see it
uses wesen for the crypto stuff so and
then it has you can do plots as well and
when you go into this you actually auto
generates an ID for you and then just as
a small demo I built a system here where
you can then actually start and getting
the messages so I'm going to do an
initial thing here and I love the
artwork you can see her cycle from ROM
multi community members as well and what
it does now it then it downloads all of
these messages so it actually downloads
from the perspective of my profile the
latest 25 messages from
and from from the people that I'm
connected to and then it then it starts
getting this you can see or 145 feet one
four thousand messages and it does
everything here does it downloads the
messages looks at the private messages
because the way the prod messages works
that there's no recipient on the five
messages
so this means that when you when you get
a private message you actually have to
see if it's if it's for you or not by
actually trying to decrypt it and then
it get these messages into this because
I'm only interested in these posts
messages and then you have a system why
can you see if this works probably
likely to this is really very new so
because here we have latest ten messages
and replies and you can go into the
profiles of people and see the messages
as well have private messages working as
well so and this is there supposed to be
messages in here and you can do private
blobs as well and this so so this is
pretty exciting and I think so so to
sort of sum this up this is we call it
if you're latarian software so this
means that people actually run the
interest structure themselves it uses on
control of the data and you get these
subjective data views on top of the data
that's set this is not a technical
solution to any kind of social problem
do you have out there this is still the
socialist it's really the hardest part
of all of this but I mean at least you
have like a level playing fields where
people can start experimenting with
different solutions in this way I'm
going to change gear a bit as well so
this is a really fascinating book if you
haven't read it you really owe yourself
to read it to read it it's relatively
old book but it's very very good one of
the books that you read and and it
changes the way you think about things
and what it talks about
this high modernism which is form of
morality which is like like this really
unfiltered confidence in science and
technology and what's interesting is
this point here that it reorders to
social and natural world for for these
things it was very it has the sort of
high in the 50s and 60s after the Second
World War and it's really characterized
by a lot of centralization even though
it doesn't look like it's like it and
it's like really rationalization of
everything everything has to be
rationalized and the problem is that it
goes into this kind of so ration that is
all almost like over simplifies things
and it has this tendency of of having
like the end justifies the means so you
see a lot of these kind of systems used
for example in the Soviet Union and also
here it's not necessarily in the I mean
just look at the picture of this Chicago
and people would actually look at the
system saying this is oh this is so
beautiful look at all the straight lines
everything is ordered it's really nice
especially from a plane when you're the
planner of this city
and then when you look at this old
European cities this is this is really
interesting when you look at them you
had like these small roads like which on
this road is probably because you want
to move stuff from here to here in a
fast way and not go around this so this
is really an organic system and it's
really interesting when you look at it
this way it actually looks like
something from nature not something
built and the reason why I bring this up
is that I think we have a lot of this
digital high modernism I mean literally
computers are like modernist wet dreams
like systems with a really stupid just
follows the rules that you do it's
really really great that you can do like
top-down and approach to this because
you have these systems that enforces
really simple rules
and you can see it in China for example
with the Soviet credit system but even
in the u.s. I mean if you go to more the
people that have been analyzing some of
the bill posts that they have there and
they actually put in tiny cameras to
analyze your face and look at your
agenda and the mood as well and use this
to data mind you so it's not I mean only
in these systems and what you end up is
this digital panopticon and this image
is from a prison actually from 959 1925
that they built in the US and what's
interesting is that the build is now in
the middle and then you have people
looking out and then you have all these
cells here which are the prisoners and
what's interesting in this system is
that the people in the cells because
they're open then they don't know if
they're watched or not but they know
that they might be watched and alone
that fact actually changes the way that
they behave so your end of this with
this system of global surveillance like
on a state level with the Chinese Social
Credit system for example even with the
NSA's as you can see Snowden has been
shown as well but it's very interesting
that it's not only and that's one of the
point in the book it's not only in this
state-run systems also a lot in the
capitalism as you can see as well
because they are interested because they
want this centralization of the global
surveillance so almost all the companies
in the Silicon Valley does some kind of
thing like this there are ranges of
flights in this system so like one of
them is Barcelona which just has some
really really great stuff going on and
what's really interesting here is that
they value it is sovereignty like
technical sovereignty and the way that
the series is that data is a public
infrastructure and more concretely so
whatever one honor to be the telecom
provider and they said that ok you can
get that contract but then you have to
provide the
data after you're done anonymously on
this open data portal we have and this
means that anyone then afterwards can go
in and actually have a level playing
field for actually doing the next kind
of system and what's interesting of
course is that they resisted for over a
year before they actually said okay we
can do that so just put this quote up
here because it's really cool
I mean if and this is like from an early
Chinese menu this one is like several
thousand years old but it really shows
very well that they knew exactly what
was at stake here even back then so some
rice I've shown these different kinds of
architecture centralized decentralized
and distributed I've shown different
kinds of power models in this system
hierarchical have put in machine
learning here as well and then it's a
latarian as well and I talked a little
bit about high modernism and how it
relates to all of these things put it
into sort of put it into a historical
perspective okay thank you
are there any questions so when this
sounds like a really cool project then
we're gonna look a bit one two okay so
my question is it sounds like every user
will have their own keys and their own
identity and so on yes is there any
building ways of handling anonymity and
privacy yeah so so the system is so when
you actually start up as a user you get
your own key and you don't have to
reveal anything about yourself and then
you can and then you can communicate
with the other notes as well and often
when you communicate you for example
leaked information about yourself let's
say that you you connect your pop and
then you have an IP address this means
that you leaked information about where
you are on the world and we can and we
can do a connecters / / / tour here
which means that you are actually not
revealing anything more that you want
then you can then on top of this you can
put in everything you want to do like
pictures of yourself or names of
yourself but it's not like in facebook
we're actually required to use your real
name in order to use the system you can
have it any way you want to speak in any
way you feel comfortable with but it was
actually interesting is that when I
started using this system I had like a
normal profile I didn't post that much
about myself but actually over time
there's a really really great community
here and people really care about each
other then you start revealing more
about yourself and sharing more stories
just out of sharing with the people that
you care for in the system it's really
interesting to see these dynamics and
play but you are open to do that when
you want
um thank you for the talk that was that
was great um I I really like scuttlebutt
but I also have some misgivings about
the way that I've seen it like by
default it seems like it's actually not
very privacy friendly at all like it
goes on the local area network and
announces your identity when you install
patchwork I don't know if this was like
a year ago I don't know if that's still
the case but then like every pub you
connect to you tell it all the things
that you want so that you can get them
if it has them but they they can
identify you from that right so is it
has it gotten any easier to use it in a
privacy sort of conscious fashion to not
just broadcast your identity to your
land and like a list of who you're
following in yeah yeah so so one of the
things that underscores has been working
on is a new connection manager which
actually means that you have to have to
open when opt in when you connect
through pops for example or local area
connections or bluetooth for example so
that once you run around with your phone
and somebody else comes in they could
just not necessarily just connect you
you have to actually authorize in order
to exchange that data but the other
thing is that once you have this public
data it is public and then it's actually
start spreading around like gossip in
the system and the only good way to
actually solve this is going to be with
these private groups and private groups
are going to solve a lot of these
problems as well
for the private groups are you thinking
about having different feeds for the
private communication because like when
you put the private messages in your
public feed that gives you a nice sort
of a receiver on observability it would
seem like but if two people are having a
conversation like you can sort of infer
that like since everybody sees it when
you're sending so like are you are you
thinking about having different feeds or
still just one feed for everything well
it's sort of up to you you could do
whatever you like if you want to
communicate privately and not
necessarily put these feeds you can do a
different feeds but then you can still
try to correlate these things what I
would say about the system which is
interesting is that it's very delayed
tolerant this means that you can post a
message and and the next day or like
another time actually exchange the
message you don't necessarily have to
exchange the message right away so you
can add this delays which makes it
really hard to figure out who's
necessarily communicating with each
other but that's a trade-off of
anonymity towards or and on the other
side like how fast you want the system
goes like traditional any kind of
anonymous system has this trade-off any
other questions
you mentioned the Linux kernel thing
using SSB for internal do you know if
anything has happened with that is
anyone actually going to get that during
no so I think that the message was
posted on his blog as a way to sort of
start the conversation and you could see
that that's people worse were discussing
about this by themselves but as far as I
know there hasn't come anything out of
it and it and if something comes out of
it I have a feeling that it not
necessarily going to be SSB but
something is be like bubbling but with
the same ideas I think but I haven't
happened anything like concrete with
this any other questions okay then
that's have another round of applause
for thank you
[Applause]