who is going to tell us about whether we
can trust our encrypted cloud services
or not yes that's exactly what I'm going
to talk about so this is something I did
some some time ago and I did it with my
current advisor so I work at almost
University and I do the like
cryptography daily so not so much
security but like cryptography and this
is like there's a lot of cryptography in
this okay so can you entrust you or can
you trust you encrypted cloud this is an
assessment of like one of these
applications than you can use so to put
like this into some context that might
make sense to like what do I think of as
like a traditional cloud storage when I
say traditional cloud storage I'm
thinking something like Google Drive or
Dropbox or or something like this and
these applications like the traditional
cloud storage you know the way you just
put your file on some server and now
it's there it's nice because now you can
access it even if your computer gets
stolen and so on but it still raises
some concerns with regards to the
privacy of your files so for example
like decides myself
who else can read this file and of
course you know anyone with access to
these servers will be able to read the
files there are some more like subtle
issues for example if we delete a file I
store a file unlike Google servers now I
delete it is it actually gone do I have
like any insurance assurance that
somebody who later comes along I don't
know steals Google servers or the NSA I
don't know sex you know takes control of
these servers to actually have a
currency that they can't you know
recover my file and I don't really have
this and the same applies of course with
if I did like if I cancel my account or
something there was an incident like a
couple of years ago with Dropbox where
they got into some some trouble because
they suddenly started to basically
recreate files that people had deleted
up to like six years ago or so so that's
not really like even if I delete this
file and it's completely gone from my
account suddenly it shows up again
because it's actually not deleted from
the servers right it's yeah and of
course what what happens if you know
this storage company sold I might trust
Google or
I trust Dropbox or whatever but what if
it's suddenly sold to some you know I
don't know Chinese company or company
that I don't trust right it's the same
same problem again it's because I don't
have control over my files anymore
these storage systems these encrypted
storage systems they solve this and like
the most simplest way you can think of
like you have a password that you use in
any event when you log in so now you
just use this as well so some how to
write a key and then you encrypt this
password and then you upload it to the
server there's a lot of like caveats
here because now you can't use the
proper authentication anymore and this
is some of the things that we exploited
in this thing but like this is basically
the idea of all of these encrypted cloud
storage applications they do basically
this of course like in real life it's
not just you know the it's not so simple
that you just derive a key from your
password and use it to you encrypt your
files because you know an application
should perhaps do a bit more than just
you know encrypt the file and put it on
a storage device you also wanted to be
able to well authenticate first of all
because some of these applications they
might have like additional data there
are some information assorted would you
so they can contact you there might be
some payment involved and so on you want
to be able to say it like your files and
both your laptop and your phones so
there's some synchronization of files
you want here you might want to be able
to say I want to share this file and so
on so there's like a lot of details here
that act like complexity on top of this
but in a nutshell this is basically what
happens when you use these services they
encrypt your file with the with your
password so the idea of these is
essentially to protect it so I think the
the best way to see the security they
want to achieve these services is they
want to protect like your files against
the server themselves right because
you're storing the files on the server
but you don't trust the servers to
actually you know not read the files or
not suddenly you know lose them or
something like this so you essentially
want to protect them against the servers
and this is essentially what they claim
all of these or I have some quotes from
like these companies like you shouldn't
have like you should never have to trust
a cloud storage server or LastPass which
is essentially also cloud encrypted
cloud storage but now if like short
strings which is the password
I guess say the same thing sync is
another program that does despite office
also dislike no knowledge means we know
nothing about the encrypted data you
store on all servers so basically you
want to like you want to protect your
files against the server in some way and
what we actually look at is like to what
extent it's these claims actually true
so all of these are of course you know
taken from there when you go to the web
page this is you know in big text on the
front page so they can sell that product
and so on but is it actually true like
or to which extent is this true so the
way we went about this is that we first
was like defined some sort of like
threat model for this so when they say
you know you don't have to trust the
server what do they actually mean by
this because you can interpret this you
know you shouldn't have to trust this
cloud storage service you can interpret
this in a lot of different ways and
depending on how you interpret it some
of them are secure like at least like
the spy rope we looked at it might be
secure it might not depending on how you
interpret you know the can I trust the
server for example then we did like a
bunch of reverse engineering of this
application in order to see if it
actually worked and then we found out
that it was not secure and then we like
brought a bunch of proof of concept code
and then we executed these attacks and
then we you know sent them an email and
they fix the stuff and so on so
everything is like back to the status
quo or whatever you might say yeah it's
like a small like note here that of
course cloud storage since I'm like
doing research daily I don't know I have
to plug some research that is you know
been done on cloud storage of course
it's it's not just like as was mentioned
in the previous talk and it's the same
here it's not just like homemade crypto
everything there's also like some
research involved in this but yeah okay
so very informally we consider the
setting where you have like a client and
server so we don't really care about
like it many clients and where or a
setting where the client has like a lot
of devices and so on we take like this
simplest possible case where you say I
have a client and I have a server
the client basically wants to store
stuff on the server and the server wants
to I don't know give this stuff back to
the client but we somehow you know
cannot trust the server completely
because if you could trust the server
completely obviously what we will just
do is that we will just send the files
to the server right we might use TLS or
something so everybody else cannot read
what we're sending but if we trust the
server then there's no point in
encrypting our data right because we
trust the server so we consider
basically two cases so either we say
that we are in select we asked like is
it secure if the server is like only
passively malicious which basically
means we trust the server to do
everything that it's supposed to do or
we don't trust it to not try to read our
files right so it's essentially says
that you know if everything works
normally then stuff shouldn't break like
this should be like the minimal
requirement right this this you might
see that for example something like a
gmail account for example would not be
secured against this clearly right
because everything of course works and
so on but just because you're like
storing your emails and like clear text
on Google servers of course they can
know the content of your emails but it's
of course not really the you know the a
goal of Google to to like hide the
content of your emails because they use
them for various things right so so this
is like this is for something that where
you cannot trust the server in some
sense there should be like the minimum
right the I cannot trust that like I
trust the server to do everything
correctly but I don't trust it to not
read my files that's basically this is
in some sense it also provides security
in the case where you say ok I actually
trust the server to do everything
correctly but I don't trust them to you
know not get hacked for example right so
if your files are secure in this case
then it's also secure if somebody breaks
into the server and even learns all the
server's you know database like
encryption keys and so on it's like the
the most you know the most a company can
can lose the data right if it loses
everything then it would still be fine
in this case because the server cannot
read the files obviously anybody who
breaks into the server also cannot read
the files
so it's not just if you don't trust the
server it all says like nice things
outside of this the other thing is like
what if like the server just does
whatever it wants
so like I say I want my files back and
now the server just sends me whatever
you know it can send me whatever it
wants this is perhaps a bit less
realistic because in practice you'd
imagine you know this is you might you
know see if this this happens right from
the server it's a lot more fun to study
of course but it's also worth like
considering because it might be the case
that I don't know you could probably
come up with some I don't know strange
scenario right where the server is like
taken over by some hacker or an
intelligence agency and they target a
specific user and now against the
specific use of the server sends like
specific messages in order to try to
break basically its own application
right and this is essentially what we
have here of course there's like a small
note here that we test this we test
these two threat models against like
software we get from the server itself
essentially so in particular like in the
second case here you might argue
obviously no cloud storage application
where you get the application from the
cloud storage service is this secure
here right because what the server just
does in this case is when you ask it for
the software it just you know since you
broke in software basically that just
reveals your files as soon as you start
using it so there's like a small Asterix
here saying that we consider this in the
case where you already have you know the
right software so to speak so like the
software you get from the server and the
server does like its best with this
software so this is basically saying you
have the software before and now can
deceive her somehow abuse box or
protocol floors or something in its own
software to somehow break the security
of what you have
whereas I guess the other one here you
can say is like is it just broken from
like without doing anything okay
I know this is not really that
interesting if you don't like cryptic
I suppose we also provide like a simple
formal modeling of what this means these
two things and essentially what you do
is that you sit it up that's like a game
you make some assumptions about how the
user picks his password in this case you
assume that he picks his password as
something which has CAPA bits and he
picks it at random which is not of
course true in real life but it's the
physis for a formal modeling and then
you play like a small game and it's the
the rules are very simple like the
adversary he just he can ask the user to
upload two files one of these files are
encrypted and the server like the air
like the guy who attacking the system he
wins if he knows which of these files
was actually encrypted so this is like
the most I guess his mystic situation
where the guy who's attacking you knows
everything about what you're storing
except which files use like of these
files restoring so basically he gives
you two files it might just be file with
like one of them there's like a one in
one of them there's the zero and now you
upload one of them you don't tell the
guy which one you upload and you just
upload one of them and now it's secure
if he doesn't know which one of these
you actually store it so even if he
knows which files you're actually
storing as long as there's little some
like uncertainty that's basically what
that says but it's not like super
important I just drew it here okay so
everything based on the passwords we
make like three categorizations of what
is what an attack can be in this case
like one of them is like okay you you
recover the user's password and remember
that everything in the end is like
encrypted with the users password in
some way so you cover the users password
like it's game over right now you can
decrypt everything because the attacker
here is still the server so he has all
the encrypted information and so on so
there's nothing else besides the
password essentially all right it might
be the case that he can recover like one
file without actually knowing the
password as you see like we'll see how
this could be in this case because it's
not clear from the simple situation
before or it might actually be because
you might leak the
some duration of the password but not
the password itself so this doesn't
reveal the password but it does reveal
enough information to actually recover
the file a last thing it might be
possible that you somehow run a protocol
that just basically weakens whatever
information you have about the password
beforehand so typically the way these
protocols are like sorry these
applications perform authentication is
they derive like the hash the password
basically using a strong hash function
or like a key deviation function and it
might be the case that you can actually
tweak this from the server's so now
instead of getting a good deviation of
your password you get like a weak
liberation that can actually be brute
forced that's essentially what you have
down here you're like we can the
security by some factor greek-letter
yes okay so some information about this
application so as mentioned again it's a
bit more complex or what is essentially
happens in Spy doc is that you have the
password you use this somehow to encrypt
like some long-term keys these long-term
keys are used some how to encrypt
directory keys so you get like a key for
each directory and these are used to
encrypt files so you get like this nice
nice kind of like hierarchy of keys like
in the end from the server's point of
view only this guy up here is unknown he
has everything else which is of course
encrypted but in the end he only needs
to know this guy in order to reveal
everything down here communication is is
fairly simple it's like some back and
forth to do authentication and like this
is actually the most interesting part
the authentication because typical
password over TLS authentication doesn't
work anymore so when you log in to like
any online service essentially what
happens is that you send your password
and you username to this server the
server does something to check that this
was the right combination of username
password and now it lets you in based on
this obviously this doesn't work anymore
if you cannot give the password to the
server right so what they do instead is
instead of using any of the protocols
that is has been developed within the
last 25 years on unlike authentication
that doesn't reveal the past
they designed like a couple of their own
which of course doesn't work so once you
have authenticated to the servers then
everything is basically our PC using
[Music]
something from the matrix library so
this is like a Python framework for a
network communication and like I know
there's a bunch of extra stuff in a
typical crowdsource application but this
application had something like 95 I
think different methods that the server
can call on the client which is like a
lot and we also found out that this can
also be abused in like very ease very
silly ways essentially to break the
security totally ok so briefly about
encryption so basically like how does
this this this stick figure area to the
right what does this what so when you
want to encrypt something in this
application you take the password an ID
your file you generate some random keys
in this case like one for the file one
for the directory you derive a key based
on the password so using a key duration
function this is in practice this would
be pbkdf2 with some fixed parameters so
basically just hashing this 10,000 times
that's essentially what happens here you
encrypt the file using this KF which is
a random key you encrypt this KF with
this KD which is another random key and
now you encrypt this KD with the key
from your password so this is basically
what happens here right you have the can
imagine you have the file down here
somewhere and now you have this key
encrypted with this key encrypted with
some key up here encrypted with this one
so that's how like this this is how it
works more or less the reason for doing
this is that you can imagine this
basically as putting the key in a header
of the file in this way it gives some
flexibility in particular if you want to
share a file it's enough to just send
this key to whoever plus of course the
cipher text to whoever you want to share
this with and if you want to share like
an entire directory it's also just a
matter of sending it like one key and we
imagine that this is like this is at
least some of the reason why they
this particular scheme is because it
makes file sharing very efficient
of course note security is entirely
dependent on the password ok the entire
thing is written in Python this is great
because python is very easy to decompile
well you can apply obfuscation to this I
know this is something that happens in
Dropbox
they obfuscate their applications but
spider one doesn't so you can take like
any off-the-shelf Python T compiler and
you should be able to basically unpack
the installer that you download from
their web page and you can just
decompile the whole application and then
you have some very nice readable Python
there's like a whole lot of files that
you have to look at here a lot of these
are not really needed for the core
application but there's still like a lot
of filtering about what is actually
relevant what is not it communicates
over a TLS which is of course like
needed to not be like really broken I
suppose it doesn't mean that of course
like man in the middle cipher texts are
not possible we don't really care about
this because in the end we want to
protect against the server and the
server is like the intended recipient of
your data in any event so TLS doesn't
really factor into this whole like a
tech scenario we envision here in
practice of course you still want to
have TLS because otherwise like
everybody can just read what you have or
I guess you could say that's like if the
application is broken and you're not
using TLS then it's not broken only
towards the server it's basically broken
towards the whole world which is like
somewhat more bad I guess somewhat
better it does makes experimenting a bit
difficult because it has like hard-coded
certificates and so on so and also like
analyzing what traffic it sends back and
forth also becomes a lot became like
sort of difficult the approach we took
is the I guess you could say like the
tried and true tested of like debugging
by printing you know when you write a
program you put like print statements
everywhere to see what's actually going
on we do the same thing because now we
could decompile the whole thing
and then we made use of the locking
framework that it already had to print
stuff all over the place in the
application and we did this for example
to print the the connection keys that it
uses in the TLS so it prints this and
now we can capture all the traffic in
Wireshark and then we can load these
keys into Wireshark afterwards and now
we can actually read what it's sending
back and forth without actually touching
the application except for like very
minimally some places yeah okay so the
attacks I guess
the interesting part the fun part we
found four different things so one of
them is basically you could again this
thing where you you compute some
deviation of the users password in
connection to someone's dedication like
basically it's possible to weaken this
to a point where it most likely doesn't
provide awesome like a adequate security
anymore like it doesn't pretty like it
doesn't hide the password well enough
essentially we found two attacks that
can recover the user's password one
somehow requires some interaction from
the user that you might say okay this is
not realistic or it is realistic and if
so if you don't believe that one we also
found one that does the same thing but
like now it doesn't require any
interaction from the user at all so like
it it can just happen silently in the
background while the user does
absolutely nothing and then we found an
interesting attack which actually
reveals files also without the use of
doing anything but this is actually also
happens without the server doing
anything so this is essentially like
certain use patterns of this application
or like you of this feature which is
like file sharing in this case will
actually reveal more than it's supposed
to
so essentially you say I share this file
but now you inadvertently also share
like two other files basically something
like this sorry yes of course like the
required statement I we contacted them
and they fixed it and we did this before
we made anything public and so on and so
forth of course
so the first one like the uninteresting
one because it's basically just if you
have a good password then this doesn't
matter if you have a bad password and
likely this doesn't matter either
because like usually you have a very
terrible password or you have a password
that it's like good enough you don't
have a password is just like only
slightly good enough if you had it like
twice more than its suddenly good or
something like somehow passwords work
but in any event one of these
authentication protocols that it uses is
basically password over TLS but now the
hashing that you usually perform on the
server side as part of this
authentication protocol now it happens
on the client side as well so like this
is a the easiest way perhaps to avoid
the problem of sending your password to
the server so this is essentially what
happens so the server will send some
random number random string to the
client the client computes a deviation
using in this case B crypt which is a
it's an iterated hash function
essentially it's like a it's a hash
function you apply and like the on
itself and then just do this a lot of
times so now it's expensive to compute
and this provides a bit more security to
the just doing it one for example it's
essentially our voice uses a block
cipher what is the same thing so you
sent this back and the server will say
oh you know you're the person you claim
to be if this matches some hash that it
already has on the server right the
problem is that in bcrypt the the the
salt contains essentially everything
that the client needs in order to
compute the function in particular it
also includes the parameters for how
expensive this function should be so
instead of saying that this should be 12
which is like the default on almost all
libraries and machines and
recommendations which is like two to the
twelve iterations which is some power of
two
I can calculate in my head right now of
course you can basically take in like
just push this all the way down until
the library start like the library
they're using start complaining that
this is you know below what it's
supposed to do in practice you could put
this down to four which is now 16 so 16
iterations of this underlying function
which is like very very fast this is of
course not enough this is like like way
way less than is recommended in the
original bcrypt paper from 92 so of
course it's also not enough in 2017 or
18 or 19 it's a fact to rate downgrade
in principle this is essentially getting
like an md5 like in terms of computation
required and so on it's essentially
getting an empty 5 of the users password
something like this which is not enough
in practice but this of course doesn't
reveal anything it just makes it easier
for already weak passwords to be broken
basically so the first password
recoveries
so again this is again an attack on one
of these authentication protocols
interestingly they had four
authentication protocols that we
discover in the application so the
weight of indicates is or the weight
runs these protocols is the server tells
the client please run this protocol and
now they run a protocol and stuff
happens there's like four of these in
the application and it only ever used
two of them when we looked at how it
operated when you just used it normally
but of course if we assume the the
server just does whatever it wants it
can just tell the client to run you know
one of these protocols that might be not
used anymore for example or might be
used for different things in this case
it's not used in the client server
setting it's used in most likely
something else and like an and key
escrow setting which is basically what
this does anyways so what how this works
is that the server can say run this
protocol and here is a list of RSA keys
and here is a random number okay so now
the client first it does something it
computes like a function of this list it
computes a fingerprint using some RFC
that is
also from the late 90s it tells you how
to take a binary string then chop it
into pieces and then map these pieces to
English words and then how to display
this string as a as a list of English
words basically so what it does so
that's basically what it does it hashes
the fingerprint or sorry it hashes this
list of keys it uses this thing to
convert it into a string of numbers it
displaces to the user and the user is
asked you know do I trust this random
like the string of random numbers if yes
click you know continue if no click
cancel if the user clicks continue then
you use these keys to basically encrypt
a concatenation of the password and the
challenge and then just like iterated
and now he sent this back to the server
of course the attacker is is clear if we
ignored this fingerprint the thing for a
moment is that the server just picks his
own keys right so he picks some keys he
asks the user to encrypt what is
basically his password on this challenge
under keys that he know how to decrypt
and of course this learns like this
reveals the password to the server as a
small aside if this we also found that
if this list is empty the user will just
like the client will just send back this
thing like unencrypted also so you don't
actually even need to have the keys you
can just send nothing and then you just
get back the password so like it saves a
bit of work on the server I guess yeah
of course this is what's it so but when
we change this list yeah so you get
these this string of random words that
the user have to accept so the question
is like how realistic is it that a user
will accept it and in this case we argue
that it's very realistic because
together with this list of words you
also get this nice warning which it says
something about this fingerprint phrase
and it also says that if you have not
been giving this fingerprint before then
just click yes anyway which is you can
sort of compare this to like a
certificate you get on when you visit a
webpage right and obviously if your
browser says I don't trust the
certificate it shouldn't be you know I
have not seen this certificate before so
just click yes which is probably what
most users
do anyway but it shouldn't be encouraged
by the application at least they fixed
this by well not really fixing this
protocol because I we believe they use
it for their enterprise products because
it does provide a form of escrowing
encryption keys and passwords but they
fix this wedding so now it doesn't say
that you should just ignore you know
comment logic and just accept whatever
it starts to do but it is it is a proper
thing in like software right it's trust
and first used in this case yes so file
recovery I'll take this this is the one
night mentioned where it's basically
like a use pattern that ends up breaking
the application or like the security of
some of your files and paste in some
sense the server actually doesn't have
to do anything in this this case so it's
based on how this encryption works so if
you share a directory this happens by
revealing this directory key so you had
this you encrypt the file with like a
directory key and these keys are
encrypted with your password essentially
but now if all the files in a specific
directory is encrypted with like the
same key if you just reveal this
directory key the server can actually
recover all the phone like individual
file keys and now all the individual
files so that's how it works
[Music]
the problem is that when you start
moving files around in like a directory
on your computer this is not really
reflected in these keys so in like there
doesn't there's no like rien krypton of
these keys so somehow like there's a
there's mismatch and like the view the
application half of your directories and
the view that you have of your
directories and yeah these directory
keys never rotate it so it's quite easy
to come up with like scenarios where
this is bad so for example if you have a
directory with some files you move one
of them to a different directory and
then you share the old one now because
of these things up here I mentioned here
when you move this to a different
directory the encryption of this guy is
not updated so it's actually still
secured under whatever key is associated
with this old directory and now
you share the old directory this also
reveals the file you moved away right so
like this is and it's quite easy to
think of like scenarios in real life
what this applies right it's like this
is all your vacation photos and this is
like a particularly not shareable
vacation photo right you move it to a
private folder and then you share your
vacation photos but now the server has
all your vacation photos right obviously
you don't want this to happen the sort
of like reverse also happens if you have
a directory with like shared files say
this from before you can like keep
adding stuff to it it will be encrypted
under a key that the server already know
so now it's also like intuitively shared
when you do this if you stop sharing
this directory because these directory
keys are not updated when you now add
new files to a directory that is no
longer supposed to be shared it's still
going to be encrypted using a key that
the server knows right so this also
provides like this provides some sort of
like false sense of security essentially
for a directory that you're you know you
don't think is shared but it's actually
shared because it happened to be shared
some somehow in the past and I guess
like these two situations in particular
are can be bad right in if you use this
application for a long time you like
keep adding directories you keep moving
stuff around and so on like at some
point I COO knows what is actually known
by the server and which is not right
okay
so then yeah beause I guess this is
worth stressing that in both of these
cases you actually take specific actions
right in this case in step two here in
this case also step two like the the
user actually takes like specific
actions to avoid sharing files in this
case but somehow like security like the
privacy of his files are still like not
there okay so finally the completely
silent password recovery doesn't use
that protocols are broken it just uses I
guess
dead code and bad programming I suppose
anyways after installation in order to
like authenticate automatically
basically when you start up the your
application after you put and so on this
happens because the password is
basically stored in plain text on your
own computer it also means that if
you're using Spyder most likely you
shouldn't lose your computer because if
somebody gets access to the files in
this computer they actually also gets
access to the password that you're using
even if it was like turned off at least
if they're still doing what they're
doing here which I think there are but
they stored the user's password in clear
text plain text on the user's machine
because this means you don't have to
input it to the application every times
it starts because now I can just run
whatever authentication protocol it's
supposed to run with the server just
runs it normally like automatically
right we found some like our similar
methods that most likely have to do with
like debugging and so on which is like
you can give it a file path and then it
returns the content of this file so now
you might imagine like what they what
the attack here might be right it's that
we could like it accepted the file like
the the path for the file containing the
user's password as for this method so
basically the server can can tell the
user or the client can sell it please
send me the content of this file I need
it for debugging and now the client will
just send back this file that already
contains the user's password in clear
text which is like yeah the check here
is it's it's not sufficient to to guard
against this attack so it's like there's
all of these like interesting protocols
they write and so on and then in the end
like the most broken part of this is
just like I don't know old code the fix
they had for this one was just to remove
these methods because they were not used
according to them so yeah I guess yeah
so some conclusions like I'm a bit ahead
of time I think but okay yeah like I
have one slight web so some takeaways I
think so it's not just attacks the main
interesting part is authentication like
authentication in this case is the
reason for all of the attacks except the
one with the file-sharing and moving
stuff around and so on but the fact that
they have to come up with like their own
authentication protocols in order to get
around the fact that you have to send
the password and so on just breaks
everything and it's in particularly bad
in this case because the password that
you enter in order to say I'm whoever I
claim to be is also the password that
you use to encrypt your files so now if
they've right like a broken
authentication protocol which they did
at least twice here you also break like
the security of the confidentiality of
your files basically the application is
somewhat over permissive in these RPC
methods and this also ties somehow into
the threat model that we used it's like
in the end it's not clear like how what
exactly is the trust like the the threat
model that they're using they claim to
you know oh you shouldn't be able to
trust us but of course this is somehow
at least if you care about it it's not
really that it doesn't tell you much
about like the actual security so the
application is somewhat overly
permissive in the in how much the server
is allowed to do is this an issue maybe
depends on how much you trust the server
trust this application if the
application designers are like upfront
at the beginning saying like this is the
specific threat model that we use then
it's easier to say that okay
this matches my expectations of security
from this product or if it doesn't then
you just don't use it instead of this
thing where you think that you know the
claim they have on their front page it's
like oh it means that you know
regardless of what happens my files are
still secure which is not the case here
well the security provider should match
the claims I think that's like an
obvious one of course
somehow formalizing the security
provided in a way that makes it you know
somehow equivalent to these nice claims
they have on the front page is hardly a
trivial thing to do it's like it's a
very non trivial thing to do actually
but there should be at least more than
just this pitch sales pitch
justbe I think and yeah if they use like
custom-made protocols they should be
possible to order these protocols in
this case it's easy or an easy ish to
audit the protocols because like in the
end the application was written in
Python so that it like took that removed
like it's large requirement of having to
debug its program but if you want to or
like audit some of these other
applications that also does encryption
and so on and then the only thing you
have to work with is like a compile C++
program or something then it's like
suddenly this is a lot harder to do of
course right so it should be possible
they should at least like describe how
these protocol works I said I don't
think there's any case of anything in
the history of software where anybody
has well I was going to be has gained
anything by you like designing their own
protocol and somehow pacing security
partly or in total on this protocol
somehow being hidden from everybody else
like it doesn't work it doesn't work in
cryptography and I doubt that it works
in protocol design as well so that's it
basically so questions yes
um thank you for the talk I was
interesting at home am i understanding
correctly that the sharing feature
actually isn't meant to be and and
encrypted you normally just reveal the
content of the yep you just reveal in
this application you just revealed the
content to the server is that um I mean
obviously like there are things that
have end end file sharing where like for
all their talk about zero knowledge I'm
very surprised to learn that that's the
intended design of it I wonder do do you
think they make that clear to users at
all I've never actually used the
software but I've seen it advertised and
it this seems totally counter to their
yes so like it's very strange
the this file-sharing thingy where you
just reveal stuff partly one of the
reasons we wanted to look at this
particular piece of software in the
beginning is they have it here is that
this thing they call no knowledge yeah
which is totally used to be called
sterile knowledge at some point which
means a total different thing if you
study cryptography so it's that was like
a large red flag in the beginning it's
like oh they use this word and I don't
think they know what it means but yeah
they don't for the file-sharing no they
don't it's it's different from for
example something like megaupload where
the key is actually like the whole thing
happens in your browser so now it's
actually proper in to end encrypt it
also for like sharing of files it's not
revealed to the client but not in this
case known in this case it's just you
revealed this content to the server and
now the server access essentially like a
normal file sharing system but is that
like clear in the user interface like
when you install the software and use it
do do you think most users or paying for
SpiderOak or for finals yeah I think so
I seem to remember that this is like
they mentioned this they have like a
bunch of caveats also like if you log
into their whip-like
log into your account on their website
they also have like a small footnote
saying now it doesn't apply anymore this
file-sharing because you log in with
your password and this is normal
password over TLS when you log into the
website it's just like so yeah so when
when they fix this
bugged or RPC method for asking the
client for the password did they do an
advisory about that
no they wrote a blog post which i think
is now it might be lost now because they
redesigned their webpage so now
conveniently they lost a lot of stuff
was it written about in the media at all
like I was right it was like it wasn't
there like I was interviewed for an
article for version 2 like fishmoto like
a Danish thing so oh thank you for the
research and any other questions no then
let's give a spin
[Applause]