music sitting in a room so um what what
Alvin Lucier says there at the opening
is the piece of music it's a process
piece it's called so his voice feeds
back through the tape recorder and goes
back out into a speaker and by the end
of the piece it's about 45 minutes long
you end up with the resonant
characteristics of the room so usually
an scholars don't skip through the 45
minutes you know you listen to it and
it's quite an incredible listen and it's
very much active listening but I've
prepared a spectrogram run for about 25
minutes through where you can see the
room resonance is starting to appear you
should be able to see
[Music]
that's what it sounds like towards the
end that speech that you heard at the
beginning after it's just multiplied or
being convulsed with the room acoustics
so going back to the idea of reading
sound this definition I pulled up it's a
very interesting book about how sound
design and sonic clinking has been used
politically to influence and in the
consumer round to influence so many
things so it's something that we need to
get much better at and learn to control
because it's bits but also being
targeted and used in in ways that I
don't completely support but the first
step is that we have to start to listen
to things like that resonant
characteristics of the room how am i
doing for time I think we're going to be
alright so I wanted to do a live demo of
something that it's a music hack that
I've written which wraps the free sound
API does anybody know what free sound is
so it's a project that was initiated in
quite early 2003 I might say from the
music technology group in the University
of Pompeu Fabra in Barcelona it's a
community built archive of field
recordings but they can also be any type
of recordings it's an audio archive so
many things they are available under a
free attribution license and the API is
really thorough so you can look it up
you can look up sounds in terms of just
tokens or descriptions or keywords but
you can also look things up according to
their spectral content and duration and
volume and stuff like that so I made a
little exercise to see if we can do
actually do some of that reading sound
just try to see what it feels like to
push beyond your literal interpretations
of words and what you expect them to
sound like
[Music]
seems to be wanting to do the scientists
so this is like a news headline story
and what we're going to do is use those
tokens to pull out streamed audio from
the free sound database and it will just
compose them in in the written the order
that it's pulled them out but it will
make a sound collage for us and let's
see if see how you feel about the
relationships
that's that one is interesting because
they're sometimes gravitational waves in
the article pulls up the actual sound of
the sonification of gravitational waves
that was you know a major milestone in
in in physics and it was the result is
so difficult to explain what
gravitational waves are to the public
that what what they did the scientist
was put out the sound of it so it's
quite a famous sound which I sometimes
it comes up but not this time so going
back to the slides I think it's also
important to think about what what I was
saying there that you might think that
I'm listening to sound or this type of
deep listening practice is limited to
people who have the you know good
hearing but this quote from Dame Evelyn
Glennie
and she's the first person in history to
successfully create and sustain a full
time career as a solo percussionist
incredibly talented musician who's
completed that career profoundly deaf
and she now listens in a very
interesting way
that could have been the microphone on
my pulse there but it's actually so our
room recording so not the acoustics of
the room the acoustics of the womb I'm
just going to share with you now a few
of the interesting facts about our
relationship to sound to hopefully
inspiring you little yes or they ordered
to resist them becomes functional around
25 weeks and they're in between
maternity and when I was looking for a
picture with his slide I found that one
and I thought it was quite good because
I was talking about a deep listening
practice and I think that could be a
good example of when somebody who might
not be comfortable with doing that sort
of listening you know tries to begin to
relate to the yet unborn child by
listening through sounds so we
established these relationships very
early on and they mean a lot and I think
there's a there's more area we're
talking about sound but music as a music
space if we talk about music as
organized sound there's a lot of really
interesting post rave literature about
how important that is for the shaping of
our imagination and the scope of what we
might be able to think about in terms of
organizing principles and organizing
ourselves this book is highly
recommended and it just starts to Adam
starts to open up the probability space
and he's calling it infinite but with
many multi dimensions reminds me a lot
this is how I'm able to keep up with
some of the conversations I've had with
networked people here and it at born hat
because you know in music we also think
about these huge spaces with multiple
dimensions of variables infinite
variability as an example let's talk
about you know this idea of infinity
well anything's possible so Adam quite
early in his book starts to postulate
that music without
is something very viable that a composer
composes so when we talk about non sonic
music I'm quite comfortable with that
but a lot of people have a question and
say how can you have music without sound
so I thought we could try some exercises
on that so let's talk about kind of
imagining sound
this is working even better with the
screen moving I have to say but does do
any of you hear a sound when you look at
that silent gift what it was so what
does it sound like to you well many
people report hearing a low sub when the
pylon hits the ground there's a there's
a reddit thread full of noisy gifts
where's people who experience this
latent synesthetic synesthetic phenomena
they start to post loads more and if you
want to if you're getting something from
that then you might want to explore more
and also Elliott Freeman's research so
he's trying to explore this visually
evoked auditory response which has
become quite prominent because of this
this particular gift by happy toast was
the one that went viral but there's
loads of other ones the point of that is
that the neural plasticity of the brain
has kind of fixed our senses in place
quite early on but what I'm trying to
get at is that our relationship to sound
even for a large amount of people who
can hear that pylon here's some sub
coming out of it you know it's still
something that we can train to get a lot
more information out of it and it's
totally entwined with with the way we
think and the way we perceive things and
it also goes back a really long way so
that what I'm telling you now is not
something new that new research has
shown it's starting to say hey before we
were dominantly visual culture we used
our auditory sense much more and of
course the navigation of cave systems in
the dark with very little light and the
archaeologists that go down and study
primitive art have there's a new branch
opening up relatively new called
archaeoacoustics where they try to
assess
the placement of certain cave drawings
and primitive art and they try to assess
it acoustically like why did our
ancestors choose this spot to paint this
and they think about the limited light
they would have had and they go down and
just try to assess the acoustics and
they found a lot of correlations between
very weird phenomena of sound in caves
reflecting off walls and weird
underground echoes to the location of
some of the most impacting art they feel
that there was a that the sound had a
sort of supernatural quality for our
primitive ancestors I've got a video of
Igor Resnick off exploring a cave with
his voice
[Music]
okay that's good so for a long time
sound phenomena has influenced ancient
art and architecture and the way we
think it's only in recent years and the
rise of screen culture and then digital
visual culture that we sound has
seemingly taken some type of backseat
into him some type of entertainment or
like a good playlist for coding too or
like it's very secondary was I still
think that we can get a lot smarter with
it so just some more examples from that
I've collected to share with you so
these are the the Aboriginal song lines
you might have heard of them a Bruce
Chatwin he wrote a quite a famous novel
at the end of the 80s which documented
this concept but the the aboriginal
cultures have this like G of psychic
supernatural environmental song
tradition that maps out man's
relationship to the spirits and the
locations in the environment and this
sort of sound and story starts to give
you hopefully some ideas about how sound
and sound forms and music can encode
some really complex information that can
be decoded by sharing with the next
generation by singing a song and so on I
wanted to play this as an example of a
kind of sound story that it's quite
personal for me so I told you at the
start that I had started out a little
bit in the amiga demo scene making mods
that would fit onto the the boot blocks
of the floppy disks and and at that time
it was 88-89 and we were trading through
through the post in jiffy bags and disks
would arrive one day this disc came with
this four channel thing of numbers going
up and is called a tracker and it's the
first time I saw a sequencer and it was
written by the hacker community for them
to be able to make mods right so um I
got really into it and made lots and
lots of music for my group that group
that I was in and at some point I had
recorded a sampled my mum coming in and
I said we were I was making a track I
said mum shout punch it down the mic now
she said I've got it yeah and that's
really weird because I pulled this this
is a mega demo scene archive that's been
organized by people I don't know around
the world that appeared I just came
across it about a year and a half ago
and they had a bunch of these mods that
I had made in my bedroom in 1988-89 on
floppy disks and they are merging their
fully attributed from people who are
documenting a subculture through a music
tradition that's really tied with a also
the roots of compression technology and
lots of things so for me personally I'm
still I'm still can't figure out how
they got from the floppy disk to that
Archive in 2018 but I played it to my
mum you know and she said when did I say
that
in 1989 interesting so what I'm getting
at here with that personal story and
something that's more culturally an
anthropological is specified is that um
again that sound this is a big subject
so I've put that on one slide in a nice
layout but it's it's the same sort of
thing that we talk about here and it's
about encoding information sharing
information bringing communities
together evading control evading being
manipulated you know unlike music plays
a huge
huge role in that and sound as of as an
energy form and a data transmission form
can be used in many ways the think
before you think paradigm again I'm
going back to it because it's like how
can we begin to how can you who maybe
who haven't practiced deep listening
maybe as much as I have for all you know
as associated with music as much as I
have how can you start to get at those
ideas and it's really just about doing
some listening practice so here is a
great place when you're camping and
there's some sound systems that are
distributed around the place and over
here you might hear something and then
the sound of the trees and then they
start to blend together so you need to
just sit I find if I close my eyes and
just sometimes put just cut my hands
over their ears and you can just sit and
breathe and just listen for five minutes
do that every day and you're gonna
you're going to start to perceive nuance
in a way that mint might resonate with
with your other work
[Applause]
[Music]
so now going to this idea of music which
is the probably the most common
association that people have with sound
and apart from language of course spoken
language
whenever we
we changed we are no longer the same
after having very little certain sounds
and this is the mole of the case when we
hear organized sounds organized another
human being
[Music]
right so the point is this piece of
music so that Stockhausen it's a
composer modernist composer very very
very intelligent bloke incredible vision
of the future and of other worlds and
his music is astounding and impressive
to to explore I did that version there
some time ago because I thought about
how he just had over he how could he
have seen that sound and music or it
might not be organized by another human
being anymore right so that's what that
whole sound piece is meant to written I
don't know if you've been listening to a
I produced music on a sample by sample
basis but you know sound is now being
organized by a not by human beings
anymore we're hearing new types of
sounds I've also been thinking about
this idea that music changes you on a
cellular level and I've been thinking
about that song the Dec own so it made
me want to drink beer I've got another
example here about how efficient
organized sound can be and they pump
death to second track very famous so now
I've got to a point in my practice where
the some of the things I'm telling you
I'm only dipping into it but I hope that
you're trying to you're getting an
impression that I believe pretty
strongly that everything that I've
learned in a lifetime working with sound
in order to be practice can start to be
put to better use than just I'm going to
make cool beat I'm going to do a good
track whatever so I'm starting to look
at ways that I can give a much more
meaningful result from my work I've got
a couple of examples to show you where
that might be this is a local one from
Finn from Auden see so there's a device
embedded in a cup
and it has various recordings of at
least Hansen's daughter reminding her to
drink she suffers from dementia and it
forgets to drink and has terrible time
going to bed completely dehydrated so
this this simple touch of order to
redesign thinking instead of putting
letting an engineer approach that
problem by just putting a beep in the
cup you know they actually put
recordings of someone who's very
familiar that she trusts so a sound that
she's familiar and trusting with and
that's a really good start that kind of
story and here's one that I wanted to
bring here to - born hack I haven't done
anything with this protocol yet but I
think it's really promising it's called
chirp I all
now the chirp guys sent me this I've
been following the project since 2012
and I asked them if they had a slide
that could explain it for me and it's
like this it's basically a frictionless
data - it's like a cute they they say
like a QR code in sound so you can
transmit data to any nearby local
devices is completely for me it's just
saying right this is a technology that's
decentralized this ad hoc that can
network that could communicate data
through sound it's really robust I did
have some of some of it chirps so yeah
this is the payload is really small
something like 32 bytes and the
transmission time is relatively slow for
a data network like five seconds could
be three seconds but it can also be
those tones can be working in the you
know what they can be inaudible in the
higher frequency ranges they can be
multi-channel and they can be
transmitted just from any device that
can hear that tongue to another device
that can descend it and vice versa
I'm really interesting protocol so if
you're interested in approaching this
topic
from a really specific technical
sonification exercise this one would be
great there they've got their
development kit an SDK up there on chirp
IO and this is a the agency that I've
established the startup I'm establishing
this year in Copenhagen and we are going
to start trying to bring like
facilitated workshop based learning to
get people to open up and listen and
start to hear for nuance and listen for
nuance before piling into okay now we're
going to change your environment and
tune it and things like this first we
want to have some type of life centered
goals and impact oriented design you
know so I'm starting to explore a lot
more of these direction for music and
sound
there's contact details and we are
totally open that's well put that little
did you see it drop us a line because
I'm also interested to see what ideas I
came here also to have lots of
conversations I've had so many amazing
conversations and inspiring things that
I hadn't thought about from from the the
lighting system that's here on the poles
what's it called the special message
coming out of it and and how that was a
visual version of something that could
also have been done with auditory you
know and it could have been pretty it's
kind of happening already with the camps
and the sound systems but if it could
have been integrated into the the lights
and all sorts of stuff so you know also
I was thinking about ways to and enhance
productivity and a deep dive for when
you're working with some really critical
coding situations and you need to have
special concentration I mean you know
it's quite primitive to have this
headphones and white noise and noise
cancelling stuff that and these sound of
surf and all this stuff that seems to be
quite popular at the moment is really
primitive as far as I'm concerned for
the possibilities of designing sound and
that's basically the talk so thank you
so much for listening
[Applause]
questions any questions some ideas and
brainstorms requests yeah and you had
that one recording of the sound of that
bird they have basically two layers of
sounds in there was it both from the
bird or was it some background noise or
actually that's it that's a whole LP of
first-class recordings it's a very very
good example of it of field recording
and I think that particular soundscape
it's not it's not edited afterwards it's
like that's what it sounds like to be in
the place where John Walsh who was the
recordist he would have to take
mission-critical audio technologies so
that's already something that is here if
you camping here okay you can you know
cook and stuff like that but you've got
to try and find those types of sound
scapes but that's as they are and I
think to go out there and be in a field
recordist and bring that back so I can
play it here for everybody and you think
oh it's layered maybe it's been
processed or something like that that's
already blowing your mind so it's not no
that's what it sounds like not only the
implications went of the particular
sound of this particular bird singing a
death song you know it blows my mind
that nature can be so good at organizing
a sound question
so thank you for your talk I haven't
actually been but I've heard that
Helsinki is like one of the cities in
Europe that has done a lot out of sound
design like it's it seems to be well
known for for having done a lot about
this but other cities are not following
up keeping up with with this trend like
what do you think is needed so that we
will get create more awareness about how
important sound is for our well-being
and reducing stress and such things in
cities I said it's a good question
because the soundscape of the cities is
something that we make and you would
need to start to get as thorough and
rigorous as John horse going out to find
that particular part of the Venezuelan
jungle and those birds you know like how
can we do this in the city to to try to
capture the way that the sits sound of
the city changes around us what
information can we get from listening to
the sound of cities from 20 years ago to
how are they sound now so that's
something that is absolutely really
important to document Anthropocene
impact on the soundscape yeah if there
are no further questions this terrific
run of applause for question
[Applause]