hello everyone thanks for coming
this is Jenna and we present half thing
100 filled accounts per day from
internet service this is Howard
disclaimer well mister things about how
we found larger our nobility winning the
Facebook no by application we will talk
about how it works
well how will it how it works
basic proof of concept little problem we
have exploited in this world this winner
already amassed how we solve it also we
will pay because we reported through to
the book bounty Facebook account and the
rumination thing implemented and this is
our first researched
will of learn interesting things and
break things well first of all the
banality we found larger was related to
instant articles functionality this
functionality basically is where you
cannot think media content directly
within the Facebook mobile application
we are opening for instance a browser
you can directly check news and whatever
they are clear on the facebook mobile
application this functionality
functionality allows you to view the
content to share it copy it paste the
link and so on so we found a session
will narrate
kayaking in this functionality so we
inform Facebook on May 2016 about the
this problem turn to the football
program how it works
with a couple narrative insured limbs
from fizzled mobile application this
molarity is caused due to the lack
proper position in what the lighting
will graded URLs shortened from Facebook
instant articles we made a little proof
of concept this is basically how it
works
ally teammate user is using his Noelle's
Facebook application he founds a Content
I'm a Content that he loves he wants to
share it so then click on the share
button copy the link he can share it
through any other media for instance
water in this case we make one and what
happens is that the people who is
receiving this link can open it and the
browser automatically automatically ask
the user to initiate session as they
first user the initially sure to link
this happened because of the
functionality of quanta blogging the
browser things that you are opening them
the link winning your sofa so the
browser ask then you click on OK and you
can assertion on the browser of the
first user that are initially sure the
link and then you come pump
okay let's plot the relative mass if
either they say the best decision seems
will find that the banality is not
always present when shaking from
facebook mobile application however
well-written you know how this shortened
lives were constructed and this is the
instructor from I would not think you
can say the VIP key and decision key so
the solution was difficulty with about
Facebook accounts of the one first
session searching in Google it was
possible to sir that is was quite common
to shellings on carbonate that can be
used to still evaluation from Facebook
accounts this is some these links will
find past six months work well we do was
to search these kind of links within the
appeal in the output PHP instructor we
found a lot of them basically by
searching in Google but the problem was
that they were tool in some of them a
lot of them didn't work anymore however
we found another solution the solution
was real time to balance around 130
Salah
[Music]
it's worth to mention that not all of
those things were necessary valid some
of them could work some up into it
however since you can find thousands of
links per day
you shared every day you can find like a
lot that are actually valid so from
there you could impersonate any any
Facebook account the share link that
we're valid and now the first person's
[Music]
always works in this one video we can
see how to perform this real-time search
using Twitter with it for the specific
instructor we had from the link and we
can observe that there's like a lot of
links that are shared within 13 hours of
powers and so a lot of these accounts
are linked with their Facebook account
so when they share anything on the
Facebook application it is automatically
automatically shared also will trigger
this moment is you search this one as
buildings in you can see many of this
kind of the structure is still used we
will see why in a few minutes
this video is on the world and this is
an example of an accountant was actually
exploited with this research
here we look for a link that is shared
by this person she was yeah also we we
found that these kind of links
obviously they were shared by any kind
of people politicians students
professors whatever so any people around
the world could be targeted by using
this kind of mix and there we found we
need to clear our check because that was
tested before
[Music]
they refrigerate the page and the
browser asked to login as a legitimate
user we click on OK
it opens the content media and then we
just browse to to Facebook and the
session is already loaded in the browser
and we obtain the session this person of
any person who do not
the funny part 3,000 bucks dollars as we
said previously we informed through
Facebook we in the Facebook County
Facebook program they pay us and they
closed the ticket and of course I
implemented our remediation the network
and gerard shortener they had me to get
when i think what that logic and a
redirection the urinal they will never
if it was implemented in playful Skaar
slash out that PHP and so that is not
undr possible to still by the decision
on them and it is possible are ready to
find these kind of openings and Twitter
Google wherever however it is no longer
possible to abuse a want uploading
functionality because our resurrection
is implemented immediately so you access
the content mania without asking first
if you can if you want to to login as a
initial user that share the content so
for instance we we open this link this
is a shortened link the it is still
present in the IP however the browser
didn't ask us anymore
first a tool and it up it opens the
content media instead of asking to
Tulagi
still the same
and open to continue so since the links
are is still present out there what's
next we found that a this vulnerability
could be present also in other kind of
links for instance we found these kind
of links that contains an SSL request
value this kind of links we found they
are actually vulnerable however it was a
little more complicated to replicate the
issue with these links the problem is
that the expiration time is really
really short so you can test these links
but they are take function like I know
15 minutes half an hour you need to find
things that I shared like right now and
abuse them so it is necessary for
instance a to totem authorize this
researches and found links that are
shared and like immediately and we have
another video with these links and how
they are also exploring basically the
searches also you can use tracer
wherever and I said the problem is the
exploration time so although you can
find many of these vulnerable links and
lots of them are you know our wellness
like this one because exploration time
is rich believing you can see and this
is a proof of concept of a polytechnic
and how to exploit it with this new cut
first we go to a Facebook and we can see
there is no not come Lala's in the
browser then we go back to the mobile
Facebook application and found this kind
of link when opening this kind of link
the browser again asked us to to log in
using one table this is the structure of
the link the application and creates a
shortened link that contains these
triangle variables that can be abused so
one one is seen a sope we get until the
resurrection to the content media
however the browser already asked you to
to log in as a user than that initially
shared link then you just have to browse
to Facebook again in the browser and you
got the session what did you use again
using the same link that was shared like
two minutes ago it is no longer valid so
this is the problem with is valera t2 to
test it and to abuse it like in mass
like the other one however it is
vulnerable so what next we have to play
a little bit with these kind of links
tempered a the value saying see what
happens
and they were our well actually they
told there's no problem with sharing
this how are these second proof of
consider is not but right now is the
first things with limitation however
they have like among top to pay through
penalty program and depending on the
kind of annuity they pay so this kind of
owner it is this is not easy to
replicate so even for them was a problem
we work a little bit with them in order
to replicate the issue in to let them
see how vulnerable was so this is likely
top among the it could give us
[Music]
[Laughter]
also this was discovered on our free
time by searching yeah but full have fun
with other people yeah actually yeah
only take is to find content may Allah
share this kind of bling soil hey look
at this
can you send a link yeah thank you very
much