so this talk is about fixing games and
out with responsible disclosures in mice
prime Masuku the research in my spare
time during the mind with normal day job
I'm an innovation manager for the Dutch
government so that means that I
investigate all kind of new things that
we can use to make you know that our
Dutch government operate more efficient
so I research technology and I debunk
hyped innovations so in the end the day
we get and we pick the right thing to
put our Arizona I come from a radio
background so I like to go with my heart
we're outside not connected to the
Internet just listen to radio waves I've
been doing that for like 15 years and
still go like to go out sometimes in the
field to see what I can hear and pick up
in the past they also flow drones to
capture radio waves but in Europe is
almost impossible to fly drones in the
city or near to an F Airport to capture
radio signals because people get a bit
nervous on that but it's still possible
to wire your lock with with extra
sniffing
equipment so my sniffer has a sniffer
I'm a hacker I'm a hacker all my life so
before we start I would like to debunk
some myths about hackers we do wear
hoodies but we wear them back so reverse
because that's the best way to store
your popcorn in to keep your hands-free
and eating a pizza with a ski mask is
nearly impossible I couldn't find any
nice image on Google so as I say my man
hacker I'm also all hacker so i'm member
of a group called the guilt of the
grumpy old hackers what we do is we keep
an eye on the internet and when we see
young hackers announcing they're going
to release a data breach or they going
to dump some data then we are the first
ones to say wait a minute maybe you
don't want to do that maybe you want to
you know talk with us first because we
have a little bit with experience with
with reporting nasty things and get you
a nice feedback for it
so two years ago I started with a
colleague of mine
GDI foundation this is Vincent he
couldn't be here today
we start a DI foundation just to get a
better way to report run abilities as a
hacker if you want to report
vulnerabilities to companies or
especially countries or organizations
that's very difficult if you use your
hacker mind all the time so any name
that shows a little bit trust and is
understandable for mere mortals so we
choose for GDI foundation and if you
want to know what this organization is
doing
I suggest you can google us in a new
section and you see a little bit we've
been doing last year's last year we run
project 366 which is a very uncommon
project for us because we spend it's 15
hours per day free for 366 days to find
as many vulnerabilities as humanly
possible and report them which resulted
in a nice in a nice
yeah a nice result we could at least it
dedicate 700 very critical of anybody
this worldwide in instigating
a loss between of faults or in
infrastructure and online services and
the best way we thought doing that was
using the responsible disclosure this is
the original responsible disclosure
policy from the Dutch government as the
Dutch government seized here and this is
what we added extra for our people that
helped us to give it a little bit of
guideline how responsible disclosure
actually worked because it has nowadays
a nice framework but I think in this
case take a nice and loyal and just
politeness get you very far in this
world so responsible disclosure is not
new it's about already 15 years old and
its origins from the sober industry and
has a nice Wikipedia page this describes
very basically what it does but nowadays
it was also known as coordinated to
vulnerability disclosure and it has its
own ISO standards actually to one the
defender with the disclosure
framework and it has also a framework
for handling disk VIN abilities which
helps organizations to deal with people
who report stuff and actually then the
most nice part will happen was that in
July the US Department of Justice has
released their own vulnerability
disclosure framework for their
government systems and this is very
important because this is based on the
NIST standards
so this frameworks deployed once and as
NIST is being updated under beneath the
framework will always be apply with the
latest security standards I also two
weeks ago the Senate and got a new bill
that helps researchers to report systems
that are vulnerable and the most
important paragraph is that in good
faith engage researching the
cybersecurity of interconnected devices
classic model you're not going to be
liable anymore for reporting it so
that's a very big step forward and it
makes this first security researchers
also much safer if this bill will pass
well responsible disclosure has become
in the last years pretty mainstream also
known as coordinated for the very
disclosure and there are already many
big bounty programs making this possible
so if you want to start researching
online services you can first check out
these platforms and they will see if
that if there's a responsible disclosure
or bug bounty program in place so that
you can start legally start
investigating and reporting the problem
is that these big bounty programs are
only limited to what the organization
wants you to test but the internet is
much bigger than that
so we tried talking to the police the
politicians in Europe and explained that
responsible disclosure should be for
everything also for companies and
organizations that have no responsible
disclosure policy in place and we've
been pushing that for the last two years
and we are almost at the point that we
go to get a general responsible
disclosure or
coordinators inability disclosure a
framework for Europe so why we do this
so this this is a chicken picture is how
the internet looks to us it's just a big
mess and we just like to dig into it to
see what was what's running at them and
so under the hood and actually that's
not so pretty because most nice new
things like innovations are actually
based on things that shouldn't actually
not be online or just meant as a joke or
started very small as a proof of concept
and certainly grow very big the biggest
example is Instagram that started with
three people or three persons and one
Mongo database that was just an
experiment and in the end it became a
very big service and was actually the
end of Co Iraq and Afghan photograph
film so going back to project 56 we mean
around the globe and what we try to do
is to find a way how countries or
organizations respond to responsibles
closures because you have to deal with
many different cultures time zones and
also there are always things going on in
the country that are not in the
mainstream media but can have effect on
the way that things are being taken care
of and the most funny part is that after
a little bit pushing China is the most
quick in accepting venerable teefin
abilities and fixing them compared with
my own country in the Netherlands so in
the lens we take about eight days and
China only takes four point nine days so
they're actually doing a better than
Europe and we want to know why that is
and the differences between between all
these continents is culture it is never
a technical problem that that says ok
this vulnerability takes more time to
fix at them than here or the
infrastructure behind it is always a
cultural thing so especially what we
notice in East Europe if you want to
report Arizona bility you will never get
a feedback and probably they will not
even accept it and why because they
don't know you didn't shake hands in
China the biggest problem was they
didn't know us we had to drink tea first
with them
after drinking tea they make it much
easier so if you look at the internet
now we see it as a threat landscape and
this landscape is still littered with
vulnerabilities like HAARP leaf which is
a very old vulnerability from 2014
silly venom of the village like poodle
padlock shell-shocked and dirty cow
which for people that are not very well
known in the info security third term
ability this can be a little confusing
but the biggest risk factor we see here
our users for entrepreneurs that want to
build a new service quickly put it on
the internet put it to test and actually
that is the reason why we have so many
so many websites that can be hacked easy
why it's so easy to deploy malware and
why is so easy to build a control and
that works for for bad things we use as
GI we use a lot of open source
information like OSINT most of them
because they are free and freely
available to everyone
so especially github is a very nice
place to start to look for private keys
passwords and other things because this
is where products are still in the
development phase and this is also a
good place to start for detecting early
on vulnerabilities but I should probably
also saw in the morning session I think
morning about O's in shodhan and elastic
certain senses are great places to start
if you want to start finding
vulnerabilities on the internet I
suggest you start here so because we
started our project focusing on the
Netherlands we wanted to know how many
Dutch domain names that were so we asked
the Dutch register caters how much what
Dutch websites are because we want to
know if we want to scan them to see you
they're vulnerable
can you give us that the information
well that's not possible so we had to
start scanning the entire internet
looking for certificates ourself and
then from those certificates get the
number names that were in those
certificates the funny part is if you
start scaring names and that your eyes
bill will start receiving a lot of angry
you've emails so this is also bypassing
your fair use policy on Gmail services
so that's a longer interesting challenge
so and the moment that you start
scanning the internet you're going to
store IP addresses
well European law doesn't help us with
this because according to the European
law a dynamic IP address is now suddenly
personal data and if we store personal
data in a database and we're not taking
care of that we'd share too much we can
get in trouble but it will be the law so
scanning is illegal in our country but
it's not storing this the IP data secure
can can be a risk so what we did
actually is build a dashboard build
stone on elasticsearch we have a github
repository where this that's what is on
and how you connect all these open
sources and you create a very quick
dashboard and that indicates hacked
servers and device that are vulnerable
and especially data leaks because we're
interested in opens open servers that
are not supposed to be open database
servers file servers are duped cluster
servers and in the end to get all these
servers fixed it
this is the end goal we want to get the
internet cleaned and save them more
structured again so I was talking about
harmony if you now Google for hardly
this morning you will see the heartbeat
is a vulnerability from 2014 but it's
still very active in India so this is
still recurring so this is strange and
if you start looking in census for
hardly you find these systems everywhere
in the world or you say who cares there
you know there are probably webcams or
not nothing important but actually if
you take that query a typing bank you
will find all the banks in the world
that still have web facing devices that
are available for hardly well okay you
can laugh because you see here Greece
well greased banks are empty anyway so
Russia who cares but there are also
other banks you can find there and when
the moment you send a bank email hey
your server portal service is invisible
in senses and has horribly plus
this is the ssl scan that proves it then
sometimes a bank has to shut down just
for a while because they cannot anymore
confirm that their transactions from the
last few years were safe so because of
time knots kidneys so one of the other
databases that that were very popular in
the last year this movie tube a movie TV
has been shipping for years with an
unsafe default setting so when you
install MongoDB and you don't change any
security settings your database will be
open to the Internet and that helped
because at some point in time there was
always about 45 or 40 thousand databases
over to the Internet and of course we
keep reporting these to the owners be
careful people are going to distill your
data they're going to destroy it and
actually that actually happened in
January in January we saw a new form of
attacks on these systems someone wrote a
very simple Python script that crawled
all these databases they deleted
everything and just left a ransom note
yeah from pay me once a 1/2 Bitcoin and
you'll get your data back the problem
behind this is that these people never
exited a dialog they just deleted
everything engine even note and this
this is a it was the first disrupting
and another way of operating in this
field so and why we're always going
behind is moving to the database because
most hospitals are using mobile
databases because they can just easily
connect every registration system to it
so 10 minutes the most most known case
with MongoDB is probably cloud paths for
the cloud that database was a very and
interesting responsible disclosure
because we reported the to the company
be careful you the database is open and
it's linking millions of other messages
from children to their parents but the
company never reacted to we tried email
which I LinkedIn and Facebook and then
another researcher founded Brian Krebs
and he made a public so at that point I
was was no reason to keep I didn't
the most interesting part is that they
still till the day to now they deny that
I ever had got an email from us which it
doesn't matter what the good thing is
that in California now there's a new
goal for making if you make this kind of
toys you need to have some security
standards applied so that was a good
lesson well this is done the examples of
the the Ransom databases the database
that were open again ransom with
messages like this and in the end there
even starts sending the the hacking kits
for it for a few hundred dollar and
after this thing went life we saw more
and more systems getting compromised by
people to just buy the script and just
run it for fun so as you know we've been
monitoring all these systems couch
Hadoop elastic and writers are very no
new systems that are if you google for
them or you shown you will find them
open still open on the internet of
course which one this one is the most
interesting because if this is running
maybe cabañas also running and Cabana
with ELQ stock is mostly used in
security operation centers for keeping
your network secure so if these systems
are still open and you're leaking a lot
of information so we wrote generic
security warnings with a little guide
how to fix them and we send them to all
go search in the world to have them
distributed like that work pretty well
coming back to MongoDB when did when the
attack started we needed to inform the
world that we saw these attacks and
where these attacks were coming from and
we wanted to share all indications of
compromised in an easy way
well if you're running this organization
with free man then you need a way to do
it and we found actually the Google the
Google slides disorder spreadsheet you
can switch it to public and there anyone
that Google's for a Bitcoin address or
for an IP address or for the Bitcoin for
the ransom message they will instantly
find us first result in Google so that
was a very effective way for us for
sharing this data and still the city is
still up and running
every week we get a new request for a
new entry to add so these attacks are
still going on and people who still are
willing to add their compromised data
let me see this is a nice one
my daughter likes to play computer games
and she likes to play big titles and
after she finished the game she starts
using mods Nexus mods a Nexus mode
allows you to go into the game data and
add extra things or change things in
your script the funny part is no one
probably ever managed to start looking
for in the configuration files for
Commons or for IP addresses so I was
going through with her to you know to
set them to get some new settings for
her to make the game more nice and
suddenly we find an ipv6 address as
booted out by the developer from please
leave this server open because for
getting research files and the fun part
was that that ipv6 address was indeed
resolvable to a group a diverse system
which is not very readable on the screen
and let me see how much it was 750
terabytes of data this was actually the
the backup or production server for that
company for hosting all the DLCs and
everything else
so we check that server again for IP 4
and for IP 4 it wasn't beautifully
firewall so what what was the problem
here well the problem was is that the
server was behind the firewall all these
years and was IP physicals only
available for inside the office for the
developers but at some point the ISP for
the good idea oh it's ipv6 launch day
click let's put it open on ipv6 for to
the Internet so the funny part is every
time we when we import about these
attacks and vulnerabilities we have
these very sharp discussions on Twitter
about whose fault it is when they get
hacked and it's still name for security
we like to say if people get owned
because they left our systems open on
our patch it's their own fault well yes
this may be their fault but someone
needs to help me
we've been dealing with with victims
from those ransomware campaigns like you
have to tell Google researcher that they
just lost years of research on leukemia
and that's that's another way then you
cannot say it's your own fault
no then you have to look for a solution
saying how can we dis prevent from ever
happening again
oh we're going to skip this because I
think this has been in the news enough
the fun part is that in January when
when shadow brokers released their their
package from here you can buy our
package these are different abilities
that we have we already knew that you
had to start blocking in sports because
there was a zero day out there that
could you know hit the services
especially when they're accessible
through the internet so when wanna cry
hit in May we start getting help
requests from all over the world just
imagine your Twitter DM following with
the international organization help I
mean hacked and I don't dare to go to my
government because I'm scared for legal
things can you please help us so yeah we
try to help as many many organizations
as possible but in the end I mean anyhow
but was it was not to be able to be
stopped anymore the only thing that we
could do was like look at the network
and then say okay you have segmented
here you have the sacrament here patches
oh and look and showing and these are
your servers on the outside why are they
still vulnerable the same of course
would not patch up this is now known as
one of the biggest cost factors of this
attacker and why these effects are
possible is because that vulnerability
eternal blue with speaker next to me
will start talking about it's still out
there so that's the reason why we scan
the internet and why we keep reporting
these vulnerabilities because these
things need to be clean up and this is
an example how we didn't we just created
a database with all the the Dutch IP
addresses that were vulnerable with city
and is be next to them so let me contact
the ISP say this is the list with all
the hosts they're vulnerable
forty no blue please help fix help
fixing this so we make a generic
responsible slower email phone this is
your server it's writable you need to
batch it or put it behind a firewall
game please help us with the
distribution and within one week we were
able to get down from 15,000 vulnerable
house to like 300 and those 300 are
because they are not owned by a Dutch
company by but a hosting company from
outside the Netherlands who doesn't want
to cooperate with security researchers
so and after that we started focusing on
Germany Ireland and England and actually
it was possible to bring down the amount
of vulnerable hosts within a week from
thousand stitches of a couple you know
couple hundred so combining social media
and oceans information and just a
helpful hand to get the system back in
time before they get hat is very good
doable and I'm doing this for 19 years
so the last thing I want to say is that
voting machines are now getting more and
more media attention if we look at 40
machines like DEFCON how is it they can
be hacked is one of the reasons we need
to keep more investigating in devices
that are rarely used but very important
and share this information in the
Netherlands we did the same and that was
for us when we tested the device it was
the deal advice go back to to paper and
pencil because this is not going to fly
how much time I have left one minute
okay so this is the amount of slides I
will show to people that just in InfoSec
or an interesting manager and they want
to understand why why it is so important
that we patch all the easy things to
start to start to become a cyber
criminal you don't need much tools you
can just simply go to get up and get a
nice read software to get you started
but actually if that's too difficult for
you you can find open-source ransomware
with a nice video instruction how to get
through it but still you have to be able
to use in a keyboard and you have to
type some commands that are not so easy
to remember maybe you have to build
probably a web server but nowadays of
course on
Dartmouth case you can buy the best
ransomware available that will pass any
any security and the good thing is that
is it become a service because you just
pay five thousand dollars or your pages
fifty two thirty doors if you help
spreading the malware on two hundred
computers but how are you going to do
that because you're not a hacker you can
just enter Windows systems right that's
impossible
well you can buy just a list with C&C
servers Windows computers with running
finishing with no password where you can
just drag and drop your malware on but
still then you have to invest like $50
for the mix so if you just go to Shonen
and type has screenshot through you can
find about more than a million systems
online that has been C running with no
password because otherwise they couldn't
make the screenshot even at if you say
well show them that's where everyone
goes that's not so fun there's also a
nice website called the world of V and C
and you can just browse through all kind
of systems that are open with IP address
and you'll find systems online like both
systems so if you drop a piece of
malware here ransomware and you don't
ask too much money the guarantee will be
paid because these systems are just
drag-and-drop you find Windows 10 system
that are fully patched and was running
antivirus there are open you find
banking systems don't work these samples
are all taken offline so not getting
infinite days but also airports and in
luggage and of course Dutch
entrepreneurs who are working their
bookkeeping systems online so the last
thing that I want to give for you is
that there's there's new ransomware
coming when somewhere that will abuse
the human e the most famous example that
we've seen out in a while is called
popcorn it will encrypt your files you
can pay one Bitcoin to get your files
back it has a nice story set story why
it's doing and doing it because it needs
money but there's a way to get your
files back the nasty way you just have
to infect a few friends of you or
enemies by just setting the link and
when they get in successfully infected
you get your files back for free and
this is the kind of innovation we will
go to see and
yeah yeah immediately well I always try
to explain to young people is like
you're going to have a conversation a
very intimate conversation you know and
you want to be as polite as possible if
you come away with a mechanism that puts
pressure to your conversation that
doesn't make it that doesn't make it a
friendly conversation so and I've been
doing it for 19 years I can show you a
some examples off screen our evils are
very polite and very helpful and it
works as also within those 30 days we
never have things nope
not fixed within 40 days unless the
problem is so complex that it takes a
little bit longer but you can you can do
you come to reports without applying the
pressure immediately I will do that in a
later stage in the status when normal
communications doesn't work anymore
had we have these kind of organization
[Music]
exactly yeah so our experience with with
when we send the report we always send
the reason why we report you know your
system is vulnerable that's how you fix
it
but this is the risk that we predicted
and we had a very well predicted that at
some point a piece of ransomware or
another form of attack will abuse these
systems and then later these companies
will contact you right you already
predicted this a year because that's
what we would do if I was an evil hacker
or hacker bit about intent that's the
thing i will do i will go from behind
these systems first because i want to
get a foothold as soon as possible and
as quiet as possible and the biggest
reason why we're pushing so much is that
if you now start looking in 2017 for
Vinoba systems it doesn't take you long
to find one there's more actually which
ones can i pick and that's our biggest
worry this is a free book about dutch
hacking as written by someone who
interviewed many Dutch hackers so if you
like to read in the past nine backstory