hey folks thank you for coming
can everyone hear me okay yep okay start
waving your arms about if you can't
anyway I'm Atticus I'm a pen tester with
assurance and am a ward member of
Digital Rights Watch Australia
I'm a former historian and a future
cyborg you may remember me from such
conference talks is the one where I rant
about history and the one where I rant
about privacy and most popularly the one
where I rant about history and privacy
together and this talk falls into that
latter category so I want to talk about
arsenic and a mass surveillance because
there's a lot that we can learn from one
about the other and as a quick note um
during this talk I am gonna mention
death a lot I'll talk about murder a bit
and you'll hear quotes of threats that
people have made to other people and if
you are not in a good place to hear
about those things right now that is
extremely understandable and your mother
welcome to leave this session and do
another thing instead this is arsenic
trioxide arsenic sin natural element
it's been used for all kinds of things
since the time of the ancient Greeks but
for the next half hour or so while I'm
talking about arsenic I'm specifically
talking about this stuff a snake
trioxide or white arsenic and this is an
industrial byproducts that began
cropping up pretty much everywhere after
the industrial revolution began it looks
a lot like sugar or flour and when it's
mixed into food arsenic is colorless and
tasteless and odorless and extremely
poisonous if you take a lot at once it
has an effect much like cholera which is
kind of like the the worst diarrhea that
you've ever had in your life followed by
the end of your life if you only take a
little bit of arsenic at a time it can
make you tired it can make you a key it
can give you trouble breathing and in
England in the 1800's arsenic was very
cheap because it was a waste product
that fir-trees wanted to get rid of and
you could get it almost anywhere in
almost anything and
anything I do mean anything for example
you could get it in cosmetics there were
a lot of companies that produce
arsenical wafers or powders that promise
to get rid of pimples and blackheads and
slow the signs of aging which is very
interesting if you think about it
I was also used domestically to kill
mice and rats and cockroaches and other
pests so it was really easy to walk into
a shop and get a box of the pure stuff
to keep in the kitchen but I think was
most popular as a color pigment
especially an emerald green also known
as Paris green which was used in the
exact same form as a pigment by artists
and as a pest killer by farmers it
produced a really vibrant green color
that no other pigment was ever able to
give and because it was in pigments it
meant that arsenic ended up in pretty
much anything that needed color so cases
were recorded of people being poisoned
by arsenic in their playing cards and in
fabric dyes and in product packaging
arsenic also found its way into famous
art like van Gogh's Starry Night this is
one of several reasons that art
galleries do not like it if you look at
their paintings most notoriously it was
also in wallpaper wallpaper was put up
in the homes of anyone who could afford
it and because our Cenacle pigment was
cheap
eventually it meant that most people
could afford it the pigment dust would
come out of the walls if people brushed
past or if there was a breeze and if he
got damp which it did in England
especially it emitted a toxic arson as
gas you could get arsenical wallpaper in
in most Western countries but it was
especially a problem in England and in
the United States two countries that
were not really keen on government
regulation of industry what you're
looking at here is a digitized arsenical
wallpaper sample it came from a book
called shadows from the walls of death
this book was published in 1874 as part
of a public health campaign to raise
awareness of the dangers of our Senecal
wallpaper and it was eventually so
successful at its goal that out of the
original hundred odd copies that were
made there are now only four left
because people realized how poisonous
they were
some brave soul at the University of
Michigan digitized this one they are
hopefully still okay but because these
are pretty and they're in the public
domain you'll see a few examples of them
as I keep talking maybe most importantly
arsenic also had a reputation as a quick
way to make money because your family
would not notice if you stirred it into
their tea and for this reason it was
also known as inheritance powder but we
are at a hacker conference which is why
we're also talking about digital privacy
or lack thereof and by this I mean the
current practice of various governments
and corporations gathering literally as
much data about everybody as they
possibly can and storing it forever not
always very well
I'm talking about Facebook and Google's
ad networks and metadata retention and
the dodgy apps that promise to make you
look really good in selfies and then
require a suspicious number of
permissions and the issues around my
health record and and and all of that
and then what happens to this data when
it's not secured properly or someone
inside a data gathering organization
develops a grudge or even when it's used
as its intended and then a thought nurse
a thoughtless new feature comes in
upsets everything so where the probe
where the topics of digital privacy and
arsenic intersect is that for a good
period of time despite the best efforts
of people who knew what they were
talking about the public didn't really
give a damn about either of them arsenic
and mass data gathering of both things
that have pervaded every day life in
large-scale ways that have seemed
impossible to change and despite lots of
well-informed people agreeing in their
respective centuries that these things
are damaging our well-being or our way
of life it's hard to get people to care
or to think that things can change
they aren't great but things are just
you too useful they're too convenient
arsenic makes vibrant cheap shades of
green that look nice it gives you a
clear complexion it kills mice really
well data can tell us how to plant
cities it can provide accurate help us
provide accurate medical care and it can
help us catch
but while these things don't change
people's lives have also been upended by
these things in increasing numbers
inhaling ambient arsenic didn't make
everybody sick in the same way one
person might die and another person in
the same house might just get bad
headaches and just this way mass
surveillance and privacy invasion
disproportionately affect the members of
society who are already most vulnerable
then there are the more targeted attacks
both with arsenic and the data that can
become devastating to whoever's on the
receiving end
to illustrate my point I want to tell
you two short stories in 1852 an English
coal mine worker named William Mowbray
married a young woman named Mary Ann and
together they had nine children over the
next years seven seven of these children
died tragically from what was recorded
as gastric fever in the mid 19th century
times were really hard and it wasn't
uncommon for children not to reach out
altered the couple collected the
insurance money and life went on after
13 years of marriage in the January of
1865 William Mowbray himself died
tragically of gastric fever leaving Mary
Ann and her two remaining daughters to
make their own way in the world with a
little bit more insurance money to help
them on their way by the way the average
life insurance payout for an adult man
at this point in time was equivalent to
about his year's wages George Ward an
engineer was recovering from an illness
in hospital in 1865 when he fell in love
with a nurse named Mary Ann when they
were married in August 1865 Ward
tragically died of gastric fever 14
months later his wife collected the
insurance payout James Robinson was a
shipwright in 1886 he had a new baby son
and a recently deceased wife so he hired
a housekeeper to help him out the new
housekeeper a woman named Mary Ann had
only been living in the household for a
month when the baby died tragically of
gastric fever Robinson found that Mary
Ann's presence was emotionally helpful
and he married her in the August of 1867
by this time Marianne was pregnant with
their daughter who was born two months
after the wedding but the baby only
lived for three months before dying
tragically of gastric fever Marianne's
misfortune continued while she'd been
living with Ward one of her surviving
children from her first marriage died
tragically of gastric fever after
marrying Robinson her only remaining
daughter from her first marriage also
died tragically of gastric fever and so
did two of Robinson's children from his
first marriage
so did Mary Anne's mother just after
Mary Ann went to visit her and Mary Ann
inherited almost everything soon after
all of these tragedies James Robinson
the shipwright discovered that Mary Ann
had been stealing from him and running
up debts he also noticed that she was
becoming weirdly insistent that he
should take out a life-insurance policy
on himself which she refused to do
Robison kicked Mary Ann out of his house
and he did not die tragically of gastric
fever one of Mary Ann's friends took
pity on her tragic circumstances and
introduced Mary Ann to her brother
Frederick cotton cotton was a widower
with two small children of his own and
he fell into Mary Ann's arms when in the
March of 1870 his beloved sister Mary
Ann's friend died tragically from
gastric fever cotton and Mary Ann
married in September 1870 and in 1871
they had a son unfortunately before the
year was over Frederick cotton also died
tragically of gastric fever Mary Ann
collected the insurance money do you
know what happens next she moves in with
another guy and brings the surviving
kids and stepkids with her wills get
rewritten and suddenly pretty much the
entire household dies tragically of
gastric fever this left Mary Ann with
one remaining stepson who she complained
loudly about all the time to her new
employer when the boy took ill and died
tragically have gastric fever her boss
became suspicious
I got the local doctor to delay issuing
the death certificate when Maryann
discovered she couldn't get the
insurance payout on her stepsons life
without the death certificate she had a
public meltdown about it which led to
people asking questions and then more
questions and then testing her stepsons
remains for arsenic which was found in
abundance Maryann was convicted of his
murder and died tragically of rock
poisoning in 1873 in her lifetime she
had murdered 16 of her children and
stepchildren four of her partners her
mother and an inconvenient friend and
collected insurance payouts and will
benefits from almost all of them it now
takes a lot less time for criminal to
make a lot more money than Maryann
cotton ever did but instead of marrying
and murdering they can use the info out
of stolen data dumps which are about as
cheap and plentiful as arsenic was back
in the day so here's my next story
sometime after July last year some of us
opened our inboxes and saw a threatening
email that might have looked like it had
come from our own email address the
message probably went a bit like this
one hello I am a programmer who cracked
your email account and device about half
year ago you entered a password on one
of the unsecure site you visited and I
catched it your password from Fredrik
cotton a gmail comm on moment of crack
hunter 2 of course you can and will
change your password or already made it
but it doesn't matter my rad software
updated every time please don't try to
contact me or find me it is impossible
since I sent you an email from your
email account through your email I
uploaded malicious code to your
operations system I saved all of your
contacts with friends colleagues
relatives and a complete history of
visits to the internet resources also I
install the rad software on your device
and longtime spying on you you are not
my only victim I usually lock devices
and ask for ransom but I was struck by
the sites of intimate content you very
often visit I am in shock of your reach
fantasies
Wow I have never seen anything like this
I did not even know that such content
could be so exciting
so when you had fun on intimate sites
you know what I mean
I made screenshot with using my program
from your camera of yours device after
that I jointed them to the content of
the currently viewed side will be funny
when I send these photos to your
contacts and if your relatives see it
but I'm sure you don't want it I
definitely would not want to I will not
do this if you pay me a little amount I
think seven hundred and fifty four
dollars is a nice price for it I accept
only bitcoins my Bitcoin wallet address
is some long string you have two days 48
hours for make a payment if this does
not happen all your contacts will get
crazy shots of your dirty life do not
take this frivolously this is the last
warning I hope you will be prudent bye
so in just one month after these emails
first appeared researchers found that
about 70 point eight Bitcoin which is
about three hundred and eighty four
thousand Australian dollars in today's
exchange rate had been deposited to
wallets that were listed in those scam
emails and when I checked again about
four months later just one of those
wallets had nine hundred and twenty
eight point nine Bitcoin in it which is
about five million Australian dollars
today
I tried checking again this morning but
after eight or so months the sextortion
scam idea has now spread to so many
people and turned up in so many
different languages that tracking the
number of Bitcoin wallets involved in
the scam took far more time than I had
available and this amount of money is
many many times more than a year's wages
for most of us and more money that
didn't Maryann cotton could ever have
dreamed of and I know a lot of a lot of
us in this room who got this email read
it and saw it for the scam that it was
and had a good luck but clearly many
thousands of other people suffered
through their own private hell before
paying up the thing that sets these
so-called sextortion emails apart from
other traditional spam email is the
inclusion of real passwords from old
data dumps a lot of us probably know
exactly the kinds of breaches that these
things came from this
is easy enough to find mail merge is
easy to use and you only need a few
scared people to start seeing these
results but most people don't know this
stuff even today and the inclusion of
something like a password which they
thought was private makes it more likely
that they're going to get really scared
and pay off and clearly they are paying
up because personal data is potent like
that but serial killers like Mary Ann
cotton were outliers when it came to
arsenic death most people in Victorian
England didn't need to live with a
murderer to be poised with arsenic
because as we already said arsenic was
everywhere gone men died from inhaling
it off the walls in their sleep elderly
women died after mistaking it for sugar
and putting it in their own tea and
children died from being looked after by
nurses who were wearing uniforms that
had been dyed with arsenical colours and
far far more people didn't die but lived
with chronic headaches and breathing
problems in poor digestion that they
could never find a cause for in their
day and age in the same way large-scale
personal data is not something that
needs to be used by individual criminals
to cause problems as we know more formal
uses of this kind of data can end up
outing trans people like what happened
in 2014 when Google consolidated some of
their messaging services to create
hangouts which merged previously
separate accounts into one legal name
identity and put lots of trans Google
users in dangerous situations it can
also end up strongly influencing
democratic elections like what Cambridge
analytic added to the u.s. presidential
election in 2016 using Facebook's data
it can end up stealing company secrets
like we learned in November last year
when a Dutch team revealed that
microsoft office 365 was sending the
sentences before and after spelling and
grammar checked strings back to the
Redmond mothership as telemetry data
which you can't turn off anecdotally I
have heard of plenty of people who've
given up on using large parts of the
internet and lots of different services
because working out who to trust and how
to stay safe and in control was too
complex without the layers of knowledge
that people like us have from working in
this industry but despite how much we
know it isn't great most people is too
kind of about the whole issue it's easy
to understand why people are either
apathetic about big problems or resigned
to the fact that horrible things are
happening and they can't seem to do
anything about them
the scale of them seems impossible and
the likelihood of it becoming a huge
problem for you this week is fairly low
the period of time where the most people
give the least of the dam is known as
peak indifference this is a term that
was coined by a Cory Doctorow in 2016
and when he was talking about how the
world was at a turning point with regard
to the issue of digital privacy and he
argued that after this turning point
increasing numbers of people would begin
to care about their privacy as
increasing numbers of breaches or
incidents affected them or affected
someone that they cared about doctor who
linked this idea to the eventual success
of public health campaigns around
tobacco smoking but almost every issue
reaches peak indifference at one point
or another and then what happens to that
issue after that tipping point is
something that we can learn a lot from
where we pass peak indifference about
privacy in the West is kind of a
nebulous thing to work out and was it
after Edward Snowden's actions in 2013
was it after Ashley Madison or Target or
Sony you know I think it was definitely
sometime after March last year when the
Cambridge analytical stuff hit the fan
after that point we saw large-scale
inquiries into corporate data use
particularly in the United States and
lots of penitent looking CEOs and public
commitments to change and even if these
things were only for sure they were done
to appease this real growing and
enlightened public sentiment of disgust
and mistrust at the way that data was
being gathered and used in June last
year the Pew Research Center in the
United States found that in the previous
12 months seventy-four percent of
Facebook users had either adjusted their
privacy settings taken a long break from
using Facebook or they had deleted the
app completely then the gdpr came into
force in Europe which meant that
companies suddenly had to pay a lot more
attention to the data that they had
and everyday people were suddenly
getting emails from everyone that they'd
ever forgotten they'd signed up with
telling them how important their privacy
was and how meaningful their consent
would be if they so graciously decided
to bestow it awareness of just how much
data complete randoms could see about
them led to more people taking proactive
steps to gain control of where their
information was going but how do we keep
up this momentum we can't let it happen
naturally more and more people ending up
the victims of data breaches and
identity theft and account takeovers and
leaked nudes or we can maintain it
thoughtfully and with purpose we spent
all this time talking about arsenic for
a reason 19th century England had its
own peak indifference moment and people
tried a whole bunch of ways to keep this
issue central I estimate that peak and
difference about the domestic arsenic
problem probably happened somewhere
between 1850 and 1870 by 1900 arsenical
wallpaper was hardly worth mentioning
except where someone occasionally found
some and had to handle its removal in
this time two important things gained
momentum awareness of the problem and
resistance to the problem awareness
happened the more that people were
educated literacy increased and I don't
mean just actual reading skills but
general scientific literacy increased
tiny particles of poison in an
environment are hard to see and without
advanced scientific knowledge for that
period of time they were conceptually
kind of hard to understand but slowly
over time the concepts of things like
germs and disease communication and
chemical pollutants became understood by
scientists and eventually more generally
understood by the public in 1840 James
Marsh developed a test which could
detect the presence of arsenic in a
human body something which had
previously been impossible
suddenly knowing that your use of
arsenic could be detected by other
people and traced back to you but the
people were a lot less casual about
poisoning each other on purpose in 1854
a doctor called John Snow
not this guy this guy in 1854 a doctor
called John snow realized the
series of cholera outbreaks in London
were happening because one of the public
water supplies was contaminated with
something that spread the disease this
went against the commonly held theory
that disease was spread by miasma or bad
air and that breathing the air around a
sick or a dead person was the thing that
would transmit all diseases so snow
tracked down the source of the
contaminated water remove the handle off
the public pump that gave access to it
and the cholera outbreaks stopped and
this led to the development of modern
sewer systems and built a better public
understanding of germs and
microorganisms so awareness ended up
leading to resistance protests
literature played a huge part in helping
people to convince others to join the
resistance efforts things like shadows
from the walls of death was an
in-your-face presentation of the problem
it put the focus on wallpaper
manufacturers to make changes and not
just the individuals who had brought
wallpaper into their homes
England's to this day has never passed
any meaningful laws banning the sale or
use of arsenic in wallpaper but it
turned out that regulations in other
countries like France and Germany had
much more of an impact on how much
arsenic turned up in English households
and this was mostly down to fashion and
consumer choice most European countries
had outright bans the use of arsenic and
pigment manufacturing since the 1860s
because of this they suddenly became
innovators for new paint pigments that
created bright colors without using
arsenic on because everything French is
automatically fancy people were into it
fashion like it does eventually trickled
down through the whole industry and over
time lots of places in England ended up
offering arsenic free products like
wallpaper for affordable prices in fact
most manufacturers had no choice the
pigments that they used to color their
wallpaper mostly came from Europe in the
first place so it was getting difficult
to find any that contained arsenic even
if they wanted to one of the best things
about this outcome was that it created
accessible alternatives for everybody
including people who still believed in
things like the miasma theory it was
unrealistic to expect that every single
person in 19
century england was subtly going to
develop a scientific understand
understanding equivalent to that of a
professional chemist people have jobs to
do and lives to get on with the vast
majority of people did not have access
to the kinds of educational backgrounds
that would allow them to even begin to
start understanding just exactly how
domestic arsenic use was a problem so
the creation of arsenic free tech that
was affordable to obtain and easy to use
and provided just the same kind of
experience meant that those people were
being carried along and helped to solve
the problem without having to become
activists themselves and nowadays it's
rare to see arsenical wallpaper except
behind thick glass in museums for those
of you who've already read this far into
the analogy you know that we're already
doing a whole lot of these things when
it comes to the privacy fied we're doing
the awareness bit it seems like everyone
and their goldfish has either beans who
will run at least one crypto party and
every other day there's a new how-to
guide about how do you signal or tor
that gets published VPNs
things they get advertised on commercial
television and we're doing the
resistance bit to you make you but
you've been quite a safety TPS thing and
the gdpr is a thing firefox build ad
blockers into their browsers now
password managers the things that our
relatives have started asking us about
Apple markets privacy as a feature of
their tech and people who can afford it
pay thousands of dollars to get it where
we are calling out the companies who are
perpetuating unfair systems we're
pressuring them in a thousand ways to do
things differently so why does it still
feel like nothing has changed I mean
don't get me wrong all of these things
are positive steps in pushing back
against accepting data harvesting and
privacy violation as normal or
inevitable but the third thing which the
arsenic fight had going for it which we
don't have yet is time this all took a
lot of time and a lot of effort and a
lot of repeating information a lot of
petitioning governments to make changes
and sometimes it worked and sometimes it
didn't work but people kept doing it
because arsenic kept poisoning people
and it was the right thing to do
and now we have wall decorations that
don't kill us slowly in our sleep
thinking about the long game it's really
damn hard I mean I am a millennial and
if you believe the papers I'm something
avocados and patience is difficult but
time is really the key ingredient we
have to keep doing this and not give up
and not given the cynicism and repeat
ourselves until we're sick of it and
then keep going keep pushing for
grassroots education efforts like and
public education I was like crypto
parties and community events official
education efforts from local governments
and anyone who wants to get on board
talk to your friends and your relatives
when they ask you about it help the
people who want to understand this get
the information that they need keep
writing and speaking and about these
issues wherever you can and if you can't
boost the voices of others who are
already doing it keep the heat on
lawmakers inside and outside of your
country you know if your government
isn't doing anything meaningful remember
that the French and German laws had a
significant impact on English attitudes
to arsenic in a lot of ways gdpr is
doing a similar thing precedent-setting
really helps and push for more
legislation that gives us back control
of our private information and imposes
strong penalties for its misuse and push
against every piece of legislation that
threatens to weaken that argue thing
considered regulations that will
actually work in practice do it even
though we already did this last month
and three months ago and last year and
in the 90s organisations will keep
trying it on again and again they trust
it will get tired we need to be aware of
that and to work around it be a voice of
reason in your own communities
there probably people in this room who
probably knows someone who's stolen
information and used it to mess someone
else up or know people who've said
meaningless data gathering as a KPI
challenge these folks to do better and
if you've ever been one of these people
it is not a perfect universe challenge
yourselves to keep doing better too and
do you research fact check corporate
privacy spin we know Facebook especially
invests big money into saying that it's
doing the right thing they just paid
through the nose for a global billboard
setup and an apology to it to do it so
hold them accountable we probably have
the biggest responsible
to try will to keep trying to make the
world better for the people who don't
have the level of knowledge that a lot
of us do the average person in the 19th
century wasn't a chemist and the average
person in the 21st century isn't a
hacker not everybody wants to be and not
everybody is able to be and there's
absolutely nothing wrong with that some
folks are gonna keep calling it's
paranoid forever oh they'll minimize the
risks or they'll insist that they have
nothing to hide and that anyone who does
is a criminal but we can keep making the
world better anyway because we're the
ones who can all of us in this room are
in a unique position to understand the
scale of suffering and the damage that's
caused by pervasive surveillance and
privacy invading systems no matter whose
hands they're in it's likely that most
of us are here because we like breaking
things and solving puzzles and getting
creative with computers and because we
have that knowledge we can do something
about it we have to keep doing something
about it the scariest thing about giving
this talk here in this room to you folks
is that nothing is so incredibly uncool
as optimism but I really want to be
optimistic and I really want you folks
to be optimistic and to keep giving a
damn it's cynicism gets you retweets and
dunking on optimism there's a lot easier
than caring about something but if you
actually do give a damn you have to
think about the long game and have
patience and keep doing what you think
is right even though there are days and
years where it seems like nothing ever
changes I know some of you burnt out on
this stuff years ago decades ago it
really does take a lot of time it sucks
though now it's real and it's a thing
that you were definitely allowed to feel
but we can do it and if you're exhausted
by it support other people to keep
trying
imagine that someone's giving this talk
and 150 years provided we've somehow
managed to survive the sea levels rising
what does the long view of this fight
look like what's the optimistic angle
who are the Mary Ann Cotton's in this
future version of the talk and who are
the James marshes and the John snows
what did shadows from the walls of death
contain that is so toxic that nobody
wants to touch it anymore
we can't answer these questions as long
as we don't give up thank you so much to
all of these people who
we make this talk of thing and if you've
got any questions or thoughts on this
topic feel free to come and chat to me
during the lunch break without thank you
for coming along to hear me
[Applause]