thanks everyone so I'm a whore and yeah
I'm gonna talk about formal verification
and whether that leads to better
security I'm a systems engineer I'm not
a formal methods person however I do
work with I do work in the team that
developed SEO for microkernel that's the
world's first formally verified
operating systems kernel and so I know a
lot of formal methods peoples and I'm
I'm also even friends with some of them
I've heard a lot about formal methods
and I've heard a lot about how formal
verification is great and how it leads
to better security and so on and slowly
that message is sunk in but I really it
took me a while to really kind of
understand why that's the case as a
systems person so I'm gonna try to
distill some of that knowledge here and
hopefully pass it on to you as well
quick show of hands who here considers
themselves a formal methods person all
right that's what I thought not very
many so that's good because I'm not one
either so as I mentioned we're the
trustworthy systems group and we
developed a formally verified operating
systems microkernel and when that got
released when we started doing things we
started seeing headlines like these
hacker-proof coding hackers can't break
this hacker proof it's unhackable etc
etc so when you see these kinds of
headlines you're either gonna cringe
with dread or you're gonna get giddy
with anticipation that you're gonna
break this hacker proof code so I want
to talk about whether form of
verification really does lead to better
security and whether that's the same as
hacker-proof code so is it really true
that we have hacker proof code or not
I'll give you a bit of a spoiler yes it
does lead to better security but no
that's not the same as hacker-proof code
so I'm gonna give an overview of form of
verification in introduction to non FM
people then I'm gonna talk about why we
claim that form of verification does
lead to better security so what is
better security and why does it lead to
and then I'm gonna talk about why that
isn't the same as hack proof code why
it's not a silver bullet so formal
verification formal verification is
proving properties about stuff with math
now properties can be a lot of different
things
this can be correctness
this can be security this can be things
like liveness safety and so on and then
stuff can also be a lot of different
things this can be code this can be
protocols this can be hardware
this can be processes etc people prove
stuff people prove properties about lots
of different stuff so for this talk I'm
gonna focus on proving correctness about
code about software so if you think
about if you ask anyone
when is code correct when do you
consider code correct mostly people will
say well when it does the thing I expect
it to do so I have some expectation of
what the code should do I wrote it
write it I run tests until it does what
I think it should do more formally
that's the specification you have a
specification for what your code should
do and it's correct when it meets that
specification so if we want to do formal
verification we need to have a formal
specification of the code this is
something that's precise something
that's unambiguous and abstract it tells
us what the code should do not
necessarily how so as an example if we
want to talk about lists and sorting
lists we can have a formal specification
of what a sorted list is informally we
might well we have a function called
sort list a for abstract that takes a
input list and outputs a list so input
is L output is L prime and informally we
can say well this specification for
sorting a list is that L prime is sorted
which is nice but formally we want to be
a little bit more specific so we provide
a more formal definition the input list
and the output list are the same length
the output list is a permutation of the
input list and the elements in the
output list are increasingly larger we
also deal with abstract data types
rather than concrete data types so in
our formal specifications we'll have
an abstract list something that you can
index something that you can take the
length of and so on but it doesn't tell
us how the list is necessarily
implemented so it's different than an
implementation which might be a linked
list for example and then we have our
implementation this is code for example
the in the C language or another
language and it's concrete it tells us
how we do something not just what but
how so we call the form of specification
a we call the for abstract and we call
the implantation C for concrete now when
we're doing formal verification we use a
formal model of the code so we don't use
C source code directly but we use a
formal representation of C code for
example and that comes with a whole
bunch of rules about what the semantics
of the C code are is so what happens
when you run certain instructions great
so given this formal specification given
this code we want to prove that it's
correct so what does that mean a little
bit more formally we want to prove that
the state after executing the code
fulfills the specification the abstract
specification so what do we mean by the
state well we have an initial state we
have some state of the system some
abstract state of the system we execute
the code and then we have some state
after executing the code so we have s as
the initial state T is the state after
execution and then execution is defined
formally by the formal model of the code
and it defines the behavior of each
command and how it modifies the state so
once we run the code we have some idea
of how the initial state is modified to
the final state so what do we want to
prove well we want to prove that the
final state after executing the code so
state T fulfills whatever specification
we have and there are two common
approaches to doing that
the first is whore logic the second is
refinement so I'll talk about both of
those the idea behind whore logic is to
introduce these things called whore
triples and a horrible consists of a
precondition some code and a post
condition in the intuition behind whore
logic and doing proofs in her logics and
these in these in these heart triples is
that if the precondition P holds before
you execute your code C then the post
condition Q will hold as well in a
correct program so if the program is
correct if P holds and then you do
execute C then Q will hold so as an
example we could say that the
precondition for our abstract sort
function is that L is a valid list so
the input list is a valid list and the
post condition after we sort the list is
that the output list is a valid list
that there's a permutation and that the
elements are increasing so this is
basically our specification and so we
find that when we're doing this kind of
whore logic these are triples that our
post condition is typically what
represents our representing our
specification it's a desired property of
the code when we want to prove such a
whore triple we need to prove that if P
holds for the initial state when we then
modify that state using the commands in
to state T then Q will hold for that
final state and in doing the proof we
use the behaviors as defined in the
formal model of the language of the
implementation to show for each command
how it modifies the state and that the
final state matches Q if we have a
larger program with a lot of commands
then we break that up in 2 sub-goals so
we have kind of sub post conditions and
sub preconditions but we show that the
overall chained fit matches those
initial pre and post conditions the
other approach is refinement so we say
that the implementation refines the
specification so the concrete
implementation refines the abstract
specification and the intuition behind
that is that any behavior in the
concrete implementation is allowed by
the abstract specification as well as
any behavior or sorry all the behaviors
in the abstract specification are
present in in the concrete code
typically we'll separate the
specification in the implementation and
the specification will have an abstract
version or abstract specification of
every function that's in the concrete
implementation so for example our
abstract specification could be an
abstract function to sort the list which
again has the same properties that we
talked about before the lengths are the
same it's a permutation and the elements
are increasing where we want to prove
refinement what we need to show is that
when the concrete code and the abstract
code start in an initial State and then
you execute them the state that they end
up in is essentially equivalent so they
start in a state that's essentially
equivalent they end up in a state that's
also essentially equivalent which means
they do the same thing now we need to
formalize this essentially equivalent
idea and so we introduce a state
relation and this talks about how the
initial State or the concrete state maps
to the abstract State what's the
relation between the two states so
here's an example of a state relation
that says okay well the lengths are the
same and the elements of the lists are
the same so if we have two essentially
equivalent States in the abstract and
the concrete then they should two lists
should have the same length and the same
elements and then the states are the
same we take this state relation and
then we show that formally that if the
state relation holds between the initial
States s and s prime then after we
execute C after we execute a the state T
and T prime will also have the state
relation between them hold and if that's
the case then we can say that C refines
a so we have this kind of nice square so
that's nice
so that's formal formal verification 101
hopefully everyone now can go off and
prove code correct but this still
doesn't tell us how this formal
verification leads to better security so
before talking about that what do I mean
by better security well bad security
means we have vulnerabilities so better
security means less vulnerabilities what
do we mean by vulnerabilities well I
don't really need to tell you much about
them but just to make it complete we
have three classes of vulnerabilities so
there's the design vulnerabilities where
you make a mistake in your design or
your architecture of the system such
that it doesn't actually fulfill the
security policy that you want
we've got implementation vulnerabilities
where you make mistakes in your code
that allow people to use those mistakes
use those bugs to bypass your security
policy in bypass your security
mechanisms and then we've got
operational vulnerabilities where you
make mistakes in how you actually deploy
or configure your system or people make
mistakes so you get social engineering
you get people who are just make
mistakes or not very good at what they
do formal verification can help us with
the design vulnerabilities and the
implementation vulnerabilities so I'll
talk about how they do that I talked
about how formal verification allows us
to prove properties about code which is
nice but typically those properties
don't relate to security they talk about
things like the list is sorted they talk
about application domain properties
which are not necessarily security
however it gives us an extra benefit and
it also helps us to prevent
implementation vulnerabilities so that
if we can prove these nice abstract
properties these nice application
specific properties about our code we
can also prove that a bunch of
implementation vulnerabilities don't
exist in that code why is that well a
lot of implementation bugs happen
because they're actually undefined
behavior this is things like array or
list bound overflows if you access past
the bound of a defined array that's
really undefined behavior especially in
your formal model integer overflow and
underflow is if your integers don't have
limits then you don't overflow or
underflow them so that doesn't really
exist
following null pointers is
to find behavior and so on so our
specification formalisms in the
languages we use for the specifications
don't allow these things to happen
you're not allowed to define it in that
language because it's undefined so these
kind of implementation bugs that most of
you love don't happen in the formal
specs of course they do happen in real
code so writing past the end of array is
something that C programmers love to do
they do it all the time what we need to
do is make sure that doesn't happen and
so what happens is that if you try to
prove that this kind of code fulfills
its specification and again that
specification may have nothing to do
with array bounds it could be something
else
you'll fail you won't be able to prove
that code that contains these kind of
statements fulfill their specification
so for example the end state after you
try to access an array out of bounds
formally is not defined there is no
state and so trying to prove properties
about something that has no state is not
going to work
furthermore there are no rules that you
can apply in your proof about no state
and so you can't continue your proof so
trying to prove something with these
kind of bugs in it just won't work you
won't be able to prove it and so that
forces you to either fix your code if
you want to continue your proof or if
you're sure that your code is not broken
which you know none of us write broken
code so we're sure of that
you need to prove that the conditions
that lead to the undefined behavior
won't happen so if you're certain that
your array indexing code will never you
know Index the array out of bounds then
you need to prove that in order to
continue proof so once you get a fully
proved system then you know these things
don't exist the big benefit of that is
that you're proving properties
interesting properties about your system
and without having to specify all of
these implements
vulnerabilities or bugs the proof for
free finds those vulnerabilities for you
finds those bugs for you and forces you
to do something about them so you don't
have to tell the system you know find me
all the array bound overflows it finds
this for you because those are undefined
so whole classes of undefined behavior
just disappear once you've proved your
system so that's really great I want to
go into a little bit more practical
detail so I have said we've we have this
verified operating system and I want to
talk about what we've done how you apply
this in practice so how would you apply
what I've just talked about with this
whore logic with this refinement and so
on with proving properties to a real
system so SEO for is is this microkernel
we've developed it's small which means
it's amenable to a formal verification
it's fast which means it's useful for
real world use it's capability-based
which ultimately means that it has an
explicit access control model so it's
really good for talking about secure
systems and it's the operating system
kernel which means it runs in privileged
mode which means it's one of the most
critical parts of software so it's
critically important to get it right and
which is why we formally verified it so
what did we verify what got verified
about SEO for SEO for verification
showed functional correctness which
shows that the implementation refines
the spec so that's the refinement I was
talking about before the implementation
of SEO for refines the specification of
SEO for it means that the kernel does
exactly what the specification says no
more and no less which is nice
hopefully the specification says
something useful hopefully it says
something about building secure systems
and so on well what does it a spec say
it talks about the behavior of system
calls so it defines what each system
called us so for example if you have a
system call that sends a message from
one thread to another it defines how
invoking that system call is going to
change the state of the kernel so you
have an initial state you invoke a
system call that sends a message
what's the state after you've sent the
message that's nice but that doesn't say
anything about security so we don't
explicitly talk about security in the
specification that was proved about SCO
for okay so what's the point if we if we
want to have this kernel and we want to
verify it in order to be able to say
that it's secure but we don't say
anything about security in the spec
what's the point well we still get these
proofs about lack of all this undefined
behavior that it talked about before so
improving the properties of the system
calls we've also proved that there
aren't buffer overflows there aren't
null pointers being followed
etc there aren't integer overflows or
under floats etc so all this undefined
behavior doesn't exist in the
implementation of the kernel which makes
it a lot harder for you to exploit the
kernel which is good that's good for
security but we can also prove
properties above the specification
itself so we can go a level higher and
start making interesting proofs about
the specification itself and because of
refinement because we've shown that the
implementation refines the specification
if we make proofs above the
specification we know that those proofs
also hold for the implementation of the
kernel so we know that if we actually
invoke a system call and we prove that
that has some other properties other
than it's just correct then that will
hold for the actually implementation so
what are these properties that we proved
about the specification well we wanted
it to be secure so we wanted to show
that given an access control policy
which you can think of as an access
control matrix or a specification of
what authority subjects have two other
subjects so who can for example modify
who who can access who can read what
data etc that the kernel will enforce
that policy and this comes down to the
classic security properties the classic
CIA properties of confidentiality
integrity and availability so we've
proved confidentiality about the kernel
spec we proved integrity about the
kernel spec and we've partially proved
available
above the speck what does integrity mean
in its context well generally the
general definition of integrity is that
you can't make authorized mod of
unauthorized modifications more
specifically and formally we have this
nice whore triple that says given a pre
precondition so the initial state s0
that's what the precondition part means
if we make one of these abstract kernel
calls so a system call after the call
the state afterwards which is state s
the difference between initial state and
final state will be authorized by the
policy so there won't be any changes to
the state that aren't authorized by this
access control matrix that's the
property that's been proved about the
kernel specification I won't go into
details about how that was proved
there's a paper about that you can read
if you're really interested the other
property which is a little bit more
complicated is confidentiality so
confidentiality says that you can't read
or learn unauthorized data and so
there's this longer statement here that
says if the initial states are
equivalent then if we have initial
states of the same Pro to different
initial states are equivalent if we do
the same executions on both of those
states then the final states will also
be equivalent with regards to the
security policy and so the picture what
it shows is on the Left these two
initial states where the green parts are
equivalent these are the non
confidential parts and then the red and
the yellow parts or the confidential
parts and those are different if we then
execute the same instructions for for
for this subject let's say it's a it's a
process if you actually look the same
instruction schooler's process then the
final state that they end up in will be
the same even though the confidential
states might be different so what that
means is the confidential data doesn't
leak into the non confidential parts of
the system so we proved that about the
kernel as well which is great
this gives you a bit of an idea of how
using formal method can method or form
of verifications can lead to better very
better security we can reduce
implementation vulnerabilities but we
can also have interesting abstract
higher level property security
properties that we can use to build our
systems on top so I'm going to talk
about why this is not a silver bullet
why does it not mean that we have hack
proof systems if we want to build a
verified secure system we need to start
with an overall threat model for the
system which leads to security
requirements it relates to properties
that we have to have on the system and
then we start at a high level
architecture or a design and so we need
to design an architecture system such
that these properties hold these high
level properties home so in this example
it might be that information only flows
from domain a to B and it always goes
through some sort of trusted component
that may be filters it or something like
that so we want to prove that this
architecture fulfills that property so
we can do that we can do a high level
architecture proof about that but then
at some point we need to implement that
so that architecture gets translated
into a bunch of code that could be
manually written code that could be
existing tools that could be generated
code and so on and then we need to show
that this code also fulfills some
properties and the properties might be
that it's a refinement of the
architecture so any data flows that are
allowed in the architecture are also
allowed in the code but the code doesn't
allow other data flows so we can prove
that as well which is nice we need to
run that on something so we need to run
it on an operating system and a bunch of
services it relies on that operating
system and services so we need to prove
that as well well now we've got a bunch
of code we need to actually load it into
a running system so we'd also got a
bootloader ideally we would need to
verify that to make sure it does the
right thing and that ultimately needs to
run on hardware so we should also verify
the hardware what I'm getting at here is
that building a secure system requires
different layers of abstraction and each
of those layers have different
properties and each of those layers need
to be shown to be correct
to fulfill those properties as well now
we've got this idea of necessary versus
sufficient it's not sufficient to just
implement verify some of those layers
and expect that you will have a verified
secure system so if you just verify the
top layer the architecture you can have
a nice architecture but you can have
implementation but bugs in the
architecture you can have problems in
the operating system in the loader in
the hardware that allow you to bypass
that and so you don't have a fully
verified system so if you want a fully
verified secure system you need to
verify all of those layers and if you
don't feel Nura bilities can sneak in
there
the other thing is that with formal
verification we're working on models and
models aren't necessarily the same as
reality there's always some gap between
the model and the reality you can try to
make that gap as small as possible but
there will be a gap and this manifests
itself as assumptions so we have
assumptions about the real world that
are proofs our models and our proofs
rely on so some examples of these
assumptions practical assumptions are
well we may assume that boot is correct
so the hardware and the software
environment are initialized correctly so
that when our verified code run or our
model runs that it has a particular
environment we might make assumptions
about how the hardware behaves we have
to have a specification of the hardware
we make assumptions that the hardware is
implemented correctly so that it
actually matches the specification we
can make assumptions about semantics
about our programming languages so if we
take code in C and we transform it into
a formal model we make some assumptions
about the semantics of the programming
languages so we need to assume that
those are true we may have unverified
code in our system so we may be using
third-party libraries and stuff like
that so we need to make assumptions
about that code as well so there's lots
of assumptions that might need to be
made and if you want your verification
to be believable to be good then you
need to validate those assumptions and
those assumptions as I showed in the
previous case can be validated by doing
formal verification as well or you can
do your your testing and your hardening
and so on on those things and so on and
if you don't do that then this is where
vulnerabilities can
Nikken as well there's the the
assumptions are fundamental right
because of this gap between the model
and reality but there are also other
potential limitations that are more
practical that can be dealt with but you
need to put effort in into dealing with
them so one as I've talked about is the
specification should say something
useful so you need to validate the
specification you need to make sure that
it says something useful for example
like we did by verifying properties
about SEO for specification the verified
code needs to actually be used correctly
so for example it needs to be configured
correctly if you miss configure the code
that might invalidate some assumptions
that you make and therefore the proof
might not hold if again this idea of
necessary versus sufficient also holds
if you use verified code but it relies
on a bunch of unverified code then a lot
of your assumptions might also break
finally scalability is a big issue
verification is hard one of the proof
engineers in our group said that you
know it punishes you for every mistake
in a terrible unforgiving way so a lot
of people don't become proof engineers
because it's hard but it also takes a
long time to do proofs and so you're
limited in what you can verify and that
means that you need to make decisions
but important design decisions
such that the parts of the system that
you do verify support being able to use
unverified code on top of that so for
example in SEO for we have
confidentiality integrity proofs which
means that we can run unverified code on
top of SEO for and still have guarantees
that there's confidentially and
integrity between them we don't
necessarily need to verify that code
running on top so we can use that to
build secure systems on top of that
without having to verify all the code
but all of these things the fact that
you don't necessarily verify all the
code that you may miss configure and so
on also can lead to vulnerability
sneaking in so this comes back to the
question does formal verification really
lead to better security and the answer
is yes it does
in particular it can lead to better
security because it makes you define
specifications it makes you define
security proper
and you can have secure specs which is
an important basis for building secure
systems it also forces you if you prove
a system to deal with all of the
implementation bugs implementation
vulnerabilities in the system so both of
those lead to much better code much
better security options of course it's
not a silver bullet it does not
guarantee hacker-proof code because
we've got assumptions we've got the
models the coverage of verification
might not be complete people might
misuse the verifications and so on so
that's the end of my talk if you want to
have more information about SEO for or
what we do at trustworthy systems those
are the URLs otherwise if you've become
interested in formal verification and
you want to explore this and see what it
can do for you
there's a nice blog post on proof craft
orga about starting into verification
how to become a proof engineer what you
should do all right thank you
[Applause]