okay thank you everyone so my name's Ben
Campbell I'm a security consultant at
Elton and we do Red Team in Pentos in
source code auditing we also deliver
training and I personally have over a
decade of experience last year we ran
the CTF here are b-sides and I love
DevOps so I also run broxbourne up in
Sydney so I'm I'm be dog I've given some
talks there as well myself so just on
that if you're if you're in Sydney if
you're interested in giving a talk are
you interested in getting involved
please come up to me let me know so
today I'm gonna be talking about Cuban
ET's so we're gonna go over a brief
introduction to Cuban Eadie's containers
and darker then we're going to talk
about some common like methods to set it
up also some common security problems
that occur within kubernetes clusters
I'm going to recap just briefly on some
cuban eddies vulnerabilities and then
discuss how to secure the clusters and
some tools and resources for helping to
order clusters and then we're gonna wrap
up with the conclusion so the cuban
eddies there's lots and lots of
components lots and lots of our projects
if you if you when you first get started
in cuban Eddie's there's a lot to learn
and it's it's it's really it's really
massive things really interesting so
what is Cuban Eddie's it's all great to
me so it's an open source container
orchestration solution and I came out of
Google so they had a similar internal
project and they then effectively did a
rewrite and and and released it it's
like it's open source and it basically
orchestrates clusters like all the
containers within a cluster like so
multiple nodes multiple hosts the
volumes and networking and all the
configuration it does all of that at
scale and it's highly extensible so all
these like various components that make
up kubernetes
they can either be like very highly
configured or they can be replaced
totally so bits and pieces can be
swapped in and out so it's possible to
have like every cluster can be different
to another cluster sort of thing so like
every different business organization
who's going to set up a cluster they
they can pick and choose and do it
differently to like what suits them best
or just however they decided to do it so
they they have a lot of options so just
talking about containers talking about
communities so they have a concept of a
pod and a pod can either be like it
seemed as simple as a single container
or it can be a container and a volume or
it can be multiple containers and
volumes or any sort of combination of
these of these things and so they will
all be scheduled together as a single
sort of like entity that's get scheduled
and then by default with the default
networking within communities each pod
will have one single IP address and so
that means that like all the containers
running within that pot they all have
the one IP address so there may be like
you know listening different ports and
stuff different pieces of like different
containers have different services on
different ports but it's all the one IP
okay so Kuban Eddie's like the when you
when you set up a cluster there's all
these different pieces or these are some
components within it so one of the main
things you're gonna have is down here
this like API this API server and that's
like all of the control when you want to
control the cluster when you want to
instruct it to do different things
you're gonna be sending the messages to
the API server then there's like
configuration manager the scheduler
schedule is going to be handling like
which pods to put on which nodes and and
then you you basically gonna run your
containers your pods on the worker nodes
so
with the implementation like I do
generally want to go for high
availability it's a sort of a point of
using Cuban Eddie's and you're going to
have multiple masters the Masters are
going to run the API server the
configuration manager and a scheduler
all those sort of control plane
components and they generally don't run
the workloads there's also the etc D
cluster and so you can run that on the
Masters we can run it separately and so
you're generally going to have at least
three except ready nodes and then in
production you probably going to have
more than two masters you're going to
have a bigger etc declaw style and then
with you with your worker nodes you may
actually split them up and have some
dedicated for ingress traffic and some
just just as like general workload and
[Music]
and yeah and so the weave with the
master nodes they will be running all of
those control plan components but they
the control manager and the scheduler
they're going to get like a leader is
going to get elected and the more of the
of the control nodes master nodes that
you have the more sort of redundancy you
can have the more failures are going to
be able to survive so when you when you
set up a Cuban Eddie's like application
you want to run a service you want to
exploit an application there's a lot of
different pieces that are going to use
so you're gonna have here on the Left
you're gonna have say lucky ingress
you're gonna have a service and that's
going to spread the traffic over to the
various pods so you can Cuban Eddie's
you can tell it I wanted to deploy an
application I'm gonna have a deployment
I want to have like save three instances
of my pod and the service is gonna
spread that across those pods and then
if a pod dies for some reason like maybe
your whole node dies then because you
instructed communities to run three of
these pods then when for some reason one
died it's going to it's going to start
another one and it may start on another
the NOTAM a starter on the same node and
you can control all of this and then you
can also set you can set limits resource
limits constraints and you can set up
various policies and you can quotas and
things like that so human it is it's
like it's very powerful it's very
flexible it allows you to run a lot of
workloads and just have a lot of good
control over them also it's going to
manage the configuration so you can tell
your pods like just in the center of the
diagram here you can tell your pod ok
get this configuration and on the left
here like get these secrets and so this
is going to be stored in etc D and it's
gonna be made available to the to the
pod server as a plug get scheduled it's
gonna be able to grab its configuration
and needs for for its run time settin up
the kubernetes cluster there's many many
ways there's a lot like five or fifty if
you go to the communities documentation
there's like a big page you can scroll
through you can set it up on a local
machine there's a few tools that help
you do that there's there's a there's
like there's a new tool in our code k3
and then there's AI mini cube and a
bunch of other tools they'll help you
set that up you can set up hoisted you
can set it up on openshift from Red Hat
there's also a lot of cloud providers so
Google themselves they have gke you got
Amazon all the big clouds and is on
Azure they will have at least one way to
run communities if not more and you can
also just to play it on the cloud
yourself so you could set up your own
say like ec2 instances and set up the
communities cluster on it so get into
the meat of the talk now cubic community
of security first off you want to start
off we have like what is your threat
model so you want to think about what it
is that you're trying to protect what it
is you're trying to do
whoo-hooo maybe like will be an attacker
will be interested in
in attacking you and so you need to take
into in this into consideration and
actually use this is like the whole sort
of backbone is to like your planning and
what sort of actions you take to defend
your cluster and the whole reason you do
this is because if you don't then this
sort of thing can happen you can end up
basically having someone being like oh
this queue bananas cluster if I gain
control of it then I can start to
schedule my own workloads on it and I
can start to do things like crypto
mining so Tesla for example fell victim
to this Tesla had an unauthenticated
access to their cluster which allowed an
attacker to come along and basically
gain control of the cluster start to
schedule down workloads start to do some
crypto mining and and it also happened
to have their they're like details for
their cloud so they could start to get
access keys into s3 buckets and things
like that and start to also attack the
cloud so it's not it's not a very good
thing you obviously this can cost you a
lot of money your cloud account if an
attacker can run their own workloads
within it then they can take up a big
bill with with all the compute and
storage X and networking etc that they
use them so with your with your threat
model you know on the defensive side
really like what you want is lots and
lots and lots of isolation so the more
isolation you can get the better so if
an attacker manages to break into
something so they break into a container
they compromised a pod then the less
that pod can do the better firm for you
for you so at every sort of level you
want to try to have as much isolation as
you can and that way you're going to
limit the blast radius of other
compromised you're going to contain them
and it's and it all comes back to that
principle of least privilege if you if
your app doesn't need to be able to talk
to too many things then like don't allow
to talk to many things that way if it
gets compromised it can't talk to many
things and it all comes back to that
principle effectively
so some common security problems with
kubernetes clusters so in the beginning
cuba Nettie's up until like version 1.5
there was no authentication for for the
for effectively like for the control
plane so as soon as someone like god
access into your cluster they would be
able to talk to the control plane and
they would be able to make changes
effectively be able to start up their
own pods or in containers stop their own
workloads
and start to attack your infrastructure
start to extract secrets from your
workloads and things like that there's
also a read-only port so you could set
up the control plane and this was
actually like often done by default they
would have a read-only listener set
there and even today it's like depending
on how you've set up your cluster this
may still be there on the on the
internal on the inside of your cluster
so your workloads containers and things
that are running the pods they mabel to
connect to this read-only listener and
from there they can gather a lot of
information so they can then work out
how is your cluster configured how is it
set up and from that information they
can then work out better ways to attack
it what sort of pieces will they try to
attack next to gain more and more
control until they've eventually
achieved their goal or compromised your
cluster privileged containers so we've
seen this in the past when we've done
some audits of some cuban Nettie's
clusters for various reasons people have
set up privileged containers and
privilege containers they're very
dangerous there near equivalent of
effectively having root access to your
node so your hosts and they're basically
containers that have privileges to
interact with the hosts and so they can
they can they can because they have more
access to the host I have a lot more
attack surface a lot more are different
things they can do
so it's quite dangerous to run them and
if you can avoid them you definitely
should so you can configure your claw
style to not allow privileged containers
which is which is a thing you should do
if you can in secure containers so this
is also very common you'll often find
containers which are set up where by
default they'll run is route you can
also have containers which the developer
who's like build the application if
they've included secrets things
unnecessarily it shouldn't really be
there they may also have sometimes like
left the source code in there sometimes
people will leave like git repositories
and things like that within the image
and so then when that container gets
scheduled then I contend it gets wrong
it has all these extra things like
source code and passwords to databases
and things like that that shouldn't be
there
then you can the etc D itself so this is
like all of the storage for the
configuration for the for the pods for
the cluster itself and all of the
secrets is sort of thing etc D so it's
very important that exception D is
secured and you can have you can miss
configure it so it's set up without
authentication and you can also set it
up so that there's no encryption at rest
so that means that you may have like
unencrypted backups of your data as well
you may have snapshots and things like
that the contain is unencrypted etcetera
D database so that's other like we
concerns you can have in exit routine if
you're running in the cloud often
there's a metadata service so a node in
the cloud I can connect to this metadata
service and find out information about
the cloud environments running in find
out information about itself think
things like it's like P address its
hostname various other sort of details
about the cloud environment so this is
very common especially it's in AWS and
Siena's your it's in all the major
clouds so originally by default when a
pod got scheduled they would mount in
service token to the cubanelle
is cluster and this could then be used
for the plot to authenticate to the
cluster and to be able to start your
interact with the class to start to find
information that it needs and various
things like that and originally this
service token effectively gave it full
control of the cluster so if you didn't
have our back enabled or some other sort
of security authentication mechanism
then this would effectively lead to a
full cluster compromise the kubernetes
api server authentication so if if you
have a listener that's set up without
authentication maybe it's on the inside
only
so maybe only like pods can talk to it
things like that like outsiders can talk
to him but once a malicious payload is
running if you had an image that's been
Trojans if you have a container that
happens to get compromised they could
then talk to this API server they don't
need authentication and then I can start
to make malicious commands they can they
can start to schedule more pods they can
start to pull down images they can they
can start to run their own workloads and
things like that Mount volumes etc
network security so there's lots and
lots of ways to set up they're now
working within
kubernetes it's probably the most
probably has like the most alternatives
but by default all the pods can talk to
all the other pods within the whole
cluster and all the pods can talk to all
the nodes so they can talk to the work
nodes and they can talk to the master
nodes it's just one big flat network so
and by default like they can all talk to
each other so there's no there's nothing
stopping one container there was like
say running a simple web server from you
talking to the database of another pod
even though they're totally unrelated
they can all talk to each other some
pass vulnerabilities so the quite
interesting vulnerability that came out
last year
it was found by the CTO of Rancho and so
this this was quite interesting so
basically on the control plane side of
Cuba Nettie's the the various components
like they have full trust
they don't need authentication and like
when they when they do things they
basically they're the equivalent of
route and so this vulnerability the guy
who found out if he worked out that when
you make this like proxied request to do
WebSockets
there was this failure to handle and in
failure to properly handle like an
exception case and it would trick the
server into connecting to itself in
thinking that what since since its me
since I'm the the server I have full
access and so an authenticated user
could go from having like we've are back
they could have not very many privileges
at all like maybe just the ability to
look at some information but not to
actually start up their own containers
and things like that
they could then effectively become route
of the cluster and have full control of
the cluster so that was quite an
interesting bug and a good find and then
most recently there was a
vulnerabilities in run C so this is not
actually a vulnerability within Cuba
Nettie's itself but it's a vulnerability
in a component that that Cuba Nettie's
uses that it leverages so run see it's
used to start containers and there was a
vulnerability where you could basically
overwrite the run C binary itself on the
host and so that meant that if the
attacker could had a malicious image or
if they had right access to a container
or if they could exact into a container
then they could overwrite that run C
binary which is running on the host and
it's running as root and they then
basically have root access to that host
and once they've got access to one host
then they can you know start to do that
attack again and again to compromise all
of the worker nodes
and with root access to the work nodes
they had a lot more access to the master
nodes and so they can start to try to
take over them as well so how to secure
clusters you want to secure the control
plane as much as you can
that's like the whole brains of
communities you want to harden the
worker nodes this is like where these
worker nodes they're running your your
pods they're running your workloads
which may not you may not have like as
much control over them you may be
running a lot of workloads from various
developers and things like that it may
not have all put the same level of care
into it as you so you want to harden
your worker nodes so that if a pod
happens to get compromised or if a pod
happens to be malicious that you're
limiting what it can do contain an image
security you're going to want to secure
your containers you're going to wanna
have good secret management you really
want like as much legislation as you can
get and then you also want to have good
monitoring so that when something does
go wrong you detect it and you want that
to have alarm in so our back I spoke
about earlier so role based access
control you can configure cuba Nettie's
so that you have different roles
different users different groups and you
can set it up so they like different
people they can only do just the limited
actions that they need to do and nothing
more and so that's generally what you
want to do and then in their suppliers
like not just to to black people but
also to various components so you can
limit what they can do and that's always
a good thing
pod security policies are PSP these are
quite powerful you can do quite a lot
with these all all these like there's a
lot a lot of different options here
but they can stop privileged containers
they can control like what namespaces
containers can use whether the
containers can have access to hosts
networking whether they can mount
various things in the file system proc
mounts all these various options around
volumes and storage they can also
control like whether a container is
allowed to run its route
and then the Linux capabilities which is
like a way to remove privileges from
like the root account so there's a lot
of different capabilities within Linux
and you can also like control like what
capabilities are containers allowed to
have and then you can restrict like an
administrator who wants to connect to a
container they the equivalent of docker
exec you can stop that you can like
limit that so a container may be
privileged for some reason like for some
reason you needed to have this
privileged container and so on even
though you have our back and other sort
of mechanisms if they're able to exact
into that container then that may give
them an equivalent of route on that node
and so for that reason you may want to
say well okay we need we have our
reasons we need this like privileged
container but we don't want to then
allow that is effective like a backdoor
for operators and things like that to be
able to escalate onto the host so we're
going to restrict them into remoting but
then that has like you know other
implement implications like they may
make troubleshooting harder and things
like that our pod security policies can
also control the SELinux context that
you give a container control the
up-armored profile second profile so set
comp is a way to limit what Siskel's
container can make so you can control
that so you can like really tighten up
what the container can do the less
syscalls it has like the less sort of
things you can do and this is also
important because the containers that
are running on a node they're all using
the same kernel so if they if there's a
kernel exploit they can leverage then
they can effectively break out of that
container and and break into the host
and then all the containers that are
running on at host they can they can
start to interact with everything start
to read so so if if you have limited
what's his calls they can call if they
can't call the sis call that has it's
like vulnerability then they can't
even though that kernel is vulnerable
they don't have access to it so it's
very it's very good very powerful
mechanism to use and then you also have
this control profile which is also
changes our settings effectively so a
really useful resource is the center for
internet security so I guess they make
many benchmarks for various things and
they make one for Cuba Nettie's and so
this is actually its really good guide
it's like it's quite long I think it's
about like 2 100 odd pages and it goes
through like all of the options that you
can set up in Cuba Nettie's and it goes
into the security implications of that
setting so like if you have left it on
the default or if you set it to various
values what would that do so there's
settings for example to do with like you
know I'll be I'll be able to schedule
privileged pods or not and and so this
will you know describe like you know why
is that a bad thing and like you know
why should you set it to a certain value
and things like that the benchmark it
basically details many many options but
it's it's not it's not sort of designed
with the idea that you're trying to get
a hundred cent pass rate for this
benchmark if you if you used like all of
the settings to the maximum security
area so they sort of recommend you'd
probably then end up with a cluster that
doesn't work so you have to take it with
a grain of salt
read read it like use it as a as a
resource to to educate you on points
that you may not know and then make a
decision like whether it makes sense to
enable this feature or disable it or
like what sort of value to set it to and
things like that there's also a very
interesting project called open policy
agent and this is like agnostic it's not
i like limited to communities you can
use it for anything really and it allows
you to do policy as code so you can
using their own like domain-specific
language you can define your policies
you can you can say various things like
users from this team are allowed to are
allowed to like
schedule these sort of pods or users
from this team are allowed to connect to
these sort of resources and various
things like that and you within Cuba
Nettie's you can set up some emission
controllers that will then talk to OPA
and run through your rules and so
anytime like someone's like trying to
say for example schedule a pod then we
have OPA you can be like well who's
trying to do it like where are they from
like what time of day is it or any sort
of like rules you want to make up and
then implement that and have that sort
of control so it allows you to implement
your own business rules and the nice
thing about it is because it's like
independent you can use it not just in
Cuban Eddie's but you can use it in
other things as well so like other parts
of like your CI CD pipeline and your any
various like DevOps tools you can set up
service measures so I spoke about
earlier how the networking within Cuban
Eddie's by default is very flat you can
get service measures or there's other
networking mechanisms you can use but
one service mesh that I quite like is
sto it's also another project out of
Google originally there's several others
is do is my personal favorite it allows
you to set up network security policies
so you can then restrict the network
communication their pods can make
restrict them from me able to talk to
other pods other containers restrict
them from being able to talk egress out
to the internet restrict ingress into
your cloths tile restricts them being
able to talk to the control plan and
various other things you don't have to
set up sto like just for your cluster it
can it can be like you can govern like
more than your cluster or it can you can
set it up so it's like pretty much just
controlling all of the traffic within
your cluster and in and out of your
cluster it's very flexible and very
powerful
so CPUs they have liked so we've had
like virtual machines we got containers
there's also secure enclaves so there's
Intel SGX and there's AMD has your
equivalent SUV
and these are these like computing
environments that like even root on the
host like the even like Colonel in the
host operating system can like peer
inside to that secure container and
interact like read its memory or write
its memory and and spy on it and things
like that and it's actually possible to
spin up cuban Eddie's containers docker
containers and etc leveraging these
secure enclaves so there's a couple of
interests in projects as one could
graphene and project golem and they
allow you to effectively quite easily
spin up the container that's going to be
running in this secure Enclave and
that's going to protect it from the host
itself so if you happen to be running
payloads running our workloads in your
cluster and your cluster say like one of
the weaker containers got compromised
and they wouldn't manage to elevate and
get access into the hosts
and they then started to look at like
what else is running on this host they
won't be able to actually appear inside
these secure enclaves and so that's
given you another level of protection
another level of isolation tools for
auditing so one one tool it's quite it's
quite good ease cube bench it's by
company code aqua security and they've
got a couple tools one one is Q bench
and Q bench uses that so IES benchmark
that I mentioned earlier and you run it
you can run it on your on your master
nodes and you run it on your worker
nodes and it's going to go through it's
going to look at like what process is
running like what sort of arguments do
they have look at the config and
basically work out like whether it
thinks that you made or don't meet the
various items within that benchmark so
this is like roughly what it looks like
so if you in this example they have
allowed privileged allowed privilege is
allowing privileged containers and so
that's a that's a fail and so it's just
going through just taken
look like what parameters do the
processes have basically and whether
meets all or does not meet the benchmark
another tool by the same company aqua
security is coupon tour it's a similar
tool to Cubans you run it against your
master no it's run it against your your
worker nodes and it's going to again
like tell you what sort of like
misconfigurations and and like security
settings are or are not there and
another interesting tool is mi contained
it's by genuine tools and mi contained
you run it so you like you can you can
spin it up it's a container effectively
so you can spin it up like using docker
you can spin up using your Cuban Eddie's
cluster and it's going to evaluate its
run time it's going to take a look at
does it think it's running in darker
doesn't think it's running in Cuban
Eddie's what container runtime engine
does it think these being used because
is there's not just docker there's
others there's some ones like rocket etc
so it's going to try to work that out
and it's going to try to work out what
Linux capabilities does it have does it
does it have root and what sort of like
syscalls can it make is there any sort
of second filtering is there any
up-armored security profiles or selinux
profiles con texas and things like that
so it's gonna sort of like do a bit of
investigation and try to work out those
sort of things and what's good about
this tool is if you run it on standard
docker and you run it on standard cuban
eddies you'll be surprised to find that
darker actually has better security out
of the box because docker out of the box
will give you a default second profile
and a default up-armored profile and
cuba Nettie's by default won't so if
you're if you've started off with docker
and then you sort of build up and
started to use cuban eddies you may be
surprised to find that it's not as locks
down from that point of view and this is
like a mistake or like an omission a lot
of people have missed and so for that
whole defense-in-depth
you're going to want to
set up your own sitcom profiles you earn
up armored profiles
selinux and things like that like which
other tool you want to use like to try
to ice try to minimize the amount of
access that your containers have to just
what they need so that if they do get
compromised you're limiting what an
attacker can do okay so in conclusion
there's a lot of options like every two
bananas cluster is can be effectively
quite different from from others take
care with the configuration there's all
those options like and the defaults as
well like you have to make make sure
like do the defaults really meet your
needs or you know should you do some
more tightening and more investigation
and look at how can you further secure
your cluster effectively then there's
like several tools and resources so
there's that Cuban eighties benchmark
and there's like various tools will help
you compare your cluster against that
benchmark and just enjoy and embrace the
power of and flexibility of Cuban it is
it's a it's a very good tool so it will
be releasing the slides later so I put a
bunch of references there that you can
grab and so late links to tools and
things like that and links to other
talks so yeah so is there any questions
I say we've got a runner going to a
question out there at the back I can see
the hands these runners they definitely
gonna get fit over the weekend okay
thank you
so thank you for the interesting
presentation now I admit I'm not that
familiar with kubernetes and I don't
know if it's Linux only or if it
supports other node operating systems as
well but when we mentioned the security
options like armor profiles and
psychopaths so forth that's all features
which are inherent to the Linux kernel
so assuming that you can have I don't
know say a Windows node or something
does it also support like the equivalent
mechanisms in Windows so you can so
daughter can run on Windows and you can
actually set up like a Cuban a DS
cluster using docker for Windows stuff
like that so i i'm not actually certain
if you can have like a worker node like
a Windows worker node in a Cuban Indies
cluster and yeah a lot of a lot of those
security mechanisms are talking about
like comm selinux
and our Palmer and all that they're all
Linux Pacific security mechanisms and so
yeah Windows doesn't have them if you
did manage to have like a Windows worker
node there was like running containers
directly on Windows Dan yeah you'd have
to you'd have to use like Windows
security mechanisms there's a question
just next to that yet you've got him
sorry it is question over on the on this
side over here yeah want me to go okay
so do you have any experience with
people migrating from Apache me sauce to
kubernetes because from my observation a
lot of the security controls that
kubernetes applies me sauce doesn't it
just deals with the sched
and resource handling yes I I don't have
a lot of experience Apache Apache
missiles so yeah and I haven't I haven't
experienced people migrating from that
to Cuba Nettie's yeah I'm not really
sure of like what security mechanisms
meat sauce has I do think that it is
purely like more or like sort of limited
in scope to compared to Cuban Eddie's I
think it is more purely about scheduling
and it's open-ended as to like how you
control other parts so I presume there's
ways to secure things but it may not be
is like its integrated as sort of like
easy as as Cuban Eddie's so yeah we get
a bike to the front to boil it so just
one of the earlier questions about
running windows server containers they
can be in the worker nodes for a
kubernetes cluster if you have hosted
kubernetes how much of your sort of I
guess security advice applies or is that
hosted kubernetes you don't worry as
much about it so we've hosted kubernetes
you have less control over the cluster
so yeah you you have less control and
it's more up to like the provider of
that hosted communities cluster to like
how they have locked it down and
configured you may have like some
control but you obviously have a lot
less than if you was your own personal
kubernetes cluster and so it's also
quite interesting like for example when
in the 20 20 18 when that when that
privilege
elevation privilege vulnerability came
out you could see the public cloud can
clusters being upgraded
so they took them I think roughly like
took AWS I think roughly 48 hours so
there's like trade-offs if you if you
use a cloud
Kuban communities cluster it's they've
set it up and their management for you
so yeah basically outsource and a bunch
of your activities you don't have to
care about it enough to sort of like
work on that part but you you then just
have less flexibility you have less
control over mr. vu
hi thanks for the presentation I had a
quick question about general AB security
when developing applications giving
these so usually when you think talk
about general AB security also think
about things like transport layer
security and access management within
the application so what's your opinion
on putting TLS on containers that are
deployed as within clusters because when
I see examples online we usually don't
do that all the applications running on
port 80 unencrypted traffic within the
cluster itself yeah so it's interesting
question so some sometimes people yeah
they won't care about unencrypted
traffic within their cluster
they'll say like these this is this
trust hood so we don't care they can
talk to each other I personally feel
that as long as you have like restricted
it down so that say for example a web
application needs to talk to a database
really only that container should be
able to talk to that database container
and not like any container not any pod
so I would want to like limit that so
that you're not just trusting like all
of the inside of your cluster all the
inside of a node you're you really only
trust in one container to another
container which are meant to talk to
each other I personally would also have
encryption I sort of feel like why not
and computing is relatively cheap so
like there's small overheads but you may
you may have performance reasons and
things like that or you may want to be
able to sleep on the traffic or things
like that so you there's like some
trade-offs so you need to sort of
consider what is best for your use case
we have tools like sto you can make sure
that all the containers are doing
encryption to each other and things like
that so that's one of the reasons why I
like and effectively recommend you do we
have any more questions in the audience
well let's thank Ben for a great
presentation
you
[Music]