alright thanks for having me back it's
great to be here another year and
besides Canberra so I was going to make
a joke about you trying to compete with
the Kiba cotton pyrotechnics but that's
fine well we'll try to get on with it
I basically hate that I had to talk
about source code auditing really doing
it
I guess quickly and efficiently and so
yeah we'll start some introduction a
little bit about me a little bit about
source code auditing talk about it the
theory
talk a bit about vulnerabilities and
eventually we get on to actually
auditing so we've sort of encompassing I
guess three things here first being the
traditional code review which is looking
at the code identifying what it does
make sure it meets the required standard
source code a review is the same thing
but looking for vulnerabilities and then
for some reason I decided that trying to
do too fast would be good that's that
sort of the three definitions but
essentially looking at a way to transfer
some knowledge to you guys on how you
can identify vulnerabilities in source
code fast right and there is one thing I
want you guys to take away and I'm
pretty sure this lapin you should all
learn at least one trick that will let
you go home and get a CBE at the end of
this talk yeah it's pretty easy all
right a little bit about myself I'm a
security researcher with Senate labs
which is the testing validation of dark
matter
I'm a former developer moved into
sysadmin moved into pen testing now do
security research and about a little bit
over ten years ago I found myself as a
sysadmin having to do some code review
for a disproportionate amount of
developers and I kind of decided I
needed to automate this and try to find
a way to at least spot like the really
bad stuff quickly and sort of try to
pull this stuff in so I created this
sort of hot spot checking to all based
on grep
and in June 2009 I made the first public
release
so that's officially almost 10 years
unofficially a bit over 10 years and
it's one of the primary tools I use
whenever I do source code analysis
because it's it's just I find it very
versatile and I'm I'm very familiar with
it because I wrote it so there might be
a slight bias but yeah so the amok that
percent is morning part of a great book
called the art of software security
assessment and it's what it what key
takeaway when they talk about source
code over you is that it's essentially a
skill right you practice it you get
better at it and as a skill it's made up
of a lot of things so some people think
that code review is you got to know the
language you got to be good at language
and then you can just sort of really
review decode but there is a lot more to
it than just that you need to understand
the systems that the codes are running
on source of like vulnerabilities in PHP
on Windows versus Linux can be different
things like memory allocation size
registry size
you know I said 32-bit 64-bit all of
this sort of place into it you also need
to understand vulnerabilities because
you know code reviews the developer
tends to be more about you know
correctness of the code function of the
code but you might not specifically be
familiar with a different vulnerability
classes that might be in the code and on
top of that you also need to be creative
because sometimes you know the
vulnerability class hasn't been defined
all right at some stage somebody had to
be the first guide that went from a
buffer overflow to actual code execution
right to pivot and that correct take
some creativity so you put all that
together you know and you do security
code review it's also important to
remember that we generally don't try to
consume the entire code base you know
you might be handling this very big and
if you're gonna read it all a it's very
slow and be it's cumbersome and takes
time so it's a bit like reverse
engineering in that imagine that you're
always looking at the code through like
a
you're only seeing a small portion of
the code at any given time and what we
really care about is being able to find
a path through this sort of tube into
code execution that's a pen tester but
just basically find the shortest path to
the vulnerability you don't have to
understand the entire code base there's
also some considerations to taking to
account it's not just the code itself
like we said the system matters for
example in in PHP the configuration can
be changed things like race conditions
writable directories compiler
optimization can introduce
vulnerabilities and I'll talk a little
bit about that later as well so all
those things can impact the code base
that you're looking at without
necessarily the being a specific thing
in the code itself it's just affected by
external factors you know such as you
know reading a fall isn't necessarily
bad in the source code but you know you
if you can introduce a race condition
then it might be bad limitations for
static source code analysis obviously
dynamic evaluation any code that only
executes at runtime and may not even be
defined at the static time it's not
something you can analyze by reading it
because it's not there also often code
that's written with a lot of callbacks
or inside out objects can be really
gnarly to to navigate your way through
and also a lot of times if you find I'm
generally say enterprises sort of
applications where maybe they take a
directory structure of xml files and
apply some transforms and then write
something out and then performs two
other operations on that if you don't
have the XML files it can be very hard
to actually know what is happening so so
when we're looking at code through this
tube we can't want to maybe consider the
flow of the application
okay so I'm not sure which part I'm
standing in front of understanding this
side for a bit so basically flow is how
execution of code navigates the code we
care about the execution flow and we
also care about the data flow where does
the data come from where does it then
end up and one of the other things that
we generally find that developers don't
think about and often researchers don't
think about it sinks that interrupts
interruptions to flow so let's say that
you have an application and suddenly get
an unexpected halt execution and it
throws an exception and you know writes
a bunch of sensitive data to log or to
the exception or it's created a
temporary file with some sensitive data
in it like a private key that is trying
to swap out and then execution halts at
that very second that file remains on
the file system it's very common to see
in terms of file uploads and web
applications you'll see that the file
upload occurs gets put in the temporary
or maybe even a web-accessible directory
and then the script goes hey this isn't
a valid gif file and then just leaves
your web shop
rotten file system so interruptions to
flow it's also something that's
important to consider so when you're
looking at flow it can be helpful to
have this kind of like nice
visualization tools it's something I
would generally recommend if you're if
you're in depth analyzing large code
base they're very handy if it's a small
codebase I'd recommend just reading the
code listing here the guy just took down
is is git repo because he's working on a
licensing issue but it's it looks really
nice oh I haven't had a test spin myself
so all right so there's a couple of
things in terms of flow we care about
basically data flow from source to sink
and source is wherever the data enters
the flow of the application typically we
want to track user supplied data because
static content is usually not
manipulatable and
doesn't tend to result in in
vulnerabilities and and the sink is
obviously the function where the code
ends up that we care about so say that
you take user input from the URL you put
it in a system call that thus you know
execute the ping utility and you don't
filter that data then you know yeah we
have a problem now it can be very hard
to identify where user user input comes
from if you look at things like
second-order SQL injection with data is
read out of a database and then use
directly in an SQL statement again and
you might be doing proper power
optimization on the insert statement but
then the subsequent select statement is
insecure
also developers tend to miss things like
environment variables or you know
browser headers those type of things
other things to consider when you're
reviewing code is trust boundaries you
know that's the flow past the trust
boundary and also just a flow induce a
state change so that you know has the
user logged in has to user logged out
these are good areas of the application
to audit taking it a bit beyond you know
just using grep for full keywords or a
reading code paint analysis is possible
from a static perspective without
executing code and it basically the
notion of tent analysis for those who
don't know is that a variable carries an
additional flag that the compiler or the
interpreter keeps track of and whenever
data is assigned into that variable that
comes from outside of the application
it's not a constant or anything then
this flag gets marked and and the
variable is considered tainted and then
eventually if a tainted variable ends up
in a sink that you care about such as
you know an executable function string
copy etc then you throw a flag issue
found that he's untrusted data going all
the way down to a sink that's important
so essentially this is this is the flow
it would follow it go from hello into
hello
then n gets so the taint flag copies any
tank that variable they gets us onto and
untainted variable the tank flag carries
over and we see in the end we end up at
the string copy right so having sort of
thought about the the different I guess
tools and techniques required skills
there's a bunch of different approaches
so there's like what hotspot checking
which is basically using grep for a
keyword and then sort of based on
whatever you find there you start
working your way up or down to code this
control flow sensitive where it's
basically you're you're following
certain functions and you only say you
can either follow every function into
the function and then back out and you
you know you read the code the way would
execute and you can maybe optimize that
by only following the functions that
they were use is applied data there's
also data flow sensitive so rather than
worrying about the code where it
executes it's tracking the data so say
you know this page insert saying in the
database this page extracts it out of
the database and then you sit in a query
again and the flow of those new pages
are separate but if you track the user
data in and out of the database you'll
find a potential second order SQL
injection so focus oriented tends to be
just looking at the application and you
go I'm gonna look at like this library
and I'm only gonna worry about any
function calls to this library I'm gonna
read the library top to bottom bottom to
top whatever and I'm only going to worry
about that so typical examples where we
see that it seems like authentication
authorization frameworks you know
they're good targets you get a brand new
application like the first thing I'm
looking at I'm gonna look at
authorization authentication password
reset all those things forward and
backward tracing is basically what it
says you start at a certain point in the
code and you read it down or in the case
of hot spot checking typically you'll
you'll find a random line of code in a
file and you start going to work your
way backwards like where did the data
come from to into this this line of code
that we're concerned
so that's reading the code and of course
we said we have to know about
vulnerabilities so essentially we say
that a vulnerability is a weakness that
can lead to unexpected undesirable event
compromising the security of the system
network bla bla bla it's a bit like
quality we know it when we see it so
this a couple of I guess main schools of
vulnerability classifications there are
others but hopefully you all know these
ones always picked up ten they're sort
of siloed there's like top ten for
mobile top ten for web top ten for
whatever and then the cwe they they more
try to index the entire thing neither of
them are completely complete coverage
neither of them have necessarily you
know always up-to-date definitions there
there's a bunch of other ones if you
want to learn about vulnerabilities
these aren't a bad place to start
read you know CW have examples for most
of the ones they've classified but also
you know go to conferences I mean you're
all here white papers a good advisory
will often showcase the flow of the code
through the application and and you know
what led to the vulnerability so yep so
how do you go about identifying a
weakness in a new product or a sort of
source code if you come through
documentation that's a great place to
start a lot of time I find specifically
designed weaknesses I'll read the
documentation I go like that doesn't add
up you know like you're trusting the
user to supply the the amount that
they're paying for the thing that
they're buying now that's that's not
okay obviously recognizing weakness
patterns and source code you know like
user supplied input being concatenated
in an SQL statement that one's pretty
obvious but you know you sort of once
you read a lot of code I guess you you
you'll learn a lot of bad habits that
developers tend to have same thing if
you're looking at
API you can even look look at the
swagger Falls then you might be able to
spot like a pattern you know direct
object reference this is often come to
mind there's a function that returns
some sensitive data and it takes a
number and you're looking yeah I think I
think that might be you think anticipate
poor decision-making that ones sometimes
easy sometimes and if whenever you come
across something that you don't know say
you're reading a language you're not
super familiar with like Java when
you're a PHP dev or you know vice versa
just write a short script and you're
saying well if this value was that this
value is that and they're calling the
function this way can I write like a
two-three line script and see whether or
not my assumption about that being
correct should have lived a
vulnerability is it going to do the
unexpected thing or it said actually
handling it correctly on the on the
function call so and also a peg breaks
from complex or difficult code you know
go have a shower if you Travis or Mandi
it seems to work pretty well so I
generally classify problems in source
code as one out of two core problems
it's either the presence of something so
you've written in insecure things you've
added you know hard-coded credentials
things that generally shouldn't be there
you know a double free format string and
then there's the other part which is the
absence of something right there's an
absence of a negation or authorization
check at this function there is lack of
encoding use of supplied output and a
lot of people might say don't know but
exercise is also you know validating
input but not so much it's mostly
encoding output particularly once you
get to the stage where you're dealing
with unicode strings at the moment I'm
working in the Middle East so we always
have to validate at least two languages
English and Arabic and you know it's a
lot easier to just handily handle
encoding securely at the time that you
need to be encoded you know input
validation it's nice to have you know if
you can do both do both but
but I consider that the absence of
something rather than you know you're
not encoding you could argue that one
way or the other but yeah all right so
now that we know a bit about
vulnerabilities you know we know how to
read some source code you know how do we
actually go about auditing yeah it
basically is a three-step process right
it's kind like how you draw the old owl
you know draw a circle draw the rest of
the out let's see see so you'd enter by
weakness however you do that through
source code reading documentation
whatever I tend to prioritize high
vulnerability or high impact vulnerable
its first always look for you know
remote code execution authentication
bypass ideally together and then once
you're there you get a check
exploitability because a lot of times
you might jump conclusion and think that
ah this thing you know this particular
function doesn't encode this correctly
and then turns out yeah you're a bit
premature so always check that you can
actually exploit it before you you go
and shut about your your latest
vulnerability now so beyond reading the
code manually static source code
analysis tool there's a bunch of them
they all function mostly the same it's
paint analysis abstract syntax notation
you know keywords like grep honestly a
lot of you guys here would have seen
sílvio livestream you know it's it's
been it's crap and a UNIX shell and very
much the same but we ordered different
different parts of the infinite
ecosystem but yeah I really rely on grep
for everything because it's it's fast
it's very versatile you know let's
research things and once you get
familiar with the tool you can do a lot
with it it's also important to remember
the tools can't find some types of
vulnerabilities such as usually the
absence of things is very hard for tool
to identify you know the absence of an
authentication check you know or in the
case of default insecurity fault values
being assigned to say an integer or a
string or anything like that the tools
generally won't find
human analysis is always required for
every type of source code review so if
you don't like grep you know say you're
on Windows you know Windows Linux
subsets then we'll get you grep but some
people like a core some people like a G
Silver Surfer because it doesn't scan
things like subversion directories to
get directories once you're familiar
with grep you can tell grep not to do
those things as well so but each through
the wrong there's more than one way to
do things right but let me just tell you
a bit more about grep because I really
like crap alright
the benefit is a lot of the static
source code analysis tool requires the
ability to compile the code before they
will analyze it so they operate on the
bytecode intermediate language rather
than the source code itself so if you're
given incomplete code if you're you know
reviewing just the partial patch or add
if those tools won't work but grep will
work on anything that a human can read
so that's good it works across platform
you know Linux UNIX PSD Windows it's all
there and you know most programming
languages are based on text sort of
English word your language like syntax
and then grep is very good at matching
text so that's that's a benefit which
means that you can very quickly like add
a whole set of syntax support for custom
languages like smarty templates if you
wanted to write a hold as a rule set for
reviewing smarty templates you want for
necessarily fund a static tool that does
it but grep can do it and it will
probably take you half an hour an hour
to just sit down and go through the
syntax tree write out a whole bunch of
keywords and now you can audit smarter
templates it's really quick really easy
and then of course that's a starting
point and you build on it from there
whichever way you go but and it usually
and this is important to me it may not
be important to you but I always find
that I want to see the source code that
grep thinks is that font something
important on and I want to see the line
surrounded I want to
give it some context I don't want to
report where they don't have to open and
read and then go searching for the fall
and then fund the line and then read the
code I'd rather just get the code use to
it straight away so yep that's a bit
about grep so here's an example mem said
it's a type of under ability that's
being introduced by compiler options
basically you're trying to zero out a
region of memory and if you're if you're
running this with the right compiler
options the compiler basically goes this
is a null rewrite I'll just optimize
that out
no need so if you're trying to unset
some sensitive memory but might contain
a password or a private key and you're
trying to use their just straight-up
memset zero there's a good chance that
it does not actually get zeroed out of
memory and that the sensitive details
are still there so here's two very
simple regular expressions that find it
but it's not guaranteed to be
exploitable even though you you know a
lots of fun memory initialization and a
lot of the mem sets that try to see
right data it's not dealing with
sensitive data at all so you probably
have to wade through a lot of options or
a lot of lines of code for this but you
know it's really simple it's like he's
two regular expressions and now we can
go and audit this code base for a
specific table vulnerability let's say
that you want to audit a whole bunch of
WordPress plugins similar thing you go
through your CI here's all the function
calls you see we started the top ones
are really simple and then I've sort of
12 in two more optimized regular
expressions because I can't help myself
I really don't want to get all the false
positives so if we can sort of shave
that down a bit
that's really beneficial so of course
what I use to shave this down is regular
expressions um I'm a I'm an old-school
Perl programmer so I really love regular
expressions I guess you know there's
certainly useful you got a year to know
their limitations
you know don't parse HTML with regular
expressions ever but the way sort of
grep rule sets work is at the simplest
form you just write a list in it
editor of keywords like require now okay
that's gonna find every require
statement and most of those are
hard-coded fall parts that's not very
useful so why don't we do any require
that deals with you know a variable and
we do that by sticking the dollar sign
in there now that's better but again a
lot of the variables are static we don't
want that either also this this other
function require once we want to check
not just for require we one both so we
can combine them and then at the end we
have limited down to be synthetics
ambiguous you know a developer might put
a space between the require and the the
parentheses I mean some do that and then
we also make sure that the only
variables we care about is the use of
supplied ones that come in through get
post repress the environment cookie etc
there might be attacking controllable or
influenceable and and at that point
we've eliminated a lot of the false
positives well literally if you find
anything with that like last rule that
should literally be exploitable you know
to straight-up local or remote file
include ninety-nine percent of the time
so but you know that's just that's just
like hotspot checking that's not very
cool what about like taint analysis
right you can trace through the code
that's fine we can use script to do that
we take the output of grep and then we
message it's for Perl and regular
expressions and then we feed it back
into grep as a rule set so it's great to
grab two more and you know you you
actually get tenth analysis
this one's been public for a while but
it's just this is a very basic example
but you know it's it's almost the almost
entire script is its comments and
version and user friendliness and then
at the bottom there is four lines of
code that actually does all the work and
now it could obviously be written as a
single line so trying to keep it you
know readable but let's say you also
wanted something that you haven't found
anything else for let's say that you
were doing research on D civilization
vulnerabilities in PHP and you wanted a
quick way to see
all the classes that can be deserialized
through a wake-up of the instructor and
an auto load function now you can add to
this right this the two string and
whatever you can just expand on it but I
generally find that these three are the
ones I care about and then I do this
magic trick where I actually parameter
inject past grodan into graph itself on
the third line there to make sure that I
want to see the next 20 line so after
every every function definition and then
I pipe that back into Gaudet to look for
potential PHP functions that we might
care about so you know it's going to
give you a lot of information but it's
going to highlight the bits that are
important so any like wake up destructor
autoload that tries to load a file email
a file do a system call anything like
that it'll show up so you know yeah you
whip this up in two minutes and then
you're off to the races so this is why I
love grep it's just it's really simple
to just go I should have something to
automate this and then five minutes
later I have and it might be noisy but
when you only use it ever so often that
that noise trade office is usually
manageable so alright don't know how
we're doing for time hopefully I think
we're gonna finish pretty early all
right so so what I did for this I went
and I downloaded eighty repositories of
github this is 1.3 gigabyte of source
code and you might think that might take
a little bit of time to scan right
granted it's on this laptop here it's an
SSD it's not that much Ram I can't
estimate if five to ten minutes
code time but it actually ran in six
seconds right so that's that's grep
running about 50 I think regular
expression rules an entire code base a
text six seconds not tagged analysis
it's a little bit more cost intensive
they took 15 seconds to paint analysis
string copy
only string copy calls throughout the
entire code base for any file ending in
the dot C extension so it's really quick
in fact usually I pipe it through more
and I started reading it and even if it
was a significantly slower even if it
took ten minutes it'll still execute
faster than I can read the code so it's
pretty easy so I'm actually the
bottleneck here you know improving
processing time for humans first of all
we want to avoid false positives and
I've sort of explained I do this by
limiting the regular expressions to like
the very stupid vulnerabilities when
someone takes direct user input puts it
directly in a require statement directly
in an SQL statement you know the really
really simple should not occur from any
developer kind of mistakes they're the
one we're gonna catch and then we might
miss some where you know the user input
gets supplied to another variable and
then that gets used in the SQL statement
all right that's one we can come back
and do the tanked analysis on the second
run first we just want to get like a
couple of starting points start reading
the code get familiar with the code base
so it's okay if ayran Ischl you know
just stumbling through it it's rough and
quick because I don't expect you to only
do this one step if you remember back to
when I spoke about the approaches you
had hot spot hot spot checking forward
backwards tracing focus ideally you
should apply multiple of those whenever
you're reviewing a code base because
they're all good at identifying
different problems if you want to find
deep vulnerabilities in in a code base
the stuff that might have lived there
for fourteen to twenty years you have to
read the code you have to get very
familiar with the code you have to
understand it and you have to look in
sort of the the weed nooks and crannies
or often how things integrate together
you're not going to find that stuff
would grep and so all right and I also
only look for certain vulnerability
classes like I'm here if you order it
1.3 gigabytes of PHP scripts you're
gonna drown in XSS if you allow any type
of exercise to
show up in your results you'll be there
for a long time so I basically narrowed
down to sort of remote code execution or
higher critical vulnerabilities so code
execution SQL injection and then just
run that through and then of course I
can come back and only look for xsf if I
want and of course you know the text
rules and if I find that this one
framework and the one app I'm looking at
rather than using the standard database
query interface they've written a custom
one I can just go into my text files
update the function name or add an
additional function name and then I'll
try to rerun it and I'll trap all of the
the custom developer bad habits so it
comes back to I like it it's versatile
it's fast so when I'm running broad it
there's usually a couple of things that
I gotta look at to try to help me make a
decision as to whether or not I should
stop reading the hotspot checking and
start looking at the code and go reading
the code or if I should just make a note
of it and come back later so the first
one is obviously the file name you know
it's a sensitive filename or something
that I think you know should be a
publicly accessible index.php that's
something that's usually publicly
accessible and I might not have to find
an authentication bypass to prove that
there's a remote color code execution
here the other thing I look at is the
line the line number so you generally
find that the higher up in a farm a
vulnerability of course the easier it is
for your exploit or your for something
to reach that code path if it's on line
8,000 something of something that is in
the class file there is probably a lot
of if statements before you get to that
point and you know a lot of those
statements may neutralize the potential
vulnerability and then of course I look
at the entire length and I say you know
how many vulnerabilities or potential
vulnerabilities am i seeing in this one
file so if there's one file like a
library that appears very full of owner
abilities that's probably a very good
starting point
and then of course the last one but it's
probably the
I actually check first it's the actual
code view now you can see it's
highlighted and this one man fortunately
this one has to cross that scripting in
there but obviously the one that my eye
is drawn to is the potential disasterous
remote fall include there and I can't
say that this particular bug was patched
a while back but so he's won this one
everyone here everyone everyone here can
take this one go home
run a single correct over any PHP base
code base if you don't use PHP you can
change the the curl options to something
else but this basically looks for any
deliberate disabling of certificate
validation within the source code and
that's something you can get a severe
for it's not a very exciting bug but
it'll get you see ve
hey you don't even have to use UNIX and
grep you can just go and github and
search alright there's a couple of
couple sitting right there and then of
course I ran on my code base and sure
enough there are plenty of them here
some of these are like PayPal shopping
carts and stuff that should absolutely
not ignore SSL validation but you know
turns out there's actually good reason
the historical reason for this and goes
back to I think it's 2003 where PHP on
Windows would crash if you tried to do
certificate validation so all the old or
none of those crashes just fail the
validation regardless so all the
old-school PHP developers have learned
this habit of automatically disabling it
because that way the code will run yeah
ship it worried about security later all
right
SQL injection again very simple if
you're not regular expressions a little
bit you should be able to read this you
can probably read it anyway so looking
for a query with anything that's used is
applied looking for the key words select
with anything that's use of supplied
followed by from or select from followed
by use is applied or being used
in the matching the right hand matching
portion of a wet cloth and then the that
and and or statement there it's a little
bit noisy so I had to add the quote
single or double quotes in front because
it's meant to match it's meant to match
multi-line statements and so if I run
that across a card base there's a bunch
of ceará decidir I'll hopefully you can
read that at the back this one is in a
yeah clicky CMS here's a bunch more GLP
I that's inventory and the ITIL style
management software there might be some
users here sentry on
it's another inventory management system
for you know taking care of you Nagios
config in your systems this thing is
very full of it at least the last two
they're all authenticated injections so
it's a little bit less important but
alright cross-site scripting any output
that directly echoes back used uh
supplied input or in the case of PHP
self and PHP self is a tricky one
because the webserver would have to be
configured with as a query in query get
options query I don't remember there
there's a there's a toggle in web
service that allows you to append data
in sort of a folder format after the
index.php script and if you have that
enabled then PHP self is vulnerable to
cross-site scripting by default so here
this one's nag Yoast dashboard it's got
a vulnerability and mumble server for
like the there's like a teamspeak thing
again the mumble server that one is
dependent obviously on the config the
other one is straight-up cookie value
here's a bunch in Libre NMS we see that
these guys I think this one's one of us
I don't know what was going on here so
there's a there's a couple of cases
where it's just like straight up just
going out user-supplied it data that's
not very good but in the same files it's
also HTML encoding some of the data and
then directly under the HTML encoded
that I ghost we've got a MySQL real
escape this starter which is obviously
that's good if you put it in a database
but it's not so great when you're doing
HTML output so you kind of think that
whoever added that initial HTML special
characters should have fixed all of them
but I don't know and I see that a lot
where it's like I we fixed it in two out
of three places unsafe to civilization
again this one is a little bit sort of
tricky nothing go back same thing
looking for the really silly stuff stuff
just an serialize with user supplied
data ran that over found a bunch of them
but of course not all of these are yes
all of these are doing unsafety
civilization but not all of them will
lead to code execution you generally
require a library that you can leverage
so if we go back to slide 37 I had a
quick script to look for these these
ones and we'll find that for the PHP
ipam one that was actually in the in the
pair next to DNS client the the caching
component will let you write arbitrary
contents to arbitrary files so that
that's very handy the other ones that's
not a direct digital accession so you'd
have to rely on a global PHP thing like
a fire filed a civil accession or
standard library deserialization but
again the file where you're finding the
unsafe to civilization it would actually
have to have it would have to consume
the the library that you're trying to
inject through you can of course also
attempt things like memory corruption
through this realization so overall it
shouldn't be there but exploitation is
a little less straightforward and
finally we're gonna talk about buffer
overflows and I would generally say that
greatests not so great at finding
vulnerabilities and see very fast it's
much better at languages that have
variable sigils so like PHP the
variables are the cleared with a with
the dollar sign in front you'll find
that in some languages and crap is very
very good for those because you can just
add that dollar sign in your regular
expressions to make sure that we only
care about information that deals with
variables we don't you know where it's
in C it's hard to tell a custom function
name from a variable name when you just
searching it with text search so this is
a variation on that tank analysis that
we had for for PHP but this one
basically just goes float through and
look for a string catch drink coffee and
s printf as well as a character
definition of a buffer so you put all of
that together and in the code base I
have here this is open Lightspeed web
server I got a couple of couple of
vulnerabilities here
I'll lock this one in particular the top
lines there the developer has an assert
that makes sure that the max length
being supplied is more than 255 when it
puts it in a buffer that's defined as
256 and then and then it doesn't
actually utilize the max length variable
at all it just starts copying the data
into the buffer very handy I don't know
what was going on there similarly they
have this other section of the code
where again there's a comment right
above there that says nah we should we
should check the length of the path but
then that's just been commented out and
like the line below I guess we'll take
that comment we'll take that path out of
the configure we just slap it in the
buffer
it'll be fine yeah and don't worry
particularly you can say that maybe in
this case the developer has
my mistake because they think that you
know maybe you'd want to be a fall name
and unless you custom can partly a Linux
kernel the files should only be that
length so it should be safe but things
like siblings can exceed that that
variable length so yeah you need to have
that systems knowledge to go with it so
that's that's all the all the demos all
the O'Day hopefully I'll have time to
report it to the vendor before somebody
else takes credit and so in conclusion
you know bond durability discovery
doesn't have to be advanced you can just
go out search github for curl verify SSL
and and you're gonna find some under
abilities sometimes the vulnerabilities
are very hard to identify I mean we've
seen that time and time again they live
in the code base for a decade and nobody
finds them again source code review if
you have a very dynamic application
source code review might not be the best
approach and of course finding a be so
vulnerable code it's only the start of
the journey you don't have to prove that
it is vulnerable you don't have to deal
with the vendor you know release an
adversary get a patch out and you know
hopefully everyone stays safe and secure
so that's it
any questions
we can take a couple of questions if
there any in the audience now this is
someone that their whereabout max
fitness Thais here we've got a runner
coming over
I should probably rub myself yeah I just
want to say thanks for making Gaea order
I use a nearly daily and it helps me
speed up my workflow insane we like it
speeds me up so taking two three hours
look through some things it takes 5-10
minutes to get some quick wins so just
once a thanks thank you for myself and
if anyone else gets use out of it that's
great
[Music]
there's people questions any other
questions no one here one in the front
that's it definitely baby you come
anyway so about that so what happens if
a vendor isn't as responsive or what
interested in fixing something well if
the vendor doesn't fix it I mean
everyone I generally say that whoever
finds the bug can't ask the right to
choose how they want to disclose it not
disclose it whatever if your company has
a disclosure policy you should probably
follow that and that should probably
define what you do when a vendor isn't
responsive but overall the standard
industry practice seems to be try to
notify them a second maybe a third time
and then just release it for the
Internet to deal with okay let's think
I'll go one more time for a great talk
you