but for now we have Martin fron who's
going to give a talk on the fresh smell
of rants and copies so can we please
welcome Martin to the stage thank you
welcome everybody to my talk this is the
last talk of a day it has been a long
day so I'm here to entertain you a bit
and what could be more entertaining than
a live demo that could possibly fail
right so let's dive into the
presentation so Who am I actually I work
as a security researcher at security
vendor Avast and to be honest this talk
is not my area of expertise it's more
like a personal story because I love
coffee you probably seen this that's
exactly the moment when you want to cry
right this is a run somewhere and it's a
well-known and big strain or run
somewhere called wanna cry and you you
can easily spot what's wrong with your
computer right because if you see this
you are doomed but what about devices
that doesn't have any screen or keyboard
like IOT devices there is a running joke
that the s in IOT stands for security
and we will dive more into how bad the
situation is right so as I said I'm a
coffee addict I love coffee so let me
ask you a question how many of you like
coffee okay how many of you can't live
without the coffee we are developers
right most of us IT persons
okay so what do you think what happens
when you deny a developer a decent cup
of coffee this could happen right
it could be it could be a crisis for the
whole industry right what what about
like developers without coffee that's
gonna be disaster so that was the
initial impulse because I'm like I can't
live without the coffee so my idea was
let's research on coffee makers
particularly on smart coffee makers
because these devices are connected to
the Internet to our Wi-Fi networks and
unfortunately it's quite easy to misuse
them and I pick this one
it's called small coffee maker and the
smart functionality here is basically
just to be able to control the coffee
maker using your mobile application so
you have your coffee already in the
kitchen before you get out of a bed
that's as simple as it is it's a really
simple device it has like four buttons
small display nothing really fancy on a
technical side it when you take the
device out of a box it creates its own
Wi-Fi network for setup which is called
smarter coffee
xx and these two X stand for the last
byte of the MAC address so that's kind
of a unique identification of the Wi-Fi
for set up it listens on the porch TCP
to old a1 that's the only port which is
open and it uses a very simple binary
protocol we don't know how Turing
authentication no authorization
whatsoever so I was quite curious like
what can you do
even without like connecting the coffee
maker into your own network because
that's the purpose of this set up
network right and it turned out that you
can do anything it comes with the
company application as a set for iOS for
Android as well
and it's pretty simple you can prepare
your own formula for a coffee like the
strength number
of cups and you can brew the coffee from
the application so that's as simple as
as it looks like in terms of a protocol
this protocol has been already
documented on the Internet to do some
extent and it's really really simple so
the whole protocol cons is basically a
few bytes the first byte is a comment
then followed by n bytes depending on
the comment and then there is like a
terminator which is 7 a hex always the
response is very simple as well so the
response basically starts with the
response type then followed by and data
and bytes of data again and a terminator
so in case the response type is a just a
neck or acknowledgment response the
response type is always 3 so that's the
whole protocol as I said it has been
documented on the internet so you can
find for example this comment which one
sent to a coffee maker it brews you a
nice cup of coffee with the default
settings of the coffee maker so just
this 2 bytes to port 20 81 there is also
one comment where specific moment which
is like documented truth only some
extent and this command is 6d what it
does it turns the coffeemaker into an
update mode and it looks like this so
once you send this command the
coffeemaker switches itself into a
update mode and waits for another
comments it turned out that all the
documented comments didn't work in this
mode and I was quite a puzzled what's
like what's going on what's how how
should I proceed to to get to know how
the update process works so I try to use
the application because the application
is able to update a firmware or the on
the coffeemaker the problem with the
application or with my coffeemaker was
that the firmware was up-to-date so that
that wasn't the way to go but something
has changed
when the coffee maker is an update mode
it changes its Wi-Fi network into
smarter coffee update xx again exact
stands for last byte of the MAC address
so I've tried everything the only open
port again is 2081 I tried everything to
connect the coffee makers and all the
commands to fast the protocol nothing
basically worked so how you should
approach such a situation there are
actually the easiest way is to get the
firmware because by reverse engineering
the firmware you can get the three C's
what's a description of the protocol and
exactly how it works so how can you get
the firmware there are again several
options one pretty obvious google it
that didn't work in this case there is
no firmware for this coffee maker on the
internet you can snip the traffic
between the company application and the
coffee maker that didn't work as well
because the coffeemaker was up to date
next option is to dismount the device
and download the firmware directly from
the CPU or from the chip that's kind of
a tedious process and I would like to
avoid that so the last option is to
reverse the company application itself
and because it's Android and it's an MP
apk it's pretty easy to do so and it
turns out when you open the application
itself it has two very interesting files
in it in its assets it has like binary
file
kofi dirt bin and binary file cattle dog
bin it's turned out that these are
basically a firmware images for all two
products that the company does which is
so smart coffee maker and a smart kettle
so when you open the file
it's obviously obviously an unencrypted
anybody knows what these strings are so
our typical 8080 common so used for
modems
in this particular case it's a it's
basically common strings or these are
common strings for for esp8266 chip
which is the Wi-Fi modem which is
probably or at this time I really don't
know what what's inside which is
probably inside the coffee maker I guess
most of you know the esp8266 if you are
tinkering with the IOT is the most
common Wi-Fi modem okay so I the
compiled the company and application
which basically proved my point that the
update process is same for both products
and it only depends on a on a type of
the device that's being read from from
the device itself so it serves either
the binary coffee that being or binary
file capital or been depending on a type
of a device so let's have a look into a
binary file coffee road bin like if you
have a firmware image you need like the
next step is probably to get to know
what architecture is it intended for
again you have several options you can
you can guess you can use some auto
detection features for example for
either pro but for me because I like to
dismount devices and eventually putting
them together I dismounted a coffee
maker that was the easiest option for me
so this is the whole coffee maker
basically this is the whole logic of the
coffee maker you can see there the
esp8266 chip which is the modem and
after a while I basically identified
like four main components on the board
the one is as I said esp8266 then the
second the number two is basically ARM
Cortex and 0 which turned out it's a
brain of the whole coffee maker and it's
kind of a funny because this chip has
like 64 kilobytes of memory and
comparing to es pH 266 it's way less
powerful it's like 10 times or 12 times
less powerful than number actual Wi-Fi
modem
but that's how it works there are also
like four debug pins or debug headers
with the ports used for programming and
also for communication with the modem so
you can basically using these pins you
can tap into the communication between
the modem and the main CPU ok so the
next logical step is to get a data sheet
for a CPU that's how it works right and
because I already knew what type of CPU
is inside I was able to to load the file
into either and started to decompiling
or reverse-engineering the whole thing
usually the easiest way how to reverse
engineer some firmware is start with the
strings because that gives you a pretty
good clue what what these strings are
used for and by referencing them to a
code which uses them you can pretty fast
get to main functions and it turned out
this is probably the most complex and
the main function of the whole
coffeemaker it's a big switch and that
switch is basically the whole handler
for all the commands that the
coffeemaker is able to to run by
proceeding further this is basically
just like close up of this function so
you can see there are like already known
comments for example 6d and I'm not sure
if this is the 6d comment which is
basically the star of the update ok so
let's fast forward a bit after 5 days I
bet I was basically able to to reverse
engineer the whole firmware and get all
the main functions like it's easy
because the firmware itself is like 49
kilobytes so it's pretty small it's
really dumb device there is no no fancy
OS nothing like this
and I came up with this architecture or
diagram of the coffee maker so you can
see it's pretty simple
very few detectors basically wired into
into the i/o pins of the CPU directly
which is like missing carafe detector so
when you when you take out the carafe
the coffeemaker basically doesn't allow
you to coffee then there is a grinder
motor heating element hotbed like it's
pretty simple control buttons the the
only interesting part would be a coffee
flap which is basically the flat between
the grinder and the filter which opens
at the moment when when the coffee is
ground so I'm three what are a lot of
sensors if you if you look at the base
picture you can see there is no security
measure in hardware so everything every
security measure in this coffee maker is
in software so once you change the
firmware once you patch the firmware you
can potentially create a really
dangerous machine which overheats
which runs the grinder forever for
example which basically runs the coffee
forever right after a while after
reversing the component application I
was also able to identify the exact
process of the update and it turned out
it's very simple again no authorization
no authentication no signature the only
thing is the CRC at the end so it works
basically like this so once you switch
the coffeemaker in to update mode it
changes the Wi-Fi network waits for a
start of the update and then
block-by-block each of size two five six
bytes
basically it uploads the new firmware
into a coffee maker following by CRC and
the command which which signal to a
coffee maker that that's the end of
update so it's pretty simple so if
you have the knowledge about how the
coffeemaker works how the update process
takes place the easiest and next logical
step is to try to update the firmware
right so this is the first attempt I
made updating the firmware ok
to be honest I've cheated in this case
because I've only replaced the image
which says that there is no carafe
because there is no carafe but and it
also turned out that there is no font in
a coffee maker so everything you see
it's an image so there is like there are
like 12 images 4 cups start medium beans
everything is basically just the image
so it's pretty easy easy to tinker with
that ok so the next logical step is to
create something more complex right so
I've created a payroll because it turns
out there is no space at the end of the
firmware which is freely available and
could be used so I replace the original
handler for a join to Wi-Fi comment
which is kind of you know like
interesting so you you basically create
a malicious payload that activates on a
try of the user to join the coffeemaker
into his or her Network ok so that's a
time for a demo fingers crossed and I
will show you what I've created in five
days
so if everything works you can see the
display of the coffee maker here so
that's my hand and let's upload the
payload I know if you can see the
terminal is it readable so I've made a
little application for that because
that's the tedious process okay I need
so the first stage is to switch the
coffee maker into a update mode which is
basically by sending to these two bytes
ok that was pretty quick so now the
coffeemaker is in update mode but Wi-Fi
changed and it right likes comment so
the next logical step is to upload the
payload and the modified firmware
and sometimes take a while depending on
the Wi-Fi
okay so that that's exactly the case if
something goes wrong there we go
update completed it should restart
automatically as you seen there is no
interaction from the user
needed so everything was just automatic
Ottoman so now the coffeemaker is tears
itself and it contains the malicious
payload so the third stage which I have
here as a setting on fire is basically
to run the command or to send the
command to a coffeemaker to join to a
Wi-Fi and this is the outcome again
thanks a while because it needs to
change the Wi-Fi network again it needs
to connect to the Wi-Fi okay
and this is how it works and
if you if you wait a while it gets mad I
think it's like 10 repetition of these
two images so what what it's now doing
is heating up the element but because
there is no water you can't see it and
now it runs the grinder and runs the
Grider for forever basically so you
can't use your coffeemaker anymore and
so
smells good
so the only thing I can do is unplug the
coffeemaker and the other thing is that
you can even change the comment or
overwrite or patch the comment that
basically says update so in that case
you break the device and unless someone
like take it apart and replace the
firmware using the debug port or the
programming port it won't work anymore
okay so that went pretty smooth actually
this is in case the demo won't work and
I can like quickly show you
oops that wasn't what I wanted to show
you okay - that was too easy right come
on show me okay let's fast-forward to
the part which is here
let's hope it's going to work if I fast
forward it has a nice steam effect when
the water starts dripping through the
coffeemaker without the car off so it's
just to entertain you even more okay so
this is just another case okay so let's
discuss the attack vector how you can
misuse this actually this device I don't
know if you recognize that if if you
have a kids and even the Lego Mindstorms
that's a smart brick which basically
powers the whole way go I was able to
create this version of uploader into
that brick so you can easily visit your
neighbor who who has this coffee maker
so obvious there are like few versions
of attack vectors so the first one is
many in the middle attack because in the
new firmware they actually edit a
functionality that needs the user to
press update I'm a coffee maker but if
you think about it because there is no
authorization authentication the open
the Wi-Fi is basically opened it's
pretty easy to do am an intimate man in
the middle attack and to make the
application belief that the coffeemaker
really needs an update and in that case
the user will happily press update the
coffeemaker and also press the update on
the coffee maker itself so that's one
possibility
obviously the proximity proximity attack
so you can as I said you can be like
passing by your neighbor or a company
because this device is also or these
devices you can find these devices also
in companies and that one which I want
to show you is a social engineering
attack that's my favorite one because it
does
any special equipment and then obviously
you can for example sniff the SSID and
the password for the network that the
coffeemaker is being connected to and
the social engineering attack is pretty
simple just send the packet which starts
the update on the coffeemaker and the
prompt spells to a user that the
coffeemaker needs an update and
basically ask them to to either either
confirm the update by pressing ok or
pressing cancel but I've tried it on my
wife and if you're sending the packet
start update over and over it there is
basically no way how we can cancel
because if you press the cancel it
displays again the update so after some
try or number of tries everybody gave up
and press the update so that's the
simplest social engineering attack you
can do and it turned out also that
probably users don't really need a smart
coffee makers because if you go to Viggo
which is you know like the database or
or map of all Wi-Fi networks around the
globe you can easily find like two
thousand and five hundred coffee makers
with the open Wi-Fi that has that have
been never that never have been set up
so yes the question is if we really need
a smart coffee maker so to conclude my
talk the one problem with most IOT
devices is so-called out of a box
problem so we have a lot of IOT devices
that just works when you when you
basically take them out of a box and
connect them and that's an issue because
for example my personal experience from
the apartment where where I moved to is
that there was a Ethernet socket for
Internet so I've connected my laptop and
because I'm curious
I was curious what's what's behind the
walls
I've connected to my default gateway and
it's turned out that my default gateway
asked me to set up the password for the
first time and that's a problem that's a
problem like these IOT devices like we
we've exchanged the convenience for
security that's a really big issue so we
should we should really make these
devices
you know parable until you properly
setup them firmware is no longer firm
but it I think this the statement is
valid for for some time all right and
the other thing is you need to build the
security for the bottom up so if you are
planning to create any IOT device you
should start with the secure OTA update
first because if you have a secure
device on a user level which with the
generated username and password for
example and you have a vulnerable
firmware update process you basically
broke the whole security and the
question at the end is would you really
trust any device today because this
could be a great example of supply chain
attack using IOT devices we've seen this
today using a software using a
repositories but the same thing could be
achieved by IOT devices and the problem
is bigger because nobody really knows
what's inside the device ok so this talk
is Memoriam of this device which I
unintentionally bricked and shortly
after this talk when I get my cup of
coffee and some rest I will upload all
the software you've seen and all the
documentation for the coffee maker to
this github repository so if you want to
download it just in the QR code okay
that's it
I don't know if we have a time for any
bonus or Q&A we can take one or two
questions yep
do we have a mic right up high it looked
like the other ASP pins we sold it in
did they go anywhere sorry so the ESP
chip that was soldered onto the
motherboard it looked like that was
being well more than just the serial
pins were sold into something did they
actually go anywhere on the traces or
were they just yes basically from the
esp8266 the pins that had been used were
TX Eric so basically rs-232
communication pins and and the power
that was that's basically it and you can
you can even like there is a
functionality inside the ARM Cortex and
0 which allows you to even update the
firmware on the esp8266 but it this goes
like through the vendor update process
like the vendor of the asph 266 and it's
like known to be pretty secure in this
case question over there as well
have you been to own a coffee yet in
Canberra is actually very good coffee I
like it very much okay I need to get
some coffee really and some sleep
are there any other questions one behind
the camera over there yeah
actually I can show you a little bit of
spoiler this is my upcoming project
hello yes yes perhaps one of the vendor
responses to these convenience versus
security thing is to now provide pseudo
secure cloud services whereby your iot
will connect to a vendor supported cloud
surface and then you login to that by
your phone up how do you see this is a
compromise between security and control
of the device as well as convenience for
the operator user it always depends what
protocol they use because that like in
IOT world is the problem here is that
many vendors are using like you know
like obscure protocols it's like the
security by obscurity
you don't really know what's inside and
they they are basically relying on the
fact that if it's unknown and obscure
nobody will like dive into that because
nobody understands that protocol and
sometimes it it turns out that the
protocol is basically a plaintext just
you know put into a nice nice series of
bytes so I think like the communication
with with cloud is not kind of a proof
that the setup is secure for example
there are light bulbs that are connected
to a cloud and the only identification
that they are using when connecting
through your Wi-Fi to to a cloud is
their MAC address so there is no
password no authorization the only thing
the only ID they are using is is the MAC
address and the whole protocol again is
plain text and it's susceptible to a dos
attack because if you connect your
script through the same cloud with the
same identifier it disconnects the
original device because it can handle
only one connection so it I think there
is no guaranteed and when the
configuration is done through a cloud
that it's secure it really depends on
the Wonder and
the implementation may be time for one
more question
will you have one well let's thank
Martin for a great talk thank you