I'm just confirming here i did get word
that not only has the website back up
thank you very much for doing that but
the agenda items for the few agenda
changes have made for this afternoon
looks like they are live so please go
ahead and check the agenda online so you
know what's going on this morning so
right now i want to invite girish up q
ish there we go and something that I
find really interesting to learn about
some advancements in guess internet on
aeroplanes right no excellent thank you
good afternoon so many of us travel very
frequently on airplanes and most of us
traveled on airplanes to get here so
when you're on an airplane you know some
of us sign up for internet access on the
airplane and the speeds and the page
load times page load times tend to be
somewhat slow so what we wanted to do
was to reimagine what a high-speed
connectivity on an airplane would look
like and so we went about building a
system that is going to it's currently
trialing on jetblue and very soon
reunited so what I will talk about today
is some of the ingredients that go into
building such a system so it's pretty
high level that's an overview talk but
if you want to get into the details of
it you can talk to me offline where am i
committing to you
ok
so imagine you were working at home and
you know your dining area to keyboard
and now you've decided to catch a flight
and it wouldn't be nice to be able to
get the same sort of experience that you
were getting at home up in the air right
most of the time people on do this
because you know sign up for internet
service essentially to check emails to
connect to do some work but what if you
could also watch video in addition to
doing skype calls and all these other
sorts of things that you normally do at
home so what you know most most people
you know what it's interesting that the
uptake rate on internet services is
somewhat limited in airplanes for two
reasons one its slow second people have
to pay for it jetblue announced
something called fly fi which is Wi-Fi
on airplanes which provides two things
free and fast internet service only in
the air so what we decided to do is to
offer 12 mega bets to each passenger so
today most planes get probably a t1 type
connection to the plane what if you
could get high speed 12 megabit to each
passenger and so when our during our
trials we're finding that you know
compared to some of the other
experiences that you have today we can
get pages loading 8 to 10 times faster
or sometimes even higher than that and
so there are a lot of things that go
into building such a system and
um I know some of you are familiar with
wide blue the service provider satellite
service provider that you know I've
heard it talked about and compared
against I think a couple of hours ago
there was some comparison about
performance of various ISPs under rain
and so on anyway why is that a brief
overview is a service provider it's also
a communications technology company and
it's also a satellite operator we have a
growing number of satellites that we
either build we have recently recently
launched viasat-1 which one they
guinness world record in terms of the
capacity on the satellite so it takes a
number of things that go into building a
twelve- service to a passenger the first
thing that that needs to happen is you
know you have to go back to some basic
communication theory and um much like
Moore's law there's Shannon's law of
channel information capacity so see
there represents channel capacity it
says channel capacity is directly
proportional to the bandwidth and is
related to logarithmically to the
signal-to-noise ratio you get you can
get so it directly tells you what sort
of lever is you have to push and pull in
order to drive more capacity so this
this random coding bound is is sort of
an upper bound on capacity um and you're
better off trying to drive bandwidth up
because it has a direct ratio as opposed
to a logarithmic ratio of signal noise
ratio so one of the things that we did
was to build really high capacity
lights so if you the the reason why most
most air-to-ground systems don't work
fast is simply because the be the
bandwidth is small it's in the order of
a few megahertz and that's partly
because on the spectrum avail available
at that FCC grants out is in small
chunks because it's highly desirable
spectrum in the lower band so the in the
chart that you see there there are bands
called el band which is typically in the
slightly above cellular coverage in you
know it's typically in your home you
know cordless telephone range and then
you have ka-band which is typically in
the 10 to 14 gigahertz and que ce aku
van and cave and it's somewhere between
20 and 30 years so those higher
frequencies tend to bring with it some
challenges and so the other lower
frequencies tend to be much more
frequently used and with it's simple
economics dictate that you know when
there is more demand the price goes up
and so and as a commodity that that's in
also doled out very you know it's
rationed out by the FCC so when you have
limited bandwidth he will drop
information capacity is going to be
small and so the other aspect of it is
that when you have lots of bandwidth and
you have the the ability to use those
that bandwidth then come in separately
you can drive service prices down so you
know information you know just to kind
of recap as like a capacity is like it's
it's like water being carried through
the pipe the bigger the pipe the more
water you can carry through it so if you
take hey you been you know like your
direct your home
dish or directv type applications they
tend to operate in the Caliban and they
if you plug in chug you know
signal-to-noise ratios the maximum
capacity that you can drive out of those
types of satellites and values like you
know a few tens of megabits per second
so given that you have a you know this
is same problem exists in the cellular
world so on the left is shown k you cut
the yellow spot covers all of the US and
it's a que you banned satellite that
covers all of the US but another way is
to use ka-band and you have spot beams
much like the terrestrial cellular
networks that you find all over so you
know given that you know you got some
bandwidth to play with what else can you
do with it well can you squeeze more
juice out of the lemon you know so can
you get more colors colors allow you to
represent information you know it
different colors allow you to
discriminate between regions so in
mathematics there's this thing called a
four color theorem it says if you have a
map that's divided into regions no more
than four colors are required to color
the regions so that no two adjacent
regions have the same color so that's a
very important thing that's used often
in cellular telephony and also in spot
beam satellites and so what we do is
extract more and more more colors out of
the given bandwidth by using
polarization and polarization is a
little bit think of polarization an easy
way to think about it is you know you
tie a string to the end of
a fixed and fixed point and then you
wiggle the string one way and you have
trying to generate transverse waves
going one way any wiggle with string in
in the orthogonal way and you generate
waves going to a normal way so
electromagnetic waves are somewhat like
that and you can cut you know they can
be used to create colors in adjacent
regions and the other thing that you can
do is if you have a lot of spectrum you
can carve out channels and then add
colors that way so so those are the ways
in which you can get more on capacity
essentially driving up the be in
shannon's or Shannon Hartley theorem and
so that's what we do with our with our
with our network the other challenge is
coverage and typically satellite
operators tend to make a trade between
one of two dimensions they you know it's
it's either coverage or capacity and so
with this new class of satellites what
we have done you know so on the on on on
your right you'll see sort of the
traditional clustering of satellites
that have more or less chosen coverage
over capacity and with the new class of
satellites you know it's called
high-throughput satellites we're trying
to drive more capacity and with the new
generation of satellites that we just
announced it there's also we're driving
to higher coverage areas as well and on
the top right side you'll see on pretty
amazing coverage that you'll see across
on the Atlantic and what that means is
you can get when you're flying from from
u.s. to Europe you can get very
high-speed connectivity across the
Atlantic as well so yeah so the program
that were trialing out now is for large
large body aircraft primarily jetblue
and united continental fleet of the
United and it will be available on the
83 2737 757 and Embraer jets totals
about 400 aircraft and we're providing
all the air time services on it so let's
get into the little bit into the
technical components that comprise the
service so on the on your right on
you'll see on the antenna and a you know
a yellow box that sits inside the cabin
now the antenna sits on a raid own it's
like a little a little bump it's about
um about yay big on that sits on top
there's a little fitting on top of the
aircraft and the antenna sits inside on
and there or is a power supply there is
an internal control unit and so on and
and then it talks to the satellite it's
able to receive and transmit on from a
from the from the antenna there on the
on your left side you'll see sort of a
big antenna and you'll see something
called an smt SN modulator it's a very
very simplified diagram of all of the
components that go into the hub and I'll
get into that in the next few slides but
suffice it to say that base station you
know it's similar to a cellular
telephony network and the base stations
basically back all the traffic into or
the run you know
the ran traffic into a and evolve packet
core and from the core you get an access
to the internet so i was talking briefly
about the antenna the it shown in the
picture is the antenna on your right in
the middle is a modem that's able to
transmit and receive and a power supply
in it so those are the three sort of
line replaceable units and then there is
next to the antenna something called an
internal control unit so what happens is
we get telemetry and GPS information and
then drive the antenna to point to the
satellite at all times so unlike the
air-to-ground system which work at lower
frequencies where you can have sort of
omnidirectional antennas here you can
you have to have very high directivity
antennas and what that means is that as
the aircraft is moving around you have
to keep the end and appointed at the
satellite all the time and so you need
to know at all times where the satellite
is where they enter the aircraft is in
relation to the satellite so we steer
the antenna based on information coming
from from the GPS units mounted next to
the antenna or from the something called
an airing interface from the aircraft
itself the radome is intended to to you
know provide give you give environmental
protection and it is designed to
minimize aerodynamic load and also
provides birdstrike in you know
lightning protection so because it's a
it's a change to the body of the
aircraft you have to get FAA
certifications no it's called
supplementary type certification to get
make it flight-worthy
and at all you know the radome also has
to be designed so that you can have RF
signals at ka pan going through through
it with minimal sort of degradation in
performance so then the next component
that's of interest that the device is on
the satellite talk to or the base
stations or we call it on satellite
modem termination system nor lucky
similar to what cable modem termination
systems are what it does is that it
operates at two levels it operates that
the phy layer where it does modulation
and demodulation of signals similar in a
qpsk or 8psk modulation demotivational
signals it provides forward error
correction coding and it does by layer
algorithms in dealing with fades and it
deals with power managing power and
timing and so on much like what happens
on the ethernet interfaces on
terrestrial networks and only or optical
things that you know the previous one of
the previous speakers talked about then
it also deals with Mac layer I'm similar
to the ethernet framing there is sort of
there is a framing that's used here and
what it does MT stands for mobile
terminal mobile terminal needs to log
into the network and register and is
authenticated and is granted bandwidth
um in order for it to transmit or
receive so so that's the set of
functions of the mac layer protocols in
addition it provides radio resource
management what that means is it allows
for managing the quality of service
provided to that particular terminal so
IP tuples are typically mapped into what
are called service flows which are
architectural primitives that are used
in the matter
they're two to provide no quality of
differentiated quality of service for
different applications and the mac layer
also deals with congestion control and
load balancing on the satellite beam
furthermore it deals with hand over as
the aircraft transitions in a ghost
across the country it goes from one spot
beam to the other much like as you're
driving along a road on a freeway you're
going from one cell tower to the up next
or one sector within a cell tower to the
next sector within a cell tower so there
are these handover algorithms that um
come into play that essentially allow
for seamless connectivity to to the
application or the server that your
connect you know that's that you're
connected to in addition we also enhance
some of the protocols to deal with a
satellite to satellite handover so in in
some areas where there is limited
coverage we have other satellites sort
of taking over so we need to end traffic
from one satellite to the next and that
poses its own set of challenges so from
a mobility architecture perspective we
again like as mentioned before there's a
number of protocols designed to deal
with handover but fundamentally there's
this csn or connectivity serving network
that talks to multiple access serving
networks or and then what is shown at
the bottom is as mobile terminals move
from one smt SOS NTS and basically deals
with one particular spot beam to the
other the protocols tell
one base station to hand over the mobile
terminals context and what does a
context context is really information
about the terminal or what its
capabilities are if you're if you're
authenticated or not if you're if you
have keys if you have encrypted
information or is or what kind of keys
or need to be handed over all of that
context moves along with the terminal
during the course of the flight so all
of the traffic from the terminal goes to
via the base stations to the Athens to
the connectivity serving networks and
out to the internet so that's sort of
the basic high level architecture and
like I mentioned before the user
services persist through persist through
the handoff process what that means is
pages continue to load video streams
continue and email and VPN services
continue so there is a brief hiccup when
when for example if I talked about
different colors and adjacent beams and
when when a plane goes from one
satellite beam to the next satellite
beams if if it goes to a different
polarization the physical layer needs to
switch over so there's a very very short
outrage causing a few lost packets but
it's no different than any you know
indistinguishable from what happens on
the Internet so that's
here's a little more detail about our
network it's it consists of a set of
satellite radio access nodes connected
to an evil packet core there are several
nodes in the packet core we call them
core nodes and they're like internet
points of presence they provide
connectivity drop-off points to the
internet at each of these quarter notes
the in you know we have one big ospf
area that connects all of the satellite
lands to the packet core and we use a CG
not for passengers and we have to buy
aircraft or airline regulations how also
have to provide content filtering so
that you know passengers are not subject
to objectionable content so that's a
little bit of the network infrastructure
and in terms of redundancy each
satellite access node or gateway we call
them is duo home to two nodes in the
packet core and we use routing metrics
one is advertising a higher cost and the
other so when one goes away the other
one kicks in and packets are redirected
to the core note that it was originally
home to if a cordon of itself fails then
we've moved all of the traffic to the
backup core node network so we talked
briefly about what happens at the Phi
layer what happens with the mac layer
what happens from a connectivity IP
connectivity standpoint but we talked a
little bit about on tcp and many of you
know tcp wasn't
originally designed for a long fat
networks and since then a number of
improvements have been made to the
through rfcs to improve the performance
of tcp on a long fat network in our case
the we have both high bandwidth and long
latencies because of the round-trip time
to a geostationary satellite so it
impacts a couple of things it impacts
you know so TCP performance is based on
the round trip times so the longer the
round-trip the worst performance and
it's also proportional to the window
size so you know the several of the
algorithm parameters are tuned to so
slow start is directly proportional to
the round trip times and has a
logarithmic you know response to the
window sizes so what happens in a long
delay network is because packets are in
flight and the TCP connection has to
stay and the buffer sizes have to be
maintained in order to drive higher
performance otherwise you'll end up
getting caught up in the slow start part
of the TCP congestion algorithm and the
back off algorithm as well so we do the
following we split the connection into
three channels we have a connection from
the end user device to the modem on the
airplane we have a tcp proxy between the
airplane and the base station and from
the base station we connect to the
server that the user is trying to reach
to by doing this we can then take
control over the window sizing the back
offs and so on
and and we use RFC 1323 to drive up
window sizes and then we also don't have
the additive increase multiplicative
decrease behavior of the tcp so we tune
the tcp performance that way we also use
things like selective acknowledgments
and so on to drive higher throughput on
tcp the other thing that affects us is
the round trip times and I like I
mentioned then we try to do sort of DNS
lookups to improve TCP perform and so
those are some of the tricks on the
right side is shown a graph those two
sets of graphs a1a the the smaller set
of bar charts shows you the 50th
percentile of a set of pages that page
this one the y axis of the page load
performance on the x axis is the
percentile of pages that we measured
against so we took lots and lots of
pages and measure the performance of
page load times and the blue bar shows
you what the tcp performance looks like
if if you didn't do acceleration the red
chart shows you the page load
performance with just tcp tuning and
then the green chart shows you the green
bar shows you the performance of web
page load times with tcp with dns with
some of the other HTTPS things you know
object pre fetches and so on we do and
we compare that against the purple graph
which is sort of the fiber
which is a fiber service which of
comparable speed so we're getting pretty
close to fiber not there yet but you
know we'll continue to work on it so
that gives you sort of a overview of the
sorts of things that we do so what we're
trying to do then is to summarize give
users residential like experience on in
the air and the ways of doing it is sort
of to get higher you know more spectrum
Ryu spectrum and then and then we
compensate for higher delays over the
satellite by manipulating some of the
protocols in order to get the higher
performance um that's that's the that's
the talk any questions
I thought I my other forms and one of
the things that we learned in that
program was that for my seniors be
sustained the movement of prefixes and
we did was the cause significant updates
I realized that not all aircraft are
going to change browse a Shinto that
that's something that over time we
figure out how soft that problem for IV
never sober look their lowly connected
so first question is and you done more
research in this area to solving a
problem and the same just arm and great
it's the question instead for those who
really think want to see high-speed
internet access airplanes in these the
United States in a non 0 or water
situation there needs to be more
bandwidth payable from your ground right
now 3.25 networks for the Go Go system
that's launching
situation how many more from the SEC is
on time future will certainly be able to
change the way that are connected or
once item thank you so I'll take that in
the reverse order so I think Qualcomm
has recently filed a petition with the
FCC for hire we know higher bandwidth
allocation so as with a number of these
types of spectrum allocation requests
there are a number of parties that are
you know involved in the in the process
like you pointed out on the air cell
logo is 3 megahertz the Qualcomm request
is for 150 megahertz so it's it's 50
times more and the system that I was
just talking about deals with 500
megahertz so which we've already been
granted so there's no contention in the
spectrum allocation at all on the second
part so we all of the as planes go from
one base station to the other we're not
really advertising the reach ability of
that aircraft from that particular base
station instead we back all the traffic
all over the way all the way to the csn
and so there's really one point from
which we do that so it's in that sense
very similar to the home agent for an
Asian concept in terrestrial cellular
networks so
46 so we're we're testing out basics at
this point we're not quite sure what our
timeline for the rollout is but yes
that's in the plan
thank you thank you very much grace
something to think about on our flight
home later this week so just a few
things I want to mention we're about to
start a break from to 32 3 p.m. so come
back here at three once again thanks to
our sponsors for this break myriad
supply pacnet and xk el there's some
snacks and some some swag out there for
you to pick up also just to clarify in
the survey giveaways you know this is
remember this is the first time we did
that kind of monday tuesday wednesday
instead of the sunday monday tuesday
wednesday i got a little confused we are
announcing survey giveaways tomorrow at
two thirty p.m. when we open that's
going to be for today's survey the next
one is Wednesday 930am when we open the
conference that's going to be for
Tuesday's of survey and then again
wednesday at three thirty p.m. right
before Betty's up here to announce the
election results so as a reminder you
have to be here in the room if you want
to receive your ipad mini and other bag
of goodies from limelight Tuesday to 30
wednesday 930 and wednesday at three
thirty also keep in mind that the
ballots are open we're going to be
voting in till wednesday am so pleased
if you are an an augment log on to the
nanog net org site don't try it right
now because apparently it's not loading
so just give a few minutes left to get
back up but shortly log onto nanog dork
site and vote for vote for the members
also if you don't have the ability to
vote on that i adore dates because
you're not actually member so please
consider joining the nanog membership
it's not necessarily very expensive and
you get a lot of benefit for your buck
as well as the community in general i
think the the all of the number of
first-timers we have today really
demonstrates how valuable nano continues
to be for the network operator community
and that's it enjoy your break we'll see
you back here at three o'clock
you