alright everyone will be getting started
please find your seats that means you
Jam John van oppen alright please
welcome John spring with cert thank you
John hi everyone so this is a discussion
of some stuff that I was doing to try to
detect some malicious behavior on the
internet it actually goes back for some
time this will be a bit of a survey just
to get the flavor what's going on if you
want to look at the technical details we
actually just published this as a tech
report last Friday seems like a long
time ago to me for some reason I'm
coming in from Pittsburgh cuz we're out
of Carnegie Mellon University
unfortunately I cannot report that the
Pirates are going to the next round of
the playoffs hopefully I'll report that
tomorrow so first step of course is the
useless legal language now that you guys
have all consented to monitoring of
everything that I'm doing they move on
all it really says is that I don't
promise that any of this is real so fast
flux is not new I'm new talking about
nameservers doing fast flux under put
fast in air quotes but fast flux is not
new at all I can report it on this a
long time ago and if I can is doing a
report like this then it has percolated
up pretty far into the DNS awareness so
in case you didn't read this paper in
2008 or I've forgotten it since then
because we're all getting old basically
fast flux is if one domain uses a bunch
of different IP addresses the botnet
authors do this to avoid IP blacklists
basically so if they hard code the
domain name or something into their
malicious code then they can cycle
through the IP addresses which gets
around that block lists
they soon realize that this wasn't
enough so they started also cycling
through the domain names and so you have
multiple domain names which are hosted
on a related set of IP addresses but the
time to live for these is you know five
seconds five minutes something rather
short so you might say didn't we take
care of this five years ago why do I
care now we have a pretty good mechanism
for taking this stuff down reactively
but pretty good is relative right it's
always reactive so for reactive and
we're taking something down we're
playing whack Amole as a defensive
community that's not ideal if you're
playing whack-a-mole you're gonna lose I
actually just three weeks ago in San
Francisco presented a paper with some
modeling about this and why this is
definitely true if you're playing
whack-a-mole you will not catch up right
because you have to react so if they're
doing a fast flux botnet and they only
need to get one domain name through and
one IP address through out of 500,000
and they can update their BOTS to evade
your defensive mechanisms they will do
that they'll win right we see this as
conficker conficker still exists all
over the place so given that this is a
latent problem click there we go what
can we do so domains need two things
they need a location as I said we
already have tried blocking the location
we've already tried ip-based block lists
those work okay as long as they're
actually you know owning the IP address
that they're using for malicious
purposes but that's not often the case
everyone has compromised machines on
their infrastructure somewhere and you
can't just block the IP address if it's
been compromised because you take down
legitimate services so since there are
only two things that something needs in
the DNS to be active let's try to look
at the name servers so I did this two
ways I did the same algorithm but I did
it on two different sources which have
slightly different features that I
connects that I can take advantage of so
certain
top-level domains make their zone files
available these are the generic tlds com
org net so the zone files give me a
pretty good insight into the
second-level domains on the internet
because com is half of them right but
that's still not everything and in
general i only have daily resolution on
this so if some bad guy in the zone
files changes the IP address of his name
server four times in a day but the last
one is the same as the first one i won't
see that it's changed because i can only
pull it down at midnight on the other
hand i have a passive DNS data source so
I have the contents of the resource
recordsets so I have the IP addresses of
the name servers and the domains that
are used as name servers from that and I
can see down lower labels that are name
servers I can also see all the tlds they
get requested but it's incomplete so
you'll see slightly different results
from these two data sets but it's
provides a way looking at both sings the
you knows one gives completeness for
everything in the zone one gives a
sample across the whole internet so is a
little more complete the passive DNS
source has a slight North American bias
so there's that what I do is pretty
simple and it's related to the fast flux
detection in general so you look for
things that move IP addresses and you
prioritize those things if they change
ASNs pretty frequently the name server
is supposed to be stable right you guys
that run name servers you know that your
name server should not be changing IP
addresses that's basically forced down
time if your name server changes IP
addresses because there's going to be
the TTL pine out and people are going to
get confused might be reasonable for
this to happen once or twice in a month
probably once right people do change
their name servers but they try to not
do it so frequently even someplace like
Akamai I've gotten several questions
like isn't this CDN isn't this going to
change all of the time that's actually
not how those work quite the resource
pages that end Leafs of the CDN are
going to change all the time but
everyone needs a stable place to ask for
what those very variable resources are
so although a combined might have one
hundred or two
or whatever his name servers and they
might vary which ones you ask questions
to each individual name server stays in
the same place the IP address doesn't
change so what I'm talking about is the
actual name server changing IP addresses
and particularly I care if they change a
s because if it changes a s it's
changing who's in control of the network
and so pretty reasonable if someone's
changing their name server from one IP
address they own to another one but if
you're on you know the customer net
block for isp in France and then the
name server changes to the customer net
lock for an ISP in San Francisco i'm
pretty sure that that's not real so i
know that you're all surprised that bad
things happen on the internet please
forced laughter a little bit oh thanks
there you go if you look at this you
have the number of changes in IP address
and the number of changes in a SN if you
look at say row four or five they're
actually more than the left right hand
column a s column then there are an IP
column this is because if something
changes IP address nine times it might
only change as5 so it's not out of the
198 that changed IP four times how many
changed a s it's how many change they
asked four times out of all of them so I
would venture a guess that point 2 or
point one percent of the things that the
zone files were malicious for as far as
name servers go if you sum up down there
in the passive files there are a bit
more this is because the time
granularity is better I think it also
might be because the generic tlds have a
bit better security on the people that
they allow to register names I think
that's a pretty reasonable guess as to
why this is true also not sure exactly
which one of those it is but as you can
see there's a bit more suspicious
looking name servers if we look at
passive DNS so that data was from 2011
if you look at this this is the number
of IP address number of nameservers the
changed IP address five or more times
within the 30 days prior to the date on
the bottom this runs from October first
2011 until two weeks ago the big spike
is when Dena's changer was taken down so
they were doing this to keep their name
servers up that they were serving all
these militias ads that was stealing all
of this money also if you note they
looked like they were serving names that
had suspicious strings in it right
there's usually not too many name
servers that are RX free pharma viagra
cialis dot name server net or whatever
it is so that's what that red line means
they had one of those kind of words in
it very simple I'm not actually
analyzing like where they sold anything
to I'm looking at the strings in the
name server name however that peeks out
at 3,500 name servers doing this in the
zone files it drops a lot so we can
certainly affect it if we go arrest six
people in Estonia and turn off their
servers so that's good news but maybe we
can do without quite so much effort by
the FBI right maybe we look at this from
a technical point of view we can also do
something that number stays pretty
stable between four and six hundred name
servers doing IP flux in the zone files
for the big generic top-level domains
for the last two years about twenty two
months so I do say that this can be
changed because obviously it can be
affected but I also say that this is
still somewhat of a problem you not know
how many domains those 500 name servers
are serving right we could find that out
but that's just not what I did on this
graph so just because the 500 name
servers can probably control a good
amount of malicious infrastructure also
I said that I'd adjust the parameters
the parameters for name server IP flux
are not the same as that for regular IP
flux this is why no one else found it
right you don't find this by accident
when you just regularly run
p flux calculations it hides all of that
because in general name servers are more
stable this is all name server IP
address TTLs so if the domain was a name
server this is in the passive DNS what
the TTL was for it's a record forty-one
percent of them were two days almost all
of them are either one hour one day or
two days what does this tell you besides
that this is a log-log plot and that I
might know a little bit about how
logarithms work and that maybe I'm
therefore intelligent and should be
listened to which is probably not we
should take away from this graph that
name server records behave differently
than regular records so we have to look
at them differently we have to look at
them especially also if you look almost
all name server records have a TTL of
more than five minutes so with regular
fast flux one of the defense's was you
can pin names for five seconds in your
name server things like that you
actually don't accept new things you pin
the research record for five seconds
with name servers this is a pretty big
study i looked at 760 million records
you can probably pin name servers it a
lot longer depending on exactly what
percentage of people you want to
frustrate if you put it at five minutes
you would frustrate point probably 02
percent of name server records that's
less than the ones that i claim are
malicious so you probably shouldn't care
what they say anyway you can pin it a
bit higher if you're a bit more
ambitious
when someone gives a security talk you
should always ask so what right I'm not
here to sell you anything so I'm not
claiming that the sky is falling you
should buy something from me so there's
no analytic reason why people should
change these name servers so much if
they change this much they're probably
doing it because they're running from
somebody so if you care about protecting
someone from it and that might actually
just be your corporate 10 people that
actually run your network I know that
you guys are running networks for big
customer bases that you can't just
dictate what name servers they go to if
you run a DNS server for your own
employees though you probably want to
care about this if you run a bigger name
server you might want to think about
caring about it but there's also all
those contracts things I do claim that
as a high confidence indicator and that
more importantly transitioning to
blocking name servers is more effective
than trying to play whack-a-mole and
catch up on just blocking the actual
domains after we see that they're bad if
you block a name server it blocks all
the things that are resolving using it
so you jump out ahead a little bit and
you help to win this asymmetric battle
that's going on where the attackers have
this asymmetric advantage if they only
have to get one thing through I am
curious if anyone has looked at this on
securing their networks I don't know of
anyone that has so I would like to know
if someone has you can come talk to me
later I would especially like to know if
you tried this and it did not work so I
could try and spend a lot of effort
proving to you beyond a reasonable doubt
that this is bad I have some good
reasons to believe that that's not
fruitful I could try to sample some of
these name servers and run them down but
I think that that's more or less done
with that 3,000 of these went offline
when DNS changer was taken down and
those servers were taken off i also have
done some other work looking at black
lists and intersections between them
which makes me question the utility of
just intersecting some list of names
that had come up with someone else's
blacklist and saying if they agree that
i'm right because everyone looks at
different
things and so almost no blacklists
actually intersect so it'd be hard to
pick which one and I would just get to
pick whichever one made me look the
smartest which is not the best way to
try to actually get the right answer at
something I do continue to keep track of
this and I intend on doing that for the
near future and the foreseeable future I
bringing this to some attention because
it might be the case that some
registries are in a position to pay
attention to this and if not actually do
anything feed it into some other abuse
process right to keep track of something
in the meantime if you keep track of the
DNS queries that you ask for your
organization you can do this yourself
that type report has all of the
information about what you would need to
do to actually look at this it's pretty
simple though you can block this i would
suggest in a dns in the actual dns
server like rpz because you want to
actually block request to the name
server the point is that those are
changing IP addresses so just blocking
outbound 53 to that IP address might not
be effective once it changes names here
very cool if you link your firewall
rules really carefully with your name
server then you can probably do it that
way that is all I have I have about 14
minutes for questions I hope that
there's at least one and that I can
continue to talk
good morning dr. yahoo here so / 400-600
games for worse than you think our
suspect or potentially filmmakers do you
have compiled this you still aboard and
sp2 us to go for out the name server for
size I can make it available but I do
have to I can't just publish that based
on Serge rule I would like to say that
that was true right I can give it to you
certainly uh publishing it publicly is a
little bit more difficult however I
would be interested in exploring where
we sort of hand it off to someone else
who might incorporate it in something
that they would use that might have
better dissemination yeah I come talk to
me afterwards
so I thought about that and I basically
decided that it was not our we were not
going to issue a response to any of
those Ras so I'm doing the best I can
given that I know that I'm past that
period right but that would have been
ideal however the breezes in any case
sort of trivial these people layer down
there's nothing special about the
registries control especially for NSN
records so I so this is a always a
matter of you know how much effort we
put in on what areas you don't I agree
that it's not any kind of silver bullet
there is no one silver bullet if you can
however clean up certain tlds better
right you have better assurances that
things in precisely that second level
are safer and if I get to the point
where i can just say i'm gonna block all
dynamic dns on my secure network right
because everything bad has been forced
out of all of the traditional registries
because they keep track of it that is
not trivial if that's not useless
a real progress on the step first of all
as a matter of fact you know I can just
doesn't have that capability because all
the CCTVs are are subject to you simply
can you essentially you're trying your
cell phone but but also because of the
large expansion of the roof I think that
this is a problem that just expands per
hour I think I can't seriously bleep
list of this or are it seems to me
rather than you something that was
implied by the biggest conscious and
that is your reputation oh yeah and i
know i did not actually say in the
slides i can at all because i'm aware of
they don't actually to the extent that
they have contracts with the ccTLDs they
are not so binding on behavioral
modifications so each TLD is going to
have to be convinced of the utility of
this independently which does not
exactly give a nice friendly single
point of contact to make any changes but
that doesn't mean that we just throw up
our hands completely and say that uh
this is hard we'd better not try at all
I'm gonna put your table a question from
the table up here and we've heard in
recent talks in other conferences that
there are millions of open recursive DNS
resolvers on the internet is that's
something that's cross search radars at
using the overlap of the issue
about here and it was like 32 million
open resolvers out there yeah so the
number of open resolvers is large and
yes I'm aware of that that that's a
different sort of issue I think because
with the open resolvers one of the
things that people are really worried
about is the reflection and sort of
public health concerns which i think is
a serious issue but i think is separate
from denying the malicious content
controllers their ability to actually
have some sort of master copy so right
you can certainly use an open resolver
to make the query around some sort of
protection that you put in place I
suppose because they are approximate of
Lee so to some extent right proxies are
always a problem right the Internet is a
logical Network not a physical so we
can't oh well this is carved off here so
it does affect you know the more things
that are wrong to snowball the fact they
think any more questions okay all right
thank you very much
you