thank you so much um
how good is it to be like irl right
is everyone so i don't know about yeah
let's let's give these guys a hand
because honestly
um thank you so much um just getting to
see some of the
some of the work that went into putting
this together like doing a conference
irl like it's safe and we're able to do
this but it's still a challenge to put
it on during a pandemic with all the
stuff that's going on so
props to you all um a lot of work went
in and and
you know we all get to benefit from it
so thank you um
yeah i don't know about you guys but
i've forgotten how to fly when i was
when i was back in my bag to come up
here i'm like hang on does that go on
the checked or the
carry-on i got on the plane and felt
like i was doing a good job
but then all of a sudden i realized i
was in the wrong seat
so clearly i'm not flight fit anymore
no no i was i was actually up the back
but it was like sir you're in my
okay fine all good so anyway yeah
release the hounds um
eight years is a long-ass time that's
that's the talk uh and as i said it
feels like a billion years ago and
yesterday when all this stuff went down
in terms of the origin story of bug
crowd
but really uh you know what um i want to
go through today not to preempt
the setup too much but just to kind of
talk through
what it's like building a startup uh in
this space some of the things that we've
seen around
around cyber security and around
particularly crowdsourcing and
multi-sourcing the kind of things
that we do and we'll go from there so
where's this title come from it's an
early tradition of
ours every time we launch a new program
we tweet release
the hounds you see the date there may 15
2013. and again it feels like yesterday
because
there's been so much that's gone on in
this space um but in reality
like it's a lot of time that's passed
including you know the pandemic which
felt like about a billion years
let's keep moving so who am i uh who's
this dude struggling with laptops and
is now selling a mac laptop if anyone's
interested so my name's casey ellis i'm
the founder chairman and cto of bug
crowd
also the founder of the disclose io
project and you know i'm going to be
hanging out
outside uh or in the talks for the rest
of the conference so if
anyone wants to come up and talk about
either of those two things i'm super
keen to as are the rest of the team
i've got to ask that question who works
for bug crowd here
all right there's a few more hens this
time that's cool
so i've been basically in infosec since
high school i grew up you know tearing
apart technology and messing with it
as a kid i think you know that was the
product of
of an environment where i had a lot of
tech to play with my old band was a
science teacher
um but the other thing was that um yeah
i always and
many of you i think will relate to this
i always really enjoyed thinking like a
criminal that had
absolutely no desire to be one so there
was this kind of spark going on it's
like i don't want to like hurt people
and stuff but that that's really cool
and i really like thinking
you know outside the box um and really
to get into the security industry as a
job discovering that this was possible
in the first place that was like
christmas
for me and i'm sure that experience was
similar for a lot of you all it's like i
can do this and be legit this is awesome
uh so yeah we pioneered effectively the
crowd source security as a service model
um we didn't invent vulnerability
disclosure we didn't invent bug bounty
that's a
that's a whole other long kind of
history conversation uh but when it came
to actually
you know basically doing this as a as a
platform
uh we were the first ones to do it and
you know things have kind of escalated
since then so this talk is
is partly about that i'm a proud aussie
husband my wife is kicking around
somewhere
um father of two and uh lives in
i don't know where somewhere um we've
been living in san francisco for the
past eight years we actually bugged out
almost a year to the day flew out on the
13th of march
basically seeing covert coming over the
hill in america and that combined with
um having worked on elections and seeing
how
volatile that whole situation was it's
like it's going to be a rough year so
let's get to where we're close to family
and get the kids into a better
environment
hopefully we'll get back there but
that's basically a work in progress
at this point as is true i think for a
lot of people it's a first world problem
but it's still been a pretty interesting
12 months that's for sure
so what are we talking about um been
through this what have we talked what
have we
been through or what have we been up to
as an organization
what have we seen the industry do where
is crowdsourcing and multi-sourcing up
to now
what comes next this is really a
two-pronged talk i think
what i want to do is to inform security
folks but then also try to appeal
to the entrepreneurs in the room right
um
you know tell my story help you guys
understand by crowd in our space but
then
you know hopefully inspire some folks
that are here to step out
the reason for doing that i've been like
literally walking sand hill road for the
past eight years
alongside building the company and
australians are really really good at
this
um but we're really terrible at
realizing that
right like as a as a culture and as a
nation i actually think that we're
almost uniquely talented when it comes
to troubleshooting and coming up with
cool solutions
but we also kind of suck at sales
because we don't like to self-promote
you know we don't like to necessarily
overestimate ourselves
um and kind of do ourselves out of out
of the process i think
uh as a result so hopefully some of the
story i'm not that smart
um honestly i just had to go and saw a
thing saw an opportunity went for it got
a bunch of smart people around
me to help build it and and it's kind of
worked out so
you can do that too it's really the
point that i'm trying to drive out there
all right so back to this talk in in in
uh the 1st of march 2013
um some of the slides it's actually a
fun one to go through and it was sort of
when i started talking to the crikey
guys about um
speaking here i went back and had a look
at it because there's a lot of things
that are different
and a lot of things that are still the
same
for example the moment you launch a
bounty program you get a billion people
telling you about dmarc and click
checking
that is still a thing um and it's not
because
there is a lack of skill in the space i
think it's because the number of
participants
who are on that kind of learning process
and the ease of being able to identify
that type of vulnerability they just
think it's the right thing to do so
they'll do that
part of what bugred does is filters that
out and actually trains them on how to
be better but that's very much still a
thing
and you can see here 10 bounties we
actually ran some charity bounties early
on
um there was some some not-for-profits
that came to us and said hey
uh we we need security i'm like well
what can you pay the community
nothing we're a charity like okay let's
see if that works
um and the coolest story out of that was
a uh
basically an organization that raised
money to combat sex trafficking in
southeast asia we kind of teased out
what the mission was and got people set
up for it then launched it and we
literally knocked them off the internet
for for like a day and a half because of
the response
we then learned how not to do that
because obviously that's not something
that you want to do if you're a security
company but
to me what that did early on was to
speak to
i think a lot of the misconceptions that
the market had
and just the general public had around
hackers like we're not
bad people necessarily some of us are um
but to have an intrigue to have a skill
to have a career in the space doesn't
mean
you're someone to actually be afraid of
we're here to help right so that was
pretty cool
um you know general observations from
that deck this is again
uh what this is eight years ago now
actually just passed
it's working that turned out to be
pretty accurate
um running an accelerated startup is
wicked hard work this is before we'd
gone to silicon valley for the first
time so we'd raised a fifty thousand
dollar
what i refer to as the raman noodle
round out of out of start mate
um and and that basically paid for
flights and accommodation in sf
and about three beers because it's kind
of expensive over there
um but that was kind of the yeah the
jump start for us and we were just about
to fly over
um here's where you know the
actually my office where i started
working on it myself and then
the first place that we landed on in sf
um this is the platform in what is this
2012 december 2012 so this is actually a
a
kickoff labs form that was meant for for
people to sign up on
um the early proof that this was going
to work
was was really when i sent out a couple
of tweets and said hey we're going to
try this thing if you want to
hack on some cool stuff go sign up and
it just
it blew up um you know in in
the terms of of that particular period
of time we had about 4
000 people sign up over the next you
know two weeks or so
so to me that proved that you know the
supply side
and the people that are actually going
to do this are there and they're willing
it's just a matter of plugging them in
right
and this is the first program uh this
was actually a shitty rails app that i
built
and i'm like all right i want to wonder
if this works so i basically got 500
bucks put it out there
divvied up the reward so i wouldn't go
over the 500
amount and that's that was actually the
origin of our crowdsource pen test
pricing model because if you've got a
capped cost you can't necessarily what
if you get a million bucks you've got to
be able to answer that question so
this is where that got started and uh it
worked it was incredible i think
you know the the bitter proof problem
solution fit proof that came out of that
was seeing
um someone basically inject
a payload through the twitter shortener
into the back end that then rendered on
a unlisted page
together on mouseover xss i think it was
something like that
so it's like not you know the end of the
world but that's some pretty creative
stuff going on right there and to be
able to see that full out because that
particular person was good at that
particular thing
it's like okay this is this works this
is cool
um i think the other thing is that
you know 2012 which is when this is all
going down
uh it was a it was a simpler time wasn't
it
i think it's before people i'm actually
going to talk about the journey to
hackers becoming relevant cyber security
becoming dinner table conversation
this to me feels like it was before that
so we're all just kind of spawning
around doing our thing
um you know trying to figure out how to
make money and pay the bills and do all
that kind of stuff but
i think there was a lot less
of a business imperative on what we do
then compared to now and you know
frankly that was those nice things about
that there's obviously opportunity
that's come
since which is pretty awesome as well um
so you know rip good times but
um i remember them fondly and really
this is the idea
behind i think vulnerability disclosure
and it's not actually just us so when
i'm talking about this stuff there's
part of it's what bug crowd does and how
we do our thing part of it's just the
space at this point in time there's i
think 45
different platforms doing you know
baking a cake was roughly the same
ingredients as how i frame it um
around the world and that's because this
just makes sense
uh as an organization if you've got you
know
an attack surface to defend and
ultimately you're tasked with being
smarter with all the adversaries that
might come
come and bother you and you're relying
on single individuals it doesn't
necessarily matter how good or bad
those individuals are they're
fundamentally disadvantaged because of
the math
so okay in the meantime you've got the
white hat community sitting there
wanting to help
and there's this latent potential
disconnected with this unmet demand
like really that was kind of the origin
of the idea the other thing was to try
to get
you know stop people from going to jail
basically
it's like looking at a lot of the work
we did with disclosures around
just you know policy advocacy um we're a
part of writing the policies that we
used
uh to secure aspects of the
2020 general election in the u.s which
kind of worked i guess um
that was a joke um
but you know seeing that ahead and like
packers want to help out with this stuff
it's going to actually
you know do do a part to instill
confidence in the american population
because the integrity of this election
is going to come under attack this is
two years before
um all the crazy ship went down in
october so
um and and after that as well so those
are the things that
you know we've really invested in and
gotten into as an organization
so all right that's the origin stuff
nick minute
um one of the funny things that happened
when i landed in sf sitting with a with
a lyft driver who was sydney's
he immigrated to the us and we're
talking about security because
that just tends to happen when i ride on
a lift with people um
and he trotted out this amazing quote
like all security is the product of
something bad happening
which i think you know as a mental model
and a framework to think about in terms
of what we do is actually
pretty useful um you know folks aren't
doing secure
security poorly because they they don't
care or they don't want to
half the time it's because they're so
focused on the thing they're trying to
do
that it just gets pushed to the wayside
so that was kind of interesting i got to
thinking about that
in terms of the market and the same
months that we landed in the u.s
that happened um i promise i had nothing
to do with it that's the
the caveat that i have to often give in
the u.s because um
you know snowden not to speak about any
of the
uh input or output of what he did but
what i do
think happened as a product of this is
that the general population saw it
and all of a sudden rip good times it's
like hacking happens to me this is the
thing that i actually
you know need to have at least in some
way on my radar now i
still don't really understand what's
going on but i know it is actually
starting to affect me personally
and it kind of escalated from there so
in 2014 that was the year
of the uh the year of the credit card
breach particularly in the us but it
happened right around the world i think
as emv
and chip and pin were starting to roll
out um some of the some of the
gangs just kind of did their last hurrah
on um on
track two and dumps and different things
like that so target got popped all the
retails so now hacking happens to me
personally it's not just it happens
which is what snowden taught people
it's like now it's now it's me
and then this happened um this actually
happened in the same year as the opm
breach um and there were some others as
well that were basically uninsurable
right so this clearly isn't you know
difficult to
insure yourself against if you happen to
get caught up in ashley madison
opm was was basically clearance data
and records that were getting correlated
with flight records and different things
like that
so now it's hacking happens to me and it
hurts
um my my credit card company company's
not going to pay me back for that one so
this is starting to suck
then this happened 2016 you know hackers
are hacking
hacking happens to my country that i
think was
and by the way this is my observation
that's quite north america-centric
because that's where we were for all of
this
um but i do think you know there's
there's some pretty broad analogs that
happen right across the west
over the same time frame 27 to 2020 all
right cool software's eating the world
and and the bad guys are eating the
software um
and here we are in 2020 uh actually in
2020 coming out of that into 2021
my employees five-year-old is
responsible for my corporate attack
service that's new
and actually a really interesting you
know for the folks that are
that are thinking about this problem i
think there's a lot of scope i don't
think work from home is is gonna
go away um and i don't think we've
really thought through
what the impact of a home network is on
on corporate security uh to the extent
that we think we have
um and part of the evidence of that is
the fact that like iot
and and router oday is now flying off
the shelf
um whereas before this it basically sat
there because it wasn't as interesting
so the adversary is
clued into this which means it's going
to occupy us
at some point in the future as well and
this is really the idea if it's repeated
enough times in the dinner table it
actually makes its way to the boardroom
um so it's not just about hey like ciso
guy or
or person you know ceo person like
security matters if they're hearing
about it from their kids
or from their spouse or from their
family then all of a sudden it's top of
mind
i think that's actually driven like
we're in a pretty unique position
now i feel like when we started bug
crowd you had to scream from the street
corner
to try to get you know two or three
people to listen and pay attention to
what you're talking about
now they're coming to us which is pretty
interesting and i think that's relevant
not just for
for us and our space i think it's
relevant for everyone in this room
so what we up to um this is the first
office
in in sf which is cool i love that photo
it was just
that was like early on it was it just
felt good
um second office in ministry this is as
we're growing
uh third sorry that was the second
that i showed then the third this is the
fourth on front street which is where we
are now it's it's abandoned and all the
plants are dead but we'll eventually get
back there
um we've got an office in sydney
australia as well and and other places
around the world
basically where we're at is a 198
employees uh 80 million raised 257
194 vulnerabilities nuked
just about to tip over 50 million u.s
paid out to the supply side
about 250 000 people signed up on the
platform
they're not like we don't have an army
of 250 000 people there's a difference
between someone who signs up and someone
who actually does stuff so i'm calling
out that distinction but
because these big numbers get thrown
around i wanted to add it in
and you know 480 customers uh
which have really you know focused on
how do we take this idea of
hackers and cyber security people being
useful and having a constructive input
into into you know the entire market not
just
like the nerds at facebook and google
where this all kicked off right that was
really our initial objective was to jump
out of the
i call it the um you know the lunatics
validating the asylum
in san francisco right like there's this
kind of sandpit thing where you can
prove stuff but it doesn't necessarily
validate the relevance of it to the
broader market so we did that
you know working with department of
defense working with you know dhs
national australia bank here in
australia a whole bunch of others so
it's it's kind of
broken out to the point where it's
mainstream and that's pretty cool i'm
not going to go too far into this but
yeah i think one of the things that i
spend a decent amount of time talking
about right now
is that it's not just bug bounty or vdp
um you know going back to the the tug of
war thing
it's actually about basically connecting
people with questions to the folks that
can answer them
uh in whatever context the the the
concept of a bug bounty program got a
tailwind uh in about
early 2015 when hector pentagon started
up and all of a sudden it was sexy and
we were spending a lot of time just
trying to ride that wind
but what it also did was i think kind of
included the fact that
no there's you know pen test opportunity
in this there's a whole bunch of other
stuff that you can do
with a group of smart hackers if you can
connect what you need done to the right
person to actually do that work and
that's really what
what we're building and what we've built
as an organization this is kind of
some of the stuff that we do so i'll put
this stuff online i don't want to turn
this into a pitch so i'm not gonna
i'm not gonna drop down too far into
into this stuff right now
um i think the other part of it and this
is going back to the
you know the the folks that are
straining to like
change stuff if you got an idea you've
got this sense of
wanting to pursue greater potential in
this space maybe do a start-up maybe it
could be
you know a range of other things we've
gotten to do some pretty amazing stuff
like i mentioned the election thing
before
um working with hack the pentagon like
training people
how to have a productive career in cyber
security
um one of my favorites is is literally
diverting
you know young people that have like an
ability that's actually outpaced the
growth of their moral compass and and
kind of diverting them from what would
probably turn into a life of crime
um because that's a thing right you get
a 15 year old who does something stupid
they're not trying to be a bad guy they
just
do their thing and all of a sudden they
get dinged for it and
and it sets them off down the wrong
track so getting to kind of divert that
i think is a pretty
pretty interesting aspect of all of this
yeah thank you
and honestly we're all a part of that
because i think the cyber security
industry
that's not just an opportunity for bug
crowd i think that's an opportunity for
all of us
because of the stuff i just talked about
we're dinner table conversation now
so training's pretty pretty key um
oh and also we have an advanced services
group in in australia
and in case you haven't heard we're
hiring so i'm going to move on from that
one too
um so we'll get to conclusion stuff how
long have i got because i'm
a little off 15 okay cool
i've got got thrown with the the front
bit a little bit there that's all good
um so really my observation in terms of
talking to
you know now that we're i think in a
better position to say what a cso
actually is and what they do
i i think we're still in the position
where csos in 2021 are a little bit like
cios in like 2005
it's the nerd in the boardroom that
doesn't quite know why they're there and
the other people don't quite know
why they're there and we're still going
through that journey of basically
establishing a common language that's
not anyone's fault by the way it's
because it's new
um but you know how does how does
security
you know deliver value back into a
business in a way that the business
understands
so elevating the conversation just from
vulnerabilities and hacks and breaches
and all these different things to say
okay how does this fit into risk like
how do i think about this in terms of
differentiating myself to make my
customer feel safer so i can sell more
stuff
there's all these different things that
the business is actually starting to
look at
right across the board that are also
pretty new i think prior
to um you know 2017 like risk-based
security was this thing the cool kids
talked about
and then i noticed literally at the
gartner conference in dc um
it shifted pretty quickly mostly because
i think people in in management
kind of came to this acceptance that i'm
not going to fix all this
like there's so much to do and there's
such a continuous evolution of things
that
that need to be you know protected
detected or responded to
that unless i prioritize and think about
it in context of the business value of
doing those things i'm actually not
going to get around to all of it so
that's not going to work
um and that to me is is really the trend
in terms of the overall
you know thinking that the market's
taking an opportunity for us right the
better we can explain ourselves to
people the better we can
actually help them do their thing and
turn this into a partnership between
builders and breakers like ultimately
that to me is the end game
of stuff like bug crowd it's not about
just finding bugs and
you know kicking people down the stairs
and having a bit of a laugh it's
actually about
helping them think a little bit more the
way that we do
and vice versa so that we can think more
about their priorities and start to
give them feedback more intelligently
you know as a cso it's it's the the
financial risk side it's the political
risk side and that goes to
being able to talk about what you're
doing around security to the market but
internally as well
and then there's obviously the technical
piece which we mostly focus on
um what that means for us is that you
know humility empathy
and skill are really the preeminent
qualities that are actually going to
not just i think this is not just for
the sake of being a good human in the
space i think this is actually really
valuable
in terms of how you kind of elevate what
you're doing elevate your ability to
give input
and if you're an entrepreneur elevate
your ability to create something that's
actually
incredible and powerful right so i'm
going to pause for water for a sec here
so let's talk about some other
observations
so 2015 was like peak crazy
for venture in in in silicon valley it's
like when all the vcs suddenly realized
oh people are getting hacked we should
put some money into this
um and you know ai is a replacement for
humans forever
people will sell on that type of thing
it doesn't work like that um
to begin with and they've since realized
that but i think what it did was have
this
leave this lasting impression that
that's possible so those kind of
pictures still work i think the broke
way of thinking is that
technology is going to make all this go
away i just need to spend enough money
on it and it'll be fine
the worker way of thinking about it is
that it's a people problem
you know to me like security people
making mistakes that create
vulnerabilities predates the internet by
a couple of thousand years right
like we didn't invent that idea um and
then people taking advantage of that is
also a pretty old concept so
really what's happened is we've just
accelerated it with tech and that's how
we think about it
um broke vdp is a marketing stunt so the
whole idea of
hey techcrunch i'm launching a
vulnerability disclosure program aren't
i awesome
it's good like i think there's a there's
a genuine benefit in being able to make
that statement to the public but
i think the more powerful thing that
happens is when you go out and say you
know what
we're not perfect um and guess what no
one is
we see that every single day like even
the most you know the the organizations
you perceive as the most secure
aren't because qed like people make
mistakes right
i think that statement is actually a
really powerful thing for the
organization to get its arms around
because all of a sudden you can
improve because you're not so busy you
know doing ostrich risk management and
trying to pretend it's all not there
right
bro bug band is silver bullet work bug
bounty is a way to
internalize the boogeyman is real within
the organization so if a
if an engineering team is is learning
about how the code's been broken
by some kid halfway across the world all
of a sudden
you know they're starting to think about
their next door neighbor and and and
what you know gangs might operate
in their neighborhood and all our stuff
there's a different
impact i think to seeing stuff coming
from the outside world to even
you know internal work even though
internal work is incredibly powerful and
important i'm not
denigrating it there's just a different
thing that you activate when it comes in
from the outside and if you attach a
price to that all of a sudden it becomes
quantifiable so that's pretty cool total
payouts is a vanity metric like this is
literally broke
so you see people that want your bug
value program and it's all about how
much they can pay out
there's upside to that because you
engage more people uh because
because folk want to get paid the
downside to it is it doesn't really say
good things about your security program
um and it doesn't necessarily encourage
the right behavior like you want to be
paying the right amount
to break into your stuff and this is how
i think about it you know
hopefully in a more work way it becomes
a proxy cost
for for you know how much it like how
much money does it cost to incentivize
someone to break into my business and be
successful
if you can chart that over time all of a
sudden you've got a metric you can use
in the boardroom
um and it has a dollar sign so they'll
actually read it which is good boards
are
tough um pentest is an assurance-only
model
i think you know where i've seen this
move this is in our context but i think
i've seen it
talking to a lot of pentest firms and
other people in in that industry
um you know assurance and impact so
thinking about it less is
as a compliance activity or something
that you know
is primarily focused on making sure you
checked all the things it's like no i
want to actually
use this as a tool to assess my overall
risk as an organization
factoring in the interdependencies i
have factoring in the fact that you know
some bugs are harder to find than others
some kill chains take a bit more effort
to discover and require different ways
of thinking
than someone that's just running through
them through a list like what i'm seeing
from the market is a real leaning in to
wanting to see that output that's always
been kind of true
in the pentest industry i think but i
also do feel like there's players that
have come in and diluted it
and just turned it into this like
checkbox business activity like we can
do better than that
i think and i think there's an appetite
starting to form for that which is
pretty cool
and that creates those feedback loops i
was talking about before
this is a new entrant china wouldn't
bother with my staff uh
or russia or whoever else i think to me
like i'm not going to talk about supply
chain attacks because everyone's doing
that
um but the thing that uh the solarwinds
breach um i think demonstrated to folk
was like that's a nation state and they
came after me
um if you're threat modeling in a way
that
just assumes that you're not going to be
interesting enough to an actor like that
i think it kind of proved that that's
not entirely true
um so you know work is how do i detect
and contain
a nation state assuming they're
successful so building it like it's
broken
uh and then broke you know coming back
to the vdp piece like security at
domain.com to devnol
the folks that have tried to report
vulnerabilities that's why i was asking
that before
have probably experienced this half the
time it's like shouting into a black
hole because people
either aren't listening or don't know
how to respond
you know what we've tried to do with
disclose io is to basically simplify
that
in terms of standardization of policy
language
um creating safe harbor to make sure
that you know no one feels like they're
going to go to jail
but also that the organization feels
like they're not inviting bad guys to do
bad things or bad people to do bad
things as a part of putting that policy
up
um we've got a bunch of other stuff this
is an open source project uh
it's actually it started with bug crowd
um we had a version of it that then
merged with version out of the berkeley
uh
uc and it's basically rebranded so we
can push it all forward so
if you're interested to talk about that
um i'm pretty passionate about this i
want to see it
work because i want to see this become
normal for our input just to be like not
even offensive anymore it's just like
yeah okay cool here's the thing i need
to fix that's awesome like let's work
together to make the internet better
so in summary good things happen when
you step out um
you know i i think that's the uh and uh
chris
give us wife co-founder back there
thanks dude um some of the other folk in
the room like
you know you take a risk it's a measured
risk you're in security like the worst
case scenario is you
come back and get some sort of role that
you're not a massive fan of
probably land that pretty easily and
then figure out what you're going to do
from there so
there's risk that's available for you to
fall back into
if you want to step out and start to
work on some stuff and again come chat
to me about that because i always get
jazzed up
our industry is only only just getting
started uh and i do think you know
aussies kick ass
at this stuff hence go forward and be
rad
um grace hopper t-shirt we've got uh
we've got a bunch of stickers
uh around as well um because we
accidentally created a swag company
that sort of dabbles in cyber security i
don't know what happened we do like swag
parties and kind of hack some stuff on
the side
um but there's a bunch of bug crowders
around you know come up grab one say
hello do all that sort of stuff
and uh you know really we're here to you
know i'm here today to to basically
answer whatever i can and just hang out
obviously as an attendee but
to the degree that you guys can um you
know get something useful from my
experience i'm happy to share it so
feel free to come say hi and that is the
end of my talk
[Applause]
[Music]
hey casey that was great thank you very
much for keynoting us today
one of the questions i had around it is
you've kind of gone from the
you know crowdsourcing pen testing
approach
what does it look like from uh or have
you had thoughts around crowdsourcing
like a defense approach
yeah um so we've actually we've
experimented with this the prior art
around this is the defensive mitigation
program that's uh katy moe did
uh at microsoft actually quite a while
back now
the challenge with defense is that it's
more difficult to have context on
regression
uh so so coming in and saying here's how
you fix fix a bunch of stuff as someone
who's coming in from the outside
you know you can have a pretty good idea
of what's going on under the hood but
not necessarily a complete one
but yeah i think you know it's something
that we've been working on in terms of
crowdsourcing
for example the generation of waff rules
um you know talking to people about
recommendations we have an
open source recommendation
library basically that maps to the
vulnerability rating taxonomy that's
kind of
so that's sort of crowdsourced as well
in a way um
it's a it's a good question i think you
know where i see offense is a really
logical place to apply this model
because
it's kind of all care and no
responsibility in a way which
which does you know lend itself to being
able to distribute
and to be able to throw you know a piece
of information over the fence for people
to then go off and use
the big thing is that you can't just
stop there because if an organization's
taking that and it's not of value to
them and you have to extend that so
yeah it's a long answer to a short
question but hopefully
got there so continuing that theme and
i'm just asking questions until someone
else puts their hand up here um
think about your slides at the start i
agree 2012 is the good old days
and and that's awesome and then i think
about this week right with the exchange
bowl
and that going from zero 100 in like
five minutes
that sort of stuff now where where orgs
are like there is no time from from
disclosure to go
you know by the time you literally grab
your coffee and have logged in it's too
late sort of thing
do you see any impact around that sort
of stuff yeah i think
um it's it's really prioritization you
know
we had a we had an issue come in from
the 10 cent team to tesla
um that was like a full chain on the car
and and they had that they received it
they engineered a fix they had it fully
deployed out to their entire fleet over
ota in 11 days
right which is um that doesn't happen by
accident
so so the thing with with those folk you
know they started running
a a program actually with us about six
years ago at this point
and you know part of what that gave them
the ability to do was to figure out
where is the low hanging fruit where are
the things that can be seen from the
outside
you know as they added incentives how do
i dig people in deeper to figure out
what the outside in view looks like
and that allowed them to basically spend
more of their time on the proactive
stuff
like architecting a regression program
and an ota
service to get all the cars patched if
they needed to in a hurry so
yeah i think that's how this fits in i i
think you know can can a crowd come in
and boot
defenders out i like the idea of
basically
you know crowdsource threat hunting uh
in a sense there's some sense to that i
think
and also probably to call out as well
that we're actually doing a lot of
point-to-point work as well
so the whole idea of crowdsourcing as a
model that's really good for driving
people down to get impact
um not to go back too much to the pitch
slide but
basically finding the right people to do
the right thing and engaging them
one-off
um on a task or an effort basis is
something that we do as well so
there's lots of ways to cut the cookie
yep cool
someone's got a yep i'll start here and
then we'll go up the back
um yeah i love what you guys do i guess
um
just in the context of companies that
have previously taken legal action to
try and prevent
the you know bugs be getting out there
or even researchers doing their work
are you seeing much of a downward trend
in that sort of attitude from from
different industries
i'm what i'm saying it's not so much a
downward trend as it is an upward trend
of people being proactive
to say that's we could do better
um i think that's the traditional
reaction you know
i mean we're coming off 30 years of
people assuming they can legislate
attackers away from their staff which
is increasingly like provably untrue
at this point in time so focus thinking
about that right but then you've got
stuff like the
um the department of homeland security
with
with uh their binding operational
directive 2001 which were a part of
helping right so that forces every
federal agency in the u.s to start
a vdp and it has things in there like
you know proactive coordinated
vulnerability disclosure
and hack a safe harbor for for basically
exemption against cfa
and dmca and things like that so the
more of that stuff happens
i think the less like the dark side of
it will go down because it becomes less
of a it becomes more obviously an uncool
thing to do
i think part of what we're trying to do
with disclosure is to actually make it
something that people can
almost market it's like here's like you
know the green padlock for the internet
in terms of my maturity as an
organization to receive feedback from
the outside
world if you get consumers to the point
where they're looking at that and saying
i feel safer
working with that person and this person
then i think it's going to accelerate
so yeah that's some of the stuff that's
going on
hi casey um hey so have you
ever had a threat actor
pose as a company to uh try to get you
do some
hacking on their behalf and uh
whether you've had that how did you deal
with it or
what do you do to prevent it or minimize
that risk
we've we've definitely so i'll answer
the end of that first because it's
probably
um the the broadest part of the answer
we check everything so so we're not it's
not a
like click click click start um process
on on the platform and and
we kind of it's honestly it's more
expensive it's more painful for us to
orchestrate it like that but for the
sake of
you know the safety of everyone involved
on both sides that's just a design
decision that we decided to make
plus this is often hard to do so it's
like understanding where people are
actually up to and helping them through
the process of writing a policy and
preparing all that kind of stuff that's
where we insert ourselves so if anything
looks weird coming through that process
that's when it'll get flagged
it's not um i can't think of a threat
actor
specifically we've booted people off uh
the platform
um for basically just you know
exploiting the crowd or doing doing the
wrong thing in that sense
um we've pretty proactively taken a
stand against different industries like
there was a spousal
spyware thing that's uh they got hacked
and basically responded saying we're
going to launch a bug banning program
we're going to talk to hacker 1 and bug
crowd
and we basically turned around said no
you guys can go die in a fire because
that's like you shouldn't exist
so stuff like that is thank you um
yeah it's laterally addressing your
question i think like in terms of you
know
russia or or china or you know like an
apt actor trying to do that stuff we
haven't
we haven't seen that we've seen things
if anything even smells like that we'll
dig right into it to make sure that it's
kosher
so that's how we operate uh do you think
it's actually getting harder like post
the mca where you're seeing
vendors of products putting anti-pen
testing stuff into the contracts you're
signing
and it's just you know more challenging
to kind of bring them in
do the pen test on the product find the
bugs and then have it be reported
through whatever
you know back up to them without having
legal challenges coming back down
yeah um so so votes was a pretty good
example of that
uh there was a blockchain
voting company that decided they could
solve the 2020 election before it will
caught on fire
basically and then a bunch of uh
researchers from
the university of michigan i think kind
of tore their stuff apart and said
y'all shouldn't be doing this especially
with such a short
window and and honestly with it with a
country that at that point in time was
under so much tension it's just a
terrible idea what's not
um they went down the route of using
cfaa and dmca
to basically suppress that research so
it's still a thing that happens that was
last year
it's still very much a thing that
happened off the back of that we um we
actually
through the group that worked with
disclosure put together a open letter
like
jim langman um he's a congressperson
signed it and a whole bunch of other
folk
and we pretty like soundly kind of hit
him on the head and said that's
don't be going there because we've
worked really hard
to help everyone understand that hackers
are here to help not just to harm
and you're actually damaging that part
as well as potentially democracy so
let's just maybe not do that but yeah to
your question it's still very much a
thing that happens i i i think there is
this um
you know this general idea i think this
is relevant to everyone not just the
hunters and
and whatever else because ultimately
this is what we're doing to
deal with our adversary here right um
there's this idea that if it's in the
law that
uh you know it's illegal to hack my
staff then for some reason
the adversary is going to read that law
and obey it even though they're not in
the same country half the time
and whatever else it's silly um
and i think being able to call it out
like that without making people feel
stupid in the process is part of what
we've been trying to do
it's not like hey you're an idiot stop
thinking that because it's dumb
because that's not helpful it's more
like no here's how this works
in real life and here's a better way
like here's the carrot do you want that
instead of
trying to come in with the stick so yeah
hi i'm just just thinking outside of the
box a bit here
you're mainly with bug bounty i assume
you're looking at people coming in from
the outside
but but in the last two months we've had
a
major intrusions in brisbane at sites
i'm maintaining
where people are are selling from an
email
something and and something i've never
seen before
this this thing has started like
battleship galactica it's gone through
not through all the shared folders but
right through the entire operating
system right through all the servers
just bloody demolished everything in the
site
now now now are you doing anything about
and i assume you'd call that a trojan in
a way because it's gone in
it was set to to run at um three or
three a.m saturday morning and just went
through and just boom
now i i fortunately had a i've got a
honeypot collector which basically held
it so i just watched this thing go
and i was able to stop it but not after
massive destruction within two hours
have you got anything that works to
manage that because you've got see once
someone's inside the network and they
can do anything you want
yeah how do you stop that what have you
got to so so this is a
and it kind of goes to what i was saying
before people hear bug bounty and they
think
and by crowd obviously they're sort of
in the name so
um that's the noisiest version of what
we do it's about
15 percent of what happens on the
platform the rest of it's private
and that's a combination of private
external private internal
um you know pay for effort internal uh
doing things like um you know
simulations
uh you know like basically starting to
build in like crowdsource threat
modeling into the process to be able to
help you get ahead of that stuff like in
terms of i've just double clicked on
malware can you help me stop it
no um basically and i don't think anyone
in in the offensive space could could
reasonably say yes to that because
that's more an issue of preparedness
and and you know design like blast
radius containment stuff like that
um but what we can do is say all right
if this was to get loose what would
happen
you know what are the what are the uh
the shorter paths in terms of like
broader network exploitation that are
available that you
should probably mitigate next and then
to be able to do that on a continuous
basis
so an example of that was the um the air
force cloud computing environment
we did a source code review on on the
systems that are
basically pushing workloads up into that
that's like a tssci
skiff environment for for them and we
did
we did testing on that bouncing around
on the inside of there
we've bounced around on the inside like
we've got basically jump boxes and and
and um work into a lot of pretty
interesting places and ones that you
wouldn't
and probably shouldn't honestly do a bug
bounty in terms of going out to the open
market and saying hey you'll come hack
us and we'll pay you
they're not in a position where that's
even necessarily a good idea
but they can access the right kind of
talent for their environment
from you know a broader audience and
then we can basically drop them off
vet the talent make sure people are
trustworthy like if it's government work
you're going to have like
you know validation of sovereignty and
all those sorts of things that come into
it as well that's all
part of how it works yeah so there's one
more up the back we'll do that as the
last one
awesome you talked earlier about um
sorry can you can you just wave at me i
can't see oh there you go thank you
you talked earlier about uh sort of
you're really excited about the
opportunities
to divert young people who might
otherwise sort of go to a life of crime
into sort of more productive roles
within the information security industry
what are your views on how how those
sorts of people
those young people who maybe are leaning
towards um
less savory kinds of action how that's
talked about uh what are your views and
how it's talked about in public in the
media and in the industry
i hate it are there things you think
that are problematic or sort of
alienating those people and pushing them
away from productive opportunities and
other
positive things positive ways you think
we could talk about that
that's a that's a really that's a really
important and a really really good
question i
i honestly think that um you know my
wife and i went to a conference in in
canberra
a couple of years back and there was a
person
talking about you know a 15 or a 16 year
old that they'd gone and
conducted an operation on and arrested
and it was so
like disparaging and and just completely
almost blind
to the circumstances of this like minor
right
and that's that to me is not
you know i can understand why it happens
because it's a it's a fun
you know story and and whatever else and
i think the
sense of a win from having stopped a bad
actor from doing a thing
okay fine um but if you're talking about
someone who's
who's basically arrived at this position
out of need
and not necessarily arriving at that
position out of
a deliberate decision to be you know to
do the wrong thing or to be a bad
person um you're really kind of throwing
everyone else in the same bucket
that could be in that position like the
precursors to that
so i think that's i mean in general what
i've seen is that the idea of
you know people kind of get this thing
that there's like a digital equivalent
of locksmith and a burglar
you know we've been dealing with locks
for a long time so everyone kind of gets
that part but
the cyber version is still novel i feel
like we've made a lot of progress and
just kind of the core understanding of
what we do but as it relates to youth
yeah i think there's
um there's a lot of
a lot of stuff that gets said that's
very careless um
that said i think there's a lot of
things that that are pretty incredible
in terms of promoting it as well so
you know roots asylum in in in defcon
like i take my kids to that
um they love it you know my son loves to
pick locks and and my daughter's
more of a i want to go through code type
of person so that's cool like starting
to see like where their particular
hacker quirks
might be and pulling those things out
and it's positive it's celebrated you
know you tell people that you've taken
your kids to a hacker conference and
they freak out
and i think that's a really productive
conversation to have because at that
point as the parent i can then explain
that no this is what i'm doing
like this is this is actually something
that's incredibly important
to the future of all of us not just me
or them
um and they seem to be leaning into it
so i want to try to help that
so yeah hopefully that answers your
question i think just in general it's
it's not something we're thinking about
enough so that's a really cool question
thank you
another round of applause for casey
please thank you all
you