so for our keynote this morning and and
casey's
kindly came back thanks very much um you
heard one side of the story
uh you heard from a guy that that's
built one of the
the biggest companies in this space over
the last eight years and
in the journey he's been on um now we're
gonna hear it from the other side as a
guy who's
been hacking on stuff for the last five
years or so um and
again is pretty well known for this
stuff come say hi if you haven't seen
him
um he's going to give us his side of the
story in the last five years of what
he's been doing thanks jobs
make him feel welcome
thanks for the kind welcome i guess um
i'll start off with
you know where everything started for me
for bug bounties
i come from humble beginnings my family
is an
immigrant family that moved to australia
in the year 2000
my father always invested in computers
even though he could barely afford it
and i fell in love with hacking because
i
always lost at multiplayer games with my
brother he would beat me at
literally everything and i felt like i
was the worst at everything
so i decided that i'd look into hacking
and see how i could beat my brother in
these online games
through through that i kind of got into
application security and i started
realizing that that was a really big
passion of mine
um as a teenager as a kid and i've been
in the infosec industry for
officially for around six years now um
and i've worked at you know small
consulting firms i've worked at the big
four
high-end consulting firms and now i've
started a a co-founded a startup
so when i was 14 i was working at hungry
jacks at western sydney
i was making 6.50 an hour i worked there
for eight months
and made around 800 i spent all my free
time hacking
i dreamt about an industry that existed
that i could use the application
security skills i picked up
hacking online games and other things
like that and at the time
i was submitting low-risk bugs to
paypal's bug bounty
so you know these first bugs that i
submitted were absolutely terrible
they frankly should not have even been
paid out for but
some of the bugs included things like
apache tomcat disclosure apache http
only cookie disclosure
ssl renegotiation vulnerabilities ssl 2
deprecated protocol
html forms with csrf protection things
that you might expect from a pen test
but not really a bug bounty in the
in this day and age at the time paypal
were really generous and they paid out
for some of these
i was just finding these through google
talking running scanners things like
that it was very low level i wasn't that
experienced
but i really loved application security
and that was i guess a constant
throughout my entire career
um so some of these bugs were paid out
some of these payouts were very small
but they made me realize that i could
get paid for hacking which was a
revelation to me
because at that point i didn't even know
that an infosec industry existed
this blew my mind as a 14 year old i
didn't even know
that an industry existed and it
motivated me to spend all my time
in learning more about application
security i worked really hard to get
into hall of fame pages and just getting
recognition because
i thought even getting recognized for
hacking was
mind-blowing at the time
so the first critical bug i found was an
ssrf vulnerability
in bill me later which is one of the
acquisitions of paypal
in this diagram it just kind of shows
you that there was this jsp page where
you could input a url
and that url was getting fetched by the
server and the contents were being
returned
the url that i used in this input was
business to
port 9080 which is obviously an internal
server
and it was returning the full response
of that url
i discovered this endpoint just by
google docking so nothing super
complicated or sophisticated
um but i did identify that this was an
ssrf vulnerability that should be
reported
so after that paypal paid me 1.5 k usd
and if you remember i worked eight
months at hungry jacks for just 800
so i quit my job at hungry jax i never
showed up again
so before you start hunting um there's a
couple of things that
i kind of want to get clear around bug
bounty hunting and that's
the fact that your application security
skills must be sharp
um it's not something that you can jump
into unless you have dedicated at least
some time
at honing your application security
skills and understanding how
web attacks cloud attacks or even binary
exploitation may work
to a decent extent most bug bounties
are in web applications that is changing
we are seeing cryptocurrencies we are
seeing
more bug bounties with binaries that you
can exploit um
but you know even web application
security is a huge field to navigate
there's client side issues server side
issues cloud platform specific issues
and they all must be studied before
approaching bug bounties uh
in a broader sense you can look at
some free resources like website academy
from portswigger
or you can take a look at pentester lab
if you want to look at some paid courses
that might help you in
in your journey
another thing that's really important in
bug bounties and has been a constant
throughout my career in bug bounties is
the fact of writing high quality reports
the better your report is and the more
time you spent at trying to explain
something as
elegantly as possible the less time it's
going to take the company or the triager
to understand what you're talking about
and therefore it's going to be something
that they would be willing to reward you
more money for because of the time saved
so most reports kind of follow a general
outline of having a summary steps to
reproduce supporting materials
and most importantly the impact the
impact is probably where you should
spend most of your time
both in the contents of the report but
also proving it
and that's how you will get the most
money out of your bug bounty reports
so 2015 that's kind of when i got
started
and getting into bug bounties it can be
pretty daunting i'm not going to lie
like bug bounties can
look as if they're impossible to get
initially
but i did find some things that helped
me significantly in this process
one of them was having a friend that you
could compete with
and be highly productive with as you
motivate each other in finding bugs
and comparing which bugs you find
another thing was setting healthy goals
like for example one bug a week or month
that could be a really good way at
committing to find bugs initially
and it was really important to build
your rep and profile on bug bounty
platforms as
in the future that proved to be very
important in getting invites
to private programs and things like that
um the other message i really want to
get across is there's so much
low-hanging fruit out there
um there is literally low hanging fruit
everywhere i look
still today and i highly recommend
getting into bug bounties if you're
scared about it or if you don't think
you can find stuff i
just recommend you be persistent and
give it a good shot
so some of the first bugs that i
reported were to uh
yeah were things like exposed reader
server got 500
for that just used netcat to look at
that and
look at what was coming back i used the
info command on readers to see what came
back
i could do things like list or keys and
values dos the machine
second order attacks by setting
malicious values it's pretty low level
bug but i'm just getting started in bug
bounties to set the scene so these
aren't going to be anything super
spectacular but i just want to prove to
you
that this is the sort of stuff you can
find on attack surfaces and bug bounties
probably still today another one was
exposed ha proxy statistics so another
easy bug got paid out 500
a pretty simple process i ran nmap
across all the assets
found an open port that looked pretty
dodgy
looked at that open port saw that it was
disclosing some information
and submitted a report around how that
shouldn't have been disclosed and how
you could potentially dos the system
through a cve as well
so very easy to report just getting
started in bug bounties this is the sort
of things you can be looking for
then i reported some open administration
interfaces
you know sometimes programs accept this
sometimes they don't it's all a guessing
game to understand what a program really
does accept until
you start submitting it more often so
they paid out 500
for this and they you know accepted that
bug but immediately after
i i was like okay i found one instance
so i'm going to report
every instance i find as found as a
separate report
so i tried being a little cheeky and you
can see that they closed it as
duplicates
so something that's a bit tricky with
bug bounties is you don't really know
whether or not a company prefers having
everything in separate reports
or they prefer having a single report
with everything grouped together
some bug bounty hunters will exploit the
fact that there is
multiple instances of something and
report them in separate reports
so they get a higher payout and more
reputation but this isn't always the way
to go
um this sometimes is acceptable for some
programs sometimes not for others
so i tried my luck here and they closed
them all as duplicates of the first
issue that i reported
um and you know i thought that i was
still adding value to their defense in
depth and getting paid
for it and doing all of this so i just
want to demonstrate
it's my first year in buck bounties i
still found a lot of low-risk bugs
i was just getting into bug bounties i
wasn't an expert at them
i wasn't finding really critical stuff
but here's an example of some of the
low-risk bugs i was finding
open administration interfaces reflected
cross-site scripting
information disclosure url redirection
and things like that but you can see
there's these payout values still aren't
that bad
for these low-risk bugs so i highly
recommend you know when you're starting
not probably setting the bar too high
for yourself but just committing to
finding bugs in general
that will be better for you in the long
run because you will eventually
find more high-risk bugs and you'll see
that in the evolution and progress i've
made over the last five years
so another concept i want to explain is
high payouts
doesn't necessarily mean that the bug is
complex or hard to exploit
in this example there was a subdomain
hijacking bug
where you could hijack cdn.company.com
through something called high wind cdn
now the only special thing about this
report was i literally got on the phone
with high winds and said that i really
needed this subdomain
um and i convinced them to give me this
subdomain and register it
so that it would redirect to my domain
that little bit of extra effort
and that little bit of persistence is
what led to this payout of 7.5 k
i'm sure many other bug bounty hunters
came across this subdomain
and thought that i can't take this over
because high winds doesn't have a sign
up form or i can't sign up to high winds
over the internet
it just required a little bit more of a
little bit of human interaction to
convince them to give me that asset
and eventually i got paid out a decent
bug bounty for it and this is still in
my first year of bug bounties so it just
shows
how far persistence can take you in this
um another thing that i want to show is
how many bugs that i had closed as n a
so as you start off in bug bounties
you're going to find things that you
think is a security issue
but when you submit it to the company
they respond in a sense that this is not
a security risk for us
and you've just got to accept that
that's um that's kind of the byproduct
of bug bounties you get paid
only when something has a real security
impact to a company
and the company gets to decide what has
a security impact not yourself
so the retrospective of 2015 is that you
know competition between other bug
bounty hunters facilitated growth
having the right mindset and coming up
with logical plans and executing them
led to success
low hanging fruit is everywhere you can
capitalize on this
for me bug bounties were pretty
addictive they caused a rush of
happiness and
that's something that i've always been
chasing over the last five years
and reporting low to medium bugs is
absolutely fine i was just happy that
companies recognized
my work and paid out for my bug reports
the impact determines the payout
so simple bugs can be very impactful and
be awarded a large amount of money
so moving on to 2016 to 2018
where there was a particular focus on
techniques
i got my feet wet in bug bounties and i
focused on techniques which could
amplify my severity of bugs that and the
payouts i was receiving
um this required me to be a little bit
more creative i had to identify weak
spots and attack surfaces
and i had to be able to target certain
companies for these weak spots
i shifted my focus a little bit i was
spending a lot of time on client-side
issues in the first year that i was
doing bug bounties
i realized that i could be focusing
purely on server-side issues
so that i could be increasing impact and
you know some people have different
strategies this was my strategy at the
time focusing on server-side issues
um and throughout this evolution um
a key factor as i've mentioned multiple
times already was persistence in
executing ideas
open mind is necessary to come up with
ideas and
you may or may not know that they're
going to work so you just have to really
believe in yourself
and believe that it's possible to
execute some of these ideas
so one of the bugs that i found during
this period was
uh it it required multiple multiple
steps to victory i can think of at least
seven steps that were required to get to
this point the
bug's title was ability to write
arbitrary scripts to this subdomain
through a misconfigured s3 bucket and it
was pretty wild like i started on the
company's blog site
and then i went from there to a
javascript file from a javascript file
to another api endpoint api endpoint
found
another configuration file in there i
found an s3 bucket
and then finally i was able to write
arbitrary files to this s3 bucket which
was being used elsewhere
you can see that i could have stopped at
any stage of this process
i could have stopped when i had found
just the blog i could have stopped when
i found the second subdomain
i could have stopped when i found the
second api but it was really important
to follow it through
there sometimes is sometimes you do need
to
perform multiple steps to to get to
victory
um sometimes digging deep leads to gold
um another thing that i did during this
period of time was
second order takeovers so for example
let's say your company uses something
like
sas service one and embeds content from
that service across your blog
and things like that you've registered
an account on this third party service
and the urls look something like this
where it's embedding a random id but
your account username is included there
but your company decides to stop using
this service one day and they delete
their accounts
from that from that system what happens
to all the embedded links that are
present in all of the blog posts what
happens if an attacker
registers the same username that you
used to have on this service
well in that scenario you can take over
partial contents of a page
and this is something that i've referred
to as second order takeovers
um so i've reported a bunch of these
over the years and it's usually led to
good payouts
um in this example you can see that i
was paid out two and a half grand
for reporting takeovers for a service
called wufoo which is
embedding forms into pages i could take
over all the forms
so i could make them malicious and i
could say you know submit your username
and password
instead of a real legitimate form
so another thing that's uh really
important
in bug bounties is really looking at the
scope and seeing what the company is
interested in
sometimes you'll find that companies are
interested in any asset owned by them to
be in scope
so for example uber might be interested
in any asset on the internet owned by
uber
which is a really big deal because you
know some of these companies
they operate in almost every country in
the world
and surely some of these countries may
have different processes
policies and procedures when it comes to
developing applications and deploying
them on the internet
so the hypothesis was um if if there's a
huge conglomerate or a huge company like
uber which is operating in so many
countries
maybe they don't have such a tight
security
culture in some of these other countries
and they push out code
that might be more vulnerable than
what's coming out of their primary
operations locations
so it's all about finding weaknesses and
blind spots
in the attack surface
so in this example i tried finding
assets for each country in the world for
my target until i landed on mexico
and there was a number of assets that
belong to a company i was targeting that
were built by some web developer
contractors in mexico
the only reason i know that is because
the company told me that afterwards
these assets were running on
applications specifically made for the
mexican market
there were certain tax laws and certain
things that you needed to
abide to in mexico that required this
custom application to be made
there was almost nothing linking back
the parent organization and these assets
together
things like the whois information server
location infrastructure
code app stack everything was different
except for the css styling
and that was how i identified it it was
through the css styling itself
that i found a pattern across the
internet
and that's how i identified these assets
i found a reference
from the parent organization also
linking to this micro site
that was that that was built for the
mexican market
and this was enough confirmation for me
to start hacking on it
however you can also confirm this with
the program before you start doing that
so all the pages were in spanish and
this was made specifically for the
mexican market but it was vulnerable to
all sorts of things
really simple sql injection payload
where i could sleep for 20 seconds
it was rewarded 5 000 it was really easy
bug
but it was all about the idea of coming
up with concepts
for example there might be weaker
applications in different countries
and following through with those
concepts until completion
another example is i was targeting a
large gaming company
and i found they had specific android
applications for brazilian users
so this triggered my curiosity again and
i downloaded the apk file
reverse engineered it to discover the
api endpoints it was calling
and i found that there was an api
endpoint which would retrieve your
user's details
api v1 slash users slash your id
i simply changed this to slash users
page equals one
and it returned the full details of all
users registered
there was 111 000 users registered and
all of that data could have been leaked
through this vulnerability
it was rewarded seven grand now again
this is a concept where we've just
followed through the idea that
potentially there are weaker
applications in different countries for
these organizations
and we've proven this concept time and
time again
um another great thing to look at is
third-party platforms
so what do i mean by that i mean a
third-party platform is anything like
github
gitlab bitbucket anything that's outside
of your company but
still used by your company it's a third
party even things like servicenow where
you may have all your knowledge base
articles or
an atlassian product where you may have
your internal documentation and tickets
i look for these i look for exposures
through these platforms all the time for
my targets
and i'll often find things like secrets
on github or gitlab or bitbucket or i
might find things on servicenow or i
might find things on some atlassian
products
another creative example is webex i'm
sure many of the companies you've
maybe worked for might have interacted
with have used something like webex
turns out a lot of people don't disable
anonymous access on webex
so if you just put in the
company.webex.com you can start looking
through all of the calendars you can
start
joining events if you wish so i got paid
out 500
as well so that was a really easy bug
an example in third party platforms i
came across this source code
which was for dropbox.company.com and it
had credentials for an ftp server
this ftp server credentials were valid i
was able to log into the ftp server
able to upload some files that led to
persistent xss through flash but one
thing we can be sure of is we can be
thankful for the fact that flash is dead
today
so this wouldn't have been possible in
this day and age for all the modern
browsers
another really cool thing to look at is
dangling ip subdomain takeovers
so when an ec2 instance gets started it
gets assigned an elastic ip
amazon aws manages a huge address space
including all the elastic ips that are
assigned to instances
in many cases subdomains might be
pointing to an elastic ip
to an ec2 instance but what happens when
that ec2 instance is destroyed
that elastic ip gets released in the
pool and someone else can claim that ip
at random
so what happens to the subdomains that
are pointing to these elastic ips
well most likely the dns records haven't
been removed and this is a huge
problem that we see again and again day
in day out
in this day and age so someone else can
potentially control the full contents of
those subdomains as long as they own the
elastic ip those subdomains are pointing
to
this was a technique that i employed
during this period of time and it's
something that i still employ today
in fact something that i'm looking
further and further into
so you can detect this in multiple ways
um back then what i used to do is i used
to rely on things like
ssl certificates i used to rely on the
contents of the page
there's no aws api that lets you easily
detect this
i've literally had dreams where i've
come like i found this magical aws api
that lets me detect this and i've tried
everything as soon as i've woken up from
these dreams but
that's never really worked out and i
haven't found an aws api that even gives
a slight difference in response
or even has a slight timing difference
that will let you determine this
but there are still ways that you can do
this some bug bounty hunters are just
continuously claiming elastic ips from
the pool
checking it with their passive dns data
and seeing whether or not it points to
any domains that they're interested
in i often report bug bounties i often
report bugs to bounties
on this and i get paid out sometimes a
really low amount like 100
sometimes really high amount like a
thousand dollars depends how much
companies care about this and whether or
not there is real impact but this is a
technique that i've been employing for
quite some time now
so here's an example of a report where
i've reported dangling ip subdomain
takeover
i just tell them that look i can see
that there's this subdomain pointing to
this ip address
i can see when you visit this ip address
it returns an application that's
nowhere near related to your company and
returns an ssl certificate that's not
your company's
this is most likely an elastic ip
takeover please take a look at it please
get rid of the record
and that's how i write reports when i
haven't claimed the ip myself
this sometimes gets paid out as i said i
got paid out 100
for this one
so the retrospective for 2016 to 2018
is i'm still finding low-hanging fruit
i'm not like i'm not doing anything
super complicated to find these bugs
there's still a lot of low-hanging fruit
out there but what was important was the
growing process of
really coming up with ideas and
following through with execution
some creativity is required but it's
totally worth it when you do it
i stopped focusing on client side issues
as much and really focus on server-side
issues
and somewhat cloud-based issues as well
persistence was still key in finding all
these security issues
often bugs were found after a
complicated chain of events
and a lot of time was spent mapping
attack surfaces
in different regions and countries like
the two examples i gave you in this
period of time
so moving on to 2018 to 2021
i want to talk about three things i want
to talk about reconnaissance
and what that means to me idols as a
systematic problem and some bug bounties
and zero days as not taboo but something
that you might want to start looking for
if you're interested in finding bugs in
bounties but also reverse engineering
things and
in your free time so
in this year and in these couple of
years
recon was something that had become
second nature to me due to how
repetitive the process was
and i really got to the point where i
needed to define what recon meant to me
because
so many hackers think about recon in a
different way to what i really thought
of recon
and i tried not to deviate from my
processes related to reconnaissance
i found systematic issues in bug
bounties and exploited them for a steady
train of bounties and high severity bugs
identified weaknesses and attack
surfaces holistically
and that was what led to success there
was a shift
of focus to source code analysis to find
zero-day vulnerabilities in vendor
products
that were used by companies running bug
bounty programs
so defining reconnaissance i look at
reconnaissance
in this sort of way where there's
breadth and there's depth
breath you're going far and wide depth
you're going deep into it
so in breath you've got an example like
enumerating all subdomains
enumerating all endpoints enumerating
all cloud resources
finding related domains like
acquisitions and subsidiaries looking at
third-party platforms like github and
bitbucket
but depth is where you really start
looking deeply into the applications
or systems that a company has you might
start doing things like reverse
engineering the javascript
you might discover and test all the
request parameters
you'll test for things like route 53
takeovers and elastic ip takeovers
you'll detect all technologies and
versions across an attack surface
and you'll analyze code and public repos
written by the org
or employees of that organization so you
can see how
the way i define recon is in this
breadth and depth
approach and i make sure that i do both
of these elements as much as possible
i might find a list of a thousand sub
domains when i'm performing the breadth
side of reconnaissance
but i'll be surely reversing the engine
i'll be reverse engineering the
javascript on as many as possible
to achieve the depth component of
reconnaissance
but this is how i see reconnaissance and
this is how i wish more people
saw it and approached it because i think
reconnaissance is quite a large thing to
approach
and it's such a broad term that in our
industry has somewhat
not been defined so well
so how does someone perform recon well
really it's just a matter of putting the
time in recon is really time consuming
but it can lead to some great bugs being
found
following the concepts of breadth and
depth you should always be asking
yourself can i take this concept further
can i go deeper
and you should follow your hunches and
build up your instinct to get a better
indication
of when something may lead to
vulnerabilities i spend a lot of time
reverse entering javascript these days
often to find endpoints parameters
expected values and schemas
so idols one of my favorite programs to
hack on is uber
they represent everything as uuids a
uuid is a random string of a certain
length and it looks something like this
things like user ids vehicle ids
restaurant ids
everything on uber that could be an id
is a uuid
i reported a lot of access control
vulnerabilities to uber from 2018 to
and some of these vulnerabilities were
as simple as putting someone else's uuid
instead of mine
some bugs were more impactful than
others
so my favorite bug in uber was where i
could
obtain the uuid of any restaurant on
ubereats that i wanted to test the bug
on
so i could just click on the restaurant
when i was on ubereats and it would give
me the uuid and the url
you can see it's bold in this slide and
once you've obtained the uuid we can
move to the next step of the exploit but
really i just want to preface this as
like this was one of my least
favorite restaurants that i tested this
bug on so
i wasn't too worried about this bug
actually working but
this is what the request looked like you
could send a request to
restaurantoruba.com
and you could say that this restaurant
is closing early and it's going to
expire at this certain date
you can see that i've put us their uuid
instead of my restaurant's uuid
and then in response it's currently
unavailable
so i didn't expect it to actually work
um didn't like the kebabs that much so
it's okay
but i reported the bug asap this was
probably my favorite bug they paid out
something like eight grand for it
so what that was just one of the many
bugs in uber
that were idol bugs it was a systematic
pro systemic problem for uber
this is something that you can still
find bugs in uber today
where you replace a uuid that's not
yours it's someone else's
and i consider these bugs as low hanging
fruit it wasn't too difficult to just
replace my uuid with someone else's
i just had to understand this is how the
business logic of the application works
and i should try and test the
authorization that's put in there
to see whether or not it's implemented
correctly
a lot of my bugs from 2018 to 2021 were
bugs like this
and moving on to zero days i spend quite
a lot of time finding vulnerabilities in
things like vendor software
so we're thinking about things like
oracle e-business suite
web sphere jira confluence secure file
transfer software
and then things like django python
libraries for example there's still a
sql injection and django hvac which is
still unpatched if you're looking for it
and there's a cloud conf
all the cloud configuration issues in
aws that
you know may or may not be considered
zero days but they're still very
important to look into
i did a lot of this work in source code
analysis
and reverse engineering and finding zero
days not only because
i could use it in bug bounties to report
bugs and these software that companies
were using
but also because it has a huge role in
my current role at asset note where we
detect these vulnerabilities before
anything else does
as quickly as possible so it kind of had
a
two different use cases for me in
looking in this sort of stuff but
what i can say is at the end of the
journey like the tricky part about
finding zero days in vendor software is
not the actual process of finding the
zero day
it's being able to actually find a copy
of the software in the first place to
install on a server
so the barrier of entry though is not as
bad these days
because you can use things like azure
and aws marketplace to deploy vendor
applications
without forking huge license fees and
then you can then perform static source
code analysis
with things like jd gui or pro scion
decompiler
if it's java and you can start looking
for vulnerabilities
a lot of vendors are simply banking on
the fact that you won't be able to
discover software vulnerabilities
because you don't have a copy of the
software
or you can't be bothered to spin up a
copy of their software on whatever
provider the biggest barrier of finding
vulnerabilities in enterprise software
is
actually getting the software itself
so the retrospective from 2018 to 2021
was i took a breadth and depth approach
to all recon performed ensuring i was
leaving no stone unturned
i exploited a wide range of idle
vulnerabilities on bug mounted programs
like uber
where things like uuids were being used
and analyzed the range of vendor
software and middleware to find zero
days
and report vulnerabilities and bug
bounties and ultimately the vendors
this was really effective as well and
reported a lot of cloud security
misconfiguration issues particularly for
aws environments
so the last thing i'll leave you guys
with is just some further reading
i've documented all of this process and
my journey in bug bounties
at these two links hacking on bug
bounties for four years in high
frequency security bug hunting
but i also want to just quickly mention
the fact of imposter syndrome
everyone has it even i have it and it's
something that you know last year in
october
you can see how i had this huge slump i
couldn't find any bugs for a couple of
months
and then i finally got back into it
again and i have this really weird cycle
when it comes to hacking when i find
bugs and i'm finding all these bugs and
submitting it to bounties i feel like
i'm an amazing hacker
but as soon as i've done that maybe two
weeks after i feel like i can't hack
anything if my life depended on it
so this is a continuous cycle that i go
through in and out so if anyone is
dealing with imposter syndrome
i can just say be persistent believe in
yourself and keep on trying
because i don't think that you're a
terrible hacker i just think it can take
some time to get back into it
and it's a difficult thing to do in the
first place to find bugs and bounties
so that's it thanks everyone for coming
to my talk really appreciate it
[Applause]
imposter syndrome is real ladies and
gentlemen um there's a few hands up so
we'll go that way
first that was awesome i love watching
these kind of um
presentations just a quick question um
before anyone goes and quits their job
how how did you find your like obviously
over time
up and down what do you feel that your
average kind of
income stability was over over those
years
yeah so i think um so i can tell you the
exact figures
um this is something i've shared with
other people as well in
my whole bug-bounty career i've made
close to 850
000 uh dollars but i've worked
in jobs in between all of that so i've
i've
as i said i worked at uh security
consultancies i even co-founded a
startup
um what happened is eventually bug
bounties became a lot easier to
participate in initially i had to spend
a really long amount of time
to actually get good at bug bounties but
nowadays i can probably spend three to
four hours
you know every couple of days or
sometimes i won't hack anything for a
month and then look at it really deeply
for a week
and still be very successful i think
what ends up happening
is you start building instinct really
good instincts
for when something may or may not be
vulnerable so you spend a lot more time
focusing uh on specific assets that you
might think are vulnerable just based
off your instincts
so i think over time your experience
increases and you can get more effective
at earning it
as kind of like a side job but initially
there's a huge time investment required
to get to that point
hi in regards to the route 53
vulnerabilities that you found did you
try the bgp hijack
um no i've never done bgp hijacking
myself
but um i'm not really sure if that would
be accepted in bug bounties
um would have to give it a shot that was
going to be my next question can you
report a
bgp hijacker is a bug bounty
you mentioned at the end there with the
enterprise software stuff it's hard to
get a copy of it before you can actually
hack on it
do you find through bug bounties that's
becoming easier like they're actually
putting their software up then for you
guys to go have a crack at it
some companies are doing that but it's
not super common um
i think that most enterprise software
that i struggle to get today
usually it's a really good indicator
that you're gonna find some mad
criticals
if it's hard to get it's likely never
been looked at by anyone else
i'm just going to follow on from that
too have you been reading euler's
because i've seen some software that
specifically says no reverse engineering
i've probably broken all of those eulers
at this point
hey uh do you feel like it's a job or a
hobby uh for me it's a hobby
um definitely something i love doing
um yeah i had a question and just wanted
to
call out as well i actually spoke at
nalcon yesterday talking about the
evolution of
new uh research and attack classes and
and credited you and naffi
um around the uh the recon stuff because
that's definitely a thing now like the
internet's always had its ass hanging
out but i didn't really realize that
and then you guys went and basically you
know i think set a whole bunch of stuff
in motion
um and asset notes part of that so you
know props
um but question for you was just um you
know with with the different things that
you've learned like how
how much does that go to finding the
particular types of bugs or the type of
you know kill chain or whatever else
that kind of most suits you like is
there stuff that you
just probably wouldn't hack because
you're not interested um
that's a pretty good question i think
over time i have
like a acquired a taste in certain
softwares that are running or certain
systems that are running
for example i really enjoy hacking iis
servers
um done a lot of made a lot of content
around it but
things like um there's a big airline
that uses iis
and they award miles for all the bug
bounties
so one of my favorite platforms to hack
on is
that bug bounty and all of the iis
servers that i've come across
i've now come up with a methodology for
iis servers that's
highly effective almost all the time
so i always enjoy doing that because i
know it's going to lead to results
sometimes more modern web technologies
like
you know if i'm targeting ruby on rails
i don't enjoy that as much because i
don't have such a great methodology
there
there's definitely things i could
probably invest more time into to get
better at
but i think that's the process of just
getting better over time
hey sharbs um have you ever had recon
failure where you've thought you're
hacking the right
target and actually you submitted this
awesome bug
and they actually go uh that doesn't
belong to us
um yeah i've had that for example um
uh i found a server that had a moodle
setup page and i thought that it was
owned by that organization so i hacked
all of it and i submitted it to them
the way i hacked it by the way was using
uh my sequel local
uh file read through the setup stages
if you can specify a mysql server you
own you can then read arbitrary files
and even perform ssrf on behalf of the
server
um so i used that i got access to it i
submitted the bug and they were like
yeah this is just an elastic ip that we
no longer own
so i i probably hacked some random
person's moodle server
um did the random person pay you no i
got no no
no payout for that thanks
let's get another round of applause for
[Music]
shops
thank you
you