alright everybody let's get started
again welcome welcome you are in the
Gold Room and we have up on stage
daydream and Eric and whether you're
looking for a job or whether you
yourself are looking for job applicants
they're gonna talk to you about how you
can take back control of your job search
in a talk called it's not you your job
search is broken let's give them a nice
round of applause all over the u.s. from
somebody that's constantly being asked
about how to get into the field and how
do I get training and supportable
besides really answers that so those
that sponsor to us others you're awesome
because we have a problem not only do we
have a shortage problem yes it's true we
have a shortage we also have a
recruiting problem a job searching
problem and we have a retention problem
so this talk was inspired by Eric who is
our chief security architect at cyber
s/n and had spent years and years job
searching as a security professional
only to be horrified each year worse and
worse and then found us and was like
teacher we gotta we gotta get out there
and talk about this we've been together
two years he's learned a lot about the
business and was like I gotta help get
this out there so I'm the founder and
CEO of cyber SM I got into cyber
security in 2007 by asking to take my
sales model that I had built in staffing
recruiting for IT and software to build
rapid7 sales and so the founders I had
worked for in staffing owned rapid7
that's how I got into cyber I then went
became a CEO of one of our other
companies before I built this company
and it really stems from the love I'm a
social promote justice major my buddies
ended up being all cyber people and then
I started watching everybody just have
terrible search problems and I thought
oh my gosh I got a service industry so
that's where we were born I also founded
a few years ago a company called brain
baby org you can see it out there that
is a play to stop those fades and and
get the diversity problem solved and we
staff conferences with Steam students
doesn't matter what you're studying
you're interested in working RSA
blackhat what have you we RSA we stopped
this
so solving big problems so that's who we
are and native lives here in the area my
mom's from Butler so I'm always happy to
be here we're a national firm doing
really cool stuff so what we want to
share with you is what is going on so
that you can empower yourself we're
gonna use stories of Eric's search a
little bit in later in this so that you
can see like how do you avoid that
because you probably have already had
that experience or you know somebody
that has and so we're really going to
show you first of all how it's broken
how agencies fit into this thing and
then what you need to do to take control
of your own search or if you're hiring
what you need to do to find the talent
because the statistics show that
eighty-nine percent of the cyber
security marketplace will talk to a
recruiter doesn't mean they get to talk
to a recruiter doesn't mean if they do
talk to recruiter they know what the
hell they're talking about it just means
that they they're not completely happy
where they work and most of that is due
to two things it is due to you know
their unhappiness is due to not taking
security seriously or people those are
the two things we hear so knowing that
89% of the marketplace would love to
work somewhere that gives them more
happiness and they can't find it it
really bothers me significantly
meanwhile like our dating apps all right
right like we figured it out I could go
on a date tonight in any city with
whatever profile I wanted to go on and
it would be fun and that's crazy that
you all can't find each other in that
same capacity it's nutty so we're
solving that we'll talk about that a
little bit at the end so let's look at
what's going on okay the digital era
started really truly about ten years ago
in terms of really advertising and and
getting out of print and newspapers and
what-have-you and so one of the first
things I noticed when I got back into
staffing after leaving it ten years and
going into software was the whole SEO
content piece really skewed what's what
contents being given to you so for
instance meaning it's free now back in
the day before running an ad you would
never be pages long of a job description
ever because we would pay five thousand
dollars to put a paragraph in the New
York Times LA Times Fawcett right over
it was on a Sunday and that's your one
shot and that was your one entry point
into finding people
getting four jobs and you better know
how to write your content it better make
sense and you better speak their
language well today it's free you can do
pages and you got to deal with SEO which
means you got to put keyword searches in
your write in your resume and your job
descriptions 10-15 times each keyword so
of course you're all working everybody's
working who's got time to job search
this makes it incredibly incredibly hard
so this is the number one problem I'm
sure all of you now at this point those
of you that are a little bit seasons
have experienced that you can read an ad
and you know whether or not they know
what they're doing in their security
practice right or if they're just
cutting and pasting somebody's ad which
is typically what most people are doing
so this is a major problem it's the
number one thing we do when we come into
serve as a client is sit down and really
understand what are the tasks what are
the projects what percentage of their
time are they working on that and so
this is a big big piece why the
marketplace is so messed up everybody's
just working on keywords and if you're
in fiber it's not like software and IT
this is not a business of technology
it's a business of safety and security
and yes there's some tech involved lots
of tech don't get me wrong but it's not
about being a technology and so there's
35 job categories 150 different titles
adding to it every day seven different
profiles of a security engineer that
doesn't happen in IT right so this is
very very complicated and we need to
start words matter and we've given words
to not matter now and this is a big big
piece of this
so am I qualified am I not if you're a
woman we've all tested we know that
women don't respond to ads unless they
know a hundred percent they can do the
job now whether or not we can we're
gonna change that but that's the way it
is so think about what has happened to
all these different results and just
having this bad content so this is one
reason why job searching is broken right
contents bad and if we've got bad
content and you're all working how do
you have time you don't want to talk to
people that you don't have the job for
you so it's a big mess all right so this
is a big piece of it here's the other
piece of it so my goodness well you know
we get through all of that we come in we
figure out what we're looking for we can
identify the talent get them in front of
it no problem we'll pay whatever and the
reality is they won't pay whatever
their salary bands have to be changed
and now we're waiting on offers three or
four weeks and we're losing candidates I
see a lot of heads nodding it's
maddening so this is a big piece of why
job searching so broken right now is
that people don't have correct salary
data or they want to put cyber people in
IT you know categories which as of this
last year the salaries have raised 25
percent over IT it used to be 15 it's
now 25 percent so trying to do that
doesn't work and so we get you even when
they find people they're not able to
onboard them because of these salary
challenges and getting signatures and so
this is a bit of a mess and we'll talk
about this at the end in terms of how do
you talk if you're in you know looking
for a job how do you talk about money
what did the equal pay do to job
searching which has already been
institutionalized in Pennsylvania so
what is that all about we'll talk about
that at the end that's a big piece
internal hiring practices most companies
they're pretty archaic the real sad part
about this is that we force internal
recruiters to speak cyber and they can't
it's not gonna happen you can't speak
every language there is you can't it's
just not possible I had to build
products for my you know staffing
specialist to interview from and take
job orders from so there's just no way
you can put that burden but we do and
the other problem I see here which is
pretty mind-blowing is that there aren't
staffing agency budgets that HR is
willing to give to cyber but they give
it to IT and software all day long it's
SuperDuper strange I'm still seeking to
figure this one out so in the meantime
I've been telling everybody put it in
your own budgets put your you know
staffing budget in your own budget don't
rely on HR there's no way you can staff
your teams without a specialized
staffing partner it's just not gonna
then most cyber professionals aren't on
LinkedIn and even if they are they're
just not interested in talking to
everybody who doesn't speak cycle so
it's really hard and then on top of that
just you know internal practices of like
giving tests and all these things that
just get in your way that make no sense
so it's a it's pretty bleak and then
like I said the delayed it's on average
I did a research study on average people
wait six months before they
come to me six months meanwhile we can
fill it in 30 days with somebody that's
really gonna be happy to be there
a we've got the reach but be it's
because people aren't generally in love
with their company and I can choose my
clients and find good stuff but you know
so anyhow at the end of the day it's uh
it's pretty hard to you know it's
impossible unless you speak the language
all right so I'm gonna transition over
to Eric in a minute here but this purple
unicorn I mean how many of us have heard
in the cyber space like oh I'm a unicorn
or I want a unicorn right like that's
like the common thing a purple unicorn
or you know I'm looking for a purple
unicorn for a long time I used to think
oh that's so cute you know like meaning
that we all think of ourselves as rare
and we are rare and then I realized well
what that means is people are doing
three jobs and get purple unicorns don't
want to be purple unicorns anymore I
started you know the purple unicorns are
like hey can I get some help over here
and can we hire people and and so now
I'm like hate telling everybody to stop
thinking it's a good thing that you want
a purple unicorn because purple unicorns
don't want to be purple unicorns they
don't want to do three jobs and they
want teammates so but this is a syndrome
that we see that people because the
budgets are so under-budgeted cyber has
come hot and fast and CEOs and the cost
has come hot and fast and it's hard to
get that money and so they've made it
such that people are doing three jobs
and it's a disaster actually so I say
let's not make this so cute anymore and
let's recognize what we're saying when
we when we feel good about being purple
unicorn I you don't want to be
pigeonholed into three jobs forever so
on that note I'm gonna pass over to
another purple unicorn it takes to share
his experience and what-what happened to
him when he was job searching and then
I'm going to tell you all how to avoid
that it's a very common stuff yeah
joining Cypress and I worked as a
security architect at a defense
contractor mid Johnson Pennsylvania and
I went through the whole game of growing
my career so a tiny sans classes and
getting gr certifications SCS SP
learning continuing to volcana keep off
technology and so great company can
learn a lot I love that place
things change and careers want to evolve
so I started looking and I thought oh
great cyber is hot industry with all my
certifications and my experience it's me
no-brainer right create a resume launch
it sir again calls from recruiters hi
every time
hey what do you do what are you looking
for same pitch same spill never once
that I get the feeling that they're
critically understood what I was saying
so I was trying to explain to them what
is packet capture what is an IDs how do
you manage a firewall and through the
process I was like man's frustrating
right so what I did is I reluctantly
went on some job interviews that I quasi
interest in but you know want to see
more and interesting things happen I'm
gonna share a few stories with you what
happened one of the companies is a major
industry in this town I went through did
the phone screen everything was cool
salary was right when in great interview
aced it right didn't get a job offer
called up and said hey this is anything
coming to pipeline they're like now
sorry you were looking for another
candidate oh cool like you found
somebody more qualified like what
happened give me some feedback so I can
read define my job search their answer
was astonishing it was um you're the
most technical qualified candidate came
through certifications skills everything
you weren't a cultural fit like whoa did
I say something wrong like what happened
like you wore a suit to the interview
what you wore a suit to interview I'm
like what was this most the where well
we're more relaxed culture so you're
coming from a defense contracting your
worth suit more and more of a t-shirt
and jeans tight place so we're gonna
pass on you okay
the other interesting interview I went
on a recruiter call me and said I see
you have a lot of different firewalls on
your background do you happen to know
Palo Alto make sure I use it small cases
but I don't know anything big time
none of the layer 7 application layer
stuff but I can work my way through it a
little bit training I could figure it
out right okay cool so submits my resume
they're going suck the interview about
an hour into it the one individual who's
won a firewall team started ask me all
these Palo Alto questions I'm like dude
cool I was a checkpoint guy and iptables
guy the Juniper guy I wasn't really a
pal out to go I did a little bit it's
like well why'd you listen you arrest me
I'm like I didn't assign him my resume
and so now he's like well it's right
here and he hands me a resume and I see
that and I start seeing all this other
content on this resume I'm like it's not
my resume he's like well yeah it is cuz
here it is
and I am floored like my face is red I'm
like this isn't my resume and the
interviews one side I'm like guys like
too many things are off thank you but no
thank you and just abandoned it I mean
they got on the phone and it's called my
recruiter it's like yeah you mentioned
so I doctor up your resume well what did
you tell me this and you're like no no
this is how we get you in a door so at
this point I'm I'm just over it over it
right I go to our saying and I sat down
next to daydream and I just wanted to
drink one of the cocktail and she's
sitting next to me I'm like oh hey what
do you do it she's like I'm a recruiter
like and she's like why and I start
explaining this right and grant up a few
drinks in and so we developed this
relationship from my misery and from
there she tells me it's not always like
that and after joining cyber SN and
realizing it there's a lot of things to
go behind the scenes in recruiting and
HR just as a systemic problem and it
wasn't just me it this is out there so
what we want to do is from this store is
what did we learn from it and also what
we arm you guys with as you search for
your next stage so based upon my yes
really just to shed some more light on
our teach security officers in the room
he literally got up after about five
minutes of he's like says
his CSO like why don't you talk to her I
saw it go down do is hysterical but
again I get it I know most recruiters
are terrible and I also didn't introduce
who I really was I just said recruit of
it anyhow so so let's talk about this
the his clothing so what I what what do
I want to do I want to tell you take
your own job search in your own hands if
you were going through my firm we would
say to the to the client what do you
want them to wear and we would tell you
so if you don't have that support you
need to ask and it's not to say that you
know maybe he wouldn't have never wanted
to work in a place like that because
that's pretty messed up of a way to deal
with people and yet give yourself the
opportunity to say no to them versus
them say no to you and maybe it's just
one person that blew it from that
perspective and you know why put your
destiny in the hands of one person that
may or may not be in this firm or even
important in this firm to your success
in the firm so the idea is empower
yourselves ask ask whoever is setting
you up on the interview what should I
bear we call it prep and package in our
organization like did you prep and
package that person so not only what to
wear who you know are there tricks to
getting in the building there's nothing
worse than like not finding the building
interest feeling like you might be late
rushing like you're not gonna kick it
off right so things like tricks to
getting into the building who's gonna
greet me who do I ask for like take that
into your own hands so that you don't
have any of these problems when you show
up right the the resume piece we'll talk
about in a minute when we talk about how
to manage your recruiters if you're
working with recruiters and the
agreements that you make up front let's
talk about them in a minute so so ask
all the prep questions Who am I meeting
for get let's get their first and last
name do their look them up on LinkedIn
ask questions about them any particular
style that they interview with do they
give tasks how long do you expect
they'll be with each person these are
all things again we would do so that you
show up feeling like you know what's
gonna happen so do it for yourself right
ask questions about them is there gonna
be a test right the getting in the dress
code and then like I said test so I do
this so they don't think that on here is
it's important to be interested and
interesting and every conversation so
the more prep you do before you show up
shows you're taking a really great
interest in the job you're going after
so even before you walk in that door
you're more qualified than the other
candidates going in because you did your
homework you're really interested in
you're not just going through the
motions because even though you're in
your female from all places they're
interviewing multiple candidates you
want to set yourself apart yeah yeah I
didn't see that but the video there's a
lot of video interviews test it can tell
you how many times that goes awry and
then people are nervous and sweating and
it just takes away from it being great
the whole being interested interested
thing is like again you decide if you
want to work at the company
don't let them decide so if you come
with your game every time even if you're
not sure you want the job you'll have a
chance to see if you want the job
because you'll stay in the game of the
interviewing process you'll get to the
end and if you don't you don't but at
least give yourself the chance so being
prepared being interested asking good
questions I'll get you in the position
to make that final decision of do you
want to work there there is no question
that people are looking for you all even
though it doesn't feel that way it's
really about weeding through the noise
okay so your your recruiters so so I'm
gonna tell you in a minute about the
recruiting you want to do that first
yeah let's go back and let's tell
Stephanie and sure to do that let's do
that okay it's gonna freak you out let's
just do it a lot of it freaked me out
the second time around and I learned
some stuff like most staffing agencies
don't share candidates never knew that
my 13 years in staffing we were a group
we'd share across continents it didn't
matter but in most staffing agencies I
learned that do I bring you in and I'm
the recruiter that brings you in you you
don't get to see other jobs that my
fellow recruiters have what it's
mind-blowing to me so now what happens
in your life is dictated because of my
commission check
are you seriously freaky-deaky as I call
it so which is one of the reasons why
I'm a platform to transform a job
searching it is ridiculous it's almost
like it stupid human capital beyond
human capital its ownership of humans
disgusting so when you go work with an
agency you ask them do you share
candidates and if they don't do not
participate
that is ridiculous do not participate
force them to have good hygiene as
humans so what this means is even though
you're working with one recruiting
agency that recruiter may not share you
unless they're colleagues so yeah it's
very silent yeah yeah yes on purpose
because quote that's their Commission
check super gross
okay so there's contingency and search
firms and retain search firms retain
traditionally has only been for
executive staffing c-level staffing
which means if it's retained they're
gonna put some money up front they're
gonna pay you up front they'll pay you a
third upfront a third and thirty days
and then a third when the candidate
starts that's traditionally only been
executive contingency is where the bulk
of staffing is and contingency means the
staffing agency does not make a penny
until you've been at the org ninety days
like find you get you there you need to
be there ninety days okay so what do you
think that breeds like who works for
free other than people they're just
trying to wheel and deal in life in our
life situations it's nutty
absolutely nutty and I never I was
always contingency for all my years but
because we should worked in groups and
stuff you'd walk in and I can show you
ten opportunities in two days so you
know as a team so we didn't care we were
you know sharing and working together
but you put contingency on top of an on
shared model it's even worse right I my
business today is forty five percent in
retained engaged even though our
specialty is engineering practitioners
red team blue team doesn't matter I our
threat that that's our our bulk of our
business I'm not touching it unless
you're putting skin in the game not with
the problems that we've gotten cyber
today and well I can go deep in my
conspiracy theories of whether people
really want to fill jobs or not I would
talk about that another time so so so
understand that the way that the
industry works is it there's no license
you don't have to have any training and
then you get a bunch of people on the
phones working for just the Commission
check make nothing unless
it happens it's uh it's a silly cheating
one of the eye-opening experiences me
was whenever I was interviewing the one
was a recruiter in town here he's like
hey I don't understand cyber which is
awesome like so he was very aware of it
and very forthcoming and I'm like oh
cool how long you been his new staff
he's like dude six months just months
ago I was working at an hour primarily
car okay so how are you qualified to
represent me to a company right and what
I learned is there's no license you
don't have to go take an exam or get a
degree in recruiting you show up and
here you go right how does that person
gonna represent you and your career
because we're all professionals here we
all are going places right you want that
person to be your agent and really know
what you're doing yeah super weird so
the other problem that you may or may
not if your hiring manager you probably
do know but the relationship between
agencies and external agencies and
internal staffing departments is forward
I mean in fact the platform that I'm
building hit me in the second week
because we were talking to a fortune 100
that was yelling at second week of
business already got my website up we
already got an offer from a big company
that you would know that was breached
for a security engineer and this HR
person is ripping our heads off and it's
like you know what I left this entry ten
years ago I forgot about these people I
have to get out of this I can't do this
I need to empower them or somehow
empower the managers there's this
three-pronged inside out that's terrible
we're fighting over budgets right so
we're brought in but meanwhile we're
taking their budgets that's why I'm like
put it in your own budget get out of
this you do it for software and
technology all day long get out of that
it's ugly ugly ugly it's I hate it
we work our best to make that not happen
oh we've got to be really good at
communication cuz it's hard yeah what we
do is we go I wanna we go and talk to
our manager directly so we want to know
exactly what you're gonna do and then
we're gonna find the best candidate for
you yeah we're not gonna work we're not
gonna work a job we're not talking to
the hiring manager and so that's like oh
well you can't talk to our hiring missus
wait what are you talking about so so
that world is pretty crazy and bizarre
and so the other thing is if you are
submit your resume and a recruiter
submits your resume or to recruiters so
symmetry resume you're out so we'll talk
about it with managing your recruiters
here in a minute but that you gotta you
got to understand those referrals and so
every time an agency's three four
a candidate you get six months to a year
ownership of that which means if they
hire you and anytime in the next six
months or a year the agency gets paid so
you get a double referral they're not
going to touch it which is why and let's
just move on to that in terms of
managing your recruiters again you have
measurable agreements one agreement is
they do not alter your resume whatsoever
and you make that clear I'm gonna work
with you don't get to alter my resume
I'm gonna work with you you do not
submit my resume unless you ask me first
right so if you all take control your
search write down everywhere you sent
your resume anywhere that anybody's talk
to you about a job you document it all
somebody calls you with an opportunity
you can check your work make sure you
haven't been submitted maybe somebody
else called you about the same job you
want to be clear and who's done what and
figure it out you do not want a double
referral so in my firm if anybody ever
sent out somebody's resume without
confirming with that person it would be
grounds for termination that is terrible
again
we will not be causing problems we need
to be solving problems so however a lot
of agencies use resumes to quote open
doors to try and get in the account
right got your resume you're a hot cyber
person let me try and get in here so you
have to make the agreement with them
upfront they're not gonna make it with
you like we do and sometimes what
happens is these larger organizations
you may go and fly for one job but then
another job pops up three months later
you want apply to that and sometimes
you're never called back for that job
and it's nothing because you're not
qualified it's because you were locked
in on this particular department that
they're not sharing you over there and
there's no way you could get ahold of it
yeah the only good part is if you have a
good recruiter they can put a call and
push it through is like why is this
can't get ignored
what are you doing this can is periphery
you have to move on or else he's gonna
get picked or he or she it's gonna
picked up by another company so move
yeah I mean you're a recruiter ought to
be your advocate your agent I honestly
don't know how people get hired without
us it's fascinating I'm starting a live
greenroom situation where I get to share
stories because I'm listening constantly
I love understanding what's going on
and it's pretty mind-blowing types of
things that we have to do yeah let's
talk about why I recruited yeah so this
is a trip right so my entire career I
was trained and you know and how
everybody used to handle money is what
what are you making today
yeah that's what everybody started with
what are you making today and that
always tended to be just salary like
nobody looked at total copic which is
salary what are you making today and so
what we would tell everybody is look
when you get asked question make sure
that you talk about the whole package do
not just answer the question with your
salary because you may have more
vacation you may have a different higher
bonus you may have thought you think
that you got to get it all out there car
phone whatever it is cars the old days
huh so that was old school and so when
you get asked the questions we'd say
give them everything tell them
everything well here we are
2018 and we now have the Equal Pay Act
does anybody raise your hand if you know
what the Equal Pay Act is Wow okay so
we've got like 10% in here that or maybe
15 okay so the Equal Pay Act came to be
because to help women and minorities
make the same income as other
professionals and so the idea was that
women don't negotiate and they're
traditionally taken advantage of because
they're a woman from the perspective of
money and so they start out lower and
then they never catch up even though
they're in high-ranking positions
they're still making less than their
male peers and so what went into
Congress years ago was solving that
what's the Equal Pay Act well it finally
hit this year it's taken a couple of
years to get into play and one of the
most interesting things about this and
I'll tell you how to handle it but the
quick that the law says I can I ring
organization it doesn't matter what
position you hold I can't ask you what
your base salary is I'm not legally
allowed to ask you anymore and so that's
supposed to stop basing the offer on
what you are last making and base the
offer on industry standards and what
other people in the company are making
and it's working it so works all story
oh my gosh and it's just happened this
year but in we do every time we place
somebody in the organization there's a
mail that goes out of the story and what
have you and we all the stories are
including $50,000 raised
$60,000 raised no joke because they have
they're just going by what everybody's
making in the company and what the
industry nobody gets asking the question
any more it's fascinating and guess what
they're men so for those of us that
thought that we were you know women are
gonna get special treatment or whatever
it was always some you know people
getting upset about that law I'm not
here to tell you all its benefiting
everybody it's benefiting everybody it's
super cool so so they may not ask you
you can decide to divulge it it's not of
course you legally can tell anybody what
you're making it's just that they can't
ask so you know what ends up happening
now is people are gonna ask you what you
want
yeah and they definitely have you know
what do you want what's it gonna take to
get you it's a really being put in your
court and I'll tell you what I said back
in the you know before the law and I
still believe it today don't quote a
number because whatever you quote is
either what you're gonna get and you
could have gotten more and you left some
money on the table or it's too low and
use me too high and you priced yourself
out of the job and you would have taken
it for less but you were playing what
you thought maybe was the negotiation
game or whatever and nobody wants to
hire somebody thinking oh well they
think I'm paying them less than they're
worth or they want so it really could
mess up the deal for you so instead you
say you know what I'm all about the
total package which is the job the
opportunity itself the people the entire
package of what else you have
beyond the salary I want to know
everything and really until I have all
that information I couldn't tell you
what I'd take as the base salary what
did you have in mind you know start
picking their brain a little bit hear
what they have to say and then again
stick with the I don't know until I hear
everything that you have offer and
really that means finishing even the
interviewing process because truthfully
nobody comes to my agency because of but
there's just that's not that's not it
right I mean you guys that's not it it's
really more about the job the people
maybe location can you work remote I
mean that was one of the biggest
challenges for York which was that you
remote you know your wife's a doctor you
raise your two children
and the funny thing is like frost
remotes no problem it doesn't matter of
it for meaning you could still help but
the he didn't people didn't know how to
you know represent you wrote at that and
talk to folks and sell you based on that
which unfortunately you have to you know
that's what the marketplace is because
we're not dating apps yet we don't have
that down yet you need an agent I'm
gonna create one though or I have so
let's talk about the interview fails so
this is another thing like how many
times we get in an interview and we say
one thing and we come out of her mouth
and we think that we answered the
question right and then somebody
misinterprets it so I just picked a few
like three here to go over and these are
generally common like so I don't answer
these yeah why are you why why are you
looking to leave your current job what's
what's the safe answer yeah well okay so
truth sells you can tell them all about
truth go with truth however words matter
and he can say one word that it gets a
reaction and say another word and it
gets a different reaction and it's the
same context so you must think that you
must practice you must understand
without knowing the truth your truth I
you know can't necessarily give you the
answer however truth sells now I don't
like my boss it's probably one of the
most common common things nobody wants
to hear that that's not the answer that
they want to hear so what do you do if
it's you don't like the people you don't
like your boss and you still want to
speak truth well go through your list so
what I took what I said leave all-time
is first make a list what are all the
things is it really just the boss is
there is there like career aspiration
stuff that's missing is there maybe of
you know the commute is really long
maybe there's other things that it's all
truth and maybe the dot the the the boss
one is number one but who cares if the
career path one is there use that
because people get a little weirded out
even though we all should be able to
relate that you know so it really is
about like first put all your reasons
down on a piece of paper figure out
which ones will be less challenging for
people to get you know and
and talk to practice it really have it
down because this is the number one
thing people are looking for they want
to hire on passion they want to hire
like that you you're gonna be happy here
you're gonna be passionate about what
we're doing and so you know I tend to
think that the best way is to focus on
the role and the responsibilities and
and tackle it that way it's a it's a
tricky tricky thing for sure and what
ends up happening is there's a when you
ever you have these interviews that are
multiple people like we've been on them
where you go through rounds of three
five people a few of them want to see
what's good and you what can you bring
those are the really experienced
interviewers there's a few people that
go on the committee that just want to
find something wrong with you me a
reason why I can't hire you and those
are where you're these land mines you
really have to be cognitive because you
can ace interview with those other
people and that one person finds
something wrong and just it's like hey
let's move you more people let's go on
pretty soon you're kicked to the curb
and everybody forgets about you it's
super true we're all just because we're
not trained on hiring naturally we're
looking for reasons not to hire even
though we met your brain may not tell
you that I can tell you that in that
every time we have a you know somebody
interviews and all my years of
recruiting like the first things out of
their mouth when you say how did it go
it's always the bad and even when they
end up hiring that person they still
start with the bad or the things that
they thought weren't there because
they're just looking for that majority
of what we do is coaching is really get
back on the phone of higher manager well
what did they do good yeah yeah Mon this
is what you can do like the thing you're
thinking about is so minor and so like
you're overanalyzing it yeah tons and
tons of coaching cuz video like you said
there's a committee and you know new
managers and do I fight for this person
cuz I like them but somebody else in the
in the company said no to them and even
though it reports to me should I take
that on should I challenge that person
oh my goodness and so imagine if you
don't have an agent sticking up for you
to find out well what happened and what
was asked and well why did they ask them
that question that question has nothing
to do with this job and defend you
that's why I'm like how does it even
happen without us you know it's pretty
interesting what we didn't do the
weaknesses one oh yeah yeah or two more
actually so the other common thing is
what are your weaknesses
been asked that question sitting here
hands it's the worst right again be
ready for it what's your answer how much
you know can't come from truth without
saying you don't know how to document
you know and then whatever you find
coming out of your mouth when you're
preparing when you're writing down
things fix that to make your weaknesses
your strengths do you know we only have
weaknesses when we don't know there are
weaknesses typically in my world that
being said it is it is true that people
will ask this question I want something
significant so what is that gonna be for
you you know for me I'd be like I Drive
by you know I drive by every executive
in my company I just sit down you know
and some of them love it and some of
them are like oh my god I'm gonna you
know they're they're pulling their hair
out they're pinching themselves under
the dust it's super uncomfortable for
them and that's a weakness I shouldn't I
need to pay more attention to that I
don't want them uncomfortable I do love
to just drive by and let's do this so
that's what I'd say if somebody asked me
so you got to think about it and prepare
for it and then where do you see
yourself in three years this is the fun
classic one right and and also difficult
to answer and so think about it so the
good news is that in your profession in
cybersecurity there are you know where
you want to go and so what I tell people
is don't be afraid put it out there you
know you might be an analyst today you
want to be a chief information security
officer great say it don't hide it
anybody this doesn't like you because of
that you don't want to work there
anybody who doesn't like the path that
you've decided to choose and that's
holds that against you great you've
eliminated them right instead of waiting
till the end to be told they don't like
you when you don't even want to work for
them and then you your psyche gets
damaged like no be yourself put it out
there what is the answer to this where
do you want to be in three years and put
it out there like I said it isn't like
it the market the market will absorb you
in a great way it might be painful as
hell but once you land it'll feel good
so be truthful be prepared like write
your answers down think about them what
if somebody said that to you when you
were interviewing them would you like
that
how does it let you know words are
SuperDuper impactful they start wars and
they end wars and I think about that
every day when I'm speaking is that I
can blow stuff up good enough or I can
calm stuff down I can move things
forward or I can make it go back just by
my words just by what I say to people in
at the office all day long clients
doesn't matter who it is I can make that
happen so can you we all do the best
part about these questions is they're
gonna ask them to every single
candidates interviewing so if you could
own these you move their front line yeah
yes yeah yeah you separate yourself
you're not you not you no sweating
you're ready you're putting it again I
just want you to keep thinking about you
decide whether they hire you not they
decide you're taking control you're
showing up ready you've got information
you're interested you're interesting now
it's all in your seat you know you get
to make this let's talk about how we
find the jobs okay
you go I'm gonna drink some Drive Zion
you all know how my executives feel now
so yeah how do we find these jobs you
job we keep hearing there's so many
cyber jobs and there truly are remaining
industry there was so many vacancies
there but how do you find them we got so
many different job boards you got in
Dean you got monster you got all kind
different laces look but not everybody
say each job works they each cost
different fees right and a lot of
companies think like hey we're such a
popular brand they're gonna come to our
website our career page and find it
reality is they're not you're not and
then you're gonna get there and you're
gonna read the job description some of
you wrote it from the beginning of our
talk we said is there vague they're
gonna copy and paste and it's not gonna
be the dog you're gonna blow by and
you're gonna board or move on so
unfortunately and so link LinkedIn is
there and I know that is cyber
professionals 10 minutes the cyber
professionals we are gonna sit of what
we put on social media for operational
security you're not gonna get fined
unless you're not on LinkedIn yeah it's
your choice it's a choice it's
definitely choice we're all about
privacy and that doesn't give it to you
that being said that is the number one
place people go and the interesting
piece about it is that they're gonna
message
hell out of you and you've got to decide
whether you're gonna talk to them right
so there's nothing convert about it
you're really you know not able to
figure out who they are very easily so
here's the deal there are more technical
recruiters than there are technologists
which by implication says there's more
to recruiters than there are of you all
because people lump it under there is
that not the craziest thing you've ever
heard so that means these boards are
made for agencies they're made for us
okay they're not made for you by any
means all their money comes from us we
pay I pay LinkedIn a hell of a lot more
money than you'll ever have to pay them
to have the same access like $3,500 a
month per a year per recruiter where you
pay 60 or so for the same for the same
access okay so that's where they make
their money and then and then posting
the ads are and Linkedin is the most
expensive fifteen hundred bucks or so
you know but they're made for agencies
they're not made for you so it doesn't
mean you shouldn't you know go after
them look at them apply to that I'm just
saying that it's it's it's a lot of work
and if you truly are committed you're
gonna have to work the boards if you
don't have an agent
the events like that's one of the great
things about b-sides and all the events
we do this is a place to market and meet
people I know that there's entry-level
people in this room and I and I tell
them all you've got it the worst because
cyber yet hasn't figured out succession
plans and and so therefore we can absorb
juniors and so we're not absorbing
juniors necessarily easily it takes a
lot of time to find so you all need to
pound the pavement at these events these
bracelets are nice I also tell people
make a t-shirt put on the back of it I'm
looking for a job I mean no joke put one
on the front I mean we are in a crisis
of content overload some you'll say what
are you doing yeah I mean these are
great but man imagine if that's why I
wear this shirt all the time like
whatever I'm shameless I don't care I
put my own money we're doing a great
service I'm gonna wear this thing so you
all got to think the same way it's
broken get it out get yourself out there
so these events are massively massively
important and just be willing to talk to
people and Tillery but
you're looking for a job very very soon
we will have a covert job platform for
you all it's not too far away we use a
lot of the technology ourselves today
we will release this it will compete
with job boards because uh you know
today that's the only place to go but
it'll be for you not for agencies yeah
and it'll change the game yeah well one
of the reasons why I have the cyber team
that I have yeah we're building a
platform for them so you can market
yourselves without getting her ass
without and yes you know if you see our
jobs posted today if you take a look at
cyber sitcom just them they are posted
using a product it speaks common
language you're gonna do this every day
this percentage this percentage that
percentage is it's the baseline of your
funds we've got questions we've got five
minutes left let's let's do it yes
and the question rittany obama is that
pretty much every woman for sponsorship
so how does it job seeker be that's
right that's right well that's what this
platform that we're building is gonna do
which makes you covert but also clearly
shows what you are so those women get
their pictures and their profile and
traditionally men are supposed to come
ask women so that's why that works but
you know you know what that woman looks
like and you know a lot about her before
you get to say hi to her right well
that's that's the sex act not the dating
act so different story but that's my
answer is that it's what do you do a
security title doesn't tell me anything
and most likely the stuff on your resume
isn't gonna tell me anything because
here's what you do as job seekers we
wide our resume based on the jobs we
want so right and as hiring
organizations we make our ads based on
the persona the person we think we want
to hire three years of this five years
or that that's not a job description
that's a persona of the person we think
we want to hire so we need to flip it
around and we all need to say this is
what I do for the last year I've done
10% this 20% this 20 right and the year
before I did this and so that people can
stand who you are are you that pretty
lady and that's pretty to me right we're
all beautiful to each other in different
ways or not and so that's my answer to
you and there's some analytics behind it
maybe too
yeah oh you're by yourself
yeah let's restate the question yeah
good mic dude
for who the microphones let's restate
the question so the question is about
salary calculator how do you know what
you're worth or what the she's paying is
what yeah this yeah and the data one to
two years old at best it falls under IT
we already talked about it's 20% higher
so you got it you understand your graph
yeah I said look this is an IT this
isn't software this is cybersecurity I
need to be need to be looked at that way
that's too low for me that's not the
band's I'm in today if you want to share
what you're making today share it if
that at that moment it probably would
help you right because nobody expects
anybody to take less money so at that
moment it'll help you I'm two months
away from releasing a real-time salary
guide like real-time everybody it's in
our system anybody who wants to
participate around the world put your
base salary covertly in here let's
empower HR it's a big problem for me and
my clients on my hiring managers nuts
we're working so hard we're working so
hard then we go to HR and they've
already been told yeah you can hire over
the budget but then they go to hire and
now they need three weeks of signatures
so now I've learned to like oh my gosh
I'm not starting that job until those
bands are hurt you know so it's a
nightmare
and HR is using really old data so you
just gotta stand around I'll have
something for you all soon that will
empower everybody just stand your ground
come join our network yeah sell your
calculator be there take a look at how
we do jobs is really different it's all
based on percentages so you definitely
know immediately what the job is
yeah totally and if you're hiring me
well you know what here's the advice
they're hiring the questions cuz I hate
to not take all questions I saw some
hands where did I miss one no any more
good you guys are all professional job
interviewers now so hopefully we'll have
a career track here next year we've been
talking to besides about it
there's a lot more content we can give
you happy to help out at anytime I wish
I could stand in here for four days that
I've got a jump on a 5:30 flight which
is not usually I'm stay for hours and
talk so anybody wants to chat with me
but my stuff I'm very social all it
really did just send me away so just we
have a table a brainwave table of their
Lance's there he's our pittsburgh
managing director of staffing so he's
here if you want to talk to him please
dude I hope this was helpful yes yeah
yes
what's a contract side but cyber sn.com
and we're all on it yeah yeah we're all
there
thank you everybody it was lovely to be
at besides I love besides so much