all right so our next talk is no
disassembly required Brian cetera with a
readout okay
I was like can you still hear me is that
alright well we'll try this microphone
and if it doesn't work I'll switch back
to the other microphone okay if somebody
can grab the doors so I am Brian cetera
and this is no disassembly required
which is a terrible pun and fully
intended is the subject of this talk
we'll be talking about script based
malware but it's also going to be kind
of an exhortation if you're not am our
analyst to not be afraid to start doing
malware analysis so I'll talk a little
bit about some VBS malware talk about
some offensive PowerShell and some other
some other types of script based malware
the important parts upfront you can
follow me on Twitter I've read out with
a three I get home page I have an open
source projects that I'm working on and
we're starting up and running I over the
past year done a lot of Mac OS related
security stuff some free scripts up
there for hardening Mac OS and some
other materials related to that previous
talks they've given and you can follow
me on my blog at blog read out on IO
again with a three which again currently
is mostly some Mac security related
stuff if anybody's interested in that
and using an OS query for EDR some
tutorials up on that but the stuff from
the training yesterday and from this
talk will kind of be going up on there
as a series of blogs hopefully soon so a
little bit about me
not really I usually kind of like the
idea that you know talk should kind of
stay on its own don't believe like the
lab coat commercial philosophy right
well I'm standing in a lab coat so by
our product
but just because people have asked me
like yesterday at the training that we
did you know how did you become of our
analyst or how do I become a malware
analyst or how did you get started in
security brief in the background so I am
originally this furred got out of the
military went back to school and GI Bill
University of Pittsburgh had in
information security program at their
School of Information science like your
graduate program went back to do that
but really ended up getting into what I
do now doing an internship with NC FTA
which I know there's some people here
today with NC FTA or hence the FTA alums
as well you know where I got to work
with federal law enforcement and see
what they do and started just learning
by doing right so way before your tax
dollars paid for me to go to a $5,000
sans course with Lenny zeltser thank you
uh-huh as a government our analyst I I
was just learning by doing as you know a
guy working as an intern unpaid intern
who was told go learn C go write a
HelloWorld C program you know can pile
it and throw the assembly and Ida Pro or
Olli and see what it does right so and
since then I've done kind of a InfoSec
jack-of-all-trades
it's like two of some background in
intelligence like as an Intel analyst so
it helps stand up some threatenings all
programs and done a variety of other
things too but you know I consider
myself mainly a reverse engineer I see a
reverse engineer instead of am our
analyst in part because I've probably
spent my work 5050 working on industrial
control systems and embedded stuff from
a vulnerability analyst standpoint some
more offensive ranted but also kind of a
is a philosophical point and that I
think it's more than just blog hunting
or in the case of malware analysis
throwing something in a sandbox and
finding quote-unquote IOC s you know
getting indicators that compromise its
really understanding what does something
really do not what the person who wrote
the code thinks it does not what you
originally at the outset thought it
but what can it really do what does it
really do how does it really work and
that's kind of the essence of hacking
right is discovering things can really
do is this talk for you so by a show of
hands regardless of what your job title
is you know how many people here have
ever or on a relatively routine basis
get asked to look at phishing emails
okay how many people like get asked to
do sort of EDR even if it's just your
Joe helpdesk and hey go reimage this box
right okay
now out of all those people feel free to
put your hands back up and put them down
you know how many of you if this is not
the case how many of you your company
just says oh you want to go take a
$6,000 sans course or you want ten grand
to go fly out to Vegas to go to blackhat
no problem any anybody anybody so so a
few people and I've been lucky enough
that I've had companies both working on
the government side and or certain
companies that work for where I had the
opportunity to do that usually because I
controlled a budget and myself to go do
that but but not everybody does right
and and out of all the people who raised
your hands how many of you your actual
title is you're a malware analyst okay
so not as many right
so my point them trying to get across
with this talk is just you know maybe
you don't know where to start maybe your
idea of malware analysis is well I'm not
a malware analyst I don't have the right
tools and/or the right environment I
don't have the training the
certifications I just I can't really do
anything other than just throw stuff in
a sandbox and you know really all you
need is the curiosity and persistence
and the persistence is not to be
underestimated right the unless you have
the persistence almost to the point of
masochism of I'm gonna do a really hard
so doq puzzle or crossword puzzle and
get to the end and realize I have to
start over that's the type of
persistence I'm talking about you know
really just have to
to to want to learn and I would say
bottom line up front for anybody who
suddenly has to go take a phone call or
whatever you know like they always say
tell people we were gonna tell them and
tell them and then tell them what you
told them you know start with
script-based our this is this was an
epiphany that actually I kind of had but
really all credit a friend of a friend
of mine and former former coworker I had
and we were talking to our analyst one
of the better ones I've known had the
Epiphany that you know 10 years ago
or you know if we could tell somebody
today like where should you start you
know you have one day to train somebody
that sort of thing that we would have
you know before we did the whole
learning sea and windows API and Windows
internals and spending a lot of time
staring it assembly in Ida we would have
started with script based malware or
scripts right so it's just sort of the
most bang for the buck the second point
I would make is that it's it's it's not
magic it's just code so even if you say
I'm not a developer I've never written a
line of code in my life write a
HelloWorld script pictus pick a
scripting language I guarantee you and
if you already know something stick with
that I guarantee you there's malware
written in it I mean how many people
here are Lua developers nobody right is
can anyone here you know my show hands
even even familiar with anything vaguely
important written in Lua it's like maybe
a handful of people and out of any of
those people is your answer not world of
warcraft mods the other thing would be a
bunch of Stuxnet and some some related
stuff related implants there's been
plenty of our written in Lua and it's
pretty obscure language doesn't require
any special software right it's
literally all you need is a VM and
notepad or some text editor and you can
analyze script based malware it's not
going to be the ideal environment maybe
there are some other things that would
help but you guys are going to see
that's that's really about as basic as
it gets and you know you
smarter than a sandbox so if I had like
a single tagline for this talk that you
are as a team or as a defender
regardless of what you think you're
capable of doing you are smarter than a
sandbox and malware authors aren't
stupid right they're putting in all
sorts of anti forensics they might have
fake call-outs they might have you know
a weight that you don't know about and
if all you ever did was detonate
something in a sandbox and then go oh
yeah I got the hyper tease you know we
got this domain and that domain maybe
you did maybe you didn't get the right
payload you know maybe you didn't get
the right situ you might not actually
know that unless you've really looked at
the malware and done some manual
analysis and that's not to say that
automation doesn't have its place right
for triage and things like that but it
should be the first step and just that
triage step right okay so enough on the
soapbox I said that this was gonna be
your best bang for the buck so this is
kind of the Pareto principle anybody
here familiar with the Pareto principle
maybe a few people so this is alfredo
Pareto he was an Italian economist
clearly clear clearly a wise incredible
man based on his beard it's actually an
apocryphal attribution that I've only
ever heard from people with MBAs or like
from a business school background as
somebody with an econ Amish degree once
upon a time you know it's it's not an
actual economics thing and they think
that it's like an apocryphal attribution
by an engineer he did come up with
Pareto optimality which is a real thing
and like game theory but that's all
other pull their talk
my other nerd out area of expertise yeah
so it's the idea is 20% of effort to get
80% of the return right so why not do
that up front and start seeing an
immediate ROI you know if I when I when
I train interns or I've trained like new
malware analysts this is always this is
now like my standard approach because I
can get them immediately doing useful
work and feeling confident and feeling
like they know how to do something right
rather than having somebody stumble
around learning learning
assembly so phishing email attachments
drive-by downloads live off the land
activity how many people have heard that
buzzword right that's sort of like been
the flavor of the month for a lot of
months now so scripts what are they good
for you know everybody here familiar
with miter attack model or like Lockheed
Martin cyber kill chain whatever model
you want to use to kind of look at
attacker behavior most of your stages or
activities or something that an attacker
can do with script based malware of some
sort without portable executable files
in many cases today may be doing without
compiled binaries just because that live
off the land principle of using
components that are going to be
whitelisted things that are going to be
kind of found tools that systems and
ministers use and so on and so forth so
let me start you start by getting into
VB right into an example of this and
that's the visual basic scripting and
phishing emails so it would not be a
malware talk without a little bit of the
wayback machine talking about malware
that nobody remembers maybe somebody
some people in the room do you remember
I love you were it was one of the first
really big really big phishing email
campaigns like mass mailer sort of thing
and it was just two students from the
Philippines who wrote this in VBS and
this is just a part of the code the main
method or they may be you know the main
function and sub in the script but it's
estimated it affected something like
forty five million users around the
world unintentionally and this wasn't
really a deliberate part of what the
malware were supposed to do but it was
just so successful that when it was
going around looking in people's email
outlet contacts and then remaining it
copies of itself as an attachment as a
phishing attachment it ended up crashing
Outlook servers and and being like into
a service attack on huge huge companies
and governments around the world
and it was pretty malicious despite the
claim so the two students that wrote it
it looked for document and other
specific file extensions and over wrote
things so it's pretty disruptive the
point is it was written in VBS and it
was written in VBS with API API code
that you know standard code that is
still around in Windows 10 or some
version of it it might be a new CLS IDE
and a new you know a new version of
something but it's like the same comm
objects are still to be found on a
Windows system today and so in terms of
that mitre attack we're talking about
you know initial access we're talking
about initial delivery and installation
there's still stuff around today I've
looked at phishing emails in the past
year that we're not really that similar
from something like I love you worm
other than the fact that they were
heavily obvious gated which which it did
not have to be because there wasn't
anybody looking to detect it so eighteen
years later is still pointing strong
which in a certain sense is kind of
depressing in another sense though I
think kind of makes the point that I was
trying to make about the value of
starting with scripts and learning
something very simple can help solve you
know a lot of problems or help give you
a lot of capability so today primarily
you're gonna see this VB these types of
VBS scripts used for staging payloads
rather than as necessarily the main
payload and what I mean by that for
those who aren't familiar you know is
either droppers or downloaders so a
dropper we have might have an embedded
executable not necessarily a VBS
contacts but remember couple years ago
it was a thing where people were using
to compile dotnet files and the actual
payload was just a variable that
contained you know and encoded or
encrypted string and they were just
using it as a carrier file to get around
defenses and specifically as an anti
forensics against oxes downloaders right
so it might just be a short snippet of
EBS using a handful of calm objects to
go out and download the real payload and
or it could the the real people could be
scripts but so why would we do this this
is making things a little bit more
complicated than it needs to be well you
know think about it this way would you
rather write if you've got your new cool
banking Trojan written in C or C++ or
whatever and it took you six months to
write or you paid for it from some guy
in the Ukraine who it took him six
months to write do you want that to get
burned if you're a phishing email
campaign go sideways or would you rather
just have a Java Script downloader that
took you a half hour to write get burned
and and I'd be the end of it and of
course cybercrime you know is is a
business and and there's not always
vertical integration so I might be just
delivering payload for a client and I
want it to be sort of agnostic right and
then to the defense evasion which I kind
of already mentioned so in terms of
tools I mean really you're just starting
with a text editor and a VM now I would
recommend using more of a full-featured
text editor something like notepad plus
plus that is intended for developers
especially people who do scripting a lot
and where you can kind of set it to a
particular scripting language and it'll
highlight all the keywords that it
recognizes as being associated with that
scripting language but that's not
necessary I mean you could just use
notepad or something or G edit or
whatever VI if you're really adventurous
no VI event no VI them them fans okay
that was a joke
I would I would not I would smash my
hand in a car door before I analyzed
however but VI yeah
so of course internet access we always
want to be safe don't have your VM set
to a bridge or an added connection ran
into this yesterday with the training
there were some folks who really didn't
quite get the concept of hosts only
networks and we're asking questions
about that
so I'm not trying to oversimplify things
but some people you know are not clear
on that yeah I generally don't use real
debuggers for most of the script power
because it's so a lot of it is just
simple downloaders and they're not real
expensive I generally haven't found a
super big need to use like a
full-featured debugger but if you did
want to like if you install Microsoft
Visual Studio there is and there is with
CS C script Exe E and like W script
there's an option like a forward slash
ax that you can start
Ronna VBS script in like a debugger a
real debugger mode and I think set set
set points and things like that I don't
do that
my poor man's debugger is just using
message box
so in VBS if you just you'll see it in a
minute but if you just put things in a
message box you can get an immediate
feed out our output and feedback of what
the code was doing similar thing if
you're working with malicious JavaScript
or just using like an alert box right
general strategy for these VBS
downloader phishing emails you've got to
first extract it from source and
sometimes this is the hardest part and
that's a whole talk onto itself it's a
whole talk for another day but and I'll
go through an exam I'll go through some
of it and my example that we have coming
up here in a minute but you know it's
generally gonna involve extracting like
an O le object from interact extracting
something from a word document and
carving it out and then getting it into
your text editor finding unobvious gated
code keywords and cleaning up line
written generally cleaning up the code
so in fee BS you'll have the whole
script will be shoved together with
colons which which act is like a line
continuation and so breaking those out
just so it's more readable and then as I
said if you're using something like
notepad plus plus anything that's uh
Navia skated which there's always going
to be some code that they've left
unobvious gated it's going to go ahead
highlight that for you and that gives
you like a better fun better starting
point right of determining hey this is a
worse of function starts and stops or
something like that even if I can't read
what it does sometimes iOS user just in
plain text as you'll see a little bit
later but as I said don't believe it
because you don't know what took me it's
high forensics are going on try finding
eval or execute functions and
substituting them with message box
that's like the go-to first Jose maybe
25% something less than 50% with a
sizeable chunk of VBS malware you can
defeat the obvious case in just with
that right because it's they're being
lazy they just want to avoid basic
detection and they're just running
everything through eval and you can do
the same thing too and just output with
message box the unobvious gated copy of
the code get rid of obvious garbage
functions you know look for the DD the
decoder or D obvious keishon functions
because they have to be in the sample
somewhere maybe possibly if this was
like a second stage to some other
malware there might be some other
component that does the decoding and
decrypting but generally you're gonna
have some type of decoder function like
that the simplest method being that eval
statement that's gonna be in the malware
itself so if you can find that first you
can write it a quick decoder and
whatever scripting language you're
comfortable with doesn't have to be the
same scripting language I mean I've had
people ask me that just because I'm
looking at VBS doesn't mean that I can't
use Python to write my decoder and
especially if I'm seeing the same type
of thing over and over again and the
same type of phishing emails over and
over again you might start to have a
payoff to writing those decoders and and
making them a little more robust
identify the really useful bits it's
typically gonna be common really common
or run-of-the-mill common seem calm
objects over and over again you'll see
and we'll see all this coming up in the
example renaming functions to something
meaningful and commenting your code this
is even more
in our analysis than it is and I think
in being a developer because ultimately
you have to communicate your results and
your information to someone else for
your work to be a value whether that's
reporting to management whether that's
talking to thread Intel guys who aren't
as technical as you are or whether
that's communicating information so you
can write a yarder rule or a signature
for an IDs or something so you want to
right off the bat start commenting your
code as you go and renaming things in a
way that's gonna help help that and I
think them like the miter attack model
or something along those lines is a good
way to standardize your language in
terminology when you do that
establishing sequence of files and
processes noting anti forensics the last
the only thing I'll hit on here is this
last point it's a little bit of a
soapbox point but that observables are
not indicators so you know I once got an
Excel spreadsheet from an analyst at a
fortune 500 sock that was more or less
just a big list of ip's and I was kind
of like it was like did you get those
indicators yeah so are these IP
addresses you know hosting second-stage
payloads is this a c2 server what is
this right it's that contacts that makes
an indicator and indicator and
actionable and so again when you're
you're you know making your notes and
you're saying I'm trying to find IFC's
make sure you're finding actual IOC s
and have all the information
sorry soapbox point so let's go through
an example I think this is going to be a
little bit more clear VBS downloader so
phishing email was received forwarded to
security to an organization there was an
embedded it was embedded in a word
document the word document was password
protected so going back to answer
forensics we had a cuckoo beast like
sandbox farm setup that we could throw
samples through and we were actually
more using that for kind of threat
emulation and helping develop blue team
tactics then
like operationally focused malware
analysis but the point is is that that
that kind of broke that model right and
broke the idea of just detonating it in
cuckoo even though we had cuckoo sandbox
is set up with with were office in them
and we typically could just detonate
office documents and get get information
so how to use used ms ms ms em sock
which is a ms o le or excuse me an MS
password removal tool third a number of
them out there this is just a free one
that I think has a github page and then
carved out the the script in from word
and he had just in this case it was easy
enough to do it once it was decrypted or
decompressed the password correction was
removed to do it it was a hex editor but
you know you may do that with some other
tools like Baldwin's ma office mal
scanner or the de collage I forget the
actual name of the tool but the site is
de collage that have the Oh le extractor
tool that they have there you can google
for them this is a little you know and
then it was just a matter of starting
the base and cleanup so as I said to
kind of focus on the actual script part
is that first part is sort of its own
art form as well on the right here you
can see that is the obvious gated copy
where I've just done an initial cleanup
of breaking out those line continuations
so that it's a little bit more readable
and you can see that notepad plus plus
has identified functions and so I'm able
to say okay this is a function here's
the name of the function it's not a
human readable name it's sort of a
garbage name but I can highlight that
and then search to see is this function
even called anywhere else in the script
and if not it's probably just garbage
code there to distract me and I can
delete it out at least out of a copy of
the script and start working from that
assumption and I'm gradually reducing
this stuff I actually have to look at
right so after I've eliminated some
of the garbage code I'm going through t
obvious Gatien so I've identified this
function which you can see up there
which is actually three functions that
were the main obvious Gatien functions
or I should say D obvious Kishin
functions to undo what they had done in
the in the in the script the top one was
just a modulus function that they
implemented themselves for some reason
probably just to avoid having that VBS
keyword in the file plain text I don't
really know but that's what they did and
they just did some math operations on
strings that they had converted from a
character to the number value of the
character and so they were doing math
operations on them an XOR fun that they
did that they were using well we'll see
what it was used for in a second and
then the main decode function that was
used for the main obvious keishon of
like the body of the code and so then
from there I was able to take that main
D obvious Gatien function and write a
quick decoder and start clearing up the
useful code that actually did something
and it wasn't junk code and as I said I
came up with some fairly common comm
objects so in this case they're creating
an XML HTTP object so typically you're
gonna see either that or you're gonna
see an Internet Explorer object being
created sort of as a headless browser to
go out and pull down some other content
that's a pretty good indication or
potentially to push information up to a
c2 server it's more often has in this
case a downloader and yeah I don't know
if you can see this but in the open
statement they're using a get request
method and then that queue v70 I
probably should have renamed for this
just for this screenshot for everybody
but that was the URL so I was then able
to find they had a function that was
essentially doing a URL chooser it
wasn't exactly like a domain generation
algorithm it was just choosing from a
list of hard-coded URLs to use and there
were some anti forensics measures beyond
that like we times and things like that
so if I just thrown the
into a sandbox and rolled with the first
thing I got or had been running like
fake net and G or something I might have
gotten a domain name that wasn't even
being used actively by the attacker I
may have gotten one that was no longer
being used or whatever the case may be I
would not have gotten all of the URLs
all of those out of the file and then
the XOR function was actually discovered
was not being used and you can see this
at the bottom there is a selection that
can ISM for what byte key to use and
just you know level set here for
everybody you know if you're not
familiar I mean XOR is one of the more
common methods of obvious Gatien simple
obvious Gatien that people use it's
pretty convenient because as I said
whatever you do you have to undo so if I
have converted things to a number and
then I X or if I X or a byte stream
right by some bike key and then I XOR it
again by the same bike key I get back
anybody the same thing I started with
right it's kind of convenient that way
so this was just their method of
decoding the payload that they were
going out and getting so in order to
decode this payloads when I would go out
and curl the second stage or you some
some manner to go out and get the second
stage and if you're gonna do that curl
kind of keying on the red team talk that
just happened you know it know to people
that if you use you know you can use
tools like curl and set up your own
profile so that you're not just using
the default header like that's basic
practice you should be creating a
spoofed spoofed header with a spoofed
user agent and all that stuff so that
you don't look like and a blue team er
going out and getting a sec payload you
look like a dick yeah so then I was able
to decode the second-stage payload so
lessons learned dynamic analysis
wouldn't miss stuff you need those XOR
keys who's able to recover those and
it's just reuse of basic comm objects'
like a handful of common objects is this
you can see the file system object in
the second part and
you know typically some type of W script
shell object because you can use those
to do a headless command line and run
files run files with an argument to it
that sort of thing
edit registry keys so on and so forth so
if you learn in like JavaScript let's
say or VBS you learn the example cut you
look at SS 64 calm or MSDN and you look
at api's and you look at how to use a
basic set of maybe four or five
different comma objects the ones I just
named being most of them you can you can
a do be stream objects with the other
you can you can pretty much understand
and identify the important parts of the
vast majority of like VBS or JavaScript
download or phishing email code that
you're gonna look at so you don't have
to be a hundred percent proficient
expert in VBS you just have to be able
to recognize those important parts and
kind of understand how they work this
was just some stuff that I think I've
already kind of covered about string
string manipulations and character
manipulations with the ASC key you would
see the opposite of it the undoing of it
is going to be done with the reversing
of that it's gonna be done with a CHR
like with a kid that character function
to get it back to a character that's
that's an example this dim foo they're
just storing in that variable the whole
script is a big long string and then
running it through execute and so this
is one of those cases where as I said if
I just substitute execute with message
box I get the DD obvious gated script so
rolling rolling right along PowerShell
scripting try and knock through this
sure everybody here is familiar with our
shell anybody not familiar with
PowerShell
right no ok good so you know basic idea
was more
or Bosch like experience more powerful
for systems administration features like
command command dot exe above blue 2012
was sort of the year of PowerShell
I mean PowerShell came out in 2006 but
the offensive PowerShell use really
kicked off in high gear 2012 with all
these big talks at blackhat and der beek
on DEFCON all the conferences yet Dave
Kennedy and Josh Kelly I think there's
actually another Ian his name I
misspelled it doing their talk that oMFG
talk at blackhat Matt graver you had
tools coming out like power sploit
followed by you know Empire and the
Shang and so on and so forth and a team
really has sort of led the way on this
this philosophy and this live off the
land methodology but the advanced
persistent threat actors and you know
various actual malicious actors have
adopted the same techniques because they
work because there are all of these
legitimate InfoSec professionals doing
all the development work for them and
this this chart on the right was just to
show that again with PowerShell we can
do pretty much all the stuff that we
need to do especially in that middle box
which is this sort of actions on
objectives in this ekc terminology this
is where the offensive PowerShell really
shines right and that lateral movement
privilege escalation so on and so forth
and so I mean how many people here have
not heard that you might live off the
land or fireless intrusions usually in
the sales pitch if some vendor who
claims they can detect it and defend it
and defeat it and make you cappuccino
live off the land oh really how I sort
of interpret it is using white list of
applications tool scripting engines
stuff that your admins use so that it
doesn't look unusual you're making a
smaller footprint you're making a
smaller footprint for EDR Geoff fewer
artifacts in the endpoint you're not
writing as much stuff to file and you
also have fewer artifacts you're
downloading that are gonna be in network
traffic file ish file this intrusion I
think to the extent that it has a
meaning beyond a buzz word or
eles pitch is you know just this idea
that we're writing fewer artifacts to
disk and PowerShell is sort of uniquely
capable of that
because of the remote management
features that has so I can run a
PowerShell script on my system or on a
system that I'm using as a pivot point
and run it on a remote host and it's not
gonna get rid own to write the file to
disk on that system it's gonna be in
memory and maybe if they have a script
block logging enabled they're gonna
catch it in script lock logs and like a
Windows Event 4104 which I'll get to in
a second here
and so these are some of the basic
methods that you commonly see again one
of the advantages is with like the
invoke command you can run this not just
against one target you can run it
against multiple target hosts the term
cradles so I'm sure people here have
heard maybe the term like PowerShell
cradles and wondered exactly what that
means other than jargon and buzzwords
this came out of like raffia lodges talk
and 2015 the flying a Cylon Raider which
you can read the PDF version from sands
of that this is a great example
you're commonly gonna see right is this
invoke expression which that's aliased
and then creating a dotnet web client I
kind of had in my previous slide you've
got access to everything dotnet natively
so and commonly used we're going to use
the download string method instead of a
download file method just because it
allows me to do that running of a remote
grab that remotely hosted powershell
script and run it without writing it to
disk first on the local system and of
course other tools were adopted to take
advantage of that
so the invoke mimic ats version of
running mimic adds one of the cost of
putting putting this in context where
you may see stuff like this getting used
if you're looking at phishing emails
since a lot of people said that they
looked at phishing emails would be and
each a files anybody here run into like
malicious HTA phishing emails I see a
few
heads nodding and some people putting
hands in the air yeah so in 2017 there
was a CVE 2017 199 which really wasn't
it wasn't a bug or anything it was just
Microsoft function how it either could
be abused which is always the best part
and that's why I said in the beginning
of my talk reverse engineering is more
than just finding a bug right sometimes
it's a feature and this allowed HTA
files to just be opened in a Word file
and was billed as like macro less macro
less exploitative Word documents with
EGA this has since been closed down that
that loophole has sort of been closed
down by Microsoft but there's still
other methods to execute HTA's it's
still used by attackers one thing is
it's a defensive defensive asian measure
because you're using a white listed
legitimate application MSHDA dot exe to
launch some other malicious content to
look for this by the way in Windows
event logs 46:56 queries to HTA related
CLS IDs and your forty six eighty eight
process creation from SH ta would be one
way to start this this is an actual
malicious ht8 downloader that courtesy
Nick Carr from daily daily scriptlet guy
if anybody follows him I would recommend
it that he got emailed from somebody
else another malware researcher and it's
just kind of humorous because this is
how not to obvious Khaitan HT a file or
any other malware so you can see some of
the similar stuff you saw in the earlier
VBS script but they've left
they've heavily obviously did it they're
using PowerShell and sort of the middle
part for the downloader there's
PowerShell cradle and then they've
decided to for some reason not obvious
Kate the IOC s like the stuff that we
would really be looking for right and
you would still want to go ahead and you
obviously this just to make sure that
this isn't messing with you and some
sort of anti forensics but this gives
you a good look at what the
functionality would be so I've got my
HTML and then enclosed within my HTML
I've got a VB script
and the vbscript is really being used to
do the filing handling of writing and
running the file which they're
temporarily storing into an
environmental variable and then pulling
it back out again and the actual
downloading is being done with with the
download file method of that dotnet web
client object why they chose to do this
instead of doing a one-liner with the
download string I'm not 100% certain but
that's what they did so again it's not
too different from what you saw in the
earlier VBS file but they're using
PowerShell for that download or cradle
we could sit here and talk for an hour
just about or more her weeks well I
couldn't because I don't know a week
worth of material but there are people
who do like Daniel Bohannon
hunt powershell obvious gation it's a
lot of the same games you know there's
aliased expressions or aliased
commandlets base64 encoding as you can
see on the right using tick marks
concatenations
your dash F format feature is a really
common string manipulation you see with
the powershell and at the end of the day
there's - there's too many to cover over
here the end of the day the big point I
would make is just that it led to this
PowerShell arms race and you had the top
some really top researchers like Daniel
Bohannon from a Myint and the ALMS with
Microsoft and Microsoft Azure who was
one of the people who who originally
wrote PowerShell script in PowerShell
getting into this this cat and mouse
game with who could create even more
complicated obvious caissons and
Microsoft introducing security features
with each version of PowerShell so
that's really behooves you to use five
five one or if you're getting into using
Linux systems as well
version six engine because it built in
just enough administration script lock
logging and so forth and on the left you
can see that script lock being caught
with a 401 for when it is event log
which you would not catch if people were
running their PowerShell your
administrators or
using like v2 of PowerShell or the
attacker has successfully downgraded to
v2 and so that becomes another thing to
look for as you're looking for the
downgrade instead of instead of the
malicious activity itself at least as a
starting point and then of course you
have the end of the PowerShell arms race
cold war with damn Bohannon and Lee
homes coming together in 2017 and doing
like the revoke obvious Gatien and
revoke obvious ocation talks and that's
a really useful tool that I would
recommend and basically their point that
they arrived at was that it's so hard to
manually do view skate some of the stuff
you can create in terms of PowerShell
obvious keishon that you almost need to
adopt more of the logs and statistical
analysis based approach and that's a
part of what their tool does is it
facilitates that and reassembling
scripts that span multiple logs other
malware really quick since we are are
ticking down the clock I thought I
mentioned this one Mac OS malware so
this just shows you the scope of what
you can do just looking at script
malware so last year 2017 one of the big
big news items in Mac OS malware if
people follow that stuff Patrick Wordle
I would also recommend like Chris Chris
Ross from Spectre ops is a good guy on
that stuff was this fruit fly malware as
they called it and you had all these
InfoSec blogs and researchers who rushed
out this is clearly some
never-before-seen really stealthy apt
actor who was targeting very
specifically the biotech sector and in
these complicated theories based on what
was found on this professors laptop and
this university and so on and so forth
and of course as it turns out it was
really just this disgruntled software
engineer from Cleveland and named filthy
Phil juror chin ski and he has not been
convicted but he has been charged with
16 counts of everything you can do
naughty with a computer and he was
probably a Browns fan so is this really
surprising
ah you know so the point is is that he
infected systems like at police
departments and on US government systems
and had persistence for years on some of
the systems as far as anybody could tell
why he was using one of the most
low-hanging fruit no pun intended
persistence mechanisms you can use on
Mac OS which is just a P less item in
the uhland long n launch D um but nobody
was looking for him and nobody really
knew how to look for him and nobody was
analyzing his Mauer and it was just Perl
script so he was able to create a
completely workable rat entirely in Perl
script so there you go and in really old
libraries of Perl script that was that
was what people's interest they thought
it was some sort of anti forensic
stealth measure or something that he was
using out of date code malicious
JavaScript that again that's a whole
week worth of material I would refer you
to a wasp I think there was like kind of
a new hospital this morning but you know
JavaScript was intended to be able to do
client-side dynamic content for web
content and so you can just as easily
dynamically create bad stuff right and
tiny web shells same thing last ditch
effort backdoor doing government work
I've seen this a lot with apt actors
targeting government organizations that
is their backdoor of last resort after
they've been kicked off a network is
leaving behind you know it could be as
small with like China chopper is a 4k
file with just a simple PHP PHP code in
it to receive commands and run commands
on the web server and it's just a
toehold it's just you know propping open
the back door while you ransack the
house just in case right
so my final caveat I'll leave you with
so I would say that it is the 20% that
gets you the 80% looking at Script
malware and I would encourage everybody
to start there but if you're going to be
a full time our analyst if you want to
go work in a shop where all you do is
sit and go through a queue of malware
sample after
our sample you probably do want to get
your gram if you can you want to learn
see learn C++ and assembly maybe even
our arm as opposed to just x86 64 you're
gonna start looking at like Android
malware or something and start to
recognize control flow so write your own
hello world file compile it in different
compilers and then look at the
difference in the assembly when you open
it up in ida pro or a ladybug and you'll
see the differences that are just
artifacts and pilers right what is the
calling convention who call you know who
cleans up the stack is it the calling
function or is it the colleague that's
gonna vary from compiler to compiler
that's ocean Lotus rat it's a Mac OS
mock Oh binary in Ida just a random
gratuitous this is some water shot you
have to have one of those in the malware
talker it's not a malware talk learn
file formats like I said you learn to
use disassemblers and debuggers but
start with scripts and for most of us
who your job title is not an hour
analyst but you're you are a maori
analysts you're being asked to do it
you're being asked to look at malicious
phishing emails take take a look at a
time and if you you know if you're able
to remove the time and and just start
scripting start writing scripts and
looking at your own scripts start with
those basic calm calm functions or comma
objects so they talked about like the
ones that create web objects XML HTTP
and how to do that or the Internet
Explorer object and so again it's not
magic it's just code all you really need
is a VM in a text editor and some
persistence and you are smarter than a
sandbox so you can do it and I wish it
was as easy I love Dilbert but I wish it
was as easy as you know just getting a
software engineer to write an app for
that but there's no magic bullet
it's just persistence of doing it that's
that's how you become the Mauer analyst
special thanks yeah like I said just a
shout out to Adam swan and you can
follow those guys and Nate with Jennie
follow them on Twitter they're big elk
stack blue team er
guys and analysts who do cool stuff
well and help contribute to this talk
and these are some of the blogs that I
follow or Twitter feeds and I follow of
people who are relevant to what I just
talked about and who do a lot of good
work on what I just talked about and
I'll put the slides up at some point
like as a PDF on my github page which we
kind of saw it beginning and I just
weird out with a three and if you need
to find me the easiest way to google for
it is applesauce in the bucket
that's my Apple security repository and
it seems to be the one that pops up in
Google any questions we have just a
minute or something left questions yes
[Music]
yeah so yeah so so to speak to that
point really quickly two things okay
number one yeah there are sites you can
go out to websites that will obvious
skate or div escape stuff for you
automatically they don't always work and
more importantly if you're doing this
for reals for stuff from your company
and this is stuff you've gotten it's
just a matter of basic OPSEC that you
don't want to go out and just don't
paste that into an online tool and you
don't know whoever's running that site
or why they're running it and what
they're doing it's kind of like just
saying well I can just take the samples
and upload them all to virustotal
right it's an object thing it depends on
why you're doing the analysis and and so
on and so forth
and in terms of getting your hands dirty
I mean so the people who did the
training yesterday we did a whole
training I had them start out by writing
scripts rather than trying to div escape
real samples and that would be my
recommendation right so if you're not
you just said if you're not a coder
okay
I would start out by not trying to div
escape obvious gated samples that some
malware author is written I would start
out by writing my own really simple
downloader with two VMs and having an
Apache server with a text file on it and
writing my own VBS or JavaScript
downloader that downloads a file and
understanding that functionality and
then when you start to look at obvious
gated stuff you'll recognize even though
it's quote/unquote obvious gated you're
gonna recognize the basic structure of
what's going on does that help answer
your question yeah sure so that would be
the right way to do it if you're using
an automated tool would be to make sure
you had a local copy yep like I said
that may not always work though right
any other questions okay thank you
[Applause]