all right everybody thanks for coming
out to b-sides again and thanks for
sticking around for the end for our last
talk before we wrap things up at five
o'clock hmm so it is 4:30 you're in the
black room and we were about to hear
from Joe mast he's going to talk to us
about red and blue team tips for crypto
mining in your environment that's all
good man
thank you everyone for staying so long I
really appreciate it I know it's the end
of the day but we'll start to talk off
does anybody happen to the characters in
the upper right hand corner your left
sorry and if you do could you raise your
hand so I knows okay good all right so
that show is that Eddie and the plot of
that show every time is there's a scam
they try to go out and they try to get
free money from all their friends when I
started research just researching this
talk to me it sounded like one of their
scams but it turned out this scam
actually works and you can get free
money from crypto mining on your works
infrastructure so today we're gonna talk
about some tips you can do to do it
better how you can protect against it
and how much money you can really make
all right so Who am I
my name is Joe mast I work for federal
investors my undergrads from slippery
rock and I want to I'm doing my masters
at Western Governors University I have
some interest in cryptocurrency cyber
security usually breaking things asking
a lot of questions traveling and those
are my cars so if you're into cars let
me know I always like to talk about
those as well so if you don't know
anything about Krypton mining I'm just
gonna give you a brief background about
what cryptocurrency is and as well as
what mining is cryptocurrency is just
basically it's a digital currency it's
not regulated it's decentralized I'm
sorry it is regulated it's it's just
decentralized and it's regulated by an
encryption algorithm and there's no
central bank to distribute or operate
the currency ie just magic internet
money so you can have fun with that as
well where does it come from the short
answer is it's distributed by a minor
and a minor just performs a complex math
algorithm to verify transactions on the
network and by doing that work they're
rewarded with more coins so they're
provided the coins for the work that
they put into the network
so some perspective where are we coming
from with this talk I just want to give
like an outsider's view again where the
is that if this is this as an outsider
there's no oh like key to this it's just
it's mining by even malicious employees
or an attacker or a red team so we're
talking about anybody who has access to
your system or potentially could have
access to it and where they're going to
be attacking one your assets to your
power bill and three your free air
conditioning so where is the best place
to mine obviously anything with free
power right like a college dorm we've
been seeing that free power is best
power think that all the time everything
that's free you want to take the best
utilization of that that you can
colleges are cracking down on it if you
aren't properly logging and auditing
your Amazon Web Services they're also
great place to mind because it's really
easy to set up new devices and spin up
machines and instantly mine there as
well any device that can really run code
on it
you can also mind they're pretty fast
and easy and of course your works
desktops workstations and data center
because they're all climate controlled
and maintained by other people other
than yourself so this is in my opinion
and many others starting to become like
the new ransomware we're seeing it and
why is there a shift from ransomware to
cryptocurrency mining we're seeing that
because this guarantees a return in most
cases I'm sorry not most but in some
cases people don't pay the ransom it's
not guaranteed but if your
cryptocurrency mining software does run
you're usually guaranteed some sort of
return as well we've seen a lot of
resources where botnets have been
repurposed from doing malicious things
to running cryptocurrency miners and
then generating a slow profit for the
the owner as well
popular ransomware tools I've been
repurposed one such one was the eternal
blue attack with wanna cry had been
repurposed to one of mine so it's just
there's a lot of different tools out
there they all exist they use the same
bar abilities as regular ransomware
tools as well it provides a long-term
strategy for an attacker and what that
strategy provides is over
with a ransomware it's like a one-hit
wonder you're out you get your money you
leave but
the long-term strategy here is you can
mine over a long period of time and go
ahead and that's also how it draws less
attention you're just on the system and
constantly draining and using resources
to gain money for yourself over time so
mining costs money and this is where I
took into account for the power bill and
analyzed it I have a home lab right now
with two Dell are seven ten servers and
what I did with this is an experiment to
see how much money the power cost really
did or were for my month right so I kind
of took into account two different sized
firms a small and a large
at the small firm we had 250
workstations and 50 work and 50 servers
and the average cost per day for a
workstation was around a quarter and for
the server's around $2 a day in power
over the course of the year I ended up
calculating that it was around 22,000
dollars per year for all your
workstations at a small firm and around
36,000 a year for all the servers where
it really starts to get serious is in a
larger firm the more workstations you
have obviously it's gonna cost a lot
more with 5,000 workstations it's
somewhere near a half a million dollars
in power costs as well more servers you
have they'd if I cost a lot more so it's
almost three-quarters of a million
dollars in power for a thousand servers
and this is just an assumption that
you're getting a commercial rate of
power if you're doing this at your house
or something along those lines to be
even worse than your rates are gonna be
way higher than this and this doesn't
take into account air conditioning
maintenance and other things related to
maintaining your own hardware so how
easy is it can you click run and paste
your wallet address that's really how
easy it is to run some JavaScript miners
in the browser they're there honestly
just if you can load a web page you can
load a binder it's so easy a baby could
do it for more contour for more
dedicated miners you might have to run
an executable on an endpoint but there's
not really much configuration just to
get it up and running to optimize it yes
there's more configuration and need for
permissions but you can usually get it
running in an environment where there's
not a lot of protection as well things
you need to mind just internet a device
that works
a border more need for some free money
so free money is best money what are we
talking about we're gonna take into
account the small firm we saw earlier
and with that small firm we had 50
servers and 250 endpoints this is where
things started to get serious and you
can see there's actual returns generated
and why someone might want to do this so
what the server we're looking at a hash
rate of 300 hashes per second that's
very conservative and low for an average
grade server just doing CPU mining as
well this workstation accounts for just
an eight-hour day so that's why you can
see the daily yields are lower for the
workstation so I'm on two different
coins in my lab on the servers and the
workstations that I had and the daily
yield for the smaller sorry the Monaro
was 18 cents and z cache was 62 cents
which is quite profitable at the time
still is on the workstations as well
since we're just planning for an
eight-hour workday I was able to earn
around five cents and seventeen cents
for Z cache where this really comes into
effect is if you can do this for a long
period of time for over a large amount
of assets three to five thousand dollars
is nice and so is Z cash is fifteen two
to eleven thousand dollars but it's not
something crazy and I don't think I
would want to lose my job over that much
money but where this is the small fry
right this is like you have a small
organization you take over it but it's
still a lot of money for people to go
mind for right so this is the small fry
but wait there's more the large firm is
where the returns really come out what
these numbers is they grow largely
so that the same hash rates we're
getting the same yield depending on your
assets if you can control obviously as
you can see here a thousand servers from
an arrow that's sixty five thousand
dollars your current market rates which
are pretty low right now as well for Z
cash that's two hundred twenty six
thousand dollars a year which is some
serious change if you can do that on all
your endpoints and this is just a very
unwise mining level as well for our
workstations it's almost a hundred
thousand dollars a year and three
hundred thousand dollars a year for Z
cash and that's some it's Lamba money
you can go out buy anything you want
with that I can see why
people have been mining on their works
infrastructure and this is just to get
you to think about one it's possible -
it has serious returns three just if you
can do it it's easy and simple to run
and there's obviously money to be made
here
so with this there's broad attack
surfaces only I know meant we before
mentioned that the web browsers but as
well with most of these monitors there's
not much privileged access needed to
make them run at least in from a basic
standpoint as well you can mine in the
browser via JavaScript if you're not
blocking that and another friend of mine
proposed an idea and I've seen attacks
made for it
where web proxies are attacked and then
used to inject the JavaScript directly
to users browser pages as well Internet
of Things devices have been used and
manipulated to mine consistently because
no one's really checking on them are
looking at what they're doing all the
time
a popular attack those just released was
for kindle fire sticks Amazon fire
sticks as well as we've seen the
repurposed botnets just to go out and
earn money for themselves and mine and
then we've seen a lot of from ransomware
fishing to go to mining and that it's
been either a link to a web page
JavaScript miner in it or an executable
for some type of miner that runs on a
browser page it's hidden in the
background so it's very easy to attack
multiple surfaces with this so we're in
team how can you make more money or do
this better when I was doing this I just
pretended it was malware in my
environment my test environment most
antivirus software thought that it was
or at least a malicious item and in
order to get to run some cases I used
off UK obfuscation techniques I use PE
scrambler to obfuscate the executable
and then run it Pig got past most
signature-based antivirus software as
well thing was important if you have
really good server admins that are
always on there and understand the
utilization of your servers and when
they should be working hard not you you
can tune around within most miners such
as reducing how much CPU power it uses
and as well having an only worked
normal work hours so it doesn't look odd
and on mobile clients you can as well
work to work towards battery power so
that doesn't look odd if it gets below
20% maybe it stops mine things along
those lines as well you can tune your
phishing attacks you don't need to go
dropping executables on somebody's thing
you can just go and drop a JavaScript
infected link and mine via the browser
there if they just click on it you're
gonna make some sort of return as well
almost all Meyers were able to be loaded
via SMB shares just like normal malware
if your antivirus software doesn't know
how to scan those that was very simple
to load those in most of my lab
environments blue team what can you do
to prevent and detect this at first I
would definitely say that your company
should have a formal stamp established
against this or it doesn't have to be
exactly crypto mining but maybe a
hardware software abuse and if you don't
have that already you should definitely
have one drafted as well you can employ
a next-gen firewall and with that it's
great to have a next-gen firewall but
you should be using the tools that it
has on it and implement them such as URL
filtering or SSL interception or
decryption as well you should employ an
intrusion detection system keep it
updated ensure that somebody's actually
read the alerts that it produces that's
great to have it again but you should
pay attention to what it's doing it's
probably doing a good job and then as
well implement a strong antivirus or erd
solution and update it keep it updated
with roles and ifcs
and just watch it as well you can check
out this point blocker list tool and
what that coin blocker list tool does is
it produces a list of IPs which all
contain every node in the coin hive
JavaScript miner that's built into the
browser and you can use that to
implement it downloads as a text file
you can upload that to your tools and
then block those IP addresses that for
those web addresses as well you can
patch your browsers and install block
browser plugins if you don't have any
other protections and some of those
plugins are no coin and miner block and
what they'll do is they'll just think
they have known mining signatures in
them and then they'll just block those
scripts from running as well talked
before one of the ways I was able to get
lowest mining software to run in my labs
and other areas I played with is through
attached storage or shares if your
antivirus software or your D solution
isn't configured properly to scan that
it's very simple to just have it run
through there so I found a lot of evil
if you just scan most attached storage
or shares there's lots of interesting
things out there and you should probably
be doing that and as well you should
have a process to properly validate your
firewall rules and what's going on there
if you're not properly validating
checking the configuration or saying
what's going on how do you know what's
really happening on your firewall so
there should be some sort of audit
function third-party that knows what's
going on there as well just before we
wrap this up I wanted to go over some
recent news there's some interesting
links for the first one is the Georgia
Department of State some man mined over
$300,000 in Z cash I think it was and he
was caught he was asked to leave he
never actually got fired and he ended up
keeping the money too so it sounds
pretty sweet to me for the second one is
it was just a post on Stack Overflow a
colleague found that his friend was
mining on the company resources he's
asked him what to do the comments are
great if you read that one and then the
last one is a Russian guy that doesn't
he went missing he was mining on
supercomputers at a Russian State
University and then just to go over
again some pros and cons here it's free
money what there's no reason not to do
it and it's pretty simple and easy to
install you just Google how to mine you
can probably figure it out pretty simply
and some cons if your environment set up
right you might be privileged access to
do this more properly as well if your
firewall set up well you might need to
whitelist something in there but if you
have access to it it could be easy to do
and you might get fired I haven't really
seen many cases where people got fired
though so just things to think about and
just things to leave you with again it's
easy to do you should have a policy
against this and free thank you
[Applause]
anybody mind questions
so yes there are I don't know them off
by heart but I know that in most
firewalls there's the ability to I know
Apollo out there signatures for it that
you can enable to blocking with URL
filtering in SSL decryption great
application so thank you anybody else
yes there is an IOC list one of my
friends was talking about a tool that
you can download it and what it'll do is
it'll give you a list of all the IP
addresses to know in pools and then you
can block those because they're all
communicating back out to those pools
but there is known public things that
you can go and download to produce with
an IP list for you to implement into
your tools to block them no minor tools
thank you everyone
[Applause]