so the next stocks gonna be starting now
with Erin and Christian and I'll let
them take it from here and tell us about
some wormholes cool hello I'm Erin Chow
mara and Christian rural Cohen we both
work at secure works we both work in the
counter thread unit which is notionally
to threat research team but also threat
operations I'd say Christian works on
the special ops team and I work in the
cyber Intel Center typically what that
really means for me is most of the time
I spend looking at malware or specific
threat actors and threat groups but over
the past year there's been a lot of our
time that's been spent working on a few
internet scale worms which has been
really an odd occurrence in the past 10
years it really sort of all started with
this in April 2017 a group of online
activists or personas of sorts released
a whole bunch of tools that were
notionally based from the NSA in that
set of tools there were a handful of
exploits which were were mobile most of
these were based off of SMB exploits and
vulnerabilities all of those were the
eternal based tools but there were also
some exploits and vulnerabilities and
tool sets in there that were were mobile
which were not based off of SMB but for
some reason they were really picked up
on so those were released in April 2017
and Microsoft had previously released
patches back in March 2017 so everybody
patched right like we learned these
lessons 10 years ago first with Ken well
most recently with configure but
previous to that with quite a few other
worms that spread incredibly quickly
across the internet well in May 2017 we
found out that no a lot of people really
didn't patch and there was this worm
which started spreading and it was
want to cry and it compromised a lot of
hosts and got a lot of press play at
least that we saw in the media which
meant that I worked all weekend long
and that what really kind of caught
people's minds and really spread through
the Zeke Geist was the fact that these
were based off of and and this toll was
spreading based off of an exploit in the
the shadow brokers release which had
been released a month earlier so when we
started to really dig into this story
though we found that that really wasn't
what had happened there was a previous
version of this worm which had started
spreading in April 2017 and it had
actually the version number 1.0 in it
that worm only used stored credentials
and input and create a list of
credentials that were stored in the
binary itself that it was trying against
different open SMB servers if we took a
step back a little further we found a
previous version of the backdoor which
was called W cry beta one a cry beta
that version really didn't spread well
at all
and it looked like they were trying to
spread it manually and via sphere fishes
and so forth like that but taking a look
at the source code brought us back to a
whole set of other SMB based tools which
had a North Korean Nexus in the same
time frame there was a much more
targeted compromise which used the same
basic SMB worm technology and functions
but it dropped to backdoor tools called
alpha and C and Bravo and C at that
organization and really that SMB worm
was based off of this toast toast week
named ramble which the North Koreans had
been using since May 2015
when we took a look at our data we were
able to find these worms have been
trying to be they were trying to spread
these worms from way back in 2016 at
least and nobody paid attention to it at
all until it started to compromise
people's sales kiosks but you know there
was a lot of media impact from this
there was a lot of questions about this
but when we actually took our step back
and looked at the organizations that we
were managing their security for we had
73 unique clients who had actual
detections of this worm in their
environment and that's out of a bit over
4,000 different clients that we managed
security for we had 399 total tickets in
those 73 clients and we had 278 unique
clients who requested information from
us so the actual number of clients that
were asking us information was much
larger than the number of clients who
were actually impacted when we really
dug into it we also found that none of
our clients had a true major impact none
of their core resources or core
information technology infrastructure
was really impacted everything that was
impacted were things like a computer
over at a sales office and they had
somehow they had a single internet
access point that was completely open to
the net things like that and then that's
also why you saw a lot of ATM machines
and display kiosks that were being
compromised these were all hosts that
had almost no let's say core business
impact and inside an organization but
you know we had a lot of hype around one
a cry and a lot of hype around these SMB
vulnerabilities that were out there so
everyone's patched right
a month later this happened and we found
out or it started to look like nobody
had applied these patches or a lot of
really large organizations had not
applied these patches so on June 28th
2017 around 10:00 a.m. UTC we started to
receive requests from a few
organizations first based in Europe and
then later based in US where they had a
massive amounts of their systems
compromised and all that Christian take
it from here okay thank you so both of
us have been involved in a handful of
not Petra investigations and of those a
lot of our clients were completely hosed
I thought was important for us to bring
you stories about this stories from the
innocent response stories to how it
happened how it could have been
prevented but in order to do that I need
to protect names of the innocent we can
obviously give client data so I've
created a fictitious company protect
identities of these other organizations
but this fictitious company everything
that I given these stories actually
happen these are actual facts they're
not sensation alized these actually
happened so the company that I'm
presenting that I created I just call it
a beach wear clothing manufacturer and
retailer so presenting Seaside's
that's Seaside's as in the sea you kind
of have to question the credibility of a
company based out of Pittsburgh that has
a Sun in their logo so Seaside's they
have about roughly a thousand hosts our
window shop so they lost most of their
host they'd already engaged a third
party to start manually real building
rebuilding these hosts so it's a long
laborious process they called us in to
help them out to determine well what
actually happened how did we get
impacted how do we prevent this from
happening in the future so our first
goal is was well let's work backwards
let's find the earliest evidence of
compromise because that's important
because obviously they'll need to fix
that determine the entry point to the
environment and then determine how it
was spread within the environment
because you know fixing the introduction
patient zero is one thing preventing
something from spreading is another that
the client needs to take care of so my
initial thoughts was Ms 1701 zero
eternal blue because the news had come
out that not petrol uses this
vulnerability so I asked the client hey
are you guys patched fraternal glue and
say no we patched it's not eternal blue
so I'm like okay we're gonna have to dig
further and investigate
so starting point like I said the
clients of window shop they were hosed
so things as an investigator an instant
responder that I am used to getting
don't in it didn't exist domain
controllers hosed
no domain controller logs their sim was
a window sim their sim hosed no data
from their sim and by now the media has
already reported on a few handful of
companies that were completely and some
of these were very large companies that
not Petra affected their entire
operations they were down and so I took
this list and I provided to the client
and client Luca listen said that one is
one of her vendors and of course that
got me thinking okay back to my mind I
need to consider that the burner
proof is still very low so I can't say
yep this is what caused it but this is
something that need to focus on so where
do we start well fortunately we did have
some logs there far away obviously
weren't Windows boxes and so we pulled
firewall logs and started analyzing
those working our way backwards to the
initial time of the infection and the
logs as we figure it out showed a lot of
SMB tracking traffic indicative of not
Pecha great it just proves that you know
we're just further supports that yes it
is not Petra you got the splash screen
you got the logs we know that so didn't
really give us much more information one
of the problems was visibility
limitations the you know the their
firewalls were placed only on certain
locations through you know outgoing
ingressing through outside the network
VPNs they've had a ton of 24/7 VPNs to
their third-party trust trusted third
parties so it helped us a little but it
didn't really give us the answers we
need
so the next step well we're gonna have
to go to where the data we need and get
it from there which means we're gonna
have to rebuild and conduct forensics on
things we think is a will contain this
data things of evidentiary value so we
determined we got an AV server let's do
that let's rebuild the AV server
you got a sim let's rebuild the sim and
possibly any early affected computers
from the firewall logs so we started
doing this so those of you not familiar
with not Petra does to a computer
it literally rewrites the MBR the Master
Boot Record so when it boots up it shows
that splash screen like hey you've been
owned send money to blah blah blah but
it also tries to encrypt the first end
amount bytes of your ma or your your
master file table which is your table of
context to the to the drive without that
you can't actually rebuild and figure
out where your files are that's all gone
you need to basically carve data it's a
forensic technique where we have to
carve data and free or unallocated space
whatever you call that but it's worth a
try for us to recover the data because
the
were in this data so first thing we said
is will rebuild the AV server it's very
easy it's one workstation one drive and
there's a tool we use to replace the MBR
and fortunately the MFT was untouched by
not petra I don't know why but through
that the forensic software was able to
rebuild the structure of the drive and
then we were able to pull off AV logs
however the AV logs was not a real
benefit because AV didn't catch non
pedra and stop it
so there were no logs at that time there
was no signature to stop the not Petra
outbreak so AV logs now been to any good
however these security event logs on
that host was very fruitful what you see
up there make sure I press the laser
pointer is a snippet all made up by the
way names domains made up everything
else actual names domains and target
servers was a pattern we saw of
authentications these were five five two
event IDs so for you event ID gurus
you're probably thinking what's five
five two five five two is a explicit
login logging on trying to log on to
another resource using different
credentials than what you're logged on
to that box it's like but isn't that 46
48 or something it is for machines that
are greater than Windows XP and 2008 or
so on you're like wait a minute so that
means this is a Windows XP rc1 box yes
one of those that's a important point
that I'm going to cover in a few other
slides but basically this is logs
indicative of not Petra trying to
authenticate out to the rest of the
environment from the AV log it's
important data so I pulled this data and
I mapped it like this and there were
some interesting patterns I saw the
domains the domain names and the
accounts so one of the first things is I
showed to our client do you recognize
these domain names and the ones on the
bottom yes that's our domain ET net
do you recognize any of the names up top
I don't recognize the domains but
entropy that that's a company that is
our vendor that's the one that was in
the news that got impacted by not petrol
whoa we got more data we're like okay
this makes sense now
we've now have a higher burden of
evidence that we know where nan Petra
came from
perhaps we can dig and find more then it
hit me it's like hey this is interesting
you see a pattern of where this moved
through we did some research on some of
the domains like there's a domain called
EMS you found out that it was actually a
division of entropy or entropy tech
called Enterprise marketing statistics
and that's the other thing I didn't say
is the client said yeah entropy is a
trusted vendor we have a full-time
connected VPN to their systems they
provide a service they do statistical
marketing and we use their product and
of course it all makes sense now
right EMS is actually a subdivision we
look at looked it up on the web's called
Enterprise marketing statistics East ATS
is the actual name of the application
that Seaside's uses okay so you can see
kind of like a pattern of movement so I
contacted Arin and basically said and if
you look in this slide you can see the
same set of user names being repeated
over and over and over again in that
same path so you looked at that and that
that's kind of key to determining the
path of the malware we call it a flight
recorder erin look at the malware and
basically validated that yes the malware
passes on credential is that it captures
first-in first-out so you could use that
order and basically build the flight of
not Petra determining where it initially
came from which is kind of cool because
you have not just patients are on your
own environment but patients are all for
that chain of the outbreak other
interesting things what is these names
of the users searched it on the web and
found their LinkedIn accounts and said
they work for entropy tech and I do
blahhh there's also read you know
looking at some of the names so Oksana
you google that the first thing that
comes up it's at you
in your name we didn't talk about I'm
sure you guys know the whole history
about and I don't know that's something
we probably should cover but the whole
history of the nod Petra what has been
reported in news I guess validated was
originated out of the Ukraine
possibly Russian government interference
meddling in Ukraine it was related to
the ME Doc's software which is a tax
software that is very commonly used in
the Ukraine it was back doored and
Aaron's gonna cover that more in depth
so I don't want to really steal his
thunder but looking at the pattern that
first user named crane Ian so it may be
Ukrainian user I don't know the other
user name so we're all South Asian so it
makes sense regionally how maybe this
mal removed I'm starting to build this
picture but we know now entropy tech is
patient zero for our client so next step
we're going to rebuild the symbol we
want to that was a little challenging
because it was a raid like a twelve
drive raid 5 and and from forensics we
don't want to muck around with the
drives unless we have a backup so we had
to forensically image the drive to make
sure we had a good drive and then we can
play around and rebuild the MB are we
able to rebuild the MBR MFT did exist so
we could power up took a little work
talk to the vendor to get their sims off
we're back up and running but then we
could do queries on the sim and we then
identified the actual authentication
into the application we call the e stats
application the first authentication
into the environment so now we have the
server a patient zero within C sides and
the authentication we then did forensics
on that box so it's rebuild the MBR but
the MFT was encrypted so we have to
carve out event logs and then we found
the first successful malware indication
via PS exec so the sim basically had
domain controller logs not as lofty not
as detailed so we decided to do
forensics to get more information so I'm
going to do a very quick nice of the
graphics play-by-play of what happened
so as you can see here on the left this
is the entropy Tech environment there
was a 24/7 trusted VPN into Seaside's
Seaside's had a separate domain for the
East debts application called ET net
when I looked in the firewall logs the
interesting thing is I did not find any
SMB port 139 or port 4 5 traffic
connections immediately preceding the
propagation and I'm thinking that that
doesn't make sense because you know the
malware traversed from entropy tech I
should see a record add in the firewall
so that was that was got me wondering
but I did see a day prior there was a
port 4 or 5 session initiated a day
earlier so huh this possibly could be
involved I don't know yet what I then
saw is the actual propagation of the
malware into the e stats applications
interesting and interesting in love
enough it only successfully
authenticated and ran on one server at
first at first exactly the raining
servers within this application domain
it tried to run with credentials but it
failed because they would only use
credentials it knew from entropy tech it
didn't know when he seaside credentials
so when you combine that with the fact
that there was an active session and we
validated through eventually through the
analysis of the malware that not petrol
utilizes and abuses active sessions
right so it doesn't need to actually
have a credential if you have an active
session between two trusted environments
not Petra will be able to use that to
spread so huh that's that's really
interesting really cool not cool
depending on what side you're on
then from the host that it initially
compromised it's excessively compromised
other environments within the e stats
environment with a different credential
so now it makes sense the reason why was
that different credentials if you use an
active session it didn't actually
capture the credentials on the entropy
tech side so for the most part w digest
which is a clear text caching of
credential has a clear text caching a
bit ability to text sorry W digests
cached his clear text passwords that was
likely turned off on the entropy text
side but because of that active session
it was able to then infect this box our
client environment because it was a
older version it was 2008 not our c1 or
I'm sorry 2003 there was no patch to
turn off the caching of clear text
passwords so not Petra was able to get
an actual Seaside's credential the
actual password and used to spread
internally so you're thinking okay well
this is in within a separate domain it
should be contained with proper security
segmentations yes it should be contained
within only the e stats application
however what happened was there was a
successful not Petrov successfully able
from one of the boxes to move to the
rest of the environment and within
seconds basically owned their entire
network since opposed so how did that
happen
we found that the domain admin have
logged on to one of the boxes now domain
admin for the entire environment logged
on to one of the boxes in the e stats
application because W digest clear text
password caching was an able not Petra
was able to capture the domain admins
credentials and spread across their
entire environment this is an issue of
domain trust and a poor implementation
of domain trust within security so we
know now how we know patient zero we
know how the malware spread we know a
lot about the miss configurations of
security for this client that we can
report to them but an interesting tidbit
is like whoa who's this person who's
Oxana be
and it did a little web search and we
found that there was a freelance site of
freelance sites for people to go look
for freelancers coders doing different
things there was actually a profile
called Oksana be of someone in the
Ukraine who did very very niche work
that was so related to type of work
there we go
such niche work that was related to
entropy text type of work now obviously
this is just loose information it's just
a hunch but it makes sense when you look
at the path of the malware think about
the story is well it started in the
Ukraine again this is just this is not
actual this is more of a just thinking
and a hunch but it follows a story and
should be Tek hires contractors hard one
crane and me dog software installed on
their box connected with an HP tech
environment and it spread from there it
slowly worked its way getting entropy
Tech employees credentials slowly
working its way out until I got to the
east at application and from there and
moved over to our client it's pretty
tricky how this thing moved but you
think about it like there weren't a lot
of businesses that completely got hosed
by not Petra it's not like you know
you're hearing like there's a good
handful but maybe that's because it
requires all these gates and steps to
occur right this is pretty complex to
happen but all these conditions existed
in order for the not Petra to affect our
client code so taking some of the good
lessons in Christians story they're
really that you should really take home
from you is really to like evaluate both
the network segmentation pieces but also
the trust relationships you have with
those external parties frequently those
can be abused in ways that you can't
really war game or envision when you're
first setting those up the other
takeaway there was in a lot of the
organizations where we saw that not
petia had
catastrophic ly taking them down that
happened within 50 minutes in one place
it was pretty quick
in other places it was within an hour as
well it was if it's something that I
don't think anyone has been looking at
or building their defenses for until
this past year but when we took a look
at not petia itself what we really found
out was that payload the way that it was
pulled down was through a Trojan I zap
Lakai Chinon the EM edocs
statistics software and attacks attack
submission software that update was
truly pushed on June 22nd so what a lot
of organizations had done was they
pulled down that software tested that
software made sure that it didn't cause
any implement any problems with their
implementation and they didn't see
anything wrong with it but then the
actual malicious payload was pushed six
days later again on a Friday
luckily which caused me to have to work
all weekend again so before that they
had pushed previous implementations of
this back door within that Trojan high
software first on May 15th and
previously on April 14th but one of the
biggest stories with this was afterwards
there was a lot of marketing and a lot
of press about another worm called bad
rabbit but bad rabbit really almost
didn't impact any of our clients at all
what we saw there was that were that
tool had three components one of them
was that this concretion component
another one was really just there to
shut down and restart the hosts and then
the third part was a worm component but
it uses hard-coded credentials for the
IPC dollar share in SMB
the big difference with this backdoor
versus the other backdoor in the other
work and the reason why this didn't seem
to spread quite so quickly was it didn't
pass the credentials from host to host
like not petia dead on the command line
when it propagated through an SMB
which meant that it didn't take
credentials that were stolen from
Christians computer to my computer to
the next computer and move forward
through all of the hosts that it could
touch and those credentials could
authenticate too so those were the
stories that got the most press this
past year but there were others worms
that have been spreading and that have
been being used which really had a much
larger impact within our organizations
in our and the organizations that we
monitor the first one and the one that
we see almost every single day is a
motet emote it's really just a piece of
software that's there to load other
software on your computer it's really
opportunistic cybercrime malware but
what we've been seeing is they've been
deploying this SMB spreader module with
it and at first it was just purely mini
cats based and that was first based up
and that was first introduced back in
July 2017 and then it started to get a
little bit more press when in November
2017 they introduced a variant of it
which also used the eternal romance
exploit in it the funny thing was when
they added that eternal romance exploit
to the worm they broke it and it only
worked and it only successfully
propagated within the local host that it
had already compromised when it was
trying to propagate to additional hosts
it actually didn't drop its payload and
didn't successfully propagate the other
one that we've been seeing a lot of
husband the trick bought SMB spreader
and this first got a lot of press back
in July 2017 as well but at that point
all it was doing was trying to enumerate
the credentials that it could see
through SMB within your organization but
then at some point and I'm not exactly
sure when they introduced it they also
added mini cats and the ability to
scrape credentials through from
plaintext into that worm those two worms
they've not been deploying ransomware
they've just been deploying themselves
and other pieces of
crime work but what's been interesting
in what has been causing a lot of issues
in organizations has been when those
worms are spreading they're spreading so
quickly and overwhelming to the main
controllers and Active Directory systems
within organizations that people are no
longer able to authenticate to hosts and
it results in a denial of service
situation within these organizations and
we've seen this a lot of you know in a
lot of situations so how can
organizations mitigate against these
situations the first bit is yes you have
solutely still need to patch so yeah
we're not going to tell you anything
here novel or new it's all fun in the
nose right basic security hygiene
repeated over and over and over and as
you've seen in my example if it was just
basic security hygiene implemented maybe
just one or two gates would have been
prevented and this wouldn't have had a
major impact to our client so one of the
things that I do and I work on as I do a
lot of thought they've been over the
last four years for secure works so I
looked at a lot of environments and
there's almost a correlation between how
ugly and bad and dirty your environment
is and what's just basic stuff that that
client has implemented and when we do
are after a threat hunting weed or our
recommendations the top recommendations
are basic stuff that you've heard over
the last 10 years one of them get
updated operating systems right it's
2018 not 2008 you need to run supported
operating systems in the case of our
client if they had to support in
operating systems they could have
patched the W digest clear text caching
interesting enough and this is a sure
you guys are aware of this right the
point of contact for our client was the
security guy was like yeah I've been
trying to get these updated for a while
for years however there's backlash
because this business area needs the
software and there's like they don't
make it anymore or they don't want to
buy the newest version and they need it
and I've been told to keep it running
and I can't muck around with I don't
even know like I have no idea what goes
on there but I got to keep it running
well this is what happens right
interesting so eternal blue history of
that is Microsoft actually took a highly
unusual step in their own words and
created a patch for unsupported the
Windows XP and 2003 server so an ironic
tidbit with Seaside's was even though
they asked for this
they were running server 2000 I'm not
kidding they were running server 2000
which there was no patch for those
server 2000 belonging to a specific
application that they needed up and
running because their business one
business needed it those got infected by
not Petra but not Petra was not able to
replace the MBR or encrypt the MFT
so it's almost like saying security by
obsolescent which is not the story I
want to tell sorry it's not this the the
message I want to say but it's just kind
of ironic that that happened
segmentation so segmentation we all know
segmentation segmentation occurs on
multiple levels we all familiar with
network segmentation firewalls bla bla
bla bla and would that help here
somewhat I mean it was a trusted VPN
connected that had SMB traffic already
open right so you know it's Network
segmentation may have not had worked
properly there for this case the client
had an open flat network and there were
other sub there were other clients that
shared the network other organizations
that shared that network that were also
impacted so segmentation definitely
would have helped but segmentation goes
beyond work domain segmentation you know
segmenting your domains and from
enforced and something called privileged
access hardening which Erin is going to
cover next yeah so what Christian was
saying with network with segmentation is
that in a lot of organizations I think
they think that once they implement a
firewall and set up that sort of policy
between different parts of the network
that their network has been segmented
and what we've been seeing time and
again at the top of this large
infographic of sorts is an attacker
comes in they just compromised a user
workstation from that user workstation
it's almost like clockwork we always see
this where they just use mini cats they
dump the clear text credentials from
their the House of hashes that they can
get access to and then they pass the
hash from host to host a host that
allows them to access the domain
controller eventually because at some
point a domain admin has logged into one
of those hosts that they compromised
they take that domain admins credential
and they're able to use that to access
every single host in the environment
we've seen it in these automated worms
like not patio we've also been seeing it
in more targeted ransomware cases like
the Sam Sam cases which have taken down
other entire networks and then been
ransom one-off Microsoft has introduced
a new set of technology and I don't know
how new this is anymore but it came with
Windows 10 in essence and what that does
is and and their recommendations are for
you to use a privileged access
workstation and that's the little red
computer up in the corner and that
privileged access workstation allows
only that admin to create credentials on
that host and then if that admin needs
to have actual can only have one laptop
or one workstation they have a virtual
machine which they'll use for their
actual user land life to access their
email to go onto the web to look at
sharepoint or whatever now taking an
even larger step from that is to create
this and it's truly a four tiered
set of credentials but here it only
shows the first three tiers which are
based on your administrator credentials
a tier 0 your domain admin will only
live within tier 0 and only
authenticated tier 0 that domain admin
credential
is not usable and not useful for
accessing the next tier tier 1 is made
up of your core workstations and your
what's the term I'm looking for your
your core workstations and your core and
your
core servers that put business-critical
applications out there and that's
separate from your domain controllers in
your Active Directory administration so
the credentials from tier zero which are
Active Directory administrator
credentials can't authenticate and can't
administrate your work your your
business critical servers the Tier one
credentials have to stay on tier one
they only access and they only
authenticate to your business critical
servers but then those credentials can't
even access the workstations that your
normal people are using and that's what
makes up tier two tier two are your
administrator credentials for your for
your helpdesk and for your user
workstation administrator staff those
credentials stay there now in this and
then the fourth tier which isn't shown
in this image is made up of your normal
user credentials using this model
whenever an attacker compromises one of
those workstations through a phishing
email which happens every day everywhere
when they try to scrape those
credentials from memory they're no
longer able to use those for anything
other than accessing other people's
workstations and other things on that
tier if you're able to keep these things
clear and clean like that so we strongly
recommend that people move to this sort
of model and that level of segmentation
in almost all of the cases where we've
been seeing entire organizations
compromised and and put in terrible
situations with ransomware but then
previously with a lot of the apt style
intrusions it was because there was
usually a single admin which allowed you
to authenticate and administrate all of
the hosts and it was that shared admin
account which the helpdesk used the
server administrators used as well as
the domain administrators used and they
had a single password equally or you
know a single set of credentials so once
you get that hash to pass the hash
across the organization so in summary
the mitigations our patch absolutely
we put those patches into place and this
is pretty basic and pretty standard
stuff we're not selling any special
things but if you want to buy stuff you
can buy stuff from us too but also
segmentation which is way more than just
firewalls and really includes your
different separate Active Directory
forst's but creating that privileged
access workstation and tiered model
really helps organizations improve your
security posture plus disabling wmic
where possible the W digests credentials
and scraping those really is something
that we see all the time there's there
are a lot of single sign-on applications
which require W digests to be running
and actually require people to use that
we understand that try to segment those
organizations and those parts of your
organization even more so than the rest
of the organization yeah and if not
privileged access workstations don't use
a single account to administrate all of
your hosts that is our presentation
we've got four minutes I think
[Applause]