now into the boring stuff
so what are containers um in order to
understand potatoes i'm really quickly
going to talk about what
the differences are between like
traditional virtualization so like your
virtual machines
um
so
what a virtual machine is is it uses
something called hypervisor
and it emulates your computer kernel and
all the hardware and all the software
your operating system the whole ship so
it's an entirely like
software-based computer
on your computer
um obviously problems with that it's
chunky it's slow
[Music]
it's not better
okay right perfect so
um containers try to solve some of these
problems um so they don't actually
traditionally they don't have hypervisor
um so they only emulate all the software
so they have to be obviously compatible
with whatever machine you're running on
um this makes them much more lightweight
so you can get a lot more containers in
the space you only get one vm
and it also makes a little more portable
which obviously is good if you're trying
to like ship out
um lots of containers and people you
don't have
to wait ages to set off and
although the problem with this is
they're not fully isolated as a result
so
you have to watch
breakouts a lot easier
and so you have to be careful
of what's your security on them
so docker straight in 2013 currently
uses container ds it's one time
and when people talk about docker
they're usually talking about like
docker engine
or dropper desktop and the docker has
tons of products to make up these are
just some of them there are others
um so real quick hub is an image
repository that's um all containers
built with images
um so that's where you get them you get
official and unofficial images
um so officials have been to apache all
that and unofficial anyone can make
images
um and upload them
account
docker engine um
that's just cli
and so that's what i'm mainly talking
about today yeah that's what we're going
to talk about today um use linux and
actually create run manage everything
docker got the desktop it's essentially
a gui version that you use for
windows um and then
yeah docker containers from windows are
all separate keller fish it's a
hypervisor uh hyperd or wsl2
they're all getting into that uh compose
this is yaml files so if you're wanting
to create lots and lots and lots of
containers or you've got a very specific
setup that you have
you chuck it in like a nice yama file so
you can like spin up whatever you want
and then drop a swarm um have you ever
heard of kubernetes
it's just the container orchestration
solution to swarm is docker's version of
kubernetes such lets you manage hundreds
of containers at once
um and it makes it a little bit easier
for you
so
vulnerabilities what's wrong with
containers
um i went on the myer database um
literally like
two days ago 194 cde records for docker
so there is a lot there's a lot out
there
um some i'm just going to go into some
we're going to go to all because we'll
be here all day
um some like vulnerabilities and
misconfigurations mainly i will say
however um not judging anyone if you're
running containers like this obviously
docker wouldn't let you do it there's no
purpose so there are reasons why people
run their containers like this it's not
like a gotcha moment you see someone
running their containers they're
probably just using it to debug
um because she's a privileged flag
not always a great idea because one
thing with containers like i said
previously they're not fully isolated so
even if you're not running them as a
super user if you have root access
inside that container and you break out
you then get root access in those
so
very dangerous as well
um adding extra capabilities and lots of
different resources circles without
saying
um you can use that to like damage the
host machine or any applications in the
container dot attacks the whole
oh how can you say
i kind of see that
i'm sorry this is my work here and it's
there we go no
this talks is going great
right
dangerous directories so
sometimes you need
some files resources applications that
are on your host machine you can mount
them into the container
absolutely fine not an issue but there
are certain directories you probably
don't want to be
allowing your container to have access
to etc bin
home sometimes you can put ssh keys
um to just be mindful of that
i did say i won't judge but if i see
anyone mounting your whole host file
system to your container i will find you
that's unacceptable what is the point of
using containers at that point
but it is something you can do i don't
know why you would
um and then running containers in the
host name space
so
um talk about namespace a second but
essentially
um namespaces restrict what
um
what processes can see and you've got a
host named space and if you tell a
container just to mount on to that you
can see all the processes of your host
and then you've messed up with them
which is
not a good thing and that's the flag
so more
unofficial images like i said anyone can
upload images um
it's a bit
it's a bit of a tricky game
some companies make their own versions
of images if our specific um
requirements is fine
um but just be mindful of what you're
pulling
so i study some research on 2020 and
they
scanned all the images in docker hub and
of the unofficial ones 74 of them had
medium and high rated vulnerabilities
compared to only 47 of the official ones
so
also in 2019 um a security research
company found
um
multiple um
containers that have cryptocurrency
mining malware on it and trojans of all
sorts and one of them in chicago had two
million pools
so there are containers out there that
are mining bitcoin people don't even
know
uh not regularly updating your images so
it's really easy to spin up a container
have it do something small and you just
leave it you ignore it you don't think
about it
but
you need to update it um it's not
difficult please do
but you need to be careful docker can be
a bit funny um so
it's easy just to be like oh update late
i'll just pull the latest image
even on official they forever are
releasing unstable images
so you can actually give yourself more
vulnerabilities than you initially had
and so always try and go for the latest
stable versions uh for example in 2020
there were 40 cds to occur
32 of them had the exact same
vulnerability all of them were given a
cvss score 10 for privilege escalation
every single one of them
the um root user password
so
again be very careful about what images
you're going uh like i said poison
images um
people are private malware things and
networking i'm not gonna go super into
networking but if you're exposing your
container to the internet be really
careful um there's currently an apt
called team tnt it sounds like a
minecraft server and if you google it
it's going to come up they're not
um and they essentially scour things
like showdown
and they're pretty indiscriminate uh
their main motivation is finance so even
if you're like just dual blogs they're
going to try and put cryptocurrency
money malware on your thing and they
don't care and if you want to know more
about their attacks you just say
something factually incorrect about them
twitter and your correction
right so is it all doom and gloom what
can you do
i have the solution
absolutions
uh i will also say none of these have to
be used like separately you can mix
match with minerals
so make spaces i didn't talk a little
bit about i can't really see last time
um so yeah they restrict what resources
are processed most children can see
um i have some people refer to it's like
almost called container light
um so it's not contained at all but so
essentially you put the
process in a little bubble where it
doesn't know it's being restricted
but it can't see what it's not allowed
to see so it thinks vibrancy that's it
um
yes so docker has a default namespace
that you can enable called docker remap
um and that first
file path and you just create
daemon.json and then you add in uh
essentially just use your ns remount
column default and you just like please
use the default interface
um and this bottom two are just where
you check seeing your spaces if this is
enabled
and it's a pretty good one um it's not
too destructive
but it just stopped for all minor things
c groups control groups um very similar
to namespaces um
but
the process knows it's being restricted
unlike new spaces where it has no it
can't see
secrets
and secrets are specifically for
hardware resources so like memory ram
memory uh cpu all that shenanigans so
really useful if you want to try and
prevent um
like gloss attacks and things like that
um again it's screenshot the safety job
but i just didn't really
i restricted memory and swap memory and
honestly it's like three lines of code
really easy to recommend
right getting into slightly more
complicated so app armor it is the
default linux security module used by
docker what is one of the security
questions well as the name suggests
it's a way of securing processes and
applications in products
um
and you get two types you get mandatory
access controls and discretion access
modules so
dac or discretion access control systems
are like the older ones
um
and they
put everything into put all the users
into groups and they restrict
the like users from access nodes like
group one you can see abc script two can
say abf
now the problem is it doesn't restrict
the processes the users are running so a
user can just run a process and be like
right now go talk to like c
and they can see it so um
they came up with mastery access which
is a little bit more modern
and they
are a lot stricter and they um restrict
processes
rather than just like user groups so the
processes themselves different systems
um armor itself is policy based so you
set little policies both um you're
running
and
docker has one called docker default
that you can set up um it's a bit funky
you can't really edit it and it sort of
like disappears from the file system
i don't know how to touch it and they
don't want you to touch it if you want
to create your own
um don't do it by hand just no it's
horrible
no one does um here's some nice madeline
tools you can use
um easy profane and my personal favorite
mainly because of the name is securely
and that is specifically that's the one
specifically for docker and the other
two are
less specific but they're really easy
just a couple lines of code you just
tell them what containers what's you're
thing he's going to be doing it and this
stuff might be at home
[Music]
sc limits
the bane of my existence i'm going to be
honest it's also essential security
enhanced linux and it's also a mac
system and but it uses labels
to control access to like all your files
or your purchase everything's labeled
that sounds great and it is genuinely
more secure than our plumber
but it's absolute fafsa
like it's disgusting i would say unless
you're doing
unless you've got very sensitive stuff
or you're like working for a business or
whatever i wouldn't bother with essie
linux i'd just stick with armor like if
it's just you doing stuff you know
small application at home
hobby or something i wouldn't bother
um
but the reason i see linux is better
than our farmer
is mainly because
the logo is good it depends on the
sunglasses but also so app armor only
restricts docker whereas it doesn't like
restrict individual containers so
they're all got the same rule whereas
seo linux you can
make specific rules for each container
so if they need different amounts of
access you can do that
and it's great
and it's a lot more difficult to like
break out of the rules and stuff on it
so yeah
oh
second secure computing it is not an lsn
it's not a linux security module
um but it's a kernel security thing
um
and it limits system calls that process
can make docker is a default one
it disables about 44 of your system
calls
um and i i'm honestly i wouldn't mess
about this too much it the
docker default one is pretty good uh
here are some of the
ones that disables so you've got acct
or account and it disabled you can use
it to disable resource limits
um delete module you can delete kernel
modules
and p trace so
p trace
um you can use to circumvent second
completely and the reason i have this
gift is because
even if you
have a second profile that restricts
that you can't do a single system called
you still run containers like oh they'll
let me do this
so if you're running a container and you
can't do anything but you've got ptrace
enabled
then there's no pull
like an attack can just
change everything and get out
so
i've spent this
right conclusions
be careful of what you're doing with
your containers make sure you're mindful
of why you're like what are you wanting
them to do so like do you need all those
resources do you need
um
that
file system mounted
uh new best friends i would honestly
recommend app armor s linux name spaces
secrets like try and set them all up
have a play with them if you get
no check on what's yours if you guys see
linux working like please
teach me um i would love to know i've
never successfully done it um
but yeah i honestly wouldn't bother like
day to day stuff but
i think if you want
um
sorry for the disaster that's been me
talking about
any questions also i have a cat want to
see my cat that's my story
that's not my first time
[Music]
oh so
are there any tools that will
like tell you if you're potentially
running a horrible dinner
yeah i'm sure there are i've not looked
into that specifically um but i'm sure
there are
i know securely that i was talking about
earlier it does tell you if you're
trying to run a container that it
restricts
so
that might be something similar so it's
like you you said you don't have this
done
testing sorry i'd probably stick to vms
for that um because like i said
um
so my whole discussions into the
breakouts and it's shockingly easy
so you're honestly putting your whole
your whole thing at risk doing that but
if you've got it
i don't know even if you got it locked
down i wouldn't trust it
maybe let me know how it goes but
honestly i would stick to vm for that
yeah
[Music]
so
are you asking if i would use containers
as honeypots or vms
[Music]
um i don't know too much about honeybots
um
i mean if you want people
to like
go for it
i guess containers are more attractive
so later
and people don't have to install as much
because like vms are massive um
yeah i don't know that's a good question
i don't know i don't have an answer
though
yeah
i was gonna say on the mother
entertainer's probably not the
to be best application containers that
don't take long for immune system
or like the web browser
you'd better rock work or something like
that
but even
anyone else
thank you