right so hacking 95 a day in the life of
so thank you for all being patient and
staying with me through the the problems
it's working now it's all that matters
so that's it so
this talk
is about a pen testing and
what to expect in the other life of so
i'm a pen tester
and i've been pen testing for quorum
cyber for
um three years now
uh prior to that i have been pentesting
for another three years so cumulative
six years pen testing experience
and i was an ethical hacking student
here in abertay and i graduated in 2016.
so that's a basic summary of me so how
many of you have thought about being pen
testers
okay and how many of you have given
other
other areas of cyber security thought or
is it just
it's a lot obvious
so that's perfect so that's it
so as i say this talk is about what to
expect of pen tesla the reason for this
talk was when i was a student here i
kind of knew i wanted to be a pen tester
i knew what i wanted to do but there
wasn't a lot of information about what
to expect out there so pen testing isn't
exactly what i was expecting when i
graduated but i'm glad that it's not and
it's basically helped refine me to this
profession that i am now
so it's going to cover the engagements
that are frequently encountered on a pen
test engagement
people may encounter in general not just
on pentest engagements and this is
basically aimed towards people who are
looking to take their first steps into
pen testing
so this is just a brief summary of my
day-to-day overview luckily a quorum
cyber i get the ability to work from
home so i could wake up relatively late
and so it speaks still before nine it's
quite good if you're a bit
of a bad morning person i get out of my
bed i can make myself a coffee have some
breakfast
get down to my office and check my
emails direct messages reply to
what what basically
reply to people who have contacted me
could that be clients give me employees
looking for help just to basically
assist them
once that started and then start my day
testing and just juggle my testing
through
through the day between the means that i
carry out
so the
penetration testing journey
so it's not just testing so that's the
first thing i'd like to say people just
expect you're going to be put out in
front of people
and you're giving a website to test so
you're giving infrastructure to test
it's not always that it's a whole
journey from start to finish whereby
you interact with the clients
at an early stage and through to the
final cause of the engagement
so there's three sort of three-star main
sections here as you see the pre-sales
the delivery and the reporting stage
so we're going to start off with your
sort of your pre-sale stuff
so initially
you are first brought into your sort of
pen test and engagement and pen and
environment in your scope and call with
the customer
so the customer calls you and
basically says look i'm looking for this
test i want a pen test done and
pentest means very different things to
different people
so people come in like i want a pen test
they've heard the term that's what they
want
so it's our jobs along with the sales
people to find out exactly why they want
testing exactly what they want tested
and what elements they are most
concerned about
so this is your first interaction with
the clients i've mentioned
to me is important you are the face of
the test and team at this stage you need
to
to paint this professional image to help
help the company give off this good
thing with ethos to make sure that they
are the right person for the testing
because a test engagement with the
customers
so
it gives you the chance to ask them
questions i've mentioned
so you kind of want to understand why
they want testing done so is it for
compliance reasons is that they want to
improve their security posture or is it
just they have to have a checkbox a
little bit saying a customer wants us to
get a pen test done can we get something
so you get this whole spectrum
of people coming in for tests
as i say you get to ask your relevant
questions so i had someone come up to me
earlier on to do for the day asking if
we carry a load balance and test it so
obviously we don't carry out load
balancing testing so it's denial of
service if you were to toss a customer's
real environment that's bad you don't
want to
cost them money you don't want to have
downtime for it so
one of the questions you could ask at
the scope and stages for example is
do you have a uet environment so do you
have a testing environment do you have a
development environment and if so does
this directly replicate life and
obviously the reason behind this is to
make sure
that
this environment can be used as an
alternative for testing so you can be a
bit more free reign you can basically go
a little bit more vigorously without
worrying about knocking it over or
polluting their live databases
so
again
it's just basically making sure that the
customer has
a good overall experience of testing a
good overall experience of the
engagement so if you have a bad
engagement they're less likely to come
back it just
helps paint a better image
and ultimately it gets you to the point
whereby you can understand what services
they would actually benefit from
so
that pen test terms thrown around they
come and say i want a web test or i want
an internal test you've asked questions
and you've found out that their their
main concern is their external posture
so why have they asked
they say they want an internal test if
their main concern is their external
facing network you would tailor
something around this and then you would
say the end goal is to ultimately get
you to the point where by your concern
would then move to your internal aspect
and then at that point you could then
carry out an internal test
so the next stage of testing is your
sales support and proposal writing
so you've collected all this information
from the client on the scoping section
you have
asked them the questions you've noted
down and this is the point whereby you
help create the first document that is
delivered to the client
so this in my opinion is an important
very important document because
from the get-go this is the standard of
work that they would be thinking about
expecting so to me it's important that
it's
it's clear concise and
basically just
easy to follow and so they can
understand exactly what they are getting
so again i've said
clear and concise the completeness is
important as i mentioned so you want
this document to summarize testing you
want it to
include the targets that the customer is
wanting tested
and you want to include the effort and
if it's an objective based test you want
to include the objectives so at the end
of the day the tester who comes behind
you to do this engagement can get the
one document there and be like this is
my target this is what i want
and then they can go to do it
so following on from your sales support
you get to your active active delivery
of the engagement the testing so to me
this is the
the bet where i get most enjoyment not
that the other bits are bad it's
obviously
just
what i enjoy that's why i do pen testing
so this is the active delivery so prior
to testing you have a couple of
prerequisites
so you can't just target anything you
kind of need to say hey you do need to
have appropriate authorization in place
you can't just randomly head a website
if you do you're obviously
not an authorization you're breaking the
computer missions at so you want to make
sure everything is in place that you
have written consent saying you have
authorization to test this
target between this date and this state
and if anything were to go wrong you can
go back and say well actually you've
said here that
i'm allowed to do this and obviously
you've signed our terms and conditions
and that's fine
and you again in in discussion with the
targets you want to make sure they are
exactly what is expected
uh if there's any doubt ever in place
you just go back to the client be like
look
i've got this
discrepancy is this to be expected and
again it's basically covering yourself
to make sure that you are actually
hitting what you have authorization for
and
basically are
ready to do
again prior to testing you need to
provide the organizations your test and
ipe ranges this is so if they have any
wasps or web application firewall or an
intrusion prevention system they can
allow you through it so obviously
attackers have unlimited time
whereas us as pen testers we have a set
duration of time we can try to get
around the wife and ips however
with the time there it's not going to
with the time time restriction we have
it might not be possible it might just
continually deny us testing so if you
allow us through we've got a greater
chance of covering the
the basic
coverage of the application and
make sure that
it's
basically we find as many possible
issues in the testing window that we
have
and another important thing for testing
is
continual communication with clients
so
if you have an engagement in my opinion
it's important to liaise with your
target if you speak to them you are
basically saying look i'm about to start
testing on the day i'm about to stop
testing so that way they can keep an eye
on anything that's happening if anything
happens out with this allocated window
they know it's not us and you can treat
it as a real incident and follow the
correct escalation cool calls that they
have in place or escalation policies
in line with communication
critical issues should always be
communicated as quickly as possible to
the client so for example if you've
found the sql injection
and this sql injection allows you
back-end access to their database you
can get password hashes for their
application users you don't want this to
be publicly accessible for a prolonged
duration of time you'd always want phone
of the client once you've obviously got
your proof that is possible you phone up
the client i look i found this issue
here
and
this issue is replicable
by following the steps
and allows them to make an issue whilst
you're testing so that way once they've
done it you can follow back and say this
issue is no longer present you have
successfully been able to
to resolve it
and despite this you would still include
that in the in the report and this is
just basically so that they can
they have order that in order to show
that it was there
and you can then document that same
that
the test the development team have
followed good practice they've responded
in a timely manner to resolve the issue
that is important at uh pentest report
as well which i will discuss later is
basically you don't always want it to be
negative you want to put in positives as
well so a penta pen test report can be a
negative thing but you want to try to
put a positive spin on it so that it's
not just we're not just tearing down
what works being put in place you want
to refer reaffirm
what's done well
so you're reporting
so this is arguably the most important
element for
for the client for the test so
everything prior to this
has just been um
it's just been theoretical you say
you've done your testing you see you've
done this
but what has the client got to show at
this point
nothing they have literally nothing to
show that you have done any work
so arguably is the most important
element and to say ultimately is the
product that the customer pays for
so the important factors in a report is
you want the report to be clear so you
want to say this is the issue
and
the i found then such in such a location
so i found the nexus issue within the
search search functionality on your
website
then you want to be concise and say
basically what the impact is so the
impact of xss is obviously
what is
and
you want the report to be the shape
you're applicable so you want to supply
some sort of proof like a get request
saying so that they can literally copy
and paste it directly into the url so
once that they have once they have
addressed the issue they can test
themselves whether or not the issue is
still present
so
this is
why it's important so
they need this audit trail to see the
works being done
once the work's been done you're telling
them where all their issues are
and you're giving them the point whereby
they can
resolve them they can address the issues
so status tracking as well as i've
mentioned for example the sqli injection
stuff that i mentioned a minute ago did
hypothetically replicate remediated that
during
the
during the test by having this ability
to stash track we can then mark that as
the issue has been remediated rather
than just putting in a different section
in the report
so again
as i mentioned communication on areas
are implemented well if you can
communicate what you've done well that
helps the
helps the organization justify the
development team which in the end will
help justify
the testing that they're carrying out
so once testing's been done there is a
post-test follow-up section
so
this is the chance to touch base with
the client again this is where they've
had the report for a couple of weeks
you can speak to them and say look do
you have any questions about any of the
findings
or is there anything that we can offer
you
further that that's not been covered in
this report
and it just opens up the communication
channels again and it allows them to
provide feedback on what they
experienced was good and what they
experienced was bad so that we can
basically refine the process
and help care for better engagements
moving forward
so that's the basic summary of the the
pen testing journey so hopefully that
gets across the point of it it's not
just your testing and that there is
other elements to it
so after that how many of you are still
thinking about pen testing
okay so i'm not putting too many people
off so that's good
so we're going to cover the types of
tests and experience as a new tester i
can only speak on my behalf
so these are the type of things that i
experienced when i graduated my first
role and ultimately they helped
helped shape
me into the test that i am now and
hit hold the basics that i've learned
and used throughout my
my job so far
so the first type of testing that you
would experience as a new tester could
be your web application testing
and your web application testing has
sort of three main categories
uh your brochure rare your
unauthenticate and your authenticated
testing so have any has heard of
brochure we're testing before
no
so brochure testing can be described as
purely an informational site with no
sort of login element no
no way for clients to use further
functionality that was present on the
application so your brochure we're sort
of an informational website you try to
try to think of an example of top of my
head but i can't um
whereby it's just information supplied
to them and they read off that's that
your unauthenticated testing is
obviously when your client gives you a
web application
and they say try to break in try to
bypass the authentication mechanism and
see what you can do as if you were as if
you were an illegitimate attacker who is
trying to just
break in
so
unauthenticated testing can have some
authenticated element if you find a
self-registration page on the
application if it has this self
registration you are within scope to
then follow through the self
registration process and then test the
authenticated element behind
and your third main category of web
application testing is your
authenticated content so you're
authenticated take the test and this is
when it's an application that doesn't
allow self registration
it's just purely a website for example
employees use but without having an
employee number or some sort of way of
identifying who you are you cannot
self-register
so that's that
and that's basically the three main
categories
so these web application engagements can
be tailored to clients needs
so not every client as i've mentioned
has the same requirements
um
they can be objective based coverage
based or focused on risk levels so all
depends on what your clients budget
budget is and what you've discussed in
the scope and session so if it's an
objective based test for example get to
this back end database that's your
objective if you can't demonstrate this
objective it's not being let's say it's
not going to success it has been because
obviously you've you've demonstrated
it's not possible
and whereas your coverage base is here's
a web app find as much as you can
and your specific risk levels it could
be for clients who don't have much of a
budget whether i look i'm only
interested in heiser criticals
find them report that
so some good good things that i've used
for learning web application testing
has been like the
oscp i learned a lot about web
application testing doing that when i've
done it understandably it's changed from
when i first passed however
i can only speak on my experience of it
there is goods learning opportunities
there to
to basically learn the basic
fundamentals that can help shape your
career
so your web application test typically
follows a methodology
and this methodology
helps ensure that you're covering the
applications in full and complete scope
so for example some methodologies are
your olaf or your oss tmm
typically you'll find people use a
hybrid of both and they all have their
own their own specific one that they use
and basically you shouldn't use it to
ensure that the application is covered
off
so
these methodologies all follow a basic
structure
and the basic structure is your
reconnaissance so this is your like nmap
scans of the website what information
can be found
can this information is basically
painted a picture of that
and this information can be then used to
tailor towards further attacks
your
server levels so the client wants your
underlying infrastructure done you would
then start trying to touch these pores
that are being found open you see if
there's anything to be exploited at
infrastructure level
and you would then move on to your
authentication issues so authentication
issues are a lot more common than what
you'd expect so some real life examples
of what i have found during testing with
authentication issues is
does it actually check for a password
so you think surely all applications
nowadays would check whether or not a
password is present
however there's a vulnerability called
failopen whereby is only checking for
the username string and once you've sent
the request you can then delete the
password and you're able to log in i
found that quite recently on a web
application test i was doing and was
able to log in without having a password
not good when you're a large company who
is trying to care for clients and all
their sensitive information is present
so that was basically another thing well
basically
i was able to take advantage of that
from an unauthorized point to
authenticate into the application
without having
any valid credential sets
so another example of an authentication
issue is
does an application actually
check for the session token does it not
so
one that i was able to do on a very
similar application to the
aforementioned one was it was using a
header so the header's name was for
example username colon it was like my my
name mark rose is the token
however i was able to change this to
admin
and successfully become an admin just by
changing one word once i had logged in
so so going from low level tab in this
case i'm just deleting a word and adding
another
again
ultimately these are simple security
issues that you need to look for as a
tester
so the next level after that would be
your your authentication as it just
mentions authorization sorry your
authorization issues
so authorization issues lie aloud around
your
for example insecure direct object
reference how many of yous know what
idol is
okay perfect so a couple of you so
basically within the url and there could
be example an id equals 12.
if you're able to abuse that you are
then able to
then access a resource that you're not
supposed to have access to
so
another example that i found when
testing a web app was i logged in
went to my profile section of the
application
and i noticed within the request there
was using a backend api
and within the api url there was for
example get slash api slash user
12 slash profile so i was able to change
that slash 12 to slash one to view the
admin page once i had viewed the admin
page i noticed i was actually able to
edit so it wasn't checking to make sure
i had the proper authority to edit this
page
once this i was there i decided you know
i'm going to change this admins um email
address so admin's email address then
was changed to mine i was able to use
the forgotten your password function
once i logged out to reset admins
password to log in as an admin
and you have your
miscellaneous slash injection issues so
this is where you would test for your
likes of your xss your sql injection
your xxe
and your server side request forgery
so server side request 4g is when you're
able to trick the back-end server into
making a request to a resource that you
control so another example of a
vulnerability that i found was testing
was
one of the applications allowed
allowed a user to create a list
this list was then created and whilst
when it was created the year the media
request and it looked for a specific
image as a cover cover form
so
what you could do is you could change
this cover photo to a url that is in
your control
and
that was the list saved at that point
there was nothing wrong your image was
just loaded in
but
what this web application allowed you to
do it allowed you to
export this list to a pdf
and once the
list was exported the server looked for
the image because obviously it puts in
this pdf and the server then made a
request to the asset that you're in
control of
and
that's it you have control of the server
at that point you're able to gain remote
access if you play your cards right
so the next type of testing that i
experienced as
a graduate was external infrastructure
so external infrastructure is an
assessment of your perimeter systems
so this is typically a client who comes
in like i want to know what everything
that's out there that we own
can you do tell us so yes we can but we
redo your external infrastructure and
allows the clients to gain an
understanding of their security posture
and
determine if the firewall rules that
they have implemented are correct
and if so we tell them this is what's
found they can then go back to their
firewall be like yep that matches we're
all good or if not we found
for example our rdp connection so we're
able to get a remote desktop into this
environment
and we could potentially use the
information we gave previously in the
engagement to obtain a valid credential
set to then log in and have access to
their internal network and then from
there you'd start trying to move
laterally and vertically to
obtain domain admin and basically be in
control
so your approach for an external
infrastructure test varies on client
requirements
so
some clients only want a low interaction
where we want to tool and give them the
output
so
it's a bit boring and you only kind of
verify your manual stuff you're sorry
your mind your critical or high stuff
however
this
this is good in some aspects but it
doesn't in my opinion allow complete
coverage
whereas
my personal approach to action would be
what i would call high interaction
whereby we do everything possible so we
found that snt people are open for
example so that's um mail for example
your emails so can we connect into this
mailbox yes once we connect 10 is it
possible to mail smith so mail spoofing
is the ability ability to pretend to
belong within this organization so you
would issue the correct commands
to say
i am for example mark at
this
company.com
and i want to send this email to
mycontact.thiscompany.com
and then from there you can if the
client then replies by saying yep that's
um i received that email that's fine it
could be used for example fishing or
whaling where you start trying to target
your
more high level up
and high level up people in the company
to obtain a valid credential set which
could be then used
and compare nm in correlation with that
rdp poor that i've hypothetically made
up in my head
to log in and that's it you've then
became for example the id man of the
company
at that point you can do what you want
and again the testing structure and
methodology
for the external infrastructure ailment
is more varied it's
there's not for example an exact thing
you should follow all depends on the
services
that are located during the testing
window
and the third one
you might experience during testing is
what we call an assumed breach
so if any has heard of a soon breach
testing before
no so assume breach testing is
ultimately an assessment of the
organization's internal network it's
similar to an internal test however
we are taking the point on their network
that we have previously discussed the
thumb so the perspective the point or
the perspective could be for example
we've walked into their organization
we've plugged in a laptop what can we
see we can do
so
can we
obtain a password hash using the tools
and can we replay this password hash to
then start in person in this user
or we have we can mimic an account a
current compromise via efficient so we
would use a command and control set a
command and control tool command and
control center to send an email to the
organization and try to trick their end
users into clicking this link which
would then provide the hook back into
our command and control center and we
can start
trying to move laterally or vertically
around their environments to obtain the
main advent
another way we could look at this is
your credentials compromised so they
just provide us credentials so we've
pretended that we could compromise these
credential sets with them they've
provided them we can log in and they
ultimately run
run the exact command that we need to
get the hook back to the commander
control so as you can see there's
various different ways
that we can do this and it all comes
down to client budget again which you
have communicated with and you've
tailored it to
to their requirements
so hope you can see that pentest isn't
just testing it as you may think there's
a lot of communication with the client
prior a lot of communication during and
a lot of communication after
and your assumed breach testing is is
often objective driven so it's not a
case of what can you find it's
an objective driven test so can you get
to the main admin so for example i was
testing an internal organizer an
organization's internal network
they said right can you get to da
so obviously as the tester you obviously
want to
to make sure that you meet their goal
and that is possible so for example an
example i found
in during testing was a client had
multiple network shares visible
within their network shares
there was a member of the iit team who
had their folders accessible to everyone
on the network
within these folders there was a regis
registry key and within the registry key
there was a username password and clear
text for a service account
and there was basically
if i recall correctly there was five or
six of these service accounts each one
incremented by one
and you had with compromising this
registry key you had the password and
username combination for all six users
so
once you've found that when i went
a back to
we use called um
bloodhounds
so basically it's an ingester for sharp
hands whereby it assesses that the
directory in a quick manner you put it
in and it visualizes the
high level
and i basically
create clouds and said i've compromised
this user what is the shortest path to
domain admin from here turned out that
user had
right all access on
and i was able to use the right all
access to make myself the main user that
was it
that's how is it
okay and other types of tests then that
we do uh do now and other types of
testing that are available
are
so you're basically telling you they
aren't just tied into one or two
types of tests and there is a large
volume you can go into and you can
specialize in whatever you want
so the other types of testing that are
available are your mobile applications
your ios and your android application
testing
are you able to find any issues within
that so
i must admit i'm not a master and any of
my master in any of the testing i've
mentioned or this
but you just mentioned other stuff that
are available your source code review so
they prove the client provides you the
source code of the application two thing
vulnerabilities so a source code review
can be
provided alongside a web app test and i
personally would call that a source code
driven pen test so you can use the web
application front end that you have and
you can use the source code that's
provided to kind of tailor the issues
and find them in a faster manner than if
you were
looking at your breakout testing so
if a client uses a citrix environment
which is a lockdown desktop verbs don't
know
uh are you able to
break up this environment to gain a
command prompt and then start trying to
move laterally like the assumed breach
test and i just mentioned
your social engineering testing
so
are you able to break into building can
you use the information provided to gain
physical access can you use public
information to obtain valid credential
sets like your phishing
your wireless assessments just walk in
scan the wireless that's a
web service assessment api your
vulnerability assessments which ties
into your external sort of
infrastructure and
again you just run the vulnerabilities
and your cloud security assessments with
the cloud becoming more
more
more pre
common now
so common tooling that i experience as a
tester
is barb sweet nick told wp so it's just
the less they'll let you read it
relatively loud
and
that says all these tools are worth
worth learning and worth investing in
so that's the end of the talk does
anyone have any questions or anything
yes
so it varies on what the client wants
but typically a web application test
would be five days worth of effort on a
common web application external
infrastructure it varies depending on
the ip addresses and the services that
they have so commonly you're looking at
again like three four days and it's not
a large volume
uh you mentioned the last role is
okay so
i probably should explain that whilst i
was doing it but good question thank you
so your lateral movement is going from
user a to user b
whereas your vehicle these users both
are on the same user role and both part
of the same same ad groups
your vertical movement could be going
from user a to user z and user z being
an admin so you move laterally around
the environment trying to learn
more and more by compromising other
users of the same level
and your vertical is going from user to
admin
[Music]
so typically
presuming you mean taylor made by
interacting with the client so we meet
though every single test would be
tailor-made to a client requirement
whether that be they just want a web
application test or not so you're you do
have the same checks you run but you're
not going to be doing uh
a test without speaking to the client to
understand where their concerns lie does
that answer you
yeah perfect
yeah is um so i'm guessing the most
important part of them all is reporting
yes um
how automated is that
like it looks very repetitive but if
it's very repetitive that means a lot of
things can be reused from report to
report
yeah so
it depends on where you go it could be a
hands-on process or an automated process
what we have is we have this thing
called the knowledge base and the
knowledge base has the basic information
on youtube as you've mentioned written
up already so we would use that from
report to report but within the
vulnerabilities we will add in the exact
specifications of the issues that we
find so it is quite uh a manual process
by the sense of your copying and pasting
it across
but it is already written up for you
there it's just the case of adding in
this the specifics of the vulnerability
so the client can follow what
what's being found
like everyone says don't go into context
[Music]
yeah exactly the report isn't a bad
thing
it's important to learn how to report
though it's not a case of you want to
copy and paste there's a very specific
way you want to present to the client so
you want to present it in a way that
they
they can follow because it's not often
the reports given to a techie
it could just be the reports provided to
execs and they need to be able to follow
at some sort of level and then go do you
know what give it to my t team and they
can follow it so you need to get that
balance between technical and
non-technical rights so everyone can
understand what
is perfect that's fine to answer your
question yeah yeah perfect no worries
uh what proportion of your time would
you say
so
a pop portion you're looking at around
20 of the time is given to reporting so
you want to improperly invest time into
those reports as as you see as i
mentioned it's the deliverable that's
given to the customer and it's what
they're paying for so you want it to be
a good document it's not just giving
straight to them as well i must add it
it goes through a quality assurance
process whereby it has another tester
set of eyes on it as well and they can
be like no this isn't right or yes that
is right
[Music]
so we would try to ask questions to get
the customer to give us the right
information obviously as a tester we
don't know their complete environment we
can only try to get the information from
them
ultimately it's about knowing how to ask
the customer a question and get the
correct
information from them and provide it to
you and then you can then off the back
of what they've told you or often after
you ask a question you ask the question
to them they come back with some
information and then that allows you to
then start filling in the gaps that
they've told you and ask them more off
the back of it so
your question asked how often does it
can be given it varies because it just
depends on what the customer tells you
yes
when you're doing free testing to the
client yes you're introducing to it
that tester has to pay on to someone
else yes does that mean that you have
testers you're specifically there to
introduce the client to the test
beforehand or if does everyone sort of
take a better process
so
the process can be taken by one person
all the way along or it can just
typically the process is taken all the
way along by one person it's not often
once you've spoke to a client it's been
passed off to someone else because
they're used to your face and then
you've kind of created this rapport with
them and they start getting to recognize
what you're you're saying design so yeah
i said i hadn't
i think it's inevitable as you test
you're going to knock stuff over it's
how you communicate with the client that
has been knocked over as an important
part you don't want to hide it from them
you want to go back and say i knocked
over between this period and this period
i thought i was doing this could you
check your logs to do this again it's
just engaging with them and making sure
that they know that you've knocked over
so they don't go back to the logs in
like
10 weeks time and
and say the same is over
[Music]
so
if it was a five-day engagement we would
work solely on that test for five days
it wouldn't be juggling between things
uh at least that's how we work at quorum
cyber is if you're on engagement for
five days you're on that engagement for
five days and your sole focus is
[Music]
sorry i'm still going to hear you
no so that's a perfectly fine so i just
get the microphone over here the person
was asking if i do a pen test and
nothing's found is that a bad thing so
no it's not a bad thing it just showed
demonstrates that they have a mature
approach to security and
they are in the exact place where they
think they should be
it's not often that does happen however
it can
happen by any chance
so we're all humans everyone everyone
does make mistakes it's how you remove
how you go about resolving the mistakes
and i think
customers is very rare we do miss stuff
but as i'm saying we are humans and it
can happen
perfect
i think that's all the questions
so thank you all for coming and thank
you for the hacksaw for organizing
security