so I try to keep this short in this 200
slides really quick about my
that's me many years ago i've done pen
testing red teaming wargaming i have a
different industry than some people I've
worked in retail or working in retail
and finance I have also worked in local
government but in addition I spent 17
years in the United States military I
started a computer as many years ago on
stuff like this and then somehow ended
up doing stuff like this if you don't
know what a corpsman is especially
marine corpsman they're pretty much
double docs they look kind of funny and
they stand out but you tell them you
tell marina de about their dog so when
the peacetime was around when there
wasn't bad things I played games like
this played with nuclear biological
chemical warfare hot days and prepared
for disasters like this good good good
you all wanna know really what this is
about talking about four games and one
of the things that always happens either
the military local government or
anything else if you're not talking the
same speak how do you know if you're
still talking to same stuff we could go
out there and talk to linux people and
then you have a Microsoft person to
spend more time trying to figure out
just the commonalities and the
differences than anything else so it was
we dive into that we'll talk about what
a red team is and you want to hire one
again back to that level setting we've
got vulnerability scanning we've got pen
testing we've got red teaming right here
is probably where some people get a
little heart there hurts feel it
feelings but I wanted to define this for
this conversation as well as the people
we work with I heard mojo talk about how
many people know about pen testing it's
not a common thing so we're going to
break this down we'll talk a little
about their skill sets and their
advantages not saying any of this is not
valuable but they have their place
vulnerability scanning is usually
general to specialize depending on what
you're going back for mediating
troubleshooting that understanding its
automated you can go it across the
enterprise it's fast but it's usually
around an application or some type of
software it's not going to do all the
other things and its signature dependent
just like antivirus it's what's been
defined there's an 0 0 day we get a
little bit deeper into the thing we've
got pen test
can be general can also go into
specialized areas there are some people
in here that have skill sets that I will
not even touch I will never say I'm an
expert in anything it's crossbred it's
got an automation it's got manual
testing it does do physical and human as
we've already talked about social
engineer but it's always that cause the
end result is really around information
security it's slow and low the
challenges is the scoping a lot of times
they want this done in one or two weeks
you have to learn environment turn back
around and explain it to someone in two
weeks very hard to do and there are many
well defined industries out there have
done this if you're looking for if you
haven't done any of this i definitely
look up some of these it's defined
doesn't mean it's in a box just means
it's defined then we get into red
teaming red team is a total different
animal this comes actually from the
military comes back more from the Cold
War red versus blue and actually having
that fight this is where they bring in
everything this is that full a team this
is orchestrated this is not just one one
team this could be a multiple aspect
ronik ethnicity I'll use that word so
someone can drink cyber side as well as
physical they do human engagement to
mimic that they also do opt for which is
operational form immense
these or other military forces and they
act like in Iraqi or Russia or whatever
but this is everything social
engineering and what you're going to
touch making sure that when you get
broken into and all your stuff stolen
you're already prepared but we also find
haystacks we find those needles but we
also find those huge areas make excess
of center of gravity that will take down
that one application that's been sitting
in the back end no one's paying
attention to because you know what it's
running it's an old mainframe you take
it down guess what you can't do your
business we also find those elephants
one other thing I'll talk about the
shortly there's a little side off of it
depending on where you come from
vulnerability scanning is what
penetration testing is what red teaming
is question is are you ready or are you
not I can't tell you that I'm not going
to tell you exactly what a red team is
to to make it to find it's going to be
what you need however you need to know
thyself not really just anything else
you need to know exactly what your
business does if you have no idea what
your business does you're already
failing you also need to know where
everything is as well as where your
controls are and have them deployed and
yes we've all seen this horrible thing
and we all know at cissp and it's chuck
norris approved as well but there's
other things other aspects that are
technologically induced that fit into
this which movement be information
security be business security if anyone
in here in a financial industry I'm not
going to ask this is what you're held to
this is basil this is what the
stakeholders and those high-level CEOs
are held to to make sure that they're
able to run their business this is what
the federal holds if you look at this
and dig large enough we could just take
the stock market the stock market's run
a lot by by using network time that time
base if it goes off just by seconds
changes the chance for someone to get
bids that can change an industry you can
change the world then you have an
understanding of fully how to deal with
all these pieces because if you brick we
come in we tell you you're all broken
and you don't do anything with it we've
wasted our time and we don't know what
your ruler is it's going to be dependent
on you and you have to have that risk
but I don't know what your risk is does
anyone think this is risky what about
this what about this guy here looks
really scared over here but he's got a
rope versus this guy or if you're really
daring who would want to do that I don't
know what your risk is I can tell you
one thing my background in life and limb
was totally different in time of war the
minimum the green was the people I would
worry about first I try to get people
back in there to fight in civilian world
it would be the immediate the Waldos in
black well unfortunately there was only
so much time we had this could be your
other risk just people throwing money or
for this gentleman who's in a lawn chair
flying over Iraq is that your risk I
don't know but before the war before we
come and tear you apart and you're not
ready and make a sad you have to be
ready the other thing I want to talk
about is you can all see a little bit
older I've been doing this for about 20
years I grow up in this time frame where
this was the cool technology nowadays we
can spend all day about to do this and
look like this all day I wonder what
sound he's making that's all I want to
know and as technology moves forward who
knows what's going to happen I don't
know if anyone's noted this but I'm also
kind of another side of geek it's kind
of cool so let's talk about a red team
person they're a little insane because
they also they have to know a lot of
things they have to know what your
business is they have to know the
technology which and the the adversary
in itself we'll talk a little bit about
the adversary part you need to know what
is that what's that motorists operandi
what exactly why they doing it what's
the cause it's that why this person's no
reason
is different from these reasons taking
it a little bit of psychology this is
Maslow's law it will not go across the
whole world but it does straight a thing
that here at the very bottom you have to
worry about your survival if you're in a
survival situation you're not going to
be worried about how pretty you look
you're going to be worried about getting
that food in those things as well as you
move up to this there are certain
triggers but as a human that you have to
do also back from the Cold War there was
a way to try to turn spies what they
used is they tried to figure out what
were those triggers and they put that as
mice so if you look down some of these
crimes it could be a combination of
these but if you look at it you have the
money you have that necessity back to
that survival what did you need to do
why did you rob that bank or why did you
rob that liquor store because of
whatever that causes the green could be
it it could be you decide to do criminal
college causes because you want to be
rich as well as vices it could be that
you have something you're trying to cope
with that you need that money same thing
in patriotic in the ideology this is
that want that feeling that that that
call to action we've got Patriots in
which we've seen enough on the CNN and
from either the uniform side or
religious cultures as well as we got
Julian Assange and the list goes on from
there and with the whistle blowing and
then we get into cohesion and when you
start talking about corrosion and
blackmail and particularly having an
inside red team that gets really scary
when you start talking about the
possibility someone coming and
kidnapping your kids in those areas it's
a hard conversation to have but it's
real and it's been going on forever ego
as well same thing it could be anything
from curiosity Morris worm how many
people are familiar with the Morris worm
okay 1986 the computer buter computer
abuse act was because of that Morris
worm was basically a curiosity to test
out this this worm that took down half
the internet at the time and you can map
those to those people what you're doing
is you're now getting an understanding
of why what exactly they're doing this
not just someone say I do the scope I
want to see if thumbs vulnerable what is
their intent did you piss them off on
the outside or is there something that
you're doing that they have that its
value then you take us a little bit
deeper you start looking at it and we'll
start at the top here we look at the
holistic time frame
to do a cross-site scripting may take
seconds but how long did it take you to
find that how long did it take you to
validate that to come up and craft that
whatever that exploit is that's a simple
one what if you want to do something
more of a Jack Bauer it takes that time
period to do that as well as is it
repeatable then you start getting into
finances and resources how much money
you have is there a particular element
or whatever is required to do that
attack that is not local in your area
you have to go procure that or someone
has to build it that takes that time
your skill sets you have to do a gap
analysis of yourself where you at now
what do you need to learn as well as
partnerships collaborations and levers
it goes back to that that partners if
you have more people joined into it it's
easier then you look at how they're now
they're actually doing it if you're
going to do China look at what their
paths are what are their what's their
regular pass to use their tools they use
then there's always the great debate
between the the pirates and a ninja but
really what it illustrates is do you
want to keep that money or do you want
to go to jail do you want to be covert
or overt and then how many adversaries
do you want once you figure that out
it's very dynamic so what you do is you
spend most of the time trying to figure
out what you've learned what's your
rules of engagement what you've seen
from oceans or what you've engaged from
what you've learned and you keep making
this decision over and over again it's
not simple it just keeps going and going
in addition every test you do you rinse
and repeat you do this scientific
methodology over and over that's just
the adversary side then we get to the
business we need to know what you do
what are your drivers what is key to
survival for you because that's the keys
of the kingdom we also need to what's
important what's the most important
what's least without having that we
could be hey here's a vulnerability or
here's exactly what we found as an
exploit it means nothing to them you
waste your time you also need to know
what's good or bad and their worst case
scenario what keeps them up at night
so now we talked a lot about it and some
of the things of if you're going to hire
here are some keys that you should you
want to do either if it's an external or
internal one you make sure that they
have clear objectives they know what
their scope is or not first of all it's
also very it can be very perceptive if
you do something you think you have the
right get-out-of-jail-free card and it's
interpreted the wrong way you could be
sitting in court so there's part of that
being played you also need to focus on
quality not quantity this isn't
something you just spit them out that's
what the scanning czar for pen testing
can be done as well depending on how
flexible you make it you need to accept
that challenge into criticism you need
to learn lauren and lower you also need
to synergize and partner having that
that report sitting somewhere is not
going to do anything you have to figure
out how to collaborate how to educate
and change that culture and then be
loyal to that red team having a lot of
sport for that red team will give you a
lot of value and have and give you some
intense stuff and for those fellow red
teamers right tool right skill right job
pay attention to detail remain humble
remain loyal that's key you have few if
you build a red team and they're not
ethical you're going to have a larger
risk you've induced the risk plan
rehearse rehearse synergize and then
give back to the community the other
thing I want to talk about is there are
number people talking about from the
artist perspective red and blue makes
the color purple it does but if you use
a term from the military it goes
actually back to this is the NSA and we
can use that word if you want or not but
this is really there OPSEC this is
operational security and this is
actually core to a lot of the criminals
who do get caught because they don't
look at certain things as I understand
it and I'm not an expert on the Silk
Road but he was caught because his
instant messenger closed while he was in
a store they could tell that that was
the person who closed this laptop
because he logged off and that was his
catch he didn't know who was around them
he didn't make sure he covered his
tracks that i think is it but i do think
the synergy is put important as well as
you've got to find that balance if you
tell too many secrets outside or you're
talking your friend and saying here's
the vulnerabilities who else is
listening and then you have a sad red
team does they I want to talk about is
semper Gumby it's once you have this
plan and all
changes so now going back to the war
games perspective we talked about this a
little bit does anyone want to play a
game because you all seem kind of tired
I've got the lucky of trying to wake you
back up and I hope this will illustrate
why red team is important but the first
thing I will say is I'm not going to say
who or what or bastardize anyone on this
this is an impact of it but right now
this particular story has so many
political stories I'm not diving into it
and everything I gathered here is only
from Intel that was on the line I don't
have any other information so today is
November 24th it's Thanksgiving time
period for all frickin happy come on be
happy and won't wake up people you're
thinking about your turkey or if you're
vegetarian your tofu turkey so you're
standing around you getting ready you're
thinking about leaving and you hear from
this reporter there's some information
about your company online well this
turkey that you are dreaming about has
now turned to this and now you're
feeling like this so the first thing you
do is start working really hard to try
to figure out what exactly it is damage
control well and this is a great
conference for the conference for this
all your windows devices decide to lock
up on this and you just stare and do
this what do you do go to help desk well
they get to work
while you're stressed and you have
nothing else to do you go and decide
let's go hang out at the water cooler
because you know what if she is broken
can't do anything then you hear about
this you start feeling like this and you
wish you would have did this two days
have gone past you're starting to find
out some information that's out there
does anyone tell me this is good or bad
just feel good you feeling like this
then and this is me this is this is
where we start shifting outside of
technological you spent how much money
on making these movies some of these
movies have not even been released yet
some of these are targeted for August to
fit august of this year guess what to
free free I tell you so you spend all
that money and you're worried about your
budget you're not getting that back and
your boss is usually like this you've
got to work through Thanksgivings more
like this and you want to do this
continues start finding more information
it's getting worse this is not even
within your business now you're
cascading outside of your business now
you're affecting other people and
they're like this in addition all your
social media is getting compromised by
this time this is what you're really
feeling like continues the Calvary runs
in and you receive this email and let's
save you guys a time to read through
these because this is important started
talking about terabytes into information
really right what's the biggest thing
and it says GOP d and this is important
in this case more data is going out yay
this is what you're seeing ask your
finance officers what they'll think
about that ask regulatory is what
they're going to feel about that yes
continues and a DAT to add salt to
injury here's your global security
guidelines of exactly what to do and all
the people who've took training and
their addresses and their passwords
again you're starting to feel more and
more like this and then screenshots like
this go up online again what you can do
pretty much with your network is this
now wait you start getting more emails
and this is why I think it changed if
you look this is all sony but right here
they started going after something that
changed they went after your family and
when you do that you play with hearts
and minds we all have certain things we
were we talked about earlier we had a
conversation about social engineering
and the emotions but when you feel like
this what does your team do there's
nothing else you can do in addition for
those hackers out there who or those who
like to keep their privacy their network
which takes a lot of work for them to go
through hotels to avoid paparazzi and
all fanboys have all been destroyed
because it was there do you think they
want to work with them what about their
employees here's copies of it with their
signatures going back to more cascading
ideals here's the here's their contracts
that were cascaded out of it pretty much
everybody else is pissed off at you as
well this is only a few days in
continuing on still GOP d they're
talking about the FBI they start to get
a little brazen those areas to give you
a second to read through that but
there's still about more of so many
employees besides that one of the family
and they started talking about terrorism
so it's starting to escalate this to me
kind of throw a wrench in a question
these people showed up and they wanted
something totally different now for me
and you could just take movies or what
any other story you
why would you change your motive halfway
through and why would you add complexity
of this going on and I'm not going to
discuss these people which was a
different attack and if it was
coordinated would make it even more
interesting but this was occurring at
the same time continuing down the streak
Laura comes in they get a Christmas gift
or potential christmas gift it never
actually came and then again getting
more into the hearts and minds as you
read through this the world of fear
starting to call out 911 as well as
saying if you live near these houses you
should move this isn't a normal thing
nor am i saying everybody's this is this
isn't the fear uncertainty and doubt
this is just really what happened this
is a good war game story if you were
going to tell a story to your CEO or
financial officer there are impact their
impacts in here that they can see so
what did that happen well all their
contractors all the people to push out
your product said you know what hell no
hell no what did that force your
business to do this they had to figure
out a new way to push everything they've
done and they had to stop because of
life and limb injury which is weird
because I don't think I've ever would
have said life and limb and Technology
together but this builds into at least
that impact that threshold so there's
tons of Sony impacts I'll talk about a
few of them just to give you an idea
this is called attrition warfare this is
basically stopping someone from being
able to work this is basic sunzu type
stuff and I don't know if you can read
that but that's how many servers three
thousand computers and 800 servers is
that a good day in addition while the
ax-cut well the attacks were still
occurring there sony employees were
suing them fast forward a few more you a
few months you know what's still coming
now we're starting to talk into the
cascading effects and indirect effects
that most people have a challenge to
talk about because it's hard to say
we've tried the stock options and or
stock and set all the stock is going to
go down once in a while it does but it's
not really a good metric but the legal
fines and a simple fact that one that
all these are still sitting out there
now continuing I I know you can find
Seth Rogen's email I mean but has he
changed it how many other people that
are not so many employees have changed
there's one of their information is out
there what other attacks that have
occurred so if we do the adult friend
finder is there Sony attack people in
there could you use that to blackmail
someone at a later date I don't know in
addition it's also started to hit gender
and right now in day and age of female
equality and as equality is everything
else this is impactful this will weigh
or sway your money makers your big-time
people in addition so much I have I live
with my wife and my 17 year old daughter
they read more of this it wouldn't
influence me but I'm sure someone reads
this magazine and this makes their
decisions of how they look at the world
what about all those people watching
soap operas it's just ironic this year
happened to be there 50 year anniversary
spend all that time advertising and
doing this for a number of years and
potentially could had that cancel change
your customers the people you care about
and unfortunately this lady here the
whole most worst picture they could ever
find ever and I feel really bad for her
at this time I can't condone what she
did if you haven't heard about this she
sent a nice little email to a friend
about this person which is really bad
but look where she SAT before this
incident this is Forbes she was one of
the 100 most powerful women she's been
dropped ask your CEO if they wanted to
be on Forbes I bet they'd care this
person here total different incident but
he feels horrible to this actually
happened to be a CEO who his company
happen to have some type of foodborne
pathogen this is him in court not sure
why this person still there that's a
whole other thing of male and female and
I'm not here to say whether you believe
Sony
real or not it is a Black Swan event i
will guarantee and if you don't know
what a Black Swan it's that one off it's
the rarity it's like a 911 it could
happen when it happens it's really bad
but what if one of these attacks what if
just the malware occurred or your doc
seen this is coordinated that's what I
think also makes us more interesting is
it wasn't just one attack vector it was
coordinated to add to the complexity
this was only a few months ago this was
on 60 minutes this is the old view of
what a cyber hacker was as well as this
and this God actually this is more the
truth and there's another interesting
factor in psychology so basically what
this is is this represents what's called
the hundredth monkey in Japan there
happen to be a bunch of scientists who
are working with these particular
species of monkeys and they would feed
them sweet potatoes they look they
learned that the older monkeys would
just eat the potatoes with the sand on
it but a few younger ones would actually
wash it off they watch this culture for
a while and a document what happened is
they learned that as they started to
grow up into the numbers up to a hundred
monkeys more people start to accept it
what they hit that pinnacle point that
tipping point not only did they change
here they changed across the other
islands without interaction which was
interesting so if you put a hundred
bunkies a bunch of monkeys together
eventually you'll get some kind of
intelligent design so what it's
illustrating is once people learn how to
do stuff will go back to will use
skating Tony Hawk has set set mines and
it set the perspective of Mines for
people to do amazing things when I
started skateboarding it was just flake
flat board and that was it it just
changed your mind once you see something
happen to changes it but the other thing
that's also added to it is tools are
getting easier anyone know what this is
I do not know what this is if you don't
this was part of the anonymous movement
what this basically gate is gave
everybody including your grandmother's
the ability to do a denial of service
yeah
and we can use that point but I bet when
most Linux people started here youtube
and google was not the most easiest way
to learn how to do things now it's easy
but that's very good point I didn't get
into that deep part but the ease of use
is there is what I'm illustrated well
also illustrating is original if you
went back the cost for this ransomware
was up now it's free now it's free which
makes it a little hard again three
anyone get internet but thank you for
the information so the question is
really going back to what would you do I
don't know you now understand the
differences between vulnerability
scanning pen testing and red teaming you
can take this term if you want or not
all I can tell you when you're trying to
explain this to people it's already
convoluted you add more to it not get
clarity it makes your job even more
challenging and this job is very much
partnerships so when you hire the man to
do the full rampage and destroy
everything remember it's going to hurt
but it's the lesson you get out of that
that you that you receive and the
collaboration you put together across
these attacks with this different view
and a holistic thing that will save you
from being this this is a lot faster
than I thought for 200 slides but get
out there or if you're a business person
get out there there's a number of great
sites on there on red team in itself
some of them come from the physical size
exclusively some come from the
electronic side some bring the human you
need to have that holistic view be
completely flexible and thank you thank
you also for b-sides and for sale for
having you here