so did this work everyone hear me okay
do i need this No okay great well need
for my my presentations got some audio
in it so we'll try that alright thanks I
am surfer Dave we have a group called
Charlotte hackers anonymous I thought I
just plugged that real quick it's kind
of our new group we get together on
Saturdays and hack and drink and stuff
like that so anyone that's interested
you're welcome to come we have actually
a little table out there that's horribly
staffed and no swag because we're we
don't have any money so so anyway social
engineering is something that I do for
work and I'm not going to say that I
don't not a social engineer the idea
behind it those is a misnomer is for in
my opinion so that this talk came about
before Carolina con the CFP was closing
and there wasn't enough speaker so one
night after working with a very
prominent social engineer in the
technology field I had a few Bourbons
because I was a little upset about
things and came up with this talk and
then forgot what I came up with and
actually had to email them back after
they accepted so this kind of forced me
to get out of my comfort zone and do
some research that I've been wanting to
do so the standard disclaimer is these
are my views and opinions obviously i do
work as a red team ER for a large
international bank in the charlotte area
so obviously those are not their
opinions they're mine and much like the
title of this talk citations are needed
but i do provide a slide deck at the end
or slide at the end with some of the
books that i use for reference so just
warning you now so this talk might
contain some of the following things it
might have triggers like this is a
trigger this is the
humuhumunukunukuapua'a it's the Hawaiian
state triggerfish there might be kittens
there might be Chuck Norris there you
know the usual stuff that ends up in
security talks a lot of times
and of course at and most besides
there's alcohol involved at some point
of the day so if you hear anyone mention
anything about advanced persistent
threats or any of the thing with a
c-word or someone telling you that as
hackers the world is going to end if we
don't protect it no it's not the world
went on for eons before hackers showed
up on the planet so anyone talking about
fear uncertainty and doubt really take a
drink or make them take a drink actually
so a little bit about me I thought who
introduced me but me at 14 years old
we're going to see if this audio works
because we're kind of I'll so I'll have
to hold up to the microphone that's
water guys though
you guys hear that we're recording
alright so we were actually building
things from the Anarchist Cookbook in
the basement and thought it was smart to
put it on video a 9 site the internet
didn't work that back then now it's on
the internet so FBI please just remember
that was when I was 14 sacchi
limitations has run out so let's get
let's get started let's let's kick this
off let's talk understand a little bit
more about why I kind of want a rail on
social engineering so what's social
engineering social engineer all right so
basically I the way we use social
engineering in the media and as people
and we're not the only ones that use
social engineering and everyday speech
its kind of like polar vortex was a
thing I really would like us to move
away from it so we're going to go
through a few things we're going to
define what social engineering is we're
going to look at really what it is some
history behind it and then some
techniques that work from a sociology
perspective now this isn't a technical
talk i'm going to be dropping zero days
and things like that but this is more
about the human element involved in
information security and just being
humans and really how we relate to each
other
so let's break it down let's talk about
with what the word social and engineer
mean so social is an adjective it
describes somebody means it's relating
to it activity spending time with each
other doing enjoyable things together so
they lock Phil guys are out there right
now we get together quite I'm not
completed with those guys we get
together once a month at a bar and pick
locks and drink beers and things like
that same thing we do with Charlotte
hackers anonymous same thing we're doing
right here right now something we do
together it's a social gathering we
would like to be with and talk to people
now this one's for us as a group at
least for me and some of my friends
relating to people or society in general
doesn't really work I don't know about
you but as the big guy in school I was
picked on because I was one playing D&D
at the lunch table instead of like
hanging out with the jocks and stuff
like that but so sometimes we don't
necessarily relate to being social
butterflies now an engineer is a person
who has scientific training who builds
all these awesome things that's brought
us in the 21st century now this is a
female engineer she's working on a power
plant and by far this is the hardest
picture to find on the internet ever
because the internet doesn't think that
engineers can be women or if they are
they have to be in like some kind of
skimpy costume but she definitely you
know it can be either gender it's also a
definition of a person who is in charge
of a ship or airplane or so these guys
or a guy that runs a train like that guy
an engineering as a whole is the
professional art of applying these
things these knowledge is it's at the
bottom there it says a special knowledge
is associated preparation for
professional practice involves extensive
training and application of that
knowledge now do we think that the word
social and engineer really work here I
think not personally engineer kind of
like a my title at work I have engineer
in
title but I don't have a degree in
engineering I don't even have a degree
so why am I called an engineer these
people went to school for years and
years and years but yet they're called
engineers social engineers so I think we
really need to break it down and call it
what it is we're not social engineers we
are manipulators and we're we use
manipulation and deception to help
protect our environments so how do we do
this in information security well we use
fishing to test people's response to
possible phishing attacks that are very
real threat on the internet phone calls
also known as fishing we're calling up
and trying to solicit information
password social security numbers and so
forth dumpster diving you're looking for
information about businesses and people
to use that information to leverage
against them daxing where we find
information that is available on people
to use against them and then open source
intelligence and this slides kind of
small I apologize but this is a tool
called multi go mal t go will pull
information from multiple different
sources on the internet to find out more
about people and you'd be surprised what
people put out there that leads to
making using for manipulation so if
you're on Facebook and Twitter and all
these different things if it's on the
internet it never dies so just keep that
in mind and and using tools like this
make it very easy to plan targeted
attacks against people through
manipulation okay let's switch gears now
and talk about the history of
manipulation and deception why these
things work why is it possible why as
humans do we allow ourselves to get
deceived and manipulated well the first
story arguably the first recorded story
during creation in the Bible was the
first thing that happened involving
humans was deception so just to recap
that story real quick God is puts Adam
and Eve in a garden of eden and he said
they cannot heat this from fruit of this
tree they can eat for everything else
Satan he's checking this thing out and
he's like wait they serve him I want
some of this attention i'm going to go
down and heat and then satan turn
himself into snake he deceived Eve and
the interesting thing is that Eve
actually went and took it back and use
deception on Adam Adam never saw the
snake never talked to him so that
deception was actually passed down so
arguably that's the first written
history of deception in ancient times
false waits was a big problem still to
this day it happens but people in
marketplaces would think that we bind
like a unit of grain it might be
actually half of unit because the
weights would be falsified so they
actually in Roman times enacted tax
collectors to go and check the weights
that people are using not to defraud the
people we still do this today if you go
to a gas pump you'll see a sticker on
the gas pump that says it at this
certain date somebody checked to make
sure that the measurement of gas from
this gas pump is accurate and it still
happens today in other countries yes you
will get deceived out of gas just FYI
and from experience clothing makeup and
smells the things that we hardly think
of as being deceptive but archaeological
evidence shows about 70,000 years ago
our ancestors started adorning their
bodies with ochre a reddish powder that
purposely was used to manipulate men
into thinking they were ovulating and
obviously procreation is a big thing
otherwise the humans would die off so
this this thing these techniques were
used ancient Egyptian women would use
different pace and things to make their
eyes big they would use paint to color
their lips and Greek and Roman ladies
would die their heads their hair blond
they use makeup and lighten their skin
and remove unwanted body hair sounds
familiar it happened back then it's
still happening now
nothing wrong with it it's just
something that's happened it started off
as something to continue the
appropriated process of the human race
so that deception all these things are
ingrained in us so as kids were told at
a young age and and this is to me when I
read this in during my research is
really at home for me they were house
supposed to be polite we'll just have a
manner not supposed to point out to
somebody if they are acting rudely or
inappropriately like this guy here you
probably just crossed the hall I'll
never say anything to him because he's
acting out of not normally for people in
society so we're taught to do these
things but what are we doing we're
actually not telling the truth we're
thinking ourselves that's disgusting
what's wrong with that guy must be like
from some you know backwater town he's
never known these things but we're
really teaching art we were taught to be
polite the politeness is actually a type
of perception because they're not
speaking our truth speaking away we
think
now the origins of Santa Claus and
Easter and the Easter Bunny and those
types of things our deception and we
continue to propagate to our children so
Santa Claus actually came from Germanic
people the this is a picture of the
Norse god Odin and at ye olde Tom Odin
leads a great hunting party through the
sky celebrations so this kind of leads
to comparisons with Santa is reindeer
there's actually there's other HD ities
and rode across the sky and chariots
drawn by goats and gave presents to
children at the end of the year and
that's kind of fed into that legend as
well this is Easter OST or stara is a
dramatic timidity that was the one of
radiant dawn the uprising of light and
it's that's why Easter happens around
the same time every year it's the spring
equinox and this was celebrated every
year in her honor the Easter Bunny and
rabbits and chickens and things like
that these things reproduce really
quickly you have these animals as a sign
of procreation as a celebration of
fertility so all of these customs and
things like that don't have origins and
Christianity they don't have origins in
the Bible they are they were woven in to
help make the people more likely to not
rebel against the government's that
we're taking away those pagan traditions
okay we're going to look at some of the
techniques that that really work when it
comes to manipulation and deception and
and how because as humans we follow
these techniques in our day-to-day life
so this an awareness of them really good
help help us identify them and also use
them for for testing our own
environments so the rule of reciprocity
or ruler reciprocation it's basically
the Golden Rule do unto others as you
would have them do unto you now the Hare
Krishnas found an excellent way to
exploit this the hairy Christmas would
be worship being in public and they
would walk up to a person and they just
hand that person to flower and to stand
back and obviously with someone hands
you something for free you don't
understand why they say well I don't
want this flowering the Hare Krishnas no
that's yours it's a gift from the hairy
Krishna but if you'd like to make a
small donation to our cause we'd be
willing to take it so the rule of
reciprocity and what we're used to doing
you don't receive free you know it's
usually reciprocating so someone gives
you something you give them something in
return so those worked really well for
many many years from the seventies into
the 80s now a days most of our sinaa
chol about doing things like that we've
heard about these types of things and
how they work so it's not as effective
as it was previously but the next
example it's still and this is a legit
reason why the rule of reciprocation
works so I was in New Orleans for
conference one time went to Jackson
Square is watching these guys doing some
breakdance because I like that kind of
stuff but this any kind of street
performers I notice the way that they
were getting donations for what they
were doing they actually had one guy
that had the money but another guy in
the crew right next to him would be the
first one it would dropped by five or
six one-dollar bills into the bucket now
everyone sees that and they walk around
one is donating so you know we saw
something cool in that that's perfectly
fine because I enjoyed their performance
give them a couple bucks I want them to
keep doing it so that that is actually
reciprocation that works correctly now
this example when I was doing my
research I came across i recalled
something that I used to do when I lived
in New York I used to take people when
they come to visit all around town New
York we'd go on the subway but we take
them all over the place there's this
olive bar up in the upper west side and
a cool thing about this olive bar and in
New York City it's unheard of is you
could have as many olives as you wanted
while you're in the store like 50
different types of Olives as much as you
want it there's no one standing around
watching years no one like Costco
hovering around giving you free samples
so we would you know spend some time in
there but inevitably every single person
that took up there nine out of ten times
they would buy olives and these are
people that flew in or staying at a
hotel and no refrigeration and we're
taking the subway and walking all over
the city why would these stupid olives I
don't know how I says I don't know why I
didn't think of it before but they the
rule of reciprocation says that you know
they went in there next sample these
olives it's not because the olives are
super good it's because they were
pressured into doing anything they
thought well you know subconsciously hey
I i bought some of these all right i
sampled some of these olives might as
well buy some so it worked really well
in that case and the next story can't
tell this I might just skip because it's
if you want to hear this story about Las
Vegas come talk to you later I don't
want to offend anybody if there are here
that in this story actually one of them
is in the story in larkfield okay anyway
we'll just bypass that for now it's a
good story I just don't want to always
look at that another technique that
works is commitment and consistency
racetrack betters when they go to the
racetrack they look at the the track
record the odds of the horse and they're
not you know usually not to decided when
they go in there as to who they're going
to pin once they pick that horse and put
that money down on that horse now they
stand by that horse you see people
cheering they're cheering for that horse
that they put the money on but why
because they committed to that course
and if they started cheering for another
horse or booing the horse that they
already picked their up staying
consistent that commitment another way
to illustrate you straight this is that
of abuse spouses I wanted I don't want
to downplay this isn't a joke this is an
actual service message from Australia so
it doesn't matter what gender there's
abuse on each side I'll give you example
of commitment and consistency here you
have men and woman they're living
together the man's an alcoholic drunk he
doesn't do much he's not interested in
getting married the woman wants him to
stop drinking and they want to eat what
she wants to get married but what
happens things keep going on he doesn't
want to change she wants some change she
finally says I'm done with this I'm out
of here so she leaves she finds someone
else falls in love with that person they
get engaged because it's what you really
want
to do what happens the first guy first
guys says well he comes up to ghost
ghost to her and says you know what I've
changed I went to rehab I stopped
drinking I bought a ring we can get
engaged and married you know in six
months if you come back to me ultimately
she really wanted to be with this guy so
what does she do she breaks off the
relationship with him with her through
fee on current feelings that goes back
to live with this guy this is all
theoretical this is all this story that
was in one of the books about commitment
and consistency I don't want to use real
life examples when talking about this
but so she goes back to him and what
happens after a few weeks he starts
drinking again she mentions when are we
gonna get married well I don't know I
kind of changed my mind on that what
happens now she is even more committed
to him than she was before because she
was getting married to another person
and she had to defend herself she had to
tell her family hey I'm with this guy
I'll never this guy was an [ __ ] I'm
not gonna go back and Jim ever well now
she's convinced people that he's not
that bad and I'm going back but she's
now she's committed to him to him again
now she has to stay consistent to that
commitment so it's kind of reinforced
that commitment and she has to defend
the way that she thought
another way commitment commitment and
consistency works us during Christmas
time during the Christmas the toy
companies were saying well we queue for
us is amazing we're selling all these
toys are selling all this stuff he one
comes around and nobody's buying toys so
how do we fix this problem well if
you've ever gone through the console
wars in the 80s nintendo and sega and
all those things you know that trying to
get one of those things around christmas
time was damn near possible but as soon
as the first quarter roll around you can
get one why did why is that toy comely
figured out that if they push the
product really hard all the kids would
want that product and so the parent says
the kids like yes dad this is all i want
for christmas I don't care about
anything else that says of course some
that's only thing I promise I'll get
that for you what happens that present
is not available for him to get so he
buys a whole bunch of other stuff for
the kid just say as a nice Christmas
comes around next year but he's promised
that he was going to get this thing now
he goes back to the store spending the
exact same amount of money he already
spent to buy what the kid really wanted
because we have to be consistent in
training our children right otherwise
you know they don't have that that up
bring that we didn't grain with since
human time so parents want to show
children consistency and the toy
companies have taken advantage of that
as well so now we're going to move on to
NLP and I've already talked to somebody
today and they said LLP is a bunch of
crap but that's fine everything it's a
way of identifying certain things at
least in that I've been able to identify
certain things to get inside someone's
head and the whole idea that I use it
for is to actually gain rapport with the
person so we're going to go through a
few few neuro-linguistic programming
techniques you'll see this a lot in
movie shows and things like that but
things that you can pick up on about a
person that really can kind of aid in
your understanding more about who they
are and how they're feeling at that time
so pacing and matching is the first one
is similar method acting and Johnny Depp
says here that if you don't if you're
part part if you're acting if you don't
put some of yourself in that acting that
character it's not acting it's just
lying so that's true you're trying to
match your you're trying to match
another person's body language basically
in their speech in order to build a poor
it rapport is the most important part of
Norland Wisty programming because once
we gain that once we close that gap and
able to talk to somebody then we're
better able to manipulate them or find
out information about them so this
method actor you can see by the
different expressions on his face you
can discern a lot about what he might be
feeling at that time if you saw a real
person with those expressions you
naturally you can have to see when
someone's upset or someone's happy or
someone's
drunk or whatever so you can tell a lot
about a person by their fingers so
pacing and matching is not mirroring
itself it's integrating parts of their
personality into yourself so this girl
here you can tell when speaking with her
you can tell by her parents somewhat but
you could tell when speaking with her
that she's probably from the country she
probably won't understand a lot of big
fancy words they come from like New York
City or things like that she might not
be able to relate to those things
whereas this person doesn't speak any
kind of language that makes any sense at
all so speaking to her speaking of her
you'd have to bring yourself in line as
well and use vocabulary that she would
not find it inappropriate to hurt the
way said she speaks however that is yeah
we'll just leave that alone mirroring is
another NLP technique there's three
different types of mirroring behavioral
mirroring it mirrors things that I have
a symbolic meaning and just an example
of this a lot of men might not realize
this but when we speak to women our
pitch goes up a little bit because we're
matching that person's tone and makes it
a little bit more disarming we do that
naturally a lot of men do because it is
something that we've learned as an
instinct to keep the human race going to
match somebody else to make them more
comfortable symbolic mirroring there's
there's a couple different ways the
symbolic narrowing works one's wardrobe
i lived in austin texas and i work for
the local governments association there
so as all the old commissioners judges
all these guys from all these very rural
counties and then all were Stetson hats
and boots and wrangler jeans and things
like that I walk in like this how do you
think I get received not as well as
another person from Texas so I said
what's the O'Neill I'm changing my
personality to move to Texas but after a
while I thought well let me try this out
and see how I'm received sure enough got
a hat got some boots but not that
uncomfortable I thought they would be it
started dressing more like them now I'm
seen as being one of them now I'm
welcomed into the boys club that is
Texas and I never thought I never owned
a gun before I went to Texas now i know
many guns and i joined I'm you know so
it works both ways if you actually
become and start mirroring someone long
enough parts of their personality and
their ways of thinking will actually rub
off on you writing is another way of
doing somaliland symbolic nearing an
example what of this would be for a
liberal person writing to conservatives
what type of language would be most
effective liberal language or
conservative language so there is a
paper that was written in the late 70s
about Cuba and Fidel Castro but it was a
liberal trying to express his message to
conservatives so he wrote in a
conservative language if you think about
we all have different sets of language
that we use with each other like our
security language of dropped in sight
metasploit or popping boxes and dropping
shells and things like that we talked to
normal people they have no clue what any
of that means that's our language so he
used conservative language language that
they're comfortable with and normally
are used to reading and writing this
article what happened all the Liberals
went crazy because they're like what is
this liberal writer writing
as a conservative the language there
that he used to mirror that mirror the
Conservatives was more powerful than the
message itself exchanged matches it's
not mirroring exactly it's a trade off
so say you're trying to understand how a
person's feeling or trying to calm them
down with their breathing you can notice
how how their breathing and actually
match it with with your arms moving back
and forth and things like that so your
training off different things that
they're doing so if they have their hand
on their face like this you might give
you this you know something here so
you're not nearing them exactly but
you're exchanging one part of the body
for another what happens is you both
fall into a rhythm because of you
matching their their body language now I
give you an example of how this works so
the guys get super pissed off or very
frustrated and like you know he's going
to explode any second what do you do a
man just calm down calm down this is an
exchange match you're trying you're
using your hands and trying to bring his
his level down trying to bring his
breath down so we all done exchange
matching we didn't make maybe didn't
even realize that we were doing a type
of mirroring to help someone bring
someone back down building at
maintaining before it is showing
interest in another person is not just
the the only way it's it's a positive
connection between you and another
person or group so it's not just showing
interest it's something that really has
to be taught you really have to learn so
being someone that might not be a
socially like a social butterfly
something that we have to practice us
manipulation professionals not on what I
call in any new terms will just keep
keeping all random but sensory acuity is
the ability to recognize about something
about a person's disposition and it
helps to close that gap so in this
particular instance what do you think
would happen if this shy guy at a party
if those two girls behind him went up
talk to him it probably would end up
being pretty bad he probably run off and
hide or something like that personal
experience I I know that's what I did
feel I got over that but what if this
guy shows up anyone's to talk to him as
well very flamboyant outspoken how do
you approach to talk to that shy person
well you don't you don't become these
people you become more like him you look
at me shy you go and more model mannered
and and your posturing and things like
that will more replicate what he's
feeling how he's doing things to gain
the report I mean who knows that looks
like probably the guy that has all the
passwords to the network that's the guy
you're going to go and want to be
friends with so once you start picking
up on some of these things you can
understand more about how a person's
feelings so this guy you can tell he's
obviously had a hard day he's stressed
out a little bit so understanding that
becoming sympathetic to him you can
actually close that gap with him as well
speech is a great indicator as well some
people say that a pause or delay might
indicate someone being deceptive but i
can ask Matthew what were you doing
seven years ago today right you don't
know yeah you have to think about it but
I ask you seven years ago today did you
rob a gas station maybe
alright
of course I picked on the guy that's
going to be cynical but anyhow so
generally speaking that person's iono
robbed a gas station if they are you
might be hanging out with like the wrong
people you know but but so you can you
can tell just apologizing necessarily
mean deception so you have to kind of
way those circumstances they come up dry
mouth can show anxiety on the stress
level the voice can show what the
person's thinking or what how the person
is reacting to what you say the accent
also not only could tell them where
they're from and also their educational
level or go back to these two and if you
notice when speaking with them that then
I'll use a big university level words
that it's more like a high school level
or in Snooki's case whatever planet
she's from whatever level there you can
tell more about their education for
example i live in Bessemer City which is
outside of gastonia and when I go to
local establishments there I don't use
big fancy heavy-duty university level
words because they'd look at me and they
think I'm being a pompous ass they're a
lot of it's a working-class town a lot
of you haven't been through much more
than high school if they even made that
far and that's fun there's nothing wrong
with how people live their life but
understanding their accent and their
vocabulary level allows me to adapt so
that I don't offend somebody once again
we're talking about building that
rapport there the best way to piss
someone off is to talk about their head
body language you can look at body
language for clues about how to proceed
so stress levels are pretty
instantaneous we have that
fight-or-flight response that really can
can tell that that switches on
automatically that we all have as
instinct so we can tell a lot about a
person's face facial expressions tension
rigid body language language so on
although I think this guy's face is
permanently stuck like that now here is
a good example like what are they seeing
off off you know off camber you know
Barack looks a little disgusted and
Michelle looks surprised as you can tell
that there's something happening off
camera that wasn't expected no Lance
Armstrong we are familiar with his drug
use and coming and being banned from
from the sport but this interview
happened at South by Southwest before
any official allegations come out and
you'll notice he's doing something
called shielding okay a great indicator
for persons not telling the truth is
that they instinctively will cover parts
of their bucket their face or dark their
eyes or look away so as to not directly
tell you that lie so that's a great
indicator someone's being deceptive if
you're if you're speaking with them
and then there's this guy um but you can
tell that there's something wrong here
this is an extreme example but pupil
dilation thinning of lips is a real
thing and something each you can
actually look for and dropping in some
information see you drop in some
information on somebody that they might
be uncomfortable with is it's a great
indicator once you're going to flight or
fight response kicks in and the body
automatically makes these changes
calibration is using sensory acuity to
gauge the state of persons in and once
you understand the statement that person
then you're able to cultivate that state
in yourself so for example this this
actor here he uses various techniques to
kind of an method acting so that he can
become different people depending on the
role she's in so say you came up to
somebody that looks very upset and you
want to calm them down do you become
very upset so that you can calm them
down or do you become the opposite of
that so this is this calibration is
gauging how the other person's feeling
and then making yourself turning
yourself into what would change that
situation maybe you do really want that
guy to get more pissed off I know a
particular person that I encounter with
and that's all I wanted to do is get him
even more out of them so I got in his
face and ended that so it depends on the
situation how you calibrate yourself to
the other person body language can tell
you a lot the posture now in this little
and this look if he changes his posture
and the stance in a sitting position
quite rapidly and every frame is it
tells a different story so you could
tell a lot about a person by their
posture and whether or not you can adapt
that posture for yourself so if someone
standing rigidly and straight up you
could present yourself like that if
someone's being casual you can tell a
lot about
how a person's feeling that way
gesturing how fast or how slow often
open and closed will tell you how to
approach that person so if you're used
to working with somebody that speaks for
their hands a lot it's very normal to
come and speak with your hands a lot
i'll allow you to build that rapport
without them even knowing that that's
what you're doing but you don't want to
be open and things like that with
somebody that is like this or doesn't
feel like having a conversation very
closed now breathing is harder to master
and there is scientific evidence of this
because there's an entire field of
hypnosis that uses breathing to to put
someone in a hypnotic state but what
this does I instead of trying to match
breathing and things like that when I
used breathing techniques I notice a
person as they're breathing they're
going to have to take a breath in and a
breath out and usually you speak on the
way out so you match your breathing and
try and find out when you can interject
into the conversation so you match your
rhythm with theirs so that you can bring
your point across as well so just a
quick wrap-up of everything's what we
think about social engineering in my
opinion needs to change when you start
looking more at the human element I know
its technical folks we like to be y'all
hacker and all that cool stuff and gain
gucky pop shells and get people to click
on stuff but really we're trying to
secure the human not necessarily just
the technical so we can use these these
things in all aspects of our life we
help our family our friends understand
that these people that are performing
these manipulation techniques really
help them identify these things so that
they can protect themselves and we can
take some of this information back to
our companies and help protect our
companies as well anyone have any
questions do you use these as part of
your actual day job
so the question is do I use these things
in my day job yes I do to an extent one
time on a red team member and part of
our mission our Charter is to test our
security controls so whether or not our
social engineering awareness program
works so I might use a phishing email
that cheap someone click on blank but
for me personally I'm more effective
over telephone when I you know I'm not
just waiting for someone to click on
something I actually like to call and
engage somebody it's easier the phone as
well than in person because you're more
comfortable because you can't see what
that person's reaction you use more of
it to detect from their tone of voice
and and how they're responding how that
you can proceed and how you can better
get information from them that answer
your question because in a quick follow
you don't mind
happen what percentage of cases would
you say leads to uncovering of a gap in
the education of your corporate users in
other words how often does someone
develops
how often is someone divulge information
um where I previously was with another
large bank I was getting around seventy
percent where I'm at now i'm ninety-five
percent and it's it's a it's a change
for an entire organization to really
understand those things because a lot of
these trainings get it buried down in
emails and things like that i do another
presentation on building your awareness
program at the Charlotte is a summit a
few weeks ago but what happens is you
have emails that get sent out for
awareness training but they are part of
another huge email newsletter so they
get lost or it's not mandatory training
or something like that or people are
able to next X finish and click through
it really quickly but you know you offer
someone a free dinner or some tickets to
a sports game generally speaking people
will give you more information so you
make it enticing for them and basically
you're feeding on what they're saying or
what they're doing in order to give you
no respond so you end up with a lot of
people especially if you're targeting
it's very difficult to stop the targeted
manipulation attack I mean how its
social engineering but that's what we
call it as a turn but and ironically I
think John's got something for me to
give away but is there any other
question
state-by-state different states regulate
the use
the question is states by States and if
I heard of anything I honestly I haven't
I would love to find that out because
there's a lot of people that are called
engineers I'd like to throw that law
North Carolina does have statutes in
terms of the professional use of the
term engineer I know the case in the
early 90s guy was charged he was in New
York State for calling himself a
tortured engineer for doing some
unpopular research and so it's
interesting the rise of the term social
engineer
I would love for that to happen I love
for that to happen because I've been a
Microsoft systems engineer since from 15
16 years now come on it's a piece of
paper that says I passed the test it's
not an engineer degree I know a lot of
Engineers i went for years and years as
much as you know doc doctors and things
like that i go to school to get that
engineer title for us to throw it around
like you know it's kind of you know I
just don't like anyone's big pet peeve
of mine yes so what are you so 95%
impact rate what I do for follow-up so
in doing so I take a multi-tiered
approach so we start off so if I'm doing
running out of fishing campaign start
off with a level one fish is very
plainly obvious that it's a fish so if
they click on that link they're going to
have to go back for additional training
in remediation if they report that link
then they go to level two level T is a
little harder the spelling isn't you
know better it's not coming from Nigeria
up to where everything looks legit
except for you know the link is actually
going to the wrong place you teach
people to think if it's not something
that they're used to seeing so that
multi-tiered approach kind of helps
graduate people up and make it more
difficult more secure unfortunately
getting buy-in for a major organization
to to do that type of training is very
difficult it's still unsuccessful where
I'm at now but we're working on it so
smaller organization I think might be
able easy to remediate if you can go
talk to the person but with you know
hundreds of thousands of people
programs makes it difficult yes
so the question is using only ASCII text
and email and and then to only what you
can say on the over the phone one ASCII
text I would never be able to do that
because marketing every marketing groups
maybe Brad everything and they stick
links on everything there's no way that
they would let that happen and two I
think there are things that you're
supposed to give out but once again it's
one of those things that sits on the
side of the computer desk and if it
sounds like you're legit from tech
support no one does any kind of
authentication there because I
especially if you say if you mess with
someone's computer remotely and then you
call as your tech support like say if I
said a phishing email they click on a
link that does something malicious on
their computer and now I follow up with
a tech support call it's going to sound
legit because I've actually targeted
that person when after so if people
would use that that'd be great but it's
like this disaster preparedness Flyers
that get some workplaces you put it up
so you know exactly the procedure if
this happens then you do this well if
you don't read it and it just sits there
forever it gets forgotten about so
unfortunately there are scripts in fact
in the computer a lot of these will love
screen pop with the customer information
which spoofing and I caller Ids pretty
easy to do call it customer information
and they have a script on what they're
supposed to say and a lot of times you
can get them diverted off of that script
yes
um
the question is is there a specific age
group that is more susceptible to social
engineering actually I don't think I've
done any kind of analysis over that that
would be interesting i would say
Millennials and you know Gen Xers
through Millennials would be more
susceptible because we are what they
term digital natives we grew up around
this stuff we're used to seeing it we're
used to putting stuff and and tweeting
things as they've been developed I would
say that they more susceptible because I
know some of the boomers in our company
I mean they still you know mess up
emails and things like that so that
would be an interesting analysis but
that's just my opinion off the top of my
head any more questions I think we got
like a time for running one more now
okay cool where's that uh I can do it or
you can do it that's all I do it okay