hey Stephen all right away go to the
mountain stick does look for coming
uncle jokes yeah it was a lease it yet
but the sweet page debug little bit
overcome the html5 semantic star
involved even if blowjo volume unless
you take off now so i play video ck2 up
w e've in circuit visits alright so i'll
leave you to the the conference like I
just said to them that we will take the
question at the end like which is our
before so if there's anything to sign up
all yours okay thank you alright so
welcome everyone thank you for coming to
tonight's presentation before we get
started I'm going to make the assumption
that everyone has an idea for the De Aza
packets and so most of you know that
DDoS attacks are on the rise they're
becoming more and more powerful and they
are becoming more frequent as well and
with that the kiosk mitigation industry
is booming companies are spending tens
of thousands of dollars a month putting
all these offenses in place to protect
their application but one thing we
notice is that oftentimes companies
don't look at what their application can
do to actually help protect itself
against ddos attacks and so tonight I'm
going to be talking about some of the
common issues we've seen
with these third-party defenses and as
well as things you can do with your
application to actually help it be
protected by these other defenses so a
little bit about me um I'm actually a U
of T grad and I was hired a couple years
ago two sturdy compass to actually work
on training tools so I was brought on to
develop another solution we had for
training the game is sandbox environment
and a few months into my job I was asked
to work on a secret project so naturally
when somebody asks you to work on a
secret project you don't say no so I
jumped on it and it turned out what I
had to do was find a way to evaluate a
company's digas defenses so I started
planning out how to actually do that and
I figured the best solution was actually
launching a DDoS attack against them so
I started building our solution and it's
funny because in University my dream job
was developing some software that was
super powerful it was brought on the
distributed system they would do some
sort of powerful computations something
powerful you know a typical Comp Sci
students dream and so it turns out with
launching DDoS attacks actually fits
that bill quite well and so now I get to
actually live out launching DDoS attacks
in coordinating thousands of service to
actually you know created the office
attack and send powerful in illicit
traffic I kind of unsuspecting servers
um so flash forward to today I the lead
d das consultant for detox drink at
security compass and a off strike is our
in-house service for launching realty
office attacks against annie's the
offenses
applications put in place and actually
evaluating whether those defenses will
withstand you know it's a time I built a
platform we use for launching DDoS
attacks and I've been building and
launching the office attacks legally for
about two years now so before I continue
tonight's presentation is part two in
part by the Empire shows a few Star Wars
fans out there so you know if you think
you're fighting the rebel scum consider
joining the Empire so as I mentioned
before DDoS attacks are happening akamai
reported in ninety percent increase in
the office attacks in q4 2015 over the
previous quarter and there's constant
news coverage of DDoS attacks I'm
constantly getting emails every day from
my google alerts about new DDoS attacks
on companies extortion campaigns things
like that and a lot of high-profile
attacks playstation network was down
recently and as part of their apology to
the user base they sent out a free day 0
PS boss because of it xbox was hit
before the Christmas break and even more
notable one is BBC was taken down by a
really large penis attack and it's kind
of interesting really really knows to
say how powerful DDoS attacks are
becoming because the BBC has been
streaming digital media for years now
and surveying hundreds of thousands
millions of people and so their
infrastructure is actually overwhelmed
with the dogs a detox of flood
indicating the power that that time
so I'm sure there are people in the
audience possibly the other two have
been either hit by a gas attack or know
someone and you can proudly share sorry
just do the 4matic tonight with product
we won't be sharing those stories but I
can tell you that I can he knows i
launched ddos attacks spread my job I've
launched a variety of different attacks
both volumetric and application launch
volumetric tags up to 25 gigabits per
second UDP jump traffic and also not as
powerful application layer in fact I
worked with a variety of different
infrastructures to evaluate so things
ranging from you know infrastructures
that don't actually have any defenses
and want to see what a DDoS attack will
do to infrastructure the tub on-premise
inning Club defenses little help that
will protect it from any grounding point
and so it's actually interesting because
we typically see a lot of success with
the a player attacks despite them not
being as powerful it's really because
you don't need as much power to actually
be successful because of that they're
actually harder to detect there's lower
bandwidth they can fly under the radar
making it trickier to actually notice it
and determine this actually develop at a
lot of times companies are hesitant to
block these attacks because they don't
know whether it's legitimate traffic and
they're actually scared of being
overzealous with what they block in
blocking legitimate users and that's
really why companies fear a planar tax
the most at least when what we've seen
that the clients we work with a lot of
times we hear from companies that were
trying to approach about
is that their app is protected they pay
Akamai tens of thousands of dollars a
month to have a cen content delivery
network and a web application firewall
in place don't you know supposedly
protect them against all of these
details and apps and our question always
is how do you actually tested it have
you gone through tests and different
parts of you have tested the parts that
are likely to be targeted because there
are certain parts of it even with the
cen defense in place that will be
targeted and consoled leagues with
potential dee da situation and one
question we always ask or consider is
have you even looked at your application
to see you know if the designing it
actually helps protect them against eat
off attacks if it helps make a cen to
finance more efficient so we can't talk
about the US attacks without talking
about the supporting infrastructure now
I'm sure a lot of you have seen various
different infrastructures work with
different ones probably combinations of
load balancers servers other on-premise
devices firewalls so wondering if
anybody's infrastructure it looks like
this probably not I mean in my past
experience nobody's raised their hand
for this so what if we what if we look
at it like this you know so so the desks
are you know not your column any
infrastructure so maybe if we look at it
this so you can consider the desks are a
lot like you know that actually called
an infrastructure we're at the very core
that you have your origin server serving
applications a long way have routers
firewalls on-premise devices maybe even
load balancers and at the very outer
layer defense is where you have your
content delivery network that's serving
static content and absorbing most of an
attack observing an attack if there is
one on your infrastructure for the most
part so more simplistic view is this and
this is actually a generalization of a
lot of the infrastructures we actually
work with and so some combination of
these components will see and is
something to commonly test so even with
all of this you know there are still
issues you're not fully protected and
it's surprising actually that we see
some common issues amongst people with
similar for structures so even with you
know CDN layered defense we still find
issues similar to any sort of pen
testing where you know people have done
their due diligence you can still type
most of the time find some sort of
security issue and when you're thinking
about CDN defenses you can think of any
issue as a big hole in the Death Star so
some ways to bypass the cd8 defense and
completely you know completely bypasses
offenses and actually attack the origin
infrastructure itself for CDN defense
one way one vent hole is actually
getting access to the origin IP if you
can get access to the origin IP you can
potentially bypass CDN defense just
because of how they typically set up
what we typically seen is they'll use
DNS to route traffic to the
gdn defense which will proxy any
requests or serve requests from the
network and proxy any requests it cancer
back to the origin infrastructure so the
vent hole there is if you can send
traffic directly to the origin
infrastructure your defense doesn't do
anything for you and so one way one vent
hole is potentially when your
application leaks the MP so if your
application tcpip an attacker can then
bypass you defenses with the CDM defense
you want to make sure that you want to
consider your origin IP sensitive data
so this can actually be considered one
of the OWASP top ten the a6 sensitive
data exposure if you're leaking your
Jenai key to an attacker and there could
be a number of different ways they could
be in the response bodies even in the
headers or even worse if it's logged in
some file somewhere that's somehow
publicly accessible either through other
vulnerabilities or just really bad
screen set and like I said all of this
would allow traffic to be directly to
the origin server another kind of Avenue
or play on that is when response bodies
are HTTP headers leave some sort of
fingerprint so we've seen have five
devices where they'll send back the HTTP
header big-ip which is enough 52 private
area technology for fighting up detox
defenses so right away from there we
know we're working with the neckline
device and if we can get access we can
find out through other means the block
might is that company almost and then it
is start anew Maury ting it to see which
servers are which I keys return a
similar head
and kind of match up the the IP that way
to the fingerprint we found through you
know through some sort of leak and in
that case through that means we have the
origin IP and again can attack directly
to the infrastructure another common
thing we see a common way to see origin
Eyed Peas linked is through DNS so one
actually very common scenario is where
the root domain say example.com well
actually points in the original IP and
when you just go there when the browser
goes there it'll send an HTTP redirect
back to actually go to triple w example
calm and from there that point to the
actual CDN infrastructure and obviously
this is an issue because again you know
it's an easy way to discover the origin
of P and even though you're only sending
can only send small amount of traffic to
that orange light d you can still send
traffic to it and when we're talking
about details we can send massive
amounts of traffic to it even enough to
just knock it off and in some cases
we've been able to do that there have
been specific cases are specific
services running that you know we said
it enough traffic that it has memory
issues or something and suddenly it will
stop accepting connections tcp
connection floods another thing you can
do and that anyone trying to navigate to
example calm doesn't get that redirect
anymore is that they going to connect
and you've successfully you're
successful with you details of time this
is number of different data dns records
that can also expose the origin i think
we've seen old and outdated records
subdomains so might not be example.com
but it could be blogs on example calm
little slow point to your origin
infrastructure and any other type of
record
it's like male records on our
authoritative DNS records so the way to
help protect yourself from those kinds
of leaks and really just protecting
orange my team is to subscribe to bgp
based services with that your your
service provider is now announcing your
IP space so either Akamai or one of the
top detox negation providers will
actually announce your IP space and
route traffic to their infrastructure
first so that even if you get your own
IP you know they can still rub the
traffic before it gets the
infrastructure and keep you protected
there are no different services also but
so are supposed to protect your origin
IP I could my ass one called site shield
and typically bgp is the way to go one
major defense of CN providers and web
application firewall providers is radon
is a regulates are intended to determine
non-human potentially not including
clients so those are you know if a
malicious fog is trying to attack the
site they might be requesting it at the
nonhuman rate of 10 requests per second
typically the application is for
websites I've seen there's no need for a
person to you know request the same page
over and over again so repeatedly and so
great limits are intended
to detect that and block out those
malicious I piece or potentially
malicious IPS because you know there
might be a rare case for some sites
let's say a ticking sun if you're trying
to take it for an event you might sit
there hitting refresh over and over
again just to try and get the tickets
you want so in some cases you know a
legitimate client could actually you
know make a request too many times
request to page too many times and get
themselves flogged so they've they're
pretty defenses implemented a short
clock period time sometimes it's
adjustable and so it will really depend
on your provider and we've seen times
between two minutes and five minutes and
there's a number of different rate
limits that you can actually use to help
protect yourself there's monitoring
rates and requests for second concurrent
connections per second from a single
source and even the link speed typically
depending on your client base most of
your users will have a decent speed
internet connection speed and so the
really slow lines could be a sign of
malicious users trying to do something
like a slow loris type of attack so even
with the rate limits we've still found
issued when we're testing clients and
ravens are commonly the most configured
defense misconfigured defense that we've
seen a lot of times we'll go into a test
the climate be confident that it's
protecting because it has these random
is and it just wants us to verify on
them however we go in we don't actually
see a great limit take effect and that
can be either miss configuration they're
not switched on for whatever reason or
even let their I'm figure to be too high
for the application that's another
scenario you see a lot of them where
they arbitrarily set a rate limit on an
application but even the amount they set
is too high easily flying that radar
distribute our load to you know
thousands
couple thousands of servers and still be
able to take that server down and we'll
still be doing 90 + per second if they
have a rate limit of 10 requests per
second which could still be considered
non-human depending on your application
one of the things we see is a great
limits are only configured at the
automotive outermost defense so they'll
be only if we figured on the cen third
party CDN or wack provider and that's
kind of an issue because we talked about
eventful being the origin IP so my can
bypass the CDN I can bypass those great
limits and then suddenly there's
absolutely no defenses and you can even
block the the most simplest of DDoS
attacks so you want to be able to rely
or prove your rate limits to help
protect your infrastructure and to do
that you need to know what limits you
can place you can put in place so I
managed before they're 30 there are
three three examples those are requests
for second connections concurrent
connections per single source and link
speed and you really know what to set
those values you need to establish a
baseline so baseline will involve
monitoring the traffic to your site for
a period of time we typically see two
weeks or suggest two weeks at least so
you can calculate averages and standard
deviations and figure out which pages
are accessed most frequently and things
like that and that will allow you to set
same same rate limits for further
different pages in your application for
their parts of your site if possible you
want to be you want to set exponentially
increasing block times for repeat
offenders so anyone that's constantly
you know little violate or little go
past the limits
plot for a period of time as they can
pack if they come back and go above that
way for it again you know that's even
more indicative that they might be some
sort of bond so you want to block them
for a longer period of time because
there's actually a case where an
attacker world roll through a different
side of my peace throughout the duration
of an attack so it's once there we've
actually experienced and will have pools
of attacking nodes and basically when we
detective one pool is blocked we'll just
rotate to the next school and you know
even though the first ones a block we've
got a fresh attack going fresh eyed peas
and those ones on your block and they
continue to take down the site and we'll
just keep rotating it depending on with
the duration time if it's tagged and in
that scenario we might we might not be
able to keep a consistent downtime but
we can keep knocking the page offline
online offline to the point where any
users of the site will probably be
ticked off and you know will complain my
extended email to support my coil your
support center if you have one and well
typically not want to use your site the
lose confidence in it another way to
improve your rate limit to make sure
they're more effective is to not use a
global brain limit and that's the thing
we've also seen as well basically
clients will do some sort of baselining
they'll go through that activity but the
lonely set a limit for the entire site
and that's kind of an issue because
different parts of the site are used at
different rates basically you might have
a gate will go back to the ticket site
where there's one page where users will
you know refresh a bunch of clients you
get your tickets but when they're
logging in they'll typically only
abstract
page me once or twice perception and so
there you can set an even stricter
unlock your you can set a stricter great
just because you know typical use will
be very low and that will allow you to
better protect the login page which is
actually actually one of the more common
targeted attacks when you do have CDN
defenses in place because it needs to be
processed by the origin server and so
more stringent controls can be placed on
it to help protect that partner I
mentioned before that another issue is
only setting limits at the outer
perimeter on a CDN or wha service
provider now you really want to enforce
them inside all the different layers
because of the issue of bypassing some
of those defenses so you can do this on
on-premise devices routers firewalls
even in your application server like
internet engine X you can separate them
is bursting limits as well so if you can
figure it out multiple different layers
do you have a better chance to protect
yourself and blocking out even the most
simplest DDoS attacks finally you want
to verify that it all works I mean if
you put go through the motions set
everything up spend the time put it all
in place you want to test it you want to
touch that it works it works as you
expect it to and that there aren't any
holes or you know that the rates that
you the limits you put in place are
actually able to protect your
application from a DDoS attack so even
with all those defenses we still see
other issues some sites will allow slow
connections and I mentioned before that
will open you up to slow loris type of
the times we've seen services are to
properly and how to adjust the open file
limits or TCP connection pool limits to
state amount and so it's actually really
easy to exhaust all
mention terminal servers we've seen a
rare case actually where the CDN
provider would allow invalid HTTP
requests we are trying to do a slow
loris or slow post type of attack where
we send a post request but we never read
neverend request on our end instead the
CDN provider and close the connection
and what we saw was happening was that
it would actually forward that request
back to the origin server anyways
despite of being invalid or just like us
than for completing it and the origin
server would process it and we were able
to effectively bypass the CDN through
that post attack we've also seen servers
with memory issues and this can be on
more in the application side where your
application and either has a memory or
certain operations of memory hogs and
you know if we hated numerous amounts of
times not even sa the huge amounts of
times we can still cause it to use a way
too much memory and have the OS actually
respect the process taking down for a
few seconds we just sort of repeat that
to keep taking it down over and over
again to really really destroy the
usability of the application so even
with all these defenses in place let's
say you've verified they'll work your
rate limits are good they're adequate
what can you do to actually helped you
know bolster your defenses improve your
defenses and you can look into building
a buddy to the center building a better
application through either it's more
efficient or just certain designs will
help your defense is protected so with
the CIA in place your major issue now is
dynamic requests so they give you issues
you can't control them simply because
they need to be sent to your origin
server your server needs to process it
and these are pages like logging pages
where user will send credentials that a
database needs to be interacted with to
verify them search pages for any sort of
story content on your server or in
another database authenticated pages
typically you don't want to catch those
there's actually a recent issue with
steam when they were under in Jos attack
they enable they made some tweaks to
their CDN pages or CDN configuration
which caused authenticated pages to be
patched and served to other users so
that was a huge issue for them because
it was actually leaking leaking other
user details just because those pages
were cashed and any foreign submission
will also need to be processed by over
it's over and these types of pages are
the main target for ddos attacks it's
what we look for when we're doing
engagement anything that will allow us
to send traffic to or caused some sort
of processing on the origin server so
what can you do to help you know reduce
the impact of these dynamic requests so
reduce the impact of DDoS attack you can
try to make things more static you want
to make things as static as possible in
the application specifically i'm talking
about websites here so you want to
abstract as much of the site structure
into some sort of capital format and
make it easily catchable by UC game
provider so that'll be things like your
JavaScript your CSS any HTML these are
all typically static and can be cached
and you know any time you use requested
it'll be served by ucen by the
infrastructure even if you if you're
using a front-end template engine to
rendering dynamic pages that can easily
be cash to and again reduce the load
that your urgent has the process another
thing you want to do is consider how
dynamic you
actually is if you're aggregating news
results from various different sources
or something like that you might not
actually update that let's say you only
updated every 30 minutes something like
that can still be cash for that 30
minutes where it's never updated and you
can actually configure your CDN to
invalidate that page after you know
whatever time for install then it's
valid for and the next request for that
page will cause a CDN to make a single
request here infrastructure and update
its own cash in that case if the US is
happy you it will only result in you
know a thousand note sending requests to
that one supposedly that edit card will
only actually results in a single
requests every 30 minutes d origin
infrastructure so again the cen is
taking the impact of load of the DDoS
attack and keep your site and
application up and running another thing
you want to do is limit interactions so
pages where either those form
submissions and logging pages you want
to be able to limit how many times a
user can submit to it through the actual
application and this is for the case
where if you have a login page the
actual process of connecting to the
database and verifying those credentials
to be resource intensive so if I school
the final attack when I'm still sending
three requests recycling let's say it
could still be enough of the load from a
thousand different servers or tackling
agents to knock your application on
flying or even not be dying so choked up
your database and that kind of behavior
is stall you know not typical and might
be blocked by CN funds for the game you
want to have multiple layers just in
case it's somehow bypassed or whatever
rate
you put in place isn't you know if the
if I can fly under it you still have
some sort of protection and so what you
want to do with these limiting
interactions is probably using our
method you already use and things like
sessions or cookies to help block out
more simple botnet attacks but that's
like that can't store cookies and send
them on subsequent requests will not be
able to interact with that specific page
if you validate the cookies first before
any sort of other processing happens the
next step up is using csrf tokens which
you should already be doing especially
for for submission pages these block
endings sort of botany tags that cannot
do any sort of HTML parsing because it
can't parse out that token out of the
page the next step up and this will
block a lot of majority of you gossip
acts out there except the most advanced
ones is using javascript cookies and
this is actually what a lot of Geass
defense providers use themselves as a
sort of challenge they'll inject the
snippet of JavaScript into your page
which will run all in the clients
computer set some sort of cookie or some
sort of value and return it on the next
request and that validates that you know
the clients running a legitimate browser
or at least something that can process
JavaScript another other tools you can
use on any sort of energy on occasion
controls so another example is actually
capture and it somebody else defense
providers use that too but kind of as a
last set because they're not is
user-friendly even Google uses is to
some degree when made too many search
requests on their page the presenting of
the capture just embarr fly that you're
not actually a ball so you're not using
their infrastructure another thing to
consider is how scalable is your
application you might not need
depending on your user base and things
like that but you still want to design
your application so lets you know if you
do if you are receiving very high load
for traffic you can scale up to kind of
absorb that impact and you know this
will help you in cases where there's
some sort of hole and your other
defenses or even just some of the delay
that exists between when you get
attacked and when your defenses are
actually able to fully scrub out that
attack and with some of our nation's
you've actually seen times of up to 45
minutes where we started an attack took
down the site and it took the day off
the fence provider 45 minutes to run a
custom role that will filter out the
traffic and then slowly roll that up to
all of their edge nodes so in that time
you have downtime and while they're
mitigating its soul it's a small roll
out and so you're still taking depending
on size of the office attack a huge hit
from it
from that AWS actually believes them a
white paper recently for when you're
running applications on their
infrastructure where they're
recommending defense against ddos
attacks is to actually use the elastic
Beanstalk service and the elastic
restart service will dynamically scale
out your application by setting up
additional VMs that'll actually be both
balance and during a little balancer and
do some of the processing and spread up
that look this is kind of kind of not
defense coming from AWS because right
away implies up there there d das
appliances to just pay for more their
infrastructure and they make more money
obviously but really just ensuring you
have some sort of dynamics dynamic
scaling will make it more cost effective
so that only why do I directed office
attack you're actually being attacked
you don't just have tons of
infrastructure lying around that most
the time is 13 ugly there's even the
concept of hybrid standing where you
have physical machines in your data
center and when loads get too high
either through DNS or other methods will
actually start splitting that load
between auto scaling infrastructure in
the cloud and you're only on site
infrastructure and in that case you can
stall see some cost saving from under
your own infrastructure and again only
scale up to the cloud needed so if you
dos attacks are not just an a problem if
your application can be easily taken
down it becomes everyone's problem you
want to make sure that you're actually
testing defenses you put in place
because any sort of small issue
configuration issue or any overlooked
part of the defense could result in a
DDoS attack
and that could actually cost you tons of
money depending on what your application
does
engines revving we're in retail stores
any online store if they're down there
losing revenue so you want to make sure
that all of you defenses are tested and
not just tested a single time when you
put them in place you want to
continuously test test as you make
changes test if anything in your
infrastructure changes or even just over
time to make sure that I like you people
and your processes that are handling
these DDoS attacks are our training they
can recognize the dasa time it's
actually something we've seen before
where we've launched at the office
attack but the people responsible for
monitoring and defending infrastructure
they didn't recognize it they just
started with some sort of application
issue and it took them actually a week
and a half to realize that it was
probably a DDoS attack and like
obviously a week and a half later is too
late for them to start putting defenses
in place so you want to continuously
test and verify so that again your staff
is trained they can recognize it and
that your processes make sense and
actually able to help you recover from
those kinds of attacks so I'd like to
thank you all for listening to me
hopefully you've been able to take
something away from it to help protect
yourself against ddos attacks because if
you have experience in detox attack i
might be coming for you thank you thanks
my god that's for the question level
this is ripped it just a sec is common
all right just a small question for you
during christmas from amazon.com you
have a lot of a lot of connections the
same time and if you have someone who is
using a botnet you will have a lot of
concurrent connections same time
though the rate limits are not working
at that moment because your application
is highly used it's two weeks before
Christmas so how can you detect if it's
a pity baby DOS attack I sooner we'll
hang on your application some of the
more advanced detox defenses will detect
some sort of behavioral some sort of
behavioral pattern for how the sites
actually use so that will involve you
know if you have multi page application
where the logical order of H could be
you know going to the home page or use
login page going to another finish and
you sort of malicious user that is just
hitting a single page over and over will
be identified as fishs or something and
in that case you can detect them in that
way again if you notice like you with
specifically Amazon you can get
notifications about when your
infrastructure is scaling out because
you know these concurrent connections or
usages and from there you're staffel off
to any staff involved in your software
that are responsible for mitigating the
attack could potentially take a closer
look and you know hopefully they can
recognize that there might be some sort
of you know hit put it to the also time
it really depends how sophisticated the
DDoS attack is as well only the most
sophisticated attacks well you know
bypass all of those controls so a lot of
the time five percent of the attacks of
C will be basic or simple in nature
rolla just you know request same page
over and over again and in that case you
might might be able to detect it despite
what the right
thank you any other question good thanks
again Michael and uh was a great
presentation so I'll talk to you soon