so the talk that i'm going to
give you today is about free emfa for
all
i see i work with the security pattern
and formerly i worked for about 10 years
as a
red team engineer in a big smart card
company
and when they hired me
they
[Music]
told me that i would be going to work
with lasers in order to inject fault on
smart cards
so as soon
that
they told me i would i would work with
lasers
i imagine that i was going to
fight with
lasers
against hackers in order to defend the
security of credit cards
in reality it's not that but
still i was thinking something like this
where i had to use lasers with mirrors
and then direct lasers to something
but again
reality is a little bit
subtle than this usually with lasers to
inject faults
you have a computer that drives a laser
in some
box
and then you get just to work with the
computer
so the talk today is to show you
lasers but why fault attacks are useful
are used by hackers and how they works
and now you and now everybody can
build a small tool to try using fords
so where fault attacks can be used
basically on
the smart card worlds
then there's one main place where
faults can be used when you use your
smart card to to make a transaction you
basically
insert your pin to verify that you are
the owner of the card
the flowchart shows that if you insert
the right pin the card inside compares
the pin inserted with the with its own
pin and if they are equal then the
transaction is performed
if not the transaction is halted
but
what happens is that there exist big
pockets so
if the card if your card is stolen then
there's only one thing that prevent the
pickpocket to perform transaction on
your money it's that
input pin if they turn if the
hacker if the big pocket
don't know the the right pin he will not
be able to perform transaction with your
money
but
what can happen is that
the hacker
can try to fault this execution in order
to obtain
a correct
transaction to fault the execution of
the card in order to perform the
transaction
to accept a wrong pin even
as if it was the correct one
so from this flow chart how does the
um
the
the implementation a generic
implementation of this flow chart
can be can be expressed this is a really
generic
view of the
of the code of the implementation
the function is verify pin which takes
an input a candidate pin from the user
and then in step two a first
function is the comparison of the
card pin
against the input pin if they are both
equal then
the function return a status true
in
instead if they are different the status
return is false
in step three there's an if condition if
the status return is true then the
transaction is performed
if it is not then it jumps to step six
and the transaction is stopped
so
how
the attacker can try to
[Music]
perform a fault in order to corrupt the
execution
we can think of at least three
main points where the fault can occur
first one is the comparison function if
the attacker is able to corrupt this
function in order to return always true
then it is sufficient for the attacker
to
get a transaction
another point of
injection or fault
is the value returned by the comparison
function if this value
which is returned false for example for
a wrong pin is corrupted by the attacker
then the transaction is performed once
again
and a third
point of injection of the of the fault
is the if
instruction if this instruction is
faulted then instead of executing step
three the
flow of execution goes directly to step
four and the transaction can be
performed
so we can identify at least three
different
models for the attack to work
the first one is the corrupt instruction
corrupting the
comparison function
may lead to a
transaction performed the second one is
the corrupt value where the value on a
register inside the
the smart card is corrupted
then this can also provide a correct
transaction and finally
skipping one instruction can make the
flow go
to the perform transaction step
so
fault attacks are very useful
a real threat
because they cannot be applied to many
different things
it can be used to access protected
features or bypass limitations
for example
we have seen smart cards but it's also
true for automotive or internet of
things
they can
allow attackers to
bypass activation codes secure boot
send boxes or perform privilege
escalation
it can also be used
to disable protections or restrictions
for example drones usually have a
limitation on the zone they can fly due
to no flight zone
and this is a limitation these are
limitations imposed by the the vendors
and by using fault attacks it's possible
for example to make drones fly even on
no-flight zones
also it's possible to bypass pay tv
restriction or avoid security measures
usually when you input too much times a
wrong pin into your smart card the smart
card is blocked usually it's about 10
tries
and faults can be used to prevent this
blocking
allowing the attacker to try more even
more than 10 times
fault attacks are historically
being devised to
break cryptography because fault attacks
can be
employed to retrieve secret keys in
embedded hardware
performing
symmetric asymmetric even post quantum
crypto lightweight etc
so
why do fault attacks work
they works because electronics are
basically made of many many many
transistors
millions of transistors
if you can
cut
a microchip in half and look from the
side we would see
mainly three layers
three genera general layers the the the
first layer is the metal layer
which connects the
the chip to the external world
the second layer is the transistors
layer and the back side of the ship is
is the silicon substrate
which embeds the transistors
so transistors are basically switch
they are activated by current or voltage
and by activating a current
is similar to activating a transistor is
similar to pushing a button
and when the button is pushed
electrons flow from the source to the
drain
and when the
button is not pushed then electrons
cannot flow
so the
idea of fault
is that even if the button is not pushed
even if voltage or current is not
applied to the transistor maybe some
physical tampering with the environment
where the
embedded processor works
allows some of the transistor to be
artificially
activated or even artificially
deactivated
so
how
to
perform such
manipulation of the physical environment
in order to make such transistors
behave differently from expected
there are a few different attack vectors
that have been devised in literature
the first one uh
temperature
uh most of you should know
about the airpod called gate where
if you put an iphone an older version of
iphones into the fridge then it stops
work it stops working this is because
lower temperatures or
much higher temperatures
make
transistors not behave
correctly and so
the the the phone shut down
the
positive thing
about
this kind of
fault vector is that it does not require
preparation
preparation means
decapsulating
the
microcontroller removing epoxy or raisin
in order to
reach
the the the electronics
so there's no need for the capsulation
or something like this for temperature
attacks
but the countermeasure are easy because
it just need a temperature sensor to
detect that the temperature is too low
or too high from the
prescribed
also there are other two
easy
fault vectors that are clock glitches or
voltage glitches
basically an electronic device
which is can
get its clock from an external source
if it is the case then an attacker can
try instead of providing a stable clock
to
insert some peak some glitch into the
clock
in order to make the electronics behave
literally
a little bit differently from expected
once again preparation preparation is
nothing and
the
best country measure is not to rely on
an external clock just use an internal
clock to the uh
device
voltage glitches works a little bit
similarly
usually you have to provide power to the
electronics to to work
and
instead of providing a smooth
uh
power you can provide some
glitch has more power with some peak
with some glitches
and these glitches may
make the transistor internally behave
differently corrupt the internal
transistor functioning
so
for voltage glitches usually you have
nothing to do for preparation to
removing some decoupling capacitor which
are there in order to try to smooth
the
voltage incoming
countermeasure one of the best
confirmations is to use regulators for
example to smooth the incoming power
other more advanced
fault attack vectors which is the one i
was talking at the beginning is lasers
or light
the
the bench
that is shown on the right
is a bench from edsi in 2001
and
it's basically a flash of a
camera
uh targeted at the atas mark card
the idea is that by irradiating the
transistor
with some light with a
powerful enough light enough light
then it's possible to change
its state from switched off to switched
on
so
laser benches have evolved since 2001
and today you can have something similar
to this one
this the bench on the right is from
alphanub
and it's capable to
use
two laser sources
a different special position and
activated at different timing to perform
double fault injection into for example
smart cards
another way to inject faults is by emfa
this is the object of the tool that i
mean that i'm going to present you
in this work
and
the idea is that by
producing a super sufficiently strong
electromagnetic field
near the chip circuit it may induce eddy
current
inside and such at the currents may
activate some of the transistor
another way to inject fault is
body bias the idea is similar to em is
that by injecting a high power
[Music]
voltage to the back side to the silicon
substrate of the chip it's possible to
modify the behavior of internal
transistors
and finally
leity showed in 2017 that it's possible
also to use x-rays to modify the to
corrupt the internal transistor of a
function in chip
so this the tool that i'm going to show
you is based on emfa
and there are a few uh reasons why
we have choose to use emfa first of all
it's need it needs know the packaging
basically you just
get near the target with your probe
sufficiently near
and the attack may work
the
risk is relatively low because for
example for faults
for for lasers sorry
there's a risk of
for the eyes because you have to wear
glasses
protecting glasses and the
laser bench must be secured
with emfi you can be a little bit
electro shocked
but if you insulate sufficiently
the device it's not really a problem
emfi are very portable the tool i'm
going to show you is really portable and
they can be very effective they are used
daily on the security of smart cards in
order to test the security
let's have a little
show of recent low-cost attacks and
tools appeared in literature
starting from cheap fail chip.fail is a
website where hackers
show
how to bring fault injection attacks to
the masses
they mainly use voltage glitching
and some of the outers recently broke
the security of the apple air tag by
usic by using a raspberry pi pico
the chip fail show
how to introduce faults into target like
st
esp sam and nrf
they the the outers of chip that fail
are also the authors of wallet fail
where they show that it's possible to
corrupt the execution of the ledger nano
s uh bitcoin wallet
by using glitches and thus
recover the the secrets inside
um another company working on on similar
results here is rail eyes where they
show that it's possible to mount fault
attacks on autosar it's autosar is the
middleware for automotive
also it's they show a secure boot bypass
on the esp32 by using ice glitch which
is a low-cost glitching tool
then limited results
use the
another tool they
conceived
to
resurrect the debug functionality of nrf
chips and recently they were able to use
this this tool to
break the security of the em er
efm32 jacob family
from silicon labs
finally cracking.com
show
how by using glitches it's possible to
make a similar attack like the one from
ledger
on ledger unless on another
family of
bitcoin wallet is the trezor hardware
wallets
on the tools used to mount such attack
there are
the problem of mounting fault attacks is
that they are usually very expensive
lasers goes from 50 to 100 000
you you need
[Music]
costly oscilloscopes
and so people are trying to see if there
are
cheaper
ways to achieve faults
one of the first to suggest a cheaper
alternative is
a cheap shelter from ua
which cost around four thousand dollars
and enable you to
inject emfa
uh into chips
another suggestion from the
ledger team ledger security security
team is silicon toaster
which is the
the first one
on the left
it's a handmade device that you can
create
at home
but
which is which is basically similar to
the chip shelter but requires uh deep
knowledge on electronics and firmware
development
finally limited results
showed the their injector which is a
glitch em
injector probe
but they do not provide the the
how to create this
so
even more recently two weeks ago uh the
author from new a karin of flynn
showed
his last
tool which is calling gplr
which is very similar to the one i'm
going to show you in this talk and
here's the the
circuit of the flash of a disposable
camera in order to create a tool to
mount for emfa attacks
so
let's get to the
subject of this speech
first of all
the tool uses about
from 330 to
600 voltage so
be aware of this if you want to try this
atom it's easy to be electroshocked
electrocute
so try to insulate it properly
the idea is to try to find the cheapest
way to mount fault electromagnetic fault
attacks
our target is the arduino mini it embeds
on a tmega
328 microprocessor
and it's an easy target
[Music]
and the the
tool
that we have conceived is based on a
disposable camera the circuit of the the
flash circuit of a disposable camera
the disposable camera is the informed ac
hp sync plus
so when you open the the camera what you
find inside is this
flash circuit which is capable to
transform the 1.5 volts of the battery
into
330 volts
if you look at this circuit basically
there's the pins of the battery
for the ground and the 1.5 volts a
switch to
let the flash light
and then
pins around the flash which holds 30
around 300 volts
it is possible to find online
some reverse engineering of such circuit
or similar circuits basically they are
almost all
the same
there's uh
on the hike part there's a transformer
which is used to transform the 1.5 to
300 volts
and then there's a big capacitor
of
in the middle of the of the circuit
which holds the charge in order to
discharge to the flash and make the
flash uh work
and finally there's a flash switch
which is used to
to activate the the light
the
this circuit
we have
make a few modifications by soldering or
disoldering something
that are really easy to do i'm not
i've not a degree in electronics
so even me can do this so i think
everybody can do such simple
modifications basically
i have removed the big capacitor in
order to not be
annoyed by
having to discharge it
it is not really necessary to perform
faults
then
shorted the big resistance in order to
get the 300 volt passing through
the coil and then
put a coil
instead of the flashlight
and the coil is basically an inductance
and it is used to create the
electromagnetic magnetic field to
fault the
target
so at the end
this is the the result
there's two pins that are powered with
three volts
a manual switch
on the
upper side
in order to create the current flow and
when the current flows through the
induction to the probe to the inductor
then
an electromagnetic field is created and
if it's sufficiently strong then
some force can be induced into the
transistors
so it's time
for a demonstration i hope that the
camera works
how to switch to the camera
okay
so
does this
works
do you hear me okay so i'm gonna
try to explain
how the target is coded while preparing
the
the demonstration
target
has a code inside that
upon
reset flashes
blink
fast
and then blink steadily
for
the rest of the time so
if you see when i reset
the target it blinks a little bit
and then blinks more steadily
okay
the
the tool is this one
maybe
okay so
this one you can see the switch here
and it's connected to two batteries
and when i approach
the tool to the target
you should see something different
happening the the blinking stopped
because something errands have happened
during the the program so i can try to
restart it so
it
flashes again if i try to
fold in another position
i can reset the target so luckily
i had no demo effect
so you can see that it's possible
to
get even from quite a distance i don't
know if we can
even from quite a distance it is
possible to
fault
the target
so okay this was for the demonstration
sorry
getting back to the slides
so this is the conclusion of the torque
the
purpose of this talk is to
yes
the purpose of this talk is to show that
fault attacks are a real threat
specifically specifically for customer
devices which are
barely or not at all protected from
hardware attacks
it can be easily mounted and is easily
exploited in the wild
there's no need for
large sum of money in order to start
parking with faults basically
the camera can be
retrieved from a shop
and even a disposed camera can be used
by uh getting the flash circuit out
nor you need deep knowledge
to uh create this it's easy to find some
the instruction
this the flesh circuit on the internet
and it's easy to disorder the two or
three small parts
also emfa is
easier than other
fault attack vectors because you don't
need to decap the target
it works also from a distance
as a show
and it's very effective also and is also
used against high security targets like
smart cards maybe not exactly this tool
but uh you can try to modify the tool to
make it uh
more powerful
another thing is is that not all fault
attacks concern crypto you don't need to
know cryptography in order to retrieve
the keys etc basically what we are doing
here is just disturbing corrupting the
flow of execution so it may be easy as
this
and
finally recycling is fun so this is one
opportunity to recycle some disposable
camera
if somebody is interested
next steps
would be to try to
make the the the remove the switch and
switch
the the circuit
by another arduino to control its timing
so if you are interesting we can talk
together
thank you very much if you have any
questions
[Applause]
is there any question from the audience
for alberto
how did you know what would have been
the effects
on the board when
you clicked the switch
so you can i cannot hear you
how did you know what would what would
have been the effects
on the board when you clicked the switch
for example when you blocked
the ladder when you reset the
switch
with this kind of tool you don't know
basically you try and
see what happened
the the the algorithm is sufficiently
simple that even
an uncontrolled fault can
make it behave differently from expected
i have tested with a little bit
more advanced
algorithm where a for loop
was incrementing a variable
and
there was an if statement where if the
variable reached a value which not
supposed to be reached inside the loop
then a pass then it passed and a
string was
printed and i was able to
make
the the algorithm step into this
[Music]
this
instruction so it's possible to
perform
something but it's not really well
controlled you know don't control the
timing or the power so it's difficult to
have a
a good control on what can happen
this is one of the reason why
some work can still be done to improve
this tool and make it more reliable
thank you alberto
for the nice talk and the
brave live demo