[Music]
so hello insomniac um happy to see so
many people in the room i think it's
because security folks love blockchain
right
uh
how many of you are running a blockchain
node or validator
not so many okay well i guess at least
you've heard of ethereum so as as you
can see i'm alone here my friend denise
could not make it because he he lives in
tomsk in siberia in russia and because
of the recent event he had to change his
plans and he could not be here today
um
so it's called hunting for bugs in
ethereum 2.0
but if you're following closely the
interim
news
you know that we should call it just
ethereum the term 2.0 is obsolete i will
explain why a bit later
and more specifically i will
talk of hunting bugs in ethereum clients
well
clients because as you will notice later
they're not only clients they're more
like servers but they're called clients
anyway
so the context of this work is um
uh
a grant from the eastern foundation that
we received jointly with uh denis
koligov and evangelia statopoulou from
university college london
uh we published a paper
in october that is quite long so i will
summarize it so that you don't have to
read the paper
so what is the room uh if you've lived
under a rock for the last three years
last five years it's a blockchain
platform so what is a blockchain
i'm not going to explain it
uh
it's kind of a database but
slower
and run by many sketchy people uh but
it's the future you know
and it's the the main domain uh
blockchain platform as opposed to the
main cryptocurrency which arguably is
bitcoin according to some metrics and
ethereum is the main platform that
people use to create their own tokens
such as es20 tokens but also use it to
create decentralized applications also
known as dapps
and one specific class of dapps is a dab
that serve for decentralized finance
applications so the
alternative to a centralized exchange
platform such as kraken
uh in defined markets it's a way to buy
and sell tokens
which may or may not have some value but
what do logic is run purely on chain via
smart contract i suppose um to a
centralized computer so in the
blockchain world centralize bad
decentralize good you don't need to
remember you don't need to think that
much
um and there's a big problem with
ethereum as you can see here people
started complaining because ethereum was
so successful
that it became quite slow
and inefficient so high gas fee so the
gas is the price you pay to
send your transaction
slow and congested a lot of transactions
fail and people lose money this is not
the future
traditional finance is probably laughing
at us
we need other blockchains
so ethereum needs to
do something to scale so
scale means being capable of managing
more transaction
and the problem is that to manage
transaction to process transactions you
need two things you need processing you
need computation and you need data why
computation because when you execute a
smart contract when you want to deploy
smart contract it has to be verified on
chain and verification usually happens
by recomputing
the program which is completely waste of
cpu because you have hundreds of
validators and for one single pro
program it has to be verified recomputed
by
tons of people
and the blockchain has a database also
has to source some data so the state the
arguments
the logic that has been executed
and so the more transactions
the more data and computation and at
some point you reach
the threshold when it's not manageable
and it's quite slow indeed 15
transactions per second the transaction
is not only a transfer of money it's any
change so remember it's a database so
the database a transaction is a change
of the state
or read a read operation
so it's leading to you know by simple
offering demand high gas fees
and by account to a content network and
people who are not really happy so you
see a comparison between
this big computer that a lot of people
are using distributed over many
computers
uh 600 000 additions per second and you
compare it to a small computer that only
one person wants to use
like raspberry pi like forty dollars
three billion additions per second yeah
that's the future
um so how to scale there's many two
classes of solutions the first one is
change the operating system so to speak
that's called layer one change the way
each theorem behaves
the second
way is what we call layer two change how
the application works or try to create
another network on top of ethereum so
that's what people call side chains
where you create your own separate
blockchain and from time to time you
commit your state into the main
blockchain
that's a poor simplification of how l2
protocols work but i think it described
the general id so today i will only talk
of
l1 layer 1 of ethereum and i will not
cover layer 2.
um
so the layer 1 approach to scale is
what includes different components
that's what used to be called ethereum
2.0 the first one is proof of stake
whereby instead of doing a lot of
computations like in a proof of work you
just take assets so you say oh i have a
lot of money so i have the right to do a
lot of things
and to be rewarded for it and data
shouting
is uh if you know database in your con
family or sharding sharing is just a way
to distribute the storage across
multiple components in a relatively
efficient way
and the main component to manage this
proof of stake and sharding mechanisms
is what they call the beacon chain
which was deployed in production in
december 2020 so what is the b condition
the beacon chain it's
a network of nodes technically
that maintain a state so remember it's a
database you maintain a state and it's
decentralized distributed so you need
multiple people who work to work
together and because they don't trust
each other you need some complex
consensus protocols to make sure that as
long as the majority is honest then the
state is safe so ethereum described the
beacon chain as
as follows imagine ethereum is a
spaceship it's not quite ready for the
interstellar voyage you know the
the thing big uh with a beacon chain the
community has built a new engine and a
hardened hull when it's time the current
ship will dock with this new system
merging into one ship ready to
light yours okay makes no sense
maybe in french it's clearer
it's the official interim page loose
sticking la mison jose missangel is the
french for proof of stake
discovered today like the deputy
what
changed the valley so they're a bit
confused they do use different
translations for beacon change and the
first and the bodies i don't know which
one you prefer but
so to run the beacon chain these know
they need to run some piece of software
it's called the beacon client or
consensus client but they actually mark
into to a server component which
confuses me at the beginning and still
today
so these are for one
a nimbus lighthouse thaku and prism
respectively
in nim the name language not the name
blockchain
lighthouse in rust teku in java and
prism in go
in terms of popularity so the main
metric to computer popularity is github
stars as everybody knows
so the most popular is prism
two thousand around two thousand stars
the night house one thousand
then uh the queen numbers are a bit
closer to three hundred that was yeah in
last september
in terms of usage prismary dominates you
know more than half of the nodes are
prison nodes
then lighthouse and the near tequila
number so you see this
kind of matches the github stars which
demonstrate that github stars is a good
indicator again um and no no surprise
here most of the nodes are in the united
states of america
so how what is a bitcoin client so again
it's not a client it's a server and it's
running two main services one called the
beacon node which is a kind of passive
service that is just looking at the
blockchain at the beacon chain
and that you can query to get value uh
to get information on on this beacon
chain uh you can ask the latest at a
station you can ask how the latest block
looks like this kind of thing the
validator is the most important
component is the one that is really
doing the work to actively maintain the
blockchain and the one where security
really matters because they are
checking that the blocks that are
submitted so block is essentially
a
proposal of a change to database to the
blockchain
and then you sign at the stations
let's say to say that okay from my
perspective i've done all the security
checks and this block fulfills all the
requirements and you cannot accept it
and we're going to only to accept this
one because you cannot accept two blocks
at the same time
so
this introduces some new components
because the beacon chain is quite
different from the non-beacon chain
so first of all a new type of
cryptographic signatures bls
slashing a punishing mechanism that i
will not discuss because of time
constraints and because we didn't find
bug in it and an api and also a
peer-to-peer peer-to-peer layer
okay is the sound okay do you hear me in
the back of the room
okay
our methodology is very deep and
scientific
well
we're lazy like everyone so we look at
the code we try to find bugs and the
easiest way to find bugs is to compare
the specs with the code you know rocket
science and even easier to compare
implementations of the same thing
so even if you don't understand anything
you compare the code of two different
clients you don't know what they're
doing but they do the same thing
differently then you ask yourself why
why did do these operations in different
order
why they have different parameters and
maybe that's a bug
maybe not so that's essentially what
what we did um
yeah
okay so first bl signatures
uh maybe you're familiar with you know
ecd say in particular dss signatures or
ed25519 all these elliptic curve digital
signatures so we're talking about
asymmetric public signatures not max
they're quite complex you look at each
dsa it's very complex you take you pick
a random value you have to do a lot of
checks modular inverse
division multiplication addition all the
possible math operations
to sign and your signature is not one
value but two values
so here with builder signatures it's
much easier you have your message that
you want to
to sign
you hash it
and you do one multiplication with a
secret key and that's it
so technically this is a point it's not
a hash function like black two it's a
hash to curve hash function whereby you
hash a piece of data
onto an elliptic curve so the result is
not a string it's a point on the curve
um
and the secret key is a number a scalar
so crypto people say scalar because it
sounds more serious than a number
who's calling me no i'm giving a talk
sorry
um okay so what can go wrong here look
at this this line
can you imagine what could be the
problem
yeah i'm hearing the google response so
the first thing you learn in security is
validate your input
and reject bad inputs so what could be a
bad input here it would be
the zero value here so typically you
receive either the message or the hash
of the message in your api and if this
value is zero so zero multiplied by
anything is zero um so it means that you
would get the same signature regardless
of the value of the secret key which
means that you could forge a signature
of a message without knowing the secret
key i mean it sounds very stupid but
this zero bug was present in many
implementations
and
someone wrote a paper called xero
which is annoying when you want to
google for the paper you google zero
and then he did another paper called
double zero because he found other bugs
based on this
so
this zeroness issue is uh one specific
instance of a class of invalid
uh values that you may receive
and you have some um
so this is the soda code in the
ietfdraft that describe the core verify
function
the they coverify procedures to verify
signature and you have these two routine
signature
check except group checks so you check
that
your point is in the right subgroup
of the
group of points and you validate the key
so here several things can go wrong
maybe you can just you know forget to do
this all together one of the two or
maybe you have a function that is doing
it but it's doing it incorrectly or
maybe it's doing it correctly but you
don't check the result correctly or
maybe you check the result but then you
do the bad thing
a lot of things can go wrong here
likewise here you look at the specs
and you look at this
like the offshore reference and you say
if one thing is wrong written invalid
invalid invalid invalid and if you see
the return value you know that it's
failed you don't know why so just you
see an invalid but what most
implementations would do
uh they would written an error message
or an or code that would be specific to
the error which gives you more
information
on about what happened internally which
might potentially be used as an oracle
to determine
what happens inside
so i'm trying to give you know some
examples of
cryptographic protocol failures
so i'm not going to give details of the
bugs but it's this kind of bug that we
found and we found 90 19
90 of these bugs across all the four
projects and also in the specifications
of ethereum 2.0 so none of these were
already
exploitable in the sense that you could
steal money for free
well otherwise we would have reported it
of course
but um just happened not to find such
bugs
so we reported the bugs and what's funny
in the blockchain space oftentimes
well some projects do have a security
contact but uh some people just report
stuff in the github issues so yesterday
somebody told me the case of a guy who
reported a bug in the github issue of a
project and say oh critical bug you can
steal minutes worth of money with this
bug and the guy was so nice and he even
included a poc
so
and what somebody told him what the
you're doing and he removed it but uh
some people do not think so much
next up the peer-to-peer layer so what's
great with blockchain people is that
they're very smart well some of them not
all of them
they have a lot of money a lot of time
so what do you do when you have all this
you're in advanced things you do
using so they're invented peer-to-peer
secure transport protocols
and they encrypt connections between
different validators so why encrypting
things
because you want security so you need to
encrypt but it's not just about
plaintext cipher attacks it's also about
authentication to how to authenticate
your parties how to authenticate to
other parties confidentiality makes top
secret integrity make sure that stuff
hasn't been modified uh non-reputation
uh making sure that if you sign
something well no one else can sign
stuff on your behalf or can modify what
you signed
uh and a few other things i don't know
if they mention it yeah perfect for our
secrecy uh and non-replay be
non-replayability on t replay
okay so we looked at the p2p protocol
implementation and we tried to see if
these were satisfied uh spoiler not all
of them
um so what do they use for peer-to-peer
they use lip p2p which was uh designed
similarly by protocol labs for the ipfs
so interplanetary file system
protocol which is really cool
cryptographically
i don't know how useful it is but
cryptographically it's fantastic they do
proof of space proof of space time
it's like magic
and limp b2p is not just one library
it's not just one protocol it's a suite
of protocols for sexual transport mixer
discovery peer routing a lot of things
that you have uh listed here
and it's called the de facto web stream
networking layer and i think it's a fair
description
so what is the p2p again is the suite of
protocols lib b2p dash noise is
one secure transport so think of it as
kind of secure tunnel that's a kind of
wear regard or ipsec
and this one is using the noise
protocol framework
and in a noise protocol framework you
have multiple flavors of noise multiples
away multiple ways of doing a handshake
uh so it's a handshake is when you
initialize a cryptographic session a
cryptographic
tunnel between two parties
or more and noise xx double x or 20 i
don't know how to spell it is a specific
version that happens to be used in
israel
okay so here's jessica and morty they
want to communicate well morty wants to
communicate with jessica but in this
case she initiates the session
so you have three types of keys
the ephemeral key
with the suffix e here so ephemeral
means that it's short-lived
just for the sake of this specific
session
you have the static keys
some that which are here so each party
knows the static key of the order
they're more like long-term keys
so in the noise
framework the static keys are really
long term long long long term keys but
in the world of ethereum
they're more like midterm keys because
you have another layer of keys called
the identity key which is your key that
never changes
and when you want to issue a new static
key you sign
the static key with your identity key
and hopefully people will verify this
hopefully so what happens in noise i
don't have too much time but
it all goes as follow you send an fml
key
then
marty is
picking a new pair of emerald keys he's
doing different operations between a
combination of jessica's public key and
his secret ephemeral key his secret
static key then he sends his fml public
key and the encryption of
his
static public key you might ask why
why because he can
and he can with what
with the
dh1 here so each stuff that you send
here is encrypted with the key that you
can generate uh
with what you have
and then he does she does the same you
don't need to understand what happens
you just need to see that a lot of
crypto is happening here so three
different operations the h1 the actually
s3 the dhquan here is the same as the h1
there
and so on for the rest and at the end
they have 3d h values and they derive a
symmetrically from it and they can
encrypt stuff
with that so ultimately they both
authenticate to each other using all
these keys so a lot of keys of crypto
too much crypto maybe i don't know
what can go wrong here if you
assign your
new static keys with an identity key
what kind of attack can you do
you have a secure signature scheme you
have secure keys
and you just take the key and sign it
and send it
no idea
sorry
yes
yes uh yes but yeah you they know your
identity key and you want to say
uh okay i have a new static key here
signature of it
so the the risk is replay replay attack
because it's not bound to the session
there's no counter so you can take a
previous signature a previous public key
so the public key is public it's not
secret so you can take the public key
you can take the signature which is also
public and
use it again on behalf of the person so
you don't know the secret key you will
not be able to initiate the session
but it will force the other parties to
erase the other public key and it it's
kind of a dos vector
so how to fix it you can just sign
instead of just the key sign x
the key and some value that is
unpredictable to not occur it can be a
random value a random challenge it can
be a harsher decision transcript
anything that the attacker cannot um
cannot predict
another attack vector is the following
so here
what can you exploit if you're an
attacker
in this part of the protocol so jessica
is sending her public key and morty is
doing some crypto computations
so it's again a dos vector because
you send many public keys and you will
force
morty to do one two three cryptographic
operations so two exponentiations and
one key generation and if you send
thousands or more public keys then uh
he will use a lot of cpu so how can you
fix this so if you look at um
so it's it's mostly for udp in this case
we're working with tcp so it's less
relevant but if you look at dtls at
ipsec or udp or wireguard they have some
trick to prevent this so what where
guard is doing is using what they call
session cookies if they see too many
public keys coming in they will say wait
hold on uh
take this challenge and sign it for me
when you send your next public key and
if you sign it correctly i will accept
the session
uh so it's kind of a trick to prevent um
this kind of dos so it's kind of you
know right limiting whereby the receiver
receives
refuses to processes the public keys
if they receive too many of them okay
so one bug that we found
is a simple integer overflow
in the javascript or typescript library
and when we traced it back
we traced it back to the go version and
this go version we did some advanced
forensics and we found that it came from
the noise explorer framework which
generates automatically some
implementations of um
of noise
um and here the problem is um
you know the non-reuse problem in crypto
if you use twice the same notes with
asgcm or stream cipher then
you can potentially decrypt for free the
plaintext so here's exactly what
happened the nonce was only 64 bit it
was incremented but then if you reach
the maximum it would wrap around and
repeat again the previous values
whereas the spec says that you should
not do it because it's bad
and it was not
done in the in the code so
they fixed it like this and now it's uh
now it works
uh this one was from a few days ago and
it's not our bug um
quite a shame that we missed it
by the way but it's because we we suck
at uh at javascript
so it's much more serious than mine in
the middle whereby
uh the signature verification can be
completely bypassed so before i describe
a replay attack here it's even worse and
not just replay it's a full money in the
middle why because of some
specificity of typescript
it doesn't complain about
this i don't know what it means in
javascript it's some
some promise issue
but it looks apparently quite
non-trivial to to spot
and well the upshot is that the
signature verification was not checked
it was accepted even when it was not
valid
which is not
not good
okay now let's go to the api so the api
it's a standard um
send out um http rest or rpc and grpc
underhood the usual stuff
and we since it's the usual stuff we
found the usual bugs
so
the spec is saying something about how
to process not to process the http
headers and most of the clients who are
doing this wrong
like
not looking at the headers or accepting
invalid headers this kind of thing they
will not validate the json schema they
will accept invalid fields in the json
schema this kind of thing
sometimes the api would be publicly
exposed whereas it should be
authenticated
we even found some authentication tokens
written in the logs as a convenient way
to access the tokens but i don't
recommend this um
the logs are not secret in general it
depends
also some requests that were possible
without an api token and some dos
vectors whereby you send some parameters
you send like you know 10 bytes and you
receive 100 bytes so this kind of
uh device vector
uh last part the supply chain risks
so
as you know most of the modern software
projects have maybe eighty percent of
their code written by other people
because they come from dependencies or
packages and it's very convenient
because you just need to
call someone else's package you don't
have to write it yourself
but the flip side is that you depend a
lot on
these other people and their code and
their security and maybe you have very
good sdlc pipeline and ci and
you know all the tools you want to have
the linters and that's but these guys
you don't know what they do you don't
even know if they maintain their code at
all
so there's the risk of active sabotage
malicious sabotage it's happened in the
past
your back doors or bug doors or possible
deniability
it can be a version management nightmare
because let's say
you find
this direct dependency that is outdated
you say oh i will update it in my
cargo or
go mod or whatever
npm stuff is using but then you discover
that one of your dependencies is using a
dependency that is using a dependency
that is using a dependency that is using
the audited version of that one and it
happens to have a vulnerability
and even if you have the latest version
of the first equal dependency
if this guide did not you know update
all the dependencies then there's not
much you can do
um
to accept the risks so to speak
uh another point in an enterprise
context can be
quite annoying is the copyright and
licensing issues uh if you have some gpl
dependency buried in your dependency
graph uh
it might bite you at some point so the
good thing is that the last two or three
years there has been a lot of great
tooling develop for example in npm you
might know the npm audit
command in rust the cargo audit cargo
outdated cargo geiger all these
fantastic tools goes catching up as well
and it helps you to identify easily uh
the problems and there are some other
platforms in go and github also you know
depend about all these cool tools
so
i'm quite happy with this making our
life easier but we wanted to have some
let's say some indicators some metrics
of the risk
for these four clients so we started
looking at the prism and go so that's an
excerpt of the dependency graph
so can you see how many dependencies
there are here
403 in rust it's even more artistic
so just a small part you know
so how many
dependencies in lighthouse there were
121 direct dependencies
but 440 in total when you include all
the transitive dependencies
and prism 93 direct but 665
uh in total so it's quite a lot
um so we try to enumerate the audited
version and variable versions but these
numbers are not always meaningful
because i know that some projects they
just update the dependencies
when they're going to release a new
version
so i don't think you should draw any
conclusions from the audited version and
vulnerable versions here because each
protocol has their own
release process and an update management
process
uh so we we tried to find some metrics
that were meaningful for all the
languages
uh that were that made some sense in
terms of in terms of risk
um so i don't know if they are good but
that's the the best the best we have we
also try to see the number of cvs so cv
is the well you probably know what the
cv is anyway
and in java or surprise a lot of cvs in
java you don't know it might be because
in the java ecosystem people prefer to
report cvs
in in rust there is another database for
vulnerabilities and maybe people are
less interested in cvs
you don't know there are a lot of hidden
biases here
also what is also hard to find is a more
qualitative metrics uh in terms of
which dependencies you use
and
you have a little time so i will talk
about this uh initially we were like
okay
let's focus on the critical dependencies
which are the critical ones
the ones that do crypto operations they
want to do security they are critical
but then we realize wait hold on
any dependency is code that you're
running
so if i were to back door project i
would not target the critical one i
would target
the one that people would not look at
the one is changing the color of the
buttons the one that is just you know
doing some unicode
whatever or if i'm even more evil i
would take some dependencies that many
projects are using
um
see it was very hard to
to think in terms of okay which
dependencies should we look at
because we cannot look at 100 projects
and manually
see if they are done by reputable people
if they have a good
set of unit tests of sdlc um
so
yeah
we didn't
we
we gave more questions and answers to be
hardest
but
my conclusion of this
in terms of language
in terms of security lighthouse is doing
a much better job because they have
fuzzing in their ci pipeline
they do things pretty well they have a
lot of
you know linting static analysis
and
as far as i can tell
they have pretty smart developers uh the
other ones are a bit
less advanced as far as i could see in
security but
you know any project can have scary bugs
even if you have the best people on
earth
so to conclude uh again we did not find
high severity or critical bugs
um we did not three surprises because
there was really huge amount of
you know
cleanup done before we came
all the project has been well audited
by
the usual suspect companies
uh there's been some fuzzing done
fuzzing of the interfaces fuzzing of the
state machine
a lot of testing
um
so yeah and they're doing their best
but as you know if you have a complex
system a new system a lot of code is the
recipe for many bugs
and especially in the context of
blockchain or it's decentralized
distributed and you have bugs that you
can only identify when you're running
this in a production-like setting where
you have multiple meshing
interacting in this asynchronous
context
and you hit some edge case that you
could not anticipate just by looking at
the code
and that's what scares me a bit and
that's how many people discovered some
bugs they were like oh
our testing is stuck why and it takes
them hours or days to investigate until
they find a bug
but yeah that's
you know the proof is on the putting at
the end of the day because if your
blockchain is running and if people can
make millions
if they if they break it and if it's not
broken
then it means that your security is at
least i know five ten million dollars
you know
so i think that's a good way to tourism
uh
but at the same time there's a some high
incentives if you find a critical bug
and if you're a bit you know
evil you may not want to disclose it
because you can say okay i can make
ten thousand from the back bounty it's
clean money but i can make one million
by exporting it but it's dirty money how
does it cost to
launder the money and that's really how
people reason
about this
so what's the best client which one to
choose that's what people ask us we have
no idea but the difference is that
lighthouse as i said is the most focused
on security in terms of performance you
know cpu
disk usage is quite good but prism
happens to be the most popular so maybe
because go is easier to use i don't know
nimbus is designed to be lighter i don't
know if it's runs a smartphone probably
not but it's quite lighter and teku is
more enterprise oriented they have some
commercial support if you if you need
that
it's probably good to have some level of
diversity of clients because if you have
only one single big client and if you
have a bug in it then all the clients
are down
but you can argue that if you have many
more clients you have much more bugs
much more bugs to exploit so you need to
find the right the right balance
so
last but not least the question when
will ethereum 2 will israel 2 be
available
i have no idea and
so what uh eachium is saying they say a
date has not been set as of the
publication of this boss which was 14th
of march
any source claiming otherwise is likely
to be a scam
updates will be posted on this blog
please stay safe
and funny i looked at the french version
did they say the same thing
the merge is when you merge the proof of
stake world with the main network of
ethereum
it always sounds smarter when you read
french you know
i love this
and you know how to say i
have a few minutes we're in a call with
a client my company a french bank and i
say
come
okay so
i hope you have fun
good
proof
thank you
[Applause]
thank you very much jb
i know you have a train to catch and you
need to run so do you have a time the
time for a few questions yeah i can take
a few questions okay if you have any
questions please raise your hand so i
can bring the microphone to you
[Music]
uh so thanks for the talk
i have a question about the denial of
service defense
because
even if the
the defender
asks that the attacker to to sign
something for him to verify that it's a
legitimate request then you still need
to verify the signature and that it
feels like it would take a similar
amount of time to actually performing
the step of the protocol
um
i for the dos vector uh where it's a
multiple public keys yeah but in that
case you also force the attacker to do
many computations
and they would do the same kind of
competition if they design it with a mac
it's the same amount of cpu on the
attacker's side and on the victim side
but uh they can send a bogus signature
and what happens then you just
disconnect and oh yeah again so yeah i
think there's a yeah a good point it
doesn't make anything whereby if they
send too many inverted signatures you
just reject everything for some some
period
i think you might want to check the
where i got implementation
i think they have quite a clever version
of this
okay thanks
[Music]
hi
um you mentioned that they are
in the original protocol there's an
option for replay attack
when sending a key update
and you propose to include a random
value that's not predictable by an
attacker
what about using a sequence number so
that you can check if it's a new one
instead of an old one
yeah that would also work but then you
need um
so either you transmit the sequence
number with the value
but the other party needs to be
synchronized with the same sequence
number
um and the problem is that if you miss
some message
okay
you send the the two the three
you receive the twitter three you don't
receive the four and suddenly you
receive the five you're like okay did i
miss a message
so you need both parties to maintain a
counter
and
it gets more complicated
so typically it's better to be stateless
uh in order to avoid having uh to
maintain a short state
all right any other question
[Music]
hi thank you
next talk
so i have a question um
what is the idea behind uh
catching denial of services when you
control
uh like the beacon uh infrastructure
because
when they deployed proof-of-stake
basically they are not able
uh
to to stop people to actually take over
to the
to the network so i mean denial of
service is just you are attacking a
service but you can actually
go and do
a kind of transaction hijacking by
controlling the bitcoin servers you know
yeah i think the expression scenarios
are non-trivial but
what i didn't mention is that
there's also a service called the
slasher service
where somebody letters are trying to
detect invalid transaction when someone
is cheating so being able to deal some
of the notes
might help when having a collision of
attackers and you want to prevent some
not
from reporting
a faulty and invalid
transaction
or you want to have an edge
for example if you want to exploit um
you know
now if you're familiar with mev attacks
where you try to exploit the early
knowledge of the next transactions and
you want to force one transaction to
come before another and you colored with
other parties
uh so especially since there are there
are not that many validators well still
but i guess you would prevent isolation
of some the eclipse in attack you would
prevent it you know
i mean otherwise uh
the beacon network wouldn't exist yeah
so yeah that's the point to have a
highly connected network uh yeah but my
question i mean
like the latent question is who is the
owner of this network is is really
decentralized but in the end because you
have this infrastructure which is like
24 7.
supposed to be decentralized and i think
that they try to have uh
knowledge validators maintained by
different people different organizations
in different countries
um
from my perspective it's a fair level of
decentralization at this point and even
better than in some other blockchains
where you have
big pools of proof-of-work
whereas here it's um
well to my taste a bit more
decentralized i will not give names of
blockchains but
all right thank you any other question
okay so we finished a little bit earlier
we have like a little bit less than 20
minutes so if you guys want to take a
break
and the next
the next talk starts at five thanks