[Music]
okay let's go
my name is andy robbins thank you lam
for the kind introduction i'm the
co-creator of a tool called bloodhound
this is the logo for it
i am now the product architect for the
commercial version of that software
called bloodhound enterprise
i work at a company that's called
spectre ops like elan mentioned
and on twitter you can find me at
underscore waldo with a zero
here is our agenda for the talk
first why abuses and not bugs then we'll
do a crash course through the basics
and to explain my own
abuse research methodology we'll look at
a case study of some research that i did
recently regarding the ms graph api
i'll share some ideas about where you
can find research opportunities for
yourself
and then a conclusion at the end so why
abuses and not bugs
in looking at the
talks for this conference there are a
lot of like very low level very
technical like let's find bugs in
android or let's find bugs in arm or
let's find bugs and some other kind of
software
our team and our company generally
focuses more on abuses rather than bugs
and there are a few reasons why
first generally
abuses compared to bugs enjoy a
dramatically longer shelf life
exec has been around for 20 years and
adversaries still use it very reliably
every hour of every day
ms-08067
not so much eternal blue not so much
obviously they're still there but the
abuse primitives are generally way more
reliable than bugs
over time they are also much cheaper to
maintain
like i said p.s exec thank you mark
rusinovic for that it's very stable it
works you don't really have to patch it
to be able to target a different windows
operating system version like you do
with like mso8067 for example so
maintaining abuses over time is very
easy and cheap
the abusable configurations or
circumstances generally exist in every
single instance of that platform that
you're doing your research against
so
who has seen someone have local admin in
active directory when that user
shouldn't have had it everyone
who has seen ms-08067 in the past 12
months
maybe some of us yeah maybe depends on
where you go
finally on the detection front
abuses present a notorious challenge for
detection engineers it is
extraordinarily difficult to tell the
difference between legitimate usage of
an administrative protocol and
illegitimate usage of an administrative
protocol especially when it's the same
user to the same system it's extremely
difficult to see the difference as a
detect as a detection engineer
if you don't believe me believe the
gruck he said give a man an o day and
he'll have access for a day teach a man
to fish and he'll have access for life
if you don't believe the gruck believe
matt graber he says a sufficiently
advanced threat actor is
indistinguishable from a competent
system administrator
so for these reasons these are why we
focus more on abuses and discovering
what those abuse primitives are rather
than bugs if you want to find bugs and
get a bug bounty more power to you i
go with god uh
but you know here we're talking about
abuses
so let's go through a very quick crash
course of the basics
uh maybe just by a show of hands who has
worked with azure before
maybe half yeah okay and of those who
have worked against the microsoft graph
api
about half of that half okay great
so for the rest of us i'm going to
explain some of the very very basic
concepts of azure so that we're all
speaking the same language
first of all what exactly is azure
azure depending on who you ask can be
different things so
my definition is i say that azure is the
all-encompassing suite of services that
comprise microsoft's cloud computing
services and platform and product so
when i say azure i basically just mean
microsoft cloud computing as it is
distinct from aws or gcp
azure itself is actually comprised of
more than 600 distinct services that
cover all kinds of
services identity compute storage data
management devops iot you name it if you
can do it with a computer you can
probably do it with azure
there is a very specific
uh okay that stopped working
oh no no yes no yes okay we're back
there's a no
yes yes no
yes
no
i can just project as well
is that okay for the video
for the video recording is that okay all
right i'm just gonna project
so there is a very specific securable
object hierarchy in azure regardless of
what service you are using if you're
using m365
if you're using azure ad if you're using
azure rm
the same hierarchy will apply
so whatever you're doing the very top
level object is called a tenant this is
equivalent to
an on-prem active directory domain head
and so the tenant controls what is known
as a trust boundary anything under the
tenant anybody with control of that
tenant has control of everything within
that tenant
directly under a tenant you have
different object types you have app
registration objects
service principles
devices which can be windows linux
whatever
security groups and users
if you want to actually do any kind of
compute with azure like you want to
stand up a virtual machine or you want
to have a key vault or something like
that you have to start using azure rm or
azure resource manager which is also
something that people just call azure
now
that hierarchy
can try this one
okay hello all right how's that is that
can you hear me in the back good okay
great
so if you are going to have compute
resources uh managed under an azure
tenant
then that hari that hierarchy starts
with what is called a route management
group
this is a management group and under
that management group you can have one
or more management groups
under that management group you can have
one or more management groups or none
under a management group and that can
nest
i don't know forever maybe or maybe up
to 255 nestings i don't know
under a management group you have what
is called a subscription
under a subscription you have what are
called resource groups
and under resource groups you have the
actual
resources and so for example a virtual
machine a key vault a database or a blob
authentication can be done using either
a service principle
or a user the service principle is just
as good as a user maybe actually even
better than a user
when you authenticate to a service in
azure there is a token issuance uh step
by step that happens
so our principal there on the left that
can be a user or a service principal
will authenticate via the security token
service
to the service that it wants to act
against
uh and so for example this principle is
authenticating against the azure ad
directory
service but as you're doing this
authentication you can also specify an
audience for the resultant token that
you get which i'll show on the next
slide
and that token that you get back will
specify in this example that
we want to access something via the ms
graph resource app
whatever resource it is that you're
accessing the principle because its
identity is controlled by azure ad
it will be authenticated by azure ad
specifically by your tenant
when you get a token back you get what's
called a jwt or some people refer to
this as a jot
and some relevant things that are in the
jot which is base64 but you can decode
it very easily the audience there we
have it the graph and roles just as a
quick example it will list out what
roles that principle has for that
specific audience and in this example we
have this
approachassignment.readwrite.all
and i'll explain what that means later
so what about access control or
authorization
this is where things get extremely
complex in azure
so different objects at different scopes
are controlled in different ways
for example the objects that are
directly under a tenant
can be controlled by azure ad admin
roles
ms graph api permissions the legacy
azure ad api permissions
object scoped admin roles
and the objects that are highlighted in
blue can also have one or more or none
explicit owners of their object
so there are already five different
distinct
access control mechanisms just for this
scope of objects here
in azure rm
you also have azure admin roles which
are not azure ad admin roles
are you confused yet i was
uh for blobs there's also uh abac uh
access
i'm sorry
attribute based access control
and then certain objects like key vaults
have their own permissions model
specific to that object
how much fun is that
like if you're an admin and you're
trying to determine who has control of
any of these objects you have to have a
perfect understanding of all these
different access control mechanisms
and of course there is no one click in
azure to see the effective permissions
against any of these objects that would
make way too much sense
[Music]
additionally
azure has the concept of permissions
inheritance
so if i describe a permission against my
root management group for example
that privilege will inherit down
to every object under that root
management group
admins cannot change this behavior
or if i sp if i set a permission at a
subscription level that also will
inherit down
to all of those descendant objects
the same is true at the tenant level if
i specify a permission at the tenant
level that will inherit down
not only
to all of the objects directly under the
tenant
but also all objects
that have a trust relationship through a
subscription
to the tenant
okay
let's go through a case study of
what my methodology was for
discovering the abuse primitives that
are possible through the ms graph api in
particular
i heard about the ms graph api from a
co-worker daniel heinsohn
also known as hotknops on twitter
and basically he told me hey this looks
like a pretty cool thing maybe there's
something interesting in it why don't
you take a look here's what i know about
it so far
and that was about it i didn't have any
kind of administrative uh
uh experience with ms graf so it's not
as if i was an admin of it for two years
and knew it very intimately
uh but that's okay like you can do these
abuse primitive researches against
technologies that you don't have
experience with
and this is how i do it this is how i
did it for ms graph
at a high level i'll start with
what the entire methodology is and then
we'll dig into each step
first i try to begin with the end in
mind
then study the intent and the design of
the system
explore the system using various means
and from various perspectives
catalog the actual abuse capabilities
that are exposed by the system
and then share findings and so these
steps comprise my own abuse primitive
research process
and we will start by looking at the
beginning
uh which is to begin with the end in
mind
essentially in this step
there are several things that i want to
lay out to basically establish success
criteria for myself
that you know did i succeed in this
abuse primitive research
process or not
and so i start by
you know laying out what i want to
understand i want to understand the
fundamental mechanics of the system how
it works behind the scenes
i want to understand how it interacts
with other existing systems that i
already know about or discover new
systems that it interacts with to have
as future research
and obviously i want to know how the
system can be abused
i want to produce a blog or a talk for
others to be able to understand what i
have learned so that others can build on
top of that
for defenders i want to be able to
produce example audit code so that they
can
audit for these dangerous configurations
themselves and i also want to produce
example abuse code so that people can
prove that these configurations actually
are abusable easily
i also want to produce practical
remediation guidance especially for
defenders
so that if they find something in their
audit they know what to do about it and
it's something that is practical and
doesn't require like a p5 license to do
or
just you know giving microsoft more
money
and because i'm a product architect for
bloodhound enterprise and also for the
free version of bloodhound
for me i want to know what is the impact
on my existing graph model going to be
because i don't want the performance of
my graph to degrade because i extended
the design of the graph in a way that i
didn't anticipate that kind of
degradation for
i want to know how to expand the graph
model
and i want to know what data do i need
to collect
how do i collect it where are those
objects and then how do i ingest that
into the bloodhound database
so the end result of that very basic
first step which is basic but critical
is that i've established success
criteria for this research
this is more important than it might
sound because if you dive into abuse
primitive research without this kind of
in goal in mind uh that's for me at
least a way to rabbit hole into several
different things get distracted lose
focus and basically produce nothing of
value
the next step for me is to study the
intent the design and the usage of the
system i don't have
first-person administrative experience
with this system but i can glean that
experience from others who are involved
in the architecture and design of the
system
and also the people who administer the
system as well
there are a few different resources for
doing this i always start with the
official documentation both technical
and non-technical what does that mean it
means a lot of this
and so in
after my conversation with my colleague
literally my first google search would
have been microsoft ms graph what is
that i don't know
so
you google that you'll find the
microsoft documentation for microsoft
graph
and
this documentation is not written for
somebody who's trying to figure out how
to abuse the system obviously
it is written for
somebody who's more of an admin or maybe
somebody who's a decision maker and
they're trying to decide between aws and
azure it depends the documentation of
microsoft is all over the place
so one of the interesting things on
their documentation is what can you do
with microsoft graph
and going through this eventually you'll
find that there's a use case they
describe for a help desk person being
able to reset somebody else's password
okay that's kind of interesting from an
abuse perspective
so let me google that ms graph reset
user
password and i'll find this
so there is a method in the microsoft
graph rest api called
password authentication method reset
password
what's more interesting on this page is
if you scroll down
it starts to describe the permissions
that are required in order to do this
so
if microsoft graph is going to allow you
or not to reset someone's password it
does this assessment of the privileges
that you hold
so now i can start to understand that
there is a distinct permissions model
distinct from the azure ad admin roles
that i need to understand
and so back to google
ms graf permissions
and you have a nice
permissions reference page
on the official microsoft site
what
this documentation covers
is basically the names of the
permissions and then a very basic human
readable explanation of what that
permission is
but
they don't tell you how the permission
model works behind the scenes
so
we'll talk about that later
so maybe my initial notes at this point
might be something like this ms graph is
some kind of azure related service
it exposes a rest api
it can let you reset someone else's
password if you have the correct
permissions
and it seems like it has a distinct
permission system from azure id and
azure rm
okay so some decent initial notes
next though i need to get that kind of
uh second hand perspective from people
who have been working with the system
for a long time
and try to make their experience my own
as best i can so through those people i
will find
code repositories blogs and talks that
other people have done on this topic
one of the most reliable
uh methods for me
is to look at the people at microsoft
who are responsible for this system
so if i look for
an architect for microsoft graph on
linkedin
there's actually
maybe more results than you would expect
uh and you can start to look through
these people's profiles you can find
their twitter profiles
this is very similar to just doing like
basic open source intelligence gathering
is
but instead of finding a
person to attack you're fight you're
trying to find a person to learn from
helpful person here is daryl miller
so he's actually the api architect for
microsoft graph
and
just scrolling through
his twitter feed
very very quickly you can find
good resources that he has retweeted or
that he has written himself
and so
this is a great example of a powershell
deep dive into the graph api i
personally love using powershell so for
me this is very relevant to try to
understand
how do i interface with the system
uh how do i communicate with the system
and then additionally there's like great
write-ups you can find like this
30 days of microsoft graph blog series
that goes into all kinds of very
technical things
and then i'll also look at talks and
spend
maybe 12
to 24 hours just watching talks
talks are very good usually people are a
little bit looser than they are in
writing and they usually give up some
more detail than they typically would
otherwise so you can find really good
nuggets watching people's talks on this
topic
finally
i'll look for community resources
this is extremely helpful
because
while the microsoft people are a little
more cagey about some of the bad details
about
any of their products
the community
is very very open and very loud about
those issues
and finding those issues means that you
can find
bugs and you can find abuses
so
a really good example is on the
powershell sdk github repo
there are hundreds and hundreds and
hundreds of issues uh both open and
closed where you can find all kinds of
conversations and this is where you can
just easily find something like
well this interface doesn't support mfa
okay that's very interesting
or
this
permission which says it needs a human
to approve
uh actually it doesn't so that's also
very interesting for
a red teamer or somebody trying to abuse
this system
after going through all this my abuse
notes or my initial notes look like this
and then my updated notes might look
something like this
microsoft graph microsoft is investing
into ms graph as a sort of api for apis
a unifying endpoint that may eventually
allow for indirectly interacting with
any object in any service just by
interfacing with ms graph so that kind
of consolidation strategy from microsoft
to me means that it is worth investing
time into learning this system
ms graf's rest api is instantiated into
every azure tenant as a resource app aka
enterprise app aka service principle aka
first party app there's a lot of very
confusing language a lot of like these
different phrases mean the exact same
thing
but
this
fact that the ms graph is available in
every tenant means that it is ubiquitous
so no matter what organization i'm
trying to target if they use azure they
use ms graph and so that ubiquity means
that i can apply the same tradecraft
that i learn here to anywhere
ms graph brokers request a particular
azure services including privileged
action requests like resetting passwords
or adding users to security groups okay
great
so at the end of that phase the basic
success criteria for that phase is to
have built some foundational
academic knowledge i haven't done
anything practical at this point of just
basically
reading and listening and looking at
talks and just taking everything in that
i can
to have this very academic high level
knowledge
which of course brings us to the next
step which is to start actually
interacting with the system
and start exploring it in various ways
i think it's actually very important to
have built an academic knowledge base
before going into the technical details
of a system
because without that context of the
intent and the design and the usage of
the system
you're basically just spelunking into a
cave of
a technical system that you don't
really know why it exists
and so for me that's a way to just waste
a lot of time
to that end you must go beyond the
documentation
in particular with uh let's say cloud
products
these systems they are interconnected
and they behave
in undocumented and non-public ways
the documentation if you have ever read
the microsoft documentation you know
this is true that often it doesn't keep
up with changes to the system and it
quickly goes out of date
if you make tooling based only on
documentation i can almost guarantee you
that it will be on inaccurate and
unreliable
so what do we do in this phase
for me the easiest way to start
exploring a system is to use the easiest
administrative interface for that system
for the ms graph api that means using
the azure portal gui
so i'm not going to go into too much
detail about
how that works in the gui
but
one thing that is extremely useful
when you are using the azure portal and
if you're
if you're going to get into azure
research this is something that you'll
want to know
uh this is the chrome browser that i'm
looking at the azure portal gui with and
if you bring up the developer tools you
can see all of the different requests
that the browser is making to that api
the azure portal gui
is actually primarily api driven there
there are some services that use like
the javascript modules that are loaded
to
interface with services but for the most
part
the
things that you click in the gui they
are doing an api request through the
browser
so you can see here
what did i click i clicked on
getting my user object here
and so in the developer tools you can
see that there is a get request to
graph.microsoft.com v10 users slash my
user id
what is very useful here is not only can
you see the uri that is handling the
request and you can see the response in
json format
but you can very easily get free
api interaction code from the browser by
right clicking on the request
go to copy copy as powershell
paste that into something and you have
a pretty decent minimal client for
interfacing with the ms graph api
you do have to make a change of this you
have to get rid of that referrer line at
the bottom or else it won't it won't do
the request otherwise you've got
everything you need to start a very very
basic client
we can copy and paste that into
powershell
and the request there is at the bottom
status code 200 okay and then we have
the
uh the raw object that represents the
user and you can see that it's json
formatted obviously this is good for us
because programmatically it's very easy
to manipulate and work with json objects
what i also like to do is look at the ms
authored cli tools
so
for azure in particular this can mean
the az binary
the azure ad powershell module and the
az
powershell module
when you import these modules in
powershell are there any powershell
users
here
not as many as i thought okay so
yeah i love powershell i can't say
enough good things about it uh obviously
because azure is api driven you can use
whatever you want
so you could use curl if you would like
or just use bash in general
but uh i love powershell i'm a
powershell fanboy
when you import a powershell module
like this like import module azure ad
you can do a very simple command to see
what are all the available commandlets
uh in powershell uh for that particular
module
so in this example if i import that
module and then get the commands that
are exposed by that module
i've got all these different
commandlets and this goes on and on and
on and on and on
and i say this because
just reading the commandlet names you
can get an idea of what is possible
uh
beyond the documentation
uh and then the powershell command let's
powershell is self-documenting so if you
like look at the equivalent of a man
page for a powershell commandlet it will
often include examples although some of
the microsoft author once don't include
examples
but they'll show you how to use the
commandlet what the expected output is
and things like that
the existing microsoft authored
powershell modules are what i initially
used to create uh something called azure
hound uh which is a data collection
capability that feeds the azure data
into a bloodhound database
uh and then finally with exploring this
system from different perspectives uh we
can create our own very basic client
so we did that already with uh chrome
where like we can copy copy as
powershell paste uh but it's better to
have control of your own very basic
client and uh for powershell in
particular to be able to create modules
for
whatever you want to
do here's an example of the most basic
ms graph api client that i can conceive
of
so at the top we are accessing the
sts service the security token service
to get a token
for ms graf
for this client
which is a service principal in azure
and we're assigning the variable that we
get back to the dollar token variable
the yellow highlight there that is where
we are accessing the api very easy so
with powershell you have a method or a
command called invoke rest method
which will put the output of that
optionally into a variable that you
describe
so i'm i'm putting the output of that
into dollar users
and then you can work with the data that
comes back so
uh users users.value will show the raw
information that came back
and it looks
something like that
uh so these are
json objects but powershell will convert
them to a ps custom object or serialize
it as a powershell object but you can
you can translate back and forth between
powershell object and json very easily
when you start doing this you will start
to run into issues obviously so
one issue is that this user's endpoint
and many of the azure ad
scoped endpoints
they will only return the first 100
objects that come back
so you have to go through a loop
to uh
you know page through the results and so
that looks like this
there are some gotchas with jwts
so jwts they facilitate stateless
authentication so that azure doesn't
have to keep track of your state like it
does with a cookie
and it partly facilitates stateless
authorization
but not all of that authorization
uh information is stored in the jwt
the azure ad roles and the ms graph
roles are stored in the jwts
but if you have azure rm role
assignments or if you have explicit
object
ownership
or if you have key vault permissions or
whatever that information is not stored
in the jwt
so the tldr is that you probably
actually have more permissions than what
the jwt describes
what are we doing here
so in this example what i want to show
you is that we are assigning our jwt to
the dollar token variable and then on
line 20 right there we are printing out
the actual base64 encoded access token
we run that in powershell it looks like
this
there's a handy service you can use
called jwt.ms
that will parse your jwt
and there are some interesting things in
the token to look at
one is the audience
so the audience is the service that the
jwt is valid for
and it is invalid for any other service
in azure
the issuer so this is the security token
service and then the id that you see at
the end of that is my own azure ad
tenant id
the ms graph
scoped app roles are in the roles
parameter and then the azure ad roles
are in a parameter called wids
i think i have about 10 minutes left
is that right
15. okay cool all right we're doing well
so the
final result of this phase of exploring
that system from various perspectives
is that we've created a very simple
very functional client
uh and so we've we've kind of we've
dipped our toes by studying how the
official microsoft author tooling
interfaces with the system
we've been a little lower level by
creating our own clients so we can
access the system in a more raw nature
we also now have the foundation for
building a more mature client that we
can use to do our abuse primitive
discovery
and
with all this context and with this very
basic client we also have the foundation
for automating that abuse discovery
process which is what we will talk about
now
so this next phase it will catalog the
abuse capabilities that are enabled by
the system
first step
what are the permissions that are
available by the system we want to
enumerate all of those
with our very basic client we can do
that like this
so ms graph
instantiates itself as a resource app
also known as a service principle so we
access it via the service principles in
point
and then we
well actually we're just enumerating all
of them and we're putting them into a
variable called service principles
then
we find the service principle that
matches the ms graph resource app guide
which is going to be the same in every
tenant
and there is a property
called app roles and what this describes
is all of the different permission
or permissions that are exposed by the
app
because they are exposed by the app they
are also scoped to the app
what that means is that an ms graph app
role
cannot be used against another app does
that make sense
so our graph app roles are only valid
against the graph they're not valid
against azure ad they're not valid
against azure rm they're not valid
against anything else except for the ms
graph api
or at least that's what the intent is
maybe that maybe somebody can find a way
around that
if you can that would be worth
probably several tens of thousands of
dollars
here's what i do here's what i did i
copied all of these different
uh app roles
i pasted them into a spreadsheet
and then we're ready for the next step
our next step is we're going to test the
existing abuses that we already know
about
and consider new abuses that maybe we
learned about through looking at the
documentation or looking at the
description for an app role
or
looking at a talk whatever just keep an
open mind about what the other these
possibilities could be
so as an example in the microsoft
documentation
there is this privilege called
directory.readwrite.all
this says it allows the app to read and
write data in your organization's
directory such as users and groups
without a signed in user does not allow
user or group deletion
that's
it that's all you get
you don't get to know what the scope of
actions are that are allowed by this
permission
you don't get to know the scope of
objects that can be touched by this
you don't know does this affect azure ad
and azure rm
literally this is all that we know
and
this is why i say
if you make tooling based on
documentation
it will be inaccurate it'll be wrong and
the people who use your tooling
including yourself will be
extraordinarily frustrated
so you have to go beyond the
documentation when you're doing these
tests
so
in this spreadsheet i will start to list
out the different abuse primitives that
i already know about
against azure
so for example can i promote myself to
global admin that's fun
can i change a global admins password
it's useful
can i add a principle to a role enabled
security group okay that's pretty good
and initially when i started doing this
research i would do this i would have an
example application i would give it one
permission at a time
and then i would do
abuse tests with that permission
so for example let's give it access
review.read.all
is that abusable is it not i don't know
we can't prove that from the information
available from microsoft
here's an example of how to promote a
user to global admin
using the
post method against this particular
endpoint in the ms graph api
so
manually by hand i will
use that service principle's secret and
authentication to try to promote itself
to global admin
and i will get a 403
and i'll go back to my table
and i'll enter no
so there's
uh
about 175 ms graph app roles
and the abuse tests that i was covering
is maybe about a dozen
so you can do the math it's impossible
to do this by hand you have to you have
to automate this process
which is what we will do
after you automate this process
you go from
i'm sorry wrong slide
you go from something like this
to the end result of what i have in my
actual spreadsheet which is this
so the actual per the actual app roles
that can be abused i have listed here
and then all the other ones that cannot
be abused are just
below that with all red nose
and so the example that we looked at
before was
directory.readwrite.all which you could
see in the middle of that far left
column
and so it turns out that the two abuses
that are actually enabled by that
are we can add someone to a non-role
eligible group or we can add an owner to
a non-role eligible group so as far as
read and write on all directory objects
i'm not so sure
the end result of this automation
is for me
i need to know how am i going to expand
the bloodhound graph database design
and so that would look like this
so this is what you were looking at
before in the spreadsheet but it is
modeled as
a graph
so we'll just look at the very top
example we have an az app that will
authenticate as a az service principle
that service principle is granted the ms
graph app role called
application.readwrite.all
and that gives them four different abuse
possibilities they can add a secret or
an owner to an az app or add a secret or
an owner to an az service principal
so at this point i'm ready to
introduce these attack primitives into
the bloodhound graph i haven't done that
yet it's coming soon
what you can also do is from this you
can create
a you can create an example attack path
and then you can look for those examples
and those patterns in real environments
and so after doing this research
we do red team assessments for
organizations that use azure
and one of the most common attack paths
that we find for turning low privilege
access in azure into global admin relies
on abusing these ms graph api
permissions
and such an example attack path looks
like this
on the left we have a user called matt
nelson who has
no azure ad admin roles
it doesn't belong to any role eligible
security groups
if you were to audit
this user using the azure portal you
would see that this user has no
permissions
what you wouldn't see
is that this user has been added as an
explicit owner on an app registration
object
that app registration authenticates to
azure using a service principle
it's a one-to-one mapping
that service principle has been granted
an app role called
aprilassignment.readright.all
which allows the service principal to
grant itself or anybody else
any ms graph api permission
so they can give themselves
rolemanagement.readwrite.director
which means that they can then promote
themselves to global admin
this is the most common privilege
escalation pattern that we have seen in
real azure tenants so far
for defenders it is very very hard to
audit any one piece of this
so
that sucks
another end result of going through this
automation process is that you will
discover
where the official documentation
materially differs from reality
so a good example is this
on the official documentation
it says that only an administrator
can consent
to application permissions
but if we rewind about 20 minutes
remember the github issues that i was
showing you before
one of those is
how do i automate
granting consent for application
permissions
and it turns out you don't need an
administrator to consent
if the service principle has a
particular app role assigned to it
and so it used to be true what's
underlined in red here used to be true
it no longer is true
so you can you can find where
the documentation is wrong
i was going to try to have this ready
before this talk but i didn't have it
ready but something that is coming soon
is the automation framework that i've
built and so working title atomic azure
tests
this is inspired by red canary's project
called atomic red team
it has no dependence on the powershell
modules it just accesses the graph api
using the powershell methods
um
you could easily port this to something
else like golang or
bash or whatever it's an api you can use
anything to interface with it
and additionally my intent is that it
will be easily expandable to cover other
azure services so that you can take this
and you can extend it to cover maybe
something else that you're interested in
the end result for us is that we have
daily automatic permission to abuse
mapping
available for anyone to see so that will
be coming soon as well
that's the end of that phase so we've
automated collection audit and abuse
capabilities
finally we want to share our findings i
don't have a whole lot to say about this
this basically means write a blog
share your code
give a talk
let other people learn from what you
have learned and let other people build
on top of what you have built
or improve what you have built
just help people save time by getting
through this rigmarole initially
the way that i like to say that is
write the blog post that you needed at
the start
let's go back to
where we started we wanted to begin with
the end in mind here are all the things
that i wanted to do
so i can check myself and i can see that
yes i did all these things so i feel
good about that i can move on to
something else
where do we find research ideas
like i said at the beginning
azure lets you basically do anything
that you can think of with a computer
so if you have existing expertise in
databases maybe look at the azure sql
database service or devops and ci cd or
ci cd
or web apps or or infrastructure
management
there's a full
maybe
list of what those services are at that
link in reality there are probably more
services than what are documented
i also recommend following people in
leadership at microsoft because they
often talk about new cool things that
are coming out
and those new cool things are ripe for
abuse research
follow these particular people who don't
work at microsoft
they are always putting out high quality
high signal content specific to azure
there's a link to this deck
at the first slide which i'll bring back
up so you don't have to
rely on taking a picture of this
bookmark these pages
and read these every so often
which brings us to our conclusion
there has never been a better time than
right now
to get involved in abuse research
specifically against azure
azure has been around for more than 10
years but really it hasn't been adopted
by the mainstream until the past two or
three years
there's a lot of misconfiguration debt
in the system there's a lot of
opportunity to discover new abuse
primitives
i hope that in this talk i've shown you
how easy if tedious
it actually is and i wish you happy
hunting
and with that i'll thank you and you can
find me on twitter right there
[Applause]
thanks a lot andy awesome talk
uh since we started a little bit late
we'll give a five five minutes or so for
questions so if anybody has a question
please raise your hand
uh thank you for the great talk uh i
always find that always finding these
talks very inspirational
but from my experience the hard thing
about this research project is managing
your time
so um how do you go about managing the
time and also
these goals for the stages the for the
phases that you set are kinda abstract
there is really no way to find if you
have researched the documentation enough
and it's really hard to
sell to yourself
like spending additional time here and
there this is the first one and the
second one is very very short are the
azure apis
stable
so that your tooling does not
get outdated
those are great questions so the first
question was how do i manage my time
it's difficult i'm fortunate to have
uh working hours available to me during
the day from nine to five that i can do
this research not everybody has that
luxury so
when i did not have that luxury it was
sitting at a bar like on the on the week
uh
you know weekday evenings
um it's challenging uh but i also have
maybe a more personal answer which i'll
answer personally to you
your second question was um
oh yeah this this the stability of the
tooling yeah that is a great question so
you might notice that in some of those
requests that i was doing i was
specifying a version of the api to hit
the last stable version for the ms graph
api came out in 2015.
uh
there are beta versions available as
well that you can hit but certainly
my belief is that if you specify the api
version that the
service should behave the same way maybe
maybe not
probably not
uh and did you have another question in
there too no okay
good questions
any other questions
oh over here
yeah
uh thank you uh first thank you for blue
down
it's helpful every day so thanks
then uh oh uh
how long
did
something like this take from the stars
so your friend tell you uh hey look at
that it's interesting
to uh
the end of your
yeah
so the question is how long did it take
to go through this process from hearing
about it initially to having a product
or a talk or whatever
it took about
two months
now it could have been a lot faster
if i would have figured out the
automation process earlier
the truth is that the resulting table
that you saw earlier i actually did do
that manually by hand so that took
a long time
but
that that's what most took most of the
time but with the automation uh
framework i think that could be
compressed down to maybe a couple of
weeks
maybe two or three weeks that's my
intent uh with bloodhound especially i
want to
extend the scope to cover other abusable
services and so part of my
responsibility is to have that abuse
research
and
uh practical application process
more mature
and so this is what i'm doing now with
other research that i'm doing now
is automating that as quickly as i can
so now i would say it's two or three
weeks to go from hearing about something
to have something that is
uh
publicly digestible i would say
okay so we have time for one more
question and then we'll move on
uh thanks for the talk really
interesting
uh one of my question is actually what
do you do when you find an uh abuse
especially like uh in the documentation
you you show us that uh it was actually
wrong yeah did you inform microsoft and
what was the reaction that they had yeah
um
so i i did have a few conversations with
people at microsoft uh around this
uh i also submitted some pr's to the
documentation repos to correct them most
of them are rejected
uh
but i i did talk to people at microsoft
about like the abuse possibilities with
this system
and
because this is the way that the system
is designed their response was
this is not a vulnerability this is how
the system works which of course makes
me happy because that means that
my abuse primitives last forever
so they're not going to change this
and that means that bloodhound will be
correct when it shows you an attack path
and that means that the documentation
that i write or the
the code that i write
will
stay the same it doesn't need to change
and i agree with their position that it
is the way that the system is designed
and intended to be used
it's the same thing with
abusing the service control manager in
windows to create or edit an existing
service it's the way the system works
can it be abused yes is there something
microsoft can do about it
not really i don't think it's like rdp
what are they going to do
so um
yeah then otherwise there there's other
like documentation uh corrections that
i've uh asked for them to make or i've
made the prs and
you know i've asked that's the best i
can say is i've asked
uh
yeah i one more thing i'll say is i have
uh bloodhound stickers with me but
charlie's talk is coming up i don't want
to interfere with charlie's talk
so maybe find me in the lobby after
charlie's talk and i'm going to stay
here and watch charlie's talk
all right thanks another round of
applause randy