[Music]
that's bright delight
okay thanks for having me i think it's
the second time around for insomniac the
last time was about six seven years ago
still at mandiant at that time
and well i'm really happy that i can
talk a little bit about managing large
scale incident response because
in the last few years um i've seen a lot
of people doing really great incident
response from a technical perspective
but in the end they still fail to an
extent the client is not super happy in
the end and mostly that goes down to
arrows in how you how you went through
that whole engagement because it's more
than just knowing your technical stuff
there
so first of all what do i consider
large-scale incident response
before i introduce myself i just say
that first i don't think that there is a
clear definition right so for some it's
like a couple of hundred machines
for some it's a couple of hundred
thousand machines that does make a
difference obviously not necessarily
from the technical perspective that's
the funny thing that is just something
that comes down to tooling but if you
have an organization with a couple of
hundred thousand machines they just work
a little bit more complex than an
organization that has a couple of
hundred machines
so it's more that human factor that you
have in there
the only thing that i want to make clear
is i'm not talking about
a sock ticket incident response because
you know most of the tools of those soar
tools they also call that kind of
incident response when you work on a
socket ticket that's not what i'm
talking about so i'm talking about a
deep breach of a network where an attack
was active moved laterally to a few
machines maybe exfiltrated some data
that's what i'm talking about here
so the term is a little bit overused
here
it's very funny because from the sizing
perspective there is actually an analogy
that we can use here so when you go back
to medical support in in big accidents a
mass event is considered an event where
the resources that are locally available
are just too few to manage that response
and i think that works pretty well here
as well
so it doesn't really depend on um on
the size that you're facing but rather
on how you work there uh what kind of
people you have how many resources you
have and so on so
how do i i know that so why do i
think that i can talk about that well
first of all how do i learn all that
stuff
i make a ton of mistakes sometimes looks
like this and over the last decade or so
i don't make
less mistakes probably but they're just
not as big as they used to be and
i also got lucky over the last few years
because whenever i was about to make a
bigger mistake there was someone holding
me back
that makes sure that i'm still in
industry but when you do incident
response you're always at the brink of
losing reputation pretty quickly right
so if you do something wrong if you
declare an organization is super clean
and they're not then that's a problem
and that happens more and more
uh the second uh thing where um i
learned that is i'm teaching for sans um
actually the the five weight advanced
incident response class i'm authoring
two more classes one for memory
forensics and one for enterprise
incident response and there we have on
the sixth day always a capstone so
people are confronted with a made-up
case but that looks pretty real right to
an extent
and they need to present that case and
the funny thing is you see the whole
process so they are going to be grouped
in groups of four or five people and
they work on the data that they have and
in the end they present what they have
and even groups that are doing
technically great and found a lot of
stuff
don't win in the end and the reason for
that is sometimes they found something
and then just forgot it forgot to put it
into context and put it on their slides
and stuff like that and that is
something that happens in reality as
well
and the most concerning thing of how i
learn is actually if well the easiest
one for me because learning from other
others mistakes is usually something
that's less painful for you
we're getting more and more called uh
for a second opinion so either there is
an investigation going on the client is
not happy with the first vendor who went
there
secondly um we have um expert witness
cases where we write reports about uh
investigations that happen in the past
and where something didn't went that
well and where the clients use the
provider so that happens more and more
and
the first case when it happened in the
us i think was 2014 2015 around that
time in the u.s
had to do with my hotel and stuff but i
can't go into details on that case
having said that um to my history i've
been doing incident response for over a
decade now teaching for sense about a
decade and
i've been doing that pretty much all
around the world except china maybe
because
all the companies i worked for were not
happy working in china that much
i used to work for german telecom for
mandi and now i'm working for a swiss
company running an incident response and
intelligence team
there but in another part of switzerland
and i got a question uh because i want
to know who i talked to here so who have
you let incident response engagements in
the past no matter if internal or
external
oh quite a few that's cool
uh never hesitate to correct me or tell
me your view on things right that's how
we all learn right
uh how many of you or who have you uh
had investigations over a thousand hosts
well most of you um that raised the hand
before ten thousand
hundred thousand
[Music]
that's where it gets um well a little
bit more dicey because um
they're not so many companies that have
that many machines out there who's
working for a competitor
was nice meeting you goodbye
okay
so what we're going to walk through here
is a few key success factors actually
i'm sort of stealing the
part of those slides from myself they're
coming out of the six-way class it sends
but
well the information is going to be the
same so it doesn't make sense to have a
complete separate
set of slides so those are the critical
factors because when i had the
opportunity to build my own team i could
take whatever i learned before that and
try to avoid the mistakes but that also
means that you kind of need to formalize
what you learned in a way to make that
like a communicatable to someone else
and those are the key points visibility
we're gonna go into detail pretty soon
efficiency
technical skills of course
documentation and also soft skills
and the last part
or all of these parts in in combination
are very hard to find and usually it's
either on a technical side or in the
soft skill side but finding the
resources that can do both very well
that's a different uh
story that's that's really difficult and
it's giving us a hard time and probably
many of you have the same problem
so talking about visibility um that's a
question i usually ask um also tool
vendors very often uh i got like four
questions here um if you're not a
technical person never mind i'm going to
explain a little bit what i'm asking for
here and why i'm asking that but with
the tool set that you
use i think i put a size down here
somewhere 8 000 hosts for example so
you're faced with an intrusion 8 000
hosts we're not talking ransomware here
right so we're probably talking about
someone who's interested in in your ip
or something access broker whatever
and the first question is which machines
have executables on their users videos
directory
at the same time get their timestamps
and checksums for these executables
so
could you do it how long would it take
you
so what do you think is an acceptable
timing for for that information 8000
hosts
um
yeah maximum for for the ones that are
online obviously right
i mean if you have to wait in
international cases you oftentimes have
to wait especially for clients to go
online and stuff
but that's that's about it minutes we're
talking minutes here so whatever tooling
you use in in a nutshell if you have the
right visibility is just an extension of
your brain right you ask questions and
you get the answer you just phrase them
right uh give i mean all the creation
time stems of the profile folder of a
specific user from all machines
same thing pretty much right
i think those two things that i just
mentioned especially the second one you
can do with pretty much any edr the
first one i'm not totally sure about
because you need like a wild card
somewhere in the middle with the
username that makes it a little bit more
difficult
the third one
is a even more complex one find all
machines that match a certain yara rule
in their memory
so that is what
what would uh make me ask a question
when we're talking about memory are we
talking about the memory as a whole or
are we talking about the process memory
that's the difference right
so in other terms if malware is in there
and um there's some residue somewhere in
the memory but it's not addressed
anymore well then i will not find it if
i just go for a process memory now the
problem is many of the tools that are
used out there which is going for the
process memory right
and
especially the most user-friendly tools
most user-friendly edrs out there don't
give you that opportunity at all
to look into the
memory that's not attached to a certain
process
recover the rdb bitmap cache from a
specific user on all servers where the
user logged in after a certain date
so you see
um i keep combining more and more
things more and more factors into what i
want to have so first of all what is the
rdp bitmap cache just for non lots of
technical people there rdp that's a
remote desktop protocol
i guess most of you have used that
before and you probably realized when
the internet connection is pretty slow
and you move your mouse right around the
mouse you see that the resolution of the
screen is different than on the rest of
the screen and that's because
this is the way how rdp updates your
image it updates uh in small squares and
it stores those squares in the rdp
bitmap cache so that means that it get
like small parts of the screen of an rdp
session from these
now when we notice a certain user
account was used
to
to log in or move laterally using rdp
we can get pieces out of that session
but i don't want to do that manually so
i need a way to to make that collection
automatic and get that on a number of
machines and also when i have a first
date where i believe that that user was
used in a malicious way that is another
factor that i put in so i don't want to
have the information from the legitimate
user so visibility is important and i
think um i usually try to to visualize
that using geography in a certain way
like uh length for example here
um this is from a real case hundred and
seventy thousand hosts that we did and
out of those 105 turned out to be
accessed by the attacker some with
malware some are just accessed with
living off the land tools and so on
if we put that on on a 100 meter race
track like olympic racetrack the whole
machines only six centimeters of that
would have been um infected by the user
which well doesn't sound like a lot
especially because those six centimeters
are not together right they're spread a
whole around the whole population
that means you need to look very closely
at everything because if you miss one
thing they're going to be back so we're
talking there about nation states there
was a very funny case
because they had three groups three
different groups in there and they were
battling each other
do you get that information first
and um they never got rid of the
attacker by the way um they still have
them in there
because um it was impossible to
completely remediate at least of all of
these i think they later got rid of one
of the attacker but not because of what
they did but because of what another
attacker group did so that was very
funny
we see that more and more by the way
that attackers start to fix uh the
initial holes how they got in right so
they start patching your machines
so if you don't do it never mind the
attackers will do that for you
question is if the price is right for
that but that's another story if you
look at the tool stack for for for that
um what we're usually faced with is you
have some sort of always on kind of
thing so that means all data gets stored
in in some sort of central repository
like a sim or so
uh you can collect it using sysmon
whatever you get net flows from from
network devices or whatever and you have
the on-demand part so edrs are usually
today
depending on the exact product
um a mix of those two right so they
store some data locally but you can also
actively demand data from the clients or
servers if you want to
so there is somewhere in the middle uh
you can have enriched alerts with that
uh you can collect pcaps so
pcaps could be always on but that's very
rarely the case right especially when
it's about broad internet connections or
connections at all
you you have only very few organizations
that really record pcaps
in a broad sense
unless you demand them to do that in a
certain extent and forensic agents so
what can you do um if you're internal
for example to to get that whole thing
better so first of all uh let's talk
about threat hunting so threat hunting
in a sense is like leaving incident
response so the only difference in
threat hunting is you don't know if the
attacker is really in but well what do
you know in a real attack right very
often you find more attacker groups that
you were aware of in the beginning so
that's not different so you use the same
techniques you use the same tools the
highest form of
threat hunting is hypothesis based
hunting you set up a hypothesis so for
example
apt i don't know 28 that's could be very
current is in our network so what do
they usually do what tools do they use
how would we identify them with our
toolset
and what i depict here is not correct
right i say you have that hypothesis and
you could either accept it or you could
reject it but actually there's a third
outcome and that is the well sometimes
even more valuable one and that's the
visibility is missing well this is the
hypothesis this is how i would check but
i can't with our toolset
and it also tells you something right
because usually when a threat hunters in
an organization cannot uh really hunt
for a certain threat you suck can't
detect it either and that is not a good
place to be right
and that brings me to efficiency i have
to to run through that a little bit
obviously you can't get full disk images
for all machines when we're talking
about a couple thousand machines
i'm not saying that there are not
organizations out there who try
but they usually fail i remember a case
for
a medium-sized company last year
beginning of last year they have around
30 000 endpoints
and um we were again the second ones
they called in so the whole thing
started on wednesday they got another
company in and
till friday they didn't do anything
because what they requested from the
client was to set up a very beefy server
right a lot of ram a lot of storage and
so on and they wanted to have the images
of the patients here of the suspected
patients here delivered to that machine
and you know how it is in big
organizations you have like tons of
outsourcing providers it's just
something that does not work easily
right to get that data from a to b
quickly
uh so they never established um
visibility there and that's what we did
in the end
when they would have looked at the
machine like maybe on saturday sunday
whatever when they would have gotten it
they would have realized that they would
need to look at another 15 machines so
would they then request 15 other images
so what is their approach to that
so it's it's just not going to work so
that could have hurt that organization
very much but in the end every resource
that you want to spend and resources can
be a lot right like storage but also
human resources needs to be justified by
a question that you need to answer with
that i mean that's in in business that's
i think a very logical thing right
whatever you invest you expect some
return on that investment and why not
work the same here
so what we're using in the different
sense classes are actually those um
uh those cones there so um basically
that funnel starts on top right so at
the beginning you look at a ton of
machines uh which basically allows you
to use a set of techniques
then if you go down that funnel you
select out certain machines where you
use other techniques if you basically
translate that to a sort of resource
pools that's what we do
you basically have the same amount of
resources so that means you can look at
very small data sets from many machines
or you look at bigger or complex things
for a few machines right
and the funny thing is most cases begin
somewhere in the middle
right some machine is acting up it's
still the case that very often in
non-ransomware cases
capacity management
is one of the first things that tell the
organization that they have a breach so
it's not the av it's not their edr it's
actually capacity management right so
drive is running full because they're
pulling together to gather some data
maybe a process is going high because
the attackers don't know how to use the
tool properly so we had all of these
right so for example one case they use
the tool uh that's called recharge and
that's basically um a proxy into the
network uh where the the server side of
the proxy can be whatever web
web file that is so that could be an
aspx that could be
uh
whatever could be uh any kind of java
file
and so on could be php and you just
tunnel into the network but the thing is
if you do that in apache and you keep
that session open for too long it will
uh it will peak out the cpu
so if you use that before as a pen
tester and
were called in that situation you know
that but if you just use the tool it
works the same right even if the cpu
peaks it works the same but if someone
monitors that server they will realize
that something is going on and if they
are careful they will find that
so that's what i'm saying so for example
small data sets what could you do with
that data stacking is one of the
operations that we tend to use a lot so
for example you can stack things like
persistence because malware
does not only need to run it also needs
to keep running to a certain extent
after reboot so what you can do is you
can get all the different locations how
malware could persist itself and then
from there on stack that data because
obviously a windows system looks pretty
much like any other windows system to an
extent so that means
everything that's very unique will
bubble up if you just count the
occurrence count in the whole network so
in other terms if you have like c
mapper.exe it's probably not on on all
8000 machines that we just discussed
it's maybe just on 10.
so that means if you sort by the
occurrence throughout the whole network
you will find it pretty easily um
technical skills
um it's i guess it's pretty
straightforward that we're talking about
some sort of technical work here as well
so um the attacker the investigators
really need to understand their tools
and to be honest that's one of the
things where i see most failures happen
because
people just overestimate their tools
one of the most common things is that
they use iocs for example let's take
open ioc as a format open ioc allows you
a ton of different parameters to specify
right
but that doesn't mean that every tool
supports these so what they do is they
shoot certain iocs at a tool
and if that comes back negative they
mean everything is clear but maybe the
tool just didn't check every part of
that ioc because it was not capable of
doing that i just give you an example
for example let's say you have an edr
that for some reason that's a very made
up example but that for some reason only
allows you to create md5 checksums for
files now your ioc includes a sha-1 hash
for the file but not an md5 so you shoot
it at the network it comes back negative
because every file produces an empty
hash because it can't do that and you
think it's clean and that is very
dangerous because the most dangerous
thing for us is incident responders is
false negatives right false positives
are annoying i'll give you that right
but false negatives that's what's going
to break our necks right so if we think
it's clean and it's not
uh ttp's of the attacker they should
know how attackers usually work so in
other terms and that's something where i
see some shortcomings with analysts who
have never done pen testing um
for example you end up on a machine
like with one sort of your backdoor
let's go back for conte they have the
bazaar loader there let's assume you're
on that machine and you have a normal
local user so what are the steps that
you could do to get a higher privileged
accounts
or higher privileged accounts if you end
up as a local administrator what are the
possible steps then
and so on so if you have a normal user
what you could do for example would be
cover roasting right that
works with a normal user if you have
local admin you could think about
something like lsa dump mimikats
whatever
and and that is something that you have
to understand from the attacker's side
because their options are limited based
on what they have what privileges they
have at this point in time
artifacts all the different artifacts so
how can you prove a certain point so
what i always tell my people is the
theory comes first and then there comes
the way to prove it because
uh other than that you have the risk of
using the so-called golden hammer method
so if
the only tool you have is a hammer every
problem looks like a nail even though it
isn't and that is super dangerous in in
that regard
um enterprise architectures they need to
understand how normal enterprise
architectures work in their setup
and then the most difficult thing
sometimes is blueprint so that's the
ideal company enterprise normal which is
usually a little bit more messed up than
unusual it's not necessarily bad and
then really malicious so there it's it's
not like a um a clear differentiation
between those it's it's more like fluent
uh in between those stages
documentations and the questions that i
asked there is when people say the
document very well is did you ever write
a report for a case that you didn't lead
that someone else left and you were not
on the case and you had to rely on their
documentation did you ever do that
if if not you're doing well because that
means you you manage resources wisely
unfortunately i had to do that very
often and to be honest it sucked every
single time
before we went up um and and came along
with some sort of standard uh
documentation is not just important for
writing the report that's one thing
right but you also have to manage the
stakeholders i mean if you're in there
like an external entity and you already
charge them like 200 300 hours but you
need 100 more i need good grounds to
discuss that with the client right so
that is also one thing that is important
the police might ask me something then
it's important for resource planning i
don't want to have too many people on
the bench i mean having the worst thing
as an external entity is when you have
people on the bench and at the same time
you turn down engagements right so that
shouldn't happen because that's a really
bad
resource management there
intelligence development so for us um
i'll show you that later uh it's
technically possible when we record
something during an incident you put it
into our documentation and we can put it
on the on a feed pretty quickly like
within hours right david about hours or
within the hour depending on how much
coffee you had right
okay
remediation uh i need to have a clear
understanding what i need to clean up
because rebuilding is not always an
option that means i need to clear out as
much as i can but that means also that i
have to come up with a plan because in
remediation also have limited amounts of
resources liability prevention so if
it's coming back to me um
well
you shouldn't be
well someone else shouldn't be able to
really disassemble what i did in a way
that they say they did stupid things
they missed this one they missed that
one i should have recorded everything
also all the things that the client told
you so when a client tells you no i
don't want you to do this uh you're not
supposed to go this to this machine
we're not gonna install your agent there
then that's something i need to record
right because later on that's how
i can prevent liability there
um a general rule of thumb there is if
you don't document it it didn't happen
right so
obviously there's
we also don't manage to get it right
every single time but yeah
soft skills uh so the most important one
is right at the end pizza orders and
coffee machine operating coffee machine
is very important that was difficult
during covet i'll give you that
no but really a stakeholder management
that's very important keeping the client
happy it's it usually doesn't work very
well no matter how good you are if you
just say okay uh we roll out our agents
then you go silent for two weeks and
then you come back they will call you
they will not be happy they want to be
entertained right
for uh to a certain part at least you're
going to lose a resource on that that's
for sure because those people who
entertain the board are usually not able
to work anymore on the case really
but yeah that's just how it works in big
organizations you have to manage the ir
team i mean
it's different for the client usually
it's the first time or maybe second time
they don't do that every day
but it's not that thrilling for your
investigators anymore if it's too
thrilling for investigators you probably
have an unexperienced team
so they don't care if that case is super
thrilling for the organization they want
to go on vacation the next week right so
you have to plan around that they do
that every day so
that is important to understand regular
i.t teams
i mean they could be in a very bad
position depending on your client
sometimes they get pressured because
someone says they've basically put the
organization at risk which most of the
times
is not necessarily true at least not
alone
so you have to take care of these people
as well then they might have socks that
work with you but sometimes they have
them internally sometimes they have an
external outsourcing provider
they are also concerned about their
liability so they probably not give you
everything won't give you everything
that you need and not in a way that you
want to have it so that's also very
difficult
uh the breached entities clients you
would wonder how how often i have to
talk to partners clients and so on of
our breached entities because they don't
trust the entity themselves anymore but
they oftentimes trust us because
sometimes there are our clients already
and they know how we work
it's it's often about like reopening vpn
tunnels and all that stuff to the
breached organization
um so how could you set up a team uh to
make all that work from a
human resource perspective so usually uh
we have one ir lead who leads a case
uh for smaller cases the lead is the
only person you'll get and sometimes
even that only for fifty percent
depending on how how it works out right
uh bigger bigger cases you you might get
uh more analysts but they can pop in and
pop out i don't have like
people assigned a hundred percent to a
case that makes it a little bit more
difficult then we have cross function
like malware reversing they don't care
they need they don't need to be attached
to a single case right they just work on
malware
intel analysts they need to be aware of
any case and give you the information
that they saw something that they also
saw in another case before
roles and duties so you have the ir lead
who basically uh manages the engagement
uh sometimes they also well
do some sort of an analyst role
depending on the case size again i mean
if i have an engagement with 2000
machines
i don't really need a second analyst for
that right that is what one person can
normally do alone depending on what
exactly happened you have analysts there
that work on on that case uh date to the
actual triage they do the hunting and so
on on the shared functions you have the
member analysts so they get married to
analyze they tell you things about for
example callbacks right because if they
find an ip address the host name
whatever you can go back and figure out
um what other machines are connected to
that c2
c2 server
based on firewall locks or whatever you
have
intelligence analysts first of all for
us cater for our for our
feed and secondly they
sort of interconnect
investigations so as soon as you get
bigger it's difficult to have
all analysts watch all the chat channels
for the different engagements and if
that happens we need someone to be in
control and and make the connection if
something is similar into different
cases
external entities that's super important
to manage them
you have so many different entities like
law enforcement for example they can do
things that we can do not necessarily
because they're technically better but
they have some legal means that they can
use like freezing servers i mean in
europe they cannot give you the server
right away but at least they can make
sure that the provider doesn't change it
anymore right
so they keep the server until you can
legally get an image from them
until that's sorted out so things like
that can be very useful law firms that's
especially difficult sometimes in in big
international companies in the us it
goes as far as that legally would have
the obligation in some communities to
even report a breach to the mayor of
that city
it even goes down no one does that right
but technically you would be obliged so
they have very different reporting
obligations there coming communication
firms it's all about communication
remember there was breach in 2014 i
believe for the british
telecommunications provider the ceo went
out and she said uh yeah we had a bridge
but we didn't lose data the next day she
came back well we might have lost like 7
000 customer data sets
next issue came back well maybe it was
rather 60 000 or something
and they kept finding new data until
2019 that's when the bbc got back and
found additional data
she was there for another half year the
organization was losing about 300
millions in value so it was not a super
good communications example here the
important thing is communicate with one
voice right either it's really one
entity that communicates but if multiple
entities communicate
then do that with one voice
going back to resource management real
quick we have different types of
resources so julius caesar uh divided
impera so divide and conquer
it's meant differently by the way so he
meant that differently than we do uh but
it's still very useful for us so we have
the human resources like analysts and so
on we have storage cpu uh you know for
searching and stuff and we have tools
process and content with content i mean
iocs and all that that kind of stuff
and only the middle one can be pro can
be procured very easily i mean i can
spin up as many machines with as many
ram i want at amazon at azure whatever i
want right that's easy
but
on the analyst side you got what you got
and on the tooling side i mean i can buy
a tool pretty quickly but that doesn't
mean i can integrate it into my workflow
that quickly
so that is what i mean there
so good resource management in a
nutshell means bringing resources and
tasks together with the minimum overlap
right
so on the other hand if if that is the
the resources and that is the tasks the
ideal match would be something like this
if you do it like this you you're
missing a lot of tasks you're not doing
them and you are wasting resources
so that's the general idea behind that
and the key is standardization because
only if everyone knows in the teams what
someone else is talking about only then
you can basically succeed there and for
that you can predefine tasks like okay
what is a sweep and hunt so i'm hunting
for user assist for example so i create
a stack out of all users these keys so
users stores execution of gui tools
right for example so this is something
you could also hunt for
triage that's another set and
those sets always come with the timing
involved right so what kind of skill
sets do you need what resource can you
put on that and how how long can that
resource take for that
and then you can in the end come up with
something like this so for example
analyst one is working on a triage two
triashes we usually take around four or
five hours for that to really be sure
about what happened on a single machine
so that's about the maximum for that uh
so that analyst will be blocked if you
talk about an eight to ten hour day
another analyst has uh two has a
persistent stack an execution stack and
triage so also occupied the whole day
then we have an analyst three who
probably worked in a different case so
we assigned like two hours three hours
to familiarize himself with the case and
after then one triage and then there's
still some leftover from the other case
and when you schedule people like this
uh you you avoid too too big overlaps
all right
and it's not that we don't want to pay
for more people we just don't get them
and that means we need to manage them
wisely and i think most of you are in
the same situation i would wonder if not
so if you're not in that situation then
please let me know how you do that
i would be really thrilled to know
uh so never do anything without a
guiding question right so everything you
do should got a question because no
question you can dive down into a
forensic images for days weeks and
months and still find new things
but does it help the case uh mostly not
right so that is you have to
differentiate research that you can put
on your block from from things that you
do for your client or your organization
that's very important there
so questions could be what did the
attacker do on system xyz which other
machines have the attack the staging
directory so for example if they use
program data
whatever
then you can look for all the machines
what data was that staged for
exfiltration on host xyz things like
that
so in general you first formulate a
question
it's not that formal right in reality
it's hey analyst xyz can you really
quick check this and that in the chat
right
all the other stuff is implicit right so
um they know what i'm talking about
because they are usually technically
skilled um they understand my question
because i well asked them
they know what way to use to figure that
out usually
um
i already and i have the right analysts
and they do that and they give me the
results so it's not that formal such as
try to sort of formalize that in in some
sort of way
that brings me to to well the last
points their documentation and there are
some principles that we try to follow
there and again documentation especially
in high-pressure environments is
difficult but on the other hand
especially in high-pressure environments
you should document very well
so
as soon as you have breaches in big
organizations it's always a political
game
so what you can't do and what will make
you fail is and that is what almost made
me feel when i was a very young analyst
in uh
in that regard it was an organization
with around 200 000 hosts and i was
fortunately not leading that there were
so many political games going on and i
didn't understand them at this point
because i would thought okay everyone is
pulling on the same rope going into the
same direction and working for the best
of the client in the clients
organization that's not true
in reality it was a lot of infighting
they used that whole incident to kick
others out of their position and take
their position and so on
and that is something you don't want to
be drawn into much as an organization
you have to separate yourself from that
and and be aware of that and control the
situation
so what i try to do and that is
something we really do uh good our leads
can brief their staff but also the
clients and also all other stakeholders
at every given time
even if and that happens to me uh i have
clients that just want to talk to me
like some sort of escalation or
something i can call up our so-called
spreadsheet of doom i'll get to that and
i can brief them even though i have no
clue about the case
if the analysts
document documented right that is the
idea at every given point in time that
should be possible
um so usually especially in large cases
documenting takes time that's for sure
but it saves more time than it takes in
the end that is also something and don't
get me wrong i hate documenting i really
love hunting i hate documenting but i
hate it even more when i get confronted
with a badly documented case and i can't
say anything about it because then it's
usually embarrassing and i try to avoid
that
so as soon as uh documentation is
confirmed uh sorry information is
confirmed documented i'm not saying that
we for example always put it into um
into the the documentation software at
uh right away but at least we have it in
a chat and we mark it that it has to be
added right because sometimes when
you're on a call information keeps
coming in and you want to think about it
a little bit before you document it
right but then you still need to make
sure that it ends up in the
documentation in the end so spreadsheet
of doom is actually a name that came
from mandiant
we had it in sense as well that's why i
can even name that um
i think it was 2015 as well when mandy
and changed that name the reason for
that is we always send a redacted
version to the client for the weekly
status meetings and it always said sod
and then the case number it was done in
excel and unfortunately one client cared
to ask um
what does sod stand for and we said
spreadsheet of doom and they didn't find
it funny uh
that is the reason why they changed the
engagement management sheet but i'm
but i'm happy to keep that name there
okay so the idea is it's the the single
place of truth about the investigation
so i'm not saying distorted the the
actual malware in there but at least
references to it so it contains a master
timeline that tells you the whole story
about the case and that is also what i
see in those day six challenges at sans
usually the groups that fare best are
the ones that tell a story rather than
answering single questions i mean i just
said answer questions and so on right
but not in the presentation not in how
you basically then present the case tell
a story they came in via this
vulnerability on that server shortly
after that they p voted to somewhere
else um then there was nothing which
makes us believe that maybe that was an
access broker who later sold the excess
off to someone else that's how we
explained the the gap of one month in
between the first breach and
you know you know how it works right
those of you who do that know what i'm
talking about
uh
also it's a good a good way for resource
management because if you have like
machines piling up for triage for a
closer inspection
i need to know how fast i can work
through that so if i have two people i
know one person can do true triages a
day
and i have like eight machines piling up
i either invest the next four days doing
that
or i need to get more analysts whatever
works best in the setting of the case
right
and that is important to know because it
also is
uh it basically influences
prioritization because if i know that it
will take four days i need to think
about what do i need first that's
important
okay
so there's a basic rule for us
if it's too big then it doesn't go into
the sot but it will be referenced so for
example like large powershell payloads i
don't put them in the salt directly i
reference them by number put it in a
wiki or whatever you fancy for that
because um
for me when i tell the story i don't
need to have the full powershell i know
this is
the powershell implant cobra strike
implant or whatever right
so the problem that i was faced with is
at mandiant we try to create a tool to
make that
now you have a ton of very experienced
incident responders and no one works the
exact same way as the other one
so that means that they tried to come up
with a specification to have that
software written but they failed for
years
because too many big egos and so on so
it didn't work out they kept working on
excel and sharing that by
what is the predecessor of of git uh
uh
sir yes right uh cbn right
yeah because there you could lock the
files to indicate that no one else can
overwrite it's it's super annoying but
it works in the end
but the problem is that works with
experienced teams in the end you end up
with like
20 different versions of this sort one
has more columns one has less columns
one who who knows how to use spivo
tables uses pivot tables and all that
kind of thing right and it did the job
that that's for sure but it
is not suitable for not so experienced
teams right and it's it's particularly
hard and i know that because i came to
an organization who had that already
for someone new to get into that tune
that's super difficult so now when i had
the chance like five years ago to build
my own team i said okay i need to do
that differently
because if you give unexperienced people
too much freedom in documentation you
end up in a mess that's for sure
so i came up with the first version of
aurora ir that's what it looks like
and i sort of have to excuse myself to a
little bit here
the the biggest problem with that it's
not super handy when it comes to being
used by multiple analysts so the idea
it's it's basically pretty much the
thought that we had mentioned plus a few
things particularly um interconnections
visualizations and so on i'll get to
that at the moment
but it's a flat file it's a flat file
that you work on with the tool
the reason for that why i started out
and that's also one of the reasons why
they kept to excel is
i still had in the back of my mind's
cases where i was sitting for example in
some bunker in riyadh in saudi arabia
you did not have internet you had
nothing we literally had to leave the
machines there so they just paid for the
machines we had new machines we left
them there
when we wanted to check
iocs like you know md5 sums and so on
that we found we had to literally print
them out we had a printer there in that
bunker we had to print them out bring
them with us to the hotel ocr them which
not always worked very great
ocr and back can check it against our
data sets on other machines and in those
settings uh you know having something at
azure or somewhere else does not work
very well
and that is why i came up with that
second reason is i do well before coving
and now it's starting and i flew around
quite a lot
so when you want to write a report
you shouldn't be relying too much on the
internet to write that
because then you lose the time in the
airplane that's another reason for that
that's why it's monolithic you can use
it with multiple um analysts but in or
you could with um
just putting data on a share so super
easy that way um
no it's not but it works
um forget about that there's a new will
be a new version out pretty soon
one of the good things is you get visual
timelines and one important thing in
incident response is those false
negatives things that you miss right
those are the denture things so if a
timeline is inconsistent if there is an
indication that you miss something
you should see that graphically you
should visually see that i'll give an
example we saw exfiltration to mega with
our clone or something no mega sync
and it ended like
seven eight hours before encryption in
the ransomware case
ah sorry these water and
the thing about that is uh
we couldn't make sense of that did they
go on vacation or what was going on
there
and the thing was we then realized
because we saw that that they recovered
that machine from a backup that was
exactly seven hours older that was the
reason
so they got a little bit newer snapshot
which gave us a little bit more locks
about the exfiltration but we would have
missed that without the graphical
representation because if it's in a flat
table every distance between two lines
looks the same right
that is super dangerous
and you also get an idea about the
lateral movement and here we're looking
for islands so if you see lateral
movement between machine a and b and if
a big cluster like that then the
question is how is a and b connected
with the rest of the cluster we must be
missing something
that is also important and then we
hooked it up to other tools
like wires total or misp so we can shoot
every indicator right into miss so it
goes on the feet
right investigation
this is going to be the new version i'll
just show you real quick at least i
tried to
it's not out yet
because there's something in the ukraine
that
came in the way a little bit
that is
a mirror this is
oh great
let me just see
look i had to google how to mirror the
displays on the new macos uh this is
what it looks like um it's a little bit
different it's a web application as you
can see it will work on a um on a graph
database so there's neo4j in the
background of that whole thing and the
idea is the same right so you have like
the master timeline is the thing you
talk about but on the other hand if
you're new to a case you get some
information already right you start into
a case um we start a case with a
questionnaire so depending on what kind
of case that is we ask different
questions right we also ask
non-technical questions like are you
publicly traded because then we want to
know in which uh stock exchange if it's
in new york
we know we're gonna have to deal with
the sec and that's not fun
right so that is just um what i'm
talking about you get an indication so
that would be a typical case where you
have an access broker right
so you see like on the left hand side
some activity and then on the right
again and in between nothing so either
you're really missing a lot
or it was an excess broker you see how
long they have been breached so quite
long and
the other thing is it helps you
throughout the process so as i said you
can look through the timeline like this
but you also have the visual timeline
where you can later see gaps
so you see exactly what happened
let's walk through it real quick so we
had a web shell you know outlook
vulnerability we had tons of these
the attacker put in recharge with the
recharge the rdp to localhost that works
pretty well with the admin user that
they got right off the web server they
installed something kill av but then
they ran mimikats under the name x64
which is quite frequent
we got that
installation because that's when the
file got there we also got the execution
here
because they double clicked it on the
desktop
then they pivoted to the domain
controller they started cobalt strike
there and on that server we seen the
shellbacks that they were looking for a
file server or a server called f1 and
the finance share there that is as far
as it goes we can look at it from the um
from the lateral movement perspective if
we want to
it's not super complex it's an easy case
right i just made that up out of real
data but it's not a real case
and also it will help you in the future
and that's very new in cleaning up so
for example uh all the it's a graph
database right so everything can be
connected with everything
so in other terms uh before that we had
that that the timeline
and we had that malware stuff and we had
to go through the malware tab and filter
for hosts to make a cleanup plan for a
specific host now you just need to go
like for example this is the exchange
server go ahead and say okay what kind
of malware do we have on this server
okay those three things
get rid of these then we should be good
to go um
what is the specific timeline for this
machine
only for this machine and all of the
things can be well presented in any
given way which gives me a little bit
more flexibility
to
work on your suggestions before that it
was very difficult in the old version
because with data model now everything
is possible because we are talking about
a network here and
it's in the end all about um uh
the presentation and that can be changed
quickly the underlying data model that's
a different story but presentation
that's usually just a matter of time
nothing else
and uh well this is the idea there any
questions
oh it will be open sourced again uh the
problem with that is uh i just do that
once it's
far enough that pull request will not
kill me that is the idea
thank you matthias thank you
[Applause]
are there any questions in the room
hi thanks for the presentation uh i just
have one question related to resource
management so as you mentioned very
wisely so the the case is a
very important exciting event for the
customer
but it is less for the team who does
that every day so how do you manage
resource management uh in the face that
the customer expects people to work on
the case every time all night and just
people just have lives
on the side of that
the funny thing about that is that my
perception especially in switzerland is
very different than when working in
other countries so in switzerland i made
the experience that clients are very
relaxed and reasonable that's not always
the case in incident response
and uh there it works and otherwise it's
about it's the
the client will not be watching you work
what the client sees is progress
so what you need to make sure is that
whenever the client expects progress
they get to see progress no matter when
it was made and that could also mean if
it doesn't
that the the major uh thing is never
hurt the client
but if the client gets crazy that also
will hurt the client so in a nutshell it
also might mean dosing information
right so instead of just throwing
everything in a client sometimes it
helps the case to dose the information
wisely give the right information at the
right time not not basically over flat
the client
that is what helps there
we have time for two more questions
yeah thank you very much for those
awesome talk um i have two quick
questions hopefully first is
yeah it's interesting hearing your
experience building a team and getting
that all set up and sorted uh we're in
like similar situations typically and
we're finding it's a bit of a especially
if you're dealing with a lot of legacy
baggage and way things were done
especially with tooling
we're finding like there's a there's an
over over tooling in some ways where you
have so many tools and so many ways you
know people need to know how to use them
and they overlap in a lot of ways like
how do you avoid going down that rabbit
hole of over tooling and over
complicating things essentially
first of all congratulations to building
your own team that's a lot of fun
sometimes
secondly over tooling
my usual quota on that thing is a fool
with a tool is still a fool and that is
what we see very much and i i would like
to respond with the question based
approach so if the tool answers specific
questions
well then it has its legitimacy right
in in that case if it doesn't um or it's
like
also covered by three other tools then
you have to make your selection
but what the i like the question because
there's one thing that i didn't say
about that because obviously and i think
you know that oftentimes you get asked
by the client hey we bought that super
expensive tool why don't you use that
and some organizations too do and the
problem with that is then they're not as
efficient because how could you right
you're used to a certain approach and
you're only efficient if you use that
and that is uh some advice that i might
give you and that is something i said to
our ceo when i started that
i said you have to be prepared to turn
down cases because if we want to be
successful we do it our way if we have
to do it in another way we're just
one like the others right
and that means that if they don't want
it that way then well
try someone else and come back later
when they fail that's what we did very
often and they kept coming back trust
them great cool thanks and second
question is uh relating to the point you
made about where companies
more and more are uh you know
looking at the the legal stuff and like
they're looking more and more when an
incident happens it's very stressful
obviously
in some cases kind of for a scapegoat
for example so you come in and the risk
for the
for us is supporting we want to support
them but if things don't quite go so
smoothly or well they're looking for
someone to blame essentially how do we
reduce that risk of where we are blamed
where ultimately we're just trying to
help and support them right and how do
we reduce our risk exposure from that
well one of one of the things is um you
shouldn't deviate too much from the
industry standard
that is one thing because that's what
you're going to be measured so whenever
for example um i write an expert witness
report for for court or something for
for damage
things
then my reference is always uh the
industry standard at the time the
knowledge at that time i can compare i
just recently wrote something for for
for an incident that happened in 2019
um so the organization got on site they
charged like 10 000 a day for one person
which is quite a lot they got inside um
they investigated until friday and
friday they said you're clean now
on sunday they were fully encrypted
and so we're looking at day one right
knowledge of 2019. um they knew because
they had it in their daily report that
at this day they had uh emoted on one of
the domain controllers 2019 remember
sodino kiwi emotric but all that stuff
was was on that that time
and i found from that vendor i found a
blog article no actually it was a
webcast like two or three weeks prior to
that event where they said exactly
that's all nowadays it's always related
to those ransomware attacks right
so that means they didn't act after
after what they set themselves right and
that's the ideal thing right so you have
to basically just align to the industry
standard then they can't they can still
blame you but they cannot hurt you too
much
you can always say that this is it was
this was normal back then
so we are a bit limited for more
questions so i invite you to come
directly to matthias if you have any
more questions thank you thank you
matthias thank you