so hey everyone I'm a doctor X as was
introduced um senior security researcher
cyber adapt and I am responsible for
keeping everybody on track and
presenting our speakers so here we have
two awesome speakers we have kasim ijaz
and he works from Blue Bastion and we
have Adam Andrew Clinton and she works
for a Vienna Healthcare and they're
gonna make their introduction and
they're gonna talk about stealing the
beans so enjoy thank you thank you
it's uh it's weird being in South and
talking about beans
like y'all probably know better how to
spill beans than we do
um so I'm uh Gossip as mentioned I work
at Blue Bastion security I'm the
director of offensive security there
and we've got Andrew I'm Andrew Clinton
I'm a director of cyber security at
Aviana Healthcare we're a large
healthcare provider based out of Atlanta
Georgia
and uh this this talk really is a
combination of text messages okay uh of
course it's presented more in like a
PowerPoint now because hey we are
professionals after all uh but uh Andrew
and I were for many years now just just
complaining to each other how terrible
the pen test was and how terrible the
scope was or how we fired a consulting
firm or something like that what did
this company do what did this company do
well what did they do poorly the
original incarnation of this talk was
intended I don't need slides I just need
45 minutes and Podium I'm not complaint
just give me like a lazy boy and just
lay in there and just complain for a
while yeah so the talk is really about
the the ways we've found some consulting
firms do good work the ways we found
them not do great work and we'll talk
about the perspective of a
consulting firm and then the perspective
of a client but also perspective for a
candidate Okay so
why don't we start with that so client
wise you know it's going to be how do
you evaluate a consulting firm
it'll work on that how do you engage
with your security partners and get the
most value out of those engagements you
know what to keep an eye out for
if there are good security consulting
firms they're a not so good consumer
security consulting firms and there are
challenges with navigating those
relationships and we'll talk through a
little bit of that
and then we'll jump into working as the
consultant or the consulting firm how do
you engage with client how do you push
for transparency and really build that
relationship and then as Q mentioned at
the very end we've got uh we've got a
section on as a potential employee of a
consulting firm if you're looking for a
job well can you keep an eye out for to
try to avoid toxic workplaces or you
know places you don't want to wind up
because we did line up in a few places
that you shouldn't wind up real world
stories
um I think uh before we step into the
actual details a little disclaimer so a
lot of this stuff all this stuff it
comes from Real World experiences like
awesome will buy custom and I have had
either together or at firms we've worked
at other all points in time stories
we're not naming and shaming in this
session although we'd kind of love to
well we're shaming but we're not naming
shaming but not naming yeah but um it's
as all all real stuff that we experience
but it's all point in time so any uh any
firms that we encounter the problems
with May no longer be the situation that
they may have changed they may have
updated but it's it's still a good story
to tell so not not naming but uh but
talking about frustrations and
challenges and how to approach them
all right so
so for our first our first perspective
here as the clients
um one of the most important things that
you want to talk to
talk with your consulting firm about or
your goals
um
this is a critical item to communicate
especially in those initial discussions
where you're talking to sales you're
talking about engineering you're trying
to arrange for a pen test or some sort
of an audit you know any initial sales
discussions scoping discussions you want
to make sure that your goals are brought
to the table and that the company that
you're talking to has the ability to
help you achieve those goals there's
sometimes there's a there's a breakdown
there
um a lot of the times the sales
representatives will be happy to sell
you whatever you're asking for
but can they actually do it and do they
actually have the staff to to achieve
what you want to do you know are you
looking for a a comprehensive mobile pen
test for an application that needs three
weeks worth of work do they have the
skills on staff to do it do they have
the uh do they have the availability
um and you want to have those
conversations be upfront with that stuff
make sure you get clear answers and make
sure that that's a two-way conversation
and that
that it winds up in the documentation
you know so
you know as you're talking through hey
these are my goals this is what I want
to achieve with this engagement we're
paying you x amount of money for for
services rendered you know make sure
that uh
make sure that those details of your
goals wind up in the contract the quote
or the statement will work somewhere in
writing so that they're actually
followed through on as I've seen I've
seen several situations where we have a
really good conversation with sales
sales engineering maybe we even got one
of the engine and one of the testers on
the phone and everything sounds perfect
they're going to be testing everything
to the spec that we are requesting in
this specific specific scenario and then
the paperwork comes through super
generic high level and then when the
actual testing comes down the pipe a
month later we get we get the wrong
tester and we get bad results and it's
it's not what we asked for now what we
expected so goals are really important
you want to be upfront about them and
want to make sure they're understood
received
discussed and then represented in the
paperwork and otherwise you might run
into some risk yeah and one thing that
also add to that
you define the goals you had the
conversation make sure it ends up on the
sow on the statement of work okay
because sales built that statement of
work sales had that conversation with
the client
me as a tester I am maybe two or three
layers broken diff further from sales so
might not even hear about what
conversations happened first thing I'm
going to do as a tester is look at the
sow the statement of work if it does not
talk about those goals at least at a
high level I don't know about them
so if it is not on the paper
you may not be as well covered as method
Tech just because you had a competition
with sales who knows if sales even took
notes
sales love to sell yeah yeah no we can
do that we can do that sure we got you
sure
two thousand dollars please
so as we're talking about the goals and
as we're talking about how make sure the
goals on the paper and whatnot
the flexibility to meet the goals is
also a very important piece in there
okay
um are they going to have the skill set
you want Andrew mentioned earlier
getting mobile app and test oh yeah we
got mobile app testers not a problem and
then on the side they go to the hiring
manager go hey can you hire a mobile app
and tester before the test starts all
right can you can you subcontract
another company to do the pen test for
us because hey we're going to make the
sale at the same time and there's this
nothing wrong
because then you're starting out as a
consulting firm you may not have enough
people to do all the tests that you're
going to end up selling you want to sell
more so your company gets bigger you get
more clients at the same time if you do
not have a mobile apps pen test skill
set in the company right now how do you
know the person you're hiring is
actually a good good mobile app and
tester well you already sold five pen
tests already on that topic okay so a
lot of times as a client you want to ask
those direct questions I've even had
some clients ask me to get my tester on
the line and they've interviewed them
nothing wrong with that you want to
spend fifty thousand dollars a hundred
thousand dollars on a pen test there's
nothing wrong with saying hey Consulting
form can I talk to your tester can I
evaluate their skill set you would do
that if you're hiring a person why not
do that with the company okay
will the report reflect reality we'll
talk about reports later but
when you are talking about those goals
it's important to have that conversation
with the consulting firm and say is the
report going to be related to my goals I
want a pen test because I want to comply
with HIPAA right but the report is
written for PCI
would that even make sense
so clarifying that beforehand and making
sure the report isn't going to be just
something like straight out of a
template and then now you're looking at
it going will my CFO like paying for
this will my data governance officer
like this will my HIPAA assessor look at
the report and go this was written for a
Healthcare Company
you know I'm Healthcare company but your
report talks all about credit card data
we don't have any credit card data so no
findings done no findings awesome you
guys are looking good the finding is you
did not have credit card data
um and this is where the buckets come in
and I'll let Andrew talk about the
bucket so so I want to talk about the
bucket story I'm a shoehorn in one other
thing real quick I want to mention it so
I've worked for I'm currently working in
an internal role as a director of cyber
security for a large Healthcare
organization but I've worked for three
different uh consulting firms over the
course of my career and on at least at
least 10 or 15 occasions especially with
the smaller firms
sales has sold something
and then the director calls me up and
says hey we sold this thing we don't
know how to do it figure it out
you know what do we need we got we got a
mobile test in a week what do you need
to accomplish that in an effective way
and
do we have what we need to conduct a
presentation
but uh yes um I'm gonna keep going but
it's I think it happens a lot more often
than you would expect and the the
trouble there is it's not always
transparent to the client the client
doesn't always know hey
company X said they'd be happy to give
us a mobile test you know in reality
they don't have the skills to do it and
they're going to try to find the skills
in three weeks leading up to the start
date and are those going to be good
skills are those going to be
comprehensive are they going to
Outsource it you know what does that
look like it gets Messier it's not
saying it's not going to guarantee a bad
result but the risk goes up
and you as the client don't have
visibility on that at all but um it
doesn't fit into our bucket this was a
real situation happened about a year ago
I wanted a internal Network pen test we
had some very specific goals and we
didn't want a general you know drop into
the network run run responder then try
to Pivot through A.D we had some
specific areas we wanted to Target with
specific set of engineering skills and I
even had a buddy of mine working at a
large a large pen test firm who I knew
had the skills to do it and he was
excited about the idea so I got on the
phone with him and one of his sales guys
and we started talking through it it was
now a long phone call talking about the
engineering
really exciting we are on the same page
my goals are lining up with what he
could do and everything was perfect
there from an engineering discussion
standpoint and what this should have
boiled down to was hey
let me pay for 80 hours worth of this
guy's time and we'll get the job done
and then we'll write whatever report but
we ran into a problem because because of
the size of the consultancy and the the
rigid way they do sales there were
certain types of services that they
offer certain types of buckets of
services that they offer and what I was
asking for didn't fit into any of those
and so we got through this fantastic
engineering discussion really excited to
hey we're gonna we're gonna give EDR a
run for its money we're going to do some
Invasion stuff we're gonna really hit
some areas hard on the network that
don't normally get touched it's going to
be really interesting and the sales guys
like
yeah it is
it's not on my list here
and I I hate to say it but that's that's
where that conversation died
we tried to have follow-up discussions
but the the quote the quoting process
the statement of work just fell apart
because of the bridges structured the
way they do sales it didn't fit into
what they normally sold even though on
the back end it would have just been
hours
hey give me give me 80 hours of this
guy's time you know it's a
225 250 an hour and let's go through and
write me a report at the end not that
complicated
um all right
responsiveness and project management
exciting Okay so
love-hate relationship with project
manager I love it I love it a lot but
it's it uh it stays up you love to hate
it I hate to love it yes yes okay is it
Friday and my PM's asking for updates or
is it Monday and I'm telling the team
what to do
um
uh communication and project management
so there's a recurring theme throughout
this whole throughout this whole
presentation about transparency and
communication between client and
consultant and you know that's a huge
huge deal if you want to talk to each
other have an understanding be open and
honest and transparent
um it's a in those initial stages when
working with an outside consulting firm
you want to make sure that they're that
they're timely they're respectful of
your time
um
do they have the resources available do
they have the time on their schedule to
do what you're asking or are they just
having to take your phone calls and
potentially line up the sale
um
are they well organized do they miss
meetings do they they uh you know do
they ignore emails do they not get back
to you for for weeks not not naming any
names
um
but um
is there a dedicated project manager on
their side it's something that that I've
run into
quite a lot and it it surprises me
um most most of consultants and firms
will have project man dedicated project
managers and they serve a critical role
they let the testers do the testing the
directors do other things and management
do other things and the project managers
coordinate the meetings can coordinate
the conversation and make sure things
happen on schedule and get done but if
you call it the consultancy firm and
everything sounds good but there's no
project manager
oh that's kind of a red flag and who's
who's keeping track who's making sure
that we're hitting those milestones and
and moving the project forward
um yeah and again are they respectful of
your time do they miss meetings do they
show up late uh
how do they communicate to you
um said if uh if a firm is disrespectful
or unorganized you know it could mean
that their their overall overwhelmed
with other work and they're not they're
not capable of taking on the project
that you're asking for or maybe they
don't have a project management team or
they have a bad project management team
and I think any of those you know
they're not necessarily deal breakers
but they're red flags it could increase
the risk you know every any time I I
sign a statement of work and I don't see
a project manager on the other side
I'm thinking to myself the report's
going to be late
[Laughter]
that also is this
time zones
when it comes to practice management you
gotta understand the start stop time
when did the test start when does it end
but time zone is very important it's
there's nothing wrong with hanging
overseas testers there's a lot of really
good talent in the US and outside the US
but if your tester is going to be
testing during the time all of you are
sleeping
and they have a question which is
sometimes the question is important
enough they cannot test without an
answer to it
you lost a whole day of testing really a
whole night of testing right if they ran
a scan for example or they were testing
something and something went down and
they were testing that specific
application has gone down now well
something pretty bad has happened I
would write that down as a finding in my
in my opinion but at the same time I
can't test anymore I gotta wait for your
team to wake up next morning and then
I'll test the night after that right so
discuss the time zones understand when
the testing is going to happen and make
sure resources are available on both
sides for that and it's it's critical
for a number of reasons but I wanted I
want that we're talking about we'll talk
about price transparency a little bit
further on but uh but on the back ends
99 of the time it boils down to
engineering hours and so if if your
tester is testing overnight and they run
into a problem you know they're gonna
test for an eight-hour block and at 2
A.M you know two hours into their
testing they uh they run into a problem
and that stops them dead in the water is
that and then your team can't respond to
their emails for another six hours is
that six hours lost yeah you know how
does how does that company handle it is
there an escalation chain to try to
resolve it is there other stuff that can
be done to to give them work to do to
keep working because
six hours could be a lot of money and if
you have multiple testers working on a
single project it just it just
multiplies yeah I mean average rate is
like 200 250 an hour right now in the
consulting firms that's a lot of money
there for sure so
very important piece of information if
there's one thing you walk away with
from here ask for a sample deliverable
ask for a sample report from the
consulting firm if you don't know what
the report is going to look like
you're not gonna like whatever you
receive after spending fifty thousand
dollars because it will either not be
something that fits your organizational
culture
or it is maybe great quality but they're
wrote it from a different perspective
okay I had a pen test where I was
testing 35 applications
when you're doing that it's very
important to know if you want all 35 in
one report or 35 separate reports okay
and at the same time understanding what
the client was looking for is important
so ask for a sample report if the
company doesn't have it because
something firm doesn't have it ask them
to go and redact the clients report and
send it to you right I I don't want to
spend fifty thousand dollars or
something that I have not seen
if they don't have a sample report that
might be another red flag
yeah so as we're talking about reporting
it's very important that when you look
at the report it speaks to you about
your environment
okay if you for example are heavily
Linux environment and the report is all
about Windows did they just not touch
the Linux environment did they not have
the skill set for it
if I am Healthcare company and there's
no discussion of ephi in there they
gained domain admin they gained access
to databases but they did not even
attempt to gain access to ephi do they
even know what business I'm in
I was working for a healthcare provider
and they wrote a critical finding we saw
your critical information for doctors
online okay what information is it oh we
saw the NPI numbers
do you know what MPS stands for no
national public
identity but it is it's it's public
information all right like you are
telling me that you found public
information is critical it's and nothing
wrong with with you thinking that right
you saw some random numbers in front of
a name that looks kind of serious but
Google see what that actually means
right uh use one finding the road was
sensitive Services exposed to the
internet
the sensitive Service Port 22 SSH all
right or sensitive it's very sensitive
yeah and they also a lot of findings
stating that we had uh really outdated
SSH server
now realizing it was a red hat with
backboarded patches and headers okay so
yeah they never tried to log in there
was no attempt of trying to go the next
step okay you give me a report and you
said you guessed a password that doesn't
mean anything to me what did you do with
that password did you even find that we
have MFA that you couldn't use that
password with did you even try to log in
to email did you even try to log into
maybe a payroll system what do you do
with that information is what's going to
be important show me impact in that
report don't just give me a finding the
self-signed certificate on the internal
network is not going to matter as much
as a self-science certificate on the
external network okay and I I still see
reports with oh you're using TLS 1.1
it's a high risk issue well show me like
show the impact don't just hand me a
fine name right so as you're looking at
the sample deliverable look for those
things and I'll end that way then I'll
hand it over to you
vulnerability scan is not a pen test
give me a nest Report with your logo on
it this is not a fantastic report
I could run NASA scan myself for 2500
pay 50 000 for a NASA scan okay so be
very mindful of these things because
there is a lot of that still happening
nowadays we've been making jokes about
nasus as a fantastic tool for many years
now and that stuff is still happening
if you find a consultancy firm that
sells you a full-fledged pen test for
two thousand dollars you're probably
getting an essay scan
[Laughter]
so this is kind of
hired a seat but we're moving on to the
consultant section and uh
you know I drink and I know things
because I'm a consultant I had I
actually have a news story about the
reporting piece oh I'm going back yeah
so so this is this is actually a nice
story is that about it it's new no no no
it's not you not you it's someone else
and it's not a catastrophic but it goes
to show it was a failure on my part we
had a uh we had a purple team operation
conducted with in conjunction with an
external third party and the the purple
tea mop itself was fantastic huge huge
value there the Tactical level you know
teams were working together well we got
a lot of great results out of it a lot
of great takeaways and you know it gave
us ideas and pushed us further but the
report that we got so it was a purple
team op the report that we got was very
much structured like a pen test report
and it kind of outlined technical risk
it highlighted the attacks that were
performed
um but the attacks that were performed
were conducted in a purple team context
so it's not necessarily that we're
vulnerable to the attacks but that's
what was used to exercise the detection
and response systems however if you
glanced at the report it looks like a
pen test report and it looks like we're
vulnerable to all these you know like a
legal team glancing at those reports
gonna be like
did you guys fix all these you guys fix
all these attacks that were vulnerable
to it no no no that's not that's not
what that was but the structure of the
report was such that it gave that
perspective and it it's it led to
confusion and we we had to we had to fix
the report on the back end but that was
a situation where I should have asked
for a sample report we should have
talked over it ahead of time and
resolved that so we weren't trying to
fix it afterwards
um that way the the report communicated
what we were trying to achieve and what
we actually achieved in the exercise
rather than looking like a pen test
Report with a whole bunch of unfixed
vulnerabilities that weren't really
vulnerabilities
that's you all right
so
so stepping into the consultant
perspective
um or the consultancy perspective I
think the one of the best things you can
do is you can tailor tailor the work to
the clients you know it's kind of
calls back to that initial talking about
goals you know engage with the client
talk about
talk about their environment talk about
what they want to do
talk about what they want to achieve
talk about how testing should be
performed where the focuses should be
where the risks are you know we already
talked about uh
um about reporting and tailoring
reporting
accordingly but I think transparency
about how the work is being done open
communication and respectful
communication of hey this is how we're
going to step through our process and
help you achieve your goals and deliver
that final high value report you know
it's it's it's critical and there's a
lot of companies that will
that will go through the initial stages
sign off on the work and then quietly do
the tests in the backgrounds and the the
tester is never actually on the phone
with like the blue team or the uh the
internal representatives and sometimes
that's okay you know sometimes as a
client you know it's it's a fairly
isolated test and you know if it's a web
app that's that we just need to you know
do our annual annual pen test or mobile
app where we don't need to necessarily
chat about it of course in the process
sometimes that like working in a box is
okay but if you're if you're doing an
internal pen test in a large Network and
uh
and scope is only so much but the
Network's massive and you're trying to
find out how best to use your time talk
to the client
you know have those discussions about
what the client wants to test you know
what are the areas of focus and what are
they concerned about and uh
and work through it adjust your
communication level to what the client
prefers you know some clients want start
and stop emails every day or an end of
the week wrap-up email saying hey we
tested all week long we found these high
value findings you know you'll get more
details in the report some clients don't
want to talk to the the Consultants at
all and that's okay too but have those
discussions ahead of time so you can get
out in front of uh in front of that and
make sure that you're fitting what the
client's expected
so uh we already touched quite a bit of
this one thing I do want to mention here
and it goes into the transparency slide
um
if you are
that's you
um
if you want a pen test to be done and
report to be delivered on December 31st
you may want to tell and schedule that
before December 25th
okay had a client a really big very big
name in the industries wanting a pen
test they were going live with the
product on January 1st but they came to
us end of the December like week or two
left we still got the pentas done okay
money money money
um but uh we had critical findings where
you could see patient data without
providing credentials on public internet
they still went live January 1st
okay so speak to the as a consultant
it's important for us to speak the
client about their goals and their
method and uh you know capabilities at
the same time speak to your own
capabilities about timing if you want a
good pen test go to the consulting firm
and have them do it in q1 or Q2
Q4 is a really busy time and the worst
time to do the pen test right we're
competing against PTO versus getting
billable hours and then you end up with
some places where we were in one place
where they're paying us extra as testers
to work as robbers okay so just be
careful with that
uh priced transparency all right price
this was a huge pet peeve for my oil
tried to run through it quickly so I'm
gonna try not to complain too much
that's uh there's there's a huge amount
of companies out there that will happily
hand you a code this is one pen test
fifty thousand dollars please and
there's no additional details no no
detailed statement will work just uh
yeah no we'll do that pen test and this
is how much it's going to charge
um but uh but as as we kind of talked
about it a little bit already on the
back end the price is almost always
determined by the number of hours worked
so one one thing that I've seen inside
inside the consulting firms is sometimes
the consulting firm will undercut their
competition
and slash engineering hours to to fit
that without making it transparent to
the customer so you know pen testing
from one you know quotes at 50 000 pen
testing firm two says oh they quoted
fifty thousand we'll do it for we'll do
it for thirty thousand and there's
without transparency the client may not
be aware that
you're getting the same deal on an
hour-by-hour basis yeah but you're just
not seeing those hours disappear
um
you know I needed 250 an hour one
engineer for 40 hours a week is ten
thousand dollars if uh if you get you
know client or Consulting for May I
think coach 10 000 and consulting firm B
uh quotes five thousand consolidate firm
B may present the same the same
statement of work but really they're
only putting 20 hours into that test
instead of 40. yeah I mean put the
number of hours what are the cost on the
sow let's be transmitted and there's I
don't think there's any good reason to
hide that breakdown so price
transparency is critical of me
um if I have to reverse engineer your
quote your statement will work to find
out like where that money is where my
money's going I'm gonna be annoyed at
the outside
um but uh but yeah that can be a little
bit of a red flag but it's it's fairly
common just to kind of Disguise it yeah
so uh one more thing in the console
important perspective and this really
dives into the next topic which is going
to be by the candidate perspective but
training and culture as consulting firms
one things that we often fail at is the
training perspective I've seen some
forms require things like you have to
have oscp to be a consultant I teach
oscp in the after hours and I can tell
you now
it doesn't create good Consultants it
doesn't create good pen testers all
right but across training among your
organization is great creating a culture
of positivity we've got a lot of
negativity in this industry you know we
are all leads we all feel like we know
the best we all have opinions on things
but when you do not have a culture of
collaboration you have a culture of
competition among your own employees and
that just creates a terrible work
environment right so as we talk about
that we jump into the interview red
flags
it's we're running a little short time
we'll run through this really quick
um so there's a couple more stories here
but I think I think really the the high
level takeaways here is if you're a
candidate if you're looking to get a job
with a consulting firm keep an eye on
the documentation keep an eye on what
they're offering you you know look at
look at ndas non-compete agreements as
you're walking in the door you know
those are pretty standard non-compete
Agreements are fairly standard ndas are
extremely standard because you're
dealing with sensitive information from
a bunch of different clients but keep an
eye on the time frame you know it
a five-year NDA you know is a little
unreasonable a three-year NDA might make
sense in some contexts but generally
like 12 months 12 months after leaving
the company is is my experience pretty
standard
um non-competes are pretty vicious too
especially in certain contexts sometimes
companies will put
unenforceable non-compete agreements in
the documentation that you sign you're
pressured in signing it and you know
it's got like I said unenforceable from
a legal standpoint but it's meant to
scare you it's meant to so I've seen
non-compete agreements that say that you
can you cannot go work for another
consulting firm for five years it's like
yeah and that's that's not really it's
state by state that's not really
something that can be enforced yeah but
the employee doesn't always know that
and so you feel like you're stuck in
this job and you can't go take those
skills elsewhere when you discover that
as a highly toxic workplace and you want
to leave
um if you're in the interview process
and they're disrespecting your time or
if you're unable to meet with your
future team or your future manager those
are huge red flags you know keep an eye
out for those an interview should always
be a two-way street it should always be
mutually respectful and a good
productive conversation if it's
if it's six interviews of them grilling
you on technical skills and you never
get to actually meet the people you
ground will be working with or working
for uh maybe go find something else
there's a whole lot of openings in the
field
um grilling the interviewee is is a
serious problem or uh being elitist if
you walk into an interview in the uh in
the interviewer is is elitist like no no
just don't put up with that go uh go
hunt some more somewhere else yeah and
you know what turn it around ask the
hiring manager when was the last time
they took PTO right I asked them when
was the last time they went for a
training
um why are you hiding right now did you
have layoffs recently it's a two-way
interview why not okay so
as you are going to the interview
process assess the employer also
think about the reputation check glass
door glass door is great place for you
to see sort of Yelp reviews for
employers
um what kind of Technology do they use I
was working at a place where I was using
a Dell Inspiron
for my pen testing I will do pen testing
the daytime and I would take it to my
hotel room in the evening and it would
be cracking passwords okay while I'm
sleeping and it's running in the
background tracking passwords the hotel
didn't have a heat bill because my
laptop was hitting the room up but uh it
was terrible
and then I would use the same laptop to
run NASA scans
as I'm writing report for the previous
client so think about that what kind of
Technology are they using internally
um how often are the double triple
booked on an engagement
that's a that's a big red flag okay
um and what is the billable goal if
their billable goal which is the goal
for you how many hours you spend on a
client engagement if it's 100 well when
do I go to the bathroom all right so
think about and ask those questions
directly because they're gonna have a
big role in your work there most
consulting firms should have a very
specific billable goal that they're
targeting for any consultant working for
them and 80 is generally a good number
it's probably the highest I would go for
60 to 80 yeah you start going north of
80 and you're stressing out and you know
overworking people you're pushing them
in the 50 60 hour weeks because when you
take PTO you're not billable yeah
so
in conclusion you know beans have been
spilled it's kind of hard to see in
there I love that picture yeah but
always look for transparency both client
and the consultant okay and the
candidate look for transparency in there
I think that's it
um
five minutes for questions and we've got
some stickers and business cards in here
if you want any but questions
no no and so the question was uh asking
about the project manager on from The
consultancy Firm during those initial
conversations I would say so long as a
project manager is present that's that's
a good sign it's it's when you're going
through those sales and early
engineering discussions and building out
the scope of work if there's no project
manager present
um then you maybe want to ask about it
but uh depending on your circumstance
you might want to ask for specific PM
yeah I have some more questions there
but uh I think the biggest word flag for
me is when we start having those
discussions and the project managers
just non-existent yeah that author tells
me they don't have project managers or
they've got a very limited project
management team and there could be some
disorganization there is no industry in
the world that has more ADHD than pen
testers all right you you expect others
to manage our time not going to happen
okay if it was up to me I would never
stop and testing which means I will
never end up writing a report which I'll
I nobody loves writing a report okay so
project manager plays a very important
role in that making sure things are on
time making sure that we are delivering
on time making sure that goals are met
of the test so it's definitely a
dedicated product manager not
necessarily a product manager specific
to that client maybe they're taking on
10 clients but their job is to make sure
that goals are met and timelines are bad
that yeah are there any uh projects that
make you stand out more
you want to take that one sure the
question is are there any projects that
make you stand out more at as a
candidate uh one of those is right now
right here you're at a conference
right it's it's a little difficult to
show your work in pen testing than it
may be in development okay you don't
have a portfolio that you can chill but
doing things like hack the Box try hack
me and most importantly being at a
conference especially a small conference
like B size amazing place for hiring
there are probably a lot of hiding
managers in here right now a lot of
candidates in here right now and also
one thing I would recommend for
everybody wanting to get their own pen
testing figure out a way to present at a
conference everybody has something to
share we all do we may feel like we
don't but we all have something to share
or at least do what we are doing stand
up and just complain right these are all
the terrible firms I tried to get hired
by yeah but definitely find a way to
present Duke ctfs
um and most of all make connections to
people as I'd say as a hiring manager
one of the things that I love to hear
most from a prospective candidate is
like a passion project something
technical either from a previous job or
something outside something you're
excited about that's it's Technical and
just something that you can just ramble
on and on about because I'll let you go
and just listen yeah because the passion
is the passion is really important you
know technical skills you know details
can be learned along the way they can be
trained but uh that that drive is huge
well one last question yeah go ahead
so the question is what are your
thoughts about clients requesting in
ndas for the testers for that project
oh
I'm not allowed to talk about that so
the question is the tests are signing an
NDA individually for the client
um so as a hiding manager as a manager
inside a consulting firm I would push
back against that right I'm not having
my tester sign an idea to you for two
reasons one I don't know if that tester
is gonna do the test for you
things can change maybe they need a PTO
right at last minute maybe they end up
in a hospital okay so that's gonna be a
nightmare in terms of scheduling because
now we have to find another tester to
sign in any a second I'm gonna lose
people if I ask them to sign ndas with a
client individually because now they're
individually responsible
so that the legal backing of the company
gets getting muddy water in there
uh I mean I sometimes have clients asked
me to do a background check for a tester
from them and that's that's a pain yeah
MBA is going to be even bigger pain yeah
yeah I think the the request for
individual background checks and the
repressor individual ndas have fallen to
similar bucket and in my experience I've
seen I've seen testers refuse because I
mean from a legal standpoint the
relationship between the two companies
there's an overarching NDA that should
cover everything and most clients 90 of
clients are happy with that I think some
clients do get specific they get picky
they want to run individual background
checks and new individual ndas but that
that gets messy real quick all right I'm
with Q I would push back against that
but it does happen and sometimes
sometimes your consultancy firm and
you've got a multi-million dollar client
that's throwing their weight around and
you have to play ball it's and it's a
rough situation but uh I said I'm
opposed to it but sometimes it's just
the reality of working with really big
companies
all right thanks everybody uh we got
stickers
take the stickers you need to get rid of
stickers yeah I'm going to get rid of
the stickers