thank you everybody for coming to the
ninth workshop on hot topics in privacy
enhancing technologies hot pets 2016 I'd
like to introduce the people behind the
program today in some sense I had some
great co-chairs that helped put together
this workshop Saudi off rose from XE who
was unfortunately not able to be here
today and also more it's Bartel of the
Renewable Freedom Foundation who is over
there so you can thank him or blame him
and then there's myself from the US
Naval Research Laboratory so the three
of us kind of did everything so if you
have any complaints or you know well
wishes or compliments you know you can
blame the three of us we kind of did
everything from publicizing to deciding
the papers to putting the website
deciding what goes on the website so it
was kind of all rolled into one from us
okay so I kind of wanted to explain what
Hot Heads is as opposed to pets um it
was a question of if it was not hot
enough yet this week do we really want
to get hotter so uh well we will it's
gonna get hotter and I hope that you'll
enjoy it so yeah there wasn't actually a
proposal for cool pets that may appear
in future years but not this year so we
had some set we have some separate goals
or slightly different goals from hot
pets one is that we try to present new
ideas more um we provide prioritize that
more or less mature work we're open to
and even invite people to present so
that you can give ideas before it's
fully formed and would appear in a
journal for example so you can get
feedback or so people can get early
early results also we try to be
accessible to communities that don't
typically publish academic papers so if
you're a journalist or you write code
for a living you might not want to or
really know how to write a 15-page
proceedings of privacy as you can have
technology symposium paper but if you
want to reach this community and you'd
like to talk about what you do hotpads
is a great
for you to submit to we just asked for a
two page proposal just telling us what
you're going to talk about and we're
open to any kind of format you don't
need to have references so we try to be
accessible a little beyond the core
audience of academics to mix communities
a bit how we also prioritize group
discussions so we have a fairly long
time for each talk at least relative to
this year's pets 25 minutes but we ask
the authors to only use a part of that
and reserve a great deal of that for
people to talk so I know there are lots
of the individual discussions that
happen during the week I mean there are
some questions that happen during the
pets talks but we give a lot more time
so that you can you know have a two
minute back and forth if there's enough
time for your individual question and as
a group we can kind of hear what other
people think and I think there's value
to that and also uh we're sort of a
little trying to have fun I look trying
to be a little more relaxed here at hot
pets so in that spirit I thought I would
try to give you some analogies for the
difference between pets and hot pets if
the raw facts didn't kind of get the
message across okay so pets might be
more like the family dog it's dependable
you know he's reliable and he's around
for a long time we're hot pets might be
more like your cute new puppy he's more
rambunctious he makes a little bit more
noise but he has his own you know unique
value another analogy you could say pets
is like the awesome power of the dark
side Darth Vader you know this is a guy
whose power you can't deny he's going to
take over and rule universe with an iron
fist wear hot pants might be more like
kylo Ren the force awakens villain who
is in Adonai bleep our fall on his own
right but as a little more impetuous and
a little bit of control it safe on a
final analogy
pets might be the esteemed chair of
computer science our professor chaired
professor of computer science at a very
highly esteemed University in 2016 we're
hot pets might be year 2000 brilliant
sniper punky and over okay so some
logistics here to explain how this whole
thing works so you know what you're
seeing we did ask for two page talks
emissions so we just ask people tell us
what they were going to say and we only
do talks there aren't any proceedings
this allows you to just talk about
something and then publish it elsewhere
we want all allow that and the decision
was made by just the coaches there
wasn't a big pc it's just the three of
us so it's kind of ruled by of you know
triumvirate i guess i'd also like to
suggest how we do fit into hot pets
publishing how you might work hot pets
into your PO pets submission eventually
so on the right we can see the possibly
tortuous life cycle of april pets
submission all the way through major
revisions to maybe minor revisions to
hopefully accept and so you could see
hot pets as a parallel option yet
another opportunity to be judged by your
peers which is always great but it has
some separate properties so it's not the
same thing but there's some you know
mutually beneficial effects that can
happen here so we're happy to consider
you're currently not accepted or about
to be accepted papers in the pets um and
we hope that that happens sometimes so
you can come even if your paper didn't
get the decision that it wants if we
thought it would make a good hot pets
talk and then in the reverse are we hope
that we could serve as initial starting
point for ideas that do make it into a
pope has paper at some point and this
might be a good place to show those
initial ideas and get some feedback
before you turn it over to the
terrifying reviewers ok so the logistics
for the schedule today we selected nine
talks we got 29 submissions that was a
d % increase over last year so our
acceptance rate is getting a bit low I
was never my hope to make this a highly
selective very difficult to get into
venue so if this trend continues you
know future chairs may consider changing
the format increasing the number of
talks or something like that so but that
is happening we're giving 25 minutes a
talk three-fifths of which we are asking
the authors to live with themselves to
if possible so that we can have a full
ten minutes of discussion and we really
encourage people to ask questions so for
this workshop we have set up to mikes
one on both sides of the room so you
don't have to traipse across the entire
aisle or when your way around the entire
room to get to in your nearby mic so
hopefully that makes it easier for you
to just jump up when you have an idea
and add it to the discussion so please
feel free to and please do use both mics
as convenient for you will have four
sessions and will also have a keynote
that's going to happen right before
lunch dan Meredith of the open
Technology Fund will be giving that talk
I'm I'm really excited to hear what he
has to say I've only read the abstract
just as you have but I've heard really
great things about done Meredith from
our esteemed co-chair more it's Pato who
knows him quite well and I think he
brings it really valuable an interesting
perspective somebody who's worked as an
activist as a journalist and now as a
funder and has a really impressive
record of funding highly impactful
technology I've asiya technologies so
I'm really looking forward to what he
has to say right before lunch similar to
pets some of our talks will be recorded
some of them will not and we've asked on
the video geographers not to record the
question-and-answer session that happens
after the talk so that the discussion
can be a little more open a little less
self-conscious so that should not be
recorded at all we have a tradition at
hot pets of having an ice cream break I
guess this would fall into the fun
category you check ice cream so that
will happen right before the last
session so you can look forward to that
and save room for some delicious ice
cream also a tradition that we have is
we give a best talk award this is an
audience vote award
and the criteria that we are asking for
is what was the best talk not
necessarily what ideas do you think will
make you know the biggest impact in the
world or are solving the most difficult
problem although that would certainly
you know suggest a talk could be very
effective but we would like to reward
people who put an effort into giving a
good talk and that's something that
doesn't always happen or maybe
rightfully as a lower priority for
highly technical works but we are trying
to be a talk format so please think
while you're listening to the talks
today which one which one or ones you
liked and then there'll be a chance to
vote during the concluding remarks we
have a mystery prize that is privacy
theme appropriate and you will see what
that is at the end okay so with that I'm
going to turn it over to our first
session chair ryan henry and our first
speakers so thanks everybody for coming
to hot pets and i hope you really
enjoyed