thank you timorous and aaron and hot
pets and everyone else who is a part of
that to invite me and have me here I
really appreciate it I'm a long time
sort of fan of pets in the work y'all
doing but my first ever time being here
so I'm feeling pretty honored I'm sorry
i I'm not going to be a very good on oh
okay this is great as far as the
sideshow goes from the technical work
you're doing I'm not going to be as
visually I'm not going to visually
fulfill you but I have one or two slides
and I'm going to show mostly because it
too much traveling but i guess to start
off with here i want to thank you all
for doing work that you maybe don't
realize that you are doing which is
supporting human rights and increasing
human rights all over the world i don't
know if you start doing the work that
you're doing thinking about that at all
but um I'm very appreciative of a large
number of you all that are doing that so
that was really slide one of two it was
for a second I don't know if anybody's
playing pokemon go or not I'm probably
not in this room that much but I
definitely have set up a profile on my
phone to play a little bit so I've been
thinking about it a lot so I wanted to
start off with that thank you and then a
very quick sort of intro of who I am and
how I got here and and then I think what
we're going to do is I'm going to tell
you some stories of some some people
that I think whose human rights have
been I think we just stopped
this is distracting me thank you though
man that was a good effort so tell you
some stories highlight some technologies
that I think are really important and
then tell you some themes just as as as
roger was saying that have been really
important to us that we developed to
help figure out what technologies and
what efforts are worth supporting and
hopefully not going to talk for very
long time because i really want you to
go to ask me anything that you want to
whether it's related to the talk that
that i presented or specific
technologies the open Technology Fund or
just anything in this field so I'm going
to start with me about 10 15 years ago I
was sort of taught by a lot of good
mentors out to be a software developer
and got involved in security in the late
90s and wireless networks ultimately
just got really disenfranchised and it
didn't sit really good about doing it
for banks and other big companies and
got involved with an organization called
Indymedia in the early 2000s and
building radio stations all over
America's and I started sort of
identifying as more of a sort of a
public interest software developer or
hacker or rather than someone who was
just doing code for anything else that
led me to Washington DC actually and
around the 2000s or mid-2000s working
for an organization called the open
Technology Institute in New America and
then during the Arab revolutions I got
excited about helping folks that were
farther away and got pulled into al
Jazeera where I'll talk a little bit
about that later but part of my job was
to do technical investigations be a part
of the journalists team and then the
other half of it was to try to increase
the security and privacy of our both
sources and journalists in the field did
that for a little bit and then
ultimately just got really fed up with
just the sort of the state of play in
the technology that was out there to
solve those challenges and was asked to
help create the this thing called the
open Technology Fund in 2012 and I've
been doing that for the last four years
so I said about what we're going to do
here I guess I've got a couple questions
I think I want to ask you all first and
I've already used a little bit of jargon
Public Interest technologists Human
Rights technologists it's not going to
be as jargony as some of the technical
talks but if you've got a question I say
in an acronym or anything just raise
your hand or like shot it out be very
informal feel like you can interrupt me
I do that enough myself I'll try to
break down what it is that you didn't
understand but just as a real quick show
of hands how many of you all have heard
of the phrase Public Interest technology
before okay good this is this is what I
have some ideas about you in the room
and I wanted to like validator or break
those things down and then of those like
five maybe six people that raise your
hands how many of you would say that
you're a public interest technologist
okay so about the same you know about
the same okay then what about human
rights technology is anybody heard this
phrase used before human rights
technology about the same but different
hands this is good and then as far as a
human rights technologist anybody a
little bit smaller minus two or three
hands right okay thank you now so the
reason why I bring this up is because
like this is sort of a new thing right
it's like is is this not just a
technologist not just a software
developer not just a cryptographer but
sort of where your motivations are and
so one of the things that I like I have
this assumption about you all in the
room is how much more motivated you are
for like public interest in human rights
rather than just like sort of that the
technology itself or privacy is sort of
an ideal and and I shouldn't have that I
should be working harder to get more of
you to raise your hands so that when i
come here is just a guess next year
someone else asked that question there's
more hands in the air thank you for that
um so I'm going to come back to what
open Technology Fund is but first how
many of you have heard of open
Technology Fund oh wow how many of you
are getting supported by the open
Technology Fund or have been supported
by the open Technology Fund what about
partners our collaborators Wow gives me
goosebumps is why I can't play poker
with the short sleeve shirt because
whenever i get excited or have a good
hander about hand everyone can see it
well that makes me I'm a little bit
glowing right y'all like that's quite
and realized so many of you all were in
the room and this is just the cost of
and I'll get to this later of sort of
what happened with OTF very recently is
there's a lot of people i don't know
that i really wish i knew more of better
in rooms like this that just happens
when you start doing more work okay so
OTF started in 2012 we've we are
predominately supported by the US
government we receive we've had a really
crazy budget on one and it's been like
three million another min another year
we got twelve point seven five million
most of that comes through this high
level agreement of free expression
guided by article 19 which is the the
Declaration human rights stating
everyone has the right to free
expression free speech freedom of
thought and then a little bit further
down there's this very American centric
idea of Internet freedom that's become a
much bigger than American centrica idea
of where those freedoms should be
protected and supported online and on
the internet other communication mediums
and that's sort of where it came the
past as far as OTF sexists in 2012 they
realized that as far as technologically
goes they weren't doing enough to sort
of reach out into communities like this
and make it really easy and approachable
for an individual or groups too
assertive support for their really good
ideas that we're increasing free
expression and so OTF came to pass as a
more approachable thunder for these
projects and we we focus on technology
centric efforts that are first and
foremost on increasing more unfettered
access to the internet but also very
much related to trying to stop
repressive surveillance and repressive
privacy invasions blackouts all kinds of
really interesting stuff and then
awareness programs that help make the
tools and technologies that you're
creating or the research that you're
doing more publicly available but mostly
text centric efforts so again we start
in 2012 and we really believe we've got
a set of ideals and principles that
really
guide our work and that's partly because
we just don't know the landscape is
changing so quickly and if you're more
interested in sort of what we believe
beyond just that everyone has a right to
free to speak freely without any
repressive censorship or surveillance
check out our website you can see our
mission our ideals you can see all the
projects we supported there as well we
try really hard to be as transparent and
accountable through that as we can be so
you can see almost everyone we funded
unless there is some sort of privacy
concern that's significant so just some
numbers at this point we have over 200
different fellows and projects we've
supported in the last four years and
some just need five thousand dollars to
go travel somewhere hundred dollars to
travel somewhere an event and then
others such as tour we give almost a
million dollars a year to we we started
off having to beg 12 very trusting souls
to take our money in 2012 and had to
really convince them that it was a good
idea and now we get about 100 150
applications every two months so we've
got at this point you know over a couple
thousand applications and it's it's
become a thing we had to spend a lot of
time following you to pivoting to a
thing of where so much comes to us
that's or viewing applications in our
review process is sort of our biggest
way of learning now which is sort of
interesting we start off with maybe you
know a few hundred thousand of millions
a couple million people that were making
use of technologies that we'd say like
we're Internet freedom technologies or
Human Rights technologies to gain access
or increase their privacy security
online and now I think we've got
something like over a billion going on
two billion people making use of
technologies at OTF and or our
partnering funders are supporting which
is pretty daunting and impressive but
also cool um and we've spent about 30 to
40 million dollars about 35 million
dollars in the last four years so that's
OTF by the numbers um so if you have any
questions about that I bring that up and
totally willing to answer anything I can
or know about in the question section
there's lots to just behind the scenes
of OT FM just going to skip over right
now so this next section again I'm going
to tell some stories I got about four
four stories and sort of accompanying
projects that I'm going to frame why I
think human rights technology as it sort
of broader context for the privacy
enhancing technology that you are doing
are incredibly important at least in my
day to day and I think to those next two
billion 3 billion people that are going
to be coming online the next few years
sewing tell a story not just to be
really clear like there's some projects
here that I'm not going to talk about
for example tour partly because it's we
all know it's amazing I don't think I
need to tell you all how awesome tour is
and why it's important to this community
of what not and it gets talked about a
lot so I'm going to talk about some
other really popular projects as well
but and I'm also trying to ground these
stories in a set of themes I want to
introduce you all at the end that are
really important to us and I hope you
can think about when you're choosing
which projects you work on moving
forward so the first is Rania oh and
these are based on real people that I'm
not going to use any real names I'm
going to try to like keep the story part
where I'm talking about the actual
persona the person pretty light just to
protect privacy but I'm also happy to
give a lot more details if you want to
come up to me afterwards and ask about a
specific story so I pardon for that um
so the the first is an Iranian woman is
is self-hosting and an Iranian virtual a
VPS in Iran and she's doing a lot of
documentation of information controls or
sort of what's happening on the network
within Iran as far as policy things so
what the what the legal regimes are
doing to try to influence what they can
and cannot track and block and went on
and she wants to upgrade her for a
couple different good reason she wants
to upgrade her her hosting solution to
the HTTPS and part of that is to protect
the privacy of where she and who when
she's submitting and what she's
submitting the others for the people
that are visiting our website one of the
challenges that she is bumping into it
costs money it requires a bit of
knowledge and it takes some time to do
these things now the time of knowledge
part isn't
a limitation first she knows how to do
it she's got the time to do it she's
committed to do it but the fact that it
costs money is actually a bit of a
problem in Iran and so pretty recently
most of the certificate issuers are us
or European based and they have
sanctions that don't allow her to use
her money to actually purchase her
certificate and and this is a real
problem so the the solution here at
least for her was you know a get someone
else to purchase it which sort of wasn't
the nicest thing wanted to be able to do
it herself and then of course let's
encrypt coming up pretty recently how
many people know of let's encrypt
awesome right this is an easy i'm
starting with the easy ones first so
that's you hopefully you'll you'll
you'll come across so let's encrypt in
this case um you know it and this is
going to be a theme on top it takes a
thing that has been sort of a real
market driven problem in a lot of ways
for a really long time and it just they
automated the crap out of it they made
it free and now they're what i think the
the number three biggest issuer of
public facing certificates on the planet
and they did that in what like six
months eight months or something like
that really and i know i think set from
eff is here I don't know where he's at
but if he's here you should find him and
bother him more about let's encrypt but
this is one of those things where it
didn't really it they have they are
doing a lot but like on the on the model
of how important this is for Turkish
bloggers right now folks that are also
self-hosting while that country
continues to slide the fact that it's so
easy for them to get certificates and
not even that that there's tools to
automate the implementation process for
their servers is I mean getting goose
bumps again because of the number of
stories we get back and this isn't a
project that we're supporting and i
should say some of these projects we're
not supporting directly and i think are
really big contributors to this and if
we're not supporting we should be
supporting in this case some of these
projects but um we just get we get a lot
of emails about how like this is the
boring stuff that should be happening
to increase human rights rather than
sort of creating a brand new thing so I
wanted to share that with first the next
is related and this isn't quite a
persona on a person but it involves a
whole lot of people that are really
troubled and I'll get to this sort of
personally for me in a later story you
know very large instant messaging app
the largest in the world wants to
upgrade its transport layer protocol and
it looks at TLS in the last two years of
I'm glad to see these these bugs come
out but it looks at TLS looks at as a
cell and it's sort of like Oh some
liability there what's going to happen
if like this messaging service that's
being used by both Americans and
Europeans but also has a really high
adoption rate of highest adoption rate
in Egypt in in in a lot of other
countries that have unfortunate
repressive regimes when it comes to free
expression privacy and surveillance and
they what they decide to do is is sort
of a numerate these challenges they say
well TLS was this develop in the 90s the
first spec I think came out in like 99
TLS one point was definitely made for a
world that doesn't exist today and it's
grown over time and it's iterated but
it's it's definitely got a very large
protocol a large specification rather
that translates to an implementation
attack service if you want to try to
implement the whole specification and
I'm going to say this is a con in this
case but being managed by ETF is means
it's slow to iterate it's developed by a
committee and it can it can there are
positives there for all those folks I
was just the IETF meeting in Berlin and
I think there are some pauses but in
this case it's proving hard to sort of
iterate quick enough to keep up with the
concerns and the failures before but
also the environment today so what did
they do in this case we're talking about
whatsapp well they decided to use their
own or a not their own but a completely
different one an open-source protocol
called the the noise protocol framework
which is sort of confusing on if you
don't know about anybody heard of that
one
the noise protocol a little bit less
okay so you can see this is the trend
hopefully so the noise protocol
framework is a guy by trevor parent
who's here so you should go talk to him
some more you find him and I don't know
enough to talk any more about it the one
I'm going to say but the idea being that
it's a TLS like protocol and I don't
want to say that it's a drop-in
replacement but it allows folks that
have different motivations to have an
alternative and you know it's a simpler
more modern protocol it's got a higher
security cryptography as I understand it
as an onica tog refers so someone can
kick me if I'm wrong about that later
and it it also has sort of specified
more the specification has more
guarantees for deniability and and
identity hiding and it's also faster
more scalable so if you're talking about
out of the box something that needs to
support a billion people and you don't
have to like figure out how to retweet
something that already has a lot of
other scaling issues it's a good
alternative so that's that's one okay
now let me get back to individual people
in this case of several but I'm thinking
of one person in particular a well-known
Chinese human rights lawyer wants to do
some research on a pretty serious human
rights investigation it's making global
headlines and they're based in mainland
China how do they go about doing that
they're 55 ish years old they're not the
most technical person in the world and
they they they don't you know you can't
just go download tour for example it's a
hard it's a harder solution for them to
get involved in it in this case you know
Deutsche Welle the BBC the New York
Times Guardian a lot of your major
Western sort of English first language
sites that have Chinese native sites
those Chinese language sites are
completely banned in this country in
China punished is what it is now they
have their own english version sites
typically that front page is unbanned
but stories just sort of don't show up
when you search for them or that you
have a link that someone shared you and
it it was there for them but it's
therefore you or it's not there for them
anymore either and this is sort of a
common a common thing that just happens
in China so what we're pointing to here
is the challenges are very impressive
DPI deep packet inspection excuse me
within the Chinese the Chinese Great
Firewall the heuristics mechanisms are
ever improving as in things that they
don't even fit the unknown knowns or the
known unknowns and known whatever it is
that that phrase is like they you know
the things that start generating traffic
raise alarms where different things
start getting flagged for the human
sensors and it's just incredibly it's
incredible and it's horrible but how
quickly they can go about removing
things in different different different
mediums whether it's a whatsapp message
stream we chat or website at URL um the
Selective content filtering is in like
the ability to say that the New York
Times is available on the front page but
that this embedded URL is not or like
specific content within URLs or it is
not available the sort of downgrading
attacks of taking something that is
HTTPS and then sort of refusing to give
that connection forcing HTTP on a grand
scale are all very present and they the
old whack Amole blocking DNS or with DNS
blocking domains and IP addresses is
able to happen quicker and faster and
smarter than ever before and they have
all these great little mechanisms to you
know test to see is that a tour
connection is that a VPN connection is
this like all these things to figure out
how to how to block these things so this
is 1 50 50 year old guys got all these
things stacked up against when all he
wants to do is is just check the New
York Times and then on top of that until
i would say recently most of the VPN
tools the proxy tools we're not very
usable and or hard to come by now that
is changing very very quickly and it's
awesome how quickly it's changing but
there's still not as easy as just going
to the website or running a browser
extension or something like that so the
solution right now which is pretty
pretty interesting is this one called on
cert collateral freedom / domain
fronting and I know this doesn't at the
start if any of you know of it sort of
seemed like a privacy enhancing
technology but it is anybody heard of
this one you all are awesome it was
presented this last year of course right
so these are all the returnees and I
don't see David or David fifield here
but he was probably the one that prison
okay yet so David presented it you
should talk more to him if you've got
more questions about that that's awesome
one of our one of our folks that we
support as well so the idea here for
those who don't know and i'll try to
keep it short is you you got the
situation where the collateral damage of
blocking websites in china increasingly
Iran and other countries is is
significant economically as in there are
so many people in China for purely
economic reasons running their own
businesses that need access to you know
CloudFlare or Google or Amazon Web
Services or any of these other sort of
big international frameworks that to
block them would cause not just social
upheaval like blocking facebook social
network but actually economic and people
so they they call this collateral
freedom like the collateral damage means
that there's this collateral freedom of
these people who want to make use of
these services they're these on block
sites and then on top of that they
mostly offer pretty easily affordably or
by default https connections and this is
where it becomes a privacy enhancing
technology aspect for me in that it's
not just that you can't block amazon com
or AWS amazon com it's that by default
https AWS amazon com is available and
therefore you you've your you've got
some privacy properties included with
doing this um so the there's two
specific projects here that i want to
point out and the first one I already
did which is one meet which is really
great because it's sort of tool agnostic
it's a library that I think of is sort
of extensible and portable for other
tools whether you're a proprietary VPN
seller or you're an open source proxy
tool multi-hop Onion Routing to like
tour for example you can drop in
something like meek set up your own
accounts on these different services and
all of a sudden get these properties of
domain fronting and collateral freedom
in this case you can route everything
through it or you can use it as a
discovery to find out like what's that
first IP address
they haven't blocked yet that's
currently available more questions ask
some other folks that raise their hands
it to hear more about that and the other
is this project called great fire which
is taken a completely different track
and this is where it veers a little bit
away from privacy enhancing technologies
and more about an access how do you use
this to just literally open the door for
the person who in our case study is
trying to find out more global
information about the human rights
violation or something just wants to go
check out the cat videos and go to
youtube and see like what their aunt
uncle are doing in Chicago and in this
case they've created a way to mirror
websites a set of tools and scripts to
just mere any website put it on an
Amazon server a caching server and then
create a new link for that and then
disseminate that really easy through a
browser extension so you're not getting
the multi out proxy you're not getting
like you owe on on privacy protection
but you are getting a tool that
increases access much much much easier
okay so we got one more story how's
everyone doing okay okay whew thumbs up
a lot of people not looking at their
laptops just great hate some more okay
so the next one is this one's super
personal for me this one is and I've
said this one before so I'm sorry for
those who may be heard it but um in this
case it's another sort of Arab Arab
revolution story I alluded that earlier
so when I when I took on this job in two
thousand 2010-2011 and Al Jazeera I
didn't realize how both difficult in and
easy at the same time it was going to be
the difficult work I mean the hardest
job I've ever had you've got sources in
the field who sent you a text message
and call you on the phone and every time
you get one of those text messages and
on the phone you just like a little part
of you just like oh because especially
if the message that they just left you
are the the phone call they sent you was
something that you knew his newsworthy
because you were just like who else just
saw that and so my first job was to
figure out tools and technologies that
would help increase the safety for these
people and our journalists
and and you know if you I don't know how
many of you remember that was difficult
in my 2010-2011 for your average person
who didn't have any technological mind
at all and you know the result was I
would get a text message or mostly my
colleagues rather than I would get a
text message or phone call I hear about
this and then we wouldn't hear from them
again and the scale of what was
happening to to these journalists
sources which we all know about now has
become public knowledge was some of them
were fleeing because they knew that they
had access to something that was putting
their family or themselves in danger
they were getting arrested detained
tortured and some killed and and a
completely other story that does
anything to do with me but when I came
into this job but I find is is a little
bit a little bit lighter heart as in
knowing no one getting tortured detained
or killed that we know of but um when I
when I took this job I went and spent
some time in Vietnam and had some
conversations with some Vietnamese
activists who had this sort of
light-hearted sort of oh it's just the
way it is no harm done sort of story
where it was you know when we first
started doing or activism work we these
tales would with these these
intelligence officers or local police
would just start following us around
they asked us all these questions hey
who's that you were talking to who's
that where were you at the other night
and it's you know and they sort of
almost became friendly because they knew
these people war they these people do a
whole lot about them and they would just
sort of expect them there and then one
day they just literally stopped showing
up and they way they were framed this or
psycho they sort of missed their tails
like these people they dealt a
relationship with who they'd spent so
much time with over the last like two or
three years and they just they just they
were gone and whether there's a common
theme here is and you know they were
asking us you know to validate their
assumptions of why they were gone and
and of course this room and now with a
lot of disclosures we know exactly what
was going on we know the capabilities of
small and large countries when it comes
to surveillance of unencrypted messages
so on the first story the reason why
these these sources were disappearing
was because they were sending plain text
airplane text messages unencrypted phone
conversations and it was really easy for
them to be targeted and and and dealt
with by those regimes and in the case of
the Vietnamese it was really easy to
just stop it was obviously like no
longer economical to follow them around
all day because they had their phone
tracking information they could read
their text messages they could read they
could listen to their voice
conversations and so they just they
would target them and that would be it
and so coming back to the the challenge
is there you know Indian encryption on
mobile devices at the time just didn't
exist actually with the exception of you
some of your going to know where I'm
going and it's another big ones this
will be an easy one and this was an
early version of tech secure by open or
by whisper scissors at the time and the
same is true for the Vietnamese as soon
as they started using tech secure this
is before we met them guess who came
back around they're old friends it was
like it literally within a week after
they all started using textsecure back
in like 2011 2000-2010 you all their
friends come back and everyone's like
what's just you know they asking the
same questions and I'm really asking
them about this tool that they're using
and partly is because the people that
are falling in they don't really
understand at this time even like there
was an understanding that like
encryption was happening yet like it is
is part of the public discourse and only
what four years five years since but at
the time that was about as usable as it
got but before that that was um and that
which is not an option in an encryption
on a phone and then and then if we were
honest and we're still honest like in an
encryption on a computer it's not as
good as it could but going back four or
five years it was also very difficult
like I think this the status quo would
have been a nig male with Thunderbird
which is fine for probably almost
everyone in this room or a lot of people
in the room but you aren't the most
important people to be considering when
what what is usable in what is easy so
in this case of course signal signals
precursor text textsecure red phone and
all pulling out just signal doing at all
is the technology that we're
highlighting here is how useful it's
been for human rights purposes for
people that are really on the
the far end of the spectrum of getting
repressed and I don't need to talk about
the event i think everyone everyone
knows signal and of course whatsapp I
mean if is anybody is anyway not I don't
want to do that cuz I won't call you out
so you know if you don't know what
signal or the signal protocol it's being
used in what to have now you've got over
well if you count all the other
implementation got over two billion
people making use of a thing and of
course why is that massively positive
it's normalized encryption on the line
for one thing it's not just tour you
know I think you've got a lot of
encryption happening beyond its HTTPS
making it very very very easy for for
some new activists with a new social
ideal to not be persecuted and singled
out in a way that it was really easy for
them to be and just for five years ago
so I just wanted to quickly say again
some other notable projects because
these are just chosen to make some
points that i'm going to make here in a
second I've already said tour
approaching I'm not endorsing necessary
that I think these are amazing projects
I'm just saying I think they fit the
criteria of privacy enhancing
technologies that have a history of
increasing human rights or are going to
and hopefully you all will get involved
with it at some point so you've got tor
project cryptocat push secure in plus
one sec OTR version for you've got amino
briar and the bramble protocol clatter
mesh communication magic folder cubes
tales subgraph Copperhead OS all these
are either dealing directly with
encryption or doing things to increase
privacy in their own way and I think if
you have more if you have thoughts any
of those come ask me and I'm happy to
share more um how you feeling yeah I'll
try to go through this next part really
quickly and then leave a lot for
questions so these are this is a theme
section of like stuff that I find is
really important helps me like figure
out which of these projects are right
and which ones are important and
ultimately keep me grounded what I think
is most important in the work that we do
and the first and foremost and I like I
see a few you smiling because I know who
you are and how you think and you smile
at a couple of things that I've said but
that is um think first and foremost
about the
people that you're you're hoping to
affect and think about them the most and
never stop thinking about them and this
is you know sort of a tenant for
co-design and co-development when you're
doing something it's not just good
enough to have a good idea and then
prototype it and then hope that it's
going to be relevant for a group of
people anymore I don't know if it was
ever really good idea to do to begin
with but it's now too easy to not like
it's too easy to just reach out to a
group find out like what they think
about a thing and in particular when
you're talking about human rights
technology um you know they're not just
users they're like the people there
people and and they are you know most of
the people in this room going to make
some broad demographic assertions are
not going to be the ones most advantage
or affected by the things that you do
well or the things that you do wrong and
that's going to be a whole other group
of people that are probably not
represented widely here so don't forget
about that and if you ever looking for
funding those funders are thinking this
way now so someone's going to remind you
along the way no matter how good a good
idea is going to be and I just want to
point out too that for these people you
know the challenges for them are so much
more acute and and what I mean by that
is because they're they're so on on the
farther side of the spectrum of what
they know when they know something
failed they didn't really know that it
failed until a much later thing at the
line in the in the adversaries here are
much more advanced as far as the space
between them and the adversaries that
they're working with I might not say
that like the Bob way government is
advanced is the Vietnamese or the
Chinese of the American but the space
between the Zimbabwe government's
capabilities now with off the shelf like
hockey team sort of things that are that
are now available for a government
doesn't a lot of money to the average
citizen into the boffins op weight is in
Bob way excuse me is huge bigger than
it's ever been and the last like you
know maybe 10-15 years since this
technology to surveil oppressively and
since her oppressively has become
available so the costs are much greater
if you get it wrong and so because of
that you just just just think about who
you're trying to help and and don't just
stop at thinking about them try to
figure out how to make them a part of
the design process
of the architectures you're developing
and even better yet make them part of
the development process so that they're
there along the way and if you can't
have a good reason why you can because
there are some out there the next point
I want I was just does anybody else
think in like geometric shapes and
you're thinking about ideas squares
circles triangles and things like okay
I've been thinking a lot about triangles
and one triangle in particular and
thanks to a couple of people in the
audience who let me soundboard this off
them in the last the last few days but
in this case I wish I had I'm sorry I
don't have a picture you shouldn't talk
about geometric shapes and not a picture
but in this one it's it's a triangle of
things that are really important when
we're ever thinking about whether
technologies were supporting within the
context of human right technology and in
it in at a very high level its power
it's it's excuse me its its its rights
power and people and I know that sounds
like well whatever but let me break it
down in a little bit little bit deeper
so in this case rights the rights for
this conference in like the room in the
context what we're time is privacy
that's the right the right to privacy
and in this case let's go
technologically on on power and think
about architecture first and then think
of say like centralized versus
decentralized so this is like a
technological architecture that can
shift power it has a direct effect to
power and then if you go to the other
corner and some of you that have been
around for longer will probably have
like well this is a thing I know that
this is and tell me if it is and then
the other is people in technological
terms again we think about scale and
it's not just like scale to like seven
billion people it might be only need to
affect like ten people's lives and need
to do really well and so that's why that
that is a higher level thing of people
rather than sort of like numbers of
people and so let's just take a couple
of examples right so signal for example
where does it fit on that triangle right
so when it comes to rights well it's
definitely increasing encrypted
communication and the privacy of people
in a way that very few other projects
were doing was it doing it in a
and a novel or like the most advanced
way that we know no well so behind the
scenes as far as like supporting
asynchronous communication yes but as
far as like deniability and like you
know knowledge of keys and other things
like that it's it's you know it's not
all the way on that but it's definitely
over there and as far as as far as
people is it a protocol that scales to
billions of people well yes so that's we
not really seen anything like that and
instant messaging before so it fits over
here now what about power well so it's
if we if we use my example of arch and
centralization versus decentralisation
well it's a centralized tool and it's
definitely centralizing power around
like Google you know push service and
apples put service and the you know the
open whispers server and then of course
whatsapp it's all facebook so it's not
really shifting the power in in
architecture terms all that much so it
actually fits like over here it's very
useful on sort of and and the reason why
I think about that is because like in my
view of the world at least I want to
balance of those three things on the
triangle so if we put all of our eggs in
a basket we're not really shifting power
to the people we care a lot about now
another example that sort of more new is
this project called I PFS interplanetary
file system anybody cool cool this is a
following should look this one up so I
PFS I PFS is a server look hopefully a
server less especially they finished the
javascript implementation fully a
serverless sort of distributed file
system built on you know it's got
BitTorrent behind the scene of it it's
got all kinds of good sentiments stop
right there but they've got a prototype
called orbit which is a chat app so I'm
going to compare orbit to signal in this
case so in this case not really any
encryption on top of the app at all
outside of an https session so not doing
a whole lot on privacy now you look at
power the fact that it's server free and
it can be booted up in a JavaScript or a
browser extension and doesn't have a
centralized server except for the one
that offers up that JavaScript that's
really doing something for power
dynamics there and then you look at the
other side of of people and it can
theoretically scale pretty far so that's
an interesting one sort of the other
side of the another other side of the
triangle so i just wanted to point that
i was like a thing we think a lot about
and then there is shortening of the old
versus new let's just compare to say
let's encrypt versus the noise protocol
framework you've got let's encrypt which
is taking an old thing that needs to be
done better and it's scaling it up like
crazy and automating the crap out of it
and it's keeping it around you've got
something like noise which is saying
well TLS 1.3 maybe that'll answer our
problems but we're not going to wait
around for it so we're just going to
presume it doesn't exist we're going to
create a new thing we're constantly
trying to balance those things out as
well and like have people prove to us
the case for why they chose an old
versus new solution the same is true for
like standards and protocols you know
IETF vs posting anything on github or
learning and sharing traditional
education versus like open pure learning
and and I think a lot of you know where
you all sit on both sides and then the
last few things first thing is like open
source everything I don't there's just
no excuse for it and I don't have to say
that to this cross I'm not going to go
into like the advantages and benefits of
it but you'd just be surprised how many
people apply to the open Technology Fund
and want like a proprietary license for
their intellectual property and we're
just like are you crazy you know like
this it's not it's not what we are and
it's not what we believe in so you know
I think there's a lot of advantages
there if you want to go toe-to-toe with
me on that I'm happy to talk about and
then I finally want to say you know TF
isn't just about supporting things that
aren't through the traditional sort of
academic peer review process we've got
like 30 40 papers at this point that
we're responsible for supporting people
to publish through conferences like pets
you snakes in other academic places and
we love that and I just want to like
really give a nod to everyone out there
who's doing that work of sticking in
that space from theoretical to practical
and not necessarily getting into the
implementation and giving yourself at
like sort of satisfaction when you're
not into it because like every one of
these projects that i mentioned you know
we're talking about trying to solve
stuff that are two to three years out
but our problems of the day these papers
were they all have a paper or five that
are the basis for what they're doing
that we're written five ten years ago
and and i just want to acknowledge and
say thank you for that as well and i'm
gonna stop right there very hard cut and
say thank you again first
supporting human rights and I really
appreciate work I love following what
you all are doing and I'm looking
forward to getting more from you in the
future and any questions