never one hear me okay thanks for your
patience while I was presenting or while
I was preparing these slides I wasn't
quite sure how to introduce myself
because I just passed my dissertation
defense a few weeks ago so I don't have
the diploma in hand I don't know if I
can officially say doctor but at any
rate I can i am dr. emmanuel bellow oh
who knew and i'm from unc charlotte in
north carolina USA and i'd like to talk
to you about crowd sourcing for context
regarding privacy within using Bluetooth
beacons in an indoor setting so quickly
before I jump into it quick show of
hands can I see who has heard of beacons
who has use them interacted with them
okay very good more than expected I know
who to avoid when the hard questions
come so I'm just going to give a brief
overview of beacons so that everyone is
on the same page before diving into my
contribution so bluetooth learners your
beacons are small low-power low-cost
transmitters that continuously send a
low-energy beacon signal a Bluetooth
signal excuse me so unlike traditional
bluetooth or the Bluetooth below four
point know that most people are aware of
there's no syncing there's no pairing
required this sensor sip simply sends
out a signal continuously and any device
that comes within range can pick up that
signal and trigger some sort of action
or notification so in action these
beacons act as proximity excuse me
proximity sensors so imagine you're in a
supermarket or a shopping mall and you
walk by a section of the store and
instantly you get a notification for a
product that you just walked by and you
just received a coupon for that product
so this interaction is using these
beacons however you do have to have a an
application on your device that can
appropriately handle that signal
otherwise nothing will happen and
obviously Bluetooth does have to be on
so as far as the kind of information
that you get from these encounters the
idea of the beacon is what is being
transmitted and that's stored somewhere
in the cloud so that when that
application on the device this
covers that signal then it will check
the cloud in order to determine who owns
the beacon what kind of items might be
nearby it or associated with it as well
as the proximity of the user so the kind
of pieces of information that mark and
encounter include the time you were
there the duration the frequency of
visits even the travel path the specific
back path you took within a space that's
equipped with beacons so a lot of this
provides a wealth of information to
bacon providers the retailer's
especially from an analytics perspective
you can also know precisely where
someone is indoors but on the flip side
users due to the seamlessness of the
technology aren't even aware of how it's
working when it's being used and what
information about themselves as being
shared and so I argue that there needs
to be some sort of middle ground not
everyone would be comfortable with
sharing their location every single time
they're shopping and yet some might be
depending on where they are what items
are nearby and so that's the issue
there's no real context for people to
make a proper decision when they
encounter these Bluetooth beacons and we
do know from research that contextual
integrity is important to the privacy of
perceptions associated with technology
so in other words context matters if I'm
going to decide when and where and with
whom I'm going to share some information
so one one possible solution is to have
the beacon providers or the retailers
come up with labels some way to say okay
beacon a is associated with shoes you
can be is associated with t-shirts etc
and then maybe also indicates this is a
sensitive vegan a lot of people may not
want to share information with this
because it's sensitive but the issue
with this is that first of all it's hard
to expect all the beacon providers or
all the retailers to abide by some
standard where they provide these
categorizations and secondly the notion
of privacy that these beacon providers
would have would likely differ from
ordinary users naturally they're going
to want to collect as much information
as possible so they would be less
inclined to be or to consider any be
sensitive as an ordinary user might so
instead I posit that we turn to the
users themselves in order to determine
what is sensitive and what am I when and
where am I willing to share and so in
doing so I posit that crowdsourcing can
leverage users to contribute beacon
labels and therefore allow them to make
informed privacy decisions a
crowdsourcing can just be defined as
ordinary people coming together and
collaborating to contribute to a body of
knowledge to a body of knowledge or
perhaps a solve a problem typical
examples include Amazon Mechanical Turk
and for many of you have experienced
that or a familiar of that Wikipedia is
a website where again a lot of people
come together and contribute information
similarly any crowdfunding sites that
you may have heard of GoFundMe
Kickstarter these are all examples of
crowdsourcing so I believe that through
crowdsourcing we can allow users to come
up with these privacy labels so that
people who have discovered beacons
before can now help inform other users
who are encountering them for the first
time
so I came up with a user study in which
I wanted to demonstrate a crowdsourcing
based approach to introducing context to
beacon encounters my hypothesis here was
that crowdsourcing is an accurate and
efficient approach to providing users
with context during these weekend
encounters so for this study I recruited
90 participants from my college campus I
structured this as a between-subjects
design and marketed the application as a
scavenger hunt and so I had people
within the three-week span use my
application in a game sort of format to
walk around our bookstore and to label
nine of these beacons with a category
label and a privacy label the reward for
participating was a five dollar
starbucks gift card and the measures
that I was interested in studying
include the label accuracy the label
time and the actual location sharing
that they indicated they'd be willing to
do or not do
this is just a brief map of our
bookstore our floor plan along with the
locations of the beacons so I chose ones
that I felt would be varied as far as
the type of category and privacy that
users would have so I have the ATM as my
ground truth or my benchmark for what a
private beacon would be considering most
people probably not care to share every
time they went to an ATM and on the
opposite end of the spectrum the
starbucks beacon I considered that the
benchmark for a the least sensitive or
for a public beacon and so with those
two benchmarks I can now compare the
remaining beacons to see how sensitive
they may have been according to the
users in the study so this these are
screenshots of the application that I
built using Android this user would I
use this application in order to enter
the main menu and start a session and
upon doing so you see in the middle
screen that they would receive a list of
beacons with which they were within
proximity I'm sorted by distance so
selecting any what any one of these
beacons allows you to do two things you
can either locate the beacon in a find
me mode that third screenshot is a radar
that users would see if they needed help
locating a beacon or if they've spotted
it then they could label the beacon so
the far left screenshot they could
choose from a number of categories in
order to say that this beacon is this
category once a category is selected
then in the middle screen you see a
privacy label form that they completed
so users would indicate from low to high
how sensitive a beacon might be
considered or in other words how
concerned might they be when it comes to
sharing their location at that specific
beacon and then also marking the social
circles that they would be willing to
share with which included their friends
Barnes & Noble our campus bookstore the
university as a whole or the general
public lastly once they had done this
for all nine beacons they would be
presented with their final score again
because this was a scavenger hunt game
they received points based on the number
of beacons that in labeled how accurate
those labels were and the amount of time
it took them to do so
so I mentioned that this was a
between-subjects design so I had three
different groups that I was looking at I
described them as Top Cat crowd cat and
no cat so earlier I mentioned that a
plausible solution to providing these
labels would be to have the beacon
providers or the retailer to generate
these labels so the top cat group
represents that hypothesis that you
could provide the specific label for
them and then they would select that in
labeling these beacons the middle the
crowd cat represents the crowd the users
who solve recommendations for categories
based on other users inside of that
group I don't know if you can see but
those three that are under most popular
you'll see that Barnes & Noble women's
apparel had one user who marked that as
a category label under that polo ralph
lauren had 10 users and then under that
men's apparel one user so you can see
based on the responses from the rest of
the users in that crowd group what the
most likely category would be and then
my control group no cat did not receive
any kind of recommendation so again my
goal was to show that the crowd could be
relied on to accurately and efficiently
generate these labels for beacons within
his face so in order to make this
analysis I performed a one-way anova
between the three groups and their
respective accuracies you can see the
top cat group had an accuracy of
ninety-four percent while the crowd cat
had an accuracy of 92.5 and no cat 86.6
so the results of the ANOVA test and the
square on the right you see that we did
receive we did have a p-value of point
zero one which allowed us to confirm
that there is a significant difference
in the accuracy between these three
groups in order to find where that
difference lies we did I did a postdoc
comparison and found that for crowd and
no cat there was a significant
difference in accuracy as well as top
cat and no cat but there is not a
significant difference between top cat
and crowd cat so in other words we can
say safely say that the crowd
and reliably contribute labels that are
as accurate or comparable in accuracy
with the top cat group and obviously
performing better than the no cat group
performing a very similar tests on the
labeled time or the amount of time it
took users to provide these labels I
first transformed the time since it's
it's not a bound normal variable so
after doing a logarithmic transformation
I was able to do a one-way anova and
again found a p-value less than point
zero one confirming that there is a
difference in the label time between the
three groups and the results were very
similar here both the crowd and the
topcat group perform better than the
group who did not receive any
recommendations but there's not a
significant difference between the top
cat and the crowd cat group which is
good that's the result we wanted we want
to be able to say that the crowd can do
this just as efficiently as the group
that is given the correct label right
away and lastly I wanted to look at the
location sharing responses that users
provided through the privacy labels so
this is just an aggregate view of those
if I can draw your attention to a
sensitivity column that is just taking
the low to high that users marked for
sensitivity of beacon and translating
that to zero to 100 and then the
remaining columns marked will share with
those I'll represent the percentage of
participants who are willing to share
their location at that specific beacon
for that given social circle and so
again the first row ATM that was our
benchmark for the least sensitive beacon
and starbucks at the very bottom was our
benchmark for the excuse me since ATM
was the most sensitive and starbucks was
the least sensitive as far as our
beacons and then comparing all the rest
i did a cochrane sku test in order to
compare the matched responses that is
compared the willingness to share with a
certain beacon for all nine beacons and
upon doing so did post hoc comparisons
between four within each social circle
so within friends with in bookstore with
in university and within public i did
post hoc comparisons to see that the
restrooms beacon for example were they
more likely to share with at the
restrooms than ATM if there was a
significant difference then i would mark
it accordingly at the table so there's a
lot going on here but just
summarize this is all just to show that
it does depend on what the beacon is and
who is has access that information that
participants are willing to share their
location at that beacon so all this
combined the label time the accuracy and
their willingness to share and the
differences between who and where they
share with all help us confidently
assert that crowdsourcing can be used as
a tool to incorporate context when
encountering these beacons and so to
conclude I argue that the rapid growth
of beacon applications demands proactive
steps to handle location privacy issues
and my objective was to empower users
with a tool that allowed them to manage
their privacy in order to manage their
privacy they need to know what is the
context in which their location would be
shared so I confirmed that sharing
location information during beacon
encounters does depend on context and I
implemented a crowdsourcing based
approach to incorporate context during
these encounters so my future work is to
integrate this crowd sourcing model into
a beacon privacy management framework
something that would allow users to
based on the information received create
privacy policies for any given beacon
where they could say based on what the
crowd is saying I'd like to set a policy
where I don't share my location at this
beacon but i will share it with this
people I hope all that made sense and I
appreciate your attention I thank you I
appreciate it