so I'm John skank I am going to be
talking about putting postponed or
cryptography into tour we've seen a lot
of really cool new proposals for systems
I haven't heard a lot of people using
post quantum cryptography so rather than
start out by introducing tour which you
all know I'm going to start out trying
to motivate why we might think about
quantum adversaries today so here's a
little historical context this is a
computer from 1932 it's an interesting
computer because it was built by Derek
layman it's a factoring machine and it
was the fastest factoring machine until
well into the 1960s this is a quantum
mechanical calculator from 2014 it
doesn't do much yet but it does do
something interesting if you look at the
title their superconducting quantum
circuits at the surface code threshold
for fault tolerance what they're saying
is that if they could build more of
these qubits at the same quality that
they do right now then they would
actually be able to make arbitrarily
large quantum computers which is a
little bit scary although the picture is
a little misleading because it's just
the little part in that innermost box
right there and there's so much
classical circuitry so much microwave
electronics outside that's what's
preventing us from building large
quantum computers right now there's a
little dotted thing there that's for the
other four cubits so that's multiplied a
few times okay so that's really what's
stopping us from having big quantum
computers right now it's not the quality
of the the quantum hardware I think we
should be worried about that so I want
to say that quantum computers are a real
threat and it means that the the the
cryptography that recurrently using on
the internet is going to be broken so we
should start deploying post quantum
cryptography soon and we should do that
alongside the crypto they were using
right now and why should we do this
hybridization of using say e cdh end a
post quantum key exchange well there's a
few reasons we first might have low
confidence in the new schemes maybe
somebody wakes up tomorrow and breaks
all idea lattice cryptography but what
we should really be concerned about is
that we have
confidence in the implementations of
these new schemes we don't have much
experience in doing it so we don't
really want to rely entirely on any of
these new post quantum things yet we
have good classical crypto pre quantum
crypto we should use it another concern
maybe not relevant for tour but some
users do need things like phipps 140
compliance and so you have to keep using
the things that are already in touch so
important so if we're thinking about
quantum adversaries we need to kind of
think about three different types of
security that we could have we can have
pre quantum security and this is
entirely in the context of establishing
secure channel we could have pre quantum
security meaning we have pre quantum
authentication and pre quantum
confidentiality so that's fine as long
as you don't think there will ever be a
quantum computer but I think there will
be so what you might want instead is
something like transitional security
which is having pre quantum
authentication and post quantum
confidentiality now authentication is
it's fine to have pre quantum stuff as
long as no one has a quantum computer at
the time of session negotiation if they
get one afterwards it would be a problem
for the confidentiality that could break
the channel but as long as I don't have
one when you're negotiating your key
exchange is fine so that's an
interesting use case to consider
adversary mom's to consider and then you
could go all the way to true postponed
in cryptography you could use post
quantum authentication and
confidentiality what I want to focus on
this case and in particular I want to
focus on putting something into tour to
get transitional security so that yeah
real forward secrecy we say we have
perfect forward secrecy it's not really
true there's an expiration date on
forward secrecy and it's exactly when
you get large quantum computers someone
harvesting ciphertext at the at the
entry node would be able to just bore
through all the layers of encryption to
break the anonymity and the secrecy of
the channel so we should be concerned
about that and so what we're going to do
is put a post quantum key exchange
mechanism our key encapsulation
mechanism into the nth or handshake okay
so
and towards a one-way authenticated key
exchange is published in 2013 there's an
engineering specification tour proposal
to 16 and it's been deployed since 2013
as well it looks kind of like this so
there's three phases we can break it up
into negotiating the pre-master secret
then doing this authentication tag and
then finally deriving a key so in the
first stage getting a pre-master secret
that's two different handshakes one of
them is a static ephemeral and the other
one is ephemeral ephemeral so our
anonymous client generates a ephemeral
diffie-hellman key call that X the
lowercase letters are secret values and
the uppercase letters are public values
so they send their public value over to
the router in this case let's server
which has a long-term difficulty which
it's note by a and the server generates
its own ephemeral diffie-hellman key y
and computes the two does to group
operations it does X to the little Y and
X is a little a so the the one using a
provides authentication and the one
using y is going to be used for forward
secrecy they send Y back and the client
is able to do the same group operations
using their key ok so that's the
pre-master secret then we do some stuff
with getting the this authentication tag
this is for some more protocol level
attacks you want to bind the key that's
derived to the entire transcript you
also want to make sure that you have a
version identifier in there to prevent
cross version attacks and things like
that I won't talk too much about that's
just yet and then the final step is you
actually derive a key ok so n Tory's got
a proof of security and a totally fine
model but in order to talk about quantum
adversaries I want to consider a
slightly stronger security model one in
particular that separates everything
that happens before the clients accept
and start using the key and everything
that happens after that so I want to be
able to talk about a pre quantum
adversary during that pre accept phase
in a post quantum adversary post accept
so that's this all indoor thing so
to find a variant of n tour that just
makes it easier to give a proof in this
particular model the model is called the
authenticated and confidential Channel
establishment model that's been used
very successfully to prove the security
of some cipher suites as they're
deployed in the real world so that was
kind of motivation for why to use it
here to end towards already this thing
that's out there why not use this thing
that has a proven track record of being
good in that scenario so hybrid null is
end tour with a few modifications plus
nothing it's just it's just n tour with
a few modifications i took the no means
and that's going to prove that that's a
pre quantum acce protocol or rather the
proof is in the paper and you can go
look at if you want so we have to make a
few changes in order to get the proof to
go through the first is that we need to
hatch the static ephemeral share it's
just a slight different slightly
different assumption hash diffie-hellman
versus a gap diffie-hellman assumption
it's not terribly important but I do
think this is a good thing to do it
prevents some very theoretical attacks
against very bad key derivation function
the next thing is that n tour as it's
deployed does something a little funny
with with H max so the first argument to
H Mac here is supposed to be a key and
the second one is the message and so n
tour is using a fixed H matki for all
sessions and that's fine as long as you
treat H Mac as a random Oracle but I
want to rely on the fact that H Mac is a
pseudo-random function family so I'm
just going to take the public transcript
stuff and shove it over into the key
side of H Mac and use it that way
instead again this is just like a
provable security thing it's fine to
assume that H Mac is a random Oracle
there any problems with n tour but I
want to rely on the PRF property instead
for the proof and then the last thing is
we're really it's the same same issue in
the key derivation step just want to use
H Mac as its intended to be used as a
pseudo-random function ok so that gives
us this protocol hybrid no it looks
pretty much exactly the same as n tour
is a little
simpler there is one interesting thing
which we talked about in the paper which
is that we're using the same sort of
random key for the earth tag end for the
key there's a attack if you choose the
sizes of your symmetric functions very
poorly but as long as you're targeting
say 128-bit security as we are now and
using symmetric functions that are twice
that size you're fine and against
quantum adversaries we need to do that
anyway because quantum adversary is get
a square root speed up against brute
force search okay so going from hybrid
null I'm just gonna this is the same
protocol I've just made room so I can
add some new things I want to talk about
adding a key encapsulation mechanism to
this a post quantum key encapsulation
mechanism ideally so that we get this
transitional security property so all we
do it's it's really the most obvious
thing that you could do anyone in this
room could have come up with it you just
you just do a post quantum game
capsulation mechanism in parallel with
the existing handshake so the anonymous
client generates public/private key for
some post quantum key encapsulation
mechanism they send their public key
over to the server the server encrypts
some random value to them and sends a
cipher text back that's it you do a few
extra things in the authentication tags
you do want that to contain the entire
transcript of the session so that's
hybrid chem talk about some performance
soft with hybrid chem this is an
instantiation with n true EES 443 ep 1
it's a 128-bit post quantum public key
encryption scheme so it actually has the
CCA to property instead of the cpa
property some people choose very
different security estimates won't be a
lot more conservative and deploying
thing so maybe this this is kind of
right at the heart when t 8 bit level
maybe we want to be more conservative
than this but this is what we tried to
start with this is just a reference
implementation of that parameter set so
the times here are pretty bad but you
can kind of see
that it has a lot of extra communication
costs and the times for the client key
gen is the only thing that's really
substantially more than nth or the other
two excuse me the other two protocols
your tap is the the legacy tour
handshake so that was using finite field
diffie-hellman it's it's ends up being
comparable in time to hybrid with n 10
true and then this last protocol go
check it canta is another post quantum
proposal for tour it's specifically a
ring lwe proposal we wanted to make a
modular thing so that people could try
out different post quantum chems and not
pick winners at this stage since we
don't really know it's so very rapidly
changing field don't know exactly what
people want to deploy whether we want to
optimize for size or efficiency or
exactly what it's going to be so yeah so
we're doing a performance some other
considerations so so right now tour only
alleged have 505 bites in the create
cell and post quantum keys and cipher
texts are generally pretty large so
looking across here s idh with that
enormous prime number is the super
singular I sajni diffie-hellman has been
getting a lot of attention recently it
has pretty good sizes it looks nice and
small but still that's over that 505
bike limit entry es 443 that's the one
that we we wrote our implementation with
600 something bites you know none of
these things are going to fit
fortunately there's a new proposal that
would allow for larger create cells so
hopefully in the near future it would be
possible to deploy some kind of post
quantum chem on production toward a few
other things it would be really nice to
consider multi cipher suite security so
is it okay to reuse this a component the
the servers
long-term secret across multiple cipher
Suites so say with n tour or with hybrid
null or with hybrid and true or whatever
whatever you're using it's probably is
almost certainly fine to do we just
didn't complicate our security model to
prove that another thing would be one
way anonymity the nth or paper defined
an ocean of one-way anonymity and prove
that n tour Matt that notion they use
some features of the authenticating key
exchange model that to define the notion
of one-way anonymity since we changed
models we can't use the same notion but
the other problem is that if you're
introducing multiple cipher Suites
that's obviously going to have an impact
on anonymity so really what we need is
something that can do multi cipher suite
security and talk about one-way
anonymity at the same time if you have
people using different key exchanges or
reducing the anonymity sets so that's
that's a good area for future research
another thing we could think about is
actually deploying a totally post
quantum solution so getting some kind of
post quantum authentication in there may
be using one of these these new hash
based signature schemes in the
directories to distribute long-term chem
keys for the server and then the last
thing is that the type of symmetric
crypto that's currently uses I needs a
is 128 in CTR mode so what's currently
is in tour isn't good enough for our
proof we assume you have some kind of
authenticated encryption so there are
some proposals to upgrade the the
symmetric crypto that's being used in
tour so something like that doesn't need
to be done before you actually get the
guarantees from our proof okay that's
all thanks
you