well thank you so much thank you so much
everyone as you heard it's not my work
but I try to do my best so please
forgive anything that happens in between
but so the good thing with this actually
I was lucky because I tell oh I have to
talk so much about like privacy and
genome but then jean-pierre today
morning took care of the job for me so I
don't think I need to spend too much
time about the necessity for privacy
preserving considerations when it comes
to genomic data but these two folks that
I know chose this particular type of
computation and then said okay well
there's so much that you can do with
genomic data let's focus on only a very
limited number of type of computation
particular they chose non medical
related competition medical statement
things that are not really related to
diagnostic so they chose ancestry test
paternity test and genomic compatibility
test and so ancestry tells the idea is
like add two people want to figure out
what that they're somehow related or not
a paternity you know you might have seen
if you especially which I'm making TV
shows you know there's like the test
that oh you're not the father you know
and then the guy jumps up and starts
dancing and and genomic test is like
basic genetic compatibility is basically
ice and Bob are like have been dating
for a long time they're ready to take
the next step but they want to meet
since they're very educated they want to
make sure that the child or children
that are going to have will not have any
disease so they want to run some contact
compatibility to figure out that they
don't have any disease so these are the
computations that are the focus of this
paper was about right so now the idea is
like as I have been talking about you
know insecure computation you usually
divided into two categories to part ii
multiplayer party right well my party is
easy you know is easier i should say
because you jump immediately you drive
into secret sharing and so talking about
secret sharing verifiable secret sharing
and try to do all those things that we
a lot and we had chermont earlier right
to party well things are slightly
different here to party is better
because as I have been saying Alice and
Bob so it makes sense to focus on to
party the only thing is that to be
different in this paper they decided to
have a server like just saw what was
that was talking about somewhere there
right so the server is going to help
right so it's a survey the two-party
computation and now the assumption here
that I'm making is that at least one of
these parties is quite weak right
computation boys and communication wise
let's say Alice she doesn't want to
participate too much you know and so you
when you're trying to come up with a
solution you have to make sure that you
know you're not putting too much burden
on at least one of them right and you
are trying to leverage the server the
adat server as much as you can write
like okay I guess I can skip all of
these things I'm Pierce edits neeps and
what they are you know what the
particular type of alphabets that they
come from and everything and str czar
something different these are usually
used for a paternity test right so STRs
are basically a list of tuples and in if
I'm if I'm your child for each top oh I
should have one of those to disappear
one of those two that you have I should
have at right that's because one comes
from other one comes from father right
and so and by the way I don't know what
this dr stands for something reckon so
ancestry what you're trying to do you're
trying to compare two snips and and
figure out the intersection right and if
there is bigger than something then you
say ok you guys to close here we are
related somehow right Paterniti as I
said you try to look at this to yours
and say ok well there should be
intersection for each pair and if that
happens for all pairs then you know that
guy is your father or mother
and compatibility test basically there
are different type of combat metals up
suggested or offered by folks at the
genomic area field and it but at the end
of it is either you go the approach of
st ours or else names right so you can
talk about privacy preserving
computation without bringing up your
security model right that's the first
thing that you have to do so these guys
said that I care what is our model amen
when you define your model you have to
spend a good time justifying it right so
why I chose this mud somebody here was
talking about two different types of
adversary's semi honest and malicious
right stop thank you is the advantage of
going last is that someone else talks
anticipation so send me honest the idea
as a subset is basically the adversary's
are going to execute the portico I just
said very quickly right and they don't
deviate malicious they can deviate they
can do everything they want to do and
they can actually they don't have to
provide the inputs that are supposed to
do right so that's actually a big deal
so think about it the inputs could be
anything they can do whatever they want
so they're up to up to go alright so
they can do tampering with the input and
and these guys said that okay for our
prayer / our computations we try to
justify our choices in the ancestry test
they decided to choose semi honest for
the Addison Bob right so the idea is
that you know there are relatives so
there are not enemies to each other and
that's how they justify they said that
you know we are going to say that most
likely they just want to figure out
whether there are truly relatives or
neither have good intentions Paterniti I
don't need to talk about much about it
malicious right
yeah if you watch the shows that dance
when they hear that they are not the
father that's that explains that no they
want to basically change the result
right in their own benefits right and
competitive compatibility for disease so
if you're passing on to your children
also malicious is a good idea think
about it because that type of
competition is a computation that can
reveal information so I can pretend to
have early signs of Alzheimer to figure
out that whether you have it or not
right and if the answer comes out to be
is then I know that you have it too so I
can fake my input to basically figure
out something about your team right so
it in this particular type of
application when you come down and when
you boil it down to the genomic
computation it makes sense that actually
not only you have to assume that the
parties are malicious but on top of that
you have to assume that they may
actually input or they may change their
inputs or temper the inputs right so you
have to have some sort of verification
that the inputs are actually proper
order there are not done in any
particular badly um so again where is
the stuff he talked about a garbage
stickers but again I quickly mention it
when you talk about two-party
computation the first two things or
three things that come to your mind is
one of them is home offering encryption
that usually is expensive is too slow
and then the other thing is garbled sick
wid all de cabra secure from Yahoo's
time all the way too low and there has
been a lot of work to improve it and
make it more efficient and all of that
so I'm going to very quickly jump over
it because he had a very good slide
there that you know you can represent
your function with boolean gays and
basically for each wire you can
represent the inputs of the wire with
labels and the party someone will
generate the horse circuit with all the
labels and someone that guy will be
called a generator and the other guy
will be called evaluator will basically
engage with ever
generator in the computation and says
that ok give me the labels and I will
evaluate the function and go down all
the way at the end of the circle and
figure out the labels for the odds would
write and that type of computation as
you heard earlier on involves oblivious
transfer right and you must have heard
that that is actually costly Portugal so
you want to get rid of it and relies on
public key operations and the less you
do that the better right and ok so
that's obvious transfer I think I can
skip that right so so let's go to the
particles that these guys offer or
provide these particles number one
ancestry test so the assumption here is
that Alice and Bob are relative so
they're semi honest now they're using
garbled circles now if you think about
garble circles there has been lots of
papers that in garbled circles the
circuit generator has to be most times
it has to be semi honest but the
evaluator can be malicious I mean you
can have both of it very malicious too
but that would be very complicated but
in the journal case the generator can be
semi honest oh and then the evaluator
can be malicious so in this case they
assume that you know what we can
actually assume that this folks is from
the sky over here the server is actually
malicious so I just pop send me honest
server malicious and I think this is the
this is a protocol that they came up and
the good thing about this Portugal that
they came up hand is that this is a
garbage secure valuation with no
oblivious transfer so it's quite good
but it's very easy in concept so you
think about is that one guy let's think
about that Bob is a guy that can spend
more time than Alice one guy will
generate the circuit in certain sends it
to the server and Alice will only send
her own the labels are correspond to her
own input and send all of that and to to
server and cyber fascias the computation
facials are gone garble Sitka and then
sends
outputs and then they've both happily in
a fairway figure out the output right
and no obvious transfer quite fast right
but too easy right so I'm going quickly
to the more interesting one when Alice
and Bob are malicious so since there are
malicious they can be in charge of
generating the circuit so who's going to
generate the circuit the guy who is semi
honest which in this case survey right
so the server is going to generate the
circuit and know what is going to happen
is that Bob is going to jump in and says
oh well I'm going to be the evaluator
and now you can't avoid the oblivious
transfer so obvious transfer will come
in and the size of the obvious transfer
protocol that you're going to execute is
the size of the Bob's inputs right and
Alice will just pass hair labels to Bob
right and now Bob is the evaluator he's
going to run the circuit and then we'll
send to he's going to figure out the
labels for the output he's going to give
it to Alice all those labels now Alice
has to figure out that ok these are
actually truly the labels that
correspond to the output so she needs to
some sort of verification method and
what she's going to say is gone she's
going to ask the server so is that ok
give me something so then I will be
satisfied that these are actually truly
the outputs right that is coming from
generator running the circuit so what
the server would do because sarah has
all the labels will hash the labels for
each wire out with where permute them
send them to Alice and Alice will just
have to do a single simple exact match
of the hash of the labels with the hive
with everything that she got from the
server right and so that will take care
of it and again these guys proved with
simulations and everything that why this
is securing with respect to malicious
parties and everything now they have
actually they spend a good time and
something that initiate was difficult
for me to understand but to be honest
forgive you confession but I read that
they so they they go a step further they
for the compatibility test they actually
introduce input verifications right so
in food search
occasion I would say right so now here
you have to rely on another party the
party that like is a trusted party I
don't know like an NIH or someone that
can actually issue signatures on the
inputs right from the beats of the input
tray and so these Alice and Bob will
have the signatures and all they have to
do right now with the help of zero
knowledge of proof and some sort of your
knowledge proof on commitments they can
actually show that the label their
labels that are providing into the
circuits are actually truly correspond
to the inputs that they hold the
signature for it signature from a
trusted party right and so then what
they did so they have all of that and
then they implemented their things right
so they implemented for the upper
ancestry test and i think if i remember
correctly they had I 533 machines Red
Hat I five they just used one core and
they had the very fast land connection
between three of them right so
communication delay was negligible right
and for ancestry they had two to the 17
and snip they didn't just choose that
out of nowhere they look at the genomic
research and they saw that's like a
typical size and they anyway they
implemented and so basically this is the
result that you can see execution column
you know after online you heard about it
I'll fly you can do it separately
locally on lines when parties are
interacting with each other and so you
can see they are pretty fast right and
communication is basically just the size
of the labels and the circus that they
are sending to the to them to the party
and then they did that for paternity
tests but now it looks patently test has
obvious transfer but only one party is
doing it right so that the alice is
completely gone now she's asleep and
Bob's major the Bob's majority of
computation happens at obvious transfer
so that's the bottleneck right right
there and communication kilobytes so
that's
good right and then they did for
generally compatibility no they brought
the signatures and zero knowledge proof
of knowledge and all these times are I
believe in seconds and a millisecond
sorry all these times are milliseconds
and all the communication units are
kilobytes right and so I'm zero time
okay I just say that at the end of their
paper when you read it they actually
implemented all sort of computation with
the matrix multiplication Hamming
distance a bunch of other things and
anyway the claim is that ok we are not
the first people who came up with the
idea of using separate the computation
but they show in their complexity table
that their complexity beats everybody
right and they have the fastest right
with that and yeah we can go and read
their paper and easy questions