it started so my name is Miro and this
is joint work with Alex a Kokua Karl
Koecher and Yoshi kono from the
university of washington computer
science an engineering department and
the motivation for our work was to try
to understand their merging technology
which is the modern automobile and as
you probably know it's increasingly
becoming computerized and connected this
is just a diagram of some of the
embedded computing units that are under
the hood if you were to look at the
communication network that's occurring
in a modern vehicle and sort of a more
formal diagram of that as represented
here where you see the various
controllers that are interacting over
what's known as the the can bus or the
controller area network and as we've
seen from many previous studies security
is a really major threat in this space
and various folks have demonstrated the
kinds of things that you can do in this
space if you were to actually gain
control of that communication area
network you know you're able to to jump
on and essentially exploit a buffer
overflow from the radio to inject
packets and pretend that you're the
brake system and there's no verification
happening and so you can start to create
all kinds of havoc to someone who's you
know trying to normally operate their
vehicle so there's lots of effort now
being done by manufacturers and OEMs in
investing and securing these resources
and I think that this is an area that
that's seeing a lot of active research
both from industry and from from
academia well on the other hand
relatively little is known about the
privacy risks in this space and the the
risks on the other hand are steadily
increasing as there the data sharing
marketplace of the vehicle is growing
and growing we see insurance companies
who are trying to help you save by
figuring out whether or not you're a
good driver we see lots of these
solutions with which you can purchase
for from Amazon and plug in to your car
and then tether to your phone and add
all kinds of smarts to to your
automobile there's also a lots of
interest from the government in trying
to make
car safer through vehicle to vehicle
communication and vehicle to
infrastructure communication so our goal
was to try to understand exactly privacy
from the perspective of driver
identification so we wanted to
understand whether we can uniquely
identify which among a set of end people
is driving by using snippets of the most
basic vehicle sensor messages that are
happening in the car network and we
chose driver identification for for
numerous reasons one we thought that it
was intellectually challenging the
chance of correctly guessing the the
driver given a set of n drivers is 1
over N as opposed to some things like
categorical distinctions like you know
is this driver drunk or drowsy and also
those kinds of distinctions are really
difficult to get with IRB approval we
really wanted to see if we could avoid
having to ask our university to see if
we can give people alcohol before
getting behind the wheel so we also find
this is an important problem by
communicating with various car
manufacturers and startups we're really
interested in understanding the space of
driver identification there's lots of
positive and negative uses that are can
occur with this data on the positive
side you can imagine something like
being able to do theft prevention and on
the negative side you know you could
potentially implicate people in whatever
they're breaking the law so
ferma from a privacy analytics
perspective this was something that was
very interesting to us and we wanted to
understand if we could set some kind of
a lower bound on our expectations of
privacy x' by focusing on the most
simple components the the basic vehicle
sensors and we have a limitation of an N
of 15 folks which was you know partly
imposed by the fact that this had to be
a three-hour study with each individual
but we still think that this is a
significant number for a first study so
getting into a little bit of the details
this is sort of our experimental set up
the vehicle that we used was a 2009
chevy impala and we connected to the
on-board diagnostics port of the vehicle
which is where you get your car
emissions checked
and also where you would plug in to if
you were you know try to monitor the the
health of your of your vehicle with some
of these new sensors that are
commercially available and we tether
that to a laptop and monitored from the
list of 15 sensors that you see on the
right-hand side of the screen they're
just for informational purposes these
these sensors have various reporting
rates as you can see from the three
sensors that I've sort of tried to break
down here at the bottom so the the brake
pedal position is reported at a much
more rapid rate than the currently
available torque to the car and they
also have different ranges over which
they operate so our experimental design
was again as I mentioned 15 drivers
eight male 7 female using the Chevy
Impala and we asked these folks to
perform you know driving in a parking
lot environment which was isolated from
all other drivers as well as a 50-mile
open road stretch and we tried to have
the conditions be maximally identical so
we had the same start time for the
experiments and we also made them listen
to the same sort of pop rock radio
station so the parking lot setup was
it's part of our University campus was
gracious to allow us to use a closed off
section of the of the parking lot to
perform these various maneuvers so we
have the drivers for Villiers for Billy
arrives themselves with the car and
performed 3 laps the first of which was
practice in the second two laps which we
used for analytics and I'll show you a
quick video here of a sort of what it
looks like from from our dash cam where
the driver is performing a three-point
turn and then they'll go around and
perform a reverse weave through these
five cones and then they'll perform
other things like a parallel park and
this is just a snippet from one of the
three lap laps that they were asked to
perform and this is actually 2 X speed
so this is just for illustrative
purposes but you can get a somewhat of a
sense of what the parking lot section
look like
going up to the parallel park
alright I'll stop the video there okay
so okay so for the open road data
section open Road part of the of the
driving the selection criteria for us
was that we wanted to have this start
and end on our campus and we wanted it
to be long enough so that folks would
get familiar with with the vehicle and
start to exhibit their natural driving
tendencies and so this incorporated
driving across residential city highway
and back roads and this is just from one
drivers trip that this is the the
velocity plotted over time and you can
notice that for example the green
sections are all highway driving and
they tend to have high velocity where
some of the downtown driving which is
highlighted here in pink ends up having
a lot of stop and go and so you end up
getting these velocity pits and valleys
here is a sort of a little bit of a
deeper dive within some of those
sections so again the downtown is the
first one here shown in in pink and if
you just look at some of the sensor
values that are occurring during that
time the red is the is the brake the the
blue is the vehicle speed and you can
see sort of the alternating pattern of a
brick of brakes and gas interestingly
some folks tend to sort of you know push
down on the brake pedal more so while
they're parked rather than others and
then this here that the bottom plot is a
sort of technical back road driving
where there's lots of loops and turns
and let me just very briefly show you a
little bit of that again this is a 4x
speed so this is going quite fast but
but you can see you know this is kind of
like an interesting section of Mercer
Island around Seattle where folks had a
chance to sort of show off some of their
their fancy turns and stuff so we tried
to incorporate a mix of various driving
conditions just to enable some of these
unique
driver fingerprints to come out but as
our
I ended up showing you don't actually
need to do anything fancy to have people
as diverse driving strategies come out
so mmm just got a word on how we did the
some of this data analysis for each of
the the various sensory streams we did
some smoothing resampling to get
everything down to the same data rate so
the 60 Hertz and then we did a tiled
sliding windows so that 25% of the
windows were overlapped to allow for
really large variations to not occur at
window edges and for each of these
windows we computed a bunch of
statistics such as you know mid max
average there's quartiles and some
frequency components as well such as the
energies and the bins and then we scaled
all of all of these features from the
from the training data so we did you
know 10-fold cross-validation and during
each training fold we would figure out
what the scaling parameters were so that
the average and the standard deviation
and we would apply the same scaling to
the whenever we did our test queries one
interesting thing about the way we did
the classification here was that unlike
sort of maybe traditional methods where
you do one versus all comparisons we did
a matrix of pairwise sort of specialized
classifiers so what I'm trying to show
with this light here is that you would
take all of the sliding window feature
vectors computed for one subject which
were part of the training batch and you
would combine those with all of the
sliding windows features from a second
subject and that would allow you to
Train one specialized classifier that's
able to distinguish just between those
two subjects and that would essentially
be one cell of this matrix so in order
to or at least the approach that we took
here is that we'd need to populate the
upper section of this matrix since it
doesn't really matter whether or not you
train a classifier between subject 1 or
2 or between subject 2 and one they're
essentially the same so the upper
triangular section of this matrix is all
you need and for our purposes that meant
that for n subjects we needed to train
and squared over to class
and actually in order to do you know
retrieval or search over this matrix
given a set of queries you only need n
log n lookups using this algorithm that
we use doc you waited so long story
short the the results of what we found I
think we're pretty compelling and that
is to say that you don't need very much
data in order to be able to do positive
identification over the set of subjects
we looked at so we reached ninety one
point three three percent accuracy when
all of our sensors were available just
on the parking-lot data so those two
loops which were about eight minutes in
total you could also use just a single
sensor and this was pretty interesting
it turns out that probably the most
differentiable thing in people's driving
styles is how they decelerate or how
they use the brake pedal and so if you
just take about the first 15 minutes of
of the drive which kind of looked like
this where folks were going from our
University campus down to the Space
Needle in Seattle if you take these 15
minutes of driving you know where people
are doing murders on to the highway a
few lane shifts and then a bunch of
turns then with just the brake pedal
during this 15 minutes you are able to
identify drivers that are really high
rate I think we reached like 88 percent
approximately and then if you took just
the brake pedal over the course of the
entire trip you were able to get a
hundred percent accuracy across our
drivers so I think you know and of
course if you take all sensors across
the drive you get a hundred percent very
easily
one last thing I'll mention is this
extension that we did to try and
understand how stable the fingerprint of
the driver was across different days so
for that particular study we had one
driver repeat five days of this 22 mile
trip from the University and you know
whenever we use those those new trips as
part of a query against our old data set
where the driver I performed the same
trip that everyone else did we ended up
getting 91% accuracy and whenever we
excluded the drivers data for from the
data set and then tried to query with
their new instances of those five
we ended up getting lots of confusion
that the you know the network couldn't
figure out who to attribute this data to
so it was I was guessing quite poorly
but which is to say that you know if if
we don't have a record of someone you
try to identify them then that also
isn't gonna work well which again sense
to say that the fingerprinting is it
seems to be quite stable this is some of
the top sensors that were useful here
the brake pedal as I mentioned the
steering wheel and then the the lateral
acceleration this is all available in
the paper in case you're interested and
also just the hierarchical clustering of
some of the correlations between the
sensor data I'll briefly just mentioned
that I think you know we use the end of
15 and it would be very interesting for
future work to try and understand how
this would work for the firm larger sets
of candidate pools of drivers one kind
of encouraging you know result in this
in this direction is that even if you
take the most similar drivers and you
sort of project their data into two
dimensions you end up seeing that there
are some areas where they end up
diverging which is to say that you know
with additional effort here you could
probably come up with some features that
are really useful for fingerprinting and
again this is feature work most likely
so as far as defenses
we're just proposing some things here
and the thing that we think it could be
promising is feature transformations of
the data
sort of in real-time that would still
enable some kind of inferences to occur
or you could imagine these these dongles
that the insurance company plugs into
your car you could sort of get your own
sort of defensive dongle that their
dongle would plug into and run some kind
of filtering techniques on it or you
could alternatively inject packets by
the car maybe if you get manufacturer
Buy in here so that you would sort of
obfuscate or at least introduce some
noise that would make these kinds of
privacy attacks a little harder so
that's it and this is some of the
submarine takeaway that I'll leave up
during the QA
you