so I'm Ryan from Indiana University and
I'm gonna talk about some work that I
have been doing on making
information-theoretic PIR more efficient
using batch codes so we've seen two
different styles of PIR now we'll see
the third so I'm gonna very briefly go
over the PIR problem because I think by
now you all know what the PIR problem is
we have a user Bob here who is trying to
fetch some information over the Internet
typically he's going to send some
requests to a remote server and get some
sort of response and this being pets
were interested in providing some notion
of privacy for the user in particular
we're considering scenarios where for
example Bob is trying to research a
super-secret patent idea that he has he
wants to find out is this novel before
he devotes the next six months of his
life to working out the details and he's
worried that perhaps this remote server
might infer what his idea is and patent
it before he's actually finished so we
want to make sure that we can allow
these queries but provide privacy to
prevent this sort of attack and the
approach we're going to take is actually
the very first approach with some tweaks
the very first PIR approach so we have a
database which we're gonna model as a
matrix it's gonna have our rows each row
is going to be s where it's long and
what the user is trying to fetch is one
of the rows from this matrix so it's
just a matrix over some finite field and
the way we're going to represent a query
into this matrix is using a vector from
the standard basis so this vector is
going to be a length or a vector where R
corresponds to the height of that matrix
it's going to consist of all zeros
except for a one in a particular
position which corresponds to the row
that the user is trying to fetch and
we'll define the result of the query to
be the product of that vector with that
matrix and for those of you that
remember your basic linear algebra it
should be pretty easy to see that if you
multiply that vector times that matrix
what will pop out is indeed the J throw
okay so this seems to work but we don't
have any sort of privacy so we need to
do something here to get privacy from
this and it turns out this is actually
relatively simple
so the approach we're gonna use was
proposed by Goldberg back in 2007 we're
going to replicate the database as was
previously mentioned among several
different servers and then Adi here is
giving us the missing piece we're going
to use his secret sharing scheme to take
this basis vector which is clearly non
private and secret share it component
wise so we're going to take each and
every entry in this why isn't it going
we're getting each and every entry in
this vector and we're gonna use similar
secret sharing scheme to turn them into
vectors that look essentially random
we're gonna send those to the servers
and then we're gonna wait and wait and
wait and wait while these servers
multiply these random looking vectors
times the copy of the database that they
have and hopefully it's some time soon
because they only have 15 minutes for
this talk the server's will come back
with their responses and because
everything here is linear the secret
sharing is linear the vector matrix
multiplication is linear the user just
has to do a component wise
reconstruction on the responses and lo
and behold what pops out is the record
that the user was after but from the
perspective of any individual server
clearly they can't figure out what the
user was after and in fact the number of
servers that would have to work together
to figure out what the user was after is
the same as the number of servers or the
the parameter that was chosen to the
secret sharing the reconstruction
parameter so if we make an appropriate
non collusion assumption we can prove
that it is literally impossible for
these servers 2d anonymize the query so
what i'm interested in was that step
where we waited and waited and waited
and waited and seeing what we can do to
reduce the amount of time we have to
wait so the EPI we have PIR can we get
to the new stuff yes yes we can get to
the new stuff so the basic tool we're
gonna use is called a ramp scheme for
those of you who aren't familiar with
ramp schemes I'm just gonna go over very
quickly it's a very natural
generalization of secret training
schemes that have actually been studied
as long as secret training schemes have
but don't show up in applications quite
as often so on a typical secret sharing
scheme we have some parameter I'm
calling it T here if the attacker
gets their hands on tea or fewer shares
they learn nothing at all about what the
secret is but as soon as they have T
plus 1 or more shares they have the
entire secret and a wrap scheme just
relaxes this so that if you have tea or
fewer shares you still have no
information about the secret but in
order to get complete information about
the secret you don't have to have T plus
you shares where u is some parameter
that's at least one and the upshot of
this relaxation is we can now fit new
secrets or U times as many secret bits
into the secret cheering scheme so the
shares that the users have look exactly
like they used to but we have a you fold
improvement in the amount of information
we can pack and we're gonna try to use
this to speed up the PR and how do we
actually implement this so if you think
of Shamir secret sharing scheme as you
have a random polynomial it's random
other than the y intercept which encodes
a secret we're gonna do basically the
same thing except now the y intercept
encodes a secret and perhaps when you
evaluate the polynomial at x equals 1
you get a different secret we could pack
another secret at x equals 2 etc so in
this example there's just two secrets
and I'm gonna set T equal to two so to
make the private the polynomials we use
for a ramp scheme sharing we just throw
a couple of other random points on there
then we interpolate through these and
then we evaluate the result in
polynomial at some other points and hand
those out to the various shareholders
okay so how do we use this to speed up
PR so there's actually two different
things that I'm going to talk about one
of them is new one of them is old and
then the third thing is how we glue
those together to get a really fast
protocol so the first idea the new one
we take our R by s matrix and the first
step is just a rewriting step so we're
gonna think of it as a bunch of U by s
matrices stacked on top of each other so
right now I'm just rewriting changing
notation but I haven't actually changed
anything then from there we are going to
take this collection of eubiose matrices
and we are going to turn each matrix
into a set of ramp shares and typically
you would just set the privacy parameter
to 0 here but there are cases where you
might want to set it higher and we'll
talk about those but the paper discusses
it a bit
so what we're actually doing here is
we're taking one column of this matrix
we're interpolating through it to get a
polynomial of degree U minus one and
that's the first entry here in the
second column of this becomes the second
polynomial here so again this matrix is
a new representation of this thing but
it's equivalent right it's just a
different representation it's very easy
to go from here to here and it's very
easy to go from here back to here by
just evaluating these polynomials and
putting the results in the right places
the next step things change slightly so
we're going to take this vector or this
matrix with polynomials and rather than
handing out the entire matrix to each of
the servers we're going to evaluate it
and hand out evaluations to the server
so the first server is going to have
this whole matrix evaluated at some x
coordinate the second server is gonna
have it evaluated at some other x
coordinate and so on and so now suddenly
each of the servers rather than holding
an R by s replica of the matrix holds an
R over U by s matrix of scalars so this
is much smaller I mean at least half the
size if you set u equals to an even
smaller if you said you higher and so
now we need to figure out how do you
actually get something out of this was
early encoded IR database it turns out
this is pretty simple so we're gonna
take the index of the record rafter and
we're just gonna figure out from that
which polynomial contains the record
that we're looking for and at what value
do we need to evaluate that polynomial
to make the record we're looking for pop
out and this is very simple you take a
and you try to divide it by you and you
get your quotient and remainder and the
quotient is going to tell you which row
in this polynomial matrix contains your
record and the remainder is going to
tell you what x-coordinate you need to
evaluate that polynomial at to get the
map the record you were at how you're
after out then we're going to do
essentially the plain old secret sharing
PIR query except we're going to use this
shorter standard basis vector that we
get from the quotient and rather than
having the y-intercept of our secret
cheering polynomials passed through this
we're going to have the point at x
equals whatever that remainder was and
then everything else works out exactly
as it used to and when we look at the
costs of this protocol we find that
compared to the original protocol I
started we get some nice performance
improvements basically the upload
computation and storage costs are each
decreased by a factor you for whatever
it is that that you parameter to okay so
that's pretty nifty what's the trade-off
so I've only got 15 minutes I'll get
back to that later the second thing
we're gonna do is figure out how can we
get more information out of the database
at the same cost this is actually work
that I did with Ian Goldberg and each
along back in 2013 that I'm going to
talk about briefly and then we'll see
how it can work with this so the idea
here is rather than sending a vector
like this we want to fetch several
blocks what we really want to do is send
a matrix it has a whole bunch of
different queries into it but we want to
try to do this sort of as efficiently as
possible this was where we first came up
with the idea of using ramp schemes we
thought rather than component was
sharing this matrix why don't we use the
ramp scheme and turn this into a single
vector and send the resulting vectors of
scalars rather than matrices of scalars
to the server's and we get a nice
speed-up so here we have this matrix we
turn it into a vector of polynomials
rather than a matrix of polynomials we
send a vector to each server and when
you do that we found that you also get a
nice speed up when we pack Q rows into
the ramp scheme polynomials we get a
factor Q speed up in the upload/download
and computation cost so that's quite
nice again what's the trade-off and
again don't worry about it okay so the
next thing I want to talk about is what
happens if we try to put these things
together and it turns out you can use
this what I call the Uwharrie encoding
this taking the database and encoding it
in these ramp scheme polynomials with
those Q batch queries and then if you
add in some other very important little
details which I will just sweep under
the rug for the time being you get Q
blocks for the cost of 1 over u blocks
which is quite nice so what are the
important details that I'm sweeping
under the rug there if you think about
this encoded matrix that I was talking
about you could kind of view it as a
three-dimensional matrix so we have our
over you rose s columns but then we have
for lack of a better term new slices to
this so if you evaluate these
polynomials at 0 you get this set of r /
u records and if you evaluate it at 1
you get a different set of our / u
records and so on and if you think about
how you query this thing well if we want
the ice block from the J's slice the way
we actually fetched that is we encode a
particular standard basis vector at a
particular x-coordinate and the annoying
observation that comes from this is we
can't actually use one of these
multi-block these cubed queries to fetch
more than one block that come from the
same slice because we find ourselves in
the impossible situation of taking two
different basis vectors and encoding
them at the same x-coordinate in their
polynomials so just occurred to us and
we might all darn that's that's
unfortunate or to me rather and I went
oh darn that's unfortunate but then I
realize there's a very simple fix for
this oh yes this is the cost of I don't
know this is sort of out of place oh
okay sorry I eliminated a slide so
there's a very simple fix for this which
is basically to take the each of these
records and put them in their own slice
so we're gonna rather than using the
remainder upon division by you to figure
out which x coordinate we put it in we
just take each record so if you want
record one you evaluate the polynomial
at x equals one and if you want record
to you evaluate the Paloma at x equals
two so we still have our over you rose
but now we've sort of you can't really
draw a picture anymore I'm yeah
but sorry I think I botched that
explanation but hopefully you kind of
follow so if you want to get the record
you find the appropriate row and then
you evaluate it at the x coordinate
corresponding to the true index of the
record year after rather than its
remainder and suddenly now we couldn't
fetch any record we want in a batch
together and we don't have to worry
about these collisions at an x
coordinate if that was not clear please
read the paper because it's clear
okay so when you do that what we find is
we get really nice speed ups in every
real reasonable cost metric so to get
cue blocks from one of these you area
encoded databases we get a factor qu
speed-up in two of the metrics we get a
factor Q speed-up in the download cost
and a factory you speed up in a storage
cost and everything is is much quicker
than it used to be so I implemented this
in per C++ the open source
implementation of the basic PIR protocol
I was talking about and this is an
arbitrary graph because there were so
many moving pieces I didn't know what to
write what to actually measure but I
thought this was nice and illustrative
so here we have the database size going
up to about 256 gigabytes and the
clients there the server side compute
time this is a single core so everything
here is embarrassingly parallel izybelle
but the experiments only used one core
this top line is the cost to run the
protocol with the default u equals 1 so
the standard before I made any changes
and we see that the cost of doing this
256 gigabyte database on the particular
computer I threw at it is up at around a
thousand seconds when I set u equals 8
which seemed like a reasonable upper
bound on the realistic size we get a
factor 13.5 speed-up we get more than
the factor 8 speed up because I ran out
of RAM at around this line so so in this
case everything fits in RAM but here
everything doesn't fit in RAM and you
end up getting some latency because of
that so things are quite a bit faster
the upshot of this so basically it takes
about 0.2 seconds per gigabyte per soak
or seconds per gigabyte to process this
database if you have 16 cores divide
that number by 16 things they're quite
fast ok so I kept saying don't worry
about the trade-off don't worry about
the trade-off right now I'll briefly
touch on what the trade-off is so when
that original protocol by Goldberg was
proposed back in 2007 the actual title
of the paper was improving the
robustness of private information
retrieval and the main contribution was
that the protocol could handle quite a
few incorrect responses from the
server's so if you set that privacy
threshold to be a little bit smaller
than the total number of servers and you
can handle some server's not responding
and some of the responding server's
responding incorrectly and use ideas
from err correcting codes to make sure
that you still retrieve the information
you want and so this was sort of the
breakthrough that you could get this
guru Swami sedan list decoding radius as
your robustness level we fast forward
five years there's new techniques new
ideas and this bound has increased quite
dramatically so the idea is if you were
happy with this level of robustness but
suddenly we just get this level of
robustness for free then we can
reallocate some of that robustness to
get better throughput so at the end of
the day the user the server's get to set
these parameters however they want l
here is the number of servers T is that
privacy threshold so what we want to do
is keep L and T fixed we want to say
there's this many servers this many of
them conclude and we get to play with
these other parameters I didn't talk
about tau but it's discussed in the
paper and the observation is we can set
Q and u however we want up until V gets
down to zero and so by n V is the number
of malicious servers we can tolerate so
by reducing this number of malicious
servers we can increase those Q&U
parameters arbitrarily to whatever level
we want in as long as this this equality
is satisfied everything will still work
so that was everything I wanted to take
away or wanted to say my take away is
that if you use ramp schemes in ITP IR
you can get very fast this still slow
compared to non private but fast
compared to everything else I have an
information retrieval okay