good afternoon everyone my name is
machine so today I'm going to present
this work a qualitative study done with
my advisor professor Jung Hwan and which
one doing so we're trying to understand
people to perception of of Jones this
emerging emerging technology so the
motivation of this study comes from two
aspects so first there have been a few
studies about Jones by by scholars from
different fields such as government
agencies legal scholars about Jones
safety and security but little is known
how how people think about about Jones
second is people's perception of Jones
can help us to inform future privacy
enhancing junk design as well as public
parallel policies so in this particular
study we understand people's perception
of Jones from the bystanders perspective
so by saying bystanders we mean people
who do not have experience with drugs so
we adopt an interview interview
methodology in this study so we have for
the interview protocol we have three
type of questions the first type is
general questions so in the general
questions we basically ask people some
general aspects of Jones for example
have you ever see Jones flight do you
see any benefits and issues of Jones
this kind of questions the second type
of question our context based questions
so because as a professor Helen
nissenbaum mentioned that human behavior
are always situated in some concrete
context so we provide five scenarios in
order to get people's perception on the
different context so our scenarios
include recording of promotional events
in the shopping mall by our stall owner
on delivering goods by Amazon recording
a friend's party are reporting a parade
by the news agency and also search for
criminals in your neighborhood by the
local police department so and also the
third type of questions are about
specific aspects of Jones for example we
ask the participants to compare the
differences between jones and other
tracking technologies such as phones and
CCTVs
this is the Joan we use for the study in
terms of participant that we have 16
interviews in total and the fifty
percent of them mail filter female then
their age ranges from 60 18 to 62 years
old with an average of 29 and our
participants also represented a variety
of ethnic backgrounds advisor as well as
occupations so for data analysis we
first all recorded all the interviews
upon the participants information we
then translate the other interviews all
the interviews into pling tags we
conducted a thematic analysis which is a
commonly used method for qualitative
data analysis so how we do this as
follow so we first immerse immersed
ourselves in the data by carefully
reading all the other interviewee other
interview transcripts and then take
notes for those meaningful meaningful
patterns now so we are then we
independently code the the transcript
transcripts and then then we discussed
our difference and the win discuss how
we can group these costs into high level
things and then we come up with nine
themes 132 unique codes and nine themes
here are the things we come up with and
then the last step is is we revisit
everything and to make sure that all the
interview excerpt each team coherently
represent a day under the underlying say
magazine so so now the these to us to
the finding so so because the time Tom
strains i'm not going to talk about all
the funnies here are some the most
interesting ones so first public space
or private space is a key factor that
our participant in considered in
determining their expectations of
privacy and also whether the Joan is
Joan violence there there
privacy so generally speaking if a Joan
take a photo or record a video or even
just flies in the private area and they
consider that the Joan invades their
privacy so this is kind of intuitive but
this brought out a very interesting
question so what is private space what
is public space and where is the
boundary between Providence public space
so our participant actually brought up
very there is understanding of poverty
space in public space here's an example
so as this participant suggested so
he/she considered even she's in the
public space as long as she's not
participating in any public event she
still considered that as the practice
space for example she specifically
mentioned that if I'm sitting in the in
the in a shopping mall I considered the
area around me as private space because
if you walk close to me you will be able
to hear my phone call or look at my
email if you if you want to so so in
that this case so she has a very
different understanding of public space
then so because of the time constraint
then I'm not able to show all these
samples so that detailed we have various
definitions from the participants about
private space and public space you can
find it on the paper another funny we
have is about people's is based on the
scenario questions or participant is
suggested that they have different
expectations of privacy under different
scenarios especially on our participant
suggests that they're expecting expected
notification and consent of the German
usage in different context for example
in in the recording parade scenario this
participants to suggest that prior
notification is is needed however in the
attending a party attending party and
record the party scenario this
participant also she suggested that
prior notification is not the
sir because if you are not consent to
give you're not concerned to be recorded
that you should not go to the party then
another interesting findings we have
from our study is about that comparison
between jones and other technologies
like camera phones and CCTVs so as just
about our participants there are four
factors that can differentiate Jones
with other checking technologies first
is the distance of recording the
distance of recording indicates that
when using Joan photos can be taken in a
distance without the people's awareness
the flexibility indicates that the Joan
can can actively invade bystanders
personal space which we can their
control over their own privacy and the
visibility and or accessibility of the
controller means that when the Joan even
a Joan is spotted and it's flying on in
the sky the people the the controller
can still hide from the public side and
that the bystanders is not able to know
who is the controller and we call this
the hidden controller also the intended
purpose means that the intended purpose
of the journalists are known to the
bystanders so here's the example as the
100 the participant is said when the gym
is when the phone is taking the photo
you will most likely see it and you know
it is taking a poem but but with the
Jones they were you are not be able to
know because it's even though you see
the gym you don't know who the people
behind this so Joe from this these
conclusions we we brought up this
concept of the duality of the Jones so
the duality of the Jones means that
people's perception of Jones are not
only bounded to the to the joint itself
but also the controller behind the job
and their and the people to the
relationship with the drunk controllers
so this week or what we call this the
duality of the job the idea is that as
the this participant is suggested when
the dome is taking a photo you don't
even know who is the controller so
on this these are all the finance lead
us to the discussion of our of our
results so first we as I mentioned
before we want to highlight the duality
of Jones also we want to mention the
dome stability to to invade people's
physical privacy as well as the
information privacy so physical privacy
means people's privacy in their physical
space such as their office or houses and
the information privacy means the
people's personal data so their names
they're addressed and their credit card
number things like this but so if you
come but if you think of the duality of
the Jones and the physical privacy and
information privacy together so you were
noticed that sean has the ability to
invade the full physical privacy and
information privacy but what's more
important is that in most the case even
John even Joan invade people's physical
privacy and information privacy most
people were not were most likely don't
know who is who is a controller behind
the job and now so this is this is the
time when the privacy concerns arise and
also we discussed people's contest to
base the privacy concerns so as I
mentioned before there are several
context factors such as whether the dome
is flying in Paris space or public space
or the purpose of the drone can also
raise different private concerns the
privacy concerns of jobs so we have some
other findings like you know people's we
our participants suggest that they have
a clear understanding of the benefits of
Jones and the future development and
future the future of her Jones and also
they also brought up the security
concerns as well as safety concerns for
example if the drone fall down from the
sky they will be hurt tastes like this
and I don't
cover this here so again if you if
interest you can find it in a paper so
the next part we want to draw is the
design implication and also some of the
public policy into a policy implication
so first we placed our findings we
proposed to some high-level design
principles so the first time I is making
so future we propose that future Joan
should and their controllers should make
him both the Joan and their controller
more discoverable approachable and
accountable to the bystanders so that
they can be discovered people can know
each other and also we suggest that the
future drone system can should enable
the communication between shown
controllers and other nurse citizens or
or as we call by sanders and also a
future drone should future manufacturer
should make Joan design sensitive to
local to local social and cultural norms
so this is suggest also suggested by a
you know the content contextual
integrity so that because you know
different people have different
expectations under different social and
cultural context to be more specific we
have some we made some specific design
suggestions from two dimensions so the
first dimension is from Joan control and
its controllers versus bystanders and
also proactive measures versus reactive
matters so for example Joan can actively
send out signals indicating that it's so
here the first the first ones then
figures in fig nose signals so that
people who do not want to be in the
photo will know it is taking photos and
then they can probably walk away thus we
suggest that future systems should
support this type of signal
communication also another example would
be bystanders can actively you know send
some requests to access the photos which
might have done in the site so future we
suggest that future system should also
provide this kind of
communication the possibility of the
communication between the bystanders and
and controllers we also have some
detailed policy implications and then
because of time limit I'm not present
here so we're presenting this work in a
FT C drum workshop in this fall in
Washington DC so hopefully we can
provide them some people input on the
further policymakers so a little bit
about ongoing future work so we are
because this study is from the
bystanders perspective so we want to
understand the perp the perception from
the controller perspective to see
whether there are any differences
between their understanding and also we
want to come up with some practical
mechanisms that can that that is
acceptable by post controllers and
bystanders so the major takeaway from
this from our study so the first is we
provide empirical evidence for the
safety security security and privacy
issues of Jones and also again we won't
highlight the duality of John and the
third is we are proposed that the
proactive and reactive suggestions for
future own future privacy handsome drone
design um thank you so the any questions
I'll be happy to take them