[Music]
uh
hey welcome everybody to day two of dns
arc
my name is manu brotel and i work at
facebook and i will be
sharing the sessions today i will be
with jake that is going to be our
timekeeper
you may hear his voice like five minutes
before
the q a session um like yesterday you
will have chances to
rates the talks uh this will happen
during the q a
please do so this helps the speakers and
the forum committee
to get feedback on the talks today we
will start with a series of
talks and then there is a member only
session
you members should have received a link
if you didn't please
send an email to admin dns forward.net
without further ado i would like to
introduce ben
schwarz from google he's going to tell
us about
everything about service binding https
and svcb records
ben hi thank you manu
i i think of uh of this talk as really
just a warm up for
ralph webber's great presentation that's
going to immediately follow
so uh you may have seen these slides
before
these are almost identical to the slides
that i i used to
discuss this topic at the ripe dns
meeting
in i believe october they're also pretty
similar to a series of presentations
that have happened at the ietf
but even if this is old news for you
please stick around
for ralph webber's talk that's going to
follow on on the similar related topic
fyi we don't see your slides yet
perfect we see them now thank you
great so uh i'm one of three co-authors
of a an ietf draft that's approaching
finalization
that defines two new http new dns record
types
the service binding type or service b
and the https resource record
to tell the story of how we got here we
need to talk about cname
i'm sure everybody here knows about
cname
but and cname is great
it's really a brilliant
component of the the dns system
but it does have this one crucial
limitation
that no other data should be present
it at the same node that is on the same
name
as a cname that's because a resolver
with a cached c name will follow that
alias without
further communication with the
authoritative to see if there's anything
else there
so in effect there cannot be anything
other than a c name at a name
which means there can't be an ns record
uh
at the same at the same name
then sorry to interrupt just to let you
know we don't see your video i'm not
sure this is on purpose or not
uh i believe this client only supports
screen sharing or video
uh not both at the same time
so because of this you can't put a cname
at a zone apex
okay that's background
another important piece of background is
srv records which again i'm sure many of
you are familiar with
srv records in a sense solve this
problem
that cnames can't alias an apex domain
srvs can sit alongside an ns record at
the apex
and can provide a kind of indirection
where clients will will follow an alias
to the specified target name
and this is widely used and solves the
apex aliasing problem for a lot of
protocols
but it is not widely implemented
for http in particular much to the
disappointment
of some people who would like to solve
this kind of problem for
http and https
and it also has suffered from some
problems related to a latency penalty
basically problems if intermediate
layers of the stack
are not aware and supporting of this new
record type
which sorry srv is no longer such a new
but alas there still are many
components of the dns system that are
not really
suited for it so that was the status quo
in 2000 and then over the following
decades we've seen
in my view some transformations of
how the internet is used at scale
one of the important things that's
changed is that cdns have emerged
and cdns make heavy use of
cname to make it really easy for people
to point their domain at a very large
scale hosting operator
who can handle all the details of web
hosting
that's easy and convenient but it
can't handle the apex domain and so
there's a real puzzle about what to do
if you really want a cdn to host your
apex domain
and i won't talk through all the details
here except to say
that it's inconvenient it can be done
and it is certainly done at scale today
but it's not as easy as just c naming
your name to a cdn
uh once cdns became well established we
started to see
a growth in interest in multi-cdn
hosting
multi-cn hosting is particularly
important for
clients to be able to move between cdns
because
there's always going to be a transition
period where
some users are are experiencing a
website or reaching a website on the old
cdn and some
users are reaching it on a new cdn and
in order for websites to be able to move
cleanly between hosts
it's really valuable if those
transitions can happen
invisibly without downtime
so again with with cnames this is
relatively easy
the dns standards don't make this easy
to express in a zone file
but you can in effect just
have two cnames um
uh and everything will will basically
work fine and as you roll
out the the second cname users will flip
over to the new cdn
but what about for the apex domain
well this is actually relatively
straightforward
you can just sort of mix the ips
together if you want to host
on two different cdns especially for
example if
you want clients to be able to fl to
failover between them if
if one of them experiences downtime for
some reason
and that works fine the cdns are
completely interchangeable
but in 2018 we saw the first version
the formal version of a proposal for
encrypted sni which is now called
encrypted client hello
which is an addition to the tls standard
in this version of in this addition to
tls
the tls server publishes a public key
in the dns and the client fetches it and
uses it to encrypt the first message
i suppose i should say that dain
dain based authentication operates in a
similar fashion and so if you're using
encrypted client hello or
probably also if you're using dane cdns
are no longer interchangeable
the client gets a public key for a
particular cdn
trying to use cdna's public key with cdn
b's ip address is going to fail hard
so we have a problem
and the solution is that we we need a
new record type
that allows us to bind together these
pieces of information
so that the services ip address and
the public keys and whatever else the
client needs to know
are all bound together into an atomic
collection
that is not going to get chopped up into
into pieces and then mismatched by the
time it gets to the client
and we also need to allow aliasing the
apex
because uh the the cdn
the hosting infrastructure needs to
manage both its ip addresses
and its set of public keys really
we really don't want to put ourselves in
the position
of cdn clients copying the cdn's public
keys
into the client's zone which is
ripe for all kinds of of terrible
problems
like making it impossible to
to do key rotation and expiration
so we need a way to bind together all of
this information about a service
and we need a way to alias names
to that bound collection of information
and so we call this a service binding
record this is the zone file form of the
new rr type it looks
a lot like srv which is not a
coincidence
but it is also substantially different
in a few different ways
like srv it has a priority field that
priority field has a special case for
priority zero which means alias
effectively it means go to the target
name
and do another service binding query
otherwise the svcb or service binding
record
contains an arbitrary key value data
store
where the the keys are iana controlled
and so this can contain in effect a
complete description
of anything the client might need to
know in order to connect to the server
and just like srv the
client has to chase these aliases which
creates a performance problem and just
like srv
the recursive resolver can help
by doing some additional section
processing to include
those follow-up responses
this draft also defines a new rr type
called https
and this is exactly the same as
service b except
that the naming scheme is defined not to
use the underscore prefixes so if i go
back one slide
service b uses an underscore prefix
scheme not quite the same as srvs
effectively designed to encode the
authority portion of a uri so if you
have
a uri that has some scheme and a name
and maybe a port
or possibly other information this is
flexible depending on the exact protocol
that you're trying to
indicate that's all encoded into the
name here
with https those prefixes are skipped
if the protocol is https which it always
is
and the port is 443.
and this has two really important
properties it
makes wildcard domains work a lot better
it means that you can put a wildcard
https record next to a wildcard
a or quad a record and everything
basically
should work it also means that existing
cname delegations
work so if a client issues
an address query and a service b which
is now an https
query to the same name and that name is
cnamed to some
other name both of those queries will
follow the cname and so
they'll get you'll get the right
information that you're looking for
whereas if there were prefixes the
client would have to add an additional c
name or
i guess hypothetically convert the c
name to a d name or something
and since there's an enormous install
base of these existing c name
delegations
we felt it was important to maintain
compatibility
another interesting thing that the https
record does is that it
signals that the origin is available
over https
and so the client takes this as a signal
to never speak unencrypted http
to this endpoint the the client will not
be
susceptible to ssl stripping once it
gets this record
so here are some quick examples this is
an example of alias mode i'm happy to
come back to this if people want
to talk about it more this is an example
of service mode
where there's some actual information
about the service
one important thing that this highlights
is that the https or service b
record has the ability to convey
that a given endpoint supports http 3.
and so this is interesting and new it
means that a client
before it connects to an http
destination can find out that this
destination
supports http 3 which runs over udp
over quick and make use of that
in its initial connection so you can
potentially with these records
have clients that reach you without ever
speaking tcp
whereas without this record clients
always need to
speak tcp over standard tls
at least once in order to find out that
the service supports http 3
and follow that upgrade path which costs
many many round trips
one key thing about the client behavior
here is that
if the client is is a dual stack client
that's already
issuing a and quad a queries every time
the client issues an a in quad a query
if we're talking about an http web
browser like client
it's also going to issue an https query
so roughly we can expect something like
a 50
increase in query volume from endpoints
of this kind
and ralph weber will will share with us
some
some information about what kinds of
query changes they're currently
observing
the client has to follow aliases if the
recursive resolver doesn't
do it for them through additional
section processing
and the client essentially has full
responsibility for following
all of the indirections here
one of the tricky things here is
encrypted client hello because
encrypted client help contains security
relevant
information the client can't proceed
with the connection
until the https record completes
so the client needs to wait and find out
if there is
our data here if there is an https
record in the zone
before it can even begin the connection
process really
there's some subtle optimizations there
but but that's fundamentally the
limitation
and this is a potential operational
challenge given that we're introducing a
new rr type
this is just an example of a use case
for the multi-cdn case
there's a tricky thing with https and
service b records called ip hints this
has been i think somewhat controversial
i mentioned earlier that clients are
responsible for chasing
the chasing the
aliases and target names if the
recursive resolver doesn't do it for
them
the ip hints are a way to reduce the
performance cost of that case
so they're only applicable in the case
where the recursive resolver is not
doing the additional section processing
and they're specified
only as hints so the client is
is recommended to still follow the alias
and
cache the address records
for the target name so that in
future connection attempts they won't
use the hints they'll use the actual
address records
so that these resource record types are
real they have assigned code points
the draft is nearly final and there's
serious deployment now
in clients in servers and
now in resolvers i happen to work at
google and so
i'm happy to announce that chrome now
has
real code that is being tested for
performing these queries although not
for taking any action with them yet
right now we're just testing
whether we can actually perform the
query safely without it causing any
problems
and i'm happy that firefox is also
doing some experimentation here and that
there are many authoritative
dns implementations that are making
great progress here
so that's all i have for slides and i'm
happy to
take any questions all right thank you
ben
uh yeah in terms of questions please um
we have two ways to do it either you can
type your question in the q a tab and i
will uh
and i will ask you a question or you can
raise your hand and ask your question
by yourself we have a question from
hazel smith that is
going to ask all right hazel you can
you can unmute yourself hello
um so you mentioned that with the
https record that um
clients will no longer need to perform a
ttp
connection in order to find out whether
they can for example use quick or
something to the
specified endpoint information um
uh what how much mind has been paid to
considerations around
security if a client for example
receives an
https rr perhaps an additional section
um and it's not authenticated data
it's not sort of protected by dns sec
that's a great question the
specification
um does not rely on dns sec
so clients always treat https records
as untrusted potentially
adversarial information
any adversary who can inject these kinds
of records
also almost certainly as in our threat
model i
think certainly has the ability to deny
the client access
to the address records that they were
looking for
so uh essentially tonight we view denial
of service attacks as out of scope
our our adversary can always deny the
user access
but i guess i guess i was wondering
whether this made any difference to
cash poisoning and hack or something if
you were to set q type to https or
something or
and then or svcub or something and try
and basically get a
try and get a spoofed record in in an
intermediate in
a resolver sort of thing yeah so one of
the
so there are essentially two concerns
that i am
i'm aware of here one of them is denial
of service
the other one is breaking the
the sni privacy guarantees
around encrypted client hello so the
purpose of encrypted client hello
is to enable sni
privacy where the server name indication
in the tls handshake is not visible in
clear text
an adversary on the dns path here could
uh essentially deny the user access to
the encrypted client hello
public key or you can try to imagine
you know maybe synthesize and a
different
in uh substitute their own encrypted
client hello public key
and thus learn the the tls
sni value but that adversary already
knows the tls sni value
because it is the q name i mean assuming
it wasn't like
star.onmicrosoft.com or i mean i said
i suppose i suppose that depends on the
the threat model for the adversary if
the adversary is um
has received the the the question that
the original client
sent and they have the queue name but if
if in the cash poisoning attack where
they've just tried to convince
you know google public dns to serve
false
https records for start on microsoft.com
for example um
they might not know the uh the the full
queue name that i quit the client will
be asking for
if you see if you follow me i i think i
do that is an interesting
that is an interesting threat situation
um i have no idea how practical it is
but
yeah my my instinctual reaction here i
guess is that
um we just kind of have to accept that
that kind of vulnerability that we
essentially don't have another option
but um and of course we are describing a
very powerful adversary there
sorry to intervene i think there is a
more discussion to this uh maybe it's
worth taking offline
a couple of more people would like to
ask questions so for the sake of time
i would like to give other people a
chance to ask a question
thank you all right thank you
all right next up is paul
paul machine you can admit yourself
sorry i think it was an accident i
raised my hand
all right okay all right um i guess next
up
is wes
what um thank you um
excellent presentation by the way i
think that the you know the logical flow
and the needs were all really well
spelled out you did a great job you know
educating us on why this was needed um
you know the underbar history is kind of
interesting because we decided to stop
publishing
uh records at the apex of its own
because you know too much especially for
things like wild card and stuff like
that
but then you know now we have this https
record which gets an exception because
it needs wild cards
uh isn't this kind of setting a
precedence i mean should we
now allow everybody in other protocols
to to make use of
records at the apex because it's easier
for them as well or is https special for
some reason and what makes it unique if
that's the case
uh i think i'm missing something in your
in your discussion here uh where
what is the the rule that you're
thinking about i guess i'm not aware of
a restriction
we shouldn't put record types at the at
the end it's not a rule
it was a one of the reasons that the
underbar uh
you know protocol came around was
because
too many records were getting there with
spf and text and you know everything
else it got to be bulky
and uh you know we the the
ietf community sort of decided to push
back against let's stop pushing stuff
there let's put it
at lower levels using you know this
newer convention so that we stopped
putting stuff at the apex
what i worry about is you know a lot of
people will suddenly go well this is no
longer necessary we actually can do the
apex records because https has now
turned that around instead of precedence
back the other direction
that's interesting my sense of the
history there was a little different
and i guess my my feeling was that these
underscore records um sorry the
underscore prefixes
are particularly valuable where their
contents are
are parametric in some sense and
sort of unbounded so an example in the
case of service binding records is that
there's a port number actually also in
the https record there's an underscore
prefix port number
which obviously we can't encode
into a into an rr type we can't have an
rr type for every port number
so uh that's the case where underscore
prefixes are
are most easily motivated from my
perspective
i also have the impression that
there have been changes to the
to the rr type registration procedures
over the last 10 or so years that have
made it
easier to create new rr types and so
whereas underscore prefixes were a way
to
avoid the overhead of creating a new rr
type for new use cases
that overhead has has been substantially
decreased
in part to try to reduce the ever
growing uh abuse or or creative
use of txt records
all right folks i think there is also a
long um
quite a fair amount of time that could
be spent on that topic
um we're going to run out we're running
out of time for for the q a
so uh so let's move that offline um we
can use the um
the chat room in in mata most uh for now
it's
uh time for wild flavors from akamai to
tell us on the other side of the https
record as it's seen in production
all right live you can share your screen
i can
we can see a screen okay i'm going to
presentation mode so um
thanks ben for the very good
introduction of what https is that's
much better than what i could have given
um i'm going to just leave it at that
it's the best thing that's fly spread
because that's really what it is when
you come from
a dns or web perspective
and i'm not gonna i mean go over here
it is kind of like it was done before
with svc and
[Music]
we now have service binding so it is
seeing lots of traffic and
we have an implementation in our cache
of resolver and
we are getting data from isps around the
world
so we actually see what the implication
of of this is and
here this is a graph from one of our
isps
that shows the
jury load differentiated by uh
rr types and as you see most of the
stuff is a
then we have a bit more quad a and then
at the bottom here you see it's going up
from mid-september as you see here to a
significant portion of the traffic that
is now
hdps and that's really curiou volume
that doesn't tell you there was any
answering it's just
the client asked for https record and
when you
look around the world we see some
i mean stuff that makes sense
there's more apple in
sort of apec north america
less in europe and south america and as
apple is the only implementation
the curry loads are are different here
and this
is of course a graph that shows you when
there is a huge impact but
when did it actually start and to look
into that
we convert these to a log graph and then
it looks like this
as you see the first record we actually
received was on july 17
that we saw in asia back in europe
and then you see a couple of dates here
uh that's when apple
probably did the public beta that's
in august and then here is the release
of ios 14 and then it goes on for there
so
all of this is uh pretty much
expected so now we know that the volume
and
when it happened but did it go wrong
and the first question to ask is well
what signals wrong for dns because
i mean there are some error codes annex
domain not them
serve fail but out of these really
only surface has gone wrong and gone
wrong here is from sort of a client side
so this is the answer that the resolver
gives back to the client
and surf fail is a thing that you
normally don't want to give back
because uh surveil is something that
cannot be cached so
resolvers usually do go go a long way to
to
not answer surf fail but sometimes in
some cases they have to
and that means something has to go wrong
and
to show that something has go wrong with
https i sort of
compared the amount of stuff that has
gone wrong
to the overall amount of stuff for that
record type because
keep in mind the hd test volumes that at
the beginning were very low
so if we just had absolute values that
wouldn't make sense
but it uh to show you if something goes
wrong
we are comparing good to bad answers uh
in in the dns and the results are here
so as you see in the beginning stuff
went wrong and then it turned down
which meant probably uh people were
noticing stuff and fixing it
and then there's one spike here that is
the release the public their public
release when people said oh shoot
something's still wrong but it was
seemly fixed and after that
you see the impact
of that https record really is not high
it's lower than actually quad a in some
cases
and again we look into this regional
[Music]
similar there there seems to be some
more problems
initially in asia pacific and some
weird things in europe and the odd thing
is so
yesterday i thought well why not crunch
the latest data
uh from from january and add it to to
this graph
and i did this so cc uh
the year here is the start of the year
and then i saw this
unfortunately i didn't have the time to
look into it what went wrong there
but again it was it seems to be one
event
when maybe something came out and it
kind of dives down
quickly after that so
um now to how the how does this wrong
answers happen and the question we have
to ask us
is well what is the correct answer for
an authoritative server
if you have a new query type well
it's simple there are sort of three
options
and next domain if the label does not
exist so
and i i just made a a simple
so blog.dnsorg doesn't exist so it
doesn't exist in https
it doesn't exist as an a record and it
doesn't exist as a coordinate so
the answer is any domain period you give
an authority section so you have the
negative caching
no error and an empty or a c name in
case you are jcc names
only answer section and the case for dns
org
which doesn't have an https record well
you give there's no error
you have a question second you have an
authority section so that you know this
deep data is reported
but there's no answer so that means okay
of course the best is
well to answer with an https resource
record
and now we're going to look into will
how many people do this and what are the
results
so overall the whole world
uh on i mean this is one day
february one just day i choose but the
other days the earlier days and i looked
into
some days after uh second world yeah
also i mean it looks pretty similar so
we see 403 million unique sqdns
on that day so out of these 12 million
asked https resource records
and out of these two 12 million only 126
000 had actual https record
so out of the stuff that is asked about
a person
uh has hds records so really not that
much now
i want to do a quick shout out to uh
jeff and joe here because
one of the reasons we see so many uh
unique ftdns is that people are
trying to measure stuff with dns and
they are using
kind of uh unique
f to the ends for that and when i did
this research initially of course i
just kind of replayed a whole bunch of
of traffic to uh jeff and joao and
i then noted hmm didn't he talk about
that domain once ago and
i asked him well is that your domain so
i said yeah and then i kind of
extracted it the interesting thing is my
initial
uh use case was well i'm going to ignore
everything that only had a single query
because i mean that's just noise
oddly enough even in my traffic set a
lot of the stuff that
josh andrea did had multiple records so
someone was replaying them
to our servers somehow so but let's
look deeper into it what are the 126 000
records are
well bummer
there is zero resource record that uses
the august feature
and i was really shocked by that zero
nothing
nada and
i have no idea why but at the moment all
of them are using the
the kind of target record and all of
them
use kind of uh priority one there's only
one domain that uses more than one
resource record and uses multiple domain
and that's next dns.io what they are
doing i don't know but that was really
the only domain
out of these uh
126 912 have no aopn
that means they don't tell you that you
want to connect overh2 or h3
um and 67 are hdp only
now the problem i discovered and now i
mean i'm sort of dns guy so
https is not kind of my first thing so
when i did some testing for my own
benefit and set up some
https records i set up http servers
to see if they were kind of if the
red direction were coming directly and
oddly enough absentation meets them
and uh i then kind of
talked to the to some of those easy
options that well that's wrong
because they are supposed to have https
only so this is something that
is currently but i assume will go away
so keep that in mind and
the other thing that you see nearly all
of them have hints and uh
well uh 17 have ipv4 only hints which
i mean means they are pretty prevalent
in v6 because that's probably more than
we have
of e60 plan there was no use of other
keys no ach
no port no key whatever you can't
generate you have generic form like you
have for dns trackers use archetype
in service binding pyramids also but
none of that was used
really most of them were pretty much
alpn h2
and then a target or the dot as the
target of the domain name
as you see the apln distribution i mean
there are
three i mean h3 was with some flavors
and mostly also included h2 they were
really i mean the other two are
you don't see them here they were five
or seven or something like that
so really not that much
um so
now uh we go back to what can go wrong
so this now tells me well i
collected all these domains and uh
i wanted to see
where authoritative service are really
failing now keep in mind this is a
single kind of place where i
tested this from so the answers might be
different from other places
but i initially kind of out of the
12 million domains made a sample and i
said well
if you answer different for an a record
then for an https record so you don't
have a current answer
then this is wrong i mean if you answer
a server fail for a quad a and
uh https your host i don't care
and if you answer sort of any domain for
all of these i also don't care
i only care about domains where you
answered give a different answer for
a and quad a then for for https
and out of these other 12 million
domains
168 000 answers sometimes wrong now
sometimes
wrong i mean in the dns the
stuff fails so you always have a
serve fail rate in your server that
something goes wrong for some
reason and some that goes good again and
bad again
so i want to see well what is kind of
consistent
and to to do that i sort of tried them
to our resolver and actually
made a log of the whole recursion
process and out of these 160 hours
only four thousand six hundred fifty you
proved really wrong
so there's not that much wrong remains
and the answers that were
coming back sometimes were funny
although not funny well
so there were lots of
authoritative name servers that
answered for nothing but hey and quarter
and some have even some are even i mean
some give advanced respects for ns but
not for soda and there was one server
that i just kind of
tried well type 65 doesn't work well
what about
type 60 oh oh that does work type 61 oh
no 559 yeah so
all this stuff happens and
there's also uh sometimes when you
answer annex domain
for http but not for a and quad a this
is very bad
because if you have if you follow rfc
then this means well the a and quarter
records no longer exist
um there are and i guess others have it
also of course
stuff in the server that said well if
you answer ask for a i'll just gonna
make sure
maybe i'll ask again and see if my
record is there but
that is uh very common although not not
so common
as we sorry as the most common is
timeout
and then uh
the timeline doesn't matter if there's
an x domain at that at the real
a record like the a record or or at the
other is alex domain no arrow and the
oddest one is there's only one
i believe any domain and timeout so
these are the arrow conditions
so that brings me to the summary
so overall i believe the adoption of
https has been relatively smooth
they initially were problems which i
would expect anything
i mean they're currently uh is one
implementation and a limited feature set
usage
app on ios and macos but it is still
i think a success story i would say
and of course the devil is in the detail
and dns is hard
and to anybody out there who writes
authoritative servers
answering is always better than dropping
theory types other than a in qualities
are not attacks
they're regular query types and
answering annex domain when you just
don't have the data for the type is
wrong
and the last one i mean will sf cb ever
be used or are we gonna
will https take over the world and
that's it and
with that question
all right thank you ralph um a quick
reminder that
paul will show up to be able to rate the
talk
you can ask your question in the q a tab
and i will read them out or you can
raise your hand
we got a couple of questions in the q a
tab
so starting with peter alexis
the question is you said you have an
implementation does this mean
cash serve does the svcb https
additional lookup
absolutely so
the thing i mean again we're optimized
for speed so
we'll only give give we'll do the lookup
but if we don't have it
in the in the cache we'll just give back
the answer first and then the next
lookup comes we'll get back with the
answer in the cache yes
all right thank you next question hazel
smith
you mentioned that some were answering
nx domain for https and no error for a
quad a
were they knew where there were empty
non-terminal
meaning you name example.com returning
an x domain for q type https and
reasoning no error
with empty answer section for a or query
where record exists below that name
to be honest i haven't checked that
that might be well but yeah but
i haven't checked i'll i'll take a look
if i can get something out of the person
that i have
all right thank you and then we got a
couple of uh
ends up all right um
all of man you can uh mute yourself
hi this is paul hoffman from icann so
ralph thank you very much
um seeing real world stuff for
um rr types that actually haven't been
um you know that we don't have standards
for yet
um but but we feel like we know what
we're doing is really good
i am incredibly intrigued by
uh the thought that there are
authoritative servers out there giving
as you call them wrong answers um
and uh and i'm assuming like you did
that this is a wrong answer because it's
a new rr type
um separate from this
did did you start looking for patterns
like
was that all from one server farm
or did it seem things like that because
it seems
i'm hoping that it is one implementation
that we can then figure out which
implementation it is
and chase down the vendor as compared to
the uh authoritative server themselves
did you
did you run that down or were you mostly
focused on the good parts of this which
which was the https
well uh so
i have but i haven't i have the server
names
or that that are answering answering bad
but i didn't look at fpdns and then try
to figure out what
what kind of vendor that is
and i'm
i'm not sure maybe i can i'll have to
ask if i can share that data but
that might be something to
further investigate
all right thank you uh next up we got uh
ben
schwartz you can admit yourself then
hi uh so on slide 15
maybe that's the slide that everybody
was interested in
uh the
i wanted to clarify
are these only domains that do have a
and quad a records that is where you
didn't get a no data response
for a or quad a
so i guess but hey it'll ask i haven't
checked so
these were uh
um domains
that were asked but i didn't check if
they had a recording i only did the only
check i did
by to get into this pool is someone
asked for https
and the answer that i saw in our data
was
incoherent so it was either a survey or
or it didn't check and actually record
but that should be easy to check
okay um do you think that probably most
of them are not
no data i would think that most of them
are half a record or quarter record
but uh what was that just quickly
what what timeout or you know roughly
what timeout
were you using to declare timeout
we're using the standard cache of
timeout algorithm
and so the thing is that because
um keep in mind a server fail there
means
that cash surf has gone to all the
servers
because again i i did use a special
function in the server where you can
actually uh
trigger the recursion process and then
it will tell you what it does
exactly and it will try really to get an
answer
so having a circle there really means
there was no way to get knowledge so all
the servers were bad
thanks
all right thanks folks um i don't see
anybody else raising their hand or there
is no more question in the q a
so with that i would like to uh
thanks the farsight has been the
workshop sponsor
and we will now go for a 15 minutes
break we will resume the session at
utc sharp thanks have a refreshment and
see you in a bit
[Music]
do
welcome back everybody we're now ready
to go for the second part of this
session
um please make yours make yourself
comfortable
and now we're going to have luke
hendricks and willem turuk from nl net
lab tell us about the xd
pyramint tinkering with dns and xdp
look all yours we can see your slides
thanks
perfect you can hear me as well yes i
can
i guess we all can perfect uh thank you
manoo
um yes so i'm luke hendricks i'm with
nlnet labs
and wilhelm and i have been
experimenting uh with dns and xtp
and in the next 20 minutes would like to
present some of our findings there so um
why xdp i'm sure many of you have heard
about
these these new fancy technologies that
allow you to do a lot of stuff in your
data plane right programmable networks
programmable data planes stuff like p4
and also xtp
they offer flexibility without
sacrificing
performance and that sounds very nice so
we thought well let's see
how we can use xdp in a dns context
and a good thing about xdp is that the
only thing you need
in order to start using it is a recent
linux kernel
so that's an easy way to start out and
because you
run xtp in your linux kernel because xtp
is code you write yourself and you
run it in kernel space
so you can process incoming packets in
kernel space
because you run it there you can still
benefit from having
your user space after that so
what that means is you don't have to
write xtp code that replaces
everything you currently do in user
space so you don't have to write a
full-fledged
recursive resolver or authoritative name
server
but you can do some parts in kernel
space
and still have your user space after
that so you can augment what you already
have running
again if you have a recent linux kernel
you could actually check out the codes
that we haven't getting
and start using it right away
we have a couple of examples in that in
a github repository and in this
presentation
we'll start out with how we can do rrl
in xdp so response rate limiting i'm
sure i don't have to explain this to
most of you but
just over on the same page with rrl
you can set a certain threshold x and
whenever
the incoming rate of queries exceeds
x so the number of queries from a
certain source ip
you make a decision you either
set a dc bit to send it back or you drop
the packet right
um it's a
it's a thing we all know and maybe take
for granted
uh but when we look at the slides we can
see some of the requirements
that we need for this for this
mitigation technique
uh because if you look at queries per
second it means we need to keep state
to do this calculation right if we say
return truncated it means we do have to
alter the packet
before we send it back uh i will see
that we can actually
do all those things with xdp
so to explain the other abbreviations
before we can explain xcp we have to
explain bpf or ebpf
most of you will know bpf from your tcp
done filters it was the
simple vm that allowed you to write
those
filters um ebpf isn't
well they say it's the extended vpf but
it's it's slightly deceiving if you ask
me
because it can do far more than just
filter packets
with ebpf you can run your own code in
kernel space without
rebooting um nxtp
is a hook in your network driver so we
can run
this bpf code on every incoming packet
and the nice thing is again it happens
before you hit
the network stack so before a socket
buffer is allocated
hence performance and dns just dns well
initially i put this in there as a joker
just dns how hard can it be
but in this case as we are aiming at
augmenting what we already have this is
uh
you can interpret this in another way
we're not altering the protocol here
right um whatever is running a user
space
expects normal dns
and that is what we will do will not
alter
anything on that layer so
writing xdp code and running it in your
network driver
how do we decide what should happen to
the packet well that's all based on
return code so what do we return from
our little xtp program so for reference
your classic step
packet comes in at the neck fire the
driver it ends up
in your network stack and eventually via
a classic
e-net or internet 6 socket it ends up in
your application
now with http running in your driver
we can have a couple options here
we can return xdb tx which means
send it out of the nic this packet came
in for
we can also say xp drop which means well
no surprise there just drop the spec
and these are two quite simple things
but i hope you can imagine that this
already allows you to do a lot of a lot
of
heavy lifting processing
without even touching your use of space
right if you have to set the trunk in
bits well you can do this with the
with the xcbtx command for example we
don't need anything in user space
another one is xdp pass which means well
we have processes thing in xp
and we decide we still need something
higher up in the stack and use a space
so maybe we alter some things in the
packet but then we still pass it on
so it can end up in in this case at nsd
um there is another option which we'll
be not
using which is xp redirected send it out
of another nic and there is a special
case
where you can use that return code to
send the packet to a special socket type
but to use that socket type you will
need to alter
what is running in user space and you
might have seen this in a previous
org presentation
and not so one more time what we're
after is we're
trying to augment dns software um we're
not altering the software itself
we're adding functionality
just before a packet would traverse
upwards into the network stack we're not
changing running software in user space
we're not re-implementing
an entire resolver or name server in xdp
so how do you go about this your your
workflow so to say to get to a running
xtp program is you start out
writing c code and you compile this
with clang target bpf and um
then the fun starts because once you try
to load it this thing called
the verifier kicks in you're trying to
run arbitrary code in your kernel
and we of course cannot have any kernel
panics there right on every incoming
package well i
will only have it once i guess but um so
this verifier checks does your code
terminate is it not too complex those
kind of things and if it
has no objections it will load the code
on your interface and you're done it's
running
every incoming packet is now processed
by your code
normal probe no reboot you don't have to
reconfigure anything in user space
that's it that's that's how easy this
could be
um if you want to interact with that
running code you will need something
called bpflaps and we'll look into that
in a couple of slides so specifically
for response rate limiting
we're not going through every line of
codes that's on github
but the concepts that we need we need to
parse
uh the ethernet frame right that's
something that the
network stack would do for you but now
we have to do it ourselves so we have to
make sure
are we dealing with uh udp insight ip
inside ethernet and is it actually meant
to go to port 53
well okay this might be dns then check
if it's correctly formatted dns in there
and once we know that we have to do two
things
we trick the query rate because we want
to do response rate limiting and based
on that we either decide to
pass it upwards or maybe drop it or send
it drunk it bit and send it back
so bpf maps are specific data structures
that require specific helper functions
to read and write to them and if you
look in the header files there's
a couple of types that you can use we
are using a hashmap here
so that basically means that we keep
track
of the source of the addresses that we
see for the for the incoming queries
and we map those to what we call a
bucket and there we keep track of
a start time a a window
and the number of packets so we can
calculate the rate so with maps we can
have this
inter packet state and for those of you
who have worked with p4 keeping state
might be
quite cumbersome but with xcp it's
actually quite
doable another thing you can do with
maps
is this configuration from user space
for that we're using a different map
type here because what we want to do
in this example is exclude some prefixes
so perhaps you have paying customers
that you don't want to
subject to rate limiting you can store
those in a map
um find a prefix that's the
the key here in the type lpm3 longest
prefix in h3
and um as a value we keep a counter of
how often we have hit
these things now you have loaded your
code onto the interface so response rate
limiting is active there
and now you decide you want to add
something another prefix
you can do this you don't have to reboot
you don't have to recompile or
reconfigure
you can do this either using bpf tool
it's a generic tool to populate these
maps
or you can use your own custom user
space tool
and now that we know all this
i will hand it over to villain which
will actually demo this
to you that's right
i will stop sharing with him and then i
hope
i can start sharing my terminal
perfect so yeah so i started
a virtual machine
which is running a name server
let's set this address oh
let's see that's working
and suppose this machine is your name
server and it is being misused by
a amplification of reflection
amplification attack
and it has quite a bit of load
and you think well i saw this
presentation
at the dns org of luke willem
i would like to try this xdb
program to see if i can reduce the load
on my main server
by dealing with those packets
right after they arrive
and so i'm doing this completely
from scratch to illustrate
that you did not have to
anticipate doing this you know you you
install uh regardless of what have what
software you are winning or without even
anticipating that you ever wanted to do
this you can
start using xcp to deal with the denial
of search attack
so this gets repository we reference to
this
in a blog post that i will refer to
at the end of this presentation there's
a first blog post which
deals with answering dns packets from
xtp which
it has as the example dns says no
the second blog posts deals with
augmenting
existing dns server and it's
the rrl example but because
i will use
a user space program to
add prefixes that should not be subject
to response rate limiting i also have to
check out this sub module and compile
this
library which is not available in a
package unfortunately but we are doing
it from
scratch so this is part of it
then let's go to the response great
limiting example we actually
have three versions of response rate
limiting that we refer to
in our blog post but round
three is the fully fledged one that has
other features that you would normally
see in your regular dns software
so i will open the c file
and you can see the the parameters
you have to configure them here i have
to adapt the number of cpus
and this virtual machine has only one
the prefix length you can configure that
the size of the hash table
and how you want to respond
to the response very limiting and for
the demo sake i'm going to
respond with the tc bit for
every response very limited
answer and i will also downsize the
response rate limiting
to three queries per second
so let's make this now
i have to create the vip maps
the very important prefixes maps this is
the
way how we configure the prefixes that
will not be subject to response rate
limiting
now i can load the xdp program
it's actually reloaded
you can see the xdp generic
is on the interface
now let's do this query again that i
just did
and also i have to specify the ignore
flag so that
dick will not return over tcp when it
receives a packet
with the tc bit set
okay gentlemen sorry to interrupt there
are five minutes remaining before q
a yeah
so i sent a query twice a second
which should not be a problem because
we have set the response rate limiting
to three queries per second
so if i now
sleep a bit less we see that
a lot of responses now have the tc bit
set those will not have the address
returned and only three responses per
second
get answered so the user space program
is this one okay let me first check
and uh what my ip address is
okay this one
so i start the previous again
and then i use this tool to add this
prefix
and you see that now all the
responses are returned without the
truncated bit
okay it's the demo
now i'm going to share another screen
so what have we learned we
can leverage xtp to
[Music]
augment dns services you know
regardless of the software that was
running the servers to deal with
incoming packets so stuff like
control access control or dealing with
the
search attacks you can decide to deploy
it at any time
you did not have to anticipate it
beforehand
bpf maps can be used to maintain some
internal state like for
weight calculations but can also be used
to communicate
and configure the module from a new
space at runtime
so we've been adding prefixes of
well-known customers that should not be
subject to response rate limiting
manually
but there's also a mechanism to do this
automatically
within the dns protocol and this is
called dns cookies
so dns cookies work together if you have
a valid cookie
you're not subject to response very
limiting so if you do response rate
limiting in xdp
you also have to do cookies in xtp
and this is perfectly possible there's
actually a mechanism
in xdp to chain existing
xtp programs so we can
we have we will be writing about this in
the next blog post how to verify cookies
and if they are filled past the packet
on
to the dns service
and if not send it to the response
weight limiting program but that's just
for verification
you can also with bpf
[Music]
do the creation of dns cookies so
change or respond on incoming packets
and change outgoing packets by running
two
vpf programs one on the tc layer and
one on the xp layer but we will also
talk about this in the
blog post so a lot is possible
xdp and ebpf are a very good fit for
plain old
up-based dns less suitable for tcp
based dns and probably impossible for
tottenham
and we think using xtp to augment
an existing dns service is an exciting
new ide
and a great new tool in the dns operates
toolbox
we have lots of new ids or ids for
to do with xtp and dns to
have more tools in this toolbox
example examples of some of those ids
and i think it's now five minutes
uh until for you to ask questions
yeah thank you thank you william and
thank you luke um
yeah this is the time now to for people
to be able to
uh um answer the poll and also
ask the question through the q a tab or
raise the end
for lack of question at the moment i had
one actually so i think
i'm pretty lucky where i work at where a
lot of the heavy lifting has been done
but if any resources or any pro tips
that you will recommend for people that
start playing around with xdp
that you you actually don't need that
many tools
if you it's just a clan compiler and
ipv2
and ppf2 which already
gets you quite far
all right yeah i think i was also maybe
referring about certain resources
documentation that helps you bootstrap
to you to distract you
okay yeah
[Music]
well you could have a look at our blog
posts of course
and also there's xdp tutorial
which we have been using quite a bit to
get started with this stuff
cool um all right we got a couple of
questions coming up so
let's let's wish you that uh jess uh
jeff westhead as a question which is
could you talk about performance a bit
how many pps can this drop and keep the
server
the server live for unfiltered sources
how many qps can it drop so
i don't know so we will uh start
experimenting with hardware of loading
of xcp programs and then
it is supposed to be line speed but it
will
at least i can tell you for sure that it
will be
faster than when running from a
userspace
dns service
yeah i will add to that um as you said
in the hardware mode essentially
all the processing will be done without
even touching the kernel
right so yeah you can you can get line
right
yeah uh next question which is more
of a comment from wiki vicky risk
i don't have a question but i love this
and i want to give willem an award for
his live demo
thank you yeah also i want
also to mention that we have this xdp
and bpf uh channel created in the
matter most so it might be uh
interesting for people
if they have suggestions or ideas to
post it
in the channel yeah good idea
all right we got a last question
um that's um peter alexis is going to
ask peter you can mute yourself
all right so it's actually not another
question but a comment so
we have ebpf and dns dist as well
and we have indeed seen that if you put
bpf in the kernel you can just drop
packets at line rate
which is amazing so this is definitely
faster than just doing it in the
user space
all right perfect thanks uh
luke and william and uh and uh people
for asking questions uh
we are right on time to go on for the um
for the next uh talk let me
[Music]
all right so next up is going to be
robert mortimer that is going to
talk about the state of uh dns security
record
roberts
and we've currently stopped my video so
that might be interesting
all right yeah we don't see it at the
moment um
matt maybe oh
we can see it now
cool perfect
so yeah i'm walking with nominee i'm
going to talk about the state of dns
security records
um thank you
and we can see you we can hear you
brilliant
um so this started as a personal project
a few years back when i was deploying
spf and dmarc
records and thought it'd be fun to start
checking
what the vendors i was dealing with were
doing so
being lazy i wrote a tool to
just look things up at random as i was
being curious
and having listened at all i started
checking more records
checking the things that i recommended
best practice by the likes of ncsc
to see what was out there and of course
once you've got a tool and a set of
record types to check the obvious thing
to do
is start recording the data and make a
graph
and see how things change over time um
so the first time i did that was back in
but the problem was what was your data
source i started with
the alexa top 100 the list of icon
accredited registrars
the top 100 registrars there's a public
list of security 500 vendors
which were all good public sources and
they had a bunch of stuff
that i was using so my vendors dns
providers
anything else i thought was interesting
but
that's not ideal i didn't want to use
private data
and there's not that much good
publicness out there
so i dumped the vendors and dns
providers
and discovered tranco which is a great
list for
this sort of research started looking at
the oh providers
because they're interesting and as i'd
automated this
i then started checking all of the
infrastructure domains for those lists
so
anything providing mx services dns
services
anything like that so starting to be
a decent list and all stuff that
people can use i'm probably next year
going to
drop alexa because it's just too painful
to scrape
and tranco's a lot easier but i kept it
in for the moment for
consistency so
what was the method i did a lot of dns
records
lookups um really simple big list of
domains
look up all of the records and shove
them into a log file
that i can then pass and see how
those records compared to the best
practice document
was the caa and spf and so forth
deakin records were tricky because i
didn't know
what the identifier was
but a lot of the time if there wasn't a
wild card record
you can infer if the deacon records
there
based on whether you get a no error or
an nx domain
it's not perfect but it seems to
validate reasonably
and it's the best option i've got um
ideally i want to check registry
settings see if the
registrar lock to a registry not but who
is api access cost money
and this was a personal project
so that's the background
this is what the results look like and
apart from spf
really very few of these record types
are wildly are widely deployed in the
wild
and it's been getting somewhat worse
but that might be due to my sampling
which has obviously changed over the
years
and the number of icann registrars from
my list for instance
collapsed massively between 2017
and 2019 um not sure why
but it changes the sample size well
as you can see apart from dmarc
everything
in terms of deployment has gone downhill
um and
not most of these aren't new apart from
caa which we can let off
um these stats compare reasonably well
with a similar report that csc do on the
forbes 2000
and the dns sec is similar to what stats
dns.com are reporting um
across all the tlds so i've got some
confidence in this
um obviously a bigger data set would be
better
but
so to look at how it breaks down i'm
sorry this graph is
tiny but this is the various
lists i was looking at so alexa
doh i can top 100 registers
and so forth um
isn't security related but it's just
interesting
um most commonly
used amongst the oh providers which
isn't surprising that tends to be people
that are looking at
doing some quite cool stuff they're also
way ahead
in terms of dns sec which is good given
the service
they're providing and likewise the cia
uptake in doh
is really quite reassuring though very
low
given it's a https dependent service
and very new i'd hope that would be
better
um mail stuff is quite healthy
but for most of
the icann and the registrars it's oddly
low
given that so many dns services are
modified and managed via email
confirmations
you know you transfer domain it's an
email and
most of those haven't got spf haven't
got dkim haven't got dmarc
which is i think a big
a big gap in that security model um
it worries me
um but some new stuff and this i think
ben and ralph may find interesting um
https svcb this year
has got more uptake than dane
even though dane's been around for quite
a bit longer
um this from what i looked up seemed to
be mainly due to cloudflare
um most of the people with these record
published
were on cal flair um playing remains
reasonably painful to apply especially
if you're doing rapid
certificate cycling such as via let's
encrypt um
and in slightly pressing news a couple
of icann
registrars and one of the alexa top 50
has an apex c name record even though as
we heard earlier
that doesn't work
um this does indicate to me at least
that the uptake of this sort of security
record
is really very dependent upon vendor
support and that
domain registrars can have a huge impact
in the uptake by just changing default
behavior
so a few conclusions
you as you probably gathered i think
yeah uptake's poor
and i think this is partly because
there's not many best practices
documents
and there aren't many tools to make it
easy to be um to adopt these records
there aren't many cheap dqm reporting
services
um changing the default contents of his
own when you register a domain
if that was dns second enabled by
default negative spf
and that sort of thing will make a huge
difference
um so there's a lot as registrars
can be done and there needs to be more
research
my personal project's okay but it'd be
really nice
if um there are other people looking at
this
and people who've got data sets that are
large and apparently a lot of the cases
obviously they can't make them public
having something like this um to improve
the coverage
um people reassure me dns sec
about to take off and a lot of these
things will improve next year
but having heard that for many years
about ipv6
i'm not holding my breath
[Music]
so a very quick sort of overview
of where we are with a lot of these dns
set records i forgot to create any
question slide
so any questions
thank you robert um there is no question
from the room yet at this moment um i
have
one uh when you look at the
top 50 or so um
are over time are they the same like the
one in 2017 2019
so when we see regression in in terms of
uh of adoption is this
from the same set of domains or the the
top 50s are just different over
here so the very top part of the top 50
tends to be static
as you go further down there's more
change and i did think about that
i do have all of the data sets going
back year on year
so i can do a direct comparison but
some of those cease to exist and
in terms of impact for
the internet you know if something's
just become irrelevant
it's great to have adopted something but
it doesn't have
that much impact um so looking long-term
i thought it more useful to keep
what's the top 50 doing rather than a
specific set
of domains
cool thanks i i guess i forgot to say
something quickly before asking the
question
uh was that there were going to be the
poll and you can raise your hand or ask
the question
on the q a tab um i see through all the
mechanisms
that eric wants to raise his hand
let me reckon try
can you mute yourself yes
thank you i uh raising my hand
seems to be much harder than that yeah
thank you
a great presentation and we actually do
this
kind of measurement for dot s e zone
and uh there's a lot of there's
a few other zones that are actually
public that you could do this
measurement on for you know
larger data set and i know that there is
a
group there was a presentation at the
last imc
about this the group at the university
of grenoble said
that does this and i would really like
to work with you on this
on the data sets because i think that is
uh really interesting and
it could help us to improve security in
the dns a lot
that would be brilliant if anybody wants
to reach out to me
to share data sets and make this a wide
arranging survey
or see what i've been doing in more
detail be really interested to do that
because i think the bigger coverage we
get the better the data is the more
useful it will be
oh sorry i'm muting myself um so
sebastian you you can you cannot mute
yourself now
sebastian did you have a question
alright sebastian questro
all right i suppose this was not italian
then
okay um there is no more question in the
queue
so i guess we
are going to move on to a
question from pallavi
another angle to this research could be
to see data to determine
how many queries are made for dmarc dkm
spf by email provider and get the next
domain
so could you repeat that another angle
to this research could be to see data to
determine
how many queries are made for dmarc
dkm or spf by email providers and get a
next domain
yeah um certainly and again if anyone's
got such a data set that they can share
or want to see what i'm doing type their
own data set that would be great
i don't have access to such a data set
all right um sebastian is having um
issue with his mic
so i guess can you
i can hear you now okay perfect um
excellent uh hi robert and
wolverine and everyone um
so all right what's uh i think was
talking about the opening dell data set
from the dutch
uh i'll also like to point out we we're
doing this for the dot and said zone so
we have
statistics for the mark and caa and spf
and we have an open data set available
if you want to go and and check sort of
the adoption numbers in
dorian said if you want to compare for a
future
uh presentation robot just in case
you are interested exactly
all right cool well we are getting close
to um to the end of the q a
time period so i guess without further
ado we're going to
move on to our next talk and last talk
of the session
which is uh paul offman is going to talk
about
a not so popular way of sampling domain
names
paul hi it's all yours
let me do this screen sharing
and
[Music]
i hate this part of trying to find the
right one
um we go
and put it at the bottom of the list
all right we can see a screen now okay
um let me just get rid of that okay so
uh thank you robert because you were
talking about um
data sets and we are about to talk about
another data set
um robert mostly covered like as you
said you know alexa's a problem and
stuff
and he was uh covering popular ones this
is a talk
about a data set that are not so popular
so oops and why
excuse me
there we go so my motivation for
creating this data set
was that you know like in robert's case
and in
other cases like sebastian had brought
up you want to know something about the
authoritative servers are they doing
certain things
you know do they have certain records
and such like that
so you know the internet has become the
web
the web plus dns of course um but
because the internet has become the web
you want most people are looking for
names of web servers
um that's not always the case because in
fact there's not really a good reason
for example to have a dmarc record
for a name that is only a web server you
don't need a dmarc record for
www.example.com
um but if what you're trying to do is
collect domain names for web servers
that's pretty easy
that's the way we do a lot of research
that's how robert is
and a lot of people um
one of the problems that we always have
though is that when people
read our research is they expect this to
be true what we're saying is to be true
for typical domain names um
and the way that we often are doing it
like what robert did was the most
popular websites plus a couple of others
that he found
or extracts from zone files for gtlds or
as sebastian brought up or for even for
cctlds i'm sorry
and ulrich did as well so um
these are not typical though because for
example these zone files are full
of records that have are just used for
parking that they aren't actually active
um and the most popular websites well
there's a zillion
websites that we care about that aren't
popular that would be more typical
um and the other way that people have
done some of this is to get dumps from
passive dns
uh collection systems but those are sort
of difficult to use as well because
they're very geographically based even
if it's a wide spread
of uh passive dns collectors it still
has large pockets of geography in it
so my um
my motivation here was in fact let's
look for something
let's look for a base that would have um
a lot of urls in it that aren't so
popular
and it turns out that wikipedia pages uh
for those of you who
spend your evenings or even an
occasional evening trolling through
wikipedia
you can see that that as you go down the
wikipedia rabbit hole you can end up on
a page
that lists all of the governments of the
small cities
in a particular region so that's a
zillion websites that you probably
would not see in any of the previous
that we listed
colleges and universities all have a
website that generally has been
you know put on some wikipedia page
somewhere uh obscure sports teams um
for me every sports team is obscure but
um
things like this uh music and movie
studios
uh personal sites for academics you know
that have their own name in them such
like that
so wikipedia is a wonderful source of
this
the other nice thing is that wikipedia
has worldwide coverage
there are wikipedias in basically all of
the languages of the world
the languages often map onto geographies
but onto wide geography so for example
the english wikipedia which many people
use
covers much more than just the united
states and britain
um the spanish wikipedia covers much
more than just spain
and some of the other countries so
wikipedia is
wonderful for this that if you look at
across
all of the wikipedias you get pretty
much worldwide coverage
so here's how i did it i retrieved the
uh
i'm sorry i didn't mention one thing
wikipedia
actually makes it easy you don't have to
scrape wikipedia pages
they have a site for backing up
wikipedia
and that's not just all of the pages
they actually extract
some things and one of those is all of
these external links
so there's a database for external links
for each language
on the mirror of the main wikipedia site
so i grab all of those
i go through those it's a mysql dump
which is painful to work with but oh
well
um i extract all of the external links
i clean up the list of the links and
limit them to http and https
as it turns out that's like 98 of the
links on wikipedia pages
but you find gopher urls you
find um other things uh
so i i pulled out those and then so for
each of those remaining urls i stripped
off the scheme
because i don't really care for what i'm
doing whether it whether
that link started with http or https and
i strip off everything after the domain
name
um because i'm not looking at these as
urls i'm looking at them for domain name
this is dns or um
and of course there's a lot of
repetition there um that's fine
i i you know just ran it through unique
and then so here's the data set that i
ended up with so there were about 750
databases
that i use from january 1st this year
they update these twice a month
um but so about 750 wikipedia languages
so after doing the calling that i
described there
um about 7.35 million unique
domain names pretty good it's a large
set
um if you look through them they look
pretty legit
you know like i say there's a lot of
things that you sort of recognize as
that's an obscure university in a
country that i will probably never visit
and such like that
um i didn't do my analysis on all 7.35
million because doing some
you know doing queries for 7.35 million
things won't tell you much more than
doing a sample of a hundred thousand
so i just took a sample of a hundred
thousand um
i actually had to start with more than a
hundred thousand because it turns out
wikipedia doesn't clean up its
uh data that much which is fine i mean
it's a wonderful thing
not dumping on them at all so i started
with 150
000 and figured out which of those
actually had ipv4 addresses
so um this is my last slide um
of those just and going back to like
robert's thing
about 17 of those names also had ipv6
addresses which sort of matched
visually what robert did on his slide um
and also sort of that seems what we're
doing
of these only four percent had uh
we're not where dns sex signed um
so for the people who are saying oh yes
this is the year of dns sec
um dnsec is well behind ipv6
um interestingly robert also talked
about
uh also talked about the tranco data set
which is
is a collection of the most popular ones
i took tranco i did the same thing
mostly to compare
you know what are these the not so
popular websites with most popular
and the number was for v6 was almost
identical at 17
interestingly looking at the most
popular data sets at a sample of them
only two percent were signed with dns
sec
which makes a little bit of sense that
um
those most popular sites probably are
are more heavily managed and those
people have done the risk analysis
um but yeah so even even among that eve
you know looking at most popular versus
this set you see some interesting
differences
um the main reason i actually started
this research was some of you who are on
the deprived working group remember from
the interim
in november i think it was in november
maybe december
where we're talking about um doing
opportunistic
uh recursive to authoritative and people
said well if you're going to be probing
it would be good to know how long tls
startup happens
so that's really why i did this um
anyways
all of this will be in a document that's
coming out um in the future
here it says hopefully within a few
months it's actually moving ahead a
little bit better than i thought
maybe by the end of this month we'll
have it that has much more detail since
i only had 10 minutes to give this
ann talks more about the tranca and it
also talks about
um why even though this
is much more typical than the databases
we have
major faults in it and so for example
even though wikipedia has many of those
things that i listed before
it doesn't have local restaurants local
hardware stores things like that
which we know have websites we care
about that
but we don't have a way of necessarily
getting those into the big thing
so um that's it and um i think i hit the
right time
uh definitely up for questions if you
have them
yeah thanks paul um so again please use
the
qna tab or raise your end to ask
questions and now you're going to have
the poll popping up pretty soon um which
will be your chance to rate the talk
uh we have a couple of questions um
in the q a tab so i'm going to start
with the first one
question from giovanni mora paul during
your filtering you considered only
second level domain
or fqdns also no fully fqfqdns which was
interesting
when i had to compare it to tranco
because tranco actually strips off www
so i i did some changing on that when i
did that analysis
but no one of the things that we've
discovered when you look at less popular
data sets is there's often a third and a
fourth level
like at a college you know
department.college.edu.com
thank you next up um question from
thomas
kriesek is the domain list you extracted
available
anywhere or perhaps the script that were
used for processing the raw wikipedia
data
if you want to read my ugly uh python
code i'm happy to send that to you but
uh
pretty much it's not that interesting it
does prove the five steps that i gave on
the slide but yeah i could share that
um i'd rather not share the database for
two reasons one
is wikipedia has
a very easy to use license and so i
think people should be doing their own
and also it's for january it will change
over time and such like that
it was pretty easy to run i think it
took a few hours and i wasn't even using
very big vms for it and stuff like that
so i'm happy to share my code but i
haven't made it
that palatable yet i guess i should add
comments and stuff like that
let me know just let me know offline and
i'd be i can send it to you it's a
couple scripts
cool next up wes is going to ask
his question you cannot mute yourself
yes please yeah thanks
hey paul i i love the idea of of doing
that kind of search one of the things
that i've been
looking at is is splitting things across
the public suffix list break points to
see what the
you know number of prefixes are compared
to the
base registered domain did you try doing
that at all to see if there's much
variation
in you know prefix use i did not
um mostly because the measurements that
i was getting were mostly about
what are typical servers not where do
they
live in the hierarchy
so there are plenty of other research
questions such as
ignoring.com and net for example so
of the dot org names that i have how
does that map to the dot org zone file
like like which might tell us things
like how many things in the dot org
zone file really are just part so
there's plenty we can do i
haven't looked this was really again my
motivation was for deprived
and then but while i was doing it i
could figure out about the easy
questions of
v6 and dns second option
all right thank you there is a few
comments on the q a tab that i'm going
to uh to read through so azel smith says
i2 will be interested in the code read
domains uh regarding domains you'll even
have five level ones like w.cs.le.ac.uk
giovanni maria says it would be nice to
compare wikipedia versus cisco's
umbrella which is also fpgn based
and cisco i'm sorry cisco's uh giovanni
cisco's umbrella i thought was actually
uh taken from a re you know a set of
resolvers is that
which would be a very different sort of
thing
joanie do you want to uh maybe answer
verbally or i could be on
misunderstanding their database
oh we say it's true okay so yeah so
that might be an interesting thing to do
is to compare
um things that one fine you know a
database that one finds by
looking at the web versus a database
that one finds by looking at resolvers
all right and um final comment from azo
smith
oh let me know if you would be
interested in making this work with
postgresql you mentioned this other word
due to my sequel i sent you pm on madame
most about that
i guess we are right on time um
so let me wrap up here i would like to
uh thanks
all the speakers and all the uh
people attending and asking questions on
behalf of the program committee and work
and for now i'm going to end it over to
keith that is going to wrap up the
session
okay thank you mano appreciate um you
cheering things this morning i think
that that meant
really very well um so just a few wrap
up things we're very nearly at the end
of work 34 another one under the belt
um i want to remind all your work
members that we are doing a member-only
session
in half an hour um if you register for
work 34 or
you um explicitly requested it as a
member then you should have received an
additional private zoom
invite um we had a few people who went
of these went into the spam folder so
please check that you've got that
and you know so much for zoom's email
reputation please check
um that you uh you got it or or shout
out as much as soon as possible
um and that will start at um 1830 utc
for half an hour with
giovanni from sid and presenting some
vulnerability
information we will be switching the
remote participation on mattermost from
the you're currently in the in doing
that in the workshops channel in the
community group we will be switching to
the town square channel in the members
group so if you could please make that
switch when you um switch your zoom as
well
and a reminder to you all that you know
where or creates a trusted community
that's because all of your member
organizations signed the participation
agreement
this presentation is regarded as
confidential information so there are
restrictions attached to the
redistribution of that as part of
responsible security vulnerability
disclosure
um looks like the zoom post office
worked well so thank you all for for
giving us feedback on
on that um you know that we will crunch
that data and send it back to the
program committee to guide the selection
for future workshops
um generally event feedback is welcome
including feedback on the feedback
mechanism
um there's the uh the url bit ly slash
or 34-survey
so again we'd like to hear your your
thoughts on meeting logistics and
anything that worked or didn't work for
or suggestions um quick reminder of the
next workshops
work 35 will be the same format as this
one we're going for the 6th and 7th of
may
uh one and a half to two days long
depending on how much content we got
um we got a good pile of content this
time around
and the cfp for orc35 is now open so
please go ahead and
and submit
oh i'm sorry i failed to share my screen
friday afternoons
okay can people see my screen now
yes we can okay i apologize for that
there's always something i'll just
recap the um the relevant slides
okay so i was talking about work 35 um
that will be in may the cfp is now open
there's the url for the
event on indico program committee would
love to have your submissions
we will not be doing any physical
workshops during january
september this year um we will
um have some provisional plans for the
final quarter of the year
um which may include a short online
event
and hybrid and or physical events
depending on
on how the pandemic situation pans out
so um the final thing is just to thank
everybody um special thank you to
farsight security for sponsoring the
event
and to all the network members and
supporters who actively support and and
engage us
um to all the bodies that have awarded
us grant funding over the past year that
again that that's really helped as
operating the program committee
including all our new program committees
and new program committee chair
um i think you'll agree have done a
great job this time around
all of our speakers um and
um please consider supporting our online
events via sponsorship or
patronage for the year or you know we
will happily accept donations
so um that basically you know a big
thank you we can we can all do a round
of applause but nobody will hear because
it's
it's because it's so but then thank you
to everybody who makes this possible
and especially to the award team that
indonesia were too especially hard for
this event
um that is all i have to say for now um
see you either in hafener if you
remember or at
35 and me if you're not and if you're
not and you want to become a member
please
please speak to sue i'll be happy to
sign you up
okay thank you
you