ladies and gentlemen please join me and
welcoming the co-founder of trusted
security the co-founder of binary
defense and the co-founder of Derby con
mr. Dave Kennedy
nobody hear me okay good great well
thank you everybody for for besets
Augusta coming up super early in the
morning I got an email last night saying
hey can you be here by 8:00 a.m. I'm
like oh man like I like to sleep in and
all that good stuff so I see people
drinking coffee and everything else I'm
two coffee cups in so I should be okay
for the rest of the presentation after
that I plan on sleeping but I really
appreciate everybody coming out today to
hear me talk and I really like this talk
because it's it's talking about a lot of
things that we struggle with today and
I'm gonna dive down into a lot of the
different types of technologies that are
out there that stop attackers and really
how effective they are and what they do
but really today's talk is is looking at
how do we get better with with
identifying attacks and in the earlier
stages and there's a lot of Technology
out there like artificial intelligence
and machine learning that we hear out
there today that tell us a lot of
success rates when it comes to what's
actually happening out there so I wanted
to dive down into some of those
technologies and take a look at how
affect that they are what they really do
and really we can do to get a little bit
better with with what we're doing but
first I'm gonna says give a round
applause again for everybody that makes
besides Augusta possible
it's amazing what they're able to do
after using the funds to fund stem and
be able to help kids learn and get more
folks into technology in general and
that's so so so important with what
we're dealing with in the shortage that
we have in information security just a
brief background of myself as I got
introduced earlier a co-founder of Derby
con started trusted second binary
offense I'm the author of the social
engineer toolkit unicorn artillery
number of other open source frameworks
the pentesters framework like writing
code when I when I have spare time so
it's been been a lot of fun on the
information security space funny enough
I was doing a presentation in Chile for
four is C squared and and I started
playing a lot of my videos like it was
more of a higher-level talk and I
started playing all my videos and I
realized that every video that I'm in I
had the same suit on because I only own
one suit and and so like everyone that I
was in I was like oh no I need to change
that how cuz like I don't like suicide
just like you know when I fly and I'm
like a sweats type of person and you
know I'm that type of person and
suddenly really own one soon I really
like that tie
but even big day when I was heavyset had
the same tie that was interesting also
I've been in a rap video I thought that
was pretty cool as well in a Chris Brown
rap video which never thought I'd be in
a rap video before more of like a 90s
grunge alternative but it's all cool
like it was kind of neat I flew out to
LA and they wanted to do like a real
live skit on a hacking video and so I'm
like okay so I created a head an Android
device and the whole purpose of the the
video was basically Chris Brown and
another rapper Zoe dollars wanted to
hack into their their ex-girlfriends
phone and delete all the pictures of
them it's called post and delete it's
not safe for work by the way so don't
watch it when you're at work and so the
whole premise was is that you know they
wanted to lead all the Facebook posts
and things of them together so they
hired their best friend hacker Dave to
come in and so I actually created all
the the code in the background and you
stage-fright to trigger an exploit on
the Android device and then delete all
the phone delete all the stuff of its
they really wanted like an acro
portrayal that's been really cool steam
thing for like for mr. Roboto I've
gotten helped out a little bit with that
TV
Joe and a few other things so it's been
really neat to do a lot of the cool
stuff out there and and being a rap
video which is like I said the only
prerequisite of me helping out the rap
video is is I have to be in the rap
video and I like will figure that out so
that's me for like a half a second in a
background like bobbing my head as I'm
hacking into computer systems as people
are dancing behind me but it was really
weird it's awkward like it's like
picture of me on a computer and there's
like 15 dancers behind me like doing
flips and stuff and I'm like literally
just typing on a keyboard it was the
weirdest thing ever but it's fun that's
fun so a balance to the force the reason
why I started this that this talk is we
have a lot of problems when it comes to
being able to respond effectively to
specific threats against our
organization and the reason I bring this
up is that protection versus detection
protection and most organizations takes
a long time doesn't it
to implement application whitelisting is
anybody successfully implemented an
application whitelisting and high
integrity mode with very little
exceptions right right has anybody
gotten rid of macros so there might be a
couple in here anybody got rid of macros
in their environment nope not one right
so we have a lot of things that it takes
us time to get towards to really build
out our infrastructure network
segmentation do we do network
segmentation extremely well do we do DLP
very well all of these programs that
take a lot of effort in time for us to
implement and we're always striving to
get better at it right it's so
protection is something that takes a
long time right a good example let's
just say a new attack vector comes out
today and you can fix it with a registry
key change can you make a registry key
change across your entire enterprise
within the first day comes out maybe
maybe not depending on its impact
testing everything else that's happening
out there without a patch you get that
patch out the same day across your
entire enterprise probably not right so
we have a little bit of work to do when
it comes to the time it takes for an
attack to come out to when we can
actually protect against that and the
same thing goes for our strategic type
of protections right network access
control or network segmentation or DLP
or application whitelisting
or rolling out an old antivirus with the
new antivirus right that takes a lot of
time for us to go and effectively do
so what we try to do in the security
industry now is augment that protection
piece with the ability to to have
detection in place so that we can
minimize the damage to our organization
and hopefully respond we don't care
robbing sales gets compromised I mean we
do but we don't really care right it's
better than our entire IT infrastructure
being owned and then having access to
all the data so can we minimize the time
it takes to detect those attacks and
then respond effectively and so for us
the major concern right now is
protection equals timing and in most
enterprises it takes a substantial
amount of time we're not Andamanese this
word sorry but we're not agile the same
way we do in development to be able to
implement sweeping changes across your
enterprise to be able to do things and
so then we focused on the tactics
techniques and procedures of attackers
and that's the big buzzword right now
right TTP's TTP HTTP so here at about
400 times in this talk and I'm doing it
intentionally the tactics techniques and
procedures of attackers are what
attackers leverage in order to
compromise an organization or and the
methods that they used to do it and the
ways that they operate so everything
from standing up or operational
infrastructure or using a high
reputation sites using domain fronting
doing a specific type of code injection
attack to get code execution on the
system these are the methods that
attackers operate by in order to
compromise their infrastructure and the
big big thing that's focus focusing on
right now are what are the techniques
that attackers use that we can build
detection criteria off of it ie the
mitre attack framework and a lot of
other things that we see out there today
right so trying to get an understanding
around what attackers are doing so we
can build defenses against it now I
thought a really good comment from Jeff
Moss at the opening comments around
blackhat with hit home with me which was
we as an industry don't focus on the
tactics or the procedures of attackers
were only seldomly focusing or only
focusing on the techniques and that's
really where the industry is at today
we're focusing very very myopically
on the techniques in an attacker uses
what's the command that they use for
wmic
what does MSHDA look like when it's
beaconing out to the Internet let's
focus on the technique and let's build
detection criteria off of it and we
don't necessarily focus on what the
patterns of behavior look like or the
procedures that attackers use in order
to compromise an infrastructure so today
what we're really looking at is that
we're using signature based detection on
techniques so we're basically the
antivirus of the 90s and that's where
our security programs are today
so we're essentially writing signatures
for commands that look malicious but if
we modify them in some way shape or form
or we use a method that hasn't been
discovered we're fine
no problems as an attack goes so we're
still really back in the 90s which is a
good year at good years I love the 90s
is my favorite time got arcade games
Super Nintendo and he had 90s grunge you
know I was friends came out the 90s
right friends was a good show Seinfeld
nineties are the best so we can learn a
lot from from the techniques of attacks
we can say okay well if we trigger a
specific type of attack vector can we
detect it great that's fantastic now you
have maybe 50% of the coverage out there
but do you really know how effective
those detection criterias are unless
you're doing something like simulations
like red teaming or very specific
attacks that are very applicable and
practical to your environment as you're
actively going in and testing them and
so the current state of detection and I
love this an example I wrote I wrote
this tool in 2012 so six years ago right
six years ago I wrote a binary dropper
so it's a binary non code signed
executable and it was just a basic
native HTTP shell and it incorporated
AES for the command control so basically
you know you you you trigger an
executable on a machine it beacons out
via HTTP or HTTPS to the epoch attacker
sites and then it communicates with
command controls like a basically
command Sheldrake do IP config you do
things like that but it leveraged it
over AES so I released a source code and
I published the binaries okay and since
I since 2012 I've had 3.4 million
downloads of this specific binary okay
so really good download rate I would say
all right 3.4 million seems pretty
pretty sweet and so I decided to upload
it to virustotal to see how well it was
detected on code signed binary out in
the wild public code six out of six out
of sixty found it and guess how many of
those were by the way were the next
generation product lines zero zero zero
zero point zero like McAfee found it I
think claim maybe did which I was really
surprised that I didn't know that was
still around I was like shoot claim he
found it whoa semantic a couple other
ones great but six out of sixty found
enough funny enough I tweeted this out
and guess somebody found it after that
37 out of 60
magic right it's amazing what you can do
by a tweets that's exactly what
attackers are doing by the way when they
when they write some custom code that
isn't getting getting detected they
tweet it out to all the antivirus
vendors as a challenge that's exactly
what they do
shrubs see - I wrote Trevor see - which
was a command control structure for
basically it's it you can use it you can
bet it in documents from macro injection
you could use it as a PowerShell stager
I also has a c-sharp stager and what
Trevor c2 is and you can go and download
today is it's a command and control
infrastructure and exploitation
framework for command and control and
basically with Trevor c2 what it does is
it beacons out via HTTP and you can use
the PowerShell stager there's a Python
stager and there's a c-sharp stager and
what happens is is that it the the back
end you can clone any website you want
to so let's just say you clone Google
it'll have Google there and I'll show
Google being there and when you go to
the site or OB Google but embedded and
spread throughout the whole HTML source
code is its command and control
infrastructure and it's all randomized
author out there and so what will happen
is the beacon will go out it'll look
like it's browsing as a regular user and
loading the site but it's reassembling
the command control instructions that it
needs to do and then it sends it off and
then executes so good luck detecting
that right and this was two years ago I
released a gherkin last year and still
have 0 out of 60 detection ratio out
there good stuff
Nick Carr did a blog post there was that
every remember remember the setting
contest - MS extension type this is a
extension type that a guy named in nigma
0x3 or Matt Nelson came out with from
Specter ops and he found that this this
specific file type setting content - s
the extension type itself gave code
execution function yet specifically in
what we call deep links parameter and
instead the deep links you could have it
call an executable or execute code you
could have a new powershell whatever you
wanted to after this was released it was
weaponized within about three hours
there's a lot of different attackers
that were leveraging this in a while to
use it for commanding command and
control or for code execution because it
was something that hadn't been
discovered yet
two weeks later zero out of 60 detection
criteria so again when we look at
detection today we're focusing very much
on that pattern piece and what's awesome
and cool but yet we still don't get a
lot of value from our tools
that we're leveraging and especially the
next-generation stuff that's out there
and really the focus on today not be on
the pattern the pattern can be good for
low-hanging fruits but we need to be
looking at the behavior of specific
attacks on what they exhibit a good
example would be like application
control bypass techniques which we'll
talk a little about so instead of
looking for G's Power Cells the simple
example before explaining this so
powershell for power show do you look
for in Bocca expression do you look for
encoded command she noticed twelve
different variations of encoder command
think it's more than I think sixteen so
you can do - you can do - you see you
can do - en and Co different variations
of the coca manage you know if you throw
double quotes in there it's still a
valuable string are still a little bit
string or you throw carrots in there
same thing so are you looking for all
the variations of all these different
techniques from a full-fledged
programming language or can you look at
the behavior of PowerShell and say well
hey maybe we'll get some false positive
out of this but if we can bubbled up to
human to look at maybe we have a better
stance at detecting this like a good
example be why is PowerShell beaconing
onto the internet we're gonna get some
false positives exchanged it's gonna be
came out to the internet we do certain
updates it's gonna be came out to the
internet but can we baseline that
environment and say okay well now
PowerShell speaking out to the internet
let's look at that command that was
executed and take a look length of
command is also a good indication right
so there's a lot of things that we can
say okay instead of looking at a very
specific string that we're looking for
why not move to something that's more
behavior centric and say okay bikini
that's the Internet in PowerShell I want
to look at that from an analyst
perspective I want to see what that
looks like to see whether or not it's
malicious and there's a lot of good
examples of this so let's do a
demonstration I want to show a demo of
Windows Defender and I've had a
love-hate relationship with Windows
Defender for the past like months I
think I started to war with them so I
called them on on on on on Twitter
because I wrote this tool called magic
unicorn about I don't like four or five
years ago okay and when I wrote the
unicorn what it is is it's a PowerShell
office keishon tool and you know for
things like encoded command like if you
have - en - nee & Co etc etc what I did
is I'm able to use - value into string
convert an encoded command back so that
it doesn't get detected by most EDRs and
things like that that's out there and
what it does it takes shellcode whatever
you want it can be Metasploit also I
could be your own custom shellcode and
it uses PowerShell to inject it directly
into memory without touching disk
you know why that's important is that
PowerShell today is starting to become
more of a dying breed when it comes to
us as attackers because with PowerShell
version 5 and version 6 integration into
the anti-malware scan interface script
lock logging things that nobody is using
right now anyway those are all great
things that eventually companies will
use now it's funny about script lock
logging is it's like one of the best
things out there not from the script
lock logging it's basically getting like
the raw syntax as it's about to be
executed by the PowerShell interpreter
it's a good visibility piece but no one
enables it cuz the amount of volume of
logs that you get it increases your
Splunk license by like five hundred
thousand right and we don't wanna pay
that so so screw detection on that we
that's too much right and so a script
lock logging won't be there we don't use
constrained language Bo no one uses that
because it's gonna break all of our
developer standing over doing out there
but we are seeing more prominence of
PowerShell version 5 and version 6 which
ultimately increases to two additional
logging now I did I did the very first
ever PowerShell security talk it was
when PowerShell beta first came out and
it was at Def Con I think Def Con 14
maybe what's that I do it there die
deliver beforehand I think I did I think
it's a Def Con first and I did besides
after but as one of the first-ever
PowerShell tops ever and I basically
talked about how power show was gonna be
the new new way of attacking this is
back in 2008-2009
and what was funny about as I called a
PowerShell oMFG and we leased a bunch of
cool that we can use in PowerShell
wasn't embedded into Microsoft at that
point and and I said hey Mike this is
gonna be the number one way of going it
but PowerShell with what Jeff Snover
with the creator of PowerShell me homes
from a security perspective have done
have really made PowerShell probably one
the most secure programming languages at
least from an identification perspective
logging and monitoring on PowerShell
you don't get that with dotnet you don't
get that with Python you don't get that
with bash the amount of logging that
goes into Power Stone what you can do to
lock it down with constrained language
mode and everything else makes it a
substantially better programming
language out there than anything else so
we as attackers know that our window for
PowerShell is extremely lower but with
Windows Defender specifically and I'll
talk about the antivirus and a skin
interface the detection that we're using
right now are still signature based
there's no machine learning or behavior
going on and these things even though
that they tout it it's it's absolutely
ridiculous what is happening
is you have a PowerShell command that
gets executed in prior to execution it
goes into the anti-malware scan
interface a MSI okay again it gets
inspected by a mess sign that says hey
it's basically in its Ross its clearest
form so after after encoded command
after it's decoded and basically right
before it's about to hit the PowerShell
interpreter it'll scan it with a net
with the antivirus engine and say hey do
any of these meet our signature criteria
in a MSI and so so what happens is that
they'll take unicorn which is a public
tool and I called them out on it because
I wrote unicorn like five years ago and
it still wasn't being detected by
antivirus and I'm like listen can we
just start to get better on the
technique that that unicorn is using a
wrap injecting shell code directly into
memory through PowerShell is probably
not a great idea like why do you need
create thread why do you need a virtual
a like what do you need all these things
in PowerShell kill the technique not the
specific signature because an attacker
isn't going to upload unicorn to github
and talk talk crap to to a bunch of
antivirus vendors right that's not what
they do
so when I wrote unicorn five years ago I
wrote two versions one was kind of like
a buggy version but it worked fine but
then I'd like gala but better on the
coding stuff and I released the what
became unicorn today interesting enough
does anybody know what my detection
criteria is on that one that I wrote
five years ago that I haven't published
zero the one today it released new
signatures every week because they think
it's fun because they just basically
write static signatures on different
things my codes actually got so much
better like it's it's great works a heck
of a lot better so I'll show you a demo
of that right now I'm gonna show you an
example of what what defender will
typically look for now in in show code
specifically with Metasploit they really
really like writing signatures for
Metasploit that's their their big number
one thing and it's awesome right we're
gonna write signatures for Metasploit
we're gonna tech Metasploit well with
Metasploit version 5 that's coming out
you can get get it from the github repos
right now they've incorporated rc4
encryption to d6 AES and a couple other
ciphers or a couple of encryption
standards for for the shell code itself
so you can actually encrypt all of your
shell code completely which completely
circumvents its inspection criteria now
interesting enough if you just generate
a medicine meterpreter shell with no
encoding like like no shikata guy Nate
or nothing like that
there will be static portions of op
codes that'll be inside of your show
code that Windows Defender will look for
they'll take they'll generate Metasploit
they'll take a secondary snapshot of it
and they'll see what our static patterns
and then start to write signatures for
those and so all you have to do as an
attacker is when they decide to write
specific instruction sets that are
common across the board is just chunk
them up into different variables so if
you notice here where it's highlighted
it says you know is your X 3 3 and then
it has a new variable and then it just
chunks it up that was a specific
signature that windows defender was
looking for and if you chunk it up it's
no problem you don't have any issue
getting detected by antivirus and this
is what it looks like when you get
snagged by a mess I specifically it'll
say the content of this has been blocked
by your antivirus software etc etc and a
lot of times about logs will be
generated now what I love about this is
that it says category suspicious
behavior there is zero behavior going on
here it is not behavior at all it's
literally compare this string to this
string here and if it matches then
trigger a virus alarm ok there's zero
behaviors when you see behavior alarms I
used to get scared by I'm like oh man
people are really going into like this
behavior stuff but think about it and
from an enterprise perspective at
Microsoft can you really build in the
mass fleet of billions and billions and
billions of computers build good
behavior based stuffin out there that
100% block absolutely not
there's no way you can't scale that you
can't say hey if a parent-child process
of Outlook that Exe spawns community AC
and Power Cell that exe we're gonna
block that because it is militia 99% of
time it probably is but in an
environment as fast as there's there's
no way you're blocking that based off of
Markov chain so let's take a look let's
actually do a demo here of what Windows
is looking for
and we see that and then we got our
Windows machine here and so this is
Windows 10 fully patched with the latest
signatures up there and what we're gonna
do is take a look at what what
specifically to be be flagged on so let
me generate a quick shell a second me my
IP address I could type today I cannot
type
now this is unicorn what's gonna do is
it can generate a partial encoded
command that we can just copy and paste
somewhere for code execution okay now
I'm gonna copy this over real quick
anybody can read this right good so what
we have here if you look at the very top
let me just blow this up a little bit
and notice here some of the funny ones
with EDR is like carbon black for
example looks for Parrish W dash T but
doesn't look for /w /c okay but notice
here that we're using a two string to
basically convert an encoded command
back now you may be like what this well
down here is is our base64 encoded
strings that have all of our code in it
now what else to do inside of unicorn as
I chunk up the code because a lot of
places will look for base64 encoded
strings and while this is a valid
powershell syntax and most interpreters
that are going like EDRs and stuff they
don't recognize concatenated strings
when it comes to encoded command now
what I'm gonna do here is I'm just going
to decode this really fast and I want to
show you what's actually hat well first
let me let me actually execute this I'm
gonna take away the /w so you can see
the command actually being executed let
me run this from the command line I
notice here we get malicious content
right it has been blocked by your and
about suffered hey they released another
signature it's another signature week
with Windows Defender folks oh it takes
me a lot less time to rewrite certain
portions on my code then it takes those
folks to build these signatures so it's
been a fun game with them it takes me
about 20 minutes probably takes them a
lot more resources so it's a resource
game at this point
so let me decode this real quick and I
want to show you what's actually
happening here and what's actually
getting flagged so let me just make some
quick changes here
alright here's the code that's happening
here just move over here so you can see
it here's our code okay now you can
notice here some of these things have
changed over time like hey they're
flagging on on very specific strings
like kernel32.dll well if you put double
quotes in there and no longer it gets
detected it's this simple
this simple that we're dealing with at
this point in this case here I wrote a
tool now this is why it takes me about
20 minutes to do it
is I wrote a tool that natively
understands the PowerShell language I
wrote it wrote in Python and it looks at
my code and it basically submits it to
Microsoft's defender and then it finds
the chunk part that of the actual code
that is being flagged by NRS or if
there's multiple flags that are being
flagged by universe I'm going to run
this really quick let me just regenerate
my code real fast so we can see it and
then I'm gonna run my tool that will go
through and find out what part and and
you can just by trial-and-error if you
want it to you and what it's gonna do is
it's gonna chunk up on my code submit it
to defender to see what's actually
happening and what gets detected it
takes a sec
it takes like 30 seconds if that
depending on how long it takes so I
found one string so it's flat Windows
Defender is flagging off a very specific
unicorn command called four which is
basically a four loop and it's going
through all the opcodes and it found
that that specific string right there
triggers on a B detection okay so if we
change you look at the four instead of
doing four why not just do while true
all right
and it also said and let's let's let's
submit this I want to show you real
quick submitting this into the
interpreters well so you can see it's
still the same thing so if I hit if I
hit play notice it's saying getting
blocked by the the at the bottom so
we're looking at the same same code here
so we also found that this string here 0
0 X 8 D start these op codes here we're
gonna what we're gonna do let's take a
look at this and I'll just break this up
real quick I also call Camus like house
and I'll do mu two real complex real
hard let me see where and then so I need
to add this here and what I'm gonna do
just to make sure I'm just gonna create
my listener see if it works better
handler I'm gonna copy and paste this
into here and we got our show real
difficult right machine-learning ha
behavior yes right so if you look at
some resources you look at all blocks at
Microsoft comm this came out recently
and they've been touting a Massiah
sharpshooter now one thing that
Microsoft did that was awesome
with sharpshooter and sharpshooter is a
very specific technique for DC ization
acts is that they actually blocked a
specific type of attack on called
dynamic invoke and that wasn't commonly
used across the board and dynamic Evoque
once that's blocked it's very difficult
to do DC realization attacks and if you
obviously did enough that's great but
here's some of the benefits of a msi
notice on top that's the obvious gated
code on top on the below we can actually
see the div skated code directly through
a messiah there are benefits from an
analyst perspective in integrating the
MSI but it's still static signature
based detection isn't it it's not
behavior it's not machine learning but
you have the data at least available to
you to be able to look for I just wanted
to throw a quick dig on the machine
learning thing I'm on their comments
they're not happening
most EDRs pretty trivial to bypass as
well this is a good example for for
carbon black command a DX e / c / q
equals will get caught command ID XE /
parent c /kr q does not get caught so
we're still a signature driven industry
watch list in carbon black are
significant a lot of the tools out there
that tout ninety-nine percent protection
100% detection I love that comment you
know what the hundred percent detection
is 100 percent detection on what they're
looking for if you change it in any way
shape or form you're fine you're 100
percent fine absolutely fine no issues
whatsoever and so how detect today is
this machine learning stuff is really
based on telemetry and telemetry if
you're not familiar that term is data
that they're harvesting off of your
endpoints and using that it's a massive
big Splunk instance to be able to query
and write signatures off of and the same
thing goes for virustotal when that debt
control settings - MS came out our
settings content SMS came out what I did
is as I took that and I named it apt 28
dot settings control - MS and in the
deep links I had like a pretty op
skated PowerShell command and in there I
put a shout-out to one of my friends and
I uploaded the virustotal within about
14 minutes I had somebody reaching out
to me saying hey it was a funny joke
they literally have massive armies of
people farming through virustotal data
to write signatures they literally have
telemetry coming out of Windows Defender
and they have a team of people writing
signatures that is our artificial
intelligence and machine learning of
today human beings going through massive
amounts of data writing signatures and
again if you change that in some way
shape or form
you're usually fine when it comes to it
code execution this is from what we see
a binary defense but today about 84% of
what we see are still binary Dropper
dropping an executable usually unco
non-code signed on to an environment to
get code execution still about 84%
that's the massive amount of that's the
most prevalent amount of attacks that
are out there 13% is PowerShell
injection okay definitely an increase
from last year it was like 8 percent
last year so Power Cells definitely
prevalence in environments now what
we're starting to see is the change to
to application control bypass these what
we call wall bez binaries and scripts
and I'll talk a little about this but
most companies today are still focused
on executables in PowerShell which is
where you should be that's your highest
percentage of attack surface when it
comes to be prominent predominant amount
of out there but we still need to be
looking out for these Lal Baz if there's
a good good source from odof our mo o
d'Ivoire has a great site that lists all
of the different application control
bypass techniques and scripts that you
can use and what these are if you're not
familiar is that Windows come shipped
with all these different binaries rights
you have to run an operating system
right you have to have PE files you have
to have executables and so when that
when the operating system starts you
have what explored ID XE you have all
these different executables in your
operating system right well a lot of
these have code execution functionality
with zero logging whatsoever so a good
example of like MSHDA wmic register here
are 32 CBD DHCC stic even BG info and
other things that the background info
has remote code execution functionality
with VB script so these are code signed
binaries from Microsoft that have
additional functionality to go and
download code from the internet and
execute it either in memory directly or
download a file and execute it and so
these these things are great for us from
an application whitelisting perspective
why because you whitelist Microsoft
signing certificates don't you and so
this is where a lot of the research is
going into today is finding these in
either publishing them Casey Smith from
sub T is one of the best resources when
it comes to finding these you have a lot
of other folks too that are that are
doing research into this in this area
here but what's interesting as less time
I checked there are 68 total binaries
just binaries alone that have additional
code execution functionality in them
that allow you to execute code on the
system without detection and that's
where a lot of the research at axe are
going into right now so my personal
favorites this is my favorite meme I've
literally put this in every one of my
presentations for like the past five
years and it just gets better as you
watch it so like you know and I usually
use this for ones I'm gonna talk for a
little bit because it entertains the
audience and it just gets better like
people are looking like it's gonna get
better it is getting better right sorry
awesome whoever created that is like the
most genius person I've ever seen in my
life it's like the perfect skinny one
second one second all right all right
good so some of my favorite ones like
WIC for example you can use the slash
formats which will look for HTTP bad
sitcom and you can download XSL an
execute code cert utils you know certain
you still has the ability to download
code directly from the internet one of
the cool ones we saw in the wild that
Daniel Bohannon did a tweet on recently
no sorry about prior a few months ago
but as using cert util to download power
show code and then execute the
PowerShell code and it went with in
PowerShell what is that that that
specific chain do they may know so if
we're looking for PowerShell baking out
the internet but instead they use cert
util to go and download the PowerShell
code and then execute the PowerShell
code that doesn't use the internet what
happens boom there goes our detection
criteria right what happens if you write
certain things in EDRs
what happens when you rename PowerShell
yeah right it's usually that easy by the
way and so a lot of these have the
ability for code execution em sh t is
another good example um you can actually
you don't have to the extension types at
the end of them you can have it be a dot
txt what happens if you see em SH if you
see Internet Explorer user agent or user
agent from from MSHDA go out to github
and download something like only
github.com slash awesome tool slash
license that's suspicious to you
probably not depends on if it's em sh t
going out but a lot of
have the ability to download code and
execute and that's what's important now
let's talk about behavior for a second
so I saw when when the wmic portion came
out most almost all the EDRs
all the signatures they come out looks
4/4 Matt what happens if you change
slash format is something a little bit
different well they're 100% detecting on
slash format but they're not 100%
detecting on anything that you modify or
change in any way shape or form again
very easy for circumvention a good way
to detect something like this would be
why would wmic tidy XC and ever in the
first place beacon out to the Internet
why would it ever got to the intern in
the first place WIC doesn't go out to
the internet MSHDA typically does not go
out to dinner the only time I've ever
seen MSHDA go out to the internet is
that when they're to use like an
ancillary method for AWS management
services which uses HTA's but it's like
a fallback method that they couldn't use
the first one to go into so you
typically don't see em sh t in
environments
register you're at 32 sometimes can go
out to local IP addresses but never
beacons out to the Internet in most
cases so again a lot of things that we
can look for and so the balance that we
have to figure out is that most
companies don't have the people inside
to research all of these techniques and
to understand what they are and we'll
talk about automation testing here in a
few but you might have the data but you
don't know what to do with it hey we're
getting em point locs awesome but you
have to have em point locs today there's
no if ands or buts
I know increases your Splunk licensing I
am NOT a spokesperson for Splunk but it
increases just your licensing is
substantially you have to have endpoint
logs and point logs are like number one
when it comes to attack surface does it
mean you shouldn't do server decimation
do dns does it mean you should do
firewall logs but it means that the
importance of endpoint logs at this
point time is substantially higher and
so doing that and implementing a
protection again takes that long time
and investment and so what do you do
when you don't have the people because
we would we would solve security right
like I'm here to solve security today in
today's presentation right so we can
solve security today period 100% like I
would say that we could solve secured
99% if we had one dedicated security
person to every single person employee
that you had in your organization
because then you can sit behind the
person like hey don't click that stuff
that's ridiculous right your response
time would be awesome all you
anyway well me me take the laptop they
passed over to Bob Bob pass that Mary
and Mary pass to Jojo reimage it you
send it back it's a little loop be
awesome it'd be so efficient
unfortunately we don't have that ability
do we and so we have to say okay well we
don't have the people to do this stuff
how do we get to a model where we can
see these types of attacks in our
environments and keep up the date and
that really comes to leveraging read and
you'll hear this concept a lot around
purple to me I'm sure it's it's me a lot
everybody knows the concept of
probability I mean blue team's
and red team's working together to
figure out things but in most cases the
blue team even if it's a hunting that's
supposed to understand a lot of the
TTP's that are out there or gets threat
intelligence that shows them specific
indicators doesn't understand in most
cases how those techniques work you
don't understand when you execute the
specific command this is what's
happening behind the scene or this is a
new attack vector that came out that
applies to you know in our environment
because of this and if you don't
leverage red then you don't understand
the attacks that are happening out there
today it's really important that's the
solution
today it's often referred to as purple
teaming and it's collaboration between
red and blue working together to
simulate an actual attack and what I
mean by that it's a lot different than a
penetration test right a penetration
test we try to find as many exposures as
possible during a given time purple team
engagements aren't supposed to be
something where you are trying to fish
individual users and you're trying to
find different ways or avenues in you're
simulating very specific attack patterns
and you're working with the blue team to
build detection cards here that works
let me ask a question if a threat hunter
and this is not no offense of threat
hunters are absolutely brilliant
fantastic and needed and also our stuff
but if a threat hunter is building a
detection hole off of a specific attack
what happens you get wmic
slash format in those directions if you
get a red teamer that's helping build
those out what do they do
oh hell I can bypass that with this
right and now your detection criteria
becomes much better doesn't it so
simulating actual attacks in your
environment and working with the blue to
collaborate work together mix makes a
huge difference when it comes to those
those simulations and it's got to be
continual ongoing exercise it's not
something that's like hey I'm gonna do
once a quarter or once a year and then
from there we're gonna walk away this is
something that needs to be built into
our programs that we do today we don't
do that right now
use these as exercises as in conjunction
with our penetration test you should
have an internal dedicated red team you
should have an internal dedicated blue
team and they should be working together
to do this corrective them yeah and the
reason I say this is that what's your
biggest return when it comes to being
able to stop attacks
protection is one right detection is
there if your detection sucks you have a
big problem on your hands when it comes
to responding to those incidents these
simulations really help with that it
also goes into building threat models
everybody hates it hates talking about
threat modeling because no one
understands threat modeling but really
understanding what you're trying to
protect the adversaries groups that are
in play and then building out your
capabilities to simulate those attacks
in your environment and and what should
really be happening is the red team
should be up here a little bit right and
your blue team should want to get to
here and then your red team goes here
and you go like this right and it's
about going through and it doesn't mean
you have to detect everything that's out
there but a good example like lateral
movements people focus on decom lateral
movements pass the hash other methods
for 4wi exact to get to understand
letter movement you know many different
types of lateral movement there is in
your environment lots however if you
look for something something something
simple like here we're gonna get all
local logs and we're gonna do forty
seventh log ID 46 24 we're gonna look
for login type 3 and we're gonna see
what workstation or workstation lateral
movement that we have in our environment
that is a very specific behavior in our
environment instead of looking for a
very specific pattern in our
environments and based on your
environment saying hey well maybe we
have a few service accounts coming from
this source IP address let's say put
exceptions into those but let's look at
lateral movement as a whole and what
we're seeing do you want to see Bob and
sales moving laterally to Mary Ann I t's
computer that's probably not a good
indication that something's right there
again behavior versus pattern the red
seem responsibilities in a big portion
of this comes down to research research
has to be the foundation of what makes
up that red team building out you might
start up here we're gonna do Metasploit
meterpreter with no encoding and we're
gonna do encoding here we're gonna do
cobalt strike okay now we need to use
our own custom c2 infrastructure to
build out and use a undocumented method
for code execution because our team is
so good at this point
um we uh stood in a sales pitch there's
a lot of great companies out there a
trusted SEC we found a couple customers
only a couple like to that the
sophistication level was so high that it
made us look like a bunch of children
and so we ended up dedicating our entire
team a year and a half ago to building
an entire research team for doing
methods and techniques that haven't been
discovered before so that we can get
access to those environments and do it
and we do very well at that now but
during those periods of time like there
are only a few companies that have hit a
level based on what they're doing to get
to that specific type of level out there
and that big that's because the
continuous needs being a lot of a lot of
testing and really your red team output
directly equates into what you're doing
for your defensive capabilities now
really quick talking on on
automation testing I'm a huge fan of
automation testing if you're familiar
with the miter attack framework you know
you have Caldera you have the atomic red
team you have a lot of commercial
platforms that out there there's a lot
of great things that those tools can do
if you're not remote them you can run a
tool on and endpoints and it generates a
bunch of alarms for you now that's great
but do you know what to do with those so
if you see MSHDA what do you do you
write a signature for MSHDA
going to this and we see if we see in
our logs let me write a detection it
can't help with a lot of the
commoditized stuff that's out there but
to be honest with you and most companies
that are running these tools still have
password one as their administrator
password for their domain admin you
don't have to worry about this type of
stuff yet unless your programs actually
functioning appropriately I can't
emphasize the the amount of time it
takes for research in our industry both
offense and defense requires a
substantial amount of research and if
you aren't dedicating your team's to
having that research time you're losing
out and what you what the possibilities
are for understanding what's occurring
and research should literally be at
least 25% of the time that a red teamer
has in their environment to be able to
develop code or develop capabilities to
be able to do certain pieces there it's
it's really important to understand that
what it takes out there I mean just
looking at delegation tokens in Kerberos
and to figure out what's happening for
for Active Directory it's you understand
the ins and outs of that to build tools
around that to understand what how it
applies to our environment that takes a
lot of time if you're not developing
research
as part of your overall security program
you're behind the times research is an
absolute necessity when it comes to what
we're dealing with today
you had Edie ours out there right and
endpoint detection response tools I
approached this too the acronym first
and point detect and response tools are
supposed to be that augmentation wing
for you to be able to have a lot of the
advanced attacks into your tools so that
you don't have to have a research team
dedicated to it in most cases they can
find a lot of the low-hanging fruit
that's out there and a lot of other good
things out there so as an attacker we
need to understand how to get around
those specific tools and how to use our
techniques to get around them to see
what an actual attacker can do and if
you're not dedicating research to those
again you have a lot of a lot of major
problems so closing up when it comes if
you take one thing away from this it's
that a Windows Defender is awesome right
machine learning is awesome artificial
intelligence is awesome the EDRs are
doing a great job because they detect
100% of everything that's out there
derbycon is far less appear than BC at
Augusta there's a lot of things that you
can take away in it anybody's watching
just this talk there was a whole joke we
have before this I don't want to you
know throw anything out there but the
biggest piece around any of this is that
as an industry we are still very much
signature driven no matter what anybody
is telling you out there whether it's in
IPs and it's using behavior that it's a
baseline there are things that can be
behavior based but it still requires a
human being to interpret whether or not
the DES malicious and that's the part
that we miss in this industry we're
trying to still rely off of the tools
and while the tools may provide us
better visibility or may meant us in a
way if we don't have the people to
support that then your program is
non-existent
you cannot sidestep people period people
have to be invested upon people have to
have that time to look people have photo
training you have to have a team
dedicated to this type of stuff and if
you want to do detection today you have
to have people there isn't a tool out
there that I know of today that doesn't
require people to actively through them
a good example would be some of the best
prevention that I see out there today
some of the best prevention is
application away this thing can you run
an application where this ting program
people right we laugh right is everybody
here have a standardized laptop where
everything is exactly the same on every
machine no you have to have people for
that good example process chains if you
look at a parent-child process that's
one of the most valuable things that you
can use in an environment for detection
so you have a parent process of windward
dot exe spawning a child process of
PowerShell or command at exe or W script
or C script what does that mean
something bad happen right but if you
don't have that visibility to look at
that and say well maybe there are
certain business processes that leverage
that maybe we have a couple macros in
our environment that uses a business
process as powershell or committed exe
but if you did investigate that with the
person would you know that can you just
straight-up block that across your
entire environment probably not you
probably have deviations to those a good
example I was doing a breach assessment
for a company and I thought I found
something amazing I'm like oh I just
just paid for my whole consulting you
know experience here because I found
this one thing and it was an exchange
server and it was a domain admin account
running as a PowerShell command that was
going out to a Chinese IP address and
downloading and non signed codes not an
on coats and executable
and it was like a randomized name is
that bad yeah right I'm like I just I
just made my money domain admin go don't
going and downloading an unsigned a
binary from the internet from China I
made my money so now I can just like
chill and write some code for the rest
that we know just getting on in there
they did what we do right so as funny as
is is I went to the customer Mike found
some stuff like this is critical urgent
we got it got to shut down the exchange
server we got to change the password
like oh no that's we have a third party
development company in China and it's a
reporting tool for our exchange service
it's it's legit I'm like oh
I got a couple suggestions this is here
for improvement there however is that
malicious is it it's a business process
that they're using in their environment
but if I didn't look at that and
investigate that I wouldn't know when I
look at em sh TI b XE beaking it's an
internet maybe we have a business
process that does it but if you don't
give that to a human are they gonna are
they are you gonna know so detection
really focuses on the people and one
thing I want to close with is that there
has to be a innocent I notice a big term
but there has to be a whole process for
how you continuously mature a good
example would be hey is every the D de
Otto stuff that happened about a year
and a half ago right so if you're not
familiar like DD Otto most most code
execution through office documents comes
through macros right that's the the
primary method well a security
researcher have found a way to do code
execution without macros so it's called
DD ATO as a method that you can use to
then get code execution on a system does
anybody know how long it took to be
weaponized by locky 24 hours does it
mean know how long it was how long it
took to get weaponized and used an
exploit in the wild for hours so our
time window for that is is very small
right how do something like that in your
environment where DD odd is being
released
get to your Security Operations Center
from an analyst to be able to detect it
and that's the gap alright how do you
continuously make MSHDA when it beacons
out the internet a known issue for your
analyst and how do you train them on
that and that process that it takes in
order to do that if the red team
discovers new methods for bypassing your
detection there should be direct ways of
building detection into there and
training your sake analysts or
individuals that are going on the hunt
looking for those as a way to
proactively identify those in the future
one of the biggest things and I run a
24/7 security operations center one of
the biggest things I have with humans as
humans looking for something that is
legit like not legit like me asana as it
is a attacker we had recently that that
our team missed and the really we caught
him on the Power Cell execution so we
got on that but we didn't get him on the
MS HTTPS so there was a thing that was
like user awareness training HTA is
there ever going to be a user awareness
training that HTA if you're an attacker
you know that that's not legit right you
know that there's never a user we're
gonna stray today HTA out there there's
not a company uses each tas so our stock
analyst looked at it and said oh it must
be user awareness training and you
closed the ticket didn't know that that
was a method that's our bad for not
being able to train them in a way to get
better than now luckily our other
detection is like power shell injection
everything else you know quickly hit
that which is fantastic we caught it but
in those specific cases do you have a
mechanism to train your stock analyst of
what looks malicious and what is unusual
behavior those are all big pieces that
we don't focus on today and that process
where you're looking at from the
beginning of when we discover or when we
actually do a simulation or test in our
environment what does that mean to get
that into a format to where we can use
it intelligible in our environment and
those are the things that we have to
answer in security today
I want to thank besides Augusta for for
having me out here really appreciate
everybody's time is they made many
questions open up for like like two
questions or no questions you don't feel
shy I don't bite yeah
good question and just for clarification
- I wasn't ripping on any of those tools
the tools are great for visibility
carbon black is great for visibility we
can get from process chains what you can
get for what's being executed on the
system itself they're great for
visibility but if you don't have the
people to build them up and to manage
and maintain them then they start to
become a problem and so the question was
is there any tools out there that have
given us a headache and honestly the
answer to that is is there's not a
product there that it's giving us that
it's getting us a headache it's been the
teams that have given us a headache
there was a company that was leveraging
a specific tool and I won't name the the
vendor and this one the the product
itself out of the box is is not gonna be
good for detecting us right but they've
had a team there built in and doing the
testing back and forth purple team
exercises having a hunt team and they
built the tool over time to where once
we got code execution we did something
that we thought was super stealthy like
we're like oh yeah we got a show or I'll
high-five all of a sudden two seconds
later the machine goes in can team and
we no longer have communication with our
command control infrastructure like how
the heck did they attack that so we used
somewhere else so that the people have
really been that been the big aspects
there really hasn't been a tool that has
has been a major problem for us that to
get around as an attacker I would say
that things are definitely up ticking
getting better it can get harder for us
depending on how much they lock the
machines down like a good example would
be silence silences AI components aren't
hard for us to get around right but
their application control functionality
Devon there's actually a really solid so
if they implement application control
very effectively then we have to figure
out ways to circumvent and get around
those to be able to do it so I would say
that again it's not necessarily the tool
it's how its implemented and how the
people are using it in order to make it
better and understand those attack
vectors so it's not every doesn't matter
fusing carbon black using science using
CrowdStrike using whatever you whatever
you want is fine as long as you can
build those tools to be better than what
they are out of the box is out of the
box they think about it from an
organization perspective if a company
releases protection that actually works
is that going to work across every
single enterprise most likely not the
variations and differentials that you
have to
do in most environments is substantially
large so they have to deal with a lot of
these things and while they can mock
things down to stop things it requires
the people to customize and to use those
tools in a way that makes it makes it
different so they answer your question
no not not really any tools that have
caused us a lot of headache hurt issues
good question any other questions one
less one or well thank you all very much
for having me on I appreciate it
[Applause]