good afternoon we're going to talk
windows event forwarding and a sec today
so first thing that I want to talk about
is why specifically I wanted to talk
about this so one of the things about
decides Augusta is that coming here over
the the last several years there's a lot
of defensive talks and there's a lot of
people who are students or maybe
starting off in their career and you
come to this conference so I wanted to
kind of pick something that is something
that I think a lot of people can do and
the title for this presentation is you
can do this
so just presents an organization that
has less than let's say a thousand
employees okay so maybe half
is anyone here support less than maybe
200 okay all right so a lot of the
presentations that you see and if you're
on Twitter and you are going to other
conferences people are talking about
supporting organizations that have
10,000 endpoints that might not those
types of techniques might not be
applicable to what you do so the
unfortunate thing that happens is once
you start engaging with the community
there's this thing called the perfection
fallacy or the Nirvana fallacy where if
you if your solution doesn't fix
everything someone is going to show up
and say but that doesn't scale or you
know that's not going to fix this
problem it always comes up with patching
right so the one across stuff the MS
1710 you know some people come out and
say just patch our machines somebody
immediately comes out and says you don't
know my environment well you're the best
person to understand your environment
and people coming out and talking about
that you know immediately responding
back with this perfection fallacy and
all that kind of stuff is like us having
a health care discussion and I say
everyone needs to wash their hands and
someone comes up immediately and says
washing your hands doesn't cure cancer
right it's it's not helpful so given
that specifically in the United States
the vast majority of organizations are
actually really small so in my
professional career I support a agency
that does economic development and a lot
of the people that we interact with are
actually really small so the ten
thousand in point thing doesn't
represent you trying to do security for
an accounting firm in Augusta Georgia
where you have 250 staff members right
so the other thing that happens is a lot
of times especially in smaller
organizations IT is responsible for
security or there might only be one
security person or you know some
combination of things like that so one
of my arguments also is that the vast
majority of the things that you do with
security are directly applicable to
traditional IT right so you have the CIA
triad which is just fancy you know
that's the other thing that happens
during presentations there's lots of
acronyms right the CIA triad
confidentiality integrity and
availability integrity integrity and
availability is a direct IT
responsibility right machines go down IT
is responsible for it so security things
don't necessarily have to be so
separated from security until you start
to get into these big scale things and
separation of duties and all that kind
of stuff right so the other thing that's
important is to begin to really
understand what's normal in your
environment and
doing things like monitoring endpoint
logs which is primarily what I'm going
to talk about is one of the best things
that you can do so we just had an
excellent presentation in this room from
people doing red teaming right the those
techniques that they were using would
have lit up the majority of environments
that are doing endpoint monitoring if
those people also look at what's normal
on your network right so using the
theoretical example of the accounting
firm in Augusta how many times is
someone that works in an accounting firm
gonna run Who am I never it's highly
unlikely they're even going to run the
net command so once you start you
determine what's normal for your
environment techniques like endpoint
monitoring my argument is that you
should immediately alert on things like
who am i net the scheduled tasks stuff
nedeth net sh those are not normal
things for even Durer when's the last
time that you sat down at someone's desk
to you know do whatever especially if
you come from a helpdesk background and
then went into security a executive vice
president of a corporation isn't going
to sit down and write and hit dirt you
know type dirt so everything that I'm
going to talk about is quote free
meaning that it's either built into
Windows or it's an open-source free
project and this idea that you can do it
is primarily that like what Dave Kennedy
was talking about this morning y'all are
the person that's eventually going to
make the decisions about these things
right so you want to automate as much as
possible to bubble up to the person that
determines what's normal for your
environment so why me I a lot of people
view the about me thing so what I
specifically wanted to talk about is why
why do I consider myself someone that
can talk about this topic I have a lot
of experience with windows
I'm started off you know in the NetWare
days with windows 3-1 and in t35 them on
all that stuff I'm one of those Gen X
Slackware Linux people who you know used
it when you could burn up your monitor
and destroy your hard drive or whatever
I like to take tests so that's the GX
stuff as I said I'm an IT Director for a
state agency for the state that is
across the river which you can and I
don't work for the Department of Revenue
and South Carolina some of you will know
wow that's funny I use left with event
forwarding an O SEC every day so the
first part is the Windows Event for me
right so how many people use Windows
Event now not not very many okay so
Windows Event forwarding is built into
the operating system so a lot of people
have talked about this over the last
couple of years and that there's a
variety of reasons for it and one of the
the primary thing is because it's
built-in it doesn't require an agent
those of you who have Active Directory
domains which is probably going to be
all of you these configurations can help
via group policy so basically what
you're doing is you're setting up an
agent or sorry you're setting up a
Windows Event collector server which
we'll talk talk about a little bit more
in a minute that the clients are gonna
send their logs to you so given that
this is a lightning talk and we're gonna
have a ton of time to get into technical
detail what I wanted to really emphasize
is to learn from people they do this all
the time so the nsa's IAD which now is
just cybersecurity or something they
changed a lot of their names created a
paper
five years ago maybe spotting the
adversary with Windows Event log
monitoring it's an excellent paper the
Australian signals Directorate also has
one it gets into what what are the
actual group policies that you need to
set up in order for this to work all the
way down to you what types of events do
you want to subscribe to you and what is
the reason for subscribing to those
events
Jessica pain works for Microsoft
that's her twitter handle jane MSFT she
has a presentation called monitoring
what matters it's a video where she
talks about when his event monitoring
she also is the sponsor of this thing
called the waffles project which is a
probably a I mean it is it's not a it's
a Microsoft tool that's used but it's
not something that you can buy on its
own github and then Palantir regardless
of what you think about what the work
that Palantir you know whatever the
internal windows team at Palantir is
awesome so they have a github which has
everything that they use event
forwarding for in addition to some
papers on how to set it up all of these
papers are going to be similar to the
NSA paper the Palantir paper is a little
bit newer they're they're using this
actually to monitor in the neighborhood
of 10,000 endpoints i believe so even
though i'm talking about using it at a
smaller scale it's it is scalable
microsoft's recommendation is do not put
not put more than 10,000 endpoints on
one collector so if you're supporting
250 machines only requires one vm so the
other thing is
bucyk right so a lot of you anyone at a
sec or know about a sec okay this site
has been around for quite a while it was
originally written by Daniel CID it's
all log based
it's job is to it's a host intrusion
detection system it's basically reading
logs off of whatever device you know the
logs come from and then performing some
kind of action so the majority of the
time what that's going to be is an alert
although in the UNIX base you know what
a Linux BSD it can fire off active
response so if you're using it on the
web server you can use it to write to
you IP tables there are some stuff that
you can do in Windows but it doesn't
work very well so the server is Linux
based generally the Windows client
Windows is the only thing that requires
a client the rest of them you basically
have to compile but it's it's not
difficult if you're used to you doing
stuff in Linux atomic core is actually
kind of the current maintainer of a lot
of the Oh sex stuff there was a lot of
forks of Oh sec but its first three
atomic core was uh or wazoo however you
want to pronounce at alienvault the
wazoo and alienvault actually have a a
suit like a pseudo sim kind of
environment that is using Oh suck and
then my favorite of course since we're
here in Augusta is security onion so
you've seen it mentioned in 401 and 504
if you take sans classes the other thing
that comes up sometimes when you're
talking about those sec is why not use
OS query so go ahead is my argument
whatever you're going to use to be your
endpoint monitoring it's better to begin
down a path and then iterate you know so
we chose to go the Oh sec path some
people made to choose to go os query
there's a lot of functionality that's
the same like OS career you can do you
follow integrity monitoring and things
like that but my personal preference is
those that cuz I've used it for a long
time
so the two things together right so one
of the problems with OSAC is key
management maintaining a set clients
isn't fun
so what what you what you do is you're
enrolling an agent with the OS X server
and then the communication gets set up
so that the log information gets sent
via the agent to the OS X server and
then there's a log monitor that is going
to do the interpretation based off of
your rules and then perform whatever
kind of action there is so the
architecture that I'm proposing to use
in this case is use Windows event
forwarding set up the policies based off
of the things that are written in those
papers yet all of your logs going to one
collector and then maintain the
connection between your Windows Event
collector and the OS X server that way
you don't have to put agents on your
endpoints you still have to monitor the
Windows Event collector to determine
whether or not you have agents dropping
off and things like that are sorry you
have clients dropping off but you don't
have to do the key management you don't
have to do any of that kind of stuff so
use the guidance from the those papers
NSA Palantir Microsoft has excellent
guidance security logs application
crashes app Locker device car or task
scheduler all that kind of stuff the
other thing that I highly recommend that
you integrate with this is sis Mon so
sis Mon can be extremely chatty but disk
space as they say is relatively cheap so
if we're also talking about smaller
environments it might not be bad to
start out with getting more data and
then pull it back as needed
because the more information that you
get the better off you're going to be
you can make the determination of you
you don't need this anymore or whatever
so the examples from earlier today like
Dave Kennedy was talking about
PowerShell talking out to the Internet
you can get that kind of information
from sis Mon right a rule and O SEC and
get an alert without no special devices
required no nothing but brain power so
the way to do this is the typical way
that you go about doing any kind of ite
or security infrastructure project take
a small number of machines I would argue
that part of this process you need to
evaluate your tiers of computers right
so you have you have computers that have
access to certain types of data and in
your environment you might have some
group of computers that has access to
PII like your accounts payable or your
HR people or whatever set everything in
two tiers and then start working from
that everything's done via group policy
as I said once the stuff starts coming
through you can actually go into the
event log viewer on the collector and
user you know just look at it to make
sure that stuff's working in this case
you can do a push or pull which the
papers will talk about I would suggest
using the pull push method so your
clients check in with the collector they
get the subscription that says please
send me your 46:24 from the security log
once that once they've done the check-in
they have some period of time where
they're going to send their logs to the
collector so that can handle
theoretically it could handle remote
clients that are going to be out and
come back in stuff like that it uses win
RM which you might be familiar with with
PowerShell remoting 5985 or 59 to 86
who knows the difference between the two
of those and it's not that one of them
isn't encrypted
59 86 uses TLS right so 5985 doesn't
however which this comes up at capably
and I believe Jason folson talks about
this in his in his Windows class once
the connection is set up in on 45985 the
communication actually is encrypted with
a EES symmetric key so even though the
initial connection isn't encrypted
between the endpoint and the other side
either with PowerShell remoting or with
this the communications actually are
encrypted so OSAC the asian itself is
fairly lightweight you are going to
produce a lot of logs doing this right
so disk disk space those cheap as I said
osek itself is included with security
onion including some visualizations in
the new elasticsearch Kabana
stuff I would argue that you need to
monitor your domain controllers and the
wefts collector so installing the OSAC
agent actually on the domain controller
will get you things like all of your
logins going to your OS X Server and the
built-in rules with osek are gonna
include things like security group
changed so if someone changes the
content of the domain admins group
without doing any kind of customization
at all you're going to get an alert that
this security group changed New Year's
is logging in you can use a
functionality in a sec that are lists so
that you have a list of all of your
sensitive accounts and if you see an
interactive log in from a higher tiered
user onto a end-users machine like a
domain admin should not login to a
workstation
right so you can actually make those SEC
alert on something like that so that you
because you have an operational problem
the clients talk over 15:14 UDP which
actually in this case uses a very bad
algorithm but Daniel SIDS argument about
that is he's never seen any exploits
against those SEC agent using Blowfish
for encryption however apparently that
is a PCI problem so what's happened
recently is virtual security who maybe
in Virginia area is working with atomic
Corp to introduce perfect forward
secrecy support using we socket which is
part is what signal uses so those of you
that are concerned about Oh SEC using
blue fish to encrypt its traffic they
will they'll soon be a implementation
using and we suck it use the base line
rules just like with with then porting
at the beginning so then what happens is
like what we were talking about how
likely is it that somebody's gonna run
Who am I
not very likely so there's no rule in
OSAC for Who am I so what you have to do
is you have to go in there and start
writing rules based off of your
environment and so I want to show a few
different examples of some custom rules
so this is actually showing so you've
got a you've got a user GIS dude on your
domain
they're running ESRI product product
yes awry for some reason doesn't sign
their dll's so this is showing that
AppLocker blocked DLL load on one of
your endpoints no endpoint agent on gif
dudes computer that AppLocker log is
getting sent to the collector and then
the collector is talking to Oh sack and
sex giving you the alert it's actually
not very difficult to do it all to write
a rule like that and there's tons of
examples so one of the other things that
has been talked about today is app
Locker bypasses application whitelisting
dice bypasses using built in whatever
they're called law bins is one word that
people use living off the land stuff
using native tools if you're using
system on and there obviously there's
going to be ways of getting around this
right but if you don't fall for the
perfection fallacy having this rule is
better than not knowing about it at all
and then it might be that this is a
developer and you need to turn it off
for their machine msbuild running on an
accountant's machine is a problem right
there's no need there's no reason for
somebody to do that multiple windows
error events in this case windows of day
failed to check for updates I'm pretty
sure that that is a indicating that it
couldn't talk to the debian sus machine
so that that's useful for security and
it's also useful for IT not talking to
wsus is bad and then on the security
side because they're not getting patches
not talking to wsus as bad on the IT
side why are that why it cannot talk to
it
the other thing PowerShell everyone
loves to talk about how PowerShell can
be used and abused I would say that you
could probably in a small environment if
you're using system on you can turn on
PowerShell detection and just see what
happens and you will be surprised
probably that once you get rid of the
alerts that are going to be based off of
the things that the OS is doing nobody's
using power
developers are gonna use PowerShell you
just put them into a category on their
own
um admins are gonna be using PowerShell
put them on a category on their own in
this case you've got a client
why does Dropbox create a scheduled task
to update itself and do you even know
that that happens whenever they somebody
puts drop Dropbox on their machine once
you set up these rules you will start to
detect you know why does this Intel
graphics driver run PowerShell to talk
out over the Internet
doesn't you know doesn't make any sense
actually they're just assuming that they
can do whatever they want but it's your
network so once you start alerting on it
then you can make decisions about what
you want to do alright so the overall
thing is getting more endpoint
visibility using built-in stuff those
sec has a ton of alerts built in already
like the group changes all that kind of
stuff writing more rules for things like
speed that windows changes occur right
so you've got things like Windows
Defender Network guard or whatever that
stuff is going to get written to
somewhere in the Windows Event log and
if it's written to the event log then
you can write an alert for it
so once something comes out you figure
out what B if event log entry is and
write an alert the other thing that's
going to happen by virtue of you doing
this is that you're going to learn more
about your network and you're going to
have a ton of data so while you begin
with using OSAC to get alerts you can
also take all that event log data and
start putting it into a sim once you get
one or if you already have them on put
it in there use elq security onion
whatever whatever you want to use
fortunately i'm almost out of time so
i'm i will be
you answer questions outside but I'm
gonna ask y'all a couple of questions
say that you can get these books Don
Murdock who was in the back of the room
and left has an excellent book called
the blue team handbook incident response
Edition so the first question that I'm
gonna ask is about networking so it's
it's not entry-level but it kind of is
what protocols number is UDP gentleman
in the orange shirt yeah you yep
either either yeah one yeah 17 or 11
depending on your number system all
right so is there anyone in here that
considers themselves to be a super
Windows guru yeah all right well I'll
ask this question and we'll see if
anybody what all system
be fully realized except for in
partially sequel server that is not it
but it's related to that and FS so who
said that okay so it's actually Windows
a future store with us re FS is the one
that you can actually use but when FS I
think gates identified as one of his
biggest disappointments cuz it was being
bit Vista kind of sucked but alright
having one more thing what a big yes yep
yep
yeah actually has nothing to do with
computers byte order or all that kind of
stuff a lot of the old school computer
Wizards were literary nerds lots of
jokes and stuff like that so it actually
comes from Gulliver's Travels alright so
I want to thank you and thank besides
Augusta and like I said I'll be outside
if y'all want to talk about this and I'm
on Twitter the Twitter's fr Columba or
you can email me at
InfoSec at epicycle org
[Applause]