Harvey here to your counters designer
today
teach you how these are three
surveillance
have a little surprise hit to surprise
for here tried and later work I do
however Sevilla's
also artwork and design and photography
disclose where it's from a jewish is
Pepsi is that a lot of people that
privacy is that
inside and this is a project he should
have a hair and makeup to be
sophisticated taste actions so we had a
very expensive costing millions of
dollars and then we have a tear in
making over $1
is detected in your face this particular
call the video Jones out there and it's
quite common and embedded hardware
divisions because it's a very efficient
at CPU usage and is active phase of the
project the death toll is how can you as
a human to a machine but still to other
people and you you want to the human and
want to
increasingly we live in a world that's
heavily populated by cameras casino last
night and so he said there were 3,000
surveillance cameras in just one on the
right side and now it's hot it goes with
them
genetic algorithm to attack detection
classify we're expecting a computer
which profiles looking for and every
letter added another way for all
classifiers and is looking for this is
what's inside that we're looking at here
it's kind of a bold tribal makeup so we
do have hair part of the key things will
teach you block 252 jurors your face to
face detection algorithm which is very
cool project
camouflage from a long time ago it's
called dazzle camouflage and we look at
it pretty clear that shit is very well
but that's not the point
the way that camouflage works is that
when you look at this area I don't know
where to show you don't go too far right
and so you can see who's the artist
Pablo Picasso painted with camouflage
being paraded down Street in Paris he
said that's being used as camouflage so
you wanna do see you can use that
actually so you made any part of your
face that they're really pretty cool
features like everybody knows that you
made it look like
wages for female to do they can be
created and create your own style
and that's what it's all about being
overly intellectual and creative lives
and get to the products I have for you
so you have to be thermal imaging
anybody had a few things like on the
bottom of this and didn't see you later
metal barrier between that and the
camera and you can block but that and
you can see the top ok if it's available
like around and metal you can you see
that parks
what model are completely excluded that
gun black he is being shielded by so
they're a pretty fast and the show and
the tight round that he has a metal
plated kind of like but it is low
to know the story about it in the new
york times and they were pretty pictures
where somebody to rate and see where
that person
other type of surveillance video has a
phone on that right
your phone's location is being tracked
by your service here and just right now
everywhere you go you can if you want to
learn about security so they may have
and how to communicate with the tower
and the answer with a Faraday cage this
year it was learned that had 52 metal
plated fabric your phone and it blocks
all signals to text
here it's a little bit small city friend
was collecting MAC addresses and looking
at when you have a computer security
vulnerability broadcasting networks that
even before and you didn't even see the
standard they fall through its market
can be pieced together all the important
bits of some of its life where they may
be and how they've been too and the
other way to the physical coo clock all
the radio waves coming from your
thoughts
try this one get away in brightly
colored surveillance camera for one
individual to why
here a little bit fabrics that are quite
useful ok to tell you things about
surveillance and privacy is within
technology to carry out such as the
person in our Privacy presented
talked about in this same conversation
so in the end of the highest in
surveillance and privacy is the power to
selectively reveal yourself have
surveillance has the power to observe
how are we to be in balance so people
are doing surveillance with all the
tower and powerful to hear that a very
interesting statistic about maybe have a
little privacy we have and it's just
three people in the united states and
three seasons of your birthday
gender and nation that you give up so
it's important to protect your
information