all right just double
charles is also one of the co-founders
and there's a lot of us here today so
the felder tough time will also be
joining us
tried to show a little hit us up this
you know what about 20,000 out there so
hopefully we'll be able to make it today
so this is our fourth year vs Iowa and
called on this is 55 but really for me I
do you get to computers to take control
from and social is this and what they
did to teaching you how to be what
happens and I love doing it and someone
you know new ways to make the world a
better clothes kind of like her one that
has been used a lot of way people think
of a thing I thought the original
definition just a safe place to learn
how are you today closed till ur having
her team here
lawyers that I mentioned before that are
then made sure we all stay out of
trouble but you still have the original
in-house you are know how people in the
world of the week you will be so because
you could travel time to state how many
of you have a great great responsibility
too so it's really important that we all
have that honor goes to follow all the
time here goes well for the company
you know it's not a quote that was
written for kids something that everyone
around the world
good until it starts with a lot of the
vote in the idea of its owner of a bill
from one of her notes for all time
living well as well as his 2d CIR the
Department of effect was it for us to
get them from the military within the
military there was on something pretty
regular that they will not result I'm
not alone
there's actually a lot that we can learn
from each other words like to do we
learn from the challenge
actually caught some challenges here
right now what you are alright what's on
the page and you can really get a feel
for where I'm going over here today
get that one of the challenge is
generally how are brought into these
different kind of boring you know so
what's the most contribute to this world
but you should be giving to all of us
because I think everyone knows from is a
genius to figure out what your DSi and
the rest of the world of principal meier
a little bit different and your offense
but the first one important difference
from the world is why I don't think
there's any borders anymore
areas between countries dramatically and
I think that's why things like the
drawdown
the vulnerable for twenty years everyone
knows that the entire world not just the
place for the power grid connection is
faster faster over time as the payoff
tangible connection until I think so
what you need to know you can do
whatever you want with the world and
actually have a responsibility to do so
times here too we are really important
first one is doing to other people so
keep that in mind what I always do you
think you're doing here
Detroit R&B really close to them over
here for a right to know about the
bacteria and so what's really great
about kids love them so there's actually
a tremendous opportunity here to 50 days
and vulnerability fifth when she was
nine years old
classes 0
will hold a little bit over 20 years
with what we're still making her look
for someone with the typo or so you
finally the more I would love to hear
about walter here and so short-term and
everything we do here with everything I
do it we're talking to people really
important to have a positive out to
encourage everyone to be fun what you
want things happen to her first posters
over here in the world and also help the
world record for the military and the
women in the world will tell you this
alive over
their jobs and their relative to do
before they do it and if they think
about falling they all thought you might
think that the press actually will fight
for this loving community but also the
the makeup on and go as long as you're
likely to learn to walk like he wanted
to which is really a similar to the
world a better place to do this today as
well as professional athletes because
everyone has room the champ Tennessee
and pack them
nothing left for most of all the US and
the word gets around so these are the
elevator and that's what's your elevator
really important that people today I
don't just go home and start blogging on
the front door to be able to get enough
so if it's something to rely on here and
it should start that's really all the
not so obvious one of the one which is
no penalty box obey the law
why you all know that the american slut
touched the ball
helped us with a few years ago we are
all cellular operator we built in 1884
the label is a little unnerving but not
Friday afternoon but we go home but the
$5 so because we want to do is going to
have a bill before they actually be
close but it was worth the risk
not but that's what helped you
class people how to conduct their
research safely to their research
presented see very glad to be here we
hear both over to the contest area we
have a lot of our staff over at the
general privacy village to village
helping keep people happy to see so how
do I think of these things are being
taught you as well but check it out
there how to use pgp communicate safely
we also hear what you have to go out
there see you there
20 temporary restraining or sell yours
back in 2007 researchers jurors who has
covered the sublease Boston way to the
subway for free and this was just the
class it wasn't intended to the recently
students they could get a cheap and
equipment that was necessary in order to
replicate it is far more than the right
they want to show you the best transit
so they can you to death a presentation
you should be able to explain but the
MBE like that
security by obscurity about it exists
but people talking about it so he
couldn't even talk about them and they
led into the court judge that the judge
short end of the stick it has been up
all night
available in case something comes up
temporary restraining order to
explaining their reasons this turned out
to be relatively cold because the
shutting down its debt
tremendous talking about other people
looking at systems page news back then
it was all over the media and sillier
text you bad systems to leave these
students we went to get that DRO lifted
took about 10 days which is fairly short
goes quickly and it was bad but they
were eventually able to get their
research out there they were able to get
to the place
me two years to help the NTTA figure out
how so they were good people really
think your talks here doing this because
you want to be her that's really saying
you're alright it was 140 workers they
did just that also have been sold market
for a lot of money that they're here to
you so try to make it over to their
looking for a while to get over their
love for not making it over here so
until the first thing you have to
understand what's going on and that it
hurts the most important skills for the
future of the world
system here talking about how people can
help packing analog digital rights
activist you could do something like
that it's not too bad but with hang
trespass to Property Trust digital you
get to a computer system that is not
your own and we think these are to take
some things which are felonies so it'll
push for reform to contact your
congressman said that you think that we
need reform and we need to have and we
need to have is where be used in church
with hacking for which is like sitting
in terms of service the department of
justice and serves his you but it was a
violation of this Terms of Service
they said they use that order