the
me
well good morning everyone the thank you
for coming to my
ok it's a pleasure to be here and to
they'll be talking about postscript
I am and the security related stuff
about postscript
so just the their shorts were mine
and I'm was involved in my photo class
occur
universal tool kit writing for
recovering RFID the
keys from my for classic cars and the
tomorrow recently I've been doing some
printer and I must be taking for the
last three years I think
and basically reports go to the
continuation of the
research I've been doing and in turn on
a interest to the politic security
the like in general approach so you have
some
my papers presentations on the
advisories
I'm maybe the student we've you recall
the yeah so what's sure the morning
I'll missus Magento the following today
a but before we proceed like to
to though source communication with
eight
home in your view the deal we will post
but let's say
printer drivers the
have you installed usually it doesn't
give you
headaches home
okay 10 percent annual you have written
any post group
air program by hand okay
free people okay is good okay so
a just for me for I
when I go to conference that I just want
to know how many people
just called or screw well
a quick refresher which is the
very helpful because it II am surprised
and the
to see but the 10 over years and years
the those professional who are not
a basically I'm not aware ovale
abuse potential carried by the printers
and MFP is
and the with businesses small they're
only shows
I'll they have the potential abuse
because
printers are part of your internal
network its
but great books have been the recorder
which nobody knows way it is usually
or doesn't care about it mud I from
another perspective or from security
perspective first of all is part of the
internal network
as you can see I and it's the a trusted
resource
right I'll because this bar to go into
not work you
configure it we were username password
for your
held up with an MP and so on and so on
are it brings confidential information
because confidential information
sometime get printed
argue doesn't have like a lot of pitch
the management or is not very
a streamlined base management or I
vulnerability management
and the
a even in most of the cases or in some
cases
it is publicly accessible through
internet because
of convenience and the because I've
misconfiguration
and their general idea o.o is just a
printer so
they'll be no problems just connecting
it to the internet right
I'll the history of hiking yeah I'm
is on the printers goes back to sixties
when there was a story about
the Oaks putting mechanical and and
economic %uh Nicole the
video camera in the
as Xerox machine in the air so that
Union embassy
so is not something new but nowadays
it's not economic conical nowadays
mortgage though well the concept is the
same so you blog
the machine from inside them to get the
confidential information
I'll so from addition there's no point
of view
there so she goes like from 2002 and it
kept the
ok during every four years ever some
kind of a patent
so recently there was the
I'm all our interests bone because a.m.
more either so does the
raised for embedded devices and the
print those following 2 some kind of the
many devices so want to vote then 2012
where there were like three or four
different direction on researching
security printers and the basically is
starting to from 2010
I'm 1 I've been doing research is like
it's a small
the special but you can see David online
afterwards
I basically on the Internet
like you can see I just quickly met this
like
lesben up with a war just quickly my
more than 20,000
I
20,000 bring those connect the public
the internet and those are
like know the you know in jet one which
you use a point to bring their for those
bizarre
like enterprise-level I they have
everything
Fox they have scans that
all all in one one piece o basically
they're all over gold you see
a lotta love is going to the the
internet just don't like them
and it's good when you see the picture
and video with a little bit scary
now ban where there's other things where
where where for example some legacy the
a from piece of were softer
as the ability to indirectly painter and
there have been the most I think
now I wore document having non malicious
where they the for the PC but they've
had the militia stream for the printer
so want to get printed
the you to upload the file or changes
the screen on the printer
so basically vez at various revenues way
you can
the sent malicious dreams and your PC
anti virus or I D S IPS will not
even trigger because there is no ideas
IPS or antivirus
solution for the Panthers and I'm
selling this for the last two years I'm
I'm not pushing for a solution but there
is nothing which actually
tries to to detect malicious things
hoping there's I am basically
I'll the printing can also be done and
initiated for
the from there internet from the side so
basically if you send a link
malicious fishing I'll victim can fall
into
a link and as JavaScript and Java so
basically the
both movies can initiate and their send
the
directed to the printer or the user the
million I could control the malicious
seem so basically
you have full control basically threw
them control sequence
about to go to the printer you get the
pretty much everything from the
victims been so again a
for side prone to bring the free ticket
or free something
I with the
think twice before printing just a
general invite a
I'm not saying everything is militias
but Vadis is there
I mean think think twice before printing
is because it's not just on the paper
it's a
they have a better device in your
opinion I
okay so but those like it very quickly
refresher
really about the IMF is in print those
if you are more interested
you can check with the previous papers
but now I i want to go through over
we've posted
because it's the very interesting topic
in itself so
I am where a little bit about postscript
it's the
it's the let's say a technology which
was introduced in
if I buy adobe and it's the being used
as a one of the main technologies paying
their printers they're all
basically it's the
you know there are two kind of printer
drivers what screwdrivers and PCL
drivers
and the I'll was cute is like pic
covering sixty percent of the share
a in terms of technology and read is
that
it's the it's one of the first languages
which was there for
formatting the that they the for the
Panthers now
as you can see the the picture is taken
from the
the from Adobe and it's very very very
a representative because they're all
these bumpy and it has
unexpected turns I mean it'll like very
very interesting
picture if you see the original so in
the silverware possibilities
not just carrier for your printer data
or for their
characters we which end up one on the
paper
posted is actually a programming
language so
giving air given it's a programming
language and its
I'll come back here later so you
understand you can do much more than
just printing they that you can actually
run
some computation on the printer or what
whatever
their postcode is being rendered based
on your computer or may be rendered on
the
printer so they've been the numbers
example
the okay graphics and others is like
bear bear the initial goal of course P
but then it got expended to very complex
mop
it has very powerful moderates
computation for doing the graphics
so know if people writing web servers
I'll
XML parsers the ray tracing
basically doing really cool stuff in
free the impossible and some people even
control their milling machines like
they connect they'll either pinter
because it has a step model
ankle when I controls very very precise
the new English so I am
what exactly is possible it is like a
very
very interesting technology and bed is
is
as I said it's not just the text or
first I think image
which she goes to the computer 30
painter
it's a programming language and
basically I'll just enumerated said
dynamically typed think okay competitive
that base during complete programming
language so maybe you you ask yourself
or the hell is this right because all
these seem very
outer space well so also you
a example by example and Ave I'll just
stop
now for the to incompleteness is a
bed is but if you have a general
computation let's say
password cracking or I rainbow table
computation
it's a general computation right you can
take this
competition from any language with
Python see whatever
and prove it to incomplete transform you
can't a
make it in a post good so basically you
can have a very distributors large-scale
I general purpose competition part for
so
you can use printers for this purpose as
well just
have everything for us for the to
postscript
and the yeah basically what happens the
when they have a user prints the I'll
I document or his print button is like
I'll
what happens in in the background is
whatever it was he
own the edit or get sent in a specific
format for all for your buck want to the
printer driver
I'll for Windows it says something a
Windows internal for the next is
different
so it gets sent to the printer driver
with printer driver
understand but for months and then it
transforms to
that they thought to the post read which
is the language which
the printer understand and then it just
sounds the
the post data over a wire okay the print
well however for example you can also
see post documents on the
on the computer basically II most %uh
view
overused or heard about Ghostscript
which is
reviewer for the servers 0 for the
PCs to view post documents because
sometimes you just receiver
academic or journal paper you post
before more than just open it to
really so a in that case it does get
render them executed on your your
machine in the
sandboxed environment because I'll post
it is like a
you can think of it as the Java sandbox
I
its I high-level programming language
running in the sandbox environment
pretty much like Jul a so basically all
can exploit the
Sandboxie for bass eight-member sandbox
or doing some
other in text interesting stuff I mean
is not directly comparable to double the
parlors guy
by the sandbox environment very high
level
programming language so again we have a
very important thing is that
VoIP a program used to is not I think
that program can make a decision you can
do
the basic he fails whatever not right I
so I'll just start with the small the
now only like the simplest single then
I'll service doesn't do anything it will
pride
so basically opposed to being a
programming language you can
crossed the simple document which looks
like this like what
thinker there's less than 10 characters
and it'll basically
on something that was it you'll have to
reset bring those or just be there is a
cancel about them fall of all for
someone else author based
you just can't get the softer and thus
also result
you have to kill it me is no other way
you can
and it so I'll just so you'll how it's
the
none for Grampian MS Office because my
you might not know but
I also later post it is like a in
many more products when you actually
manager because you have all those
renders very deep in the product but
you're not aware because you just see
the picture
or the render aid final product but the
interpreter is still there
so office has like an interpreter for
I'll postscript and for example if I
try to insert the picture okay
im so
you see is like
the EPS EPS is basically
and in case to PostScript it's the
usually the
therefore representing images but at the
end of the day it's the same postscript
whites polled it has because normally it
has like
for their soft or or printers which do
not support
PostScript interpreter it has a a binary
the
II binary
from are funk male kind of thing which
goes like pumping like this whatever
it seemed the Heather right and it goes
like this:
also for the
I'll for the pieces of software which
the support were in there but the reader
in the press for the
is also Tories with do not support
opposed to it
it'll just take the bitmap fun male and
display
okay so have with the this simple as
those
and the
will just loaded
and as you can see just
hangs because it it tries to read the
file right it tries to execute
in the office interpreter
and get stock and surprisingly not
just cannot cancel play you have to kill
it
and I mean its you velvet
velvet vez basically no bike I mean
the barges in using the face but biz
know by because both companies like a
programming language is supposed to do
the loops
i mean but the idea of incorporating
like posted interpreter in a bit of both
but
F which is their programming language is
need some more design or some more
fourth security wise right
I mean you'll be surprised to find a job
in the weather in your
I'm a soft as well right I mean you can
do a lot of stuff but
okay we'll cue it
now I'll
when male on the previous slide when I
said is dynamically typed in competitive
whether a actually means is bed
a you can
actually concatenate strings or past
eight months
okay you can concatenate this thing and
or statements you can compare them to be
executable or not
and basically you can say in now it's a
a string
but then it's an executable peace so you
concatenate
and then amplitype so you can construct
problem the
program like on the flight right and
made is that you cannot statically
analyze the both groups 3
because does because of these because
you can dynamically generate the program
on the flight
so that your static analysis will not
work and the your ideas and IPS
rules will not war because in order to
understand all the
program does you have to interpret it in
in any environment
and I'll I'll just show were
simply example where for example
you have okay so we have like
two functions concatenated string or
men's think
werewolf equivalent as you can see it
and
missus hour or regional loop right which
gets the
denial of service on softer on printers
misses the loop
but a and it is commented
it's not active is here for the or don't
social purpose
now miss is ones are you
were something these ones
the the things you see are just the
strings
we r I'll put in in their own point is
so this is a string misses a string
missus training and so on and so on
so what happens is you
in this case you see the same I
accolade not delay them loop to right
and I put this on on their aspect all
the
Ave interpreter and then
I just as long as bad as more than one
minute string on this that
I just marriage so all these
small the sequences will will manage
and it will end up in a string which
looks like this
okay and then what you do is
you do converts the executable who here
comes that dynamically typed
think so you can make you convert
executable I mean is not
executable in percent but the third
executable for Microsoft Windows but if
the executable
called in terms of course with the
interbedded so
you can go to the executable under fire
exact so I mean
and you can see about the this one is
the simplest form
of work creating that infinite loop
I mean you can go any including you like
the
band of this case the court and you'll
never understand what happens
because their causes then they would be
generated through
more to do basically infinite the number
of puffs you can generate if you can
have a generator and it'll generate
languages
or a final statement in anyway a random
possible so
and just executed so just for
demonstration and I'll
I'll do very quick okay so
it's the same thing the but these
EPS for a month okay just a little bit
different
Heather so I'll just open
world
no
so the side effect is the same
I mean it demonstrates the company that
Eve
the major and bad dynamically typed
major or the PostScript
and that's why I again the bad news is
that your ideas
and I PSM anti virus will not work
because it's
most I think it cannot have anything
should just
fire the generator engine you're done
up as part of my academic exercise time
the
working on a sandbox environment which
would
they could most people and the in a
somewhat environment
get the trace a bit to see if it's
malicious or not
now I'll another thing is that for
example
being a programming languages I mean
home interview or II think
at least while everybody who wrote the
c:\program
backtrack had their records Sivan stack
credit because it never ended right so
because the program them so you can
you can actually do the same in airports
group where you can
take a program and the
you basically crash been through better
because it
you never and recursion so you have the
a function a and the you you call it
because the link as you can see a Coles
a inside it so it's like a record the
funk and
if you if you do for example open
or on these a sample on there is
interpreters
like beat goes great or MS Office or the
some other let's say even printers I
some over interpret those
being wrongly implementing bill crash
and was
small example
the bad news for for his by for this
example is
but its not directly exploitable in
terms of
it by well by passing from was getting
there better to this
tackle their MS Office but you get the
general idea
I mean a give effective pressures I mean
you can try to to find other ways to
to get out of the sandbox
so basically just runnin questions 100
percent
like it personal but I'm and Res other
ways to
we exhibit the sandbox basically and the
gets to their
a memory space over there program
which in incorporates be interpreted
okay now well I've fall from our
perspective there like
yeah Arbor program like most people or
some other implementation which
have various custom extensions because
they have like a standard
postscript to implementation and then
they because the
they need more but flexibility over time
they had some
got an extension so mostly in under
certain conditions
for example if you receive a file
usually talk to print it right
you would have to read and then print
the
if you're sure but in this case for
example just opened
okay the and want to click OK I'm not
sure if in the back it will be seen but
here the you know where they're printing
icon appears
it will appear printing icon directly
just opening
directly it opens their connection to
your printer and basically you can
up to a certain degree you can control
the steam it still
some some some specifics
the not 100 percent reliable but you get
the idea
just opening the file for because of
some work out some
I
extensions just directly prints and bed
malicious bring stream can go directly
to your printer ink printer is
own as you can we'll see invest second
part of the stock
okay so again
I R functionality sometimes compromise
security because
once opening a file you don't expect it
ultimately bring
on this too have done some other
settings month
I'm not sure how many do do is okay
now vere their thing which I like a a
lot
is about possibly being a programming
language is that
it can actually do statement none
right I mean it can do if else and so on
so basically when that when
you open a file it can detect the
environment with runs
whether it runs on a printer whether
it's wrong gonna go script
the software or so on so basically
this example shows you as you can see it
where you that their product operator
and
the product operate the returns on the
spec I'll the product
I mean being violent way throng and for
Ghostscript its
a string we says GPL Ghostscript
right so basically what the
was good can do is like you have a
postscript file
having a malicious payload which also in
mistaken
talk part has a malicious payload and
the it excuse for example on the
on a printer X but it fails I'll
on my own use their PC because it's not
the printer so you want the user
to print the file directly on the
printer
was what the a social evening parties
you display like a if
you detect veteran by mint is
computer-based as
is you can see he is and he fails right
so the first part is beef
if it's GPL Ghostscript then it
display the image and the mich game be a
social engineer part
which says the printer driver in
counters
unexpected error please bring the stock
went directly using the
printer interface so basically you can
social engineer the user
by putting some fake where you mention
so
bad user will take a final okay if where
operating system or the printer driver
says print directly to their printer
does go to the interface with the
printer and and bomb
and in bed health wrench
the militia stuff goes here which means
but you put the militia stuff for the
printer
and when the user goes and Prince the
filing between three gets you get along
the printer
and another party's
for example again its dynamical so
you send the let's say a post group kind
of documents to
a guy and usually what what happens is
the use of always like this you're gonna
construct or a document you read it and
when you print the expected to be the
same thing right I mean
you poem interview printed like one
hundred-page contact and go again
after reading it on the skin go again a
reason for the paper nobody did right
you just read on the screen print sign
them so basically because it's like
dynamically typed
you can have a situation where you send
like an invoice or icon talk with says
okay pay $100,000 the user see the terms
right
he clicks pink on the printer ways like
in the Feltham say
okay let's put is 1000 why not the user
will not go to page 128 from one
following pages and read the exact
number and gives us time
or the sign the sign right so
again is like a good example I mean
I know technical stuff doesn't get
through very well but
this kind of business stuff gets very
well through so I mean
of course is not very common but the
businesspeople exchange documenting post
be four months but to get the general
idea
so and you'd be surprised by that
bass player when I starters where
finding this postscript the
pieces and pizzeria where trial I
actually started pumping those but then
surfers seems to be a a little bit why
there so
basically I try to do so. some kind of
charting categories
at the bottom is the is Gadhafi's
was cute in their beds or specification
and based on these I'll
bad I am implementation of the post
group standard which
the or have a result the beaches
airports group
interpreter which is the most I've Wes
author bears'
the Ghostscript a in the MS Office
axis of thick other because its own
interpreter because
yeah made in the Thunder they did their
own the rather I don't think there is
like a very
I call them various art is because
there's a lot of a
smaller companies which will do they
mean by that versions 0 mint or better
out on top you can see the actual and
and the result implications
which use various the interpreters
inside them or they are bathed on that
specific in the rest so you can see the
cops
or game or a lot they they're based on
Ghostly because they're on NBC
MS Office which is based on that is so
thick and so on and so on
okay so another or the perspective all
seeing
where I web affect the softer is
is for them to have a network and I try
to
make a category where potentially can
find these pieces of thoughts also so
based on the client machines you can
find this bar to go through
packages office or Adobe products not
all of them
on their network side there on the
printers
you you have the various artists and
also sometimes you have a
print server which is if ur dedicated
machine
or a small box we just does their
layover print jobs
and you have cops running on them or
someone somewhere
in bed the in the weather sometimes okay
so
let the small the taxonomy and
okay because everything is now web to
20 web related it's the
very interesting to find that the
there are a lot of services on the
Internet which I cannot name because
more details have to come and but I mean
if you do your homework is you find them
I there on post group as part of their
job
products or as part of the processing
stream
so basically phone their own 20 services
well which run the PostScript and the
even Google was running it and the
the had the vulnerable version and they
the got want to reward for this
I'll but if funding is both the
them for example most of them were
running
I'll vulnerable versions of Ghostscript
as part of their I'll chain of
processing which is bed
I mean bed in the sense but most groups
I if you'll go in there and check the
exploit database you'll see some of the
proof of concepts which show
a the coverflow exploitation and so on
and so so basically
running well no version of ghost written
your network
if first part of your printing subsystem
or as part of some sort or processing
makes vulnerable there but specific
server as well
well some fun finding them but some will
run
both groups as the root user I mean you
have to
have gots to run goes good as the root
user some of them were running without
safer
settings right I mean bizarre
some basic coverage but these are
findings in religion real
web services so web is not free from
post group so I mean is not very well
the
very wide deployed but that is bad it
gives
a very good insight and and very
unexpected I thought victors
for machines which people do not
expected to be right because it's just
so you know
doing some conventional were the
three more ease the doing some printing
stuff
which is not quite so we once you own
but motion or get the
lot of information from admission you
get much more a
attack surface okay resources
the general very very general post
groupings now
I'll move to the second part which was
the
which is more device specific so
as as as a sparkle the printer
research yeah as part of printer
research I'll 13 a phone
I find the way a to medically in bed
the Commons in the war the document or
in JavaScript or in Java
to worries the printer I got the way to
to send to send something to the printer
which I can control
the next logical step is like now
you what you want the payload which does
something right
once you get through foot in the door
you want proper payload
percent and the was not thinking give a
well-liked
too easy choices PCL and PostScript BC
ellis does and not the programming
language was cute is a programming
language you can the more so
will go away I go for for postpaid
and basically we start looking for for
products which support
postscript then the do funeral is how to
make them out to my to the way some time
just manually
and the
we'll come annual I found the mentation
which is
good to read the condition again for not
treating the condition read it
read it twice because it sometimes it
just gives you a very personal skins
for example if you go to the condition
from the rocks may say
its the page was says is a figure for
telegraphy in where update file and
press the green button to send it
and missus a on the page where you
actually
prine right you see print immediately
right
and it says fear where update file will
have a final extension of both PS
I mean doesn't it raises question when
you see a post we file with other film
where are they
of course if has very very nice stuff in
it a new go grab it and you go analyze
it
so 13 okay the compile and that
a good part of course bit okay if it's
not very well-off was gay that because
if you do with proper way it can be of
was getting very well
but usually it comes you know freeway
the source overflowing
is like doubles keeping the early days
everything is with the source
so start duplicating the compiling a
vote the was 15 when update them
actually following various a API's
which basically is an extension of the
rocks we have a basic
the post 15th or better and on Talbot
have some customization
layer which helps them do some
management or some a a
additional stuff with the divide so make
head
big sorts plugs API so basically you can
communicate with their makes for its
operating system
they have with debugging Q-eight guys
like generate pressure or generate bomb
pair or
and so on various it to a stuff the hell
logging bomb you could send somewhere
pulp
the pumper
parameter for fourteen well millimeters
the
Londis ROM and flash and
basically the
there were several the direction which
where possible to go
if a food banks worse but it's and
requires a lot of work and basically you
have to know
make that big source version and to have
the executable
and to have a secure the will to exploit
to have need to have a development
environment which is
again very specific so well
whether the simplest thing if you see I
mean
peak missing glistening which somebody
who
from you would choose two-goal new
yeah from yeah ROM
I okay run these keys yet would but from
yet you go directly to the ROM
mean if you have rum you have everything
and actually
I'll some somewhere institutes says that
the 2012 we'll see you
the memory scraping on mobile devices on
or
embedded devices will still be in top 10
fred's
members get is the simplest you get to
the memory get everything
so OK within the memory dumping is just
as crucial but
that is that you go for the is this
chain
and that memory dumping his is very
powerful
so basically as part of offer I
of memory dumping basically we set and
have had to run the memory dump or
import script which is
not quite the funny thing the ride but
when you end up with good results you're
satisfied with your on
you you wrote the
post good memory dump a and
we we found bed for example
if you said administrator things
impossible don't on the device
and the basically a the
and run out the you say the device is
secure it has the
possible I mean strong password and the
user's
cannot locate the device and to add
another user or do some settings
but if you connect to their printing
stream port
you have the ROM so basically setting
and password on their web interface
doesn't protect to in any way from there
on like this
the
on from the I'm like access a dock so
basically
administration fails to prevent memory
dumping Ann Arbor
API the second the doc
well I'll I'll be showing the the demos
the calls for some other salute with
later
I'll just explain by text so basically a
other scenarios which we found is that
for example that means that goes and the
I'll logs into to their
account to do some management so
basically they are tiger can go to the
I made movies we've get requests this is
important because in the GET request
everything using the URL in cleartext
and that is that
a in memory they have by web server
a logging a section and basically you go
you down the memory from the proper
location and because it together request
the URL
including the passwords is everything in
the clear taking the memory if they
would have done this as a hd2 be a POST
request
it will be in buffer but it's there very
imp
interesting point but things a small
thing like this but
re: doesn't matter it's a ghetto reports
right but it matters at the end of the
day because
air with get you have the URL being
logged and the
I correct like the the passport a
the second is like a continuation of
that %ah keys
after the user I'll missus all
for the passport change basically one
the
I mean change the password you you can
see their prime
there's been change in Europe this one
is when the
administrator loading basically all the
headers HTTP headers are there so
again in the memory you can find the
base64 encoded
basic OTE authentication strings so
again we somewhat small pattern the
recognition and memory dumping
you get the the most violators
possible being used to log into their
web interface
so the devices again compromise and
basically you'll vivid solution which
people
try to say is okay with SSL
as a so secure nevermind Bates buy
certificates or
self-signed certificates just closed
eyes it's fine I mean
if you or since is good but the problem
is what to do when your private key is
being leaked in
in memory I mean this is also a part
which has to be
properly analyzed when is not only for
the printer but I mean
for all the better divisive right
in-home interview
a or so or home until developers
you're not you about general developers
I'll
after implementing a very secure
solution goals have a memory
to see whether via licking stuff or not
not so many thing and
may have a dime piece the
missed as well been injected actually
the the private key is
being in the memory Lee so it basically
a
cancels all their benefits of SSL and
also
there are some default keys the which
you're in the
being used in Example them their use it
we have a copy paste mental
okay I'll governor think
is vet when the I user
the sends the documents to
to the printer to to send it can stand
Vic let's go away which means
I'll plain text
and no bus or I'll some people started
to
doing some encryption so bad that
document itself is being created over
the wire so
simple Wireshark sniffing would not
receive a document which is a
would step but their already is bat
how good the encryption would be on the
network anyway vet
file would be the created in the printer
to be able to be
bring to the right so at the end of the
day it will be some way into memory in
cleartext
so no matter what bus or a user setup
for for their
printer a before sending the paint job
so you have some
printers whale golan swipe your card
though in for a pin
in order to be able to get the printout
so the people
think but by putting but number or
having the swipe card basically
in creeps everything which is F holes
actually to a to all
false friend it gives you a force
protection
you think you put the pin everything is
secure it
even VoIP with a p/e as you'll see it
goes clear text
uneven vol where they are administrator
than
it or increase the traffic over the
network in just
putting a layer of protection that
document is being gay in plain text
so just the
aqui okay so
we have a the Modesto cool
mistaking that be
have a very modest ok is offer let's say
high official or air hi the
high rank manager and
he wants to to print the document and
usually what happens there %um
imprinting
one thing to your when printing to
network printers
is but your printer driver connects to
the port none 91 usually
its ninety-nine percent it connects to
port 9100 all their printer
and it sends the they don't do with
bring their own but poor
Solbi showing like a simulation what
the the a printer driver would do in the
case over
high-ranking official so the printer
driver would connect to the sport
and the a official with have a
documented
right well created in MS towards paying
the
not bad whatever have a editorials and
when bear hiring official let's say
introduces a row
a password or a pin it gets the usually
get said the
be jail said hold key like 1337 whatever
right and or a bus or you can be like
for some specific models you can be user
key
and their alphanumeric when it's cold
Keith on the numbers
so the user their parent official things
okay I put possible
I have put my pimp and let's bring that
the Panthers rival driver will take bows
pin numbers and so on
will create these post was crude other
not the three
okay
and live but I love the doc meant to be
very secret and includes a document
because we wanted to be secret then its
for their high ranking officials
and the printer drivers take this
three-man sense to the
to the printer okay and its
link the the pinball other it's the
its finishing with pinto cocaine vet
printer diver disconnects
from the
printer and now we are on the
attackers machine you don't see an very
modest ok whether or not the commotion
and that I can
goes I is about security
he goes to the
a to the same printer and he connects
buy tools or mentally to the same port
9100 and Rhonda memory bumper which I
mention and for
very specific region basically he is a
member number which
the it tastes like
of near 40 X 26 and I Cal
you cannot really is because yeah the
cases to open well
okay so that I couldn't their memory
dumping
a new okay besides over
logs on the stuff in their memory
you can see Matt
matoco got the memory
bumping and you see that against title
for seeing them so on
medical you get everything in plain text
memory right I mean
doesn't matter if the pain doesn't
matter having people unit or in the
memory the Penrith
anyway it's clear thanks so I mean you
get the
that they don't you also get the VIP
right you know who printed what's
printed
what is there a usual p.m. password
username
a basically you get with a very good
profiling over there that
you have the the most hardcore they they
can get from a printer
so
I mean let's let's the bet the over them
you have everything in in cleartext okay
just moved
limit quicker I'll
okay a Valverde more which is i want to
show is
for example printer besides forgetting
the documents war
pins or being a fun devices it can be
used there too
just come silently the network because
what happens printers have a service
discovery protocols UPnP and so on
so when they connect the networks they
want to know what Prince over the
they want to know what I'm hoping
there's our because all various
configurations top 40
because of errors default software
installed in the printer
so when it starts and connects to the
network is starts conning
right and then it keeps everything in
its memory so what they're not like you
can do
it can have a full let's say a full
local topology or the network
we've on doing anything and it's gone
any
and a mop whatever I mean does connect
to the printer and get the pol gene
printer do that for you not no need to
to make additional noise on the wire
so again miss missus the
the next them ways for they think I
the printer do the let's come for you
and
basically I do that
just one second want
sorry for this
okay so basically
I'm running a memory dump all
it's the Lulu painful with the member
number because some regions are not my
job to move a
the device keeper setting so to get them
real name
memory map is it takes some time because
the device when the printer between
three sets
it takes like five minutes for it to
warm up back get back online check all
it strays
Jill Colvin organized what's kind of
things you get when you get there like
and I might
memory and basically if you have like to
congress
at fifty-six megabytes or more is like
takes more KK it can take several days
just to
the keeper said think and keep mapping
the commemorates bit painful
if you don't buy the the configuration
the
okay so as you can see four all for the
memory
the we we have the
with first is okay
the 0 got 1 and
it's the linux-based device UPnP support
is running
mean UPnP them on the okay
and its it is my actual the
router which I used in my another set up
so you get the first thing
I mean you know lower the what is the
router what is the
the version so basically
alt what is possible to do is if you
know where these
Linux kernel version running this to BMP
driver
well have a exploits you can
thank you from seeing Turing complete
postscript all scripts printer
on right and basically the printer loop
on your
device does because it can do any
the basic if statement and because this
during complete the set
everything you can do anything you can
do in most people ok it
in this case with Xerox it helps big
because we have access to
I'll V's special API but in other cases
may have also
another vendor they have also especially
guys which you can find
so bed is that you can take an exploit
with impose great
and check for exploitable devices
from the printer yeah
we will also have another device which
was a number
printer it was a
an HP so basically we have all the
details
and in memory you can see is
all the details days baby in the bay
model number
so again you can start playing like
sending
militias jobs from one printer to a
novel just hoping for the network
right mean everything is possible so
basically you
its they're they're all to make the
I there could be a so spread is
spreading warm on
on the printers which is some some work
to do but
it's definitely doable having some were
some basic memory the
dumping stuff and the some
exercise with the post group the helps
so its across the device in these over
the bullshit we r
to about Michael and also
wavelet doorway you like bill d like to
thought gets you know you can new
whatever
stuff you want like connect do being
they did they tell
from memory X filtrate in creeped
you can implement all kind of encryption
cashing in
postscript and textile trade the data
outside
okay so basically lets the
month rick's which with with up to
to show but basically there's no
privilege level separation as they said
now that mean the settings the not
separate the privilege
on the
for the printing the port or printing
user
printing process well it doesn't have a
secure passwords that are like
everything is in clear text them need to
get the HTTP requests well
it leads to a secure base it on the
fishing day fail it leaks the
STPs as the silkies lolol the
not alert the old G protection I mean as
you can see into them all
no in memory book win protection which
is quite hard to do because
well anything have to be
at some way to create an but the problem
is that they do not clean up the memory
may just three hits Monday do not clean
up which is another problem like
the front program perspectives like free
before but it's still in the memory
right
well and yet there's no
first look at the restriction on the on
the divisive so all love is if you sum
up you you get the very powerful
very organized the away both owning
printers are mostly from the printers
all mobile devices
as a they mention you can Jake
if the router is exploitable both
explosive missed you have a big boost to
document having like 20 exploitable
there is being
just fired then see what what you can on
in but network
and there's like a a big number. oh
there is some of those
will which you're well fitted by the
superior API exposed the
they're still fixing because the
apparently the
impact bases quite I month
yes often used since the the case is
open and
I don't know exactly when when it will
be fixed
okay so just have the
short time I'll just go very quickly not
chill
and got stuck in a nutshell you both
like me is not occur send an email
or send the
URL to the victim the they may contain
the
non malicious for computer although
common but which contains malicious
all screwed stream embedded into it
which end up on the printer
or I love this site the
site sense to the user I'll has the
JavaScript or Java versions sending a
malicious payload to the printer
the user opens but I spent in the open
besides
sees the freebie by the bites the bait
for social engineering at arc is a free
coupon
free ticket to Madonna concert whatever
imagination is like
limitless well P just Prince the
postscript 3 manned up in the
MFP and from there demos
are looking for the sensible but
in a not so that once lied to cover a
little
so yeah their first the stage 1 and
stage stores like
the first part of my research from 2000
then to
11-member stage freeze the
current the
research direction okay so
the the solution as I mentioned these
because it's a programming language
again postscript uni their dynamic
execution environment and the dynamic
institution I'll which
you analyze and see wats functionality
or Wat
Super eight guys it uses and so on so
basically
I'm working into at having at
sandbox environment where you you upload
a postscript file through their web
interface for example it will be
published Maybin
one month I hope the
some kind of a better way you can upload
your file suspicious files or all the
ones who wants to bed
and it will analyze them tell well very
is suspicious militias for
does quite safe to to send to the
printer or to open on both groups
and yeah well
want their offense inside is a very
interesting the
idea to integrate some of their they
mentioned to take some exploits from
Metasploit
put them in post before mud because its
portable leads
platform-independent as well and the
have them integrated
the basically for them to PostScript and
then depending on the platform
integrating various
have endorse exploits well
yes some solutions I'll I'll just go
very quickly because they won't leave
time for questions well some
acknowledgement they want to do
me the Post reporter research was done
on the support of
security research loves very cool guys
well
and somewhere some thanks so
but take aways well for this is both
Emma bizarre
like very bad the secure than general
their career
be potential fall apart me go back to
your face
I'll they might be upcoming
I i'm not doing a few the or hype but
its potential I for
up coming up talks in form of course
group streams like whatever bye file or
by URL or
some internal autox and the
basically securing them appease the
requires better segmentation better for
on designing the net or is requires the
better
a
our sole source solutions which are like
engine Paul
you can then check my upcoming papers
the
and the videos the from the store come
from previous research to come
so on my YouTube channel e4 interest in
the in them at the door in the
war the document vidéo the
you can write to miss a male and the
basically
message thank you very much if you have
any questions
I NJ thank you very much I'm afraid
we're out of time so I don't think we
ever have time to do any questions but
I'm sure people can like you are
okay so thank you very much I'm going
much
you
in