the you
thanks guys so it's a pleasure to be our
and trying to make it to be funny
I don't want to get I know that's what I
and probably me as well
we will day was a retail for nice tall x
saw
missus the last one so they last a
fourth
and then we are done so all from
this book is about to the privacy of a
security risk a
Ave called a computing services and
to briefly about myself a so I'm i'm
italian as you can understand from the
accent
and and then moved to France II warfare
for
a five years on I spent the last three
are doing research
in a research lab in their self roth and
then previously I was working for
different companies doing at petition
past the military just says meant so any
kind of security
course I'll to sing Sirius and recently
I E
I joined Trend Micro a when I am their
senior threat researcher
okay so this is their autumn up for
today
so I we started nine to you seeing the
beat
up early with his car computing but I
think you are
but much expert on this i in particular
we focus on a1
spittle series of a cloud computing did
which is gonna I S
and we look at the Amazon ec2 it is
probably the most famous
a service provider all these type
they wheeler define what these the
problem
eloy for use it to look but we develop
and
to automatically a analyze the
the Amazon easy to serious and tool to
study the
the different the problematic serrated
to the use of this there always a
serious
we've been to conclude weaver some less
on but we want to bring on
and and that's all okay so
what is cloud computing get if you look
at that the pedia
be a says that these are the delivery of
computing
as a serious rather than a product what
does it mean
it means that at using get
in at war it usually is internet you can
to get
access to the Foreign Service such as a
obligation on for example a
Google made is an application
mitterrand's over the Internet
platform for sample platter for
developing a
a software are not to be this already
the infrastructure are so that means
that there you can arrange the a
over the Internet like cast or ash or
competition so as you can see
clouded is some ol and the all a new
concept
in fact this be in there are on scene
the cell I
me arse so popular distributed and grid
computing get
been use their I for a while from by
year scientists
the government and a different
organization for example for doing what
about a planning
I'll weather forecast I modeling of
economic
so that is nothing new there saw
so what these that what is cloud
computing wide nowadays everybody's to
give cloud computing
because God computing is there is a
commodity so who does a
not use cloud nowadays just take for
example
as we're seeing a Google made that's a
cloud service or
I mean I guess most of us probably are
using
add the domain cell why because it's
easy to use a I in fact that the cloud
the is a kind of
ready to go service you go over the
Internet you choose your service
you pay if you have to pay you click and
you're ready to go
so you have been made set up for you you
have a
for example in the air if you think at
that Dropbox
you're there some store as somewhere or
a to be used
or if we look what we win looking up
Amador you can easily buying a server
over the crowd
unit couple of clicks so
there are three main mall the other
called service
I one is called Software as a Service
now once called the platform is Sirius
and the first one is called the
infrastructure
the serious so I'm the first one what is
provided by the cloud
he is there software like at
the SERM for example Salesforce
provided CRM over a cloud so ether
Stoppers web is providing an hour the
software to work out
and the car can provide or some other
software like he made games
and so on bed about not having
reasonable modell
have it is called up after a service
where what is provided by the cloud is
that
a ver compy computing on a solution to
find a
for development for example Microsoft as
we're
on it Google up in Jain
and the for the mall that which is a
modded Wii Ware
try to to look at a it's a record
infrastructure is serious
so what is provided by the by the
service provider easier if are some
computers for example physical abuse
trial
or even a store as a fire or or even
networks
so in peace a I S a series
the leader is a is Amazon
we ve is a serious with this code that
plastique computer clout K the
their cronies ay si tu and the
services be the main play at about that
our van a ver
up a lot of other competing doors for
some poor famous name iraq's base
Terremark a giant so they pretty much do
the same things
the and probably sell them for you
probably are cheaper
and and the problem this is because that
probably fear the network a in
the amount of their coverby is it a day
that they can offer its a bit less
a.m. so what what all these a service
provider of our
is the access to waive your to ELISA
said a very image and their out talking
to pee
you're usually on a hourly or mon-fri
beezies
so we see these winged it aid so let's
look at I was a eighties 82 Amazon a
see-through
and user can a arranged what I what is
called an Amazon machine image
okay and be said
I was almost machine image usually to
machina
the diese a voter Windows
autumnleighoaks
and is usually called the worst under
software classic example are you want to
set up a sampler
a your internet site
so you can go for Outlook up for a for a
machine that there's a some specific of
you would have shown some specific web
OPP
you just choose machine select you pay
you pal you put your credit card Seok
around bomb
and then you can ready for that in OWL
are week on a 4-yard and you get charge
have any mouth for an amount that you
with you sweetie image
at the same time was interesting is more
that is that
at the user itself can publish image
to the cloud okay so
now free different type of user first
one is Amazon itself
summers and provide the infrastructures
but also provided some image
K bed about indeed love solar temple me
I can that
the verity up set up an image and
uploaded to the cloud
they can say ok ABC's at public
everybody can use this image
K event at a food party companies
that there should be run a business on
these Moda solve a pre-configured thus I
mean age
and then they put the middle of a cloud
and they ask your comments on a
to charred extra cost that so in this
way when a user
or entity made for the for type yes to
pay twice the pay for
Amazon for BA infrastructure for rape
up processing capabilities and
the surf third party company for a for
having provided the
the midge so
our time I can be bo2 that freeway to be
done and I for teeth from alive sees
them
so you have your air your with the
operating system like this
located smack for the report was ever
win this yet but it will I can run from
command line
a we do what I can stop shop for the
live sees them
we put in a easel an event that I can
upload a visa on the cloud
you can be derived from a from a bf
twyla
I machine age which have ready all you
can clone eat
from Ann Arbor MI say can take one which
is already running
is able to cloud I can take it grozny
and that uploaded over a cloud
vented in are going to start an image
okay so I was on provide the even if the
IU
but you can they're used to start the
middle from Carmel I not from the
scripting
all you can do it using the webapp in
any case if the specified the credential
between use it to login to VMI
usually for and for alien ok said
he's a mmm is there is a public
SSH key K so you have to say okay this
is Mikey
star to be seen it will be skiing so
what I was in da the around the mid and
have an apple a day
yada you are a key to remit so that only
your
yourself can access to the NIT then you
have to specify the defense resources
you won't like how much memory for a
prophesy RBR your performance on
in reach a region you want to be made to
start percent believe my businesses in
Europe
I would like to I we it makes sense to
put the meat in Europe
is that if your business for simple why
did you want to
lot bottles beloved you can start to be
made an awesome it one in you ass
when he knew it up one in Asia up Sun
okay finally when they're when you've
got a good image in you start
the mich and you can reach
I would only give your and of name
committees on these form
so easy to minus I P my nose the
different regions like Asia
not a computer that Amazon ABS look calm
and that it will be accessible the %ah
SSH or a remote desktop if you are under
Windows
okay what is important to to see your
eyes that I weather does not care about
securing be made
what does it mean it means that the user
is completely IRS possible
a to maintain this server
so that means that their abuser as
always a root privilege
because he needed to administer BC stem
so it is a key point
and we will get back to these later on
yet a couple screenshot on IBM Amazon
the
Management Console for example the seal
the corner
up left your you can that too was very
John
when he won the match start like a I
drowned
yet you have a key PR so that means my
sht that
I want to use a putting the gateway to
the image
medicaid Kiki at large when you click ER
be set a pop come up sold out even
though he's a very quick start a lot
about some predefined
email each per sample first one is in
units are provided by Amazon itself
because it has an Amazon logo
and is marked as their at favorite
and other wanna is that this is a red
dot this is an able to sleep can choose
if you want
6442 when you start death
%uh to be made that I don't mind so much
as private
so nobody asking around except me and be
serve the community and I
but at a most interesting why not buy em
i've a toda they are
the to be used by everybody so when it
would be made but they start
be made to get loaded and when it's
running
yet your which kind of ads all has been
run
and that's the public they left where
you can about
reach me image there but he's also a
private IP address
saw every images to interface one of the
public AP one of the Private Network
allowed them
okay so that's the first part
a the stability in production
physically RTF me your question before a
cool
all the cool part
okay so a popular Prachi are
in this I was on ec2 is to the possible
to create out to create
publishing share our satellite images
with other users
so if it draws from all that between
called provider in user
is well-defined in the says that I was
that is not going to hurt you
what these not clearly that was the
the mall the between the image provided
a and the user
in fact the user can create and share
images
as well so make the walkway Sinaloa
researches around is a bs1
are very threats associated with brain
team
images from public catalogue of cloud
computing providers
anti-fur OTA pratt's to text and the
saw in particular we look at three
different problems the first one is that
cool same inga
a securing the meet again because they
are not a tax
suppose you're antonin age and you want
to make sure that no other people can
access your image
the first one is a cue to be made
against many shows a major provider
because it if you start any veggie you
don't know who is great BC midge
I'm going to make sure that the the
provider because we gave it up for the
mid
is not money she also is not as luck
would have it image
battle part was for you to use them
and the for trainees to about sanitizing
the midget to protect the privacy
all the provider so what we need to be
there
we develop an automated system for the
security and I season and measurement of
these three problems
and the week desolate appeared a
seven-month all the public satellite
image provided by amazonian need for
data center
okay so US East Coast West Coast
Europe and Asia and be successfully
Es Cana more min at five thousand
machine
in the ultimate way
so I would eat we did with the tool
other to call us up and cloud
at faith
cloud because it work on the cloud south
on because it's an avid tool
and because it sounds a bit like
SoundCloud
and the tour is composed of three main
components of every
robot that is the seat and MI check
betty is that correctly running I
retriever
check with Michelle and give you okay
so battling to be when the MIS been is
both yet Ian
Pasig order to to scan their one is
called a when he's in a mood scanner
I bet scanning the machine from the
remote point of view from a network
dollar one is a local scanner so they
took a scandal-tainted Kate
to the machine and execute their some
past from the inside
so he's to stand out from a compliment
or
completely complementary to each other
soviet this simple one is a remote scan
their
let missus just a simple compliment so
we use and map
to collect information 11 network so we
scanned the VA
beer they've AP address Ave a CD to wean
stars
to collectively still open port the air
the 52 that the fair
fight if there is a web server if it is
a web application running
at a different web modules the finances
resort reports
we see that the video visa later on just
remember that this is one things we do
when we scan the image let's now look at
the local scanner
missus with the main components of a
local scanner analyze be
and I for a known vulnerabilities using
Vanessa school
and at the same time ill the
and when we scan to be the need for a
known for their abilities
we also uploader to when I to the i MiEV
what we call it past the sweet so it s
32 is a self-extracting archive
okay that contain twenty-four
past but the group in four main
categories K
the first one is a general category so
it ethicist them out for what I've
system information on
luck fis i connect different data likely
var log or like says keep it up
Benevides another component to that
these there
are you a senior he can you read it yeah
I guess also
on the top you have a the first mondavi
generous best
so that collect information on the
machine at the second one
collect information on their great
information about that percent body fat
a summer she arse
orbit on the machine if the machine is
that connecting to summer
a X there are no ulcer just oppose the
other machine that is infected by
malware
okay this one for
pilot left by the provider
because I we are seeing that everybody
can provide etc and publishing mean age
so we check if they get it published the
midget may be left something like Easter
defies
private keys Assad kurdish I'll
for a sequel database password in
finally we have some pastor 82 is
security
so we tested for the machine contain a
summer rootkit
and summers a model where or summer heat
and process
and so on get
so without a finding in a
so a first finding at serrated to
software abilities the why
we passed bath it does that because that
the mall to the business here ease okay
you can rent in the middle every cloud
you know you kinda sad about no need to
ever serve it at your home
no needed to buy yard where dedicated to
your survey
no need to invest i mean they main
config audiomachine
come to us you can buy the survey are
it's easy you know you just have to be
made
you play can you go okay so let's see if
the image but I arrange their
are up-to-date or not
so using mass oh so we just in a we just
then
enable lessons to best only the critical
vulnerabilities
so they're so says the 11th from 0 to
free free every critical vulnerability
that means that the seventy two goal
lead ability
usually a system can get from
compromiser remotely
and we got your message to that Jack
given inability locally on the machine
to be more precise
so the to plot first place we in DOS
tell the lefties Windows and variety is
the
know the lefties mean us on the right is
Linux so you can see in Windows without
a
redial of total net ability is Terry lot
of a nice
the
more than fifteen or twenty but they
have like 50
critical vulnerabilities and
we know it is a beast like the Italian
say select the batter
butts the you know that I i under the
hundred of mushy innovate as at least
there
five of panic critical vulnerabilities
so we set up a date up to enough
original
a Windows machine cam Weaver 46 a
critical vulnerabilities and link so
we'd 11
and the possibly exploited the
the software and the
in in fight if you look ninety percent
of Windows
that and 50 percent W and I comical
weekly to cover your abilities
that's really an art saw sec on the butt
out a lot of a little bit it is a bit at
Morven
to where you are or even a free er's old
it means that
on the on the other than that what about
it energies
that guy with softer but is very
obsolete a
we also found 87 MIT at the damn I bit
can leave a note or SSH open SSL will
never be discovered in May 2000 8
where the films will never be due out at
the
vicki was not generate your own to me so
it was it possible to brute-force SSH
key and get access to the sea stems
so the message here is clear you know
you have to if used to be. midge in enid
or a cloud US you want to make sure bet
and I you bet she'd you updated
and you have to invest time in that and
you have to be able to do it
saw its not point-and-click we can look
at Model S O
we also lose can they're using time
movies
an SOA free I'll hope a source that
and about 20 850,000 senior to earth and
all the MIA's
enemy beat disc over to machine to
continue on their
and I Spy at oceana but was doing key
logging process monitoring data leakage
and other one was it was a browser spy
why
spyware stallini Internet Explorer so
the first one has been a
configuring with me so bad when it did
the taft at
like to Wellfleet that two weeks later I
check I so I'll
10 VC made as a problem so I started we
meet again and they found
a bet there was be set traditionally
styled
so probably think a guy SPC study
starlet pollution in the machine to put
the machine over to be a
cloud and wait for that somebody is
using it
instead the second one as not being
called freedom and money
saw a buddy's a false-positive love
gallery or the machine got infecting
during our experiment
in fact and every machine is around for
a one-hour
weave out having a firewall and a
Kb that if the machine its a it has a
lot of
complete a BTS can be there can be so
one hour
a you can get compromise that by eBay
told him
but we look at the
at the possibility that some machine
where connecting outside the
for sending for example outta the says
city that a private information
so we found 2 Linos server but where
using syslog NG to send blog
to a remote of that means that the you
rent a
you're into machine to use it and all
your dog get will be sent outside
be so no way would be sent to the USA
that way to a russia said it was
collecting logs from his machine
good
this is an interesting point is the fact
that
there when when a user rented MI is a
westerly before yes to
provide these public key to get access
to the MIA later on
so the what is very skier
risk is that users could leave the key
be idea making the
BAE Mitch the to and motley may just
Bobby
what does it mean it means that the
sicky
if you don't delay fees if you ski still
present
on their on the image then the guy but
there's a private key can vent connect
to your image
so the sicky to Novi major into
into backdoor basically so you have the
same problem
be for the midge account with salameh
somewhere
boss for the that have been there left
enabled
order some users might have been the
left enabled so
yea you have the you know we did
experiment on the 40 rejoin
and it came out that one machine out of
5 the kind we left over credentialed can
this can be able to pass what
as enable password in anybody who's that
we shall
or can be a SSH keys
and be set weed out to to the user
but there's a a very private key or no
there the
the username and password to access to
your machine so you or your entity is
serving a bit somebody as a
is connecting to yasser and then more
than 900
Caseys disallow a superuser a
privilege so leftover credential
is a security risk at the same time is a
privacy risk
why because a if I E if I ever
if you can see here about I we found
under red
and one machine that we've left over
pasta or
so what they can do work and their I
every sposato
I can pollute for spam okay I can invent
looking last login: see
who is the guy that approved the machine
and then I can try to use the same
possible art and
get access to their machine
Sobeys we bring us to the privacy risks
related to the use over I a service like
the Amazon ec2
so what's a problem probably is that if
the image
contain sensitive information these
would be available to
anybody with renting the air by okay
that make sense nor sought not only
customers have potential risk but also
the provider
it themself so we can use our the screen
a shell
for example to log into the server or to
start
installs overcrowded for free
so this is what we look your
so we look at the Forgotten keys
so we search among good all the major
for
a SSH keys
and for I'm odds-on as a API
keys so we find out a bit
and mean machine over to be a little
cloudy where containing get
and 56 private SSH keys
interestingly 5402 fixes ceaser we're
not even protected by pass phrase
okay so it's easy you know I think the
lab AP log
poll from probit thrower from the login
from bottle augment mean I every private
key
and embed the if I also collect 67
unprotected
Amazon a key is be so great because when
you have 10 the ski
you can that start to you can that by
Southee over Amazon Cloud so I can buy
two terabyte of data I can buy their
on and read the email G sir weaver et
64 core process on and the poor guys
paying for me
to be some not protected by password
still be so anything like that so
we Amazon issued other a future where
you can at least protect
your I was an API key with the password
are things we look look at the %uh
Shelly story
okay so the
order shall in Linux like bash
seashell their baby record everything
can if I know
so it makes sense to delete this fight
before you're you're prettier image of a
cloud over rice
somebody s arraigned miss teenage you
can get access to
your shell no things in fact be such a
problem
saw it in that we we're we find
a donde read the 695 us but we're
starting to date information on
for total 250,000 line of common the
story
so able to parse el two parts or all
them and the iPhone interesting things
for example look at this
meister my sequel ditto you know that
you can that you can use it
my sequel from Carmel and you can
specify username and password
you can say my seat where michael c you
but cook minus be
people Aust name
it to be. let a brother that at the same
problem bet you ever
I own a little ever pick a show when you
press meeting for me is testing from
issues in gay catholics that the post
use and use an impossible thing to get
beget we recorded in a blog about Bosch
but if the employer it is the same so if
I
crawl I can't crawl username and pass or
so like
I a caller I ES tracked fifty-eight crew
there shall in 30 of them
are for a remote machine soul of
companies have the the AM I had suffered
a lot easier with machine
so at their username apostle for first
in a remote machine
44 Amazonia yes sir Irvine Sedaris
for one at the ninety Dennis board I'll
take a few ICANN fee would be
that I'm danis for vlc else on
so the next question is okay not all
recessed informational left by
that though by providers so
what the provider should do should obey
the delete their data before a putting
be made on the cloud
yeah maybe yes so let's look at this
so let we said the MIA can be bound on
using different methods
at sold-out extreme debase for the
friend that oath
where wanna work at 5 °c stem
K so that means that it's just that
they're copy
of the top K like it just the cops
and white free O'bama work at their
block levered
for simple and utterly no exit BD work
at block level so you can say
base my eMachine okay
think he's machine put it on and I so
and then upload a guy who would have a
cloud
usually these processes that it works at
block letter
to all the block of my machine better
but I free a battle it out ok bye bye
the tubby got into a eyes on me
get uploaded so problem
problems that the block bays their
bonding Matt up
are vulnerable to file undulate up doc
so they remember the time of the time
when there was a Dolce
and that you and updating 25 because
there are no I task on
so you are doing air there but I most
def
del they were five and a shit
I they do if I okay what they do we have
it is it would recall if I do know if
I'd
is not over for it then you can
accommodate it is the same
so republish add to what we do bait
cleanup
the data you for publishing the midst
but they're don't their
white the free space
so what what we did weeee
yet select I mean we selected
thousand under Linux and ice roundly
we're on these ext undulate to
to covered it up we ended 828 you go by
tough the tough
as a week or five for 92 percent over
and ice
it so each MI contain other aged 20 see
from six to forty thousand the fis
at bad air and I so that even if I for
example where
about 33,000 finally in the be all end
all that i three
containing a images Microsoft office
document
war x-outs on and
I was on EDS certificate in OCT risky is
one issue before
the Sun 67 had been left
they forgot even to delete it the cities
that have been
be at 293 have been delayed about you to
call them
then we have a SSH private keys evite
wanna from an official Amazon image so
100 percent this is the key of a lot of
a guy we're keen on Amazon but
setup the machine then we have private
keys for PGP GPG
PDF document possible defies as on
better screenshot
fauna for a Calder process under under
Windows
at for temple yet I was in the air in
STP over to one of the match but there
ain't
you can see at the IP BC's ac2 at the IP
the machine for the seized under forty
seven forty blah blah
or entity in the eel last
so I about cities you know your your
study we don't date
to you just a call that mean you recover
about 9,000 fights okay
so we had a we are almost on a so you
get yes you've seen Matt
the this unloads on images
they have both security problems in both
privacy
problem the so let's look at the
at the security problem so you know that
their first employer
one out of five apiece images have a cam
Weaver some enable
account ought to be some SSH public
installed
so suppose but now the attack you want
to locate
the scheme age K so me me for same price
it up in E major
I E I add some credential kale some key
so I uploaded
and then I'm wat I wait so I went with
somebody is using it
so even very is a like a even a star
like a client or
it's something that they're when the
mich start me back
and even the VIP only to be which is
running so I know which is why well
whatever they can connect to 111
of ok and it will what they can do I can
use that
I can try to match and
all the VIP's on their own got the space
of ballots on
to my Mike at a local 5,000 machine
are gonna do it I can do it they can do
it they're using a perfect solution
pretty much another perfect solution
that is based on the SSH
or ski calm Capricorn matching
order can use approximate solution like
air service banner and web on their
what does it mean it mean fat
what we need to be scared all the Amazon
IP range okay
the soviet art about 60 and red that
650,000 eyepiece
and their out of the 60 and over at
233,000 running in style so out all the
all the armored on their
IP space may have they're using about
one-third
of it K time so obvious 233,000
your stance but they're running there
are 113
about 50 percent bet that where that
that
SSH enabled K so we are at
means machine and if they have the same
is not
field so for this one we can use ssh
met-art so it doesn't mean that we we
using 'em-up
them up we saw before at the beginning
but all ok
we collected a fingerprint over ssh
and then we match peace fingerprint that
we've fingerprinted
and over different over different 5,000
machine that we scanned
and we had a perfect match want one for
a while
point 65 percent of his number let these
about that
but his 20,000 machine I'll 2000 machine
two for two thousand mushy talk for two
thousand eyepiece
we have the perfect match so I a very
know which kind of for Amazon MI is
Ronnie
any final with you fees I was a.m. eyes
runny as a some backdoor installed
I can login if a regulation then of
course if you look at the south of Bend
County date
we have a percentage bettys why they are
if you look at 10 to 50
different a nice it's why that's the
lead
is that Dane County this you can easily
feel that one EP can be one of the stand
him I E
you can easy test all 10 so it's not
not a big issue they have a free ever to
matching their system we have one is
based on Sirius
so we look at be only the open ports the
new Baseer be it is running and diverse
shown
every make sure to bat its Besim off 10
fwy
a.m. I bet we have in the catalog and
the last one is being on the web OPP
pitying start so we look at deep ready
for a table with Bob different able web
server
we try to match davir VIP's with MI
based on this information okay so I
would say that
during our experiment we wear only thing
called early ballots on
a
at security team verdi did a great job
so a little later so sometimes I don't
that feedback
from a the different provide their arse
an hour Friday for from endorse is that
Amazon did a great job
so when we contacted them about to be
hit by repost or in public keys but we
found on the
on the set eighty percent of the veggies
at that 1200
so they give them released over 2012 the
MIAC containing some forgotten
credential so what made either they
immediately contacted the all the
clients
seeing a guy said be made you are
running gear contain some credentials
so make sure you remove either way say
at the back door
and the then a beer is the public polity
new
me after and the change we started with
terrible level MI from a public to
private so that
nor more user can arrange the same I
medical about them a second time
about to be left over at the time so the
fact that about a lot of the image eason
and
where the guide published the metaphor
go to delete that they don't like the
study fight
sold out a lot of clay shaw all water
now some private message key saw Ramadan
API keys
soviet it is within 5 days a tutorial to
webcast live to shatter the public
images in a secure manner
ikat onto Shari'a public image okay baby
AB de Tierra Nashotah your sensitive
data
first for physical doesn't have it again
about a gift problem
all but according to lately the term
where you can air
on delay to delete advice so baby fight
our finest immediately rather than out
some anything over the fence a mice
had to see I'm what's the problem
bad and if it makes a is to have changed
bounding sees them
to to to make sure that it's not
possible to
undulate data from the hard disk get
so what we learned here we don't have
apt
if we want to use the cloud a best ways
to prepare your own image
I know it take time you know you have to
install the major you have to configure
late but many tea or
you know any if you want to a really
around a major although the cloud for a
long time
don't trust wanna be made better feiger
just spend maybe one day to go if you
are already made
and your down because if you buy the
Nativity sphere
then will tell you that the
configuration of I
all for little tom cat he's okay we'll
tell you that there
and all the software is bets currently
who tell you that
there are no problems so
steal if you want to use one of these he
made you have immediately update the
software
over twice especially if it's a Windows
machine because we know machine with no
fire on a public IP
we've there
50 critical vulnerability get exploited
in 10 minutes
give to regenerate this is a tall skis
to prevent the name
mock being between a running your stance
and I if great any user password is
sage keys JV configuration file serious
you plan to run
check for suspicious connection on we
have to do all this
the so if you if you plan to release a
public image
then use if I base by the mechanism so
that nobody else can recover your data
David you deleted
or shredded necessity fights invalidated
any
their locks and history any three fights
before
putting be made online so
erode just two reference you can vent
don't know there's lights or
no hurry to copy them so decided to
I so when we could at Amazon eBay
they've rotor
up to
bossed on there will be solve this
problem first one is all too
sharing is public MIT secure manner miss
a call
the second one is that in mind their own
about separately sharing the using
public and I
so this is a call could joint worker
the I'm you know among me and
a jonatha doc I read about that I'll
keep the ending and in Keokuk IA
in savage or I work with them it in a
a new to come last year and we also
publish a paper on this topic
name the proceeding overconfidence
couple more fickle
so MVP pottery to what you have there
there are actually all
faced by the weedy them select 10 pages
of details on the problem
so maybe for interesting he swore to to
read
okay that's all i/os pretty fast
saw you have time for a question on for
coffee
to work over before a final keynote
I think we can go for some questions if
you're up for it so yes you won't have
any questions from Argo
top with
when was the did that notice about
public keys in in
in a beast that was quite some time ago
wasn't it
the first problem by the public in I
think it was in September
October last year he and Outback
I wondered why all of a sudden they
started looking at that one so
think I yeah i'd get the notice from
from man is on cell
okay and now I know why hey you could
there is good reasons to have II
deployed training machines in the cloud
and there is a good reason to have a
public key on there so that students can
actually log into those machines
sure to share them talented
yeah in this case that uses
sort of nullified I have it make sense
to me know if you have any made you want
many people use the C major
you have to something better lead their
at of course
e be home the sophistication of a lot of
the mines the people
creates with homebrew and you know of
and very
heterogeneous how did your research
and find sorry the optimize the
fisherman's
to Microsoft's optimized image Amazon's
that might imagine simply
they understand you almeda suitor in
other words
and I don't I think for me miss we're
we r rightly afraid have other people's
you know home created public game eyes
for from
all these reasons but how bout Amazon's
image have at Microsoft optimize image
use you know there's it by five or six
an better put out
night into the marketplace you know by
third parties but I
the primary you know vendors or
impacting this region folks
I'll get she asked me the old the
marketplace but I'd image provide by
Amazon
itself byee individuals are my third
parties
you ask me for a reason de France among
the my wife are somewhat but are more
vulnerable
dollars actually hope you're gonna tell
me that Amazon Microsoft
optimize Harding images did much better
yeah
me we didn't make it de France because
we don't be they want to say al Madani
skid a steady provide that Microsoft is
bad or provide a CE skid
you know we tried to look a partially to
all of them
but the very sexually make sense that
the image provided by your
without wifi surely provide are probably
more secure than
arse so I know that there is this site
at the called it's called cloud
market like care
if they don't remember but when a
actually the user can
can say okay I try BC made in UK
I they can give some star so that a mark
they can give a both from one to five so
they can say
5 this is a good one is like a Google
for the rest on you know you want to go
to a restaurant you check me out to say
I did a lot of people teeth wrestling
skewed
so they've something similar for the
cloud market Obama done
say suggest that too to use the Site
just google internet like
proud market Amazon ranking and there
you can before using any made you can
check me out what the people safe
nobody say nothing maybe you better use
another one
yep Perth
you said you were contacted to the
security team of
a missile and the juror had an
indication that a
detected you before because sure comes
to machines to start scanning them
so would look like suspicious activity
see i
asking Eve when a cantata them they knew
that we had a the
testing BAM no Ashely
I
air be good things that I was there
working peace officer to lob and there
we have it was a bit lower
experimentally while
asking before like a cat thank we
started we did that they asked me
Stanley was she in there
and and they didn't the
everywhere not aware what we're doing
and the Nikkei speeding company
and when we come back to them they say
the the latter really thankful in the No
they have a way really kind to either
say I'm a great fan thanks a lot
so positive feedback is to let the guy
Kompany probably you cannot run a such
that it cannot this data scanning a
650,000
ipsa are using am absolutely the that's
about it
and overpriced have a place you'll be or
the company
but until you don't to break into sees
them in TDOT mission we test that the
machine a bit we r ain't
his PC 35 experiment and we pay for them
so all you know weepy so we we read
machine eighty
for us on for us that we pay them BBB's
machinist enemies machine
in very close down anything machine to
so we did
earth that nobody at the end of the day
yeah
pay her any more questions from our Go
no okay
well Marco I want to thank you very much
for your talks yeah thanks to you guys
go put the enjoy