the
me
the title over next talk is browser bug
hunting in 2012
please give a warm welcome to Roberto
Tsuji
leave it on thanks everyone thanks for
coming to stall
ano yes must meet I 4 p.m.
I'll try to be as much as entertaining
it's possible must be introduced many
mismatches G Ronnie
and the research to talk him into the
gonna do today
have has been done with Scott Bell it's
Michael E
unfortunate gonna make it so I'll try my
best to do
um the part of his position as well so
when we come
we both work for secure this has not
come it's on security company now
based museum we do also have office in
Singapore
and we both our principal security
consultant
I'm I have a blog so sometimes
time to time publish my search unblock
manage not that
and yes so what's the agenda for today
I'm the person tissue structures be
simple it's basically
three different points on his
introduction and then
are doing the shopping and conclusion
also all good so that action soon but
the
the main core the presentation is the
window shopping is like
going through all the bikes that we
found as part of his research
and it's kind of shopping experience
like we've built which by Vince like
going for shopping it's like it when the
shop and which bike is now in the shop
and
as part of the process old shuttle will
share with you some fun
and pain of farm it's going back to try
to exploit them
and of course which bike I'll try to to
do like them all Socialist International
I would choose
Tiger process well its parsley because
everyone use
ransoms and is a lot of Technology
shifting into the client-side
and once you find a bug in a browser
that's
the circle back because is affected so
many people so we leave with me to the
approach of Palm
like wide angles like wouldn't even just
published a memory corruption bites but
also other kind
bytes and when I say other kinda bounces
injection attacks
and also trying to defeat our security
controls Nebraska like same origin
policy
and it is something that you would see
as
swim okay let's get to know
to the columns and patient just want to
be based rate so that start
shopping I'm yeah pretend you're then
look at the window shop you see them
said the look and the shoes on the banks
with them
you could look at the local so the
Browns so the first one auto today's 25
folks use of the pre
there was found by Scott bed and the
on excluding a bus police training at
some
memory corruption Mike and has been
fixed
5-foot-11 it only works in Windows 7 and
we like to rate kinda party vendor
response with acts you 25
and his street because it took so long
for them to fix it
it's a very long trade if you check the
bike the Line train
is by think long time because once you
know the votes that we struggle to
understand the bond
and trying to to find the the fix for
the back but they fix it so that's
that's the time
so the approach we took two to to find
his back was to use
across ponds so cross part is a public
school has been developed by
Michael unsolicited and basically that's
scandal bomb to which can be used what's
miles but what was done in this case
whilst modify that
tweak it a little bit and I'll show you
what what's done
so what kind of these
what kind it is but what typist is this
pop stand is a memory corruption my hand
might produce the use of two free I'm so
the use of the free
ok years when the top is trying to use
onto the memory which has been freed
in his case is a chine which has been
pre you can see in the written this be
should be though
the fee fee fee fee is the partner which
spurred that
by the Montreux to identify the picture
which has been freed
and then you see the call I'm on the
bottom
and is trying to call the pointer which
has been freed
and of course that might be different
behavior so
thus of the mic boschman these workers
or he might actually be a big difference
I suspect that way
so in this case we try to get course try
to get them
to execute cold from from the corruption
by so what kinda modification we did
across parts
um what you see on the right side
despite the power meters
which about the prospects and dissolved
by means which can be changed
so one on the main change was to
increase the entropy when fighting with
my meters
you passing prospered and get the
modification with it will remove the top
of
garbage collection function and and then
also in the HTML template which is
passed across parts
um another major change was to set the
document doc sign mold
on which is basically like setting the
content and people
up option but for each and HTML elements
on
so that makes the entire page to be
editable
and with those changes we actually not
is the word
other crashes we couldn't find without I
mean those teams
let's play interesting and that that
spot to the modification
other modification with done is some
basically I created this tool which is
like a Python script
and college to mention and what it does
is it creates
like convey complex aged him out by and
support aged about 50 for
and so what we did this combined tease
at complicit in 15 across parts and see
if we could achieve different results
the other thing which we noticed there
was cause some problems that you have to
wait that the page is loaded
completely times the the dole if
um the fighting starts before the pages
completed
then he will always keep different
results safe have a crush
you you my end up that you can reproduce
the crash anymore
so we had to do some some kinda changes
and other things we need is like
you have different faces in cross pazzo
we try to come down so on the
the PC with which we didn't want to have
and as you can see this cation that we
just left
like tweet properties she's a function
which just last changed on the
properties of each defendant's
so kinda from mounting that and
took a long time to to get it working
and then we have the crash so the next
thing which we did it was to minimize
the crash because we were using a very
complex HTML
assess the full in cross parts performs
thousands of Thomas pit operation
against the bomb
on the page so hmm
the problem will stand for me how many
and which Thomas keep the operational
are performed but crossbar so that on
the Cali plates train
the develop of my folks a station the
Fifers as tensions sounds cold day is
long
so useful if I put sanctions in five
books
and then what happens is that you run
Jays low can dump
all the CHA mosquito operation performed
by the cross-party
and the way to do that is basically
there's a local
lock function you scenes patient and you
create art custom event
the dome and basically JS love is
waiting for the custom you went to
to treat them and when the lock function
is
call by cross parts it just initiate the
event
that is lock is waiting for at the Los
the content of
the operation that allow us to actually
make a hugely so tell us a bit operation
performed by cross but
and that's part of the many months in
the test case
I'm so love a lot of time spent many
months the state's case
and just might going by consistency
still run the five folks
a touchdown can see people still
crashing by making modification on the
HTML template
and the reducing the Dallas peeps as
well and that took a long time
and then of course the result is after
month
is to get to simplify test case as
simple as possible
where instead of thousands of people
pray she gets few jobs
integration instead the you change them
a fight you
facing 1
so this is the premier concert that i'm
gonna show so busy that to fight some
old
one is the pond not HTML page and then
if you guys can actually see him
try to make the suspicious people as
possible
miss you wanna Dusty's opens our child
our window and the child when the which
you can see now
it's basically a simple HTML file with
the form an input type file
what the parent das he opens the Chinese
owns time
then there's %uh settimeoutfunction and
his case Duclos
which triggered after two two sects and
then
it clicks on the simplified
from from the parent and any clothes
that though the chart
to make the space simple and just try to
picture
so pint sponsor a child the parents then
calls the file
clicks on the fall that calls in windows
to spawn the file open dialog
and then the pint trying to close the
child
why the file opened: I love it still
open that creates the crutch
they seem to be simple to understand but
wanted to get to that conclusion
spent six months the
andthe was not I'm and
remember this call spending a lot about
this
so that analyze what happens in the
crash so what use is a use of two free
it's obvious and is the screen should
I'm
based on the crash on the proconsul to
show and
I can you see the diet call although eat
free
on the trunk which has been freed I'm
another interesting thing is stock frame
yeah the moment to the patch
so want would we noticed here is that
the yellow part
is all like multi land functions and
then but what he knows is on the tall
which is the last function which have
been called before the crash
it's all Windows Live is the user 32
should too and then the crash occurs in
the
sahl wapi
it kinda indication that something was
wrong with Windows
rather than five
so the conclusion is this is kinda race
condition but because
it's not that much reliable because it
depends
Hall the timing which is used to close
on the child when the
and mascot is working and Blaze thats
I'm trying to to work on a bed the
proconsul
but for now I'm I'm gonna show me the
code execution on this but
but that the is disabled so I'm not
trying to defeat any
memory security protections and
of course the thing which we we we are
doing is to
tried to make his bottle so a I think
that's the thing which are not his son
looking the column
um our website these are hard to go
about
keeps playing and so the technique that
the main point of that party police
that you have to get your peeps pray as
precise as possible
to to actually bypassed some 160 members
its protections
so we're still not in that stage but I'm
I guess
thats interest in surely many try to
like them on this from now
so that my five what's Heights cm
and and the debugger is attached
want to show the form is them
to tease them is the child
and again deserve the same one that you
saw before
but I want to show in this is a little
bit different from the 1i should
from soon
romance on
spins so that this is the aunts one
so what's happening year is some is the
sprain
simple space Spain stun
and then the do close function its
I'm making the click on the on death to
win this which are open
so that two children before I say there
was only one
we had to create two windows in this
case is
just show you all complexes to to
trigger the crash
sent this case though though win the
second Windows
is a pic then the spray ok use then on
the other win the another click
and then close though the first win the
and that's what happens
so I'll try see if it works doesn't
crash was what I like
on fight I'm see crush up to so that's
that's why with so struggle to
understand what's going on
and to 20 make a better exploit
hopefully that works now
so this is some yes CC the file opened
items
on knife a check here ish issue that you
see the crash
but disease is failing failed because
um in deep space we put that these am
but on
sorry we should see the reference August
right running games
if forget like
to that is you see the fascia game
doesn't doesn't really triggered
now is just calling nothing on training
if anything again eighties by
see it it's it's also my butt saying
thanks for the field to
no doesn't work China love them
no the word yes Missy what's happened
here was about to
said the back when and then me just
poems the
talk politics in since the tape is
disabled and he would just takes a cue
the
spread acted
alright time to introduce another other
buds so
um is the bike I found maxim that the
for months
this is on two days no I'm releasing
five with them
and those aren't parched are for the
latest version
so the many responses to your own five I
send the report to them and trying to
chase them no response
and they've been 11 new releases
since I Sanders who to talk to them one
by will sign in to fix
so on the side of time nonstop two days
I in the box the approach it was
complete different up
and in I didn't do any fighting you it's
more like looking for injection points
and
the type a bike is arm different type
about which
im is can be found in Branson its cool
cross confiscating ball
costs on scripting is like a definition
which was used in some box
they were found in turn inspired 34
years ago and also in five folks
when you have injection the chromosome
which is the trusts on in five firms
so amazing if you what's cross halted
scripting means
%um kind of cross site scripting but
between two different zones
one is on trust and like internet and
then
the other one which is trusted and when
it's a process them
Rasool preached zone which at access to
APIs
so just to give you some example like if
you see in the bottom
five folks is not chrome across got
chrome
all-pro all-pro and much since the
payments
com slash slash is all previews
branson's
so what that means
if you're in that zone if you have to
ask it running that some
you cannot sis all the Intel APIs like
you can talk to the fight system you can
talk to the operating system you can
access book months you can do things
which are
to reply P pitched so I've done some
research on the past like cum in October
2008 to release these
all process getting to the operates
three a page
in Mike's blog posts to mislead just
some
all the Sri and Sandhill when it did
that
in full disclosure I'm three people
jumped into
discussions say I is the only thing you
can do
just read the story and other time I was
in Williams understanding what I was
doing
essay yeah that's that's what it's all
and
so-called if this I say it well UN
you're in opera config so
sewing you're not a race to say
something you should be able to do
something more
and so the two guys the funny bone re:
prop
in and turn them in the discussion that
you have helped
in the final weights basically jump from
the %ah pastry into the Opera
config and then change the Branson
configuration
and that could in the get code execution
so
there was quite shocking for me because
I thought of I just found the process
given them no
turn out to be a code execution which is
I'm
but shocking but at same time there was
a lesson learned
so I didn't want to the same state now
months them
and other research amino is $5 for
pendants
with my colleague Nick Freeman and the
main point of
research was to find box in the five
folks this station and dance
an injection in tolls result into the
five folks
chrome trusted zone: and then again you
that code execution and anything about
this
kinda boxes to exploitation like its
under percent reliable because
it is no memory corruption by his and
layer 7 is duplication the
any john was if we took its three during
that song
will would be relied again this
total do but not my about months in so
these
developed by in China smuts information
and it's kind of hybrid
browser because his support both though
3 at recently out engine
and also the what kid and basement I
focus of these browsers
just performance and giving extra extra
features the user's
so according to Mike some that's a lot
of people using it I
130 means users phi and that means the
lone 2010
but the the I think the most interesting
part this discourse that uses speech
and these branches just pops in
performance
and if you go to the h2 meant this
website is course more points and crawl
so this is just a few min feature that
them Chinese not tryin
to get there but also more more
performing then
stand the Browns so it is the Bison
gonna percent today
I'm some it's a different things so the
crust on this campaign which I've just
been through this before
in three different much mean for
different points and then the other box
which is some
all mention about so chaining all these
bikes together
he gives me me find a different way to
get code execution
and his bros so let's start with the
first
your thing so this is some that's an
interesting one so
you have that you can do the injection
after the location not ash
the rent part you see that it's my
malicious payload
that militias paid its friend into the
um
about easley again that something
basement to the opera
history but my phone but the most
important thing is that
that Palin its render it
India multi-story then the malicious
page not %eh
mm dust a redirection from the internet
to be a multi-screen to trigger that
content which has been injected
than other way that's the second who
they I'm
to ISS like injection is possible in the
titling conscription type
and in months and you can preview SS or
you can be
subs you can plus subscribe so both
components are vulnerable to the same
the same but book once so
you have a book might think that say
okay
and you see the %um these nothing wrong
with you and the promise on the title
and on the left side something that you
don't see these my injection
that injection would be rendered into
the bookmarks its own
which is kinda minutes
and then you have other but still like
much lost people to
for months so you can launch other
excuse the balls so it's kinda feature
for them so they fit to window open
seemed the 32 the Dixie if popup
is not lot seemed he would be called
and then you have from same origin
policy bypassed like come from when the
often you can tactical fine I'm so
that's that's
chaining his battle to get the key me
all
I'm response another
thing which iPhone yesterday which was
shocking so many for when you still
might stand
he would redirect to this page I might
not come
and whatnot is that when you go to that
page
and then if you get sincere but I'm
there are two tops last visit the pages
and most powered what most miss the
Pirates
so these pages on the internet any
displaying information which I in
and no to my brother which a new up wat
page on the two should never be able to
to retrieve people to read and that's
the problem
and if you see him though I just
launched the spektr you see them
that too I'm when the the Mozart one is
to run time:
and the other one is much the these
objects are
prearranged and they allows you to
basically interrupt he opens his temp or
the Browns
so the Bankia it's interesting because I
might stand up comics of trust in the
main
and it's the only to mean words such
dome up to its can be are available
soul the thing is
these no control the resolution on
though domain name
so and these nice a South somebody for
sale which to be
so basically what it's possible to be
done is the man in the middle like if
these and DNS poisoning
you can resolve I might sum up come to
another I P you control
and then you can have to ask if invoking
such objects and then
compromise the Houston or you can
compromise the use and
or HDPE using money she's probs or
if you're across escaping into the area
website months on the comp again you can
totally compromise the use and
and now it's time for I'm them
michael's that
it is the maximum us click on this
morning I on
and that's the patient is known the
legislation's
version that I use for them but also the
latest version is for mobile to
to the bites military so this is the
first 1i show it is the
injection the about his three-page so
you think that
and just show you what's happening years
some
I'm injecting after location ash and
what I'm doing I'm using the month stern
Dom up to and then on creating
allows you to create files so you create
a temporary find
create test but and and then when I do I
write something inside
which is same the kadu and then I launch
the file which is and just create is
possible just using
the dome just does and
no sewn onto speaking year but not busy
though was
just for the user to go to a web page
and exploit with to you don't want them
to is what happens so you click the
its own you see two shows because
mushroom the injection accused two times
and a multi-stage
so the same bill would be treated twice
and this is the page which is
basically doing the redirection you and
I need to do that because
and meets the user's at the ball stupid
to TT sweet so that
the injection is treated and teases the
injection you know
see vintage me too Smyth skip 9
you
spend these three item yeah you can see
him
you can't injection so when I'm doing in
injecting you know
a picture the beach in never gets loaded
and then based on the rule there's the
event and the
then triggers the the malicious
javascript and
accuse here also on the link pot so
that's why you see two
tune shows morning right up close
is a casing one
is the RSS
so on the shoe fits with the game
is just showing I'm not subscribe to the
RSS just previewing
the content and
that's it so the picture is here Nana
click here and
just flew to a concert he's showing me
when I am
and that's what I said before the MX is
approved its own
jealous people cures here and then again
you can call
the pre which API's you can do whatever
you want you can also
not subscribe see if he wants is a game
so that is a different model no much
since a few subscribe to you
and that's a that's on then change the
feeds all put a new entry
and you can compromise the user whenever
the feed checks for new update
it's funny you know
thinkin he could do
there's a story about this so I left my
am
might sandals Bay tied the left months
and
running with the ISS open and the the
morning after I wake up and it's so like
20 shells
so put it does is lay he keeps checking
for updates
but he keeps reading the same article
even the old one
so the injection occurs every time so
was still spawning shells and
yells I couldn't believe it which i
think you know
must be shipped in Civ confirm know if
it is considered
as all the shows the I
was amazing for them the myriad
right let schools
this from
that's another one so this page you go
to this page
with promise you to obvious follow it to
%uh the bookmark
the problem is not here this is what
Penn the province yes a
noticed is some cool and then if you go
on the left
that's and this was the problem
so you can put your injection there on
the left side and then you can put some
pop into
to actually fall the user to click OK
when the user click OK then
you click here and now in snow
John the basically what happens is when
you click on the book months
The Expendables launch and they said its
yeah I read again you you compromise
much choice not working
and the last night is this means a is
the page
announcement to I'm this dot com K
is the pay now I'm I'm
I'm assuming that my DNS has been
compromised and I might standpoints
same website up this page saudis in this
case
locals safe I do I am i stone
on you on the same page that's the
problem
like it's a thrust into me it doesn't it
doesn't matter
will IP's was hoping to and
is just have to beat I much not come out
on
document the main and if you see
chechyan that somebody website but its
resolving to my local lost is no aged
yes
nothing and why the share this porn is
that if you look at the word the source
William and thats that's because I'm
using the script and I'm just
legitimately calling the month still not
be reached bombing PI
and that's why what's and
that that was shocking seriously I'm
gonna believe this from
might
commit to the station let's keep
shopping for months
is that almond blossom thats different
one another Chinese bounce from
and I'm not dropped read delays here you
know
watched as well is the same sorry see
all 5
the Venera rating response tried to
contact them
I actually need there is a form so you
have to subscribe to the fall
if you do them right never before you
have to 10
you have to send 10 posts to be able to
contact the Ministry
then once you have denise is a content
then it tried to find a security
conference
the game in that so I send the report
and then
say okay thank you that'd then they
chased them said the
can you can give me a response or
something nothing
so again and only release all these bags
um
dizzy interesting because a is another
kind of hybrid but also so the
that two missions one is the light one
is new to me
to light is based on i you need to have
the internets platoon to
Island France the you to meet you you
might actually apply folks or chrome as
well
wanna from be funny from the FAQ pages
they
isn't process secure browsing and the
response
say yes on buses secure since is based
on the transport
on buses CQ as infants born kinda fun
dedicating
security to the other Bros but that's
that's not true
and
just to give you some starts I just
checked and although com
his brothers stopped 26 millions noles
and Donald dot com has got more almost
like chrome
I all scan indication to me that's
that's used against and and its
the its me probably nation preventing
china so little bit hollywood's
when in office when I launch it is that
I'm the main point is Devon Bostick seem
and then he will I'm call by putting I
for the nazis not though
real five times the Dixie that you have
in your system he seems to be that
corrupt nation
and it's under the it under the oven
ransom folder application
and then you seen the other side the
knife you can read but there's some
numbers
so integers the past arguments the five
first not exceed
so it is showing the kind of a hybrid
approach they took so they have Island
on the top and then call iPhone so
that's he would just be modified to work
with Holland
and the other interesting stuff which I
noticed that the ISM
Rs resources oldham inside that there
are some fights
souls trying to mop response to
privileged branson sons
and I found that on the PPN is is
matching bra so home
all ice RSS top dps is mentioned by some
locals
wanna not just these pages use of this
function which is
AF run command and their functions
be reached so they can only be use in
those pages or in the bouncer
I'm brosser call specials on
have been trying to test his functions a
look but see what he does
and it's very difficult because
a few days if you try to try and catch
should try to catch
gyro on that function like you pass one
argument
and you see what happens there is no
error but
these countries undocumented you can't
find any reference on the internet about
this function
and it seems to me like that it's an
internal function which is
I want doesn't want to put any
documentation about but what an artist
in these pages which come by default
is that like if you provide exits he
doesn't really have an integer
as the item into that function he will
contain all the story
so and then try blindly to understand
what what you can do with the function
so it's ready for my niece and like you
for past three we just pawns on empty
time
all if you passed 10025 I would just
search
for the IQ meant that you used so it's
kind of interesting stuff but I couldn't
I'm get away times than if I could
achieve code execution
so you know the box I'm same origin
policy bypass in the process homes on
and then again cross confiscating
nussbaum and stalk assess getting
into the feed reader
is the pool a concept on the least three
stealing which owns them about
and you have a night free market is %uh
page on the internet you have an iframe
the iframe point to the Browns home then
you create a reference
I'm with when the I'm from the win the
don't want to
and you point to the iframe and then and
then BC you call back to that special
function
any words too busy to pull to bypass a
symbolic importance
this case as you can see in person sixty
thousand three that's the thing about
you
for the for these three
okay so it is the same but am
see me in two months them but different
injection point
so instead injecting on the location
arch in I want
inject from the title the page you are
visiting
save that the time others like that you
a.m. then you can escape
and put your a injection them then when
the user go to the bus home page
Inc takes on the tops though for the
street
injection is threatened
and then again I says the same stuff
months from now on
you into over this but the same even the
same time it is a more noble
its titling conscription socialism
some them as well
yet this is a game use it goes the page
in them
display tokyo's so this is done
is mainstream just got one item but
that's not showing you that
from a page from I'm on Facebook com
I'm just reading these three and that's
that's kinda though
the problem with his bronze I'm not
going to them on the other two months
because
I'm thinker no time
call okay its keep going on the back
which have found
on five-foot is mean but some time ago
but it's worth mentioning is because
it's part of this research we have been
doing
trying to find my cousin is was funded
by folks
so clearance sale because been fixed
amend responses 305
I'm don't think which they define and I
know why they say that almost a month
realistically developer I'm not
tied together at that rectified but and
another didn't want to change so
projects till then and the way that his
bike was found is
because we found it for months and I
don't and one guy one
and land development was complaining the
same all that strange to you
found but speak some following all the
guidelines from the dealer
all did you find about all all that was
possible
so the promises
some dysfunction which is the and is
this Keith by and give each tenant
past pregnant dysfunction issues
and recommend the moment Salem to feel
to it
on trust H two men Palin so that's a
given and owns
and you won't get instant right the page
from the internet
use this function defeated the
page and and then do things with you and
them
so that their homes he should be no you
can see an example I get paid to
paper this year on trust the aged women
and then you have fragment
and then you basically use the past five
minutes function to feed to the paid-up
the result of that its feet with so we
should be safe to use
in the context of the AM so I'll site
out I was be clues about the comment on
the development and it's okay let's
let's try it but say that paid off his
the pain and you see that test and then
there's a script
and then run the past by the conscience
the result
and then see that the only things which
remains tests busy removing on-screen
because I gain if you haven't
and I was getting junction in 25 folks
chrome sohn
again you can do things like on
execution
so skip this shipped out which is good
but then it from the slate
deformation the painted but instead of
putting
a straight script inside the H two men
paid
and say what if we have Charles keep
into the 8 Ref
a tribute to Kristen's don't that is
that strip
I'll just the fifth and my phone is that
nah Street
up and that Spain just because if you
have that kind of condition then if the
user clicks on that evening
then the Dallas peeps which is that
would be executing the five fox.com
and then again you can get code
execution a show in
them all from that and them that we
fumble the ball and the game was
complaining about
you so it is some
is the wheat SS is he on on the left
side and
is the money supply cesspit so your
money
lignin feynman setting up listening part
until six and then
you see disney's in touch he cleats on
that
case on that and then stir the
investment and is the example
on will not be getting a 5-foot send
them since
it's interrupting the crumbs on you can
do pretty much whenever you want
this case nichols' the loading and I'm
an executable and then execute the walls
connecting back to see missed an
important
Jan other one over yourself it is moles
to meet him
it some memory function my and
it's a clearance because they couldn't
find exploit and
been responses 15 it's plain to see
because I
ascend the report of and say okay thank
you but
you is not the security issue because
you're not providing the exploit
and it's a a and said okay
I'm can you and me can you can you
should be back in Siebel so I can
understand what's going on
say no became can you shape
if um if it is exploitable so they went
by
they did the analysis in this state is
not exploitable
but then the think I say but if you find
the exploit
please let us know minutes and no if you
say that these
mondex pondimin then don't spend any
time to understand
if I can find this point and scandal
fade because
there was something I found the SBG
phone
by nope no so this game released report
opposite you don't have the export
sinisa but the guy
after six months from the exploits and
release it in full disclosure
so that's by famed problem so the bank
was found I'm
can abuse noone buttons and I'll show
you
and I if you can read for me tried to
them
basically it's is a simplified this case
on the bottom there's only to HTML
element and
what I'm doing with the Dallas peeps is
basically
clone the options and them as he removed
the art
Upton and then to append the reference
in this is done
like com four times and it's done on the
first
each the amendment in the n1 and
and then I do us I Spain and that causes
the crotch
explain to see information I can find it
spawned try to share that with other
colleagues and friends
the within the Queen fine but its but
both
to to mention and North Sea for it
we have to be there as well
yet this is dumb not showing year the
painted
so these are the two each tournament and
then you have
I'm crash function
and his what's happening stranger call
on the options from
begins hearings
like clung on to every moment up to man
up and reference
and base in his book just calling
some on the methods all that you can
call against nom nomz
in the page like long known remove time
and then upended
so against is a
simplify this case is my else could I
wrote for futzing
opera was more more complex was doing
more more operations
so in order to get the city's bond was
not it's not that easy
so you're not touching the bag into
opera and then just launching of against
them
that this case
and his the page and I'm in CA but then
you can see the fee fee
so opera Greece its use of defeat but
again
doesn't just say that's a crash but they
didn't fix it there was fix
in my 11 don't 52
alright last section on dawn the
presentation it some
really minor bugs but still pulling the
points that
I'm cross confiscating computer book
months and
immersion in both Firefox and Opera the
five folks
on is but it's been kinda that's been
reported by someone outside
try to find by order to qualify as a
reference but it's thought that is being
you
I'm gonna show me now doesn't work
anymore from 5-foot-11
won the nobel that is
also leads mention so
the approach here was lookin injection
in and from the book months
see what I could do if someone um
we assumed someone as the malicious
bookmark some
his back is nothing new disease be
reporting like seven years ago but this
guy
Michael cracks my two months Eelam
basically say all
shouldn't alone John askew right scheme
to be bookmarked people
but the stories that Chalis ki Uribe
scheme has been invented
for that purpose to be book-marking so
that there was a kind of bomb
discussion mountain I'm so let's say the
username
book months the militias bookmark what
happens um
that changes so what happens is that um
we may have a universal process getting
so
as to the use is on Jimmy and then
clicks on the militias bookmark
what happens that you might have to ask
it running into the complex on Gmail
that what happens
that's that's the impact of this problem
even worse
let's say they use instead of being on
Gmail com is on a prop Brian
on um trusted or previous branson's on
like offer outcall conflict then the
Janoskians
runs into opera config and then you can
get code execution
and that's what I'm not sure the resume
racing this point
is even if you require the use the
multiple steps there are things you can
do like
come you can fool the user like you can
for the status bar
you can spoof your own bar so you can
spoof all the new user interface
controls
which also uses to make a decision
whether to bookmark or not something
lost jospin can be compressed can be
awful skated
still to the average user you might just
say
yet bookmark it admitted so
against Islam old sure a couple times
Ben I hate is the guy
who created tells keep your eye and I
found this discussion because he was
involved
and say there's nothing wrong with using
janowski you it's in chrome
what's good for content is good for
chrome often enough but is completely
wrong
and the whole show in right now and it's
time to me
I'm the open
you can
is the problem so I've to sling and I
don't know if you guys can see on the
bottomless
on this age to be dot dot who will not
come on the stumps by
for right click then I bookmarked and
is the only thing which the user sees if
the user speaking this action is going
to click OK
if uses cable has not checked for the
address
and this is obviously is is not Google
com
is something else so i cant is read by
multiple steps
so
the same you same technique that's used
sometimes you may have even the
from the window hopes calling the part
of
the UN bar so it's even more difficult
for use let's assume new users say okay
know that and so the book once known
is year in on the Google the problem
just raising is this
so they say the uses here and is doing
the stops money for the bus and then
that's why different steps then clicks
in that what happens that's that's upon
because the task it will
accusing the Opera conflict the Opera in
this case what I'm doing is
change in the preference for the
software the
me softer and then do every direction to
the made to
your eyes came so made to winning book
cathodic seems that the pulp local
in whatever specified by default okay
let me show the same
Hanover Park against my ass five folks
again year seats the same problem like
him once the little taller but this is
normal to above on
and I say we do bookmark this link
in five for some things even worse
because you can see
you can see the %um was like that you
just based on that
same okay we save it now in Firefox is a
little bit different let's say the you
soon
he's using I'm this session the sex
sessions by FTP okay
as you can see the station can read
into my I'd system and can read into
my phone wants to not is he is the
chrome I mean chrome
okay so what happens Eve the use is
working with the sentence and then goes
here so
I want to be the Muncie the website
that's what happens
you got the code execution because again
the jobs peeps
ok who's into the crumbs on and you got
the code execution
so this is has been fixed mice by if my
folks in
mission 11 is no longer possible which
is good seems that's
someone else as reported these but so
that's
that's pretty cool in
so conclusion from this whole um yeah
basically them main points and
disclosure fame like
it's 2012 and it's still difficult to
told and have a dialogue with bouncer
vendors and
what I'm referring to especially with um
the Chinese ones
I was shocked that can get you a
response like
yes we gonna put the box yes thank you
is much weakened about there was no
response try to change that
a tape
a okay they give to negotiate for you
but
if you have to take a comprise a little
meet up to
me thank you
personal memory up by me even get a
reward
complete different budgeted and the same
with Lindsay Lohan
so I really don't understand why some
men those miss the but complexity versus
impact
so often is a little focus on crazy but
which
memory corruption but again look about
the injection ones
is a very simple but it's the one I show
for months on an island
and is just at the end is just an
injection attack which accuse
not trust them so they feed the need to
have a memory is no option but
to get code execution mouse and the kind
the bomb
proving at this point and
again that get it thing which was in
Justin's them delegation security
like Alan Russell said yes responses you
because it's based on IEEE
and the end users company but that kinda
is gonna have that kind of assumption
but it's totally wrong because what they
do is like
yes the baseball meters boring but then
they up other P so called on the public
that
this kind of hybrid miss they are the
other features
that part to the cold it's the one which
is gonna be
and so that they are wrong in saying
that boo
and yeah pretty much did not want to
think
they spend in the the little top and
Ward
to get five folks want working and to
find about as well
I don't think the teams who dis not come
I'm love is patient for my colleagues
salty some by so yes we all the banks
issued today
gonna write that by staying with the
recent sometime soon
I who have any questions I'm think
there's still time left so you may ask
how you can just contact me on twitter
just talking to me it yeah I think we
have five minutes
for questioning his voice has anyone has
any questions
reversal no or
something
a thanks thanks for the talk that
interesting so it seems that
miss couple the arse more and more
people are looking to these
XCS box I'll let you can actually run
dollars keep cool day into litas the
domain
as the UK and basically bring air
cross escaped into code execution I so
that some of your
and some about you follow on have been
fun likes it automatically
now bout my money size van away or do
you think its possible like to all to
meet
this process like too little too floods
the
there any friend Bee Gees and leather I
bloody in that these if the page
instruct information from the dole
day in a way that because I think every
reason not space tool
to find new box where the freezer
technique tweeting in
in more rapidly way nothin sweepers yes
that mean that is true the thing a
multi-nation
up for the injection once spaces just in
the user to lend to the
money to me tonight want to change
actions directly into the home
trusted zone: it's done game on I'm
for the book months 1 yes requires a
little bit of steps
on the user's part and a game that
they were required to find an injection
which triggers automatically
in terms of our team then I'm
yet it's kind of a different approach
the pressure was tweaking
base unit just miss you mean one
sentence like Austin looking for a
cross-ice keep the months
but is to the website into the Branson
that's the
there was the trick to find the spot and
if you find injection point into
streisand's on
its it's game over you can compromise
the bounced and then if that response to
you
this okay
thank you very much I think we're out of
time so I remember that I want to thank
you very much for your dog
tickets
all rights and now we're just gonna set
everything up for closing keynote and
will be back in a few minutes