I'm I missed
guy I hope you guys had a good lunch did
you go to the EQ backs launch
john Jaso the it went up in the air
well yeah table ok
go helium buttons cell
I am before we started stock we also
have all the contests are going on now
ID applications live CT apt is live if
you sign up for tamper evident you are
lamenting why you did that in the first
place about right now
I but this is Chris Charlie nm
and they'll be talking about this year's
batch K
cell I just frat warning and we haven't
really slept in the last 24 hours
so please email of that might be why
he's got it now
I A now I just saw a background we've
been doing
this is the fourth year we've done
electronic badges we really tried to
make something really cool and
interesting and this is the first
electron
actually dead this was and many
synthesizer
display
this is the the speaker batch for the
same here
this is actually the first and Bajnai it
kinda done so well
was not easy and they made me do it just
to learn
cell and Shipley then be dead
and I see remote and it came with a
little shield for speakers as well
then this is last year's which was
really awesome can do a mini
oscilloscope in logic analyzer
also was some really cool LED's just to
have
more blinking and Madonna
all else fails they make really great
custer's hand okay so
at the background for this year's batch
and
this is totally something that we've
tried to do before
and when NFL is for start-up we did this
approx mark 3 LCD is a a group project
and it was honored
lot of people had not dan's tiny tiny
service mount soldering before
and and end up with a lot of trouble
shooting
this is a printout
that by stockers photo
credit given and
this is something that we print it out
and if thou so that you could kind of
track the massive amounts have component
that detected at this point this is when
things went wrong
on one at the board's we had to do
a a lot of different antenna tests I am
there's the elephant as an HF antennas
and we can make our own
lot a different lot different s which I
am
seen seen our own and
that didn't work out
so this year add Charlie it started
their badges I know eyelashes airline
with the goal to have it done by
Christmas
cuz that's always kind of the goal to
have it done by Chris
and believe it or not we have a revision
done by Chris
there was actually a bad totally done
working by Christmas
first to
and a
a badge one batch singular
an cell
like I said little little sleep I also
only just finished this
said and
okay so the proxy Park
overall is a really complex board and
there is roughly
200 parts and and its it can definitely
be tricky
so you can understand how someone might
go little bit crazy
having to route several revisions
have something like this and there were
lots and lots of provisions and for one
of them
Charlie spend that ten hours straight
trying to you finish it to make a
deadline
to order the PCB's and there with
another
revision that he we actually title
Charlie X losses night
because he had done it so many times
right
you mean yes
so the preservation every day and they
didn't have a hardware SPI
and and it turned out when run fast
enough
so we had to change in animee I did the
hardware SPI but then we missed a few
items
mistakes on the PCB's I'm in another
revision
and miss some power lines cell
that was well reaction
and getting now in and made cell
but didn't have to worry about it they
were just moved on to the next one so
there are two revisions that
repeatedly that use the stm32 f1
and Charlie hard to really really hard
today
get this one to you transfer from the
FPGA at 13.56 cock
but then arco discovered that there is a
megahertz chance for required yours
absolutely no way without
chip was going to make it happen so on
to the next one
as so then we started using the fam 7
much was an because we knew good work
because on the original box marked and
but we did make it new Buddha make it
better
and we did include 512kb flash memory
so it is improvement
Alan the whole reason why there was the
tragic loss is mine is because after he
had already submitted
this year's badges he went ahead and
made a whole new one
just cuts this is
this year's
and okay citizen background on the
ordering process
and we ordered these from %ah to
different places
and the first party ordered we actually
ordered from inside the US it is really
expensive
but supposedly it doesn't take much time
they claim to have a one-day turnaround
end up being about a four-day turnaround
and about three and all yours for only
five boards
but much I need a quick testing can be
convenient
but when me again these boards made for
the conference's
we got two summers ago it wasn't which
is in Malaysia so it takes a little bit
longer but definitely cheaper
seventy body is interested in making
their own PCB's
and is definitely a company worth
looking into I did the really great
and %um pretty well ongoing relationship
with them
so hate relationship really
an detd
sigh I lost my spot month
okay so one thing that when you add
dealer to PCB's
one thing to know is that they charge
based on the square inches if you're
bored
so does it really matter the shape it's
the overall strange is that it takes
cell when we order the LF antenna
we head and kinda
planned out how much its gonna cost me
submitted the order and then we noticed
immediately that it was far more
expensive
then we had calculated ourself and the
reason for that
is that when you
to secure the board's you wanna kinda
turned into an angle if you have
anything protruding out to them
so that way it's not taking any
additional space the first time we did
it we did it this way
cell and staying at more space and the
cost increased significantly
citizens I know when you're making your
own we also
found out then this is something that I
had only just learned and we were told
by the many
by soldiers are kids the Paley it's
really difficult to make
oils their really really touchy and
every step of the process
and sell there was really good chance
that they would like for the dead
which is great okay
cell background on what it takes to
bring you this
badge tons and tons of time
so there's like months of planning
different provisions ordering
boards testing the boards or in part
and a huge invasion space this is my
dining room table
it is a 10 foot long table it is cuz
hovered
impact in all these parts are actually
being used on the match
so the next two parts they're all the
parts that are actually being used
everywhere
this is my his the kitchen counter where
we are making sense of
so there's paste everywhere and led all
over the counter
we didn't we prima a take-out and indeed
and in millions plates cuz they were
everywhere
was on the floor their tissues
everywhere this is the net
completely different tableware wonder
being assembled it
the huge station at Faith okay
so what is it actually deal in nineteen
nothing
the what it could do what it's supposed
to do
is an read RFID cards
obviously and you can call them IFAD
cards you ken
simulate replay which is similarly any
and any recorded card the hash
analyze way forms and you can intercept
information from other readers
and you can save we've also included an
SD card
and pad so that you can
use that to store information and we are
still
building these so if you haven't really
seen any around it's because they're
still being assembled
and Dino sleeping in 24 hours there
with a big shout out to March here just
ten JK who have been staying up with us
to help us bring you these boards
so yes a round of applause for them
they don't have to do it they're just
doing it to be nice
and some people are under the impression
that you're going to provide eases
can't and it would be really really
difficult
to you give you a kit to do you land
like I said and over 200 parts yes
so we have the parts if you wanna make
your own K hop
take it yeah
so hopefully we'll have kids but the
kids are just gonna be n
they're gonna be a lot less part
significantly a lot less parts and it's
basically getting
allow you to use the LED on the board
can also come to the really awesome Sam
7 really expensive check
cell has
or small
or again which is really important
my checklists during this whole process
is really important that you double
check all a tactless you check your
inventory and make sure all your parts
fit before you show it to the conference
homes have the same
but they don't they battled
iPad the kids were gonna start selling
them after the talk in the hardware
hacking village they're gonna be forty
dollars
and the companies that have instructions
when you buy the kit there are
only a limited amount and so when you do
buy them there are some specialized
instructions
that I'll give to you because there's no
way I can write them down
without showing on the board an hour
gonna do lined up
known
open up okay both batters died
hard
about all
hard keeping
okay so
normally on a those have a circuits
elect
cut itself off act I like 2.3 air like
2.5 volts
and I'm I decided to let it run
as far as the battery would allow so in
theory you can write it down to zero
volts
which isn't very good for the battery
but I figured you know you're all adults
seeking
figure it out I'll also use that extra
like 30 minutes
runtime: cell the batteries are
the replacement batteries for a Apple
iPod
second generation touch so they're about
to three dollars
said a few do runners down it dies in
Orem
protease part number: I am
the pork and destroy itself because
it makes enough power on the help let to
come back around and zap it's ATC
cell that's exciting I'll
but
but that that's a good thing cuz you
wanna be able to send as much power as
as possible
rikers madame back Tagore retarded
far away or you know or yeah I'm
the wall your investigating might be
Sheldon topper like this here I am
cell that's a good thing us article
Oso
yeah so that because you toward I just
kinda placeholder batch
and and what it was gonna be head
on mine it actually is is the second
layer I get attached
like so yet and
I've wired up a plus the bottom
so my might procs mark has a built-in
internal antenna
cell it's like as opposed to normally
pong so
normally you have at this thing hanging
off and that's your lover content on a
I have this little call in the back
I had actually sent you
combined hand
I think gonna ended
up
ok anyone is familiar approx mock
we site started bombing on in all
divisions about my transpass was the
the potluck free there's been another
LCD mark
which we built like years ago doesn't
work it's never works
agent ones so this is a completely
redesigned
approx mark free with real telepath done
properly suspects mafia telepath
with the old which is different SD card
it's the 500 talk aged speaker that is
not connected with b2b websites
buckingham
change that was morning
buckets fully compatible with the
dick gephardt version at the source
close you can download us
the source code I made a VM which is 4
G's a month to
is good GCC installed in action value
goes up his tight make
we also included other reef ice foreign
you can reflash
through thick gooey and so there's a
command line toward
questions initially loaded you will
replace it a.m.
just before we started the data we tried
a and you can see here's a test the
antennas for tea party-backed six-fold
into a burglar's which is you know
punish me to tag
you would've done live on stage here on
earth mean that but this is the new ago
a so one agrees we started to talk
markets cuz when we initially day
is horrible
something to do with me and the Middle
0 sorry but I'm
Rosa gotta
so data part of a when we first started
using it was
all forty use like no one knows how to
use it so
my first props mark was actually a stud
finder unseen video that but it plays
The Simpsons and find studs and because
I couldn't be bothered used to do it I'm
SES this what does the windows one is a
Linux one on this until kinda nice you
can just open it up
click on it and it worked or you can
just use the command-line version other
just like if you use these in post
market works at:
so all that is there all the tags
I'm and then radio or came out with the
chinese want it's compatible with that
too as well but
ours is way beyond that I'm so I think
this is a better want to do what it is
we're going to do is loss which the
and her driver's so you can do more than
13.56 megahertz
is clearly cause of crystal because the
new chip for use in is a hundred and
fastest the to you megahertz think
I'm sdmf t54 it's got a megabyte
Rome as well and that's going to be the
that's all I lost my mind
decides make up about a week and a half
ago I am
and we're gonna keep going back to keep
making it but think this will be a lot
better
I am Anderson if any was up smoke-free
LCD you cannot get a chance to work
reliably but I think this will work
really well I'm
I made a Windows version of the bill
does well for people don't use
like these in Linux because I don't like
using Linux like using Windows
so as polarizing but there you go
her I'm about to have a I'm having a
contest in the
toted me a hardware hacking village if
anything right Microsoft Word quicker
than I can
in the nets this o'clock at night in
Windows Jer
take me five minutes because I'm gonna
use a committee
but Sir got flash tools and stuff either
all ready to go israel's up
after other conference up to me
for sale bagged yeah
anonymously sleep in an ambush
moguls all the you think yeah all the
code
is on RCN is on get some and
we also all the horror outside files
some soul
yes of any
hickson the board
even ha we having
the and the party for me
UK
drought are
not yet sumner from
yeah yes 1 part baths
where yes its all time which for some
reason my
such as ice on the ground in the Sun
with scissors its
parts made by the same company
repins did recess which
username like just work but may decide
to make
East name different on a par
and sell yeah yeah
hustlers less we sent an email like two
weeks ago said hey everybody I think I
fucked up these lines
and everybody look at them and we watch
news editor finds Michael Gray
and yes they will build the ball or run
the code does missed
mine doesn't seem to be connected to
these you concede that Israel
hence the happy fine jumper wire
from whole here yes
yes so we ask people to verify just me
those write an email back saying yeah it
looks fine but National Guard
gonna 11 11 me
any questions
West yeah
mode still yes
hey does this repeal loaded with like a
hundred different chip 100 different
shit tubes
I'll we did forget one get one thing
on the back at the batch she flip it
over with the side that has the
doesn't have the logos you notice is a
chip that doesn't like it's connected to
anything
and it says good look next to it every
see that I got the soloist was measured
the right no
thats bit fury ASIC so is capable of
generating because if I make asses
should put a chip on their I have some
other ships well
official of the just closer up
the I
it will work if you publicize you for
the circuit will work you can connect
today
by harm in it will run he said
yes yeah
has SS are idea 156 it does
it does and does from 143 144 be all the
usual stuff but
they've added on the whole bunch stuff
which is Carlos Amy fours like
when we initially side pockets crack but
people have been working on the
for some reason decided to pick up the
key in the last year so and know the
whole bunch of stuff
chip test centres the state can also can
be right and cause a lot of people
familiar with approx what we're seeing
the Dr
you can call because he can take a card
it will read it
put a black katana it will overwrite a
and you can also
overwrite some cause I'm even if they're
not been pre-programmed
so as well as the ability to clone and
simulate
you can just hop pop deposit like crazy
a question
shop I you where the fab shop and that
the kitchen basics kitchen table
of shop scars on my arms
%uh these are actually much I slit my
wrists two days ago
shot yes formatting
dollars to get word is accusing others
joke
what do you mean
world
I'll their the gary has like 0 me up a
heart attack
yet they're all lasted into going so
unlike most commercial readers I
which have a a set number I'll hoping to
decode
I scare however much questions like
these %uh
this stuff my controller PGA so
FAA new format comes out I'll
as long as you know about format is you
can program
PJD for you this has quite a few
likes of stronger up
you'd be very hard-pressed to find one
that his moms supported by
in case you do it can be added
yes during page
be yourself should just the day
starter yet like 30 the whole day
probably
outperforming other for you know
withhold
everyday yesterday day 30
stores like yeah rightward
was those your hard
yeah so yeah
managed
higher day before reading the wall
you you talk
yeah what you gonna come up now 1 um
around in if they they that was the
commander told that I want atomic number
last year but he was also really don't
understand it just
missus all times are much is going on
he has an attorney mules but he is
working on a
and we've been kinda chanting about it
because they're interested in a proxima
tabor on yeah I think we we want to do
something with them
yeah yes let nobody
battery died a slight dunno which is
cardinal rule done was never do a live
online
I I will be in the yard where acting
saluting area questions world
well the
on yeah
now
I
yes