so
are for speakers ready to come up here
we have
Danielle giving a talk on privacy in law
in
all sorts of very important stuff you
should probably care more about than you
do
so welcome Daniel actually I'm not gonna
be speaking about law at all because
that's boring as hell
and right here for that why I'm gonna be
speaking on is basically
the importance love your community
and a are liberty and freedoms today
but we gonna start also are so I'm a
star
with the a few things i wanna talk about
overall first
who am i were I come from
its works on our privacy fears why you
should have fears like you know this but
it's nice to reiterated odd privacy
abuses tree so does it sound like I'm
making this stuff up
being a conspiracy theorist an essay
scandals
artists stay in touch with what's going
on privacy legislation that I pushed
what can states do since the Fed's won't
do anything except abuse all rights
why montana which is why I'm from
and what is the firewall freedom well as
a last resort the first words montana
I know you guys know this montana is in
red
and also the COS one more politically
right california's in blue
that's we're at right now for those you
who are lost a
a
alright my background my family actually
moved in from or Jan
in nineteen ninety four's overpopulated
they want to get out they want to raise
their kids and %uh
3 in 3 environment
it was great %uh my grandparents are
russians who literally escape communism
and a move to iran and where my dad was
born
so I have some history on Aug government
takeover in that area
and then the other grandparents are
Italian one who fought with the United
States against the Japanese and Italian
immigrants so
some pretty good history right there on
what is important what you have to fight
for
and when you need to fight for it I
graduate from
roundup high school ice wanna put that
out there all the time anyway I speak
because no one's heard around
high school town 2,000 people in a
30-mile radius with more cows than
people
its quite fascinating that I'm even here
today I went to university Mont addis a
public
I'll University three majors and a
political science minor
after that I implemented state
government taxes since I saw what might
behind the scenes and
State Department's and it was a joke a
special laws being passed that didn't
make sense
that were on policy to tax you guys more
and more
a it was not my kinda career I want to
do to try to make me a programmer and
I'm more of a social guy
so thats why I'm speaking from you guys
apparently
came back to montana ran for office so
here's just one question
you here and you have to raise your hand
if you think so
who here thank you I love guys in the
back to hear believes they have a role
to play in politics policy government
who you're actually thinks that that
something that they have an important
role in so what have you
that's actually an unprecedented amount
%uh
will talk about why is probably most
evolve you
cool may have a role
I was most concerned about is our
government is obtaining
all this data possible again I was
always what happens if they collect this
data
now it is we know that they're
collecting it
great until you get to the next point
where you gotta think about human nature
to err is human to forgive divine
I know everybody in here has done
something stupid in their life because I
know I've done quite a few stupid things
yeah
last night some you guys probably broke
curfew laws
you know what you learn from it one day
maybe maybe not but
the fact that all what you did last
night or in your past may be recorded
somewhere
to be found out a later time to be used
against you is the biggest threat and
concern that people
%uh should have to use information
against an opponent
is politics and what is politics about
does anybody know
power
money is about power cuz in the end
result
it's about power %uh sold the loss was
power tends to corrupt and absolute
power corrupts
absolutely so you get these people
enough power and they're gonna want more
you give them the ability to abuse a
system
that was meant for the idea of security
and they will abuse it
so has this happened before
yes it has J edgar Hoover was ahead the
FBI and the organization prior for about
forty eight years
his he transform the FBI into his
private secret police force and I read
this quote from President Harry S Truman
we want no gestapo or secret police FBI
standing in that direction they're
doubling and sex life scandals
and plain black male J edgar hoover
would give his right eye to take over
and all congressmen and
arstan and senators are free to PM when
you have
elected officials like myself your phone
individual who was swaying my boat
you no longer have a democracy one other
thing is they tried to
with his data he try to %uh derail
Martin Luther King's
our stances with his sex life scandals
by nineteen sixty the FBI had subversive
files on some 432,000 Americans
this is history this was before and use
technology happened
who read had or was %uh created hoover
use black male politicians
including ya
883 files on senators and some 172 files
on congressman
most these were shredded but here's a
interesting example what was contained
unique name withheld said
she had spent the afternoon up 3 June
1959 was senator
name withheld in his private office she
also said she had sexual intercourse
with the senator during the afternoon on
the couch in the Senators office
well that that is expected in politics
so
but the fact that you would present
these files saying oh you look into what
the FBI's doing how would I let this go
on be released
and all the sudden all the senator this
was as top priority anymore he had more
important things to do
in Watergate scandal this is the
gonna go back one this was the example
of one individual
getting all is power in abusing in our
system here is an example of
politics abusing on data collection
which
was done June 17 1972
basic most you may know this but five
men were arrested two thirty trying to
buck the office
the democratic national committee at the
Watergate Hotel
because you know what information is the
most useful thing in politics
we know something about the other guy
they're gonna expose it right before by
such voting
to derail them on now that we all began
twelve years of history on us
%uh expect that to happen there aren't
very few notable individuals in politics
today
especially DC level %uh this event
actually prompted montana
saudis the data privacy cause in the
state's constitution
analysis do the historic abuse and how
state gathered information
the stars you which was eastern Germany
they collected enough paper to fill more
than a hundred miles ourselves
and the index a cross-reference a five
and a half million names
of hundreds of thousands of unofficial
employees are basically writing out each
other
fall
for me me for potions to
any
said started by the government basically
is how it this is
the amazing thing is they only could top
$40 phones a time because of a lack of a
equipment and technology and I was still
enough to keep an entire nation at bay
for a while anyway for decades so
let's look at it because pictures are a
lot more amusing than words
here is what the area the stars the
filing cabinets amounts to you
%uh which is basically a terminal to
Salt Lake City
International Airport day the lineup
to a few weeks later we learned about
information are informational government
partnerships
partnerships with companies revealed
including Microsoft
now when government put enough pressure
on companies
to act a certain way that's more fascism
up few months later we learned about NSA
employees
more spying on ex-lovers so
there's on your first abuses of the
system a week later the black budgeted
intelligence community is release which
is 50 2.6 billion for 2013
as a lot of money 0
few days later AT&T we learned ATT
calling records database used by the DEA
goes back twenty years and
few weeks after that we learned that the
NSA stores metadata millions of web
users for up to year
only because the storage issues those
store longer but they ran outta space
that's embarrassing up October 2nd NSA
tracks of a location Americans for up to
two years is the one that I kinda hone
in on during the last session all talk
about later
october thirtieth dennis et breaks into
Google Yahoo data centers
I and does it without them knowing
interestingly enough we learned recently
that Google was agreeing to work with
this
an assay as well so you down kinda gets
tricky
or they only sharing some information
and the rest they were shane has been
stolen
the summer for the essay was collected
by billing records a mobile phone
location
daily and generous 16th Dennis it was
collecting millions attacks
I don't know why that was on the first
ones cuz very know the recording our
phone calls
ugh every seven 20 percent
up to 30 percent of all call calls are
being recorded
again because the storage issues that's
sad
here's here's the one I like to use a
put it out there cuz this is the most
important thing
that can affect our future November 26
the essay spot nah
just and you can apply to any have it
from my friends look up how to make a
homemade guns to
poor habits to whatever to how to hack
things
that could be considered not legal %ah
did the National Security Agency
has been gathering records online sexual
activity in evidence
visits to pornographic web sites as part
of a proposed plan to harm the
reputations of those from the agency
believes are radicalizing others through
%uh speeches according to a top secret
NSA document so this could be me
radicalizing you the document provided
by
Edward snow in identifies help personal
personal
vulnerabilities can be learned through
electronic surveillance
and then exploited to undermine the
targets credibility reputation and
authority
this has been going on
this exists today okay
so this is the only technical part all
really get into
I'll be pretty quick is the third party
doctrine
which easily enough says that
%uh it
addresses voluntary incomplete compelled
disclosure of stored wire
and electronic communications and
transactions transactional records basis
says
if you use a third-party provider you
give up your
%uh your privacy you're right
up the Fourth Amendment protection with
that information the prom how does not
my constituents know that
my get elected I go talk to I try to
talk to as many as them as possible
meaning and knock on their doors
I'm not dumb I just searched or
one-and-a-half times
no one knew that they've given the
permission
other information being shared son make
them I
you know may be uninformed as I mean it
should be their fault
no if they're not if they don't know
this
that is not their fault it's not like I
should go tell hey you're giving this up
the assumption is what I'm basing on as
a politician on behalf of my
constituents
so let's focus back on montana why the
hell am I here
I heard that
%uh a hacker starts out as one of my
close friends
montana we have a citizen legislature
who serves the people
she suggested I look in a privacy issues
right after I got elected
this there was a very big huge void up
protecting our privacy in politics
especially with now the profit up data
no one wants there to be any lines of
what is right and what is wrong they
want to be in open area I love
obtain market cell so basically
the knots where the government doesn't
outliner rights do not expect those
rights to exist
expect them to be taken and that's why
the bill rights was there in the first
place
again where the right to privacy in
Montana's Constitution
which said Walter right to privacy is in
montana we better and acted policy or
else is going to be ignored
yield to question me try doing %uh
discussing was who owns this data so
we're talking about i'd I've spoken on
this one quite a bit of HP 400
the legislation I pushed not basically
nearly in still may have ruined my
future political of goals because other
relationships I
cut off with special interests
immediately
this was all prior Edward Snowden's an
essay leak so
Edward snow in an essay june fifth and
sixth I was doing this in January
five months before trying to push
privacy legislation to protect people's
alright so to be considered the Privacy
Bill of Rights
and it focused on legislation that
implied the information that %uh
information launch the individual
data subjects must be given notice when
information is collected
personal information may not be
collected without consent
and personal information may only be
used for the purposes stated
so this information belongs to you
not those who can collect it if they
wanna club did they have to give to your
permission
I had 37 signatures in montana we have a
hundred represent is fifty senators
at 37 signatures most the from the
Judiciary Committee for
a on behalf up this bill saw a walk in a
committee
to have my bill heard its
privacy bill rights over the first on
the country would have been
it would have changed or been the domino
effect the privacy free pass in one
state it will pass and more
I walk in the room I'm a conservative
Republican legislator
who's about limited government and every
angle and I walk in
every single business lobbyists is
standing in that room
and I haven't packed and they're just
raises stand-up
and tell tell the community how bad this
is for business
montana how anti-business I am how how
out a line I am as a freshman legislator
trying to pass something
on behalf of my constituents where the
montana retail Association
montana Telecommunications Association
multiple insurance
companies I'll dealers bankers hospitals
chamber commerce montana collectors
Association want at Association it was
amazing
it that room with a blown-up all the
problems in montana woulda gone away
immediately
so I i wasnt
yes I think it was debt collectors
on club if I'm correct I love more the
montana Collectors Association
thinkers debt collectors up proponents
so I was there door about I think 30
people
ready to put me in my place humiliate me
which they
were basically successful on doing who
is on my side I was
it was me I was told by everybody don't
do this bill
it's stupid it's gonna ruin you don't do
it so I did it
%uh I
but is really nice I walked in there
and I to proponents I'm a hacker friend
and i'd the ACLU occur but never in
thought about especially being from the
more conservative right and they were
the two
but spoke on my behalf it was awesome
I now have a really good relationships
with the ACLU on
data privacy so it was a good start for
that but still
is kinda sad when after that next week
and really want to go anywhere because a
everybody put you in your poli place
little bit Sun
so what are some the consequences sb400
I got the up
order the black helicopter award because
I was considering all the crazy for
being so concerned about data collection
hollow ut outstanding conspiracy theory
creation from the Man in the Yellow Hat
thank you those from a fellow
representative he also gave me a black
helicopter at my desk for the rest of
the session
on the focus so the 2013 legislation
continue though the HP 409 pass
and people some my close friends or
basically thought my political future
all possibilities were screwed that I've
went way too far as way to marry to this
legislation and I needed to just take a
few steps back
and I heard other people say I have
nothing to hide
wiry pushing this is not an important
and the whole concept I had to keep
trying to apply
educate people on does you may not have
anything to hide
good for you for being a perfect
individual but you still have the right
to hide it
and that doesn't always work in people's
minds and so I tried also
say fearing making mistakes especially
younger
%uh is a former self censorship I know I
learned from my mistakes I've done a lot
of stupid things
I'm the only proper politics who claims
not to be perfect
and you know what it's true I'm not
perfect
we're not perfect and sometimes making
stupid mistakes we learned a lot
about ourselves about life it's kinda
what makes I think our country great
odd as self-censorship occurs when
europe
appear for what you me do now or hurt
you in the future
and then the loss one is always licks
more extreme but I think right to the
point that
remember the Germans had nothing to hide
until they're trying to hide their
neighbors so
don't tires I'll try to hide anything
was the next one again I'm trying to
make it as on technical
and straight to the point this was a
bill a senator
who is a democrat prison has said hey
you know it you really
got beat on this bill hobby try some lot
smaller he came up to me
and he said okay this is what we're
gonna do I do so I got a sponsor a bill
to require law enforcement
to obtain a search warrant before being
able to collect location information
from electronic devices
was a all the information knows only
location information
surn devices very narrow to the point as
also undefeatable in the sense that this
is a common-sense bill why wouldn't we
pass it
it was short simple one-page emergency
opt out of life threatening situations
permission of the owner and order to
respond to 911 calls
odd it was first in the nation and has
since been used as model legislation I
know Utah just pass it on to the sport
at Utah on Main a pass in 10 states pass
and other states to try to pass it
a sad thing that's happened with this
pillow resupply stalkers
a representa- from south carolina in
they had
a lot of law enforcement agencies say
this is a horrible bill
and if you wanna support child
pornography
support this bill and you know what
it's not that important for them to try
this get this bill passed
so they killed in committee because they
want don't wanna be tied to child
pornography for the reelection
because the real elections more porn
than anything like this that's
lower-level low on the priority list
doesn't stop that though is the real
question
%uh know you get a search warrant and
then that location information still
obtainable
so no but they were ready to die on a
steak for this issue
so what it is P 603 do for me from being
considered almost unelectable their kid
trying to look for people the primary
during the last session
are ready to you
had two months later did you know
montana was a leader on privacy laws
you there did montana from the
washington post I woke up from a nap I
was taking I was not
proud the guy called me I've was like
playing off I was in action take a nap
at that time yes we do you know this is
my own I didn't know that
I did not know it be a headline for the
washington post with Montana's lead
states may demand warrants for cell
phone data
New York Times if you don't the
government to spy on you move to Montana
alright that's not true but im a
smart-aleck it's all take that headlines
from Yahoo dot com
and then this one was good meet the
Montana lawmakers been called the face
of online privacy rights the US
also little far but I'll take it
army I also afterwards got
those interviewed in up by Glenn Beck on
his TV station the
they flew me down did speak on behalf of
this issue which I really care we are
politically
he said he said everybody Democrats and
Republicans who supported the cycle
legislation
a good on them which is called the here
when it's from both sides dialing he's
one saying it
the last thing was recently I was
awarded a force 30 under 30
%uh wrist award which is crazy coming
from a small town being a guy who just
don't like the system 11 a stand up
against it
oh yeah and some means and then montana
said you can spy on us
so and just for the people who are on
the other side of the aisle
they've made a fair okay
so we're gonna bring back to montana now
why is montana
relevant it's a great question
there's a million people there why am I
here speaking to you about this
all bring it down to a level help that
makes a lotta sense as montana donation
limits
right now mine are 100 something dollars
if I get a hundred
max donors I can likely when my race
it's very simple
California donation limits or about four
thousand dollars
soul you know what my mom
and my college buddies they can afford
to donate to me and trust me I make them
donate to me
%uh I in California
I people like me had no chance
unless I can so find unless I do have a
hundred people who can donate four
thousand dollars and I don't know just
can anybody hear donate four thousand
dollars to a campaign
just hell randomly want per your budget
no
that's why I thought are ash then we're
talking later
I nice to Montana House race cost
fifteen thousand
to twenty-five thousand dollars a
california house race cost $400 to $500
thousand
can go lower but a competitive one will
cost about that much oh we have term
limits
four sessions per house so eight years
in the house
years the Senate turned out %uh want
that this prize Miss California had term
limits as Walter
12 years total which i think is more
recent so
that's a good thing is you always get
people coming in up
what do with term limits if you know
you're gonna end in a few years
you don't mind standing up a little bit
taller for issues people
and other areas where they'd of term
limits all say us not worth
knocking reelected for me I'll get
reelected screw I got the rest my life
to live
these guys they got their pensions to
gather so
montana again why suit the next owners
okay why is it important one thing the
montana has
decides that is is %uh very
Liberty libertarian minded legislators
on both sides of the aisle
I got the far left who completely agree
on these privacy concerns along with the
far right
and where the nope that's what makes up
the majority in the House and the Senate
the middle all the moderates only
someone like what's good concept for
security we shouldn't
limit who can gather this access and so
that's how I deal more in the middle but
these guys have principal
on your rights these guys have Prince
Paul your rights seems to be the one the
few issues I can get the far left the
far right together on
same page with and that's awesome I
recently spoke a few times with the ACLU
to the Tea Party you get those guys in
the same room not kept trying to kill
each other
and I did you just use accomplished
something texas is trying to do the same
thing out this book about an Ashley
on trying to get these groups together
cuz they have something that they can
work on and get pass
who woulda known it took a 26-year-old
Anna
the ACLU lobby person to put these ideas
together and we're going to speak to you
up so we have
we have a very big possibility a passing
legislation
that will protect to be the first in the
nation out a montana
that's big concept that a lot of people
are realizing at that I want people to
realize it is
again if we pass it there we pass it we
can pass it anywhere
has a lot of things a Senate committee
hearing was it's never been done before
it doesn't work
no oils done it effin awesome doing it
is probably good reason why
well you know what I think I can help
make it happen
sorbonne else can make it happen and
doesn't mean it's only Montana can't do
it
I just think that %uh since I'm there
crane relationships it's very possible
so what are some the 2015 legislative
goals
for our session 0
won the first these are all mine but
we're all working together on it
while first one's a strength this is
mine strengthening shield laws
concerning technology which is
protecting sources the press
when it comes to technology that's
very important %uh that's
first-amendment stuff right there
the next one is what I've been getting a
lot of statewide press on
which is requiring the option for event
data recorders to either be turned off
require notification notification now
it's kinda transition to
all require event data recorder
information to block the individuals
so I'm expecting a huge battle all this
three or four days ago I got called by
the main
special interest lobby for the
manufacture sane not only do we want to
support this
were completely behind you
to ensure that to get this information
it's gonna require a search warrant
if you don't give it up that just made
this bill go from a ten to twenty
percent
up or maybe a youth fifty percent chance
a passing to now
85-90 percent chance passing what out it
been watered down
that is a huge deal so another one
is prevent the state you some automated
license plate scanners
and 2009 montana band red light cameras
yeah last session we banned
drone usage Limited is severely so now
is time to also prevent the start-up on
me license plate scanners one good thing
about montana
is or so far behind we don't have them
yet so were gonna
bandit before we're committed okay
another one is all
facials recognition software san Diego
is starting to use this already
and its they're testing it out there
trying it out so
I can bases my painting a picture and
know who everybody is in this room is
law enforcement
that's okay we need to stop that from
happening before it even gets
out us let another one I'm gonna try to
work on preventing the state from using
or vendors that the state can purchase
cuz I sloop or right there
a we want to know this is the big
this is the holy grail old concert to
obtain personal information
I'm gonna try to San most simple way
possible
but still gonna start it's already
getting complex you getting a shoes
lobby against me
say that personal data belongs to the
individual
and define what that personal data is it
dow one is kinda the pipe dream but
sometimes if you have one to be chilled
the other ones might
make it through so we'll see about that
reform stop asset forfeiture
years know about that issue as much
so Packers are when the cops come in
the break down your door they say you're
guilty for this
they get all your computers and they
sell off and keep the money %uh
and then they found out that you're not
guilty but the very soul of the top kept
the money
you have to spend thousands dollars and
suing them getting lawyers to get the
money if the what they've already sold
off
kept that's all we want to stop that
happens so
yeah yeah and then
continue just the thing with the search
warrants we've had one success there
of require search warrants for also for
information
all email information all social
information media your social media
information
all information if you want it get a
warrant
okay so let's pause right there
we're trying to do something the state
level bargain successful
other states are trying to do it it's
happening but
more the fed's doing nothing
the USA freedom act joke
its empty it's been slaughtered its the
over a hundred the sponsors have now
voted against it because it's a nothing
bill its I have no faith in our federal
government to be honest that's one state
politics
its through
but
saying that the government has checks
and balances
cracked federal executive
urged judicial executive legislative
there are also subject each other
now we're all working together odd
legislative branch was a small spill the
people
is no longer the people at the top
percent approval rating or lower
I think it's others saying that more
people would rather
are more people are more favorable death
then
are US Congress so that's not a good
thing her
%uh so the NSA but there is a text about
Thursday you know the NSA has its own
secret courts
that overseas its activities
that is also overseen by the NSA said
haha
hurts a joke right there on one
last 10 that is sex abouts is known
really speaks out because they say it's
not crack to speak up sometimes is that
up the people if you accept it allowed
to go on
you are as guilty as the rest of us what
he said
peanut gallery back there
all not assessed you're coming up here
in a bit
all that is necessary for the triumph of
evil is that good men do nothing I am a
complete believer in that
of so I'm gonna skip this one along
it's a little bit too close of call for
a
100 yr eighty hungover individuals I
so the firehall firewall freedom
is kinda where it comes down to we're in
a new age does not existed
ever with where our technology is going
and South the only a handful of people
really can understand these concepts
why am i speaking to you out of all the
places I could be
all the people I can talk with
politically especially why
why here first saw
all get to the second but I want to
dwell on it why am I here
odd most people really don't understand
the concerns and what this data
collection can bring us to
were actually RT at worry been for a
while most people are worried about
their cell preservation
politicians are worried about reelection
it's true
they're worried about their financial
matters a personal agendas and
there's a handful of them we tend to be
the ones to rise the top politically who
worry about power
they want it and they find their ways of
getting it
and like I said examples USA freedom act
so who has the tools acers stand up to
our intrusive government why am I
talking to you
because you'll are some the few people
who I may be depending on sooner or
later
two stops on these atrocities I'm re:
speaking with hackers
across the state and world for helping
me on legislation
to work on such things as voting
machines
which if you have vulnerable voting
that could be hacked you no longer have
a democracy
because each boat doesn't matter you
have
a smart person who can just sway the
vote sir
hacked machines and change the votes
that's what we're already facing because
all are high commissions almost all them
are very vulnerable
so again who was tools assertive centred
tortures a government you do
you may be some the most important
people in the future
i misses disclaimer first
are as it is they are not suggesting
anarchy
angle hack everything and try to destroy
him blowing up and have a firestorm
Nahla dollar I'm sayin ash by
its bloods grabbed
going to love contended I'm in montana
I know a few people who have their job
bunkers
their guns their food all built up
they have more ammo then %uh than some
other stores are carrying right now
you know it's so it's a way of life it's
kinda people I represent
because I'm a far-right more libertarian
kinda guy so
good on them their races stand up if
there's anything
that they think is a Hill wrongdoing
that is what they're there for
are some all on their own world
definitely
is it the right to be definitely so
with that let's bring it back to
the data collection it is up to
individuals
I firmly believe this in our for fathers
believed as well to stand up to those
who abuse power
univers by our own government we all
know this data will be it has been
abused
but no no no until it sorry possibly too
late to what extent
when this injustice happens those who
those with the understanding abilities
will be the only ones who the
rest the population were rely on this is
especially true
all the data collected right now we have
all black male for those trying to stand
up for something bigger than themselves
we already have the blackmail against us
officers ready
waiting for the trigger to be polled
with that
I we'll leave it and I'll answer any
questions anybody may have
and if you want to donate you can donate
cuz
hundreds of dollars me ek have a huge
effect on my race but
it's not as much as four thousand
dollars don't think you're going to get
a boat out on me though
doesn't work like that any questions yes
sir
engine amount to those minimums and
maximums
max okay I wish their minimum suggest
is getting %uh should
anybody else just pass
mind a
yes there are I condone and Ike
accepting
12 pack tax hundreds of dollars before
impact out
so it's not a huge amount yet
all I can't nobody that's how packs were
I actually I'm amazed that there are
more packs
trying to push this type of stuff in the
data community because our packs that
i've seen
for business for conservative principles
religious principles
not one to help push those behind those
who are pushing us these causes
his pupils
all their all-pro about protecting it
almost all home about either defining
who the property belongs to
what's that defines as your property
which then defines as
doing a search warrant to get its all
about the fourth
amendment except the freedom speech one
which is about first amendment that
is for the the not the freemen the press
which is also another early part 1
well that's what it's all about and %uh
that's the one interesting thing about
these grainy its
I call a grey market data collection
multi-billion dollar industry which I'm
trying to put a finger in there I
of they don't like it because if we
start change in their system
that's a lot of money and what is money
going to again money
is power so we don't really they don't
want that changed agree market
yeah were used you mentioned earlier you
to
you
produce month corners while
activity is your life there so I
this wasn't my legislation there are %uh
more experienced people carrying this
one were also freedom loving individuals
but I believe there was a
you think that these they could have any
weaponry they could be taking pictures
to use on land
they think I believe they need a search
warrant at the you were used for a
criminal case in the search warrant
wasn't there the data would be thrown
out
basically you can fly and many you
collect use and do on them as
extremely limited was the end result
after what you both
how chambers okay
you Paul shit you doll all
I old
a all so
yeah for you know your questions here
no California really playing as
I think I'm watching closely lately but
I think apostle the Senate a bill to say
even the fed's have to get search
warrants for
%uh information of californians that's
been collected so
my state my bill had passed
there was a man who put on it to save
feds are included everything
and it would've been vetoed immediately
so we kept it back to the state so the
first thing that you have to realize
States ten o'clock this information
and share with the feds organizations
Microsoft Google
they click the information companies
they stand sure the fed's
the feds don't collected themselves at
entities who do it for them
if I can limit the state entities that
do it I'm doing my part in my area
the problem is it takes to give us to do
it I in a few days on MuchMusic fusion
center
with colleagues across the board Tea
Party ACLU
up democrat on the republican
we're gonna mute fusion center which is
the entity that basically
is the collector at the state level to
share with the feds
harass them through the attorney
general's office what do you do in
how are you doing it why are you doing
it and we're gonna
where this huge amount to questions were
asked or see what the answer and if the
answer anything
again if I can stop them then there's
less information on the federal level
do expect them to listen to me no now of
course not
all do that at the state level on my I
once I get elected to congress I'll try
that and go down
in in flames but Justin demoss
almost said that and then are he almost
pass that amendment of years it
few months ago to be fun them almost
passed
I S and i've no faith in our Fed's right
now in our federal government so I'll
try do I cannot level I can do it
yes usually sell used
were here I have tried to little bit but
they're more
they're more pushing national things
non office that I know the montana right
now
if I can I've tried but it's a little
tougher so if I work with them right now
to get all my legislation ready
I can be like I said I can help push a
lotta stuff through the state level
hopefully so she was very well written
to have an impact nationally
but some groups have a love it inner
resources or I'd say so
and there again their worry about your
supreme act to worry about what
DNS is doing but Moyes
yeah yeah I've spoken to a few times
anybody else a sucky more hands on a
backer
where time I got done a little bit early
are at Walt make sure you follow me on
twitter
I cuz I know you all you had the known
actually has the montana only the
process is built the politicians
I
I still a blackberry so favs are hacking
that
one security through obscurity and no
the state is an issue it we get paid us
so we're the eight lowest-paid
legislature so we base the volunteer
everything
security through obscurity it is turned
off the wireless is turned off PC
blackberry though please on packet
I'd really appreciate that a
those pictures are mine a
also I business cards appear if you
wanna support and donate re-enact that
I'm easy
but that's all I'm here member you guys
maybe the most important people
people like me have to rely on the
future so Jen thank you very much
I appreciate the agree she coming here
thank you
and if you wanna talk I can
I'll be outside for a little bit if you
wanna meet up in