some other languages in the application
contest
so if you're playing here's a hint
500 points particular individual
the programming language is named after
disease
and when and when you read the source
code you'll
agree there's a there's a
challenging won a contest that I'm
giving him four so that every aspect
axis
for access to set him named after
disease
the programming language involved good
luck so
besides that we have for superior for
the next %ah called your hip a certified
are you have a compliant and Bob just
killed someone
I am its now
that's objective-c actually is
the disease and there's actually a joke
about that
in natural inge but I am
are handed over to bar seven again big
round of applause hi
so she once
I curse hand charm that offend anyone
here but if I do fuck you
miserly now I I'm not bob
so if you are law enforcement you
probably should leave now
arm some you might have seen pieces in
this
I I might have done this talk about
I was six months ago there's been some
more research and we'll talk about the
research
according to lawyers Camberley present
on it
but all get turn so home I am NOT the
jewish a
arm run a podcast all grumpy sack I'm
jaded security on Twitter
doing this program fifteen years om
aside pen testing one on the telcos are
doing its
some you guys who think you're illegal
cuz run display and consider saucepan
testers
we didn't happen despite back to just
yup drying out there
obviously don't care I'm so disclaimer
narrows soft airy none this
as ever happen nobody's been pop
nobody's died
nobody's still may be sending their pH I
just someone else
arm yellow could get into and
a salon it strips I don't know why
like I really didn't feel like going out
and looking for images
besides respect copyright laws some
summers some regards
I'll fuck you the G
some cool
so my friend bob was diagnosed with
cancer in 2012
not dying nobody gives a shit don't cry
don't feel sorry never Bob had a biopsy
sohn ecologist Scott
PET scan and %ah star treatment bob's
lifeline him to get a second opinion
at in other facility rate so in order
for bob to get his medical records that
he pays for rate he had to jump to rush
hopes to get the stuff done so problem
with that is stare
really wasn't a formal process at this
place like he signed a buncha forms and
nobody could figure out where these
forms Collins faxing them in
yes faxes starting in 2013 while this
was in 2013
he faxed Omni doing any responses are
some conversations with lawyers and d/a
so so we're gonna going to some
theoretical somehow Bobcats
taking his own stuff home because so you
guys all remember the healthcare dugout
fiasco right its
said that that robots that taxes still
up it's been like what nine months
fucking ridiculous at school
bay yet they don't have to be have a
combined apparently so
just going to wonder tests
still fucking up like I I just don't get
it like
these are the guys that want enforce
regulations i
Micah fuck it Dave Kennedy can ride that
thang I'll
so help us have this weird happened
doesn't actually
see you have to implement the controls
daunting have a really says is that you
have to do a risk assessed
hum who here works in health care
risk assessment sir easy ray yet just
a whole fucking checkbox ship that you
don't really have to do anything just
like we looked at it
this fucking awesome I'm sure this is
legal
whatever fuck after I'll say yes so I
the secure a 150 essentially say that
you have to
sure that the whole CSS people should
CIHI this fall
hom administrative as a call technical
safeguards are there to cover for
companies
covered and he's is kinda weird chill
because technically everybody's covered
any
by if you're not part of a if you don't
exchange Shah
if you wanna change phia over over
cultural Cheick form that's not back
actually for example it is your small
mom and pop shop
at Justins taxes you not covering most
companies are most workers are covered
and he's right
arm so health care doctors clinic
psychologist
mercury that you got the picture I'm
more than likely
your company every if you work in health
care you're covered in
om you will be pop
by I have never this is the well
so this talk is this the stock is
focused on the on
one major health care provider in the
north in the Northern California
however bob has visited other health
care providers
buzz background is about fifteen years
ago he started to hit the practice
consulting company like when hippo is
just you know
a wet dream in clinton's last night on
he knows have he knows health care he
knows how to get around things
so yes so essentially privacy insures
that the price the primacy your protect
information and social justice Eli
rate you never gonna get your health
records that sucks
om and again something you see have seen
this and you'll find the research like a
line
I do have a giveaway at the end so KS a
pay close attention
as giving away a Raspberry Pi
not really sure what versions I had in
my bag and I don't need it
it's 512 Meg I lost a bunch before
yes check with you I by arm
it's gonna cost you a blow job at least
whatever
okay problem solved moving up %ah
yes I'll something you have seen pieces
this and there's
some really cool researched at we might
have to turn the cameras off and we'll
talk about that when we get there and
at some really fun stuff I'll be a
so hipper requires each company for from
a risk assessment thats all you're bound
to do.
yacht have to implement shed you just
have to have a risk assessed
iremos controls are just small meaning
dad
you don't necessarily have to implement
the control that
would be best practice you just have to
comply controlled and auditor would be
cool with
who knows in order here they'll sign off
on any
anyone here trust with now nobody
typical
just say no they fuck it should object
target
target charge the but never
I say a so I can
I'm not can expect you read this but
fine print is adjustable ownership card
everything is adjustable the only thing
that's actually required is performed
the gap assessment performed
risk assessment writing it up and hey we
do their due diligence work or a
its
so security standards generals covered
in
in covered entities and business
associates must do the following: sure
this confidentiality integrity and
availability of all trying protected
health information
%uh the covered entity or business
associates creatures he's maintained a
transmits
the reason I'm reading that as you'll
see please violations in that
security standard at this one major
health care provider
so we all know compliance and security
ray
with the GRC you check boxes right we
all know that this is the basic minimum
to come to protect us from
legal litigation colleges right you
check the box he did your due diligence
its core a
charged check the box right he may just
checked the box insure good
some have branched off
and I know summer you've seen a way
just wait for research way logical
things
lot circle things I'll and there might
be a nap in the works is a log n
would look into I'm so yes a bob sitting
in the waiting room
scan idea to start planning things right
like you know I issue let me give me my
PH I
skull fucking steal it way school
mine ray my buds bob's body
he just wants to shed some say he set
some boundaries to protect himself from
legal complications and maybe and no law
enforcement
cool I'll CS no date or phir
extolled ever never leave the
organization nobel display racks mostly
pussies
my she have to use mostly not fuckin I'm
not that much our printer doesn't help
in a lot of instances when you don't
really feel like doing your shit
day yeah so any facility on the campus
is free game
meaning that if they might have a
pharmacy a couple blocks away that
nobody stare
connected same backbone no its cool
I'll make no determination
determination by single instance which
means that a finally saw one
problem I saw one reference doesn't
necessarily mean something happened
right so we're gonna
bring him back bobs gonna
and bacon still every make it rain cuz
we all like me
so these idiots
okay so and I'm not gonna teach you
anything like anyone who's a pen tester
will see things here in like the out
that's how we do things om yeah K
maybe you're not a pen tester maybe
yours you see shit like this on TV
and we do this shit all the time it's
fun I'm so yeah
so receptions as
actual picture bob to the receptions to
stop
should I fung plugged in we don't see is
that some under
blocking her view the consul couple USB
ports open on the right
just a few Windows environment so sue me
you now this organization that they risk
assessment their reps option is
definitely has access to pH II she
definitely can pull up your folder
she can definitely make changes to your
insurance information
she can definitely look at what your
diagnosis is
arm there's a risk assessment
Corey so bob was a check
and bob is a dick but Bob Skinner be
dick you're somewhere else
his this just way too easy so bob was dx
for chasing USB rate we all know how
we all know how the surgery nose spray
by knows that this isn't hard
Tia swings school targeting her iPhone
cuz that's not hard either
so bob was upon the contest solar array
hey Winnie
now now pensaste
but an actual game page respond just
wants to fuck with them deposit asshole
I was a dick so bob's will seek and
Kors again bob's Dec so the facility
offers free WiFi for guests
call right wpa2 for hospital staff
day day buzz my FI
local get to what we use that for inside
so this is the only time in my life
where
well in bob's life where he found this
fucking thing useful at all
but there's really no use case for this
thing at all
but your yeah Pokemon 27 might have been
the past
maybe but whenever I am alone
by I was in the pineapples his ship it
was in the bobs Bagan
Bob decide to use it the one time and
for so
funny thing about SSL so other haps
bob was able to know bob was able to
notice that all their
caps that were on the wired network
I'll will look at that the site sorry
all the app's
on the wireless segment use SSL so
obviously the
she didn't wanna do any man the middle
not to say that he might
now I down him he might've in a couple
places but
you know a saucy scoring campy to
so why well bob had to which blood work
he mighta found alive rj-45 port
carbon head in there
just in there behind that play
just in this is a live image up could
apply this laptop
right but then you know its kinda
obvious like in the
dumbass receptions analyst at she might
she pry wouldn't
I'm gonna hurt too much credit if
only there was a way home use
way to put some things you know to hit
some attacks
without being noticed so that will
anchor think it's
20 twenty thousand million LS sixties
apparently tell me more
so I dirt because up on gay
I surged in security at the time it's up
there I it's not just me on Twitter site
to have the image up there
on such as running Linux armed guy after
cap
yeah season 1 finale IC so yes he's
really really cause
if you plug into a wired network you'll
take the pop pop yeah see
ill go out and map the environment look
for all the IP's
look for all open ports and then just
locally index every file a confined
now awesome its
open source in March really it's kinda
like focus but better
much much better
and on top of that its decentralized so
you can drop
couple rash these haven't talk to each
other
and index to a cloud instance not that
Bob did any of this
he's not actually anything just you know
searching right so many data is the NSA
says men it is safe it's not private
yes he for to wish
so basically what bob did was
every file that indexed he you some
basic logic to just
not check to see if he if bob with bangs
that the day that he found this pH II
nothing advance just some bullshit magic
stop some parsing
looking for Social Security looking for
the word diagnosis looking for the word
name
looking for anything that would be PI or
pH
rate because at this point you're
violating
the agreement you have in place with
your custom with your
users with your patience that you're
protecting your data
because you're not so if it found
anything it was just send the
one still number one because we're just
counting how many
record to confine my issue
winning make it rain baby I am
so bob drop flock six long
7 to restore this was your
two are still up as a like a week ago I
Bob might check the client's interests
be a tour still somehow amazingly
plugged into much
on fuck happened so on to wear one
Sabah founds found some other cool shit
so apparently all those absent were
using a sus on the wireless network
right use have heard network says
mold legacy consulship yeah
school me no
no arrests
so I can Bob started person did because
blobs attack rate like you
X this is in water hoc
so bob found something really stupid
like I'm hoping that none of you
actually have to much
carruthers on fuck and my shoe
baden given anything this is from alive
rj-45 port
that might have been in the waiting room
school right
nobody does this
whenever a
its cool at school whatever
yeah yeah it's your
it's from the movie hackers hackers
hackers
artist right now sure
sure
so I'll Bob found something else
interesting so para leer ask these new
power i
and those little power banks expense USB
extension cords
apparently are in use to allow my sister
be plugged in
from that lock box cuz you can lock
console
right you don't want anyone touching the
tower but the mouse
can't really plug into the tower sees
little USB extension
that's cool so Exelis fun
so i didnt to pop in actually have to
look to their network text or anything
cuz he had access to the wireless
and their word right and guest wireless
see where I'm going with this
winning
so after five months that was five
months ago
so 11 months to restore party so it
since December there on the important
one
and I don't think they employed them
dust-up it was power plugged into a spy
broke Isner's
shit but yeah I do I don't have a
current number and how many records are
but there are only about fifty five
hundred patients at this place
some pretty sure I got repack Bob got
everything Bob
Bob whose body was in
worst bobsled and that's his last name
Bob slim so bob was on the Panthers game
would be over a
this is wary sandwiches animal invoices
you pay me
because you guys are stupid at this is
unlike anything
technically there's no active attack
have all there was in a shell spot there
wasn't any
hey I got domain admin I got root there
wasn't any other
there was users stupid like you check
the bunch of boxes
that's cool by yeah
so so but had a couple weeks left the
key
and first a lot more stuff to do
so he really had home network access
right technically he had
River Schultz yellow Logan yeah
this is funny Bob decide to walk around
your electrical con- possums mocked
completely
on locked that might have been where one
in the rest is one so I am NOT school
physical access such a closet high-risk
buttons on passions
spatial integration the extra PC you
guys didn't hear about
we'll get into that Bob might have
bought an IV drip on he day
and that's all talk about your bob likes
to do research and he's OCD
Shin your so yes a patient special home
sir
create tracks bilbies you they're
fucking hours you really wanna fuck with
the hospital pick a fucking heart attack
the lead you in there for days victory
Nasser's a summer your pants esters and
you need a way and that's actually
headway in have the ambulance would be
fucking awesome
be fucking great I've fallen and I can't
get up yes
nothing to see here that's last reply
bob's
Habsburg so
well exploit so why do you need to
establish a rush on
they're just workstations mocked
everywhere yeah
escora unlock everywhere
arm and I guess am to the talk about
papon shells
so we've been doing that since like 99
invading IDS Windows doesn't carry just
doesn't know what fuck a Python
challenge site okay cool
I'll run it whenever I don't even know
how this works in school so you're
I'll yeah it's like
four lines to write a potential Windows
school
whole story you don't need evil exes
just sent Sam so yes there's a huge
keep people from physically lock she
school
remember bomb fucking bomb with ok
sorry I really
this yeah
cool
Chur so what about all the celery
a costume party box
dick so in order to avoid any adverse
reactions the start of chemo
really fucking slow really really slow
like he got like 10 hours just sitting
there in
thinking about what fuckin I do if the
wifi was faster
you know cell phones work by Kim I'm not
have been
am just to fuck with you as much as I
can for 10 hours him over like
maybe I'll read reddit in use my OCD
powers something else
but so so what's shocking is bob Bennett
so bob starts looking at things
search really looking around the room
have you ever looked around the room in
the hospital
this whole lotta things there a key to
fuck with the oxygen gas and there's
things you can play
but there's a lot of things you have
access to Lake
and crash carts in the room late locks
and hard to pick
surprised right but that easy
its easy arm
so IV drips there Cherie
apparently there's a
remote consul for this fucking thing and
it uses serial teather
but it's really stupid like it's
really dumb there's no password on it at
all
show ob-gyn wanna join me by you people
will get into what bob can do in
your so Bob might've bought this exact
machine on e-bay
and that's where the lawyers said that
he can talk about that
bull talk about it for dead to
so she I just hope your
because I'm not bob llama day
just I'm I'm not that big a dick so
these are fun right Bluetooth USB
Aiken bugs easily drop on these on these
fucking things
because I was like what 10 bucks and Ali
Baba over
yeah we'll get into the act sacking
might have to turn off the cameras so
this is great
I'll apparently I the
barcode scanner doesn't Dalian port it
blue screened
for you
but Julia because you know its 2013 at
this point I guess now announced
for timber until you're not a fuck ties
to be honest I don't know what I did
with them I I really don't know if US
can I have no idea
happen the regular party actually
is a might be a one-party it has
I'd winning
the memo
party K seriously
manage passwords clearly that machines
for staff use
so that mission was wide open for 45
minutes
forty 5 minutes
I am yeah
so I to get into him machine giusto
reporting
com not the river shells really hasn't
decreased
moved talk about them which cameras
has been an actual pen test
hospital with unknown sural back doors
had been dropped
PHP would be to would-be attackers for
taking an
you guys know pH eyes worth way more
than a credit card in the black market
rate
make wish more credit cards were like 30
cents display
Ukiah five dollars record release thanks
this is just one health care facility
I bob with the mattress I have performed
and their facility maintains that there
have a complaint
make every sis Jimmy
kick chill the camera we can go into
one-stop thats Sox
yet Canton China of
can we turning off fuckin
up so whenever
fuck it sup
bob on an IV drip on the Internet
because you know
EVA's fun track right you by fucking
anything on e-bay
by but the exact same model
on e-bay with the console software
an up parent me
awesome that's fine
s fine whatever at school
at school we're all friends here I A
nah it's fine
as whatever its cool at school at school
that's fine norse no worse
where are we 0 some Bob got
the software all speaking which a buddy
of mine
some us know would like to would like me
to would like bob to bring this I V chip
So Def Con
so we'll talk but I guess after if you
guys on the self medicate
at school I'll but yes a side note
okay so bob but this trip bob spent
eighteen hundred dollars on it is what's
best
and whenever point being bob has
insulted
I am but it came with a console software
which for an probably for Windows 95 I
am
so from the IV drip which is
really slimmed-down BST colonel you can
establish
tell Mac connection to the machine
learning the consuls
software the machine running the consuls
software and
of my own been able to figure out how to
track it back to pH
means this summer the bigger hospitals
actually use them on their own thing so
they can shirt from the nursing station
see you have access to
whoever's hooked up to whatever IV drip
Marc Maurer
sugar-free marching our year
your could be worse I really don't think
you can dive
morphing over overdose can you okay
whenever
okay so maybe that is one way to kill
somebody combined with
combined with the remote access that you
have from the parking lot I
Bob just killed someone from the parking
lot
chic
this
so
Bosch training we
work on mobile you walk into a health
care provider
it'll automatically identify all open
access points
run yes across town sheesh see we can
get
along with the combination somehow sent
to see if that hospital or healthcare
facilities been pop before
and just pop morning if you should do
business but just wants to make the
world a better place
bob's done yeah i win
South
if someone wants to help bob with the
objective seekers apparently
bob does not cause for iowa's all home
be willing except help I'll
I'll sup the raspy way area okay how
many
raspy steed Bob drop first-hand he had a
first-hand
with saying
an IV drip
Bob might bring to towns someone wants
to self-medicate
kids me
least company sturdy
to sell two implementations
boxed standards did
necessarily have to hop established
telnet session
I was able to run over the same so
way all opted your
purse on camera bobbed budget your
its its interesting did your stack is
really weird like it was prior in 1995
it's a
really we're teachers sure
thats internets heart that's why I'm a
little three pilot winning fact ha
randomly
such a productive
under the under the nursing station
thingy
actually still have actually did you get
home
up by it's not on this matter but the
Sun is back
actually one that's in my back that's
about back Park Bob
box just be an ass stop being an asshole
yes check
I'm ready should I come up here sure
do not remove yes %uh when it when I
give the stock a b-side shake actually
slows
Jake actually had a really good idea but
bob hasn't done any external discovery
cents
if bob woodruff labeled those recipes
do not remove they probably will still
be up
maybe thanks guys
so if you wanna download
if you wanna grab the code