our next does be heard that we're going
to kind of move into a slightly
different direction everybody knows from
the schedule it's a little here and
there because all these things really
interest me the question was how much
can a bad guy do here in the states
without breaking any laws my friend Jake
said oh I can do WMD from a costco
welcome Jake showing us out of WMD from
costco yeah DS plural devices portal
plural for his affiliation I'm not
allowed to say he may or may not choose
will go with one of the somebody would
get ones always it's Sammy would shit if
Miss one do you yesterday this large
software manufacturer are you hopefully
this'll Funky Bunch boiler we get
version point one you're walking let's
see your mighty got a point a that you
fell be nice to stories now and why here
on here is there on the budget that's
because we all use piratebay don't worry
about a slam like they can't drive a
pirate boat up here so I can they can
get here then you ganna be so well then
maybe I'll send my word you say yeah
actually Kim Tim's talk you have a great
intro for some of this stuff because I'm
not talking about the the how I rather
I'm not talking about the why the
motivation i'm talking about that how
but there's there's a lot of freak i
really enjoyed in stone um i'm jake one
of the many titles i use internet
detective I've been doing security
physical and digital security for
way too fragile yeah you go speak well
fine then I will yeah I know you're that
because all right everybody's um
affiliated with the internet detective
agency Black Lodge research a
hackerspace up in redmond washington sec
block gorilla research and development
one of the founders one of the three
founders of both of those orgs on staff
at Def Con etc etc a first period lasted
gmail com is how you reach me I know the
spelling of my last name is a little
difficult it's not very common the
concept after win approached me I want
to care like terrorized large city but I
don't have that kind of international
funding it doesn't seem too bad an issue
you guys recognize the the hierarchy of
needs yeah you want to exactly you want
to flip it on its ass there's a whole
bunch of points I used one of the great
the frameworks that's out there
wikipedia has also got a great freaking
article on it is the Carver methodology
Carver + chaos because you have the
accumulative effect of Carver afterwards
I don't have slides on that but if
you're not familiar i strongly recommend
looking into it the entire talk is
considerably longer than an hour i took
some of the highlights best of the cheap
shit that you can do a lot of
destructive damage with electricity and
because of that water health and safety
and Trust of the same emergency services
that are going to try and take care of
you in the event of emergencies and
telecommunication how dependent we are
on all the devices in all of our pockets
and tablets and the rest of it no I lose
it again area cars the first one up so
the and of course converting my flight
is always fun um their grid you have
generation all the pack all the plants
that are pumping high high high voltage
you have transmission lines to
distribute it to where it needs to go
and then you have district
mission which is the considerably less
voltage going out to your homes and
everything else the big point is the
gigantic weak link is in between
generation and transmission from what I
found this is a phase attenuating
voltage regulator or voltage regulation
transformer a lot of people in the
industry in the energy industry called a
pervert or poverty but Herbert works
turning that into this this is a photo
from action mechanical default or defect
that caused this gigantic failure this
was in Asia I believe knocked out power
for I guess the equivalent of a state
aside the physical size of a state that
we have here in the US for two to three
weeks I believe it's a kind of for scale
for size you can see there's a five-foot
something man you know the size of a
small house a gigantic oil tank on top
which is used for the sorry see the
firewall is now yeah they're not they're
not a deterrent for attack it's just in
the event of damage or burning for once
that it does not damage the other now
this is from these are smaller perverts
i'm going to use programs and Fabregas I
think it's fucking hilarious these are
smaller ones that are used tell by the
nationalities not necessarily us guy
it's this is asia great identifier is
these grounding bolts so you can use
this as a spot if you're going to choose
an attack we're going to choose a target
for tag it's really easy to identify
these things especially if your point
you not necessarily tack it up close and
personal but from a great distance white
but great being the range of an 18 18
late eighteen hundreds rifle using
technology has been around longer than
most most modern power distribution to
take out that
they never these gigantic takes on top
is an oil rigs of work and that's all
I'll get into that in a second I guess
there's also from the perverts their
circuit breakers so in the event of
failure these will fire that's an older
design it's driven by oil I rather be
insulator is oil there's a modern design
these here it's getting the exact same
job accomplished a much smaller amount
of space these are not filled with oil
foot they're filled with a inert gas
sorry the point beam has an insulator
the amount of voltage going through
these things circuit breaker has to pop
if that was happened in an open-air
environment they would explode this
thing would shoot up you know 50 feet in
the air there'd be massive damage the
problem being is that that's just a tiny
little thin piece of metal protecting
that inert gas storage same as you have
mild tempered steel or mild steel
protecting the oil reservoir for the
circuit breakers so if those were to be
damaged by your typical terrorist you
can take out a staged over here so
that's a yeah that's a 22 I I would
assume for the at the range we're
talking maybe at 22 250 but a small
caliber rifle with a can you could make
them out of it whatever I won't get into
silencer design but those are a lot more
easily damaged from a moderate distance
than the older style circuit breaker Oh
miners in West Virginia some years ago
do this for real it shot transformers
with their rifles listened they could
just explode and they were in groups of
four and they could take on all four of
us we've actually a real world
demonstration there's actually several
last year something October last year in
Los Angeles they're all I guess San
Francisco area where there was
I guess FBI is considering it a trial
run attack we're a group that has not
been identified they figured it was two
to four people with small caliber
weapons firing hundreds of rounds I
don't know i don't have the friends of
information on that but they took out a
small much significantly smaller
substation taking out power for two to
three days i believe and in addition to
that also cut a section of fiber optic
cable which damaged AT&T back back all
communications for I believe that same
amount of time well under a week on the
on the right we have it's a mehsana got
from late 1800s 762 by 54 are with a can
which is more than enough that you'll
need to penetrate one of those one of
those oil tanks same thing with the I'm
going to roll back here because I wanted
to have you done any chiding no special
forces on this I'm sorry have you done
any Chinese no special courses or try to
shoot yeah well um let's cover that
right now yeah so I wanted to throw in
an extra slide and I think I will but on
the on the poverty these are ya pervert
yes on the pervert your typical perverts
you can tell by his mustache um you have
a gigantic oil reservoir and on the
right behind these fans let's all
galvanized steel for the majority of it
are a series of radiators so you'll know
if there's a ton of photos online if you
look for this this style design they all
look very similar sometimes the oil tank
is off to the side in most cases it's
about because they're letting gravity do
the work for them you could puncture a
hole at the bottom of the base of the
oil reservoir one of the top so it
evacuates the oil more quickly and
punching a hole right near the bottom of
the radiator you can shoot through the
fan it's a
it is just galvanized there's no
additional hardening around this this is
in much more of a secure location
because you can you're going to have to
basically be on I believe this is the
photo with the road there's a interstate
or a highway so you're going to be
coming at it from a lunch considerably
longer distance the majority of these
are in isolated places they're not near
a major city they're near much
considerably closer to power generation
when I first was looking at this as an
analysis point I focused more on the
Pacific Northwest so these are off in
woodland areas there's not a lot of
people there's a minimum crew of four or
five constantly on staff these these
buildings are manned power generation
24-7 in case it blows up but all you
would need to do is remove the fluid
necessary to cool these devices they
will overheat and you know it explode
the problem is that it's the size you
can see by that that scale photo it's
the size of a small house and it weighs
a considerable amount of it they are
very very difficult to drop in a
replacement and in most specifically in
the Pacific Northwest there are not very
many replacements on hand like where
they made yes yes there's actually
there's a couple Chinese sites we even
buy a considerably smaller one if you
wanted to set up like a mini power grid
fewer test range yeah or a exactly if
you wanted to do some testing it so you
take out one they're going to need if
they were working around the clock and
had all the equipment on hand two days
to replace and then they have no
replacement these things need to be
brought in on a gigantic carrier they
are not they're not easily replaced but
it is the a gigantic just sorry I get I
get frustrated when I when I see how
poorly we secure our infrastructure
that's physical attack it
sorry Zoey any power infrastructure
they're all we use these here the older
circuit design is much more prevalent in
in other countries not North America
because of the cheapness of the design
these modern ones have been replaced
because they're a lot cheaper to
manufacture and bacon well there we're
talking what a 30-year replacement life
cycle but again Pacific Northwest the
majority of the infrastructure the
hardware infrastructure is greater than
50 years old 50 to 60 plus it would be
yeah the power administration's up there
for in that case there is a single
pervert that is driving the majority of
fee Pacific Northwest grid in northern
washington so they have one and a backup
so you take out one wait for them to
replace it with backup take that out in
there Jake how many of these are around
the u.s. you have any clue that I don't
have any figures on I be I'd be really
yeah that's another thing I'm actually
going to look up one that's a very good
point Jake what one or two manufacture
these worldwide that again I don't know
tell you I the exact are the designs
themselves regulated by government now I
believe it's all private industry now
there's there some very basic stamps
going into these there's not there's not
a lot to them in a general sense
everybody every manufacturer has their
own secret sauce right but they all
function on the same basic principle
right is I know you're going to get to
this probably but the hardening or the
controls that you would see needing to
be put in place there's no government
agency that would actually enforce those
putting in being put in place is that
what are you sure it won't come on the
daily wells was not i'll get to how much
I don't like near except a minute
report from DHS they're released as a
belief system which could replace
remember a 24-ounce not to be now now
they track if they had one ruler yeah
testing okay but it's going to be some
kind of government responsibility so try
to before you would find is in test labs
are available and if you would consider
volunteering for the IC h JW g I know if
anyone else is rumored recommend you I'm
personally recommend use the head of
research of to clear up see about 10
minutes after finishing presentation
program you can send it to him and see
what Cynthia yeah if you end up on us
I'm always happy to talk about bad ideas
ya know I use winds name are you
anything but I'm Minister publishing my
new talks on moon in our students how
many of them would you have to take out
as a really so in the in the scenario of
taking out taking out power for the
greater seattle area 11 device and then
48 hour minimum 48 hour but what about
comes on the great thing is you be
looking face variants absolutely
absolutely there will a quickie about
the position patrick going there and
obviously lower to the US can comment on
it once the rules city still secret up
an effective a phase difference become
family second dream okay there yet the
inner thighs regulate that so pacific
northwest there's i guess i could roll
back I should start throwing the same
slide right letter P maybe and the other
century though is looking loading out
rid from the native questions yeah there
we go keyboard shortcut leave so I'm
sorry where was the what was where is
the question that i was going to need to
get to that was the oh yeah taken one
out on me there's for this section of
northern washington we're talking one
pervert one for the
the much larger greater seattle area
most people may know this but for those
who don't texas is isolated from the
other 47 I'm surprised you're not play
well with others ever separate I just
want surprise me so so you just need to
get a couple Texans with a with a late
eighteen hundreds rifle I actually
talked to the guy who runs that he was
one to one of my science classes they
have four simultaneous hot sites that
are run concurrently toward managing all
of this in terms of monitoring
everything and trying to look at that
infrastructure it's pretty significant I
would think you'd work your way around
Texas it's that's a hard target remain a
date has they got it all under one roof
they especially wanted to do a small man
and remove yeah yeah if you if you want
to focus on a small small group 4 or 5
guys that are committing gigantic
impactful acts of terrorism definitely
don't go where they all have guns yeah
that's a very good point or or come up
with some sort of a chemical deterrent
you can gasps Thunder gasps them before
you fire your laser here oh yeah I guess
yeah if you're able to kill off one of
them you don't even need to spend the
fifty dollars a rifle plus ammo you can
just take their such concentrates
Washington and Colorado everybody's
slower going well Colorado they also
have a bunch of their just watch me
watch our oh man oh oh that's right
that's right they legalized the weed I
got a baby with you couls so anyway um
the the inner type you were talking
about so responsiveness when that when
that goes down there is a twenty-five
twenty-five percent based on publicly
available information I've been able to
find comes from coal power from Montana
colorado area so the inner tie is just a
gauge dependent that will determine the
load on each side of the theater tie and
if it's dropping it's going to increase
the load that's coming from the other
energy supplier there are some key
junctures that if you time arrival
cascade pretty significant inside most
of these larger stations
there is a the inner tie box where that
gauge exists and you can watch it it's
pretty much 5050 but you can see you can
see my new fluctuations in it it's a
usually there's no big manufacturer of
the inner tie device there is but the
box for regulation and tying in with the
existing network is all hand tailored
most of which that I've seen it's just a
gigantic silver box at the top or bottom
of Iraq and has one button on it that
says enter tie off or inter tie power
off so if you're able to compromise the
security the building find the box and
physically push the button it's a single
button to destroy the inner tie so if
the inner thighs down powers down
there's no way to get the power back on
without a cold start many times I think
there'd be no edit that be nothing well
I got a bunch of different solutions for
no internet face all of your texts
revolve in these two shows hmm so in
terms of reaction or network and
real-time reporting you've just defined
a requirement therefore they need some
odds with myself for the show oh that's
why I I tried to find as many photos of
non scary black rifles so so i'm using
late eighteen hundreds rifles with a
cheap a scan on the suppressor again
that way that way you're hearing much
less report if any with a with a 22 to
take out the modern circuit breakers all
you're going to hear is the impact on
that weeks that weeks dealer oral is
going to be Melissa's for the only
absolutely now if you're if you're going
to take a series of circuit breakers
down we're talking 50 60 shots possibly
which is probably not obvious is to
manage needs the botlane exchange
program ice cubes on capabilities of
military and I was probably formally to
the stop that's a very good point the
other thing in your reconnaissance phase
what you're going to do is you're
introduced curious noise at the same
volume and the same frequency range and
if it's going to be boy who cried wolf
eventually going to shut the thing down
taking this cause and others are
problems and I can set up a PA
with a microcontroller and just make it
sound report you hang it from a throw
UAV with a little oh yeah if it's normal
it's impression on itself it needs to be
reported well that's just another system
of sensors that are going to be tied
into SCADA or or I si si si in whatever
which gets speak actually to my digital
side how many people are familiar with
the distributed network protocol be
three languages guess this between 24
vogue and the network if anyone needs it
absolutely I it's a very very good point
please break takers nobody's come out
and it takes for ya circles really I
want to talk more about this afterwards
that's yeah right before I get redacted
yeah I'm sure black bags in April last
year to people that are not security
researchers they are developers found
several series of issues with the
protocol and implementation of the
protocol found finding that with some
additional research after they found it
trying to prove against their their
implementation of software using DMV 3v3
there they were not vulnerable but the
majority and in this case eighty ninety
percent of the majority of vendors are
are vulnerable this is the I'll bring up
an example in a second it took three
four months after they reported in April
when they first found this issue they
reported it the ICS sir it took them
three to four months to actually release
a public advisory I'm so faster than
target yes faster than target yes
whether or not anything has been done
about it I know that a series of vendors
have released patches to their their
systems whether or not those are being
implemented well gets that
and this is the Goblet I believe yes
sorry terms of testing did they like
controls little fuzz testing of the
proto no they found it while trying to
implement d mp3 with their application
well it was it was an issue that is it's
it's specific as most most of these
ip-based vulnerabilities it's also can
be accomplished locally so if you have
cereal access or dial up IP access to
these devices or the sensor net that
you've been compromised it the same way
with the compromise to the gauntlet
server causing it to become unresponsive
until a physical power cycle it has to
reinitialize the the stack I believe not
just sensor stack but also network stack
yes there's also a bunch of other ways
to compromise users response to the
sensor feedback that they're getting for
n i guess i should point out these
sensors are placed on these critical
assets so the the inner tie or the
variety of hundred plus different
sensors that are always in a power
station reporting up the dial gateway
and then a server so a user that's out
in the field or someone in headquarters
can see on the big board current state
of the power network now typically they
rotate yeah we go let's to go after the
dial up so if you can figure out what
the number is a just created an ALICE
service attack by just Ethernet like
this little things trying to phone in
its panic and it's always absolutely
have a pre free implementation of these
systems so I peace covered by newark all
the sensor networks that are connected
to an ipv4 gateway is covered by newark
everything that's still on cereal and
dial-up or IP afterwards but serial
connectivity is not
Adlai I have no idea why but I know that
a lot of power companies have gone back
to the previous implementations their
sensor network because they don't they
no longer have to comply with with nerks
it so we have people that are rolling
back implementations making them more
vulnerable to attack as opposed to
getting with the program obviously cost
is a big driver I know that a lot of
them as well in the Pacific Northwest go
through an elaborate series of
exceptions because as with all of these
federal programs there's an exception
process that we I mean we also deal with
a new corporate world before you get
wanted more wnd craziness is this a
global system I mean is this ensuite no
this is it this is per site I mean you
could implement this I'm seeing the dnp3
yeah the protocol is vulnerable but I
know they're used all around the world
he set the deceivers seems cool siemens
also has an implementation of d mp3 it's
not it's standardized but it's not
regulated so everyone can come up with
their own special sauce for it okay
otherwise lean forward a little bit so
i'll tell you about anyway so just the
board said we've got the ability to for
example on a woman well head high 60 low
controls one might be planful 11 become
okay i might be four monthly mullet is a
flow so I'm the question becomes when
you control the system and if you go all
the way down as far as a way that's
about as far as you go when in control
system becomes compromised you call
nothing so these are trick for some of
them now we're as big to come the
operators that their valves and things
are flying so you totally be able to
lead defense and the main players in the
film in touch through defender are well
known so I don't we encourage you to
look in the industrial defender website
well north of detail I got some very
good expertise
but one of the things and challenges has
been until recently it hasn't been the
tech to inspect its command sets on
Syrian spaces so literally we've got
product range i'm looking now to put out
and extend so it's already deployed in
the Gulf on world aids and we specialize
in all the gas nigeria dealt a place
like that and we're looking for new
applications by Disney's new tech
leading-edge technology it needs to be
deployed events in bed I'm sure your
shall smaller boy well and I and I was
talking about when I was little angry
our exercise in the scanner was the
intrusion through this cold piece of
area yeah now we have a right p in the
both of you going over dial-up it hasn't
meant to visit all three or vulnerable
IP and dialogue isn't different vectors
well I p dial up and cereal so local
winds now serve my fine right others
there's an entire talk there that could
just be done around sensors and attacks
or or hardening hardening thoughts on
minorities just adjust the sensor
network to step back I'll introduce you
to dr. oz who use the chief scientific
advisor for a few jobs this danger isn't
know and I think we can add some extreme
value and you can also act as a clean to
face to the IT security community
because what you'll find is the divers I
know he install the diesels a tricky one
of the Japanese nuclear but if anyone
goes back out there before they were fun
but he's a guy that I've seen to it
installed covering diesel head to toe 3x
table petty officer does ships Diesel's
anything and he doesn't care about the
IT systems he just wants this thing to
work and the scalar challenge is the
ways of thinking these guys will put
stuff in the ground and you said 50
years I've met British Rail they said 25
years they do not care about the IT side
until I agree though and it's chalk and
cheese and this is the cultural barrier
that we have to learn to bridge as I
you know what you can tighten straight
that language yeah we have systems that
are being implemented on 50 60 plus year
old hardware which is designed for
specific intent take a look and keep on
tickin against you know bombs and all
sorts of attack that are then being
adapted to at least function from a
reporting or management standpoint
mostly reporting in some cases
management overall reporting and
alerting I guess some of these position
a little bit better has ended back in
the mid-90s when I work for one of those
descending Northwest cat power companies
we actually had dark fiber between every
sub statute because we what we've done
is release the right way to fiber
infrastructure companies and said yeah
you can string all the fiber you want
you just have to give us X number of
pairs so we actually so private
vibrators I did find it closed control
system to which as long as you have
access to any part of that that line the
my favorite attacks or fiber is an air
of hedge clippers in science I'd in some
of these runs and 2,000 performances
well and a friend of mine it stall them
so we know just the design of it the
code could be very difficult it's old
it's different it's not easy to
compromise well even if you get into
that these security drugs or carry radar
system car 18 inch floppy drive well
that's one thing that I you can look at
so that the keys are being signed
between the device and headquarters
where the goblet masters MC is and then
the remote users have a key issue to
them so that when they connect they show
up on a dedicated list it's mostly
public-private from what I've seen all
you would need to do you can see
actually in this photos the OS that
they're displaying the gauntlet program
on is a windows XP lucky so take your
pick your poison drive by malware I'm
look at ya
yeah yeah we're you need to have a
hardon system well if you're going to
have remote people running around with
laptops in potentially an unlock truck
where there they might be doing line
work and the trucks just there steal a
bag you already have access or you know
what Sweeney more than just a toughbook
so it can they can do more than just
being kicked around have coffee spilled
on it actually needs to be hardened from
a security standpoint Oh with with a lot
of talks that myself and my friends do
we always try and come up with a new
buzzword for each talk and I would
recommend all of you to do the same so
that we can absolutely flood the already
gigantic amount of buzzwords that we
have insecurities with ones that we want
as opposed to using cyber blank for
everything this one's fudgepacker
because it's fucking hilarious II fear
uncertainty and doubt packed into as
much as you possibly can be try and try
and consolidate and pack in as much fun
as possible at least three times per
papers life as much well no but I mean
but the implementation is the
implementation of fud back you know get
into in a second it's a good question
i'll get back to you um one of the
things that i wanted to look at is you
can have all of these these emergency
services organizations that are there to
protect public health and safety but if
the public doesn't trust the people that
are there to help them it's become
useless if people are going to run away
from cops because they have no trust
income or they're going to run away from
a fireman because of some i thought we
could go into scenarios if we want I
only have the hour so I'm happy to go on
to all sorts of terrible terrible ideas
I have with the longer talk one of the
big ones that I really enjoy is
disinformation beer ad abroad for EM
radio or feel sorry for the will exactly
exactly that's a great example
you could do the exact same attack and
people will believe it if it sounds
authentic emergency alert system Amber
Alert or whatever the the other small
one is the yeah absolutely nuclear
attack or Chinese zombies have invaded
and they're eating children or what it
whatever I mean it doesn't you can you
can actually sense every every radio
station broadcasts an emergency alert
test you can relatively cheaply and
easily take a sample of that if they
don't already have templates they may
already have pre-recorded templates
because there's one that happened
yesterday no somebody managed to
convince CNN and it worried else that
there's a shooting at the University of
Oklahoma I some solid and the White
House shutdown notices and everything
unless news reports I said last name for
what the bed or sheriff's coming out
going yeah that's a great pretty
compulsion that you've been leveraged
against your paddle shootings reports of
shootings is a test well absolutely
people will respond with their current
methodology yes the threat their
potential threat exists true someone
says I shake it's obviously they may
have suspected possible well yeah but
it's the we didn't know about it but CNN
knows about it get people desensitized
there really is a shooting chef I story
absolutely because they're absolutely
press room hmm yep then there's complete
public distrust in all of the emergency
services or at least the notification
for the public of the emergencies are
based first yeah it's it it's perpetual
april fools except April terror I guess
I don't I don't know what the I'll come
up with another buzzword for that one
too that's April flood packing April
flood back and first or yeah there's a
there's a great talk that was a 30 C 3
gasps communication congress late last
year on news tweaked and I'll cover that
in a moment it's a Wi-Fi hotspot that
will grab onto any public Wi-Fi and
using layer 2
layer to our pre Direction fill in a
bunch of actually very similar to the
device that win was talking about your
privacy guard was it what was the name
of that oh the Hat app blocker from a
drag it does the exact opposite of that
and a remote user can once its installed
get to that in bucket will do this in
the rollback there's not it there's not
a lot of great photos of the device
itself but it's they just put it into
existing bare metal plugs for an
accessory device allowing power pastor
because it's very it's embedded system
very low power you can yeah s-series oh
Christ proud legacy I give the pair that
son Oh is well took it out of a book
since folks haven't been been
transmitted fuck really hahaha luckily
like how do but it there XP when this
this implementation is large and obvious
the system contained inside of it is not
necessary for this for the size of the
box it's it's maybe the size of a deck
of cards maybe and yeah of course you
can see the the input was the
implementation of it yeah it's China
track Beijing to invest in US army
because that's always fun oh and this is
a radio transmitter that you can buy a
variety of them from China they you can
go down to to a hundred mil wat but the
price range for half a lot of to a
thousand-watt you're talking 70 bucks to
seventeen hundred dollars still very
affordable RDS for display anybody have
a anybody still listen to FM radio here
okay so in your in your vehicle it will
also tell you station identification
information if your browser that's
that's what RDS is those modules are
about 60
so if the emergency alert system kicks
off you can also implement the text
equivalent string of whatever is going
on or whatever you want them to believe
is occurring and according from the FCC
between a hundred and thousand watts
you're talking to coverage of a service
area between three and a half to a
little under nine miles that's pretty
effective area especially if you push
that yeah they this same manufacturer
that makes these also make a adapter
board that you need a much lower power
output because it does all the work for
you and it goes up to like 500 watt 600
watt and it's about about six hundred
dollars yeah yeah and and all these have
standard audio 3.5 million whatever you
want we could spend hours going over
potential yeah potential attack
scenarios pick the latest fear and go
with that one stand side so org or it's
yeah 90 degrees or there's a heat wave
coming or there's a gigantic tsunami we
can get back into Center networks and
trigger off the alarms that are you know
handling all the tsunami response for
people who live on the coast that was
one of my potential effects nerds I love
that um let's see here Oh actually
before I get into noise generators with
Internet wide scanning and a lot of you
guys would think you know we probably
patch the majority of our home
networking equipment the average user
has no concept of this so when
vulnerabilities get released for home
routers as there was three or four that
come to mind in the last two months you
could scan for instance the entire
internet looking for the high end
communication port that's open and see
also the majority of these are remote
code execution so you can do these fruit
whatever stolen credit card and flat
instance you purchased you
install and he's open source that
software it's also very not that
complicated at all for even a low to
moderate user or low to moderate
security professionals to indo month as
a scenario now the multicast has
benefited as you I think they see to now
that some of the networks are ipv6 and 0
public is frightening so tell the cell
phones of b6 but be four presumably you
can address the statewide set which is
at one go absolutely absolutely well n
and with ipv6 ipv4 encapsulation you can
do the same attack that you would hear
with an ipv4 system and let those the
rest of the hard way through the work
for you so by the time it actually ends
up hitting the home user ipv4 or ipv6 oh
yeah home user yeah bracket s bracket
absolutely taking this and say you
upload code so now you have remote
command command and injection capability
for all the modern news sites that
everyone's browsing before they go to
work while they're on their way and the
best bit no one's going to track it is
your basic absolutely well and not to
mention monitoring capability for v6 is
limited at best let's let's go with that
hmm well there's that there's a variety
of there's a variety of home routers
that you can purchase and then sell
it'll spin up an additional access point
for free that's throttled and you can
inject ads to get revenue for yourself
based on that doing the exact same thing
except obviously packing in as much fun
as you can yeah yeah or channels yes
give to give a variety of creative
writers access to it and they could they
could come up with their new stories
each weekend actually if you really
wanted to go deep on that
just alter the stories that are being
displayed with your information as
opposed to brand new stories that are so
shocking that no one would believe at
the beginning case we configure the
network every second hmm well absolutely
there's a I could do a series of talks
and I'm probably not even the best
person for that by far for just the home
router base vulnerabilities and all the
tech possibilities that exist in trouble
systems because every solutely the guy
that takes his gauntlet laptop home and
I had and his son also happens to play
whatever you know online game with it
yeah exactly they're playing candy crush
on their phone or on their laptop in the
gauntlet app also is installed you have
to compromise because you have direct
access to their private network because
their home router is compromised in
public facing yeah everyone's home
network just 441 vulnerability to came
out 3-4 months ago I used a cloud
instance and scanned the entire public
address space no no because the majority
of cloud providers will give you a month
of free compute time so you can give
them a gift card and they'll give you a
month for free and as long as you don't
exceed the cost you can use it for a
month the bandwidth is not that
intensive if you're scanning for one
port then you generated the list of
about 70 for 75,000 hosts worldwide that
were vulnerable to this remote code
execution and based on my sample group
let's call it private internal testing
sample group roughly sixty to eighty
percent are vulnerable to this attack so
we're talking 52,000 public-facing
worldwide routers that can be yes that
as an estimate and then if we didn't ish
everything a woman it which is your next
day we could probably all the best the
best part is you don't need to upload an
additional tools if if you weren't if
you were connected to the router
directly you don't need to upload
additional tools because most of them
are busy box installs that have at least
basic networking tool
agree shoot capability so we could just
do the next step Nick whatever tunnel to
network connection absolutely critical
just absolutely right over to you ssl
strip take their sorry there's no hope
you really need to secure network system
of my exes and they're not doing it and
there's no infrastructure zolecki I best
the ugly one you're gonna look at
Charlie you there well everyone it's not
just the Chinese yeah if I was you know
more malicious in implementation than
Justin in creative thought anyone can do
this the proof of concept script that
that guy implemented specifically for
that vulnerability you can run out of
the box I could teach my mother to use
it with about 10 minutes of crazy folks
everyone advertised itself is the bubble
wrap for everything in its area pgp I
mean you you that would be fifty three
thousand bucks yeah that would be such a
pretty that's a pretty substantial
botnet yeah so your one wish the swords
of you Kelly wasn't it that it yeah well
yeah dude let's get on to noise
generators for a moment this model is
sold in the US and is also it's a
refrain from China it's two and a half
thousand dollars sorry would you expect
to pay like this or the more
cost-effective solutions that anyone can
purchase and of course you also could
purchase this if you wanted to spend way
more money than you need to this is
basically full spectrum for
communication for a civilian
implementation of obviously there's of
course military applications that are
outside of these bands and high and
super low and the rest of it you if you
were going to go choose a specific
target that's outside of so regular band
this is more of a stone this is more of
it sorry oh yes yes yes
terms of being application for these by
the way a regular if you want as a
prohibited by federal law in a lot of
cases because they could jam law
enforcement or other communication so
goes Joe Sixpack is not supposed to have
well and and the FCC is a lot better
that I've seen in movies that enforcing
their own laws than they are in real
life I don't even know if I'm sure they
have listening stations everywhere a
similar device the name of schools over
hour ago so we would have a classified
discussion it wouldn't come up scrap you
just walk up little locks on the thing
and press the little buttons if it was
that is jen's all cell phones of a
30-meter radius so if you forgot to
leave your cell phone your cell phone
was rooted doesn't matter as long as
there's not a hardware bug system or or
live recording rights all wireless
transmission you can create yeah like a
poor man's skiff room get that's what
they did yep um however this price point
this price point is ridiculously high I
wouldn't i would recommend that each of
you if you were ever considering
purchased in purchasing one each other
is sorry this one also is this price is
the Chinese price yes that's without
shipping so they are using their IDs the
rebranded one costs a little over ten
thousand i think and comes with a fancy
Pelican case which is you know three
hundred bucks yeah yeah why buy one when
you can buy two it way more than they
needed because I what monster than
anything costs this is a 3 watt model
it's about two hundred dollars I've seen
them between 140 and two hundred three
hundred dollars you get most of the same
civilian coverage for communications and
it has an effective range of thirty to a
hundred and thirty feet all depending on
is this is this guy covers all of these
bands and actually do I have I'll get
into bamboo fiber second this covers all
major communication bands as well as the
entire to put four gig spectrum
so y Wi-Fi and Bluetooth obviously not
sorry police channels that be 800 so a
portion of the message so mirja up so
why midpoint is response emergency
responses though if I had the if I has
be suspect on the frequency Reese you
can compare it to the frequency range
till i haff disease and employee a
better make this is a somewhere in bad
guy that you can do ask if which is a
good guy absolutely or you can really
fuck with the system and part of the
square with the system is to screw the
first responders that's in order to make
your primary and thank works yep and
you'll see is our girl i know i gather
anyone unless the IED is or or
specifically designed to receive a go or
no go signals from another wireless
device and then when it's interrupted
then triggers well as a head man
switched out what's legality of these
things um from what I found from the
FCC's documentation and their public
statements are always much more broad
and vague than the actual written law
from what I've seen and currently
understand possession is not against the
law the moment that this device whatever
potentially hypothetically speaking be
activated then there's violation of our
goals civil or ground I believe it's
criminal is SEC typically does civil law
I believe it's like with what state
monitoring whatever you're only getting
free on what's really going on that's
why if everyone in in my effective range
consents I believe it still violates
federal law because it can interfere one
of the stipulations is the interferes
with emergency like 911 an availability
service so if your cell phone you have a
heart attack when this thing just not
related unless you have a pacemaker and
it happens to work wirelessly or you're
closing down in everett washington
bridge at the same time yeah yeah yes
it's it's yeah how you doing yes it's
illegal even if it's consensual yes yes
I mean and I mean this very serious it's
the cellular Gina would prove
you can't turn it on can you bridge that
mental gap Arizona ok there's a medigap
it's a federal water where it doesn't
lead to make sense yeah in Washington we
were for a long period of time able to
own suppressors but not actually a fix
and use them with our weapons that also
applied to law enforcement you could own
a suppressor in the state of Washington
up until two years ago three years ago
but you could not you you could not do
so i'll apply our weapon with one attack
and look at even if you regularly
allowed purposes y'all let you hold it
just don't turn it on i guess if you
turned on i don't know i can eliminate
an accessory Jake down put your couples
you don't even know what right good call
last time in West evade police what so
could end of the day way to not a labor
why do not touch that's why I have the
gigantic warning light or mile up
comedian tens on 40 minutes um besides
the matrix cellular bands and covering
Wi-Fi it also peppers which one of the
two major band chunks of GPS so you've
bought the most expensive paperweight
and then you know as far as any Leo is
concerned yet oh yeah it's just a paper
it's a display item click art book old
art you know render man's work right yes
alright 80s what their traffic control
system the air traffic you're told and
though the avionics and calm control at
GPS control from playing yeah near the
dress that please well if you're on the
plane I liked it as with you as good a
test if you're on the plane you just
have to you would have to find out
whatever the app the either boosted
power all of us hang out on the rocks
will it screw with plans to i'm going to
say yes but it warrants further research
or the backyard i have not I have not
ever
turned it on anywhere near or anything
like that maybe we all listen to this I
don't want to get a facility I want to
be the guy talking about fresh and play
not the guy that's crashing plane
because I'm a show demo this is another
cyber d das or lost one way or another
another part if he's due back tomorrow
and if I'm a bad guy that's a nice tool
one wait if you'll realize I was
thinking though you would need a lot of
GPS antennas primarily or direction and
so you would need a lot of power to
overcome an aircraft pdps in my bag is
are generally appointed not quite slug
is that's true or I mean I don't know
yeah okay when you buy a pot would you
buy a pocket you turn it upside down for
a GPS it really doesn't work that well
and you can buy tops for a laptop to
exactly how know unidirectional they let
you I'm freely travel on airplanes
domestic flights all the time with this
and even smaller devices you could set
up one on a timer with a microcontroller
how often do flight attendants check
each and every pouch you get a first
class ticket leaving in one of the
patches it goes off in three hours when
the next the next leg of that question
yeah yeah yeah actually I was a lien on
the aircraft you could probably screw
with it that's all that is a better that
I'm you're not willing to see me so I
don't want to be on the plane we did
this we do okay most stick that I'm
neither the attack let's go much faster
like your system well it's actually
jumping power directly to the same ships
that we all have in our cell phones yeah
on you have to care about three hops
it's not a single sauce walka publishes
the on strike for their communication
standard because a lot of fun
manufacturers use those all company and
this me yes yes I aww yeah I should have
taken a photo with a with us so but that
I Oh port on the back is RS 232
so for skit and those two connectors are
our I believe nan over so there's an
ability as a mechanized so we're talking
the device that's okay say no more than
I don't advise the kids but that size we
get one about the size you can place you
have to the origin and missing if you
want to have a scaled-down version of
these these they have power amps that
have a lot smaller end to the output but
25 watt would be more than enough I just
want the point yeah you can get you to
you could do a board design well that's
easily flushable why this stuff scares
me that's the so with with this I have
an effective range of wealth potential
effective range of 300 to 500 feet I
have a potential effective range of 300
to 500 feet for this if one looks so
inclined dip or or just put a magnet on
the back and stick it on a metal roof or
there's a bunch of different ways that
you can this is a watertight seal
container you can put it wherever you
want we'll work from underwater RF noise
you know yeah it's how that matter it
for the ELO really underwater without
without my modifications the standard
battery pack that comes in that mob day
and he'll know that as a battery life of
about two hours two to three hours
depending on environmental positions in
the output at oh shit i'm currently
looking at this this build right here-
blazers this box right here all parts
included is cost about a hundred and
fifty dollars to make the additional
modifications with a larger battery and
a panel plate just a digital furniture
to make it look sexy or it's going to
bump up the cost about 200 * $200 flat
the government will pay a thousand yeah
yeah I should start the set up a web for
an ncsa sell them under wins name
possession on small biz
p months we've got a customer for each
other okay all right yeah I'll come up
with a paypal account for this is an RF
to serial transceiver so that that
amplifier had niño for for command
control and monitoring on you can
remotely kick a embedded or play a
well-placed device off remotely with a
range of about six to twelve kilometers
runs on DC and the application for this
is damn near limitless there's so many
things that run on cereal that road
signs those are those emergency alert
signs was actually they're not clear so
you're using there will be one on each
end so you're sending commands over
cereal then on to RF and all of the
devices that pick this up so you can
kick off say 80 of them around the city
from one location as you're driving away
it's that cigarette thrown out of the
car under the gasp I'll see certain and
you think that well yeah absolutely
there's a bunch of wireless devices then
the wireless RF to serial bridges that
are used for Barry so what's actually do
want anybody know here that's causing
the issue i guess so so good yeah yes so
you have one plugged into the amp and
you send the go whatever i haven't
looked at the service just a comm
channel yeah it's just a comm channel
you're using it from gauger center place
devices I gotta most devices Escom I'm
Oh controlling through this I mean I
don't think we're 32 is much calm
anymore I'm sorry it sure is you would
yeah you would be surprised it's
everywhere still everywhere because it's
cheap you could build your own hundred
watt briefcase or four or five hundred
dollars now this is not this is not for
the most part 12 volt it's 120 volt but
it's fits in a briefcase that's with the
omni antenna it's a week antenna you
could probably get a much better
coverage with a larger antenna panel
pack so get a deep stack briefcase
you're talking maybe six hundred dollars
but versus the price point of
500 for the same equivalent power output
this is way more cost effective I also
do like the fact that this photo
includes the DC to AC adapter so you can
plug it into a vehicle have a briefcase
in the passenger seat yeah I've just
covered all these points and with the
with that RF with that RF transceiver
you can engage as many devices you place
around a large metropolitan area or an
attack site remotely what could possibly
go wrong having one of these engaged
with an RF transceiver and like I was
saying earlier a magnet on the back of
one of these stuck under the emergency
service command vehicle so the fire
marshal or the sheriff they respond to
an incident and then you kick it off so
none of his comms work to communicate
with the rest of that whoever else is
engaged with this gigantic fire sale
that you're committing across a large
attack areas and of course there's a
bunch a bunch of applications that I'd
love to discuss everyone's bad ideas so
I mean it's damn near limitless also the
detecting the frequency thank you that
song Texas you're talking about the
overpowering locally absolutely if
you're able to knock out on a larger
radius with this connectivity does a
tower you could obviously use a femto or
microcell implementation that has enough
power to break through this at a local
implementation than a hard-line back to
route calls and do all the rest of your
man in the middle of that see how
initiative is the pump is gone sorry
counselor major is like the HBO from 85
it's the same sort of stuff that's now
tiny you if it was a high enough power
up but yeah you could just you could
overwhelm me build a directional antenna
it's kind of sweet like this Jake is the
overload factors still six TV and
voltage terms or 3d be in power what is
it just about yes but it's actually a
little bit over each one
North take over it's so it's whatever
the manufacturers software
implementation the driving the hardware
is but yeah it's about that range okay
even with standing next to a tower
because right next to a tower you
actually could have minimized signal
versus because they're directional their
own arm you know where's many others
lawyers its own parramatta McMahon well
when we were talking back here 15 18
years ago about her vm team with a large
scale but now what's that world having
been it has been migrated to censor bars
a little Zuzu more every minute is
you're looking and ok there's my drone
there's my thing but everything else is
happening down here now that it's all
completely calm base the concept of EMP
irv unless you're trying to take out a
power grid without it requires an
amazing amount of power this suddenly
becomes a hell of a lot more efficient
way to do it yes and you're going to
direct it in your weapons we recognize
the need in the within the US military
we spent a boatload of money on it and
that has certain that's great from but I
this is for a poor man's thing it
doesn't mean that we have to go to the
metal bed well with what i would say in
15 years also so Joseph is here the
preventive measure of saying we can just
ban this stuff obviously doesn't work
and with just command and control for
the RF transceivers they're also
implemented in complete legitimate
legitimate applications and are not
regulated good question i remember back
in the tempest days a year old enough
never that tempest was illegal and all
that hard to do all the stuff that we
did it anyway whatever and there was
some companies up and around DC area at
specialize in selling tempest equipment
so i did a look-see lot as consulting to
hughes and they were selling like 30,000
of these things a year I'm not trying to
figure out where the hell are they all
gone and modern equivalent with hold on
a sec so these give any clue what the
sales figures I that I don't know I know
that china is always well stocked from
any of the variety of distributors as
you're gonna find out by tomorrow I mean
I could find out here after the talk I
mean whatever published sales going on
say if they publish any other three
being sold 302 hacker
or 30,000 to holy shit who so I'm sorry
day but just one that's good paratype
leg seems to be something to use we use
anything but it didn't they solve the
issue instead of buying tempest or a
Faraday cage on the boxed and they just
build the build a command center that's
protected there's a hole so that way you
can buy off-the-shelf hardware and stuff
in ocean and sorry if you challenge well
and it's any other signal how easy to
detect a signal and pinpointed another
Tony season to get to him to take you
out firmly it's fairly easy to man okay
very fairly easy i mean it's constantly
generating signal it's not like a Wi-Fi
Wi-Fi intruders you they can do that
should first thing it triangulate but
you absolutely absolutely if you're not
able to talk to the person that's that's
also going for this gear and you're
trying to talk over ham or FRS or cells
or whatever and none of that's working
you're going to have to set up a gear
set up here run over to the other guy
and compare notes or have a hard line
what have you originally we were talking
because it's talked about a lot of this
the early days in over in Sweden was if
you're going to do a directed-energy
weapon her vm p sort of fell attack
against the target of some sort whether
it's a government target or civilian
target at what point does the network
engineer start saying this is not an IP
problem this is an EMC problem at one
point of the thing and then how do you
find it so shit that's a whole mess of
new equipment with some new expertise
and then nobody's I mean how many p.m.
te w world's going to have some defenses
but who else not the civilian sector I
can't know nothing comes to mind just
having out-of-the-box solution for this
frequency hopping for names the
frequency hopping is this anyone you're
black when you're covering the entire
spectrum you cover the entire spectrum
after the talk I can show you some
sample data from a live capture for the
2.4 get your spectrum what it looks like
current state and what it looks like
after one of these no generators been
activated
and that data was discovered not
translate the data by captured squad
well you capture record yeah yeah banana
died capture / looks at in a country
without extradition 32 the u.s. that
allows testing of wireless equipment
let's call him I did a small low power
test captured Tampa Bay and compared the
tooth I can show you if it I can show
you have to add through the effort block
yeah so one the one point that I wanted
to cover with this is that there are so
many widespread applications for cheap
ass off-the-shelf hardware and we could
go into so many two other different
fields of attack and terrible ideas I
have for them there's no unifying
defense against it we have to start
thinking way far way far out of the box
than we currently are as a potential
attacker or to defend against potential
attackers we also have to look and it's
not just policy we can't deal with just
regulations we also have to change the
way that we think we really do otherwise
it's going to take someone that's a
little bit more pissed off and cynical
than I am to go start throwing these
around wherever and doing whatever with
them that's exactly let's have a chat
about it i'll be posting the slide up on
oh absolutely one of my favorite
hypothetical applications is you have
all the people talking on phones in a
movie theater the low super low power
ones have an effective range of about
thirty to fifty feet kick one off no one
can answer respond to text messages and
you get to watch movie and i would say
that guy's life in texas absolutely
absolutely how's florida that was
florida florida yeah second differences
they know it's not like a team no it's
not i don't host or taste what's that
you are a Jay sorry um it'll be up on
github whack bad ideas black on a budget
bad ideas is the main source so I'll be
throwing up the slides here in a bit and
a whole bunch of additional notes and
information I have
that for the next little demo I'm up
afterwards yeah absolutely I guess you
there's also sorry encouraging us before
if you want if you want to share bad
ideas that's the only way that we're
going to get this working is having
these talks about it so um the notes and
links will also be here there's also a
bunch of cited instances from last year
news stories of the San Jose gunshot
causes oil spill that caused one of
their their smaller perverts to pop the
that attack in San Francisco yada yada
yada but for now that's my talk thank
you so much