or we sort of start these are at least
as I as I understand sort of the big
players and really aggressive cyber
behavior on Chinese have the army of
hybrid hybrid private and government
actors are focused on control of
information domestically externally they
still have that ball tonight if it is
melted down let's do it anyway most
famously 61398 as put as point there on
maybe report and the ongoing use of
Wikipedia as a tool political warfare
it's fascinating to keep blocking my
websites and they invade in Huawei's of
course a Chinese fella
telecommunications company which is
known for infiltrating things and
allowing things like 61398 sort of
swooping behind them and take advantage
of the system that is for special recon
a word you will learn later the North
Koreans have their small group of very
small hackers they're based in Shanghai
told you have 121 space in their
intelligence director directly on they
are really awful to the South Koreans
constantly odd intelligence collection a
monetary damage they crash their servers
and financial servers and wipe them
couple years ago I'm so social confusion
there's always rumors going on the South
Korean and newspapers about weird things
South Korea decides to reunite with the
North has been a headline three or four
times up reading papers this is a form
of a regular warfare are the Iranians
had a small group of hackers but it's
expanding as we were previously are
there eternally folks for the population
control but that is sort of growing
outward as well especially against the
Israelis there Shamu yeah the sure moon
program we've all heard so much about is
a raid or direct action it is not a his
there the word cyber war connotation of
time and legal and ongoing definition
this is a raid running break things
leave they take a job or the Russians
have their own private of private
hackers and sort of government hacker
hybrid things they're focused on it
interesting more assertively strategic
use of cyber Estonia Draeger are the two
example that come to mind those are also
direct action raids why do all these
words matter and of course this is what
we do we do roughly the same thing on
the left is us sort of
clandestine cyber operations this is
what's open in the open press that was
not disclosed by Snowden um we look
internationally other powers and do
roughly the same thing infiltrate
exploit service that's what's going on
oh we look internally for Qatar for
counterterrorism work dealing with
al-qaeda and lone wolf attacks things
like the Boston bomber foot hood so on
and so forth all being true but as far
as no we don't actually steal things
like China does because the caveat on
the right is what happens when you take
cyber warfare can industrialize it for
the US military this is a darker project
called plan X launched in 2012 and
basically is designed to take cyber
warfare from the realm of those who are
very bright and applied to those like me
who do anything about cyber warfare and
they can use on the battlefield a
personal advantage um example would be
an army front approaches a town the
power is out of the town we want to turn
off the power shoot you know order
orders gold chain of command we won't
turn the power off comes down use this
fun it press the button the power goes
out in town great army rolls in earlier
we discussed a bunch of so exciting
words this was special operations do we
send in the sales they do one of twelve
things basically and it's these sort of
12 things that they do and I'm using
this as a framework because i believe
the cyber cyber warfare is a misnomer
cyber solok which is low intensity
conflict is much more accurate phrase to
describe it because warfare has legal
and scale connotations and there is
certainly conflict that gone between the
Iranians and Israelis I cyber between us
on the Chinese sign cyber and it is not
a war no undershooting I think there's
maybe one death associated directly with
cyber attacks that's not up that's not a
war by any stretch of the imagination
creased tension between the two how does
this apply the cyber um Syrian
electronic army that's a form of a
regular warfare practice by side against
is opposition if the Saudi if the Saudis
had the ability to defend a foreign
internal defense against our against
Chamoun which is officially done by the
committee of sword and justice or
something like that which is probably
anything arriving in front if they had
some sort of cyber at foreign internal
defense might not have been nearly if
this and we had doubled their servers
in fact um for counterterrorism network
network exploitation who talks to whom
and how often it from that you can sort
of pull out a chain of command and from
there or a line and go from there
operation informations muffins of mass
destruction in 2011 british Foreign
Intelligence got a hold of a jihadi
bomb-making website and on there they in
recipe how to make explosives the Brits
took took that out and instead put it
how to make muffins Betty Crocker
chocolate chip muffins and did you
Heidi's for while we're making bomb
muffins that wouldn't explode but tasted
great pace of my electronics fantastic
more of a great um natural recon Chinese
technology theft they go in steal our
stuff and leave that's a foreign
reconnaissance go in how do the networks
work what do they look like how are they
connected and how to sort of how do they
work so whenever the whatever they sort
of steel they can employ a pencil in
some other fashion direct action Stuxnet
this is a raid go in break things leave
unofficially it's unknown who did this
on a rumor on the street is that the
u.s. designed it gave it to the give it
to a Mossad on a stick they passed it
around some people end up in the hands
of Ronnie and scientists who plugged it
in and we had stocks that that is a raid
enter and leave but the virus stayed
behind became public knowledge and stuff
here I'll pattering goes the tighter
insurgency the buzzword of the last 12
years of up in Washington's jihadis
online have taken the internet to
recruit and do everything possible
fundraise or recruit procure things from
the Silk Road and so on and countering
that would make any sort of Qatar own
and stopping that activity would halt
their ability to ways your insurgency in
Iraq and Afghanistan and so I argue that
cyber warfare contains elements that
directly follow Special Operations
principles and so we're going to look at
the most exciting things direct action
rating rating things um the most a
simple secure repetitive surprise
feeding purpose those are six sort of
facing things you need for a successful
raid ah
by the Iranians it's fairly
straightforward go in break a ram Cohen
RasGas secure they told nobody about it
nobody knew it was coming that is good
repetition it was practicing skilled
because they got in and broke 32,000
computers surprise saw DS really didn't
know what's coming until the day before
there's someone in our system well we
should do thing about this perhaps speed
it happened quickly it's it's all cyber
happens where it quickly things can
happen quickly and that will let your
time to recover purpose the writings are
going to breaks aramco they broke a
ramco and to this day the damage
continuous it will continue the next two
or three thousand years and the flip
side there's a but the flip side through
the influence of audubon bin Laden raid
and it follows in same six principles we
want to get bin Laden if we're going to
practice it a lot really good at it
we're going to slip in the dead of night
and they did and success was had another
one at another example of this is in
fact a regular warfare this is a
definition on the left for those who do
not follow military fares as closely
writing on the right this is what I look
like they look like acai berry' things
you can have cyber irregular warfare as
a way to strip legitimacy from a
government instead of different banking
systems there are ways to degrade
because governments operate online they
there they email addresses and they have
their own sort of cyber-espionage things
you can counter that as an insurgent and
keep your own networks alive other
terrorists have done this today with
email accounts they talk to each other
to all with the same email account save
it all the draft that's a form of cyber
electronic warfare to get around and it
says power to soak things up so did
Petraeus but the terrorists can do it
properly not made a lot of things a
foreign internal defense this is us
helping somebody else defeat defeat
insurgency or the left is of course the
boring duty definition of those who
don't know what it is on the right so
this is how you can possibly do it and
anonymous and Moustakas is our examples
of this they are currently not terrorist
groups but their precursors of things to
come you have groups that sort of mobile
eyes on the road and they can do their
own exciting things
and from there they are the precursors
of things to come they're currently not
really being malignant and really
aggressive in destroying things but if
you had a well-funded group in the
future as as we have network of the
event of all things is whole internet
and I believe today's is buzz right as
that sort of increases becomes more
possible and usable that is a problem
unto itself you can actually have cyber
terrorism people run around on the
internet and maliciously break things
for political and shamu and is I think a
very interesting event because if the
Saudi ties ability to sort of stop cyber
events no and if they had Hillary sort
of stop cyber events unfolding you
wouldn't have 32,000 hard drives now as
giant paperweights that would be good a
question with this beautiful analogy for
sort of military interaction with the
civilian sector especially companies
that are multinational yes the concept
of active defense and just got
capabilities to maybe push back or take
take out command control or do something
of that nature yes um cyber cyber is not
just warfare with cyber's dollars the
domain of governments now it is a whole
of otha as a whole of because you target
mostly private things in cyber warfare I
would imagine and so now it is it is a
hold of hold basically the nation
approaches sort of dealing with this and
warfare has now become a problem of the
people i mean who is hacked by china
google it's a private company Oh
Northrop Grumman by and large a private
company called the sort of big
contractor they're all private companies
but they have ties to the government
because they are tied they're there for
target targeted by a variety of nations
so because they are so because it is
more time together public and private
sector now they must come together and
sort of proper the way to do all of this
at least you end up with private sector
saying man or the government
government's like you're saying we don't
really care until you have sort of sort
of cataclysmic event which is suddenly
also that we should care tell you today
Darren on the following John's point
here because soon you bring in private
sector to something like this is we love
the traditional special forces
they're operating outside the rules of
conventional war outside the legal
frameworks of their country of origin
yes us if you're talking bringing in the
private sector that's going even further
limit the ability for a hit with you
sick saying as the Special Forces Group
to operate it is that how do you manage
this especially under the FISA and I say
microscope that were under these days I
mean business well how do you make this
happen hug you you it's very difficult
to do but this is this is more of a
conceptual framework by which you can
examine cyber warfare I think that if
you examine side work from a class of
its Ian point of view you've lost it
yeah you do the Blackwater thing I are
solely out of the government and any
brings it then right that is a way to a
client is because I'm not privy to it
but they used to be a story that when
you wanted someone listen to you get the
rich today and then we wanted someone
listen to you get the Americans to it so
when you guys want something you ask a
British company to it you've seen
website one last night of MO and we do
the same in the Rios company from we
don't call the SAS because the seals
operation I'm sorry you're 20 pixels to
do stuff are they doing Mike jakey's
pronto maybe so you never watched try
but if you consider if I think at least
they can consider I continue to examine
cyber warfare through the realm of a
class of its Ian world you have too much
of an economy between war and peace and
the line is definitely blurred in
special forces are sort of at least in
the reality if you will be sort of third
option between a really harshly worded
the March and what is going to destroy
all of your air bases instead we'll use
we use the seals will use special forces
to do so and I think if you adapt that
framework for examining cyber warfare
it's much more effective easier to look
at
in this example of simply cyber defense
what what can we short questions look we
learn from the cold war because
everything you talked about here in
cyber ID can very easily see an
equivalent something that happened well
this is fishing director in Africa in
the 1980s KGB you can you can definitely
learn a lot on our our concept of even
even our concept of information in iron
we don't have the lexicon to discuss it
fully which is why after 25 years you
can't agree what I owe is or is that the
Russians had addiction in 1985 it's
gotta be this stick if not more to put
out by the KGB and it clears out very
clearly I of definitions and there are
some sixty terms to discuss I oh and
they have a type of lexicon and that's
the kind of state even though the KGB's
falling apart the dictionary is still in
existence that's dead and we don't we
don't have the lexicon to discuss
information operations and stuff like
this and other other nations not only
have the time to discuss it but they do
it so that's example of this with your
cyber counterterrorism um how you how to
use cyber things to take down terrorists
terrorists turn more the internet the
days of Red Army Faction and the Red
Brigades are sort of done there's no
more these large hierarchical structure
groups they're sort of more spread out
like Al Qaeda's bests or an example of
this as an speak but they've communicate
with each other from your grub to
Pakistan and back and they do it's
through the internet email addresses and
so on sort of how do you use cyber tools
to disrupt not only their communications
by funding funding research procurement
tactical discussions on even
eavesdropping there was a conversation
held between al-zawahiri and the head of
a cab al-qaeda operating out of Yemen
and it made national news here in the
States we intercepted their phone calls
and that's why we shut down a bunch of
embassies last September as I believe
this was when this was in three weeks
later the line went dead and has not
been active since in 1998 the same thing
happened we had a lead in bin Laden cell
phone and
Nathan Nate the new york times i believe
in the lineman dad two weeks later and
speak that ever since if you read the
Cuckoo's egg John hofstead he was
running the New Scotland Yard place unit
they were about to pursue my career when
the side rajendra at the time said we've
got the Soviets that are running this
campaign before the investigation could
be completed that's how only one screwed
up I mean an earlier version of this is
the IRA in northern Belfast um the IRA
the north ireland police managed to
wiretap a bunch of phones in Belfast and
the IRA found out about and tapped all
their taps and for seven years they knew
everything that the North Island police
heard and it's only through dumb luck
that they sort of stumbled on it they
stopped the IRA intelligence reef in a
traffic stop for seed ball violation
pulled out I look your folder on your
chair went through it through in jail
and rate of the houses four months later
found they attack every phone tap that
they had tapped in Belfast and it was
really quite something um sir but cyber
terrorism if you set up it's sort of a
fake terrorist group online you could
possibly use to draw that draw the mid
and sort of collect them in that fashion
um subvert terror networks there are
ways to do this in a psy ops and I oh
and again this weapon the month of the
mass destruction i think is a great
example sort of things you can do to to
twerk and irritate terror groups because
they're suddenly building better
cracking at muffin in their class that
isn't a joke that's being told a lot
visiting plus that your adversaries are
stupid and that's really dangerous
especially for specialized no no they're
actually very very intelligence about
making muffins instead of moms I think
they're dangerous they did it they they
they honestly actually I know that story
and we can talk about that offline okay
and their information operations and
psychological operations there are ways
to do with the cyber things as well and
sort of the ways you can influence the
way someone perceives the world how they
can act an interactive you can curtail
and alter how how they perceive the
reality
and act through their information is in
fair game for manipulation and if you
can alter how someone perceives the
world by flooding they're either in
boxes or altering their emails some
fashions give them bad information their
way there are ways to do that sort of if
nothing else today other countries
basically have equivalent units of this
um to can very very elite very good what
they do break in break things they raid
on spy extract information leave if
cyber fabric is in fact its own domain
it requires its own military force to do
so and you have operate here with its
own military force a conventional and
unconventional this is sort of a loose
framework for maybe what unprofessional
force would or would not do um what
greater integration between Special
Operations and cyber would make all this
much more easier I see a lot of
connections in lines between how one
operates and how the other operates and
drawing them together because the sort
of up right along the same framework and
operation in behavior keep it keeping
them separate and keeping them sort of
dissociated and unaware of each other
those no favors across the board because
other nations sort of operate along the
same lines and keeping them in their own
separate houses away from each other
does that's no good and so I perhaps
there should be some sort of exchange
program between Cyber Command and so
calm that's just an idea I had to sort
of encourage your sort of talking
between each other it's 20 minutes
that's 20 minutes that's and now bring
forth the questions some of the lobby
but successful with the up for the true
I'd freeze program so how would you see
the hunk from the virtual at some of the
lovely they're only this of course works
assuming that there in fact on a network
um bin Laden hid hidden a house in a
bottle bod under with no burned his own
trash had no internet connection of
phone lines black and white
may be operated by courier which
basically off the grid entirely knowing
then we were looking for any sort of
ties to him we eventually tracked him
down they found this courier we found
the code name for his career I'm like oh
five and the name was actual career in
07 and sort of followed his career
around for a couple years of you the
courier really good with regular
dropping her tales all around Pakistan
we finally traced it back to this house
in a bottle bot he said this house looks
weird so it really depends this is all
the face in the premise that terrorists
use but one of the plans in my head was
for a virtual Asama bin Laden so this
God pops up in any place inside the
space or parties poison and obviously
becomes bill I Max Headroom thanks Henry
with Iturbide how were the hunt a blur I
mean physically yeah could happen I
don't I don't know how would look um
even someone who does forensics to give
you a much more script answers that and
we've seen that that we've seen
ideological years you Jeff Jeff up they
take part especially in the activism
room there's they've been able to push
swarming effects against corporate
targets based on their ideological
reasons or whatever and they're not
necessarily ones carrying out the
attacks but they're certainly pushing
for all the you know at the very back of
a lot of it um cebu was a to do while he
was being run by the FBI was certainly
finishing a certainty those he was
getting information on one side of the
game from people who were come literally
bringing him access to certain things he
was pushing a very low level d ahsan
some in while he was working intrusions
on the other end I mean he was a I'm
reading into politics of it but you know
he was sort of a virtual next and true I
guess Darren thank you very much
back in back in the early days with Dan
keel and certain meeting these guys I
was on a training circuit with the
defense intelligence agency in cyber war
this was like 94 we started doing it and
I was asked to build a set of exercises
that were not sophisticated like we do
today but fairly simple conceptual
exercises with some role-playing to put
people through some of the thought
processes the games were effectively
star trek to Kobayashi Maru they were
unwinnable games I put on about 300 of
them one group in one who won the Navy
SEALs and they cheated if absolutely
cheated but it's panic that was like 95
96 it taught me so much conceptually
about our spec ops and that's why I was
appreciating your paper and the concept
because I'm not sure we've really been
talking about spec ops a whole lot with
this thing from surgical strikes and
getting things done that it's taken care
of don't worry about it he's a good
answer in a lot of cases on know they
did it within 90 seconds live I'll
didn't air stream my pleasure yeah it
was right on tell you later and the
answer you die it was it was rather it
was fundamentally ridiculously simple I
had not considered it as a threat back
there it was a my bad and I learned and
I said I gotta redo this out of a bitch
now and so I had to redo it and reframed
it and it never got one after that but
they taught me so much about their
mindset because this was not cyber
guides but that's not your back row we
thought