our next speaker and we're going to
evolve into evening and we've had a
couple schedule changes is that you
expected spend some world coxon ticket
he was in DC he works for exelon power
company and we just heard word whoops
can't and I'm not going to press whys
and wherefores from him but the power
companies do what they do so we're just
changing things a little bit and from
l-3 communications Travis Hartman I was
not formally I'm a schedule but we
evolved a min because it's something
that is just so cool and I really like
the concept of data exfiltration so we
moved him from this morning from when
when the Swedes we're doing their things
we took some time and now it's all
working out so Travis understands this
stuff like really really well I've heard
about you I've researched you okay I
talked to your teachers from grade
school I know all about you know still
let me in your house I hope you don't
have a beer if you can do is demo you
need a beer and regret I'm I'm oh yes
before the evening devolves a little bit
more so one you want to say thank you to
Pete Portman he's not here he is a
person that as I came up with the theory
and built out how everything needs to
work and he said okay I got him I'm
gonna put it somewhere guys for a while
and he built the air contraction they
will be seeing just a little while so
one of the interesting challenges when
is talked about is how people were
signed up for info work on and then
things have happened and they were told
no you're not allowed to go talk about
different things oh yeah it's gonna be a
little kludgy here on picking cruises
all right yeah
I actually had to go through and think
it a night our clearance so all my
slides my presentation so that I'm
allowed to talk about anything right
okay so it's more than able to take
about taking data out of virtual desktop
infrastructure you can do that as long
as you don't use any special code you
don't do anything that's illegal and
it's only something that some commonly
average people might be able to do what
okay so that's it do it to the screen
already yes so and I also say that as
part of this process I managed to
expense a drinking bird so 15 billion
dollar company and I expensed a drinky
bird beyond anything else I think that's
a pretty good accomplishment so what I
wanted to do is I was going through the
scenario i got like what's this common
individual yeah i'm going to be getting
some audience interaction feedback with
this most of you watch James Bond movies
growing up your doctor know whatever
else various spy movies in the 60s and
70s and of course they have to get into
building or they slip away from the
dinner party and they open up the file
cabinet got the camera and they're
taking my picture so you can get the doc
mad so anyway there is James Bond I
really think he was a script kitty will
get your boat at the end some of the
background of course high alcohol
tolerance well okay that in generally
fits with the computer security
community and made the phrase a few
times that top hackers like top dragster
is worth best when they're
alcohol-fueled but you also notice a
James Bond and where's Wayne hiding okay
but he had the the following career of
annoying the host of hacker jeopardy
curse you Trebek but you know yet he was
an extrovert and of course he was
getting all this technology for Q so not
much for the heck but the guy who always
had a solution to every problem whatever
you throw at him he's going to take some
common items
and he's going to put stuff out out
there and he's going to interview him
some make everything work and like the
picture of when up there on the shelf he
was also rocking a mullet oh he was so
hot what remote sensing your you don't
have a drink in your hand on my desk but
this is the scenario that we have so
when an acquaintance's house one day
somebody mentions they've seen this
document at their office it proves
aliens exist they're like how can i get
this document in but share with the
world that aliens exist try to get this
scenario the crew post-snowden was
horrible um but the employer they've got
a vdi they got like Citrix something
like that where they're able to go in
and direct the documents but they had
made their following industry best
practices it says you shall not print
locally you cannot save the document
work so how can we get this document out
of that corporate protected sandbox so
we can prove that the aliens exist to
the rest of the world and we're all
hanging around we've been watching the
game it's a bunch of guys or gals who
ever play they got the common stuff you
might find with a gamer laying around
the house I got their xbox 360 they've
got whatever else going on so
or some the items keyboards arrays got a
keyboard for computer some of the nice
ones a little bit programmable you can
actually go ahead and hit one button it
will record a series of keystrokes that
becomes useful later on the presentation
gamepad to actually have one goes over
here pass it around so like specialized
keyboards so if you're playing a game
watered or else you can have a bunch of
macros or functions assigned to keys so
it will do different things including
mouse clicks different movements wide
number of combinations you can have it
set to where they'll just keep repeating
or it only happened one time and what's
nice on this one in particular there
were a lot of reviews on Amazon from
graphics artist thing you don't want to
have to change to a bunch of pallets
elections rather than click through 10
mini buttons hit one button and
everything switches so definitely a
legitimate business reason for what I've
expensed is it anyway um it's not that
one is logitech the other big brand
right now is razor they bought the
Nostromo series that was previously
unplugged belkin we're looking at this
maybe we got a video capture card that's
a lot of great reviews for these hundred
dollar video capture cards will people
were recording part of their gameplay
from their xbox so lrk that was great
I've got a video of ten minutes of me
tea bagging my friend because he's not
very first person shooter I don't know
that that meets the heats the fud
packing from earlier maybe they realize
that would with some discomfort sound
policy then the marketing materials Oh
Rex is bagging the human and footwork on
20 of your life right cops back just all
right well um another brilliant ruin
you've always wanted to work in 11
Oracle yeah
so we did have a test environment for
this we both did a lot of the difference
cloud vendors or VDI type vendor Citrix
as an example they have websites you can
go to you can set up a demo account so
we use those for demo account or wasn't
any particular corporate or government
or any production infrastructure views
were violated during the preparation for
this presentation really we said okay
this is gonna be a four-step process we
need to acquire copy those images if the
screenshots or videos sixty spy movie
stuff we want to put them all into one
document I don't have three guys sitting
in the back room they're going to go
through each individual document say oh
yes this is the one that has the diagram
of the alien landing sites process it
through OCR why because I'm lazy and I'm
not going to go through a 300-page
document looking for the alien reference
looking for that desired information
okay I gotta see our apt my search and
ultimately if we're doing this well
we're not going to be showing up on a
bunch of forensics or other
investigations somebody's not going to
show up who are the people hanging out
with the FBI recently or from the FBI
there they were here yesterday and I'm
sure they will be here shortly so you're
looking at this how we're going to
obtain the images well there's still
image acquisition if you've got an iPad
or an Android phone whatever else and
mostly familiar that there's a couple
buttons you can press at the same time
you take a screenshot okay great we
looked at are there some different
applications out there there are few
applications that will automatically
take a screenshot on certification to me
I thought it'd be really nice if I had
an application running that I could say
take a screenshot once every 30 seconds
and then all I have to do is automate
the scrolling through my documents and I
can then have a series of images that
everything in the document another thing
we discussed was how can we maybe do a
video so if I've got one screen or I'm
not able to take screenshots
if i have an hdmi output i could run
that into that capture card record a
video of scrolling through that document
and then i have to extract let's say one
frame every 15 seconds that correlates
to one page and that will get stitched
together so we looked at the on device
capture the remote capture remote
captured we really can't how can I do
that well nice thing in case of this or
we have right now just one tablet I'll
be fine a two tablets together I can
have the top one going with facetime on
Apple somebody have a remote end
receiving it on their mac outputting
that to a video card or video capture
card so the video is being recorded
elsewhere by the time across multiple
states multiple jurisdictions and even
though i know there's maybe this device
on top that's face time to
something else if i get all the words
through apple I still don't know that
that having an external video feed so
very nice from the avoiding some of the
forensic capture so with that I'll go
ahead and show one of the things that we
came up with which was doing doing the
Legos and whenever we break later I'll
give everybody a chance to come up take
a look at it and poke at it product the
camera on this is probably like an eight
year old Kodak camera so it's pretty
poor quality nothing big on it and what
this does when it runs it's going to do
two different things one is going to
take a picture of it and then it's going
to use the robotic arm to advance to the
next page take a picture advance to the
next page and when it gets done on the
folder on the SD card i now have
pictures and every page on that document
so everything that that 65 person was
doing we don't have to leave the party
we're still drinking wine and whatever
other beverages this is doing the work
force isn't they great what modern
technology can provide from the good
news topology fish ain't done news of
sahaja activity awesome mount cabinet
one of the things that we did with this
as well we were looking at it and said
you know
this fits the toy somebody might have
laying around this is just Lego
Mindstorms there's nothing I tech it's
just using their little interface for
the coding and robotic arms one thing
you may notice there's an extra wire
here this wire is actually a ground wire
this has to be the capacitance for the
finger that's touching the screen where
we got the the finger or the little
rubber ball thing just went to any
conference where there's vendors doing
their handouts and we've walked up to it
both hey we have that and they're sure
and so once again this is a vendor
tchotchke it wasn't anything we had to
pay for and it was just a Babel touch
the info absolutely and I'm having a
little problem with the the grounding on
it right now I do have a video when that
shows kind of from the top down with the
page turning and everything I'll get
that to you see you in court with the
other information see this arm terms
that does take a picture and the other
arm goes advances the page it will
continue doing that throughout the dock
we could actually have it going quite a
bit faster but we have a go pretty
slowly just for the demo purposes oh the
heck is an app for that yes so if we
have to saving it's raining yes
all right it's very long having the
phrase a prince or isn't it a little bit
so some of the things that we ran into
is we're doing our so the testing like
using that gamepad the windows and mac
key sequences um what Windows real easy
you do all print screen and you're
taking a picture of that current window
that you're looking at with mac if
you're going to take a picture of a
specific window there was actually
having to click on that video after the
heat supports so I made it a little bit
more complicated also for doing screen
captures whether it's from VDI or using
the camera like that the screen
resolution actually had an impact so if
you're running a giant image full screen
you're doing the screenshots off that
later when you go to merge them into the
document may have
trouble with the borders things
overlapping and flew into some OCR
challenges we get right into some
applications depending on what you're
actually doing that they will block
different functionality they'll try and
either block down the ability to take a
picture or screenshot or they will
impair other functionality I think it
with citrix on their their demo website
there were certain things we try to do
it and we're using the hdmi video out it
would just block the video signal
suddenly we just have a black box going
there so I could affect as you say
vignette I mean if they chose for pre me
just put it in you what are you cool
with the Legos we'll just call it really
exactly a leg a tower of doom but anyway
so I'm this kinda yeah yeah you know
somebody mentioned earlier I think
actually when you provided a tablet you
said let's let's look at I books because
you can't copy them out or whatever very
easily and so there i'll give you that
functionality some of the other things
we're looking at the external picture
your video capture what we can do for
the pictures a a lot of you may have
seen this when the ipad first came out
how do you print off an ipad use foot is
out the copier this was actually out of
forensics conference and it was the
camera set up much nicer camera tray and
everything else but it didn't have the
robotic arm so that was an enhancement
we made we also looked at what if i just
take a nice camera and put it there on a
tripod i'm getting great pictures and
everything the problem with that for
most people is their co-workers gonna
notice that especially if it ain't the
office and say what are you doing in my
case my co-workers saw it and they kind
of close my door and walk you don't want
to know what you're doing alright sorry
talked about some of the things I terms
of being lazy the repeating key
sequences one things we were looking at
the tablet or we're looking at the
drinking bird since I can remember the
movie darkness
yes okay and the drinking bird in that
there is somebody was tied to a chair
and there was a bomb and they to build
suspense they had a drinking bird and it
kept getting closer and closer to
pressing the button and eventually it
press the button the problem with using
a drinking bird other than you may not
be able to expense off the seven dollars
depending on your employer is they were
lying on a temperature difference so
it's only evaporation of the head of the
material that's on the head it dips
itself with water and that's how it
keeps it going the other thing you do is
you can actually apply heat to the other
end of the bird and as we were doing the
experimentation for how we would set
things up the exhaust fan on the
computer was blowing out enough of a
warm plume that if we set the bird near
it it would perpetually be powered by
the exhaust fan on the computer so that
long exhaustive it is pretty much yes
back to your foot back okay so we got
t-shirt with a dicky-bird with a thug
pepper yes like a hood the thing else is
make it's like a crest isn't it handy
that you are the host artist so so at
this point in our evening we've now got
this SD card we've got the sequence of
images of all the different pages we had
like how are we going to go combine us
we tried several different ways looking
for what was going to be the easiest or
the laziest way to do it try doing a
powerpoint and I just creating a slide
paste an image in there and it really
didn't work well we're having problems
with the margins and stuff like that we
needed up using a Microsoft Word we had
better luck doing it in Windows than we
did in Mac so what we do is we start up
explore highlight the first picture it
would copy it tab over to word paste it
in hit enter and switch back over go to
the next image maybe just continue to
repeat that later on on any Mac or is
that because of screen resolution /
fonts or was the challenge we ran into
in the Mac was when we go to tap back
over to the window that had all the
images we were having some issues with
how it would like reach through
end of a row of images or a certain
place in the column of images and how
the cursor would go ahead and advance
and so in some cases we're able to
overcome that by changing the view from
baby doing thumbnails to now I'm just
doing a long list of that all right we
try to sometimes we had to change the
shape of the previous winter so if my
explore when it was like this and I had
three columns I change it to I only had
one column then it would be able to keep
moving over to the right so that was a
challenge we ran into able to get
through that but what was the easiest
and smooth this way of getting it done
was actually using word and in Windows
say there's genuine use for the blind
isn't they are we I like believe we have
problems for the voyage of this sort of
equation in terms of digital offensive
it'd be interesting to make something
like this for the visually impaired
that's a there are some thought any time
and you consider that one person I
saying once you have the OC r you can
you know ya have it read to you
essentially at that point well I mean if
at all the other restrictions on it you
might still be able to have it we did
you know out loud the bed you could say
this is voiced emotion was we're dragon
naturallyspeaking in those where my dad
might have a mechanical turk transcribe
it for you right yeah i thought you
could probably do it over the telephone
to really achieve a lot of bad ideas
page alisa need a really big bad ideas I
like this I'm okay except the next
conference now I get dragon
naturallyspeaking but you do attract so
many in India as a service to India and
you actually get provisioned alive and
get it running during your presentation
and then you email the results back to
everyone excellent excellent and and
probably the best way to do that is
talked to two different companies and
say whichever one has the better
transcription results from this trial
either ones that we go with for the long
term contract
and then we can get translated into
Chinese and get it back to them yes so
fellow friend won it there will be no
copies of our doctrine and don't even
know what's going on at all but once
they call the concept of fun that's
really screwed the modification
modification of the Chinese one of the
things that we ran into is we're
starting to stitch things together is
like well we have to do the OCR and we
had every searching what stuff people
commonly have around or I can you know
grab for free that I'm not going to go
out and spend the money scan store is a
one website they have a bunch of
comparisons of different OCR software
they have one of times they had free
trials but the free trials tend to have
limits it was either on page counts or
the number of images or some other
restriction there are some online
versions where you let you upload an
image and it would transcribe it and but
you only do one image at a time fail
because it's slow and I'm lazy I don't
want to I got Legos to do my work for me
I've got you know a gamepad somewhere
else or drinking bird yeah philippi the
truth that's probably not the best thing
I need for my annual review with my
company saying I've got a drinky bird to
do my work but anyway mercy father house
Ortiz would I think was it the guy from
verizon yeah yeah actually I thought he
had like three different employers and
Verizon was one he even shipped his RSA
key farm and he basically out sorted his
job with each of the companies i think
it was verizon a defense contractors one
they caught him and then there were a
couple other things but he was he'd go
get a job for a hundred thousand dollars
and you pay somebody twenty thousand
dollars in india to do the work china
was trying to China okay the guy went
was very good no he got the
cash you have used but he had to go into
work and surf cat videos on there I know
that guy was you know okay you doing the
work I mean you got to have a job where
you work at home or you do that so you
can see the feel right if you got a
burden
days remember Carrie yes yeah Thank You
bird how come you're so very efficient
well century and ultimately what we
ended up doing for most of the OCR is
actually Acrobat Pro it does OCR you can
get the trial version is 15 30 days I'm
sure many people have extended trial
versions they say it's still flex Yuma
shaves pre trudges you can get your mug
chonies wisdom it depends on where you
downloaded yeah and I've got it on
virtual the virtual machine on my other
system so later on as people get play
with that I can show both the gamepad
how it goes through and it pieces the
documents together from the different
images as well as show you how the O's
are actually does work were able to find
UFO terms there in the document some of
the things that we ran into and talked
about the hdmi and some of the
restrictions with that sometimes they're
using the copy protected on the hdmi
occasionally you're able to actually use
the converter that converts hdmi into
component to get rid of that your
protection bit doesn't always guarantee
it's going to work there's a software
application called traps it's about $37
that will let you record whatever is
happening on your screen the downside to
that is it makes huge file so if you're
it's okay if you're recording like a
minute or two of whatever game you're
playing but if you're going to record
three hours of scrolling through
document your massive massive files and
that's a real problem and we're also
we're concerned about what's happening
with server-side monitor because it is I
it's a remote desktop I'm viewing and
interacting with something back in that
corporate environment so whatever i'm
interacting with they can see if they
have their stuff to figure correctly
what I'm actually doing or at least what
are trying to do so what's the something
that typically we get left behind what
type of documents are reviewing what was
I access was I accessing the
corporate strategic plan for the next
five years what is trying to find the f
ouo translation of a chinese warfare or
theoretical documents they can also look
at depending on what how they have
things implement they may be able to
look at how regular you're going to your
document most people they're reading
through a document they may be hit the
table of contents those grows to scroll
through the boring stuff military
doctrine and they'll scroll through all
the boring stuff makeup great I've read
it as a devil whole thing about three
minutes but it's not a steady page rate
that people go through most documents
sometimes they spend a little more time
reading a graphic or less time because
the whole page was a picture but it
shouldn't be constant the way they go
through a document the hours of people
are doing stuff if your manager your
employees are doing their work and their
their 8-10 hours a day they're probably
not going home for another 12 hours and
going back through other documents again
especially documents that aren't their
normal work area that should be a pretty
easy thing to flag the talked about how
we had some issues we're looking at the
display resolution if I had the wrong
resolution I'm doing that image capture
came of pain in the butt later on if
somebody eat normally is running the
windows maximize and suddenly they're
they're changing it and some of those
other indicators are happening that's
probably then pretty good in a pretty
good chance that there's something hinky
going on with that on the device side
and this is what actually drove us to do
the camera at first instead of actually
having a device even if they weren't
able to restrict taking a screenshot on
the device a lot of times that
application had the ability to notice
that a picture was taken so it couldn't
stop the user from taking a picture on
every page but it could be notifying the
server saying Travis was going through
this corporate plan in every page he
took a picture or didn't know what
nothing something you take in one thing
you know works looking at the screen
cover it up a little sticky note if the
your policy might be
yeah what's taking out nicely probably
that's counts mission I talked to them
on the right to see you bring it up and
you need to let out a little image of
something that looks like the ceiling
over the top of it yeah oh you're shut
made for those series or we go back to
the the 60 spy movie where they have the
picture of the room and they they hang
it up there and so it's on the little
wire thing and the camera rotates
backwards to look at the same picture I
learned a lot from the 60s by movies yes
primarily the amount of alcohol that you
need to consume to be as fine the other
thing really weren't sure on the telco
records I think that's probably more of
a stretch that we're thinking out if I'm
doing the stack things or doing facetime
are doing a connection to somewhere else
a different jurisdiction at the time by
the time they're having to go after
telco records to figure out that
somebody took their corporate business
plan probably so many other things that
went wrong in that process it's not that
big of a concern at least not for our
four people that were playing video
games in somebody's living I do you like
on the device lon Sega it goes back to
what the legal requirements are and kind
of the bring-your-own-device if your
company or your employer saying you want
you can bring your own device you bring
your own iPad you can connect in you can
do this functionality take a look at
that see are they actually saying that
they have a right to check any logs on
your device or is it not included in
there if it's not included they
shouldn't be able to look and see you
are taking a screenshot or there whether
or not that policy has any clauses in
there for them to do different
monitoring and what's going on in your
dock okay this is a little reference put
this in there we looked at the ios and
android on some of the restrictions can
they actually eat stop the screenshots
can they report that they were happening
looking at the DSE android the secure
Android and the versions is coming out
with that I thought well if I was
wanting to stop somebody from taking
pictures using VDI what I'd like to do
is every time to take a screenshot while
using that
location I'll insert a white screen or
black screen in every picture they have
is whatever that third one you said life
arose as go again where it could detect
it but and detecting it the screenshot
was detected taken in and since then
there's been I OS 607 may have it in
there buddy was basically if somebody
presses the buttons to take a screenshot
is there a log and if there is a log is
that available to a different
application in this case citrix the hdmi
use that was based on the device
manufacturer some were enabling the
restrictions somewhere not I can't
confirm it doesn't work on April TV
which is nice damn I look from an ipad
ok that's good so I did I did mention
Pete earlier I did want to go at once
again to college my drinky bird because
it was key for being able to do any
research with that these children
unfortunately didn't survive a trip and
so my drinky bird is multiple pieces on
North Carolina somewhere I mean it had
more than three ounces of capacity and
TSA made you take it out of your bags I
got a couple other slides because talk
about something howdy so the ones that
didn't go through his head and slides
but ultimately if we're looking at this
one question I forgot to ask earlier so
if you're talking to a bunch of gamers
and there's one person they all know
does anybody know who that is later I
change the only Roy where they at least
know how to yellow Leroy but they all
know your mom ok sorry so with that open
up to any estes any questions you guys
might have if not a little bit people
play with stuff how did you like my mom
is like she fall for that and i'll show
a bunch of Kaiba sky
I too have felt even it's the royal
mother which pay me off and elegant
royal mother yes if you know my mom does
that mean you're my dad so I don't see
imported I think the question was why do
you hate freedom who's your daddy now
have to say sujit that email
dramatically reduce the cost of some of
these devices as well by going through
the same outlets in China oh if I
unbranded hurt where I baitcaster Kurds
all the time they're 23 bucks the UH
them to you for free if you send them a
copy of everything you take a picture
well there's no that's why it's free
shipping because once you hook it up
it's already sending captures there were
none of your truth wait for
Alibaba Alibaba or DX or there's baby
they also from the same factories but
yeah and as we're looking at stuff that
was completely commonly available furs
so what we did was he said one stuff
that's got good reviews from people that
are playing video games or there's
actual reviews from people are saying
i'm actually i'm usually this in my
office and that we can order from amazon
so that anything that we had it was
something so if you tell you advise
these are denastri cookies of the
Mindstorms roadway to kick this rebel
this can you get that industry in
chinese quite a factor that because
that's a good question is james dylan
service yes um is there something
comparable to the lego mindstorms that
you've seen yet on gratis one unfriended
the lake over here okay yeah not to
mention the servos and everything you
need to drive all that stuff so if we
gotta pull it's not it's not as densely
packed in the box where you go to fred
myers or wherever by the mind swarm set
for 99 bucks but yeah you can piece it
together okay your cost difference will
probably just for the lego stuff be
somewhere twenty twenty dollars dirty
dollars difference to piece it together
but i know we could look at this is it
isn't probably been a
a few hundred dollar ok Ken with the
mind storm hits the larger area for
Africa but if you took all the parts
exactly as is that would be a more
kissable thing for the next conference
so you havin having the vendor area have
your own catch ya some ID other demos
well we're on forensic image cap yeah
and you can come on with one and so you
may remember a few years ago Ludwig they
were having one of the DMCA discussions
in a tree so at least and the mpaa said
there's question about how can school
teachers provide video clips or sections
and do gay said well it's fair use if
you take a camera and point at
whatever's on the screen is anxiously do
yeah we're in the NBA and be the
arguments the Library of Congress are 30
this may be viable well Sam devil
sinking Pirate Bay nicely purely from
the existing now what you're allowed to
actually uses that information then it
becomes really interesting because I'm
looking at an image i'm not looking at
words or I took a image and I didn't
take words and how does that actually
apply I'm not lawyer and yet that's this
here so sure what it's a lot of study
big deal thanks yes even have the person
India that doesn't happen when you were
photos there any other questions I think
we're in time for close-ups I think it's
time to open the bar think about dinner
in an hour and change we got a couple