all right so good morning everyone
thank you for that amazing introduction
hope everyone is feeling nice and
caffeinated awake for this 9:00 a.m.
talk so I'm Emily Schechter I am a
product manager on the Chrome browser
security team and today I'm going to
talk about the trouble with URLs which i
think is a really important usability
usable security problem so let's start
with a thought exercise imagine that
you're living in a small town in India
or Indonesia and like most other people
in your town
you're coming online for the first time
on a mobile device so this might be your
first experience with computers right it
doesn't involve an introductory
computing class doesn't involve document
and document editing it doesn't involve
a desktop computer it involves a grid of
logos and brand names and you start to
get comfortable with this grid of apps
right it's pretty easy to understand
there's Facebook there's Google now
let's say you start browsing the web and
you start navigating around to some
websites and on the web we're
representing identity with URLs so do
you think that as a user in a town in
India you would be able to understand
just from the URL who's publishing these
sites do you think that you would even
look at the URL or would you just depend
on the website content itself to give
you a sense for who owns the site and
let's say maybe you're a model security
conscious user of the web just like
everyone in this room right and so you
do look at URLs all the time to make
sure that you're on the site you think
you're on but now there are new
top-level domains coming out right so
can you tell which one of these is the
real Google blog site and can you tell
which one of these is the authoritative
site for Google experiments but URLs are
great for many reasons - which is why we
heavily depend on them on the web
they're really great for sending
links to really specific things right
here we get a hint that this is gonna be
a product from Amazon and you can copy
and paste them easily to share with
friends right and of course in security
land URLs are our last line of defense
against spoofing attacks if all else
fails so we've started to call this
problem the you our elephant in the room
URLs are not working well but we heavily
depend on them for all sorts of use
cases and we show them a lot in our most
visible UIs and many applications so in
the chrome team we've started to discuss
what URLs are used for and which of
these use cases they actually succeed at
and we've started to brainstorm
alternatives that might better solve
some of these requirements and keep in
mind here that we're not actually
talking about changing things are
happening under the hood of Chrome or
web browsers
we're not like talking about dismantling
the Empire DNS or anything like this
we're really just talking about how
these things appear in our UI so in this
talk I'll go through four functions of
URLs functions that they're supposed to
have and then for each of these I'll
talk about how well URLs are actually
achieving those goals and then I'll give
you some ideas for what might better
solve some of those requirements so
here's a breakdown of URLs starting from
the left we have the scheme then the
host then the path and the whole thing
is the URL so this scheme is supposed to
represent connection security right so
here it says HTTPS so we know the
connection is secure great and the next
piece is the host which is supposed to
tell us about site identity so in this
case we know we're talking to the New
York Times and that's pretty
straightforward cool and finally we have
the path which might tell us some useful
information about the structure of the
web site as well as the content of the
page so here for example we know this is
going to be an extremely intriguing
article about the looming digital
meltdown right and we know the article
was published in early
January of this year and maybe we know
that the New York time website also is
actually organized according to date and
then according to section so this is
great and the whole URL itself is
supposed to be useful for sharing
content right so I can just copy and
paste it to my friends to send them the
school article I can just send my
friends some nice TV download that I
found of Game of Thrones whatever and
it's supposed to be great for navigating
to write so if I hear maybe geico.com on
the radio I can just input the URL and
get there but our URLs actually
achieving any of these goals let's take
a look so first let's start with the
scheme so for many years we've suspected
that just showing the string HTTP is not
enough to communicate that a site is
secure so we've shown this lock icon in
some form over the years next to HTTPS
sites and then a few years ago we did
some research on the chrome team which
showed that the icon itself really
wasn't working right we saw the example
the icon sometimes people think it's
like a green purse so now we show these
human readable strings that help
additionaly communicate connection
security so we added the secure string
and it's translated into other languages
when chrome is used in other languages
so this is great and now since this
communicates the security of the site
we're currently working on hiding the
HTTP scheme so that we're not showing
syntax that isn't actually useful to
users right so this is gonna roll out in
an upcoming version of Chrome and we're
doing the same thing for non secure HTTP
so the top image here shows what our
icon for all HTTP sites used to look
like and this was a problem because the
scheme HTTP doesn't communicate at all
the lack of security in on secure sites
right so we added the non secure string
in certain circumstances and the change
required a slow rollout over many years
because we thought that introducing this
string right away
could cause harm because when users see
warnings too many times they get what's
called warning fatigue so they stop
paying attention to warnings right and
we didn't want to induce morning fatigue
and also we just generally didn't want
the internet to seem like a scary place
we don't want people to be afraid of
using the web we don't want them to stop
using the web but the good news is that
now enough sites are HTTPS so we've
finally gotten to a place where we're
going to mark all HTTP sites as not
secure and this is coming out in version
68 of calm which is rolling out this
July in just a few months so we consider
this a success story right we took non
readable information and URLs and we did
something else to make it usable and
informative the scheme was supposed to
be telling people about connection
security and it wasn't so we replace it
with more understandable UI that did
solve that requirement and then we
removed the non readable you our UI okay
great so now let's move on to the end to
the path which in this case is pretty
useful right like I said it tells us
about the content of the page it tells
us about the structure of the site but
unfortunately many URL paths are really
not useful at all for example Google
Docs URLs right and some may argue that
this is actually a problem for security
reasons because non readable syntax
might make people ignore other more
critical pieces of the URL and I'll
actually talk later in this talk about
some research where we tested this
hypothesis but regardless of this
possible security issue I think that
this is a problem for just usability and
simplicity reasons right we should
strive to only show information that's
actually informative to humans so some
pieces of the paths actually are useful
to some people right like the New York
Times example those paths that show
useful information about the structure
of the site content of the page but I
think there actually could be more
usable ways to show this information
when it is useful for example if you can
see here this is actually showing the
google.com search results page and what
they're doing here in green is they're
breaking down the path of arrows to
actually help people
understand the structure of the site but
unfortunately the reality is that most
developers just aren't making paths that
are that useful and right now the
browser doesn't have a great way to
parse and show a useful path versus a
non useful one but the fact that
browsers need to accommodate both of
these scenarios useful and non useful
paths actually is a key reason why this
is a pretty complex problem okay so
we've talked about the problems with the
scheme and with the path so now let's
zoom out a little bit and look at the
whole URL itself which is supposed to be
useful for sharing and for navigating
and the fact that the URL is supposed to
be useful for navigating is actually a
key reason why this problem is so hard
because the the URL display service in
Chrome we're calling this the omnibox
needs to be both read and write right
people need to be able to read URLs and
they also need to be able to type into
it and that's complex so to explain what
I mean let's take a look at some of
those right aspects to see why writing
URLs is so problematic so unfortunately
typos often send you nowhere to the
wrong place entirely right and if you
were coming online for the first time if
you didn't really understand the
internet you might not understand why
this is happening and does anyone have
the patience to type in whole URLs by
hand so I remember back in 2016 I was
listening to Hillary Clinton give a talk
and I remember at one point she turns to
the camera and goes to learn more go to
www.petland.com /a issues forward slash
disability - rights right and this is
ridiculous like there's no way I'm
remembering this whole thing and what if
I don't know how to spend spell Hillary
or disability and this gets even worse
there are numbers in the URL right let's
say I hear a radio ad for 1-800 contacts
com
how am I supposed to know if any of the
numbers are actually spelled out with
words how am I supposed to know if
there's a
- in between 1 and 800 right so URLs are
actually a really bad way for navigating
for that reason and typing in new URLs
on mobile keyboards especially is really
hard right and this gets worse in new
situations that we need to accommodate
for like VR where text entry is even
more awkward right like I'm never going
to be able to enter www Hillary Clinton
comm forward slash issues forward slash
disability - writes on this thing and
copying and pasting URLs on mobile often
requires tricky highlighting and
scrolling or less discoverable patterns
ok so there might be a better way to
share content right there's been an
explosion of these share buttons and
apps which i think is actually a much
more useable way to share content than
copying and pasting URLs and so
something that's cool here is that the
URL is still the underlying transport of
information right it's just not being
exposed to the user in raw form so you
might think of this in the same way that
users see rendered markup right even
when it's HTML underneath here it's
still the URL underneath but it's a much
more intuitive UI flow on top ok so
we've talked about the scheme we've
talked about the path and we've talked
about the whole URL so now let's move on
to the host right which is supposed to
tell us about site identity so here in
this example we're talking to the New
York Times maybe we've just trained
ourselves to ignore that www sub-domain
and all as well right but unfortunately
they're actually turn out to be a lot of
circumstances where this really does not
work so well so here are five of them
I'll go through these five problems so
let's start with confusing syntax so
let's say you're you're reading this URL
from left to right as most people do if
you're reading the English language
right so you might not actually know if
this is coming from google.com or not
right it might be pretty hard to tell so
about a year ago we hypothesize on the
chrome team that visually emphasizing in
we're in pieces of the URL and visually
de-emphasizing less important pieces of
the URL might actually help users read
URLs and therefore identify suspicious
pages based on the euro their URL so
these were some of the some of the UI
treatments that we wanted to test right
the first thing up here is how we
display URLs today the second one has
kind of these left-hand subdomains
grayed out so we were hypothesizing if
it would actually help if we grayed out
subdomains like in the second picture
the third picture there we've removed
the entire path and we just tested dot
dot dot so we were hypothesizing that it
might help if we've removed extraneous
information the fourth picture there is
not showing up well on the projector but
the subdomains and the paths are sort of
super dim they're they're very visually
de-emphasized and finally you know we we
hypothesized that it might help if we
bolded just this top level domain plus
one we call this the effective top-level
domain plus one which is just the most
important information when you're
communicating side entity and so we did
research where we showed users this
screenshot with those five different
URLs at the top and then we asked them
some questions about how comfortable
they would feel logging into the page
and unfortunately we found no
significant differences across any of
the options right across every option
over half of the respondents didn't even
notice the fishy URL at all and those
who did notice the URL tended to say
that they trusted it because it was
Google so unfortunately we really
haven't yet figured out a way to make
these multiple subdomains tricky URLs
less tricky and even if we did about
half of people wouldn't notice anyway
all right let's talk about another
problem which is brand matching so when
registering a domain site owners don't
necessarily know that we're expecting it
to be used for site identity right so
they might not register a domain that
actually matches the brand of the site
this is a perfectly okay thing to do
right here in the case of the Wall
Street
they're serving it from Dow Jones calm
but it's not a great way to match sort
of site identity what if you don't speak
English right this situation becomes
even worse because domain name pieces
like maps and translate might not
actually mean anything to you and going
back to our example from the beginning
of the talk right for those of you that
are still wondering the real Google blog
is actually at blog Google and we also
are serving some smaller domains some
smaller blogs on the Google plug domain
like the security blog is on security
Google Blog comm and also experiments
that with Google comm is actually the
real site for Google experiments so now
you know but you'll probably not
remember but the point here is that with
these new top-level domains it becomes
impossible for us to expect even expert
users to be able to tell site identities
just from URLs and finally
internationalized domain names so
internationalized domain names
we call these ID ends for short and
they're actually really awesome because
they allow us to create URLs in other
languages which makes the web much more
friendly to people who don't speak
English right and it makes the web great
for people all over the world but it
then opens up this whole can of worms
for site eyes on any reasons it's really
opening the door for domain spoofs
because it can make a spoof site appear
and distinguishable from another site
that's being spoofed so most web
browsers have a set of rules to defend
against ID and spoofs where we show
what's called puny code in the case
where we think that there's an ID and
spoof happening
puny code looks like this right and I
was thinking about this and you know I
would actually consider this a pretty
weak defensive move right it's kind of
like this right instead of showing a URL
that is kind of misleading to some
people we're showing this string that is
literally meaningless to everyone right
and a large number of people aren't
going to look at the URL anyway or
understand that what we're trying to
convey here is
this is a defense against a domain spoof
so I definitely consider this an area
for improvement but my larger point here
is that showing host names is not a good
way to convey site identity okay so if
you're kind of depressed by that long
list of problems now let's talk about
some solutions so some of you are
probably saying to yourself Emily we've
seen some of your other talks and we
know that you know lots about HTTPS let
me tell you about this thing which can
map the domain to the identity of the
site right it solves your problem so
easy indeed Maps domains to legal
identities but the issue is that legal
identities are not the same as brand
names here mint.com right it's owned by
into it so it's there they're not the
same thing right and you also probably
saw this fun site set up by Anne Carroll
right it was going around the internet
in December 2017 and it maps to the
stripe ink that was incorporated in
Kentucky but unfortunately the stripe
ink that you know about was incorporated
in Delaware which makes these two stripe
inks totally separate legal identities
right and all of this ultimately depends
on the user looking at the URL bar and
noticing the lack of a warning which
they are not going to do so the
conclusion here is that Evie is not and
can never be a Silver Bullet
anti-spoofing or anti-phishing tool
right we as the browser makers we could
decide to change this UI right we could
decide to show warnings whenever a site
wasn't using validated Evie but these
examples show that even if we did do
this Evie would it be a good defense
against phishing attacks
because it can be overcome by some
moderately motivated attacker
so HTTPS solved network based attacks
right it allows us to be confident that
an attacker in the middle cannot view or
modify traffic it allows us to verify
that the site in question is really that
host but it does not allow us to
validate that the hosting question has
anything to do with
brand or product associated with that
host so we need to get these two
concepts separated in our minds and we
need to stop mixing them up so as we
make HTTP cheaper and more automated
more phishing sites will be HTTPS and
I'm here to say that that's okay and
that's expected the reason that's okay
is because phishing and man in the
middle attacks are two separate problems
that we need to solve separately and any
solution that depends on humans making a
judgment call about URLs will ultimately
not work to solve either of them but for
those of you that are wondering
specifically about the chrome UI that
says secure and arguing that it makes
fishing more effective you might be
happy to learn that we do want to get
rid of this UI but it's ultimately for
kind of a different reason we want to
get to a place where we're only warning
users when there is a problem like on an
HTTP site or on a phishing site and we
want to get to a place where we never
have to show positive UI for an HTTPS
site because it's just the expected
default and so this will look like this
second image here right you'll notice
there's no lock icon there's no secure
string there's no HTTPS it's just
google.com and the default expectation
is that it's secure so ultimately URLs
do not do a good job at solving phishing
and therefore technology that's
dependent on users making judgment about
URLs are unable to solve phishing so we
need to lean into systems that actually
are designed to use ibly solve phishing
so with systems like u2f and security
keys and password managers the code is
making the decision not the human and
that's what makes these better defenses
so when you think about it password
managers actually can become a phishing
solution if we improve their usability
and precision and adoption to the point
where manually inputting a password
becomes such a foreign concept that we
can start warning people when the
password manager doesn't trigger and
with systems like Google
Safe Browsing anti-phishing
infrastructure we using Chrome so Google
Safe Browsing is a system that's built
to look for phishing and malware and
social engineering so that clients can
show warnings on these sites and for
those who aren't familiar with Safe
Browsing the list and the API is there
free and publicly available and they
also flag you know not just fishing but
also social engineering so that apps and
sites can provide actionable warnings
that users will respond to and then
these these warnings these full-page
interstitials do measurably stop people
from getting to badness
but even if we solve phishing and even
if we solve social engineering there's
still this class of websites that urls
currently are best protected for and
these are sites that I'm calling non
canonical information sites so here's
two examples these two sites are not
fishing they're not spoofing they're not
social engineering so we're not going to
show a Safe Browsing warning but
technical users might be able to tell
that they're not the canonical
information about gmail signups right
and non-technical users who don't
understand URLs or maybe are coming
online for the first time they might not
actually be able to glean this
information so instead we need to try to
convey any signal that we as technical
security people are getting from the URL
in an understandable way and I admit
that I don't know how we should try to
do this yet but you know we've started
to brainstorm heuristics to detect this
as well as some potential UIs that we
might show but it's early days and it's
a challenging problem so in this talk I
went through the different pieces of the
URL and I talked about what use cases
each piece of the URL has and how
contrary to what you might believe URLs
really are not doing well at solving
these use cases and I talked about some
solutions that might solve these use
cases a little bit better so it's our
duty as usable security problem solvers
to deal with the your elephant in the
room instead of trying to emphasize user
education to examine the URL as a
security measure and instead of can
canoeing to build systems like Eevee
that rely on humans understanding URLs
we need to focus on creating systems
that are more usable and less brittle
and if we keep doing research on
experiments and stay focused on
usability for the average Internet user
I think that we can come up with some
ways to solve each use case of URLs even
better so if you have any questions or
ideas I'd be really excited to talk to
you and I can take questions now
[Applause]
yeah I think I so the question is how
have linked link shorteners helped or
harmed URLs in this space I think that
link Shorter's link shorteners are just
sort of continuing to exacerbate the
problem of you know URLs becoming even
more even less understandable and like
less useful for our anti-phishing
mechanism again as I mentioned like the
reality is that people don't understand
phishing they don't understand that the
URL is supposed to be a phishing
mechanism and they're not gonna look at
it anyway so I think it's just sort of
continuing to make the problem worse but
yeah yeah so the question was have you
looked at what Safari does so so far he
does two things off the top of my head
that I think are particularly
interesting one is I believe they kind
of hide the path all the time they also
show the the Evy cert if it's there as
kind of the main domain name without
showing the rest of the URL but one
thing that Safari does not do is they
don't allow editing of the URL from the
first interaction it's kind of this non
editable label and in chrome as I
mentioned one of the important things
about the the chrome omnibox is that
it's both read and write like you can
type directly into the URL and so I
think we would have to change our model
entirely if we wanted to move toward the
Safari model and we we sort of care
deeply about the ability for people to
to write right from their URL bar but I
do come in Safari on their how they've
moved toward this model of simplicity
I'm not sure I agree with their
perspective on evie being you know the
main thing in the URL bar but yeah it's
a it's an interesting example yeah I
think this is a really interesting
question so the question is how
important is it to have a consistent
experience across browsers and are you
working with other browser vendors to
make the UI consistent so to answer
yours the piece of your second question
we try as hard as we can to sort of
publish our research that we do in
papers and to like talk about the UI
work that we're going
to do a long period of time before it
actually rolls out you know so that
other browser vendors other applications
etc can take advantage of this you know
and ideally make things consistent but
ultimately I think that if we all sort
of agree on the general shape of where
things are going like for example that
there should be no positive security
indicators and we should only show
negative security indicators that really
show a warning it doesn't really matter
what shape or form those actually do you
know I don't think that you know
certainly some people use a lot of
different browsers a lot of different
apps but ultimately I don't think that
people will say like oh chrome was
showing a green lock and like edge was
shoving like a green shield so I'm not
sure which one of these they mean right
like people are gonna be warned by a
warning and otherwise they're not gonna
be warned so I'm I I don't think it's
not important for the indicators to be
exactly the same yes