but the presentation I did was it's kind
of an HK situations I like looking at
kind of weird and wonderful ways and the
ways that browsers and other software
actor interacts with each other and the
the research centered around how
browsers deal with certain HTTP response
and status codes differently you'd think
that because there's an RFC everything
responds in exactly the same way it's
written on a piece of paper that
everything should do this but not
everything does it in exactly the same
way so you get these these weird
situations where specific codes are
handled differently by browsers and i
was looking specifically on how people
could use those differences to mess up
scanners and automated attackers and
really start to kind of be more
offensive about defense without
attacking back because that's a whole
nother matter but really kind of doing
active defense and saying I'm not going
to sit still and wait for you to punch
me I'm going to budge around and if you
can still punch me great but quite a lot
of people they're gonna miss and if you
keep keep mobile try and be trying to be
harder to attack and really kind of
invest a little bit of time you can
really do some wonderful things the too
long didn't read didn't stay for the
whole presentation version of it is
described defensive uses of HTTP status
codes okay it's boring status codes who
the who the hell looks at status codes
but still we're gonna we're now try and
go through a couple of interesting and
freaky things that you can do with
status codes it's pen testers nightmare
where you go to an admin site you get
403 it's kind of good access to that but
a majority of the time you can usually
bypass it but yeah anyway that's another
talk for another time there's certainly
a practical application for this stuff
and we were right at the beginning of
research for this kind of thing and it's
very hard to say that you can use the
research that we currently have and say
I can protect myself against automated
scanners just by doing this in this but
it is it is a good a good starting point
and
hope that people are going to take on
board what I've talked about really kind
of figure it out for themselves how they
can fit it into their environments how
things like wraps things up modsecurity
can try and build some of that
automatically into protections and maybe
in a year or maybe two years time we'll
start to see that being something that
is normal amongst waves and that's good
we need that kind of innovation I'm not
saying this is the end-all and be-all is
certainly not the silver bullet but
every little bit helps and the more we
can build into these kind of tools that
do it without companies dealing to think
about things and implement things within
an application the better I think it's
going to be good
you