yeah I was talking about the new
technology html5 that came out a couple
years ago and a lot of prison there are
a lot of presentations that talk about
different vulnerabilities and the new
technologies so what I was trying to do
is to take some of the technologies that
are part of html5 talk about the
vulnerabilities and then talk about how
to write code securely how to protect
your applications from those things so
today I'm going to talk about html5
attack and defense so different things
that html5 introduced all the cool
things that it introduced and all the
dangers of the new technologies that
came with html5 it's a living standard
and it doesn't have a date when it will
be finished when it will be fixed so
it's always developing and it consists
of a lot of technologies some of them
were part of html5 and then they broke
off to become their own technologies so
sometimes you will hear people saying
that you know say cross-origin resource
sharing is a separate technology it's
not specifically html5 so yeah but that
might be true it used to be part of
html5 and it has all the cool new things
that make the web applications more like
desktop applications most of the
questions were very technical arguing
about some of the points and suggesting
some other ways to protect the
applications and I had a couple of
questions just a general questions about
like how do you do how do you write
secure code secure code standards for
different languages how do you practice
that well I mean its web two point oh so
it's new technology everybody's using it
it allows your websites to be more like
your desktop applications you know very
interactive storing a lot of data so
yeah everybody is using it and plus you
know it's kind of in some cases it's a
substitution of flash and Silverlight
technologies so you can do all the video
and audio with html5 without any plugins
so it's very popular well if you use
something new if you use something with
new functionality that gives you a lot
of power always think about the security
you know
if it gives you some good things it may
have some vulnerabilities think about
how other people can misuse it an attack
it always you know have the scales way
the good things and the bad things
you