hi
everyone i'm melinda fenera i'm a
software engineer in the united station
team at google and i am miguel
and i am a product manager at the
anonymization team
at google and today we'll talk to you
about
the ways in which we are improving
usability of differential privacy
at scale first let me introduce you the
problem
why is there a usability problem in
differential privacy
let's just start with a hypothetical use
case
uh imagine that we have a dataset that
has private movie ratings
that data set is heated by this
pseudonymous id
it has time stamps at a daily
granularity and it has movie ratings
that
go from one to five where five uh is the
top rating
it also has the name of the movies that
were rated
now imagine that we can perform just a
simple aggregation
for instance we just want to count the
number of movies that have
a specific rating on a specific date
using the group by operation
and the count aggregation method this
looks private at first
but if you look closely some counts
might be
one which is which is a single user at
one day you can use this information and
compare it to other databases
such as externally available public
grading datasets
and if there is a user rating for the
same movie on the same date
these can be used to de-identify users
so there
there's a person in question how can we
anonymize this data
well imagine that you have a
sql engine that is able to do
differential privacy
and if you're interested in learning
more about sql engines with differential
privacy
you can check out the paper that's
linked on the pdf
so let's say that we do that
we change the query to look like this
one of the problems that comes up with
differential privacy is that they
require
parameters such as epsilon epsilon delta
and clamping so how can people choose
these values what's the principle way of
choosing them
well this depends on the utility and the
privacy that we want to guarantee
and might be different from case to case
so this is where the usability problem
comes people
just want to anonymize their data sets
and want a simple way of doing it
so that's why we came up with a way of
quantifying
privacy and utility but we will present
to you today
it tries to bridge the gap between that
usability gap of differential privacy
as you're probably aware there are many
papers describing many methods to
perform differential privacy
but the space of making it more usable
has been vastly overlooked
the way that we did it and we'll explain
it to you was by defining
privacy versus utility metrics we also
provided
infrastructure so that people could
safely and efficiently compute them at
scale
think of computing metrics on terabytes
of data
finally we allow for self-service models
so that users can see
in real time the impact of privacy
parameters
on their data and if they want to they
can tune them in real time
now to give you more information i'll
pass it over to melinda
hi everyone so now i will
give you a demo of our system and i'll
also explain how the system addresses
the
usability control concern of
differential priority
so this is how our system looks like uh
first i will
explain to you the different components
in the system
in the ui and then i will explain how it
helps with the usability concerns with
differential privacy
and i will and finally i will explain to
you how
one would use this tool to tune
parameters to randomize with
differential pricing with the example
that miguel mentioned earlier
so in our tool we have different
sections uh for different
uh parameters and and controls
so on the left you can see the typical
parameters one would have to specify
um if it's able to analyze within
differential privacy
so at the top you have analyzation
parameters
epsilon and delta as you know these
parameters control
how anonymized the output is and next
you can select
different infrastructure configurations
so these are the infrastructure like the
general infrastructure we have at google
so phloem is this mapreduce style
infrastructure
sequel is sql based engines
and you can also select custom and then
set uh
specific uh specialized parameters
like noise distribution type laplace or
gaussian distribution etc etc
so for this demo i will stick to sql
so it's compatible with the example
media showed earlier
next section is about data utility
parameters also known as
uh sensitivity parameters so these
parameters control
how much effect any given user can have
in the data right so the more effective
user has
the more noise you have to add to hide
that much
uh change in the data the
the last set of parameters here are
called filters
so these are not differential priority
parameters so they allow you to look at
certain
areas of your data and then see what
happens to
say in values in a particular range so
it you can
dive into like detailed analysis
and then on the right side you can see
at the top
uh some metadata about the a particular
dataset being analyzed
so here we are analyzing this data with
movie ratings
so what we call partition here is uh how
we are grouping
the output by so here it's the date and
the rating
a particular user has given for that
rate for that date
and then the next uh field here is
called the partition value
essentially what type of aggregation we
are doing we are counting users
um and then in the next section you can
see
uh financial statistics right so here
there are different types of statistics
at the top you can see something what we
call the threshold so these are very
important
intermediate parameters and
randomization so the idea
is uh if the if say in this case
uh a particular date and rating
combination
if there aren't enough users if the
number of users in that particular
bucket
is less than that number we won't be
releasing that because it's too
sensitive right
it doesn't allow us to release that and
then claim
uh these uh these privacy guarantees uh
required by epsilon until the chosen uh
epsilon delta
and uh noise standard deviation is uh
it's
quantifies how much noise we are adding
to the
movie counts in this case uh and then
there are a couple of other
parameters here as well so these uh
basically talk about uh how many
partitions you have in the underlying
data so there are about 10 000
combinations of date rating pairs
and uh here you can see how many
partitions are there
in the output right you can see there is
some
loss but it's almost hundred percent
98.9
um and then here uh another important
parameter
so this is again the the intention of
these two parameters too is to give you
like a very high
level idea of accuracy loss right but we
should keep in mind there's so much you
can explain
by just one number right so this
parameter is basically saying um
if you add up all the movie counts
across
all the partitions in the row output
what's that value
and here it's the same thing computed
over anonymized output
as you can see there's a 70 percent
change
right there's a 70 drop so it gives you
some kind of a very high
i very high level idea of accuracy loss
uh again
it's not the only thing to look at and
we also have several plots that dive
into
this uh like the changes introduced by
anonymization
um so this plot uh is a histogram
uh where we show the distribution of
values in the
anonymized output and the row output so
the x axis
um shows a different value ranges like
this case movie count
value ranges and the y-axis
is the number of partitions with values
uh in that range so if i selected this
one
um you can see uh there are the so the
value range is sixty
thousand to sixty-five thousand movie
counts and there are 50
partitions with values in that range in
the robot
row input and in the output there's only
one partition
there's a big change as you can see
that's actually
quite a big change now another thing to
point out here is that this graph is
shown in the
log scale but in reality it's more
like that it's more like long tail
distribution but looking at the log
scale
helps you emphasize the difference it's
good for
like beaten analysis the next plot
is about um how much
change is introduced by the
randomization
pipeline right so here at the in the
previous
uh plot you can see the overall
difference
uh this particular plot division like
tries to explain how that this how this
uh
change is distributed again you say
histogram
x axis is the the relative change right
like buckets of relative changes and the
y-axis is the number of
partitions that experience that amount
of change
as you can see with the given parameters
uh most of the partitions
have changed between 40 and 90 it's
actually
quite bad accuracy wise the last plot
um is about uh the partitions that you
don't get to release at all because of
anonymization at the beginning i
mentioned there is this parameter called
uh
thresholding right so if you don't have
enough users
about this threshold um you don't
release that partition at all
so this this plot again another
histogram
shows you how those partitions are
distributed
in some cases you might want to look at
okay what can't you release
so you can address that in other ways
now how does this help with usability
now if you look at the
left side you can see these parameters
epsilon
delta right laser utility parameters and
when you look at that like what does it
mean does it give you an idea of how
much
data loss you'll have to suffer and
how much noise are we adding like like
like
at which point don't we release things
right privacy parameters
it doesn't give you any of those right
so the goal of this tool is you can
like set these parameters and get
those analyzation statistics in pretty
much real time
it takes seconds to compute this you
don't have to run
lengthy like long pipelines to
compute these things you can click a
button get the values and make the
changes
again see the the change
essentially tune the parameters so now i
will walk you through an example
where i try to get uh the most utility
out
for my use case right for example so
again
in this particular use case i'm
analyzing the movie rating data set
so you have the date rating partitions
and the movie counts
and say i start with these parameters so
when i click compute
i see um in the
output i get to keep almost all the
partitions
but there's uh massive data loss massive
accuracy loss
so what do i do uh so the first thing i
would
do is uh say for my use case i am only
interested in
uh partitions with at least 100
as the movie count the aggregate right
so i can set
that value here i click compute
and you will see um
nothing change i mean uh it's pretty
much the same right i get to keep
more partitions right because i don't
care about these
low count partitions but the accuracy
loss is still bad
and if you look at the two distributions
they are pretty much identical
identical from previous one
now the next step i would do is i would
say
let me increase the sensitivity bound
contribution maximum contribution i
allow for a particular user okay i set
it to 10
again i try that value and you will
see now the accuracy actually went to
70 so 30 percent uh dropped there
uh i still get to keep almost all the
partitions which is great
but because i increased this sensitivity
the noise
standard deviation increased now it went
from two point eight to twenty eight it
multiplied by 10 essentially
uh if you look at the two distributions
now
they look better right so at 60
earlier i got to i was able to keep only
one anonymized partition now i get to
keep four
uh this is again the log scale right but
it's getting
getting there it's not quite as accurate
as i like
um if you look at the change
distribution uh before it was like
between
40 and 90 the change now it's uh i would
say between
5 and 50 so
less change again could be better
so as for the next step i would try 100
for the max contribution limit and if i
click compute
um you will notice the again
i get to keep almost all the partitions
and the partition
value is actually quite accurate as well
right it's like not almost
almost hundred percent and if you look
at the two distributions
they also very nicely overlap right
um which is nice and uh if you look at
the distribution of the change
now almost all the partitions are less
than
um like 10 change majority of i would
say
like around five percent change see like
for my use case i like these numbers
i like the accuracy loss like something
i can tolerate
and uh the the distribution is also
quite similar to the actual data
distribution and
uh i might decide well these are the
parameters i want to use i will just set
these parameters in my pipeline and
run the pipeline once and for all to
anonymize
so this way the benefit to me as a
product team is i don't have to do this
analysis
manually come up with these plots and
matrix manually and i don't have to run
the pipeline many many times
so with this tool i can just experiment
with the
different numbers find the number that
works for my use case and anonymized
once
now one thing i want to notice here is
again uh
the numbers actual the actual utility
parameters you pick
again depends on the use case like megan
said earlier right so in this particular
case
i'm assuming i can work with only values
at least 100 and these are the
parameters that work
for that those requirements okay
and another important thing i want to
point out
now we changed all these parameters to
get to the parameters that we
like the combination of parameters we
like without
touching the epsilon and delta which is
very important
right so we didn't relax the privacy
protections but we still got a lot of
utility out of the data
now with that i will quickly explain
how our system architecture works
um and uh all right let's
okay so this is the overall architecture
of our system
uh so we divide uh how we generate this
analysis into two phases
uh we have a space where we create the
analysis
and we have the face read the analysis
we try to distribute
the work in in these stages in in
various parts because
applying differentiators can be really
costly right so we have this
intermediate data format called
sketches what we call a sketch so the
idea is this is a
intermediate data data format uh that
allows us to
apply differential priority in real time
very efficiently
but it also takes less space than the
underlying source data so that's
something
we create during the create analysis
phase
and when you render the analysis we
primarily rely on these sketches to
compute these uh matrix in pretty much
real time
um all right and uh as a couple of uh
highlights of our system um as you can
see
uh you can actually run this analysis
and get the output within seconds
our median core latency is around 10
seconds
and uh the time it takes to
you know start with the raw dataset uh
create this sketch
and leave the analysis the entire
end-to-end process takes uh
in the order of minutes maybe 15 minutes
in in most cases
and we found out through our internal uh
studies and experiments
uh product teams do find these analysis
quite
intuitive and useful and and they are
able to find the right differential
pricing parameters through this analysis
and which is that's what our goal is try
to make refresh pricing more
useful as for future work
we are planning a couple of directions
so the very first one is to open source
this work
so definitely people within google but
also outside google can
use these analysis and and use
differential privacy more
and and also uh we think once by
oversourcing this we can get
the community to build upon what we have
right make it even better
right so we are considering open
sourcing these uh
tools as part of our open source
offering
uh the second thing we're exploring is
uh introducing
local differential privacy into this uh
tool
uh so local differential price is a
model where we apply differential price
at the point of data collection
as opposed to you collect raw data first
and then apply
differential priority on the server side
um and the third direction we are
exploring is to introduce more functions
into the tool right now our tools
support uh count and some operations
uh but there are other functions we
should support
all right with that uh i would like to
thank you
on behalf of miguel and i and google
for attending this talk thank you so
much