at this time we're pleased to have
Colonel yeah catarrian the director of
the NATO cooperative cyber defence
centre of excellence in Estonia colonel
terian previously served as the
commander of the Estonian air force he
is a graduate of the United States Air
Force Academy and has master's degrees
from the Air Command and Staff College
in the United States National Defense
University please join me in welcoming
Colonel Terry
[Applause]
it is an absolute honor and a privilege
for the CCDC OE to partner with army
cyber Institute for the third time to
field this wonderful conference saikhan
us the CCDC OE
out of Tallinn Estonia is a
international military organization it's
a think tank now with 21 member nations
United States being one of them and we
have already 11 nations waiting to join
our our party so we have grown outside
of NATO we have several member nations
that are outside of NATO boundaries as
well 2018 is a special year for the
center we're celebrating our 10th
anniversary we celebrating the
establishment of the center we celebrate
a tradition by the NATO allied command
transformation 10 years in human history
is a negligible blink of an eye but when
you overlay it into cyber domain then a
we've been around since before gunpowder
was invented to reflect on those last 10
years and also to look forward the
spring we made a short video for those
who were in Tallinn for the springtime
saikhan this is a rerun but as a good PR
specialist will always tell you there is
never good enough of a good message so
well I spent those 90 seconds and watch
that together please in 2004 a new NATO
ally proposed to create a cyber defense
hub in 2007 the same nation was hit by
the first-ever politically motivated
cyberattacks surprisingly they made the
embarrassing incident public and finally
the world listened Estonia show
that cyber threats are real and we need
to approach them in cooperation a year
later Estonia with six other nations
launched the NATO accredited cyber
defence hub in Tallinn today the center
has civilian and military experts from
21 like-minded nations it does research
training and exercises in four focus
areas and highlights are the Tallinn
manual the lawyers and policy advisers
Survival Guide to the cyber galaxy blog
shields a unique international live-fire
exercise starring cyber defenders and
Psyche on the annual must-attend
for cyber gurus where to next red
teaming exercise cross swords is growing
new study areas are on the rise cyber
deterrence attribution and artificial
intelligence however one thing stays the
same the key actors in cyber defence
other people so you saw we could be
celebrating more than 10 years
Estonia proposed 2004 to entire NATO
alliance that we should stand up the
center of excellence of cyber defence
can you do you know what was the
response by the NATO allies precisely
deafening silence you all know it and
some mumbling that well cyber defence it
our focus is in Afghanistan in the
desert warfare cyber defenses it's kind
of a civilian business should be left
for EU and others like that and Estonia
do you think you have competence to run
this Center until 2007 rolled around and
Estonia was the first nation to be
target of politically motivated cyber
attacks Estonia state leadership went to
Brussels to NATO HQ and said we're under
attack and the response was well the CNN
doesn't show tanks or planes or you sure
you're under attack yes we are the
entire concept of cyber domain being
used for a military or politically
motivated attack it was absent from from
the Allied thinking it is there now
cyber is now officially
declared as a military domain by by NATO
and right after 2007 nations recognized
that hey Estonia please
let's team together let's create this
center of excellence the first mission
or the biggest mission of the center was
to get the nations aware the Allied
nations like-minded nations aware of the
importance of cyber and peculiarly it's
gone so well that in 2008 about 20
person team of seven nations that has
tripled now in size to 21 nations and 60
people we've grown small in 2008 the
center was a big powerhouse in the
military cyber thinking now the larger
nations like the United States has
thousands if not more than 10,000 in
each service branch working on cyber
small NATO nation called Estonia
recently stood up a Cyber Command with
over 300 people our center is small how
can we still be relevant yes we can the
keys in the first sea of our name
cooperation we strive to be the
champions of cooperation we bring
together the 21 member nations not only
military but government industry
academic knowledge and expertise fuse it
into products that benefit all member
nations and feed this knowledge back to
the members our enemies in a cyber
domain they're not stuck behind what we
call interagency cooperation
they have integrated really well cyber
into what we know as a hybrid warfare
fused with the info ops conventional
kinetic kinetic warfare non-conventional
warfare they've got it right we need to
cooperate
amongst the like-minded nations in order
to stand up to this this kind of warfare
a good example of cooperation for CCDC
OE is this conference for a third time
together with army cyber Institute we're
here together putting on a world-class
conference I hope this conference also
raises your appetite for more
so you booked your trip to telling for
spring time how do I characterize the
two conferences I have two and a half
year old twin daughters at home so I
hear often
daddy I want the same thing same thing
but different
so saikhan is the same world-class
conference as saikhan us just in a
different Estonian sauce the organising
team has told me that this this year the
dinner party will be in a beach party
style I don't know what that means but I
have cut down on my pizza intake I
suggest to do the same and book your
trip to Thailand I hope to see you there
that was the easy part
no I need to introduce the next speaker
who's my boss for the last six years 11
months and 9 days and will be for the
next 20 days until he will retire in a
fifth of December after a long service
in Estonian Defence Forces if you get
him talking in a smaller group than this
then maybe he will tell you about his
teenage era when when he grew up in a
Soviet occupied Estonia and was heavily
engaged in a in clandestine activities
against the Soviet state activities
which would if caught land the person in
youth jail and ruin his and his family's
future
in early nineties when Estonia got our
independence he was one of the first
ones to join the Estonian Defence Forces
back then it meant that the enemy was in
the country the Soviet occupying troops
were in the country so joining Defense
Forces meant that you don't know whether
the occupying troops will leave or they
bring reinforcements he served from
platoon commander all the way to the
commander of Estonian Defence Forces in
the next three decades in the last seven
years as a chief of defense he has led a
very successful defence reform turning
Estonian Defence Forces from what's
known as a hollow force to real fighting
force which would be really easy if
there was a massive inflow of resources
however in
dona there never is such thing as
massive inflow of resources so we've had
to do it to it with what we got
so to sum it up I I present you a man
who has devoted his life to keep the
boundary between tyranny and a free
world right where it is today your own
Terrace sir
[Applause]