he recently open sourced we built it at
coinbase and I think a lot of what has
been said so far in the conference will
actually resonate with this tool talking
about ways to automate security and
scalable operate across lots of services
this is a tool that we built to help us
do that because basically coinbase
started expanding very quickly but we
also have really big security
requirements so this is why we built it
and now that it's open-source I hope
that this is something you can use you
can fire it off today from your laptop
during the presentation if you want so a
bit about me quickly I work at coinbase
on the security team and if you don't
know what coinbase is it's a digital
currency platform you can buy and sell
things like Bitcoin and aetherium and
other digital assets so we have an
exchange and some fancy mobile apps and
things like this and the security
requirements a pretty large a coin base
because we're sort of this big pot of
gold sitting on the internet and a lot
of the money is stored offline but we
still have a fair bit of money online
and so for financially motivated
attackers that we're one of the largest
bounties online I would say but at the
same time we want to operate in a very
agile development environment we want to
deploy continuously and we we have lots
of developers writing lots of code in
lots of different languages and lots of
services so security becomes a challenge
of trying to be as preventative as
possible and trying to enforce as many
good checks in our pipeline so this this
tool really came out of scaling as I
said so as for some context I'll tell
you sort of what happened with coinbase
over the last few years so I started in
June 2015 and my manager on my first day
took me out for coffee and said I want
100 percent of services that we deploy
to have production that a deployed to
production have scanning of some kind
and back in those days we had one
monolithic rails app so this was pretty
easy I was like alright cool I have one
thing to take care of the problem is
that was here and then this is the
number of services we started deploying
over the next few years so this problem
started started getting a bit out of
hand and and this is why we built this
tool so yeah a number of services and
autograph doesn't really show up but
these are all in different all in
different languages and and on different
frameworks and things like that so quick
review of scanners I think a lot of you
already know how security scanners work
and many different types and I've learnt
about some during this conference
business which is great but I will
quickly review security scanners and
sort of what I expect out of them
input-output wise some problems with
security scanners that you might have
when you're trying to deploy them at
scale and then we'll talk about what
Salas does how it solves this very
problem and then I'll actually go into
sort of I am also as I said it's like
free you can run it directly you'll show
you a command to run it in a moment you
can run it on a repository you might
have locally and then we'll talk about
some of the cool things you can do with
Salas how you can configure it how you
can use it in your infrastructure and
then always point to like the resources
so you can check it out as well so
software scanners very quickly I think
of a scanner is just some piece of
software that analyzes some other pieces
of software it could be linting it could
be looking for CVS could be doing all
sorts of things so basically you have
some source code that is ingested
basically as an input the code is the
input to the scanner it will pass or
fail hopefully if it fails you it tells
you what's wrong with your code and then
you have a feedback loop where the
failure message can go to the developer
the developer can fix their pull request
and then they can merge hopefully
compliant code into into the master
branch so a good example of this is in
Ruby land there's a lot of Rivia
coinbase so a lot of my example examples
will be ruby based so lint is not
necessarily security related but it's
the type of scanner Rubick off is sort
of the go-to ruby linty you take some
piece of code this is actually some
piece out of salus that's arbitrary you
put this through birkoff it will say hey
this string here should be frozen
because you're treating it as a constant
and it should be immutable go fix that
and then you have that feedback loop
we've talked a lot about CVE scanners
another example would be again just in
case you don't know what it is some
documented vulnerability so CVE scanner
looks at your dependencies bundler audit
is the way to do this with ruby gems
which is the libraries and really so you
could say let's say we're including in
our
and now project activesupport three to
ten blonde Laura we'll look at this
thing and then find out hey there's this
new invulnerability came out in 2015 you
should upgrade this thing and again you
have that feedback loop so these
scanners are really good and I do
recommend knowing which scanners are
relevant to your frameworks and as Liz
said two speeches ago this will probably
save your ass one day so scanners are
really important I think firstly CVE
things scanners can be quite powerful
every year Verizon does a big analysis
of lots of breaches and they collect a
lot of metrics on them and how they
happened and in 2015 their statistic was
that name and I 99.9% of exploited
vulnerabilities were from CVS that were
out for the for about a year before the
actual exploit so just by cleaning up
you'll stack from CBE's should probably
prevent a lot of possible attacks and
then in 2018 they basically said the
same thing and for every year in between
they just gave a list of tips this year
but like one of the things they said is
you know cyber criminals are just using
new and vulnerabilities not just but I
mean usually they are if it's a
nation-state which is using zero-days
you've got some bigger problems I would
say and then so you can guard against
these by upgrading so scanners for CPUs
are very important other types of
scanners they'll look for energy
patterns so for example using eval in
many different languages including Ruby
if that's on user controlled input
you'll get nasty e that's not good I
also like scanners because they're not
fatigued like humans especially when it
comes to like ship time and everyone's
trying to put pure crude really quickly
scanner operates the same every time so
that's that's very important you can run
them on every build and you can run them
around the clock this also ensures that
you have some sort of baseline for the
health of all your services at every
point in time and the last thing to say
is these are not silver bullets and I
think the NIC the last speaker said this
as well like you should probably use
scanners in tandem with human reviews at
least I would recommend that humans are
very good at analyzing things like
business logic or custom modules that a
scanner might not
pick up usually I would say especially
the the the the non CV style security
scanners the ones that are looking for
sequel injections or remote code
execution and stuff like this they send
to work strongest for frameworks which
are most rigid so for instance rails is
a very rigid framework to build a web
application there's like a rails way to
do things and if you don't do it the
rails way in a rails app you probably
just waste a lot of time now rigidity is
not good in all cases but for security
it's actually really good because that
means that president beef as he's no
more known online can make the brakeman
scanner which is incredibly powerful
looking at how data pulses through an
application and then working out if you
have a remote code execution or if you
have a sequel injection or anything like
that so yeah it's it's worth knowing
which scanners are available and rigid
frameworks I think actually tend to do
pretty well with scanners so how might
you deploy a scanner you've decided
scanning is really good how are you
gonna run this thing in your
infrastructure so the first thing you
can do very easily but not very
maintainable is to just run it on the
repository so you download bundle audit
locally you go to the repository that
you want to just scan and you just run
bundle audit check and it gives you
output great so you can now as an
individual scan each of your
repositories the
the issue with this is that you kind of
have to do it manually every time the
code changes so that sucks you could do
this slightly better if it was a
pre-commit hook maybe but then you have
to control the development environment
of all your developers and that's not
good usually developers a very
particular about their environments and
I prefer at least of what culture where
you can sort of have your own
development environment use whatever you
want and instead I think what's a better
idea is to just put these scanners in
the CI CD pipeline directly so I kind of
think of you know you'll build up or the
thing that runs all the tests internally
as sort of like doing preflight checks
before you put something in production
so it's just like an aircraft who's
checking all their flaps and their
ailerons before they take off so instead
what you can do is just run the actual
scanner in this case rubric all the
linty but it could be anything
you could run
in the test suite itself so this block
of code here is something we used to use
to run these scanners in the test Suites
themselves to this code it looks kind of
weird but it's it's a spec Ruby testing
framework and you can execute anything
in there including your security
scanners so you could go around to every
repository and just add a test which is
like run the scanner and if the scanner
fails fail a test suite and if the test
suite fails then the build will fail and
if the bill fails you probably shouldn't
push it into production so this is a
pretty good way to ensure that you have
continuous monitoring on every pull
request and so this worked for a while
and basically we had a situation where
you have a developer in all my slides
developers are these fairies jessica's
and so you have a developer they push
the source control that thing gets run
on a CI server so that you can run the
test suite and that's where you can
stick these security scanners and if
there's a failure the developer will see
it they'll fix their pull request and
eventually that makes its way into the
cloud cool so this pipeline works well
or it did when we had one massive
monolithic rails app and I had one
codebase to look after the problem is
that we started scaling and suddenly I
had to replicate this block of code over
and over and over again into lots of
different repositories and to get this
like 100% of services deployed having
scanned metric work meant that this this
started breaking down a lot because
basically you ended up with a situation
where you had if you had m scanners and
n code bases you had to use m times n
code blocks and anytime you wanted to
change anything upgrade the scanner
version test out a new scanner decide
one scan is useless and you're going to
replace it with something else you would
have to make n times n code changes and
this definitely did not scale so I
wanted to avoid asking all the service
owners to do this for me I didn't to
have to just email the dev lists of
every day and say like hey please update
to this version of the scanner one
because that's a lot of work teams that
really I would expect the application
security team to do but also there's
sometimes a lot of context that's
required to understand how the scanner
works how to configure it correctly it's
really easy to miss configure a lot of
these scanners so that they
I then just softly fail or they just
don't actually scan what you think
they're scanning so this this sort of
just put a lot of burden on the
application security team so I thought
well I guess I'm gonna have to do this
myself once we start a scanning scaling
that's what I looked like it was not fun
so thinking back to David wheeler this
is probably one of my favorite quotes
all problems in computer science can be
solved by another level of indirection
David wheeler was a professor of
computer science I believe it Cambridge
not far away I think the only case which
this is not true for is too many problem
too many levels of indirection which can
actually be a problem sometimes so
instead what we decided to do was we
would build this thing called Salus and
it would run all the scanners and
configure them and work out what to do
and instead each test suite would just
run latest Salus and so you now replace
this block of code with a big docker
container instead and that is like now
you'll point it to everything that you
actually want to want to do so kind of
like Nick was saying in the previous in
the previous presentation at a level of
indirection to take care of
authentication in a global way well this
is kind of doing that but doing it with
security scanners instead so what
exactly is Salus internally so as I said
it's a big docker container and it has
two components in it well many
components but let's say - one is the
Ruby application itself and this is just
a small blob of code I mean just a bunch
of files but it's a blob of code that
will coordinate scanners it basically
looks at the source code and decides is
this a ruby app if yes maybe I should
run this scanner is it a rails app if
yes I should run the scanner is it a
known app if yes i should run the scan
and then it also has all the scanners
installs for many different languages
and on the right side i kind of have the
repository sitting there so that's
probably on the local filesystem of the
CI server or wherever you you're running
a test suite and you volume this thing
into the container so that Salus can
then actually analyze it so this is the
magic command right here you could run
this right now on a repository you might
have locally and coinbase slash Salus on
the end
that is sitting on docker hub right now
so you can pull it directly so I'll
actually just run through this commanded
because that basically explains how
everything works so docker run that's
like your one dependency that you need
to run this thing you will need doc Oh -
sorry I'm just because I don't this
container is irrelevant after it runs so
you can delete it - tea so that you
attach a terminal and you can see the
output that's probably useful this - V
is important this is volume in the
current directory that you're in
presumably you went to the directory you
want to scan and whom slash repo is just
a magic path that's where Salas expects
to see the source code it's going to
scan and so you volume in the repository
and then it just executes in the docker
file for this thing this is an entry
point which kicks off the the Salas Ruby
application so once you run this thing
you get some text output and it kind of
looks like this so I ran Sallis on
itself actually and it decided to run
bundle audit because it has some Ruby
dependencies it passed it also happens
to have some node dependencies so that
passed pattern search I'll go over that
in a minute but that's basically like
grapple looking for anti-patterns you
can define an arbitrary list of reg X's
and if it finds them it could fail the
build or if it doesn't find them and you
require them it can fail the build repo
not empty so we had this interesting
case where due to some rather complex
infrastructure issues which I won't go
into there was this point where we
accidentally scanned nothing we vol 2
nothing into the repository and so Salas
just passed on every possible run
because it found no errors because there
was nothing to scan so this test
literally just checks that you have at
least one file to scan strong defaults
is something we like in security scanner
land so we put that in there just to
make sure if you accidentally miss
configure something Salas will throw an
error and then the last two things I'll
speak about that as well a bit later but
we found it very useful to also report
all the dependencies that a project is
using and we have a way to ship that
into our logging pipeline and this
should be easy with Salas to do and your
infrastructure as well and then as
have talked about if you know all the
dependencies that are running across all
your services it's then very easy to go
into incident response mode once you get
CVE that comes out so sort of recap of
what I was saying Ruby application we'll
start by initializing configuration and
there's a lot of fancy things you can do
with it so I'll go over a few of them in
a minute it loops through each of its
scanners that it knows about is it
appropriate to run the scanner
if yes run the scanner it then compiles
all of the outputs of these things and
puts them into a report and this will go
to stand it up by default but you can
also post that report in multiple
different formats to an HTTP endpoint if
you want so if you have an internal log
consumer in your infrastructure you can
send all your sales reports there and
then depending on what you're running
let's say you're running elasticsearch
or something it can conveniently index
everything and keep it there so that in
the future if you're like oh wow there's
a new open SSL bug who's using open SSL
you just query elasticsearch and you'll
find your sales reports and it will tell
you which services are running open SSL
and useful for CI pipelines it will exit
zero if any issues have found usually a
test suite if it sees something exit
zero will just fail the whole build so
it's useful for that so remember this
situation I said I had a lot of code
changes to make and we were scaling too
quickly and I couldn't keep up and I was
not happy about that so now with Salus I
make one code change I have an internal
Salus that everyone pulls into their
test suite if I want to update something
or test something I just change that one
code base build the new Salus push it up
to the registry and then everyone pulls
that down so this is kind of what it
looks like now container registry or the
thing that's hosting the configuration
file I'm happy now because I can make
one change and roll that a crowd roll
that across the whole fleet kind of
instantly so that's that's like there's
no massive magic here like all the
scanners and not all but most of the
scanners inside of salus are just other
open-source projects this thing is all
about how you coordinate that at scale
so
oh and actually sort of as an example we
happen to run circle CI internally at
coin base but you might be running
Travis or some sort of other building
platform if you are using circle this is
a small piece of what they had these
concepts called workflows so this is
literally all you have to add to your
circle file to run Salus in your
infrastructure you just check out the
code and then you run it and then this
will run in parallel with all your other
tests and then on your pull request you
just get some some some statuses so this
is again Sallis running on Salus but for
this particular instance circle had
three things to do run the linty rum
Salus and rama tests and then if
something was to fail you could then
look at the details link
Souths would have output that can then
tell the developer what to do and I
remember there was actually one of the
speakers I think the first bigger the
conference talked about how a lot of the
scanner outputs sometimes make not much
sense so Salas is sometimes an
opportunity to to shim that away from
the developer and put your own language
in there to sort of help them fix
self-service their issues so are going
to sales configuration because when we
first started working on sows there are
a lot of reasons why we couldn't roll it
out across every codebase and that
probably also applies to different
infrastructure and different
organizations so my hope is that the all
the pieces of configuration that you can
use make it possible to use in your
infrastructure and especially across
every repository so as I said the first
thing that is important to realize about
the configuration is you can turn on and
off scanners so by default every scanner
that it has it will just run it if it
seems appropriate and these are the ones
that are currently supported Liz just
spoke about gas forego which is great
I'm just learning about it now probably
tomorrow I will make a poor request into
Salas to put gas in there so that can be
rolled across the whole fleet as well so
here are the scanners that exist right
now everything will run by default but
you can say don't run this thing I don't
think it's a good scanner or whatever
you can also choose what will actually
fail the build if one of the particular
scanners will fail so the way you would
do that oh yeah each scanner also has
the same configuration well so you have
a config flag making the docker command
slightly more complex you can give the
config flag and just point to a
particular file
Salas configuration is just the llamo
file and this will tell you well you can
tell it what to run you can also if you
just have a saddle sitting in your
repository it will automatically look
for that so that's an easy way to do it
and if for some reason you would like to
use an environment variable you can use
that as well so basically his like a
block of llaman which could be valid
South's configuration you could say
active scanners I only want you to run
patent search and NPM audit and the only
thing I'm going to enforce is patent
search so only if one of the reg X's
that I looked for maybe it was
dangerously set innerhtml in a react
application or something if you find
that thing then you can lead to a non
zero exit status and if npm what it
happens to fail then for some reason you
probably should care about that failing
but if for some reason you didn't it
wouldn't be enforced here cool that was
more for local configuration but how can
you do global configurations so as i
said we like to know that the entire
organization is adhering to some sort of
security policy and some sort of
standard so what you can do is also just
host this llamo file at some end point
like we could just be an s3 bucket it
could be anywhere and sales will
actually just pull the thing down from
that URL and then pass that
configuration in use that so this is a
really easy way to sort of start
upgrading things across the fleet the
configuration file can also host these
these ray X's let's say that it's
looking for when it runs the pattern
search scan so if you decide it turns
out that a lot of our developers are
making this one mistake over and over
again they keep using I don't know they
keep using
backticks in Ruby to shell out to CD
instead of just using cheddar which is a
native thing you could use in Ruby so
we're good now going to look for back
ticks and if we see that we're going to
flag it
and you can put in custom error message
in there as well so the developer knows
what's wrong so this is this is what's
what's really useful about these global
security policies it's also especially
useful if you want to test out something
new so you might say we want to try this
backtick example I just sort of gave but
we don't know if this is going to just
fail every build and every developer
will get very angry
so something I'm always cautious about
whenever I changed Alice's will this
actually break a lot of bills and then
surprise lots of developers that's never
a good position for your security team
to be in because you always want your
security team to be liked by your
developers developers as much as
possible so what you can do is put
something in soft mode you launch it on
this global configuration and you say if
you find this tell me about it and put
it in the report but you can let the
bills continue and then you can collect
all the metrics and just see if any
repositories are failing if they are you
can work with the developers to fix them
and then when everything is green you
can make this an official and forced to
check and go forward and now everyone is
is at this higher level so what happens
if you have a global security policy but
then it turns out one of the
repositories must have an exception and
this tends to happen a lot so for
instance you might say thou shalt not
deploy if there is a CVE in one of your
dependencies but then there's just one
repository over here it needs this
package and there's no patch for it but
it does have a CVE and you have
definitely worked out that you're using
the package in such a way that your
application won't be vulnerable even
though that there's a CV either if this
is the case or there's one of many other
cases that leads to exceptions in the
rules you can actually concatenate these
configuration files so you can have the
global security policy be passed first
and then a local configuration file can
go on top of that which can include
exceptions or overwrite pieces of the
previous configuration so that you can
still have Salus on every repository but
still allow for these sort of like local
exceptions here and there where it's
necessary so this is something we use a
lot to make sure that we can still
maintain a hundred percent
Sallis coverage but compliance sometimes
needs gaps in the policies where
appropriate
so a custom Salas the Salas that is open
source has scanners which we thought
would be useful to many organizations
and as I said we hope to expand this
over time but it doesn't have some
scanners that we probably use internally
at coinbase which are not useful for
anyone else and there may be some things
you want to check for internally as well
which may be more complex than just
looking for regular expression maybe in
actual scan scanner that you're going to
run or you've built internally or
something like that so it's very easy to
customize house as well you can build
your own Salas container with a docker
file with just two lines in it basically
you just write from coin they sell us
and so that's the actual container that
you're gonna be inheriting from and then
you can copy in some arbitrary list of
scanner files that you've written so
this could be an example of one an
example here is let's say you want to
check that every docker file pins the
SHA or pins the container that inherits
from you could write a small bit of Ruby
to check this logic and then you can
just build a new container with that and
south's will pick up your Ruby file and
just execute it as part of the container
so that's that's pretty useful like all
you have to implement is the run command
and the should run question mark command
and all method enough you guys so it's
highly configurable which is useful so
we we have the irken source version and
then we run an internal version with
some coin based specific logic in it and
one inherits from the other so I talked
about custom error messages this is the
output from the CVE checker in ruby
bundle audit now to me because I've been
working in security for a while all of
this makes sense to me and it probably
makes sense to everyone into the room
but I know that a lot of developers
sometimes get this error message and
they're like what does this mean like
what is CVE why am I being linked to
Google Groups and like denial-of-service
I've heard of but I don't know what it
is so you can also use Sal's to wrap
these messages kind of nicely and then
give them next steps so maybe give them
points of contact that they can speak to
which is something else you might use
sales for maybe purely just for the
messaging point of view
I think the better the messaging the
more self-service your your your
security can be for developers which
gives you more time I think as a
security team to focus on other issues
so let's talk about Salas reports so
Salas is pretty from a boost in the
amount of data it collects it will
firstly collect which scanners passed
and failed that's probably important to
know
it also looks will collect any reasons
that it fails as I mentioned before it
also collects all the dependencies or at
least looks at the name and the version
and the source of each dependency that's
being pulled into a project so I think
right now that works for go Python Ruby
and node so it collects all these
dependencies makes a big list out of
them it also just the report will also
include the configuration that sounds
used and then you can also tell it where
to send this report so maybe as part of
your build pipeline you want to create a
text file - as an artifact maybe this is
useful for the developer to look at but
then you can also post these reports to
some arbitrary endpoint don't don't send
to this endpoint this is a made-up
endpoint internal dotnet I don't know
who owns that domain they probably don't
want to receive your sales report but
you could probably have an internal log
consumer that you can send this thing to
and it's I mean you can specify the
format as Jason that's probably what
you've won if it's an API but it could
be Amal or it could be text and then
once you consume these logs you can
start to do lots of fancy instant
response with it so as I said reports
like by default standard out will be
printed the text file that might be used
for a CI artifact and then this is good
for remote consumption on the left you
see a text blob which is maybe what the
text Apple would look like and on the
right side is just a piece of it's the
equivalent report but just in JSON
format and then the useful thing is once
you ingest this thing into your log
pipeline you can look at things like
which dependencies are we using and so
as I said so we run Kabana on top of our
elasticsearch cluster and this allows us
to easily query who's using what
dependencies if a new CDE came out or if
we worked out that
maybe there's a new type of
vulnerability in rails and only the
latest version of break man happens to
look for that vulnerability we can
quickly query which rails applications
are not using the latest Salus and
haven't checked for this thing yet and
then we can easily move into instant
response mode so that's that's very
helpful for those sorts of things so
other resources you can look at we as I
said we recently reckon sauce this thing
you can go to coinbase slash Salus on
github you can find it and as I said on
taco hub the the thing is hosted so you
could build it and run it and if your
security conscious that's probably a
better thing to do then just pulling it
from docker hub because you're not
really guaranteed of the supply chain
there but if you want you can just pull
it from docker hub or you can pull it
from docker hub into a registry and then
just pull that thing down that's
probably the most secure practice and we
recently launched blog post about I
guess releasing this product you can
read that blog post if you missed
anything in my talk roughly the same
information so a bit of a summary last
Seles useful something you can inject
into your CI pipeline if everyone just
includes Salus once you can now roll
things out across the whole fleet with a
single configuration change or a single
code change to the south's container
which is very useful that keeps your
security team happy and light and
scalable and gives them lots of metrics
and it also still ensures that you have
that tight feedback loop with your
developer and I think you can actually
improve that feedback loop with your
developer because you get the ability or
you have the chance to inject custom
messaging in there which can sometimes
be very useful final note I just want to
say thank you to the open source
developers which make these scanners we
leverage a lot of open source software
in general I think most companies do but
the amount of I say additional speed or
comfort we get from these open source
scanners is tremendous so huge shout-out
to the people who make those things Ryan
Adam and Slava helped me build this
thing so I thank them a lot and deficit
corner organisers for making such a
great conference cool that was pretty
fast I actually have nine minutes for
questions anyone has anything
any questions no sweetie yeah thanks so
much
[Applause]