so my name is Nick Smith I work for
Tallis II security actually there are
some pictures of our hardware security
modules earlier I'm not going to be
talking about encryption today as I
normally would I'm going to talk about
securing microservices specifically in
the kubernetes context so some of the
other work I do on path fatality
security is I'm a member of something
called the sto security working group
SEO is a service mesh for kubernetes
this is gonna be quite fast and we're
not going to go into too much detail
just because we've not got enough time
so I like to start with the warning all
the tools we talked about today and
actually eight over the last two days
they're not silver bullets kubernetes
Sto
all the other tools that we've spoken
about aren't going to make your world
better on their own you have to do a lot
of the work yourself a lot of these
measures are defense and depth and
you've got to remember Security's all
about context it's where you deploy your
mitigations and you have to understand
that your mitigations match your context
ok so I think the last speaker asked how
many people are using kubernetes how
many are using kubernetes in production
and is anyone using ISTE oh does anyone
know what this do is fantastic right so
let's have a very quick primer on what
we think mark services are or from my
opinion what mike services are so
currently a lot of development is
focused at Mike and there's a number of
reasons for that so what's a Mike
service it's something it sits alone it
stands alone it's a small piece of
functionality that has been derived from
a bigger function a bigger service mark
services tend to cooperate so to be able
to use some part of a website it may be
a number of Mike services cooperating to
provide that functionality
most modern mark services are being
built on top of containers and on top of
kubernetes like deployments now what is
interesting about this is we can
dynamically compose products
services at runtime from a number of
component parts additionally and
interestingly from an operation
standpoint it allows us to develop
coding solutions in more autonomous
fashion so what do we mean by that we
mean we can have a number of agile teams
each of which may own a set of Micra
some higher function so that will sounds
good
but from a security perspective that
brings some challenges so when we didn't
compose our solution we start to lose
the holistic view so how do we reason
about the security of our solution as a
whole because it's no good just
understanding is each of my microcytic
eur within the context they define
there's a bigger context which is the
context that they all live in the more
so more mike services we have no more
issues we were likely to see so we've
gone from building monoliths to mazes
so as an auditor or someone coming in to
review the architecture or a system it
can be very difficult to understand the
security promises because no longer can
we perform things like static analysis
over a single executable what we have
now is a number of transitions a network
interface we're processing is done and
that is much more difficult to
understand and to reason about and when
we have autonomous teams and when they
have different goals they will use
different technologies so my assumption
is people who are running microcircuit
you are using more than one set of
technologies so you're probably not just
the spring boot house you're probably
spring and some some Python and maybe
some go and that makes it again more
difficult because no longer can we have
rigorous policies to say this is how you
must develop solutions because actually
it's changing and we as a security
community we need to be able to work
with that so I've spoken about it's
difficult to analyze the interactions
and so we heard about this earlier but
the facebook viewers exploit is a
classic one so it's three bugs and the
interesting
about this is it was the complex
interaction between them that allowed
there to be a vulnerability and this is
really hard to mitigate if you don't
understand the system at this more
holistic level and understand the
interactions between your services so we
know it's hard to do this and we know
that the tools in this area are not as
mature as perhaps if you're building
more monolithic applications
operationally it's very difficult
because security people are
traditionally seen as mitigators of
process or progress rather which is one
of my favorite terms and so we must work
with organizations now to go faster and
the only way we can do that is to build
tools and this is why dev Sec ups is
cool because we can build tools and get
developers to use them and we can move
security earlier into the lifecycle so
with that being said security for micro
services is no different land security
has ever been there are three tenants of
security which are the most fundamental
authentication authorization and
accounting although the last one I
prefer to call auditing and I probably
will call it auditing throughout the
rest of the talk so its most basic level
authentication is the identification of
a human or a service it is what we build
access control on top of it is the
cornerstone of what we need to do
authorization who can do what why when
and where enough said an accounting what
happened so accounting is the one that
generally gets left behind but is as
important now in security and especially
in mike rizzo nothing so the ability to
understand how big the exploit was how
big is my exposure to this exploit
because it once you've been exploited it
is very important that you understand
what the impact is it's no good just to
say we've been exploited because with
GDP our people are going to come and ask
how many records have you lost so it's
very important and so what we're going
to look at is how we can innermark
services world and with the security
view of this
how can we make this easier and the
answer at the moment is becoming service
meshes so we're going to talk a bit
about that and specifically we're going
to talk about sto other ones do exist
otherwise to enforce these things do
exist but we're going to talk about sto
today because it is the de facto native
kubernetes service mesh so what does the
mesh mister deployment look like it
looks like a childlike diagram on a
PowerPoint slide so in a mesh this
deployment uses connect to your system
probably services deployed in containers
and each container enforces policy and
does things in different ways because
we've got a Java container we've got a
Python container we've got something
else down here and someone was mad and
wrote a container using C that makes it
very difficult for us to reason about
the security
additionally we may have party services
in here and they will have very very
different ways of enforcing policy and
defining policy so it makes it much more
difficult so what we're looking for is a
way to bring this all together and then
we saw some talks earlier about
instrumenting code and plate using
frameworks and standards but actually
enforcing standards across larger
organisations is very difficult and it's
not something we should strive to do
what we should strive for is a mesh
network so what is a service mesh the
service mesh is essentially an SDN it's
a software-defined network it is at the
deployment of your service at the
network level so layer 4 to 7 we there
will be the injection of a sentry a
transparent proxy but the difference
here between say traditional api
gateways such as in AWS is you will have
a micro gateway per service and they
will automatically be injected
every time you spin up a container or
service now at the point their span up
policy can be injected into them and
this policy defines how people are
allowed or services are allowed to
interact with service services that
you're hosting
inside your infrastructure and here we
have we can have people who set policy
and this can be teams and teams can set
policy as code okay so it's quite an
interesting concept
but it's all based on software-defined
Network now the nice thing about this
model is scaling the policy in the
Gateway enforcement so whilst we things
like AWS is API gateway and various
other versions that you can get from
other cloud vendors it's quite a large
monolithic solution this is far more
fine-grained and actually these are very
lightweight containers so they've reduce
the time and the through and maintain
your through per of your system because
they're actually looking at a small
subset of rules just for your service or
container so in more detail what is this
do so it's Theo as we've seen is
software-defined network it's split
between a control plane and the data
plane the data plane is what sits in
front of your service okay it's built
out of a component called the invoice
proxy which came out of the company lyft
Google and IBM and pivotal and some
other people have helped build this
layer here which is the control plane in
the control plane is what manages your
security so in the control plane is
where we set our policy for our service
and this will be at the level of HTTP
see HTTP and G RPC so we can describe
this is my REST API and these are the
policies that apply to these endpoints
or in T RPC terms we can say these are
the functions and these other people
that are allowed to call these functions
you get some additional security
measures such as automatic TLS
management so that all your services
automatically authenticate with all your
other services without you having to do
anything you have no other solution
there that you need to install by
default all of your services will get an
authentic TLS cert which will allow
service to service authentication
I guess the other interesting bit there
to know is the telemetry part so also
built into sto is the ability to monitor
transparently all the requests that
going in and out of your system and that
can be hooked up to a number of other
off-the-shelf solutions such as
prometheus
you
they're with me right so let's go back
to the three eizan authentication
authorization and accounting they've not
changed we've just changed the
architecture so let's let's have a look
a bit about what authentication means to
a service mission modern web services so
authentication is it's very basic vo I
don't the unique identification of a
human or service that's trying to access
your system how services and humans
authenticate is slightly different but
generally it's a proof or a challenge
which is swapped for a cryptographically
signed token so generally I'm sure
everybody in here is is using JSON web
tokens to various expense and hates them
in various different ways but they're
quite simple to use so if we look at how
humans authenticate it's generally
through usernames and passwords and
obviously everyone in here uses a second
factor or not but that you use the
second factors and passwords to exchange
your identity for a scientist ershon and
that's the same whether you're using
sam'l or the newer authentication flow
such as open ID Connect if you're
building authentication going forwards
please choose open ID connect not sam'l
your life will be much better from a
services point of view it's not really
changed services have an identifier and
they have a shared secret or a public or
and private key which they can use to
exchange for an identity token
additionally those things like mutual
TLS but we should probably try and steer
away from that because it's harder to
manage so from the service mesh point of
view there's a pattern emerging how do
we enforce authentication for all our
services without having to put the code
into every single one and to audit to
make sure every single one of our
services is checking authentication has
happened and we can do that with
transparent authentication so
transparent authentication works like
this the user tries to contact a service
to perform an operation our century our
service mesh intercepts that request our
service mesh
can then using the policy database
identify what need whether a request
needs to be authenticated or not by
default everything should be
authenticated and that you should have a
whitelist for things that don't the
important part there is the redline
because that is where the decision is
made of who needs to authenticate the
service mesh then can say this user is
not authenticated and redirect them to
the correct authentication endpoint what
that does is it stops the service having
to deal with authentication and it means
we can do authentication in a consistent
way across all our micro services and
we've taken that logic up out of the
application layer and into our network
layer the response from authenticating
is generally a token as we've said and
then when the user makes another request
the Gateway can say okay does a token
exist is it the correct token does it
does it validate if it does request can
go through so what this does is it
solves a more holistic level how we
authenticate and enforcing that policy
for us the next the next leg of our
three-legged stool for Security's
authorization so authorization is the
decision of whether a user or service
can perform an operation so quite often
people will take note of point two on
this slide which is can somebody perform
a request given some sort of context and
that will be time policy some other
input however and when we look at the
Facebook example the Ferb on down is
actually more important now because we
can have services making requests on
behalf of other services and other
people
so there's actually it's not just can
service do this thing it's can service a
call service be bearing in mind you
Alice our user has made the original
request so authorization can get quite
difficult to manage now there's two
types of authorization that we generally
see in Web Services world and certainly
in a mesh world what we think about
there's the explicit upfront
authorization so people who understand
all
or to or had to deal with it when it's
to understand that this means things
like how do I allow my CI engine to
access my github account to perform
tasks on my on my behalf
then there's the just-in-time aspect
which is given an identity can someone
perform a task so let's look at those in
slightly more detail so explicit
authorization as I say is an oauth2 like
model and we've seen the childlike
picture to the side of the slide what
this means it means that a usual service
will request from some authority an
assertion that they're allowed to
perform a task before they request it of
our actual service so this puts majek
into the client that says I must
authorize before I try and access a
service now this is really good it works
where you know there's a limited scope
of authorization that your application
needs before it goes to perform its
tasks and you can see here that our
service mesh can check that given a
token in a request which is in
previously issued does that token
include all the necessary claims that
we're expecting to allow authorization
to occur so just-in-time authorization
is slightly different and is slightly
newer in some respects and is now being
favored and you'll see a lot of it in
the Google stack this is where instead
of a user requiring an upfront decision
about whether they can access a service
or not based on their identity the
service mesh will make a just-in-time
decision so assuming a user is
authenticated previously as we saw on a
previous slide
they will provide that identity token
each time they make a request what the
service mesh century can then do say can
this person perform the task they're
asking at this time and what that allows
you to do is build far more dynamic
authorization models and
also allow far more entropy in your
decisions because you don't have to
allow or enforce upfront decisions
so you just base it on identity and a
current and the current context that can
be identified so there are two slightly
different models but it's quite
interesting and to understand the tomb
where where you might want to use them
so if we compare them we see that
explicit authorization is a really
useful thing when we are asking an
external entity whether we can perform a
task or whether we try to allow a
service to perform on our behalf
we're just in time authorization is
useful is when we've got far more
dynamic context and where perhaps our
application or climb doesn't know the
scope of the authorization it will need
throughout its lifetime both are valid
approaches but they're subtly different
in where you might want to apply them so
final a in our three a's is accounting
or auditing so accounting these what's
been done and why this is the bit that's
always missing from whenever you go and
see vendors they will set up an audit
trail but it'll just go into a bucket
and never be seen again but actually
that information is really useful you
can use it to feed back into your
pipeline for authorization decisions
because it allows you to identify things
like anomalies additionally you need to
keep on top of it in case you ever do
get breached it's fairly simple to
understand but when we look at it from a
service mesh point of view it's
something that happens during the
authorization and authentication schemes
it's it automatically falls out what
you're doing
so when a request comes in the service
gateway
identifies authorization and will create
your audit record for you automatically
so again this is quite nice because this
offloads
a lot of this logic from the application
and allows us to centralize and
normalize this at the layer seven of the
network stack so sto supports or will
support in the next two releases all of
these functions
but the real interesting part is how sto
is configured it is configured as code
so it becomes source code so it becomes
really useful and much more easy for our
devs to use in their workflow because
they can use the normal tools they
always use they can review the policy
that they define for their micro
services they can understand the rest of
the system because they can see the
other the rest of the systems policy
definition and we can manage it with
normal tools so I don't know if anybody
seen we've works get ups talks
I don't anyone seen those if not you
should you should watch them if people
haven't seen those really interesting
where you control your whole life cycle
through gear and git commits absolutely
fantastic but the other really
interesting thing I think the next stage
of everything will be the fact that
these policies are possible and what
that means is we can build tooling for
them and so when we look back again at
the Facebook examples Facebook was
difficult to identify and to manage
their exploit because it was difficult
to see the interactions with their
system because in sto and other
frameworks we can define all of our
policy as code we can actually enumerate
all the possible scenarios and so we can
identify anomalies upfront just by the
configuration that's going into the
database for our policy store so let's
read that so really powerful thing
that's coming along and will probably be
here in the next few months configures
code as well helps us to define what our
system is and what it is doing and helps
others to understand it so it allows
developers to document on the go in a
very lightweight fashion without forcing
them into writing separate design
documents or adding comments in their
code which are then have them to be
passed by complex tools it's just a
really good and nice ways to help us
manage security the other thing that we
get with the service message is
observability and what that really gives
us as a security community
the ability to make to reason about our
system and to make macro level decisions
so are we vulnerable to certain attacks
it's much easier to identify that if we
can observe the behavior of the running
system okay and itself it allows us to
self document our system and save time
and these are the really interesting
points of the service mesh is not so
much how they're built but the
capabilities they will give us in future
so everyone loves reading yeah Milan the
PowerPoint slides so I thought I'd show
you an example of an authorization
policy for sto so there's two concepts
shown here sto works on an hour back
model so role based access control the -
yeah Mille entries at the top define
roles so the one at the top an admin
role the admin role can do everything
with all services which is probably
quite open you probably wouldn't want an
admin role quite like that but the
second one's more interesting so the
second one identifies a single service
and the methods the HTTP methods that
are allowed to be executed on it and so
it's specific to this service now this
bottom section of the configuration here
defines what is called a role binding so
the role binding binds a role to set of
principles a set of people set of
services who can perform that role so we
can see here that there's a number of
subjects listed and we have user account
service cam a and also user service
account
ingress which also has properties with
claims in so these claims actually come
from a JWT passed by the user onto this
service and so what this means is that
we can say this you through this service
this user is allowed to perform the
tasks defined in this role so what that
gives us is much greater control over
who can do what when and why and because
it's yeah Mille we can pass it we can
build tools and we can reason about so
that was quick my final slide is really
about the move towards mic services and
as autonomous teams has presented a
conundrum for us because previously
whilst there would be big gates
especially in big companies big gates in
place to do security reviews to verify
people are doing things in a consistent
way that's no longer possible and
shouldn't be how we're looking to build
our systems in future what that does
mean is we have impaired view of our
system from a security perspective and
it makes it very difficult for us to
reason by moving towards the service
mesh we can normalize some of this
decision-making up a level out of the
applications and we can then self
document and understand our system
better
the configures code bit I think is the
real takeaway from the whole and
certainly my involvement with the SEO
community this is where all the power
comes because once you start managing
your entire estate infrastructure policy
source code everything is code
everything's a text file that you can
parse you can start to build really
powerful tools and understand a lot more
about your system so that if you're
going to take one thing away from this
whole talk is move in that direction if
you haven't already and find tools that
fit that model so that was mostly what I
was gonna say today there's various
links there which may or may not be
interesting if anybody's interested in
its do please come and talk to me
otherwise thank you very much
[Applause]
questions I guess silence they want it's
one Pakman there
hello any thought hello
any thoughts about how to get the
configures code as close as possible to
the application that you might be
writing on the micro service or does it
end up in a different repo
no so I can only talk about how we're
building our internal Marc services is
that with our kubernetes deployments and
our source code for a service they all
live together including the policy
definition so whilst the role binding
doesn't live there so who can access
what because that might change because
we build products not services we keep
all together and keep it all in one
place so well that means is we can
review everything together everything
together in one source commit we can
verify that the policy matches the code
that we've written and whether it all
makes sense and it also means it's far
easier to manage from source code
perspective because there's a single git
commit instead of having separate
repositories and then having to bring
separate repositories together we put
everything with the service so the
policy lives with the service
yeah most of the thing what you're
talking about is not taking is it not
taking care in the API manager like a
double use or two or a PG maja PG and
other stuff sorry thing what you're
talking about isn't taken care in the
double use or two API manager so from an
API gateway external calls into your
system are generally stops at the API
gateway what this covers is internal
calls as well so generally you wouldn't
internally go out through an API gateway
and back in so that and this is again is
about using container native tools and
so you can supply very fine-grained
policies at the point at where they're
gonna or as close to where they're going
to be enforced without actually having
to make code changes and especially if
you've got a heterogeneous environment
where you've got lots of different
languages it's just a way to manage that
anything else
I think I might be the only person here
that actually works on the Microsoft
stack as everyone else is talking about
Java and those sorts of things but so we
predominantly using Azure and I just
wanted to know from your experience of
know what experience you have
particularly with Azure but as your uses
a technology called service fabric right
in order to orchestrate its micro
services what is the difference between
the two I don't know anything about
service fabric and I've never logged
into my Azure account okay if that's
helpful sorry okay no mics my
expectation is with kubernetes moving
into Azure which I know is happening you
will end up with something you will end
up with this teo or an equivalent in
there that does the same thing I don't
know what level service fabric applies
but SEO is really about embedding in
kubernetes all if you use pivotal Cloud
Foundry it's Jerry's turning up there as
well so pivots are a big proponent
obvious tier I assume the one big
advantage as well would be as you say
this is kind of language and stack
agnostic in terms of if you want to go
Python go Java etc you can all
orchestrate that as exactly and that's
part of the reason that we've selected
it and actually why we are contributing
back to the open source is we understand
we're going to have this heterogeneous
environment where we don't really want
our I think we've got that 25 scrum
teams we we don't want to tell them to
use you must use Java and this and
spring boot because no one actually
likes Java and spring booth but we want
them to make the right decision based on
what they're trying to achieve this is
just a way to allow us to normalize
certain decisions okay thank you
hey just a question about sto I know you
mentioned during the talk that there's a
couple of features that were coming soon
perhaps and at the beginning when there
was a show of hands of who's using it in
production I mean maybe I'm too close to
the front but I couldn't see many from
where I am know how mature is it is is
it something which is ready to be rolled
out in the 1.0 about three months ago so
it's available a managed version is
available on gtp so Google but it has
literally just reached 1.0 so it's very
early stage but the API is existing API
sardine stable and it is deemed
production quality so it is used by
people like Google in turn I think
that's it
[Applause]