hello guys good morning everyone
no we're not see you guys here and let's
talk about security and service but
first let's talk about one thing that I
want to talk about more than service and
security myself so I'm a prison engineer
at a company called has owned and since
July I've also been one of the Amazon's
service service hero which just means
like a free ticket to reinvent this year
which is pretty sweet and the zone we
are a sports a streaming platform we do
both live sports as well as sports on
demand and right now we open in seven
different countries we have about 6 or 7
million subscribers globally you pay a
monthly fee similar to Netflix hence why
we often call ourselves the Netflix for
sports a peak we get about a million
concurrent users so there's some very
interesting technical challenges there
to support that kind of load that we
have if we find a bit more about what
excuse me what jobs we have available
and what we're doing as a team you can
follow us on Twitter as well as check
our engineering zone to come because
we're also hiring as well I'm pretty
sure like everybody else here so
personally I've been using a DBS for
about almost 10 years now and in one of
my previous companies I worked on a
non-trivial service architecture whereby
we migrated a social network to run
pretty much entirely on service so along
the way I'll learn a lot about all the
different things you could have learn to
make sure you can actually run your
production workload on this new
technology so when you go to a dreary
posting this chart already in terms of
the sheer responsibility model whereby
what security Amazon takes care of and
what security they steal your
responsibilities and traditionally
you're responsible for operating systems
the networking and firewall
configurations but of course when you go
to serve less Amazon is taking alcohol
is taking care of more of the
infrastructure for you including the
security around the operating system and
networking and so on which to me is
great news because as the application
developer I just don't have time to
constantly thinking about okay when
should I update my venture patch my OS
when's your update my firewall settings
and so on and so forth and having Amazon
do that for me just means that I care a
lot better protection in which
without doing anything myself so I also
don't have to worry about attacks
against the OS like they wanna cry or in
fact when the whole whole thing went
down with meltdown and Spectre and
everybody else was busy passing their
servers and machine images and whatnot
all my functions got patched I even
forgot about it and then the next day I
go to Twitter and I see Chris mom's
portal 3 say all with the lambda
functions has been now patched for
spectre and meltdown which is great
again is it's always for actual things
that gift from the provider we don't do
anything myself however my code is still
my responsibility along with all the
dependencies that my code has and if you
look at the last Hospital 10 list we got
from last year pretty much everything
she was saying at the top it's crazy how
injection attack is still number one
after ten years and when the guys from
snake looked at the top 50 biggest data
breaches that happen in 2016
they found that a quarter of them was
caused by applications using known
losing components we've known
vulnerabilities so these are things that
can easily prevent just by updating your
dependencies sorry Fifi the slides can
be available afterwards anyway and
another article will be another article
they looked at the toppings
some of the top thousand websites are
based on Alexa ranking and found that
almost 80% of them was using some
libraries has known vulnerabilities and
it's not surprising we looked at even
some of the biggest the front-end
frameworks are a Korean react has some
vulnerabilities at some point in time of
course they were patched in the later
versions but then it's still up to you
to make sure that you are using a later
version that do not have those known
vulnerabilities that people can attack
you with and then there's also libraries
like user agent which at one point I
think had had a pretty - the regex is
registered denial service attack as well
and of course even when you go into
surveillance even though you don't have
the wipeout service anymore it doesn't
mean that you are safe from the classic
sequent judgment attacks so if a you
saying
say my sequel or Aurora or whatever kind
of sequel database for me lambda
function you see you need to worry about
secret injection attacks you're sitting
to sanitize the inputs and protect
yourself accordingly and even when
you're using those secret databases
turns on a MongoDB you can still attack
it using its query syntax and then so so
the takeaway from there is that even
though you're working with service you
still need to think about all the same
application level attacks as before and
sequence action is still very much one
of the easy things that you can take off
and the graph qi has also been getting a
lot of popularity over the years and I
was three surprised as what I'm coming
into graph here to find out that
actually someone managed to do injection
attack against graph queue as well which
I guess when you think about it it's
probably not all that surprising because
ultimately your work your query it gets
translated into some requests to a web
server that executes some query against
a sick sick old say sequel database so
you can flick out how the transformation
happens you can still inject attacks you
can still get to injection attacks
against the graph your endpoint and also
found this server and I said literally
article about how there was there was a
CO injection for ompletely to run the
libraries that the link team published
so I guess you just can't trust anyone
these days and of course that means you
have to constantly update your
dependencies and if you aren't really
unlucky you're gonna pass out your
application so your dependency to a
version and you're gonna fix a whole
bunch of depend upon abilities that you
has and you're gonna find yourself in
another world where by the later
versions now has new vulnerabilities
that so you have to constantly do this
exercise and and if the I guess the
moral of the story is that your
application dependencies is probably a
lot bigger attack service then you
probably realize for starters you've got
your own dependencies but that's just
the tip of the iceberg
because underneath that there's a whole
of dependencies that your dependencies
depend on if you just take a look at any
number of popular packages with a noise
know from the OGS
for for Java you're gonna find the same
thing where there's a very deep qi of
dependency in fact it's so much so much
so i love this and by the way that's we
got a same name but that's not me and
obviously she gets a lot more reaches in
ID and of course I guess what I'm trying
to say here is that we should use
services i snack to try to automate this
process of identifying of scanning our
dependencies omission alerting us when
we have known vulnerabilities in our
dependencies including all the chances
dependencies that we have as well I also
noticed that kid has been doing this for
a few months now so when you go to
github repo you're satelli sends you a
report of what known for the police are
you have in your dependencies but the
thing I find about patching application
our dependencies compared to patching
your OS is that when you get those
security updates for your OS they tend
to be self-contained and it's so nice
and easy to apply but when it comes to
application dependencies especially with
frameworks oftentimes the normal
abilities are only fixed in the latest
version especially when you have major
version updates so even you saying save
version one of them the application
framework and then there's no known
vulnerabilities chances are if it's open
source software then the fix is only a
very point in version two which is not
it's now is if which is often not an
easy fix update because it's breaking
changes and often involved API changes
that you need to plan and integrate into
your application as well as into could
integrate with the rest of your team and
your security chain is strong as the
weakest link and when you look at for
example if I look at one of my let
anyone my functions so it's gonna depend
on a bunch of libraries it's gonna have
a bunch of users and it's also gonna run
a two pair so all of that is taking care
of by AWS and of course if you're
working and watching a movie then I
don't know why do you always do this but
they always want to attack the physical
infrastructure where the regarded by
armed guards and they can know to you
know do the Tom Cruise and the sneak
and for some reason everybody knows all
the systems that they've never seen
before they know how things hacking
Sally in two seconds and then they can
walk away and just blow things up no
punch a few guards and you know just
look like a boss but that's an attacker
of course I'm not gonna go anywhere near
the physical infrastructure for one
thing I'm gonna leave my bedroom you
want to do that so especially when
there's so many low hanging fruits I can
just attack against your dependencies or
against your application directly and of
course we probably all know this that
humans are often the weakest link in any
security chain and I'm sure most of you
have wor have seen that mr. Roberge we
haven't go check it out there's only to
see I think the three seasons now ice
right and if you see all that most of
the tactility in the show none of them
are very technical in fact most of times
they just do very simple social
engineering against the universe or some
application I've in one episode that
dolly just dropped the USB key near
police station and a policeman picked it
up plug in his lab so a free USB and
then you can run some code as soon as
the USB key is plugged into the machine
and of course you can attack the
developers for the application as well
maybe they are leaving the github
credential somewhere in the public repo
somehow so you can get if I can get into
their account and you can ask us any
software that they are responsible for
including the ones that are potentially
used in your organization and also they
can also attack the authors for the
dependencies that you use for your in
yours inside your software so this
happened last year and I think was
amazing the security researcher was able
to gain access
publish assess to 14% of all packages on
NPM at a time which included this some
of the most popular packages that you
find in the nodejs space so in total the
packages that he was able to gain
published assess he accounts for
something like 20% of total number of
downloads in MPM mount on a monthly
basis so that is pretty scary in fact no
this could have happened already we just
didn't know about it is we're lucky that
someone did this and tell us hey this
massive gap in your security chain
because the people that are writing the
dependence writing the software that
your software depends on is not doing a
very good job in protecting their MPM
the MPM accounts and the security
researcher use basic methods is they're
not used he didn't use anything crazy
just simple proof force and using known
the counter leaks okras your stuffing
and sometimes even found the NPN
credential just left hanging there in a
public repo so and the Wender he when I
read a summary another thing I found was
this is crazy like a thousand people
were using developers was using
passwords like one two three he or her
password I mean surely as developers we
gotta know better than this right so
it's really when you look at things
deities it's really hard not not to feel
let down and when you think about what
actually goes on inside a secure
environment for my lambda function hey
guess what I've got a bunch of really
useful environment variables in my
node.js in my lambda execution
environment including the Aetherius
access key secret ptosis security token
so all the information I need to get
access to your a this account if I can
get into your function so after about
hey as an attacker how can I actually
get into your function well it turns out
if I just published a package that you
may want to depend on so as an
experiment I put something on an NPM
with a name that you clearly should not
download and to my surprise like a week
later I would I want to them being
packaged have found - over 20 downloads
I got help us
so as the part of experiment I set up my
package is it's always doing is that the
initialization time I'm gonna look I'm
gonna scan everything that's in your
environment variables and then I'm gonna
publish to some endpoint our setup and
then that in that endpoint it's just a
simple API gateway with lambda I'm gonna
look at what's coming and then if that
pelo canst contains the it bus
credentials great I'm gonna send a
message to as an S so there I can get a
notification through SNS to my email and
the main fear here is I'm looking for
just those guys potentially I can even
look for database usernames and
passwords and so on as well and so that
works beautifully it took me like 15
minutes to set up and I was able to use
the credentials I remember myself to
gain access to my my own a diverse
account to list the contest I have in my
s/3 s/3 pockets so that's not great
that's way too easy and so a check ok
can i what happens if it's a transit
dependency so it's not something that I
depend on directly so I put in the
package there also with a rather ominous
name again people just keep downloading
this stuff I don't know why and then
again it still worked so he's just oh my
god it's too easy and the tensou and
later on after I did this and publish
the publisher approach this and then I
found out like a week later
something else happened you don't even
need to compromising this in package we
can also do is just apply simple social
engine against developers and publish a
package we have very similar name to
legitimate ones so in this case someone
published a bunch of my packages I think
we underscore between two words instead
of - and so this package was doing
exactly what I was doing to scan your
environment and sending to his own
back-end of course the account got
banned straight away and to be fair the
attacker wasn't really subtle about what
he's trying to do so well the clues out
there and this and tensor wouldn't look
me further with NPM and there's other
scary stuff so it turns out when you can
actually run NPM install script and do
this so so I guess the in one sentence
that life is her and this and then with
NPM also found out that hey by ID for
when you stole a package that this
little kerosene and what it means is
that when you run NPM you store I want
to say your CI box is not gonna install
that specific version but it's gonna
install the most up-to-date version that
is compatible with the constraints that
you have
so in this case I can actually still
want version 1.1 point 0 even though in
my local development when I'm working on
my project I'm using version 1 locally
but when it's guest build is using the
latest comparable version which means in
between me downloading the package
locally and working and testing things
they're all working fine to eat getting
bill or my CI box
someone could have published and
compromised the package publish new
version and then what I actually end up
running in my production environment is
different to what I have locally and I
could be compromised without even
knowing what I said
so yes life is terrible before you
coolest developer and so it's take away
from that is you should definitely use
NPM string wrap which or if you're using
old version NPM just update to the
latest version so nowadays NPM by
default it has much more stricter
requirements and you can be you can ask
NPM to to use the specific version so
that when you have run npm install you
restore to that specific version as
opposed to the latest compatible version
and this of course this problem is not
specific to you know it or we love to
NPM I've worked with Java I work I work
in the JVM world of work in the Tor
network the same problem exists in all
those environments
in fact one of the nice things you have
in nodejs is that all the dependencies
are just text files out emulator you can
look at yourself so if you think
something dodgy is happening you can
look at the file yourself it really easy
to figure out what's going on we've
combined with a static languages like
Java Scala or C sharp or anything on
runs Internet is all you get it's binary
so now you take the extra effort to
decompile there to actually figure out
what the source code is actually doing
so the it takes more effort for you to
figure out what's going on inside those
dependencies so now imagine the
attackers when they gain to your
environment our first line of defense is
gone
that's Merri if you've got a V PC in
front of that what can we do so the next
part of that if out are the next one our
defense is our security list our IMS so
in this case we need to control who can
invoke our functions and all
more importantly what can our functions
asses so that's where the principle of
least privilege is your best friend and
one common mistakes are finding people
make in the 80s is that okay you've got
this salad where you got your
public-facing for your problem PPC and
you got your party PC and your internal
services they're only intended to be
caught by your own services in the
public facing layer and you have some
BBC peering maybe and then you assume
that okay because nothing else can call
these guys so we are safe we just need
to put our protection around here inform
the public be PC so anywhere here is the
fully trusted this is it is this is the
holy grail so as long as the attacker
can gain here taking assets whatever we
have on the other side as well so again
if you're not careful if some amount
gains through an injection attack course
to one of your dependencies then all
these networking protection you think
you have means nothing and of course one
thing we've seen more and more now is
attacker stealing your 8 verse
credentials because you don't care about
a private data you have what I care
about is getting some easy to time to do
some Bitcoin mining and make some money
that way
and of course if not careful you're
gonna wake up next morning I find a
massive a diverse bill in your account
which when I search for those similar
also similar outages those similar
incidents are found so many of them and
in fact even in my small social circle I
know of two large companies that has had
this happened to them whereby the
account score compromised and attackers
used to rack up over a hundred thousand
dollars worth of interest bill within a
very short space of time of course in
that case is their big customers to 80s
and 80s agree to cover the cost but you
had to be very lucky and also you just
don't want to be in that situation in
the first place
and we've lambda functions even though
everything is public all the time but
you can re you can control who can who
can invoke the function through I am so
that's great so on the front we don't
need to have other networking layers in
front of that just to be sure that no
one can get in but as we mentioned
people can gain from a starbase through
your dependencies through somehow
assessing or compromising dependencies
use or dependencies of your dependencies
and they can steal the information
formed through that those dependencies
as I show you earlier so what can we do
one of the guys starts in the server a
security space pure sac they publish a
free library that's important interested
in toast by this really handsome man we
should know him and we're part this free
library you can down you can download
for free and use in your packages that
disables outbound internet connectivity
by default so your function can still
talk to a tree services but you can't
talk to say arbitrary endpoint that the
attacker set up and also it is able with
other things like the ability to create
the chart processes as well as the
ability to read and write to the temp
folder which is not something that you
need to do most of the time anyway and
all these options are configurable and
one of things I've been doing in our as
well is wrapping the configuration and
for pure for this life for function
shield into a middleware so there are
contain distribute them a lot easier to
the rest of my team so that they can
very easily use
incorporate this as as a default
template for all the functions that
working on so with this very simple
thing I can then stop any unintended
outbound Internet connectivity outbound
connectivity from my functions and then
the reason why if I don't want to use
PPC with lambda at least right now is
that when your your lambda function
ultimately still runs on some form
containers so when the new instance of
that functions runs you have to go
through this whole push up process
including creating en eyes for your V PC
and that process itself can easily add
10 seconds your costar time this depends
on a number of vectors number factors
including how much memory you give you a
function because the more memory keeps
your function also means the more CPU
cycles that is going to get as well so
it does help but then still V PC alone
you can add easy anything between Street
is 10 seconds for my experience and as
you mentioned even if you have EPC
boundary
it still doesn't it's still not it still
means that anyone the compromise your
functions somehow can see us as anything
else
that your function is able to so one of
the other things that we should
do is implement authentication but for
internal services so that when your say
user facing API to talk to some internal
service that's only intended to be
called by those user facing API is then
make sure you also have authentication
setup in that communication as well and
when you're building api's with api
gateway and lambda you can do this
really easily api k way even though it's
always public of course you can now also
put them into VPC as well but it takes a
lot of effort and it's not something
that I tend to do normally and you can
also implement your authentication
authorization and authentication number
different mechanisms for user facing API
so I tend to use something like kognito
or using custom functions that integrate
with other providers like of zero but
for internal API that tend to use I am
so that anything that needs to talk to
this API can I can control the access to
Amazon's I am mechanism easily and if
you are even building my API is with API
gabion lambda using the service
framework I can enable the authorization
which is one line of code in my service
Toriyama spec and then the fin ecology
is make sure that you really minimize
the amount of assets that your function
has and this is where but you really
want to have one one I am roper function
and tailor that policy for that function
to just that what their function needs
and fortunately again some girls or guys
work in the service security space
publishing in the free library that you
can use in this case it allows me to to
use the service framework and specify an
IM role for each my functions in this
case if I call function that needs to
get some object from the particular tree
pocket and put the module into a
different folder in the same pocket then
I can provide I can specify very
specific permissions for that particular
function of course all of these require
developer educate this plane and is easy
to forget them so one of the things I've
been trying to do in my current
workplace is that was trying to build
tools to make those Tomatoes adoption
easier and you can do the right thing by
default and some of the vendors in the
service here in space like
I've mentioned them already but then
there's also a few other guys like with
tech go there also peeling commercial
tools there also does things like
looking at skinning your code to see how
you use in the 80s DK to talk to a
diverse services and then compare that
with the permissions that you actually
given your function to see whether or
not your functions are over permissions
in this case you can really find out
that hey that function has got
permission to talk to Talam and DB even
though in the code doesn't actually talk
to them DBA oh so I should remove that
permission and the earth they also tend
to do active protection so scanning the
invocation event for your function
so even event coming in from API
gateways your lambda and it looks like
someone's trying to run a secret Russian
attack then they get put a stop to the
invocation right away and then there's
also other companies like our seed and
cloud zero that focus more on the serve
with the pretty side of things from a
high level and one of the things you
also find with lambda is that you tend
to write them in a stateless fashion for
one thing you have no good you have you
never much control over how many
functions are running at a time and also
how long that function lives on for so
you want to typically write your
function in a completely stateless way
and then you end up using a lot of
different they manage the services to
manage the state that you have in your
vacation including all kind of different
databases as well as s3 and so on and so
forth and you also want to make sure
that at any sensitive data that you have
no data by your customers they need to
be secure encrypted at rest as well as
in transit and of course with AWS you
get a lot of goodness out of the box so
many of their services provide service
are encryption and but you do this you
need to use it enable them yourself
for example s3 supposed to manage
encryption you view kms so there's some
some some types of databases in RDS and
the more recently Kinesis has also
supports and Dunham's DBS one as well
now supports a service our encryption
out of the box
so again important remember with lambda
is one of the most important thing you
can do from a security perspective is to
make sure that you apply the you
restrict what the function can do and
also peep
often talk about okay when you function
no longer need it you should delete them
because anything that hangs around your
environment is still attack surface the
sermon can explore can exploit and that
is why she one of the best practice one
of the advices from the best practice
guy from the lambda documentation but
what I found instead we especially of
lambda is this a lot easier said than
done so if you work in large companies
chances are there's going to be so many
different services scattered all over
the place and it's often not easy to
identify owners for those components
especially as people move around the
organization or they leave the company
all together imagine you taking those
service components now breaking it up
into even more smaller units of
deployments individual lambda functions
so if you don't have a few ways to
organize them in some way and to find
out what functions are in your account
and who are the owners which you can do
through simple tagging it's a very
simple technique to do that then chances
are is really hard for you try to
understand whether or not some function
is actually being used he said you see
not being used because it's only used
for some failure cases that we just
haven't seen yet what if is to do so the
server recovers disaster recovery now we
delete the function what happens when we
do have a disaster so identifying those
ownership so any video functions becomes
it becomes a challenge especially for
large organizations and we all sort of
think about now service attacks still
even though with lambda is super
scalable I've heard a few times where
someone being attacked someone has was
the victim of it in our service attack
but hey lambda just scared the order way
to thousands of concurrent executions so
the immense gets through it the proof
falls through the whole thing a third
attack but ended up costing the cost
them a lot of money and all the level
executions are not free if a using API
gateway to exposure level functions if a
cable service also not free in fact is
quite expensive by comparison to lambda
so it kind of I guess you kind of go
back to the world of okay I can have to
choose gonna become unavailable to some
our customers when someone attacks me or
have to brace the impact on my wallets
so Amazon does have a double shield
service but it doesn't protect you from
your api's directly
could have your API gateway nowadays you
can use the regional custom domain name
so that you can have your own
transmission wishes now means that you
can use Amazon's the web service which
you can configure some of the rules
around identifying spammy IP addresses
and then block them so when it's just
know when the one attacks coming from a
single IP are just great when it's
coming from a really distributed set of
IP addresses I don't know how much does
actually help you
it was you advanced also if you pay a
monthly fee it gives you some payments
protection against Terminal Services
that you incur when you're being
attacked right now this is support
doesn't cover the cost for lamda and a
few other services and also with lambda
you can think about when you have a
Singh event sources because they've got
retry out of the box
so if someone is mismanaged she executes
an attack against you that there's
somehow triggers of all these retards in
the background as well then you kind of
become a double whammy on top of that in
our service type they are executing
already and you end up just end up
costing you a lot of money as well so
even with surveillance order scalability
you get orders in the cost per
invocation nicer pricing you get you see
how to think about what happens when
someone does attack you and we server we
all know that at some point our servers
gonna be infected by viruses or the
place oh no server knows great news so
one a nice benefit do you have with
service is that you don't worry about
having servers that live for very long
time however your lambda functions
themselves are still reduced the
containers underneath your lambda
function they are reused for performance
reasons so every function also has got
access to a temp folder and you
definitely definitely avoid putting any
sensitive data in that temp folder
because that gets that gets
persisted between containing vocation
well while the containers is its life
so anyone managed to execute an
interesting attack against you they can
also grab whatever from the temp folder
just as easy they can they can scan it
was in your environment
so that's where libraries are function
shield becomes also used for as well so
that it automatically by default you
disable the use of a temp folder
altogether
yep function shoot there I can check it
out another thing I find we've love the
tradition web frameworks is that it's
easy to just leave directory in a
directory browsing option on and then we
found oh okay we can actually search go
go and find the people's find all kind
of wonderful things like I was it when I
search for a secret database credentials
app config and so on app config with
credentials for the sequel databases in
plain text all of that happens because
someone says dentally left the directory
listing option on when they're
developing the web application and again
is simple thing to smoothing to fix but
when you're not have we're not thinking
about it is those kind of mistakes in
creeping and I also found the cases
where you can actually search and find
someone's secret dump right there in the
in the blue folder so now that you don't
have web frameworks it does that for you
after the box
it becomes directed listing becomes a
feature that you have implement yourself
so chances are once you're to think
about it you actually need is you're
probably not going to do it so I found
we've landed at least I've never had to
do anything along the lines of
implementing Authority listing myself so
I have noticed therefore have no chance
of acidentally just exposing directory
that contains important information that
I have my function even though I still
have to concern myself with okay making
sure that I don't know when someone does
manage to get into my function they
don't they can leak information from my
function including that I should code
for my function as well and the last one
atashi on just one time is Bitcoin
Bitcoin mining I mentioned already now
you gotta be really careful and guarding
your 80s credentials this I think a
couple of examples here whereby someone
just accidentally put database
credentials into public repo even for a
few minutes and then they they found it
okay even though they changed it push a
new commit because all those coming
histories are there forever so attackers
can still scan them if I know for a fact
that a depressed activist scans all
public in up repos and they email you or
they can touch you somehow when
see there are active advocate NGOs in
public repos in plain text but they're
not the only ones doing they're not the
only ones looking and in this prevent
this particular article the the person
left the ad was credential in plain text
in the probably Papa assitant for about
five minutes and even though he fixed it
right away
the attackers demand get that in time
and get the kiosk with a diverse
accounts so one of the things you could
do when I was trying to find when I was
searching for solutions is that you can
hook into the gate you can hook into get
pre-commit and run some script to check
to scan your to to scan your scan your
code and see that we you're not putting
any 80's credentials in there by mistake
and also with a the best you can set up
you can set up monitoring so that if you
know you only run infrastructure in say
in the in Ireland so you want you can
want to put alarms around any Easter
activities in regions that you're not
using from what some of the Idris guys
help me I think Sao Paulo and Tokyo are
the hotbed for attackers launching is
two instances the Bitcoin mining because
those are regions that not many people
use so one of the things you could do in
this case as well so I can set up a lamp
billing in regions that you know you're
not using along as well as other alarms
that you have for those regions and
finally you want to apply poke heads
which is pattern for compartmentalizing
leaks and it's also a pattern that's
been made popular by the release a book
by Michael Nygaard
so in this case you want to make sure
that your functions has got the least
amount of privilege possible and also
anslee them by per function so that each
functions got its own policies and also
you want to use separate accounts
personally I like to have one a diverse
account per team so that the team can
own everything they have in their
environments in terms of people to be in
control of their own infrastructure but
also it means that if one Inc account
gets compromised
not the attackers can only do Kok only
can only access at worst whatever's in
that particular account as opposed to
everything they have in the entire
organization so quick recap
application dependencies it's a much
bigger attack surface and you don't need
probably realized and most of times just
as relevant as before and we need to
sanitize our inputs from our functions
as well as the output and we want to
apply the principle of least privilege
to how we permission our functions then
we want to use one I am role function
and in with make sure that any data that
we're using with for many services they
are encrypted at rest as well as in
transit and when you know a function is
not definitely not being used anymore
because you're the author you delete
that function right away and to now
service still still finger still back to
that we consider and even though there
is a double shield right now she'll be
able sure balance doesn't cover the cost
for lambda just yet and the servers it
can be infested so no server means that
we don't have to worry about having
having lonely if the compromised service
in our environment but we still gotta
Karla our eatables credentials will arc
here so that we don't end up being
victim for some Bitcoin miner somewhere
and finally put account use use account
level
isolation in your organization and
remember that people know people you
still the weakest link in your entire
security chain so with that thank you
very much guys for listening
we've got like three minutes for
questions but I'm gonna be around later
for doing a break and lunch time so
you've got any questions that come up I
mean the holes I guess there any
questions I guess that was all clear
okay cool all right let's go to break
and see ya