okay hi i'm funsized and i'm davey
and i want to welcome you to shellcon
2020.
we'll pause for applause cheering
it's been a challenging year but we're
glad that you're here with us
we couldn't have done this without the
amazing community that we've built up
over the last four years
here's a quick orientation on the events
that we have going on this year
our main hangouts area is going to be in
the discord so make sure that you follow
the link and get in
this is also where you can ask questions
of the staff and volunteers
there's a link to the discord on the
main website as well as a link to the
code of conduct
we have two tracks of talks this year
you're currently watching the main
channel with our technical talks
but we also have a raising track for
career development and hiring managers
comments are disabled on the streams so
if you want to ask a speaker a question
about the talk
feel free to use the correct talk
discussions channels to get your
question in the queue
there's a simple hashtag system that
will be announced in the channel
used for alerting the moderators to your
question
we have villages for soldering lock
picking and shenanigans
these are all going to be conducted in
discord with village presenters
streaming in discord and showing off
some cool knowledge
our ctf is once again being hosted by
reverse shell corporation
thank you guys along with being
sponsored by edge scan and sky safe
you can find more information on signing
up in the ctf channels on discord
teams are limited to a maximum of five
people
if you're looking for career advice or a
hiring manager looking for tips
check out our resume channels to talk to
a consultant several of our sponsors are
also hiring so check out the child rooms
along with the job board on our website
once the main content is finished for
the day we have an amazing contingent of
djs
who are lined up for your auditory
enjoyment you can find the schedule at
shellcon dot io
events
we also just want to say thank you to
all of our amazing sponsors we couldn't
do this without you
this year our sponsors are edge scan
twitter
verizon digital media services the
paranoids
sky safe areas security re-security and
synopsis
thank you so much for tuning in to the
first day of shoalcon 2020 we really
hope that you enjoy what we have lined
up for you today and tomorrow
see you around