[Applause]
so this is amazing there's the first
time that happens you got the power
right yes I have the power I should like
to thank first of all the organizing
committee for their kind of invitation
for trusting us with this presentation I
should like you to give an applause to
all those people who are working here
for you you don't didn't even picture
how many people are out there making
sure that everything goes right so an
applause for the whole organization
thank you for making it possible thank
you all for making it possible and we're
here well I've been told give a
presentation for those people who are
not of a technical improve fine and so
yesterday and today we've heard highly
technical presentations I'm a criminal
lawyer and expert inside room and
security I'm a bit more close to Earth
but I get the support of technicians all
the time so I'll try to explain a client
some problems I often come across so
that everyone can understand this so we
are ready now so two slides ahead of
yourself now you go first okay so who
are you I'm Jose Oh Delia Garcia I'm a
computer auditor and I help Ruth in
those messes she gets me into him I'm an
IT scientists especially I work on
computer forensics and you've heard
about the hacking and computing but I'm
much more on to auditing finding out
what happens after someone has broken
into something and once I find it out I
give it to Ruth and Red Cross against
them that's what I do I'm a criminal law
a lot of you as i said i work on what we
love years we've been through
trained to play the game on the side
whose pain as so whether they're good
people or villains that's up to the
judge and so we have the skills to
defend in the misunderstood haka that
could be a cracker more than a hug
vulnera din some limits or boundaries or
defending the company the person who's
been a victim of attacks on the
reputation financial information data
etc so i would also like tooth to say
hello to those who are on stream and
specially Yolanda girl because she's
great with it would what he does at a
palabra de hacker and these nose goes to
mera peak because yesterday I saw this
twit and I saw the clip worthy say
colleagues from I let me go to where I
have so much fun whilst watching their
their TV show and they would say I'm a
haka and sauron who was huge yesterday
said you know I get so bored hacker and
explaining that we had no criminal we
are not criminals and so when you see
the clip where you say that we are
hacking the Pentagon so funny yeah it's
funny and it is not because if you think
of yourself as a hacker as a researcher
that's not that this cruise they
understand being naughty pushing the
limits all the way to crime so that's
kind of a reflection i would like to
share they say we get bored having to
explain over and over this is planation
at but its necessary we are no criminals
or a hacker is no criminal is just a
researcher with curiosity what's the
greatest engine for learning that's good
real surname what happens with curiosity
is that often it takes us to places
that might be out of sight now at
Christmas I like to go to those houses
with the curtains open and drive on my
bike and say oh this is beautiful this
is nicely decorated or else what are
they doing in there having dinner or
maybe at summer ground floor and they
are out there in the scene cheese were
in a beginning and he's doing whatever
but do we go in or not we don't and 90s
system a computer system there is that
double layer as well I Drive around then
the door along the street and I see this
company and out of curiosity what do I
did the question is do I get in let's
see what's the settings for the website
let's see if I can have access let's see
if I can have access over there so the
door maybe open same as in summertime
and some people do actually go in and
even if you've just patrolled into a
company you are already in their
security system and what do I find what
do I find there are some anonymous calls
or twist on DM saying I got into X plays
I found X pains please report it to the
law enforcement officers but why should
I do it because I know nothing about
ones and zeros and you are protected my
vibe client professional privilege and
I'd rather you to it through through me
but there are other forms to let the
attack centers the attack warning
centers and now but if you're psychic
patrol in if you're sniffing around and
go in and intentionally and you made no
use of it so do not use a lawyer for
your communications will
warning many people do it they patrol
known in this room i'm sure that's what
i Coupe is taken out or patrolling and
they keep the vulnerabilities to
themselves so that they can exploit them
they can sell them out they tend to take
credentials they have access to
unlimited amounts of information they
bribe and blackmail business people and
they use it for industrial espionage as
well so please a hugger is no criminal I
need to have a t-shirt printed next time
they are researchers and i have to say i
have to say that i went i go to cops to
police academies because cyber patrol
name means that sometimes we might go
over the boundaries and we need to know
how to clean the information I found
this I have to take a step back and make
it look good so that's still there but
please mr. charge mrs. judge go there
and check it out my recommendation would
be I get so many reports to law
enforcement officers and entities and
companies and I thought how can i solve
it let's show what happiness what's
intruding into IT systems but in a
control Wayne it consented and agreed
upon together with the victim and with
hauser or earlier we came up with a
project as presentation so let's get a
virtual machine and let's challenge them
to get inside and see if you could get
the admin privileges for the website
they had to send us an email back no one
made it no one made it this was a
project that was ready for else come
encounter 2015 on four days before the
presentation i gave we gay
an open door so that they could break
into our virtual machine so let's
explain what ethical hacking means so
this is a company that is willing to
know where the black holes are and they
contact a professional there is a
contract stating clearly what is to be
done it is a controlled attack were
vulnerabilities of the system are to be
found and find out the ones that could
be exploited by third parties so you
need to be a cracker with permission no
risk should come to the system or
there's no compromise of the system so
if you like Hawking noon it to
compromise your company because they are
your client what are the minimum
conditions to experience around there
are students that are kids out there 11
12 years old mingling around that's the
time that's a time hmm you are here to
get the information hacking researching
that's good but under control you need
to have a hack in lab or have a virtual
machine up or a virtual environment app
which is now not real so what do we find
when we are asked to hard well we start
with at agreement there is consent and
the whole company need to burn it need
to be aware once we've got the outcomes
they results of how security if security
will be munda time from the next stop
this from officer saying okay lick ah
this is my plane ticket would you print
it for me in a minute and you're such a
holidays that these are receptions would
say yes perfect and there you've got the
virus in and it's so easy so is it to
get inside a company so what is in the
agreement agreement with a company that
is willing to have
system broken the bun during to how far
into someone's kitchen are you going in
you only have a limited time I will not
hurt them for two years what the terms
and conditions are very clear you should
never buy pants or skip even a comma
first because of traces because if you
go too far if you keep something for
yourself I might be the lawyer to that
company and then I asked us our lady out
early please come and do reverse
engineering here and forensic lab
reverse forensics let's pull the thread
and see how far we go and who we can
find there are methods based on the type
of work you will be conducting there's
one highly standardized o.o what I guess
you know it this is for software
vulnerability detection Oh SST mm that's
what was this for its information
systems right so different systems to
check different systems and then
wireless questions where vulnerabilities
are as part of these parameters on how
to hack them into something there is
kind of a science science and
methodology to check the security and
processes communications internet
wireless security and physical security
and safety at our company and here's my
guy so rude explain what was a bit more
theoretical legally why's everything
having to do with intrusion into our
company's security have you heard haha
cracker so how come you all know that
word right everyone knows what a hacker
is but maybe we do not all know what the
right definition for hacker is and so we
need to go to the Sun is Academy where
hacker is defined with a computer pirate
those of us who have gray hairs there's
this term cracka that's been on for
years now and this wasn't a security
expert Simone who had that curiosity not
limiting themselves to finding out where
fails and vulnerabilities were but they
were also crash in systems years ago
well years ago Vince ten years ago for
computer science and years ago crackers
would do it all for the glory and honor
and now they do it for money in exchange
for money as simple as that there are
some stages that are quite common common
for both disciplines crackers and
hackers so action steps first it's a
finding information on Google dogs so a
full enos in on Google you need to find
fans always aimed at an attack you have
social engineering then it's all done on
facebook maybe this is not that common
anymore because we got this digital
education now but we used to post I'm
living for supported I tomorrow and I'm
going off to buy a car at that social
engineering that people were using on us
against us and that's why most people
say don't post too much on the internet
a bit more senior tech would be port
scanning port 21 well I will explain it
in a minute ftp 22 port 80 for Internet
443 secure port looking for known
vulnerabilities worth mentioning wasp
and everything owasp and everything else
is some websites where they say what the
vulnerabilities of some environments are
probably most of you you know joomla or
wordpress what many websites are
produced and for those vulnerabilities
there are people people looking into
those vulnerabilities for those
massive information management
environments and let's say that it's
version 32 for joomla and they find this
a vulnerability for SQL attacks and then
everyone who has that version if it's
not properly secured we'll have that
very vulnerability so go picture how
many websites all over the world that
have all those vulnerabilities some of
which are very important sites network
monitoring man in the middle as it is
known if I can be in between the source
and the destination and sniff for the
information sniff out all the traffic
all the information on the network I
will get the user keys that's what we
always want the admin passwords the
network is a scanned and that's when the
attack starts we find specific
vulnerabilities and such as SQL
injections and as always the idea is to
increase privileged chance to go in with
a new user that has admin privileges or
make sure that the standard user through
a fail becomes on admin user to the
machine so it I own the machine then
access gathering attacks I tend to be
Bruce vote brute force so it's all about
finding password you probably know that
rotary passwords and we have frank with
us here who recently gave a wonderful
presentation on rudders and witnesses in
the british at home users that are one
two three four that's the username and
that's the password as well how many
people in the room please hands up your
Rooter that it's telephony girls or
whatever companies and it is set up just
as us as it was set up originally and
has not changed it hands up I guess many
more people in this room has not have
not changed it but don't want to raise
their hands these are the easiest to
hack into because they're even databases
with all the passwords to those
retainers and to this company
once we've got all that information what
do they do they they crashed the machine
they crack until they take over the
admin privileges and they can do either
two things they take control of the
machine to infect other machines many of
the websites we connect we lock into
could be totally legit and yet they've
been cracked they've had a card injected
a PHP side or yoona frame size it's a
small window and it's malicious code and
the minute I log into that website which
on paper should be fully legit as it
happens it will infect me my machine if
my computer is not protected I said
before or refer before to the cracker
stages and I said one of the things that
are necessary is the social engineering
which means finding out things about
their victim to attack on them I need to
know things about them preferences needs
to attack them on the WIC spot and and
this is a real case I wanted to share
here and it was sent to me I'm I'm no
haka I'm a forensic expert and I was
written to help someone so half into
someone else's account and this is so
useful chimelong saw you probably know
him so he's so used to getting this kind
of requests and here so
someone sends me lots of information
with the email accounts because what
they want is this one is a jealousy
attack and they want to have access to
the partners I can to find out what's
going on and this is so very illegal so
it's not just that go far they go
farther they say I've got the data I go
I got the pictures and still sends me
specific information about the other
person and this is one thing and here
here it is and they say if you if you
cannot do it doesn't matter doesn't
matter but I've given you all the
information so that you gather it for me
of course I paid no attention and paper
so stages for a hacker ice explain what
a crack-up does it would be a person boy
girl or company doing something just to
crush take down the website a hacker
would be similar to a cracker but as
Rufus it would said before there are two
ways to behave either out of curiosity
they are just looking into sides and
when they spot backs they call the
company and warms them there is this
mistake or this this back the company
end reply could hire them to solve vid
back or just sue them because they got
in without permission and that's the
crime difference main difference between
hacker and cracker is that hugger breaks
nothing damn thats that spire amount
then we can consider whether it's legal
or not that's up to Ruth so a haka is
it's not a computer pirate right that is
something that we need to dwell on and
explain to other people let's see what
all the time
of ethical hacking so that hugging
that's been consented to to which that
companies have given the permission we
have white gray and black do you know
which each one is means if you don't
know it and let me explain it a white
hat hacker uses el every knowledge in an
ethical way never going beyond what
they've been requested never be on that
a gray hat hacker they have knowledge
they would never break anything down but
they become judges oh we get no names
but if there is an association attacking
on or brutalizing animals there's this
group of hot girls saying I'm taking
down your website the way across in a
boulder there they okay but do nothing
but they think for some reasons specific
reasons you should ask act no names all
the we all know who I referred to and
then black heart the ones that look what
they are crackers rap rather they used
to break things down for the glory for
their merit so you gain recognition
within the community the read virus red
coat virus and so it brought so much
fame to the other world and preach and
sentence as well but now they are just
plain cyber criminals they do it for
money most common intrusion types social
engineering increasing privileges
vulnerabilities exploit or we are
running so late right no we are doing
right on time we also have a reverse
engineering brute forcing reverse
engineering means I have a nap and I'm
want you to attack on an app to take
down to the keys probably you know that
office can be a copied and you can have
pirate copies of windows 7 you change
the password this is
reverse engineering I would change the
app into source code I'll see what what
up the spot where the user passwords are
requested or where the app is moved on
and I bypass it where I built up a hole
up to bypass it that would be reverse
engineering we know types of Hawkins now
I'm based on that there are different
ways to behave we can have the white box
mm probably you've heard about that
that's when a haka a computer
professional knows how the app works
just perfectly fine and as they know how
it works they know what all the
parameters are we have great box that's
where that's when only part of the app
is known some things are known some
others aren't and then if you know
nothing about the application and you go
in blindly I just want to find bags to
see how far i get and i know nothing
about it that's black boss bucks Fred
printing do you know what it is without
reading it on the screen of course that
would be the first stirpes step towards
getting information out through open
source intelligence techniques finding
information on social media and the
internet getting all public information
and that's fully legal that can be done
no problem you can find information on
the network on the website sorry and you
go to who is it is fully legal and get
information on an IP address everything
else you can have dns cause you know
there's been quite an attack on DNS
addresses and they I think they crushed
a half Twitter and other accountants in
the u.s. you can have ports cannon with
and mop they look into every port until
they find vulnerabilities there and then
after all these work is done
what do we do we produce an audit report
a report that is this thick we take it
to the company and we say through oh
send techniques by putting your your
application into the gray box because I
don't know it all I we found these all
these bags all these solutions come
together as well come in on the report
and then the CEO sits with the pile of
documental says oh thank you very much
and we will do it sometime sometime in
the future what I like the most of
working as a researcher will as a
researching lawyer because law is
different now if the lawyers not just
behind the desk waiting for customers to
come in and trying to understand how it
all works now what we need to do is find
out how information can be sniffed out
of a wife a what operating systems had
what vulnerabilities in Hawaiian so the
lawyers roles changed in turn that means
that I am up there patrolling using
anonymous profiles because I don't want
to be identified it makes sense and so
that brought me to understanding what
the criminal is like so the criminology
offender what are they like and what
crooks are defined by is the need to
share that information that they've
broken into something they need to tell
it and you need to be patient but first
don't you think you won't be fine found
I know that someone will be kissing and
telling that's all about their ego it's
such a challenge breaking into things
that I there's an urge to share it and a
different fora you have just hints and
you just need to be patient and finding
it out what what can happen what could
happen to you
so according to law what can happen to
you intrusions out of curiosity if you
know there's a back there a hole there's
because you've been there and you
viewing their keep it to yourself or or
tell it to someone that will have no
problem sharing it I'll call them see
this article from the criminal code in
2015 it's that what security measures
when it was open doesn't matter it's a
place where you should not be going
engine and you've not been hired for
that you've been not authorized and get
you partied or made other people gives
access to other people other people say
well please go in for me or you hold it
against the owners will that's when you
add up months and years of a prison
centers if it's the first time around
maybe it is suspended so revealing
secrets so you found it maybe you got
information and maybe you've kept it
kept it for yourself or you might be
using technical tapping or machine to
machine man intimately techniques that
what you gather information you recorded
to broadcast it that is one to four
years at prison centers and find 12 24
24 months it's not just paying money
sometimes you get a fine sentence but if
you don't have the money but two days
that you do not pay you spend a night in
prison it makes no no fun it makes no no
it's not fun right maybe it is for you
so it's been 60 years right so articled
beers if you intercept non-public
information of transmission sorry often
of IT data so now we add up to eight
years because its two-year sentence this
article this is for you
it's everything that Ruth was saying
about how you could continue summing up
adding things this is a perfect attacked
cut it out through RP spoofing as it
says on the screen you can see there so
an IP address is being attacked this is
and local one and number of data is
being traded through the arts attacks
that is to say in this case email
account and the key so this is illegal I
cannot extract any a key if someone well
gives me the key password ok it's ok if
they give it to me so for instance now
we are dealing with a case handling a
case and social media so a person that
had the social media accounts hijacked
and we are working to recover that
social media will have the person's
passwords but we have the consent that
present agreement of the person to use
the password actually went to be honest
we don't read all that information that
it says there and this is the easiest
parts in terms of viewing so we have
this old exid XML and this is the part
that we are getting this is what we are
getting this time so if i'm not mistaken
this is a virtual machine disease well
we are working this is the email account
and this is where we are just getting on
when the data from that email account
and these that i'm showing you now is
what we said before about real attacks
the actually this is an actual attack it
is from the first of december this year
so that is to save a few days ago so
real IPS actual IPS that are being
attacking that are are attacking a
machine and because well i thought that
perhaps this was not enough and for you
to have a clear understanding as to how
it works i have machine open
well it is not easy to read but well at
least you can see you can see it's and
these are attacks that are being
committed today January sorry full of
December Sunday it's doing nothing this
is an IP address 163 finishing 160 where
this is a strange name for that IP it is
trying to access with a username 111
with the password sxx and notice what I
told you before this is a user password
so this shows here user 1234 password
probably they are looking for username
1234 I'm probably the password is also 1
2 3 4 it is very very important or when
you set up your email account you web
besides you name it never ever use
passwords as easy as these ones some
people go and say well mine is more
difficult like one two three four five
six seven okay don't do that please so
what we are seeing right now may be
temporary attack no it is not didn't
notice that all right so since yesterday
I've been seen these IPS which are often
the ones from which attacks are
committed so there is an IP that is
trying to access at any cost through
port 22 ftp port because service have a
minimum level of security whenever there
is some intrusion lat time so part of an
IP then d IP get the access denial
denied if these were not the case we
could
say that that company hasn't got enough
security implemented but now let's see
other types of attacks not only through
ftp so this is an attack to an email
server again we have a number of ips
trying to gain access to it to get to it
and Toli there are some list of some
servers that have a list of ips that are
on a blacklist that is to say they those
IPS are blocked by default many email
servers are recognized that or detected
ipes on a blacklist and for IPS
automatically stopped so expand how
servers do that stop those IPS that are
blacklisted and now I'd like to play a
clip I'm sure that you've seen the clip
before it's a video as to how to guess
when an IP address comes from so this is
solve their website such as who is so
with someone I texted you equipment if
you just enter the IP address IP address
that appears in the logs of any
management program that you may have in
place for email or ftp you can easily
get at that IP nearly all the attacks
fabricator and come from china from
russia countries with which we have no
agreements or where it's very difficult
to implement any kind of agreement so
therefore those IPS will be irreversibly
lost and actually will never get to the
perpetrator to the attacker because the
country will not with not disclose that
information to us and that's why so many
attacks are being contacted from china
because cooperation just
cooperation between China and our
country is just minimum cooperation and
now Ruth is all yours so we move on with
our rep easy recipe where were we ate we
had a toad ready discovery secrets
disclosure penalty from six months to
two years the company oh my god last
week I got a call I was called direct
and they said oh we saw you on this talk
so we'd like you to come over here and
then to frighten our 140 developers and
I said well if you want me to be there I
will be there why is that well if you
are an employee of your back for HP IBM
or small or medium-sized company you
have access to third-party data use an
ib employee oh you name it or any other
company you will be held accountable
legally however this would also impact
the company that you work for so
therefore do have two frightened
employees have to be frightened have to
be want hard to be trained and be very
well aware that the impact can also be
an impact on the company and then
companies will not be very happy about
it setting up a business takes a long
time and lots of effort so companies do
not really want to have these type of
employees so this is more of the same
okay so I skip that so damaged crime
causing damage on come to through third
parties once i'm in i steal data I
tampered with I encrypted I make data
unavailable so now sentence is from
three and two runs six months to three
yes then we would negotiate with the
public prosecutor it is the first time
that this crime has been committed if I
know something if I've reported to the
police or law enforcement no enforcement
agencies have specialists in technology
they are highly specialized they have
very good teams and what is the
investigation process like using
attacked to report the incident then to
get the help of the police and then you
gather the evidence once you have all
the evidence so they may decide to wait
what happens with that person how this
person is moving then we up until all
the evidences gathered put in packets
and package then reported to law
enforcement agencies when sometimes the
law enforcement agencies may come to
your company and for instance the
program fallibility volatility is just
to dump all that information to gather
evidence and then they also scan or go
after the IPS from which those
connections are not accepting carousels
if it is very severe the case is handled
from by the scientific beliefs or
forensic police and if and sometimes the
police take the equipment with them well
sometimes they want to work with the
Machine off on sometimes with the
machine on for a specific places i can't
remember Lauren for Martinez I don't
know whether you know him he is a he
works in four and six and then he said
okay send it out the mobile phone do not
switch it on charge the full battery
otherwise I would not be able to take
out all the information so therefore we
have to bear this in mind and then how
is the legal mechanism activated so
reports by legal representative for the
police department so I just did we are
not talking about a homicide we are not
talking crime scene so cyber crime is
alive what has happened just right now
if the event the attacker doesn't know
that you are there if you wait for Kimmy
do give him time the more silent the
victim the more mistakes the attacker
makes and the more evidence that I have
from the legal viewpoint the work that
we carry out all done is different we
just wait we continue scanning we
package it and we give ourselves
sometimes sometimes days sometimes weeks
sometimes months to fully understand
what is happening even someone playing
the network or perhaps in is not you but
someone who is following us home video
streaming someone goes in there by
accidental has discovered something well
here we don't have very many bounty bags
programs so as far as I know they are
not the popular oh they are not
available here in Spain we don't have
back panties but if you find something
if you find something that you want to
report contact certs we know nothing
about one and zeros we cannot disclose
the name of our company client we are
protected by professional secrecy or
privilege but thats above profession we
are like priests so before I came here I
thought about priests in the north of
his band Pope he says if God put this in
here that's for us to use it he's an
engineer he also takes per team
participates in hackathons and he's a
great professional so he gave me food
for thought okay what he said everything
is there to learn for me too
enjoy to share it but there is a limit
there is a limit to everything and I
believe that you can't report any
incidents to any of these parties if you
want to report it in an anonymous manner
okay you contact cert and then you
choose what you want to be on what size
you want to be if you want to be a good
one you really need to know what has
happened it is like when you are a
teenager you when you are a teenager do
tryouts and then when you grow up when
you get older you just make a choice
well and this is exactly the same thing
here I would like to personally thank
Frank I have to say this in public I
admire him he's a brain embodied in the
body he's so good that the kinds of the
White Rabbit have hired him for him to
write on the blog spot so if you have a
good eye size you may see the logo type
and also that of the hani khan that is
also very good I security company but
alehana those of you who want to know
more about this world of cyber security
and technology no look them up on the
Internet follow the white rabbit so do
will enter into a wonderful different
world and sheer leavin they will never
disappoint you and this is up from me
are there any questions any questions it
is time for questions trade-offs later
on outside or confession sorry
confessions later on questions
hello good afternoon already first of
all thank you to the two of you for your
presentation it has been really
interesting and especially Ruth she's
one of these wild crazy and lawyers that
goes into ones and zeros and one of
those as well therefore I believe that
as you told us penal code is complete it
is open so the only thing they need to
include is the keylogger for it to be
more comprehensive and but there is a
problem the problem that we face is that
there is a shortage of means is it
everything is included in the rules in
the standard however research is not
doesn't have the capacity to get to the
villains to get them to touch them yes
they cannot cope with it okay please
become a policeman become researchers
they have their hands full yes I can't
afford to have a client and for me to
file every perch you know I may be
handling a case for six months or seven
months we do 24 hours monitoring where
all the time kind of looking for
information traces we are just we want
the criminal to get anxious because the
victim is standing still is not doing
nothing I can offer to do it however
judges and other professionals cannot do
that because they are short-handed they
just don't have resources they don't
have capabilities please become
policemen become researchers we need you
and actually our legal system of a penal
system criminal system is quite
restrictive and safeguard safeguard
privacy to a large extent national
police forces of qualia Seville may ask
for a permission for search warrant 04
telephone tapping and then the judge
tells them right to have this amount of
time to do it these lengths of time to
do it and sometimes
just not have the material time to
gather all the evidence that they need
and other times whenever the case wants
to well reaches the national police
forces or our hands us as forensics
experts the evidence and x is volatile
it sometimes evidence disappears and
then having said that will have to say
that the evil always go ahead of a
bigger system and we are behind evil so
there are three elements three elements
and from my experience I said that these
three elements no matter how fast we
want to produce legislation to make
legislation and policies we have legal
system which saves called privacy a lot
then the evidence is volatile and then
the legal experts professionals are
short-handed and then well the criminal
prosecution system has improved a lot
has advanced a lot and likely continues
to safeguard the rights of the person no
matter how much of a criminal that
person is rights have safeguarded
hello to questions or to comments first
of all I has that in Germany scan import
is considered footprinting apparently as
far as i know it is illegal I don't know
whether you know it or not is it
consider fingerprinting here always it
for printing what happens here and
seconds sure to go in the US apparently
well it's not legal for judges to issue
a search warrant to research the
computer no matter what it is located
even if it is located on China in China
so does that mean that DNA is authorized
to do espionage but you know that
according to our clinical prosecution
though having a tool that would allow
you to do an entry intro intrusion Helen
minutes so having that tool makes it
already everyone doing makes it already
a criminal act hello belasco person who
is one known by many of us the the other
day he mentioned that having the mere
fact of owning those tools having those
tools is already crime and then as mine
you said how many people are engaged
into a criminal case for that or is
imprisoned because of that no one well
the provision is there because there is
no material way to channel all the types
of crimes but what I do is just I for
really roll and then I take it from
there and then I do whatever I want to
do and then when you may argue whether I
don't know with a kitchen knife okay
well if you stop someone with it okay
that's a criminal tool but if you use it
to cut food is not for something to
become a crime at the end of the day the
use of tool is what
makes it a crime or not a criminal Weber
not so from what the US what I like is
like okay so back at you so I'm going to
research the computer that you have in
Kansas as it careful take it easy so
they wouldn't like it with it so I leave
it there this is food for thought think
about it so the Americans also here I am
and give it all to me okay how well that
has to be the other way around and you
tell me whether you like it or not I'll
be done 50 seconds well a quick question
please quick question hello thank you
very much to the two of you for your
presentation so in is being ported
scanning to what extent is it legal well
and let's do don't break anything and
unless no one hears about it so don't
say it don't disclose it no well but I
didn't lower level what does the law
says well scanning a website I don't
think it is illegal if it is a router or
firewall telling me that that
information is there I'm not breaking
the firewall actually to access a
website you have to go through port 80
if it is a secure port and go three and
that Porto 443 that is open so it is
open you are not doing nothing wrong
that's my understanding yes that's my
understanding as well so call me call me
oh you sent out an anonymous treats me
all right thank you very much to you
suits being a pleasure being here oh
okay thank you for being here on the
Sunday morning
[Applause]