good morning everyone thank you for
getting up early someone told me that
going out in late on a Friday night
could be a bit dangerous so thank you
very much for your kind introduction I
cannot see anything on the screen I
don't know what it is my fault or not
so first of all I'd like to find out
from you if you are aware of dualistic
so only two people so would you please
dim the lights a bit because I feel like
if I was being questioned I cannot see
the audience okay so thank you now okay
so do you know why ipv4 is or not do you
know what I PV IP version 6 is do you
know if you have any machines on the
internet with an ipv6 machine oh sorry a
machine with an ipv6 address have you
ever taking a look at whether you're
happy v is 6sf active or not alright so
today we will be talking about Julie
stack and possible problems that may
come from having an ipv6 in all the
machines that are connected to the
Internet so my name is Patti Scialfa
shoes gomez Rodriguez everyone calls me
from and the takeaway message for my
presentation is that you have a better
understanding of ipv6 and also that you
are aware of the problems that you may
have in you Camille machines those
machines that have dual stack are more
specifically an active dual stack so I
think hopefully I will cover all these
contents in my presentation that will be
lasting for an hour so let us start this
is the address that we always have had
in our computers and I'm sure that you
have seen it you have set it up and
probably you have kept it in your memory
so the open space for an ipv6 is quite
limited as it has happens in the history
of the internet when when someone
decided about that we said well broadly
these will last for a long time
but dad has started to be a problem
started to be a problem some time ago so
nowadays we cannot access and not be v6
by asking the provider to if you do
provider doesn't let you do it doesn't
give you access to it and I think they
said okay if the IP address that we
don't have now because we because we are
working the power of tune let us use a
number of ips that in principle you
should take a long time before we need
more IPS therefore we have the number of
5p v 6 addresses that are available
according to the protocol I don't know
whether there are any mathematicians in
this room and if so I would appreciate
if the they could sell me that number
but anyway I tells you that it dad is a
big big number
have you ever done an EVE config
everyone has done that you didn't well I
would invite you to come over here to do
it because it is a great experience all
right now will call you to the stage
later on so this is an eve conch I don't
know what that you've seen it or not
this is a machine that i have connected
to the internet and there are two I
piece it has a dual stack it has the
protocol ipv4 and six you can reach you
can consume the services of that sever
by using any of the two protocols so
here you see the difference between the
representation of an ipv6 and the four
wonderful ones are four octaves and then
the v6 they are eight in X of X amount
so in the previous slide we see why they
use the Excel decimal and if the word to
represent that in exile decimal the
numbers will be to be can apparently it
seems to be a simpler representation
because it makes the makes it shorter so
here you can see that the real address
interval halving ipv4 we have one IP
budding ipv6 there is a range do you
know how to represent branches in a PVC
for well in say messing up ev6 with a
slash sewing ipv6 there are so many so
many IPS that when they are signing
allocating an IP they are assigning you
a range so dodge 64 is large consisting
of 64 has exactly the same number of
high piece and they are for you the
problem is that you have to manage your
IP is more devices more IPS more
responsibility so therefore this is a
tool a tool which is good fun because in
ipv6 calc it helps you get familiar with
it the idea is to minimize the number of
characters that you have to type in and
these
tool helps you compress the IP so we see
it compressed we see the full IP and it
is good for you to know the IPS judge
you are logging on to so so far so good
can you follow me well could you write
do you know how to write an ipv6 could
you'd remember one Travie not as you
know I don't know whether you have you
know whether home have an ipv6 or not
they only feel here in his pain well
some tests have it done in a spring in
2016 I've been lucky enough to
participate in those tests and I has a
choice the luck to have an ipv6 at home
next year that will become a reality and
we will have ipv6 at home in the
meantime if you want to do something
with it we can use tunnel broker channel
broker takes your I beautiful traffic to
a point and then from that point onward
your traffic becomes ipv6 it is a tube
tunnel it is a tunnel okay you start off
from ipv4 and then at the exit you are
ipv6 the limitation is that you can use
it for a test for testing but you cannot
really end up working with them because
they are often free of charge and well
it is good to play around with it too
and it helps you understand how a PVC
clear it's all about now it tells you
where we are in terms of deployment of
ipv6 so do you know can't you tell me
how much traffic on the Internet is
running on ipv6 any idea would you say
ninety percent five percent trust a
sense that's the answer well the google
says that so perhaps this is not true
well this is the graph plotted and by
google and the idea is for it
to see this trend there is a trend it
seems that he wants to boom to boost
itself but not before the providers can
make it could profit out of it we will
have ipv6 everywhere I very much like
this map I don't know whether you have
seen it before or not and here we can
clearly see where there is a higher
prevalence of ipv6 there is an adoption
rate on the US of sixteen percent in
Spain we are at point one percent to be
honest I just don't believe that I
believe that those data are made based
on the TLD of the website that we are
using bab Frogley I Peavy or the
hospital reducing is the one is one
located in Germany and there is one
country which I especially like which is
Zimbabwe Zimbabwe has fifty percent 50
times more ipv6 than Spain and these in
the past was very appealing to me and I
said why in Zimbabwe there is more ipv6
traffic than in Spain very easy answer
because ipv6 claim later on and they
cannot buy ipv4 in Zimbabwe they just
buy the small amount of happy before
then because there are no no ipv4 left
and then they have to go and buy ipv6
any questions and it out sofa now
questions okay we move on
alright so we'll continue because i will
be showing you some demos we got in
depth option of ipv6 there is lots of
controversy there so if you go to a
conference in Europe the people from
swisscom which is a small provider say
it tells you that next year they
forecasted that they will have that the
percent of the traffic in ipv6 and in
2025 and sixty percent one hundred
percent of the traffic would be ipv6 I
believe that did is smokin it is not as
easy as that you may first your users to
use a BB app ev6 but you will need to
help them out when i told you that next
year we will have the chance to have a
greedy six at home I can't tell you
about my experience a day I had it on in
my home they connected me to the mobile
phone and I could see that the world he
had an ipv6 address can you tell me the
difference between ipv6 and four in the
range 194 I'm sure someone has the
answer well on ipv6 all the IP VIPs I
can be routed so all the IPS can be
reached from the internet so therefore
what is the problem the problem is that
when ipv6 is active at home anything
that you connect to your version by
default would be eligible to be routed
so that is to say if you don't take the
necessary measures or someone that's it
for you at a given point in time you
someone will reach your device a device
which is has been thought to be somehow
protected okay
I promise that I was here nine o'clock
yeah and I did some testing and it went
well oh I have all my demos there
hopefully it works
so this is the graph that I told you
before by swisscom and this is the
forecast their forecasts and there is
another program for ipv6 well before I
PVC we will be having the dual stack and
realistic is costly for companies that
provide a service on the internet
because you need to set up all machines
so that they support both nuts and ipv6
I always compare ipv4 we fossil fuels
ever since I was a small and I went to
school someone at the time was already
saying oil will be over class will be
over we'll have to do something we will
run out of oil and gas and then this
year well this week the OPEC has said
that they will not be instructing so
much oil because there is a surplus of
oil in the world so the first time that
I connected to the ipv6 I thought that I
was well I it was the first time the
first time I started I got a job they
started to talk about ip6 because I said
that I pee before was about to be
finished I don't know who is behind
different hubs in Mason so Illuminati I
just know well but in the meantime okay
in the meantime I've until I pee before
is finished okay we'll have the dual
stack dual stack means that from now on
many systems will have to I piece which
you will have to manage two different
ip's if you are not ready for ipv6
everything that you do on wrap it before
perhaps it is not useful at all because
you will have a way to access to your
system through ipv6 and now how many
ipv6 are available on the internet now
well Akamai will be providing ipv6 24
million devices on the network and these
are the steps that will make her ipv6 to
gain momentum and to
deployed on the internet there are very
many graphs or even Facebook runs
comparisons between how fast facebook
Michael on ipv6 vessels ipv4 well
Facebook is interested on that because
many years ago Facebook migrated all
systems to ipv6 they just want to stop
paying the hardware providers so that we
users can log onto the to Facebook in
countries where there are only ipv4
right now because we are in Lyon I
decided to bring this photograph with me
this is like beef jerk look typical from
here you know anyone from nail here well
imagine that you have a company of beef
jerk and everyone likes beef York and
then imagine that you have your business
is going very well you open up a website
you by hosting and then to make your
service is known and then there comes a
time one day and one day the another
person comes to you and says okay i want
to buy beef jerk and then they come here
to buy it and then you realize that your
markets on the Internet can be
significant and then you decide to set
up a website and then you have a small
market place but you can sell your
products over the Internet everything
goes well and in recent day that you
have very many orders and you need to
manage your stocks you also higher sales
person a person who is around promoting
your product etc and then there comes a
time that you decide to make an
investment on technology and then divide
a machine internet for your company do
you also have a company you have also
store a physical store and then as
well as an online mr. and then you set
up everything and then you set up the
Apache server who has started an Apache
server in the machines at least once ok
all of you do you know that the server
is status automatically in ipv6 as long
as ipv6 is available when you start the
Apache server automatically if ipv6
available it is a sad affair and you may
wonder why why does that happened
because ipv6 is not a reality jet a long
term or sometime long time ago
everything has been thought to run on
ipv6 the problem is us that we do not do
it like that when you call and dns then
it gives you a register on ipv6 and if
you don't understand it it gives it to
unite p before but by default it gives
you ipv6 and the same cultural services
by default they are started on ipv6 and
what will happen if i scan these machine
i will do a demo now to see what happens
in it port 80 if i do that how will see
it on both ipv4 and ipv6 and then you
will go and say well no problem well the
person working in that store here
selling the food is not a problem within
just two Darfur fiend will do the IP
tablet and then here that command says
do not let anyone to reach the port 80
imagine that you are very extreme do
don't want anyone to go there but that
means that we are going to our website
and we are filtering only in happy
before because I p tablet on the work
song ipv4 so therefore our system our
internet system would be available on
ipv6 we will need to use ipv6 table to
close to close the ipv6 and then you may
go and say well that only happens to
small stores selling beef jerky
he Leon well actually I don't know
whether you can sell and beef your
condoms and or not I hope so i think so
alright so now are you aware of Mensa
you know Mensa
alright so Disease Association of people
with high IQ son let me show you
something for you to know all right so
if you want to take the preliminary test
okay they charge you 10 euros to pay 10
euros for someone to tell you that you
are stupid well that's interesting okay
joking apart well this is what I got
what I found that we could having any
other website so all right I think
perhaps they should know more about ipv6
okay anyway they have a service it is
known as Philemon dot men sad eyes what
does that mean it means that they have
the internet service this is an
association and they are providing
services hands i guess that those
services have to be available to
everyone imagine that i asked that IP
for whatever reason i know that this is
a dns draw that provides a service to
Mensa and then I go and ask it okay tell
me everything that you know about Mensa
do you know what is a zone transfer of
DNS could anyone explain it to me okay
does you worry okay some transfer it
means asking a DNS ever do you know what
a dns server is a dns server makes it
possible to browse the web and then you
may ask the dns server to tell you
everything it knows about the area it
controls the mens are seven knows about
all the names of the machines that mensa
is using in the servers and then you can
ask it to tell you everything about that
four or five years ago it was very
difficult to do a post setting of the
mensa and sever therefore
can really easy to dump all the IPS and
internal domains and you cannot do that
anymore it doesn't let you do that
anymore they tell you that that is no
longer available and what happens if I
ask me ipv6 to do that for me it doesn't
give me that info it doesn't give me
that data because that server which is
older than as on the internet is one of
the pillars of the Internet therefore
therefore you will use all the available
RCC's when it says that ipv6 have to be
activated enabled so therefore this
comment here if I hold Mensa and we ask
filament men Sadat yes and then we say
hi X of our which is the command for the
sound reference ok here it is but is it
is returning all the open all the logs
all the register that I be induced on
the D&S so I said that they liked comic
strips because the one of the Nemesis
mortadella and philemon well these are
the things that happening so probably
they did not start the fire world
probably you may don't know that these
that is running on ipv6 Oh probably you
don't even know that the service has
been started or that it is badly set up
so well it seems that someone knows that
it knows about the back and settings so
it means that someone has been touching
the settings but not all the right
settings to fix it and because these
facilitation is about back doors and I
said ok let us now we want to find any
domain names with the name parking on it
and this is the 24 hour parking calm and
exactly the same thing happens with this
service but this Sammy seems as it issue
is firewall Apes you I just did an nmap
you know what an nmap is well only few
of you mmm i was expecting more hands up
if i do an em up on this domain name
and then I say port 587 and then I do
and map on the very same domain but on
ipv6 and simple hold on can you see that
I'm writing down the domain well the
action tool takes care of the resolution
so what we are seeing here is that the
port on ipv4 is centered someone has
started the fire wall so that no one can
access this service but I didn't do that
on ipv6 and here we have one more
variable which is the dual stack many
perimeter protection systems do not
support ipv6 so therefore you should
filter it from the origin you cannot
really do a bad setting and trust your
perimeter security measure ok and this
is what is happening here someone has
not set up the firewall well and let us
go beyond that imagine that we hold that
service we ask about that service do you
know what happens on your own port 63 79
do you know what ready sees you know
what a tale is only two of us that it
computer science all three well I time
is a tale but in computer engineering
okay you just set up something or you
leave something there for someone else
to use it for that is a server user and
then when we said in the past i said oh
i left the poor opens and then well you
may have a son vulnerability and some
someone may break into your system but
sometimes if you leave a door open of a
port that displays information that
expresses information well you may
have a problem there I don't know
whether you're aware of this tool aunt
Ella all until a tower only one of you
is aware of it well this is a tool
developed by a friend of mine and the
sukkah next to readies and ask for all
the available information at the point
since i'm all available information at
the tail well i'm glad that i have a
screenshot with me so that you can see
it
but you are seeing now is a life dump of
that tail often these type of readies
the problem is that some people are
using it to paste the cookies messages
among services that are managing users
so therefore the problem is that that
person has that system enabled on ipv6
but is not aware of it because it has
installed something by default it has
not set it up and probably stressing the
available firewall on the machine that
is using therefore and here we have all
these data and you could stop that if
you were to implement the same security
measure on both stacks and you think
that this is happening to people who are
setting up internet services and they
are learning from YouTube don't you
think that this doesn't happen to
everyone I'm not going to say out the
name of the company but it is a big
company there are many services that
many years ago where all the time being
discussed the insecurities conferences
because people used to leave them open
so one of them was telnet helen had a
huge repercussions especially for
internet providers because at the end of
the day big old bruisers those managing
lots of traffic were being managed on
well-managed chantal net and now we are
logging 27 has the tender closed and
open on ipv6 that's the banner
what is showing us his exposing a cisco
routed to the internet through port 23
which is kind of going back to nineteen
eighty nine I don't know whether
somebody here in 1989 locked down to the
Internet connected to the Internet well
that Rueter has that framework will have
to be very very careful because the
assistance even if they are all they
will be they will start themselves in
ipv6 because for a long time they've
been implementing ipv6 even if the
operating system is not available that
does not depend on them they just use it
and now this is a lack see sample mongo
DB after all the new internet service
run on ipv6 so these we are talking
about relatively new technologies
starting on ipv6 and what happens here
you have to be careful for instance in
this case this Mongol it has exactly the
same situation it has filtered the sea
to port on ipv4 but hasn't filter it on
ipv6 what does that mean it means that
the database the monk / database is
being exposed I don't know well do you
know what MongoDB is have you ever
connected to a MongoDB even if you don't
have credentials you can ask things it
is not as intuitive as telnet but you
can log onto it if you connect there if
you connect to it this script will
connect to Mongo will ask for
information of the service first we'll
do that online pv6 and then on ipv6 here
this is what it returns some ipv6 and
then he lives has all the information of
MongoDB which is running on that ipv you
understand the planning of that okay
good
do you understand that these two don't
do at home what are we are not doing
anything i'm just asking i don't know
whether it is my mashing or not but it
would happen so I don't make any
mistakes when logging on to it so this
is nice this is a client right this one
is in Germany naturally because if it's
your a bits Germany that the way it is
and what we have here is a static IP
someone is buying an static IP for a
server they are setting up in their own
machines probably for their own company
and still don't know that it's running
on ipv6 because it's left centered or
focused on ipv4 if it were closed it
would be different problem but when
filtered it means that they don't know
that it is on ipv6 problem is that if
you have an ideas you don't even see it
and probably when you go for a forensic
analyze you say who stole it all from me
and you don't even realize that they've
been using a different protocol and you
don't know how your information is
Benedict's filter good so let's move on
to our next level
differences between scanning ipv4 or
ipv6 any one time it is time so if you
remember we had a ipv4 range for all the
ipv4 and all the ipv6 that were
available if we go back to that slide
difference is quite impressive right so
you might have used some of these tools
for ipv4 Soudan census does it that dude
a ring a bell see them or anyone see the
map sorry anyone maybe players so these
tools are focusing on ipv4 I don't know
if you knew but see the map is a project
that has a large simply for anyone to
scan to sweep the whole port that can be
inverted in just 5 minutes and that's
what they say it depends on the version
you have and so now one day one week
that's what it takes you to scan the
whole ipv4 you can ask every machine on
the internet and see what ports are open
what services aren't running if we were
to do it on ipv6 that would not be
possible and that's the problem if we
cannot find out ipv6 then that means we
are a bit more safer right if they
cannot find you they cannot touch you so
that leave that even CEOs as security
companies have its burgers because
sooner or later your IP will be exposed
on the internet for someone to see
because it is is the final purpose of an
IP have someone connected to your
machine whether it's you or not problem
here well right now it's so so very
difficult to find ipv6 addresses or a
scan the whole ipv6 range so for someone
to say let's connect to the IPS that
have been deployed in Zimbabwe
by whatever operator that's quite quite
complicated as a matter of fact on ipv6
the scanning tools do not support a
range not even a small range because the
smallest range in ipv6 with this gas
debt is ipv4 so it's a very complicated
right now to have a simple
implementation to scan ipv6 ranges
actually many people complain that tools
machines for pen testing you need to
type the addresses yourself because
there's no been an easy finding again
this our IP addresses on the internet
for local networks there are the
mechanisms we have the neighbor finding
tool that is similar to to that and for
ipv4 and just to close it up let me
refer to mr. Luca look Wow so he looks
like the spanish dr. Santiago Segura you
know this is the face that comes to mind
when you think of him and mr. Luca well
it is a project that I've created with a
colleague that should have been here but
it couldn't make it and we are trying to
have that ipv6 map that is not existent
now for some time now that we've been
tired of watching Google stats and other
entities that start saying ipv6 that
it's available what's not and we said it
is pointless let's ask an all ip's and
see what the reality of ipv6 deployment
is mr. lucre it is very user-friendly
Soudan style we will compare results
with Soudan in a minute well only thing
you need to do is lock in it is free of
charge here it is
and if you can certify your researcher
and send an email saying that what
you're going to do is just for
themselves and there is no
responsibility yeah we have no
responsibility and will not be held
accountable for what they do they will
have more privileges the idea is to
conduct a few operations from here is
where I got the examples that I've shown
you here they are so this is talent
surface what is the main this is Mongo
so maybe and you come up with a search
you are you interested in anything you
would like to know anything that's
something such as all dot as domains
rain so digital series of sides with
services running on domains that are
dark ass does not mean that IPS are
located in Spain it means the domain
associated to it it's a dot SS men that
it's latching the Spain and I say it out
of experience because most of these
sites are locked or hosted it in island
or Germany where the ipv6 services are
widespread but you may say well someone
needs to have sites here in Spain yes
there are few services that are here in
Spain it you all see them into leather
because a geolocation it's our book for
ipv6 and so it's not as accurate as a
when compared to ipv4 we can have
searches that can be as complex as we
want them to be but we are trying to map
the whole ipv6 network in the most
practical way possible because we do not
have the resources to map it all and
even if we had the route it would take a
silver lung
still it is very interesting to see how
internet services are evolving and we
will post it on our blog and how there
were many services that were available
and LEDs year and now they are filtered
so there are people who are working now
hot and they are focusing on making sure
that ipv6 is secularized no no search
that you're interested in no enemies
you've got very complicated we're just
using it okay tweet it to me or
something right so spell it good at Bell
dot do B dot V in this won't be there
this is a Venezuelan telecommunication
regulating system maybe this was not
been scanned well let's hope the jump
banners from the country there you have
it we risk and we would like I hope
nothing comes to us so yes services are
active and they know services are active
because they've been said I understand
so you can run different tests
everything that it's done on mr. Locher
is not intrusive it's just are sold in
so this is a link we're we can compare
it to Soudan to see if it has ipv4 and
what's the difference between both here
soudan has not scanned it I don't know
if it's out of fear we can try it if you
wish
it is open both services are open are
there any questions examples any ports
that you're interested in your friend
from back there i don't think i will
hear you question is how long has IP
visits being implemented for how long I
don't know how old your but maybe you
weren't born nothing so very long
actually let me go back to my
presentation because this is a link for
our FC I don't know if you know what it
is that's where the Internet Protocol
definitions are written think there was
one here this one here RCC this will
discusses where the broker tunnel this
is from 2001 and this is a ton of broken
there might be a ipv6 stuff written
before 2000 good thank you anyone else
and then just to finish I have any
version so go for questions now that you
say domains but what's safer dot s or
com what's more secure I have no clue
about computers with a dot-com domain
you will pay less that's all but what
about email i have two hotmail accounts
that comment that s but does matter
domain it's a series of characters
written into a dns so that when you ask
you get an IP response it is an ID don't
ask calm it's kind of to build up
sectors in on the internet that is is a
spain harm is world level but do not
think that a domain would be safer than
than the other the only thing the bunch
of security would be the protocol you
use since you get connected to log on
domain is just the means to get there so
very interesting what kind of protocols
do you implement to look for IPS
protocol means given algorithm right I
cannot tell you sorry not been published
yet so what I can say is a super
distributed system is fully distributed
same us with sidim set map that just all
on your machine and you can do it from
home this one is much more complicated
and let me tell you why because not
every thing's been rooted on ipv6 it's
not just humming ipv6 but everything has
to be rigid are not all routes have been
tracked the way we would like them to
but we will release the weight we do it
because we are discussing it with
different people to see how to improve
it and how to build a community to
reach out a large enough number of ips
IP addresses to understand that we have
a reasonable knowledge of what's out
there on the internet thank you very
much good morning I have a question for
this search and mr. Locke where I think
you said MDEs which is Ministry of
Defence Nana that's a mistake that's for
sure education that stands for education
not defense in close friends just
actually whoa we need to talk to them so
they are releasing the DNA sir a version
so no it's not no problem no problem is
just 19 it could happen to anyone let me
show you so
you asked about something else Oh
non-extradition countries what nowadays
who does have active ipv6 that can be
writable as you say it's not the whole
internet that anyone can communicate
with anyone so ipv6 access in Spain
that's not much right here so who does
have add vegetable ipv6 that can be
routed from other neighbors AT&T and any
other large American companies have
already implemented it then well
Deutsche Telekom as well so all large
operators on the internet operating in
North America and no the bureau they
work on ipv6 and it's been implemented
and they offer it to their users but
careful because many users ask for it
have you called your operator and ask do
you have ipv6 I advise you to do it so I
understand that even if Deutsche Telekom
has ipv6 and it's on the u.s. cannot
reach is not bridgit yes that one would
be rated what I mean is it might not be
routed if it comes from our server gone
from I from a survey on to Germany on
ipv6 that's what I meant so there might
not be so many people paying attention
making sure that all routes are always
up to date ipv6 is still changing and so
for ipv4 everyone is paying close
attention to the routes that are
available to connect one to the next the
minute something fails everyone realizes
but for ipv6 it takes longer for people
to realize it because they're not so
many people who are surfing or browsing
through native ipv6 thank you
so 37 seconds left there is a time of
air this is example for the new version
this is dual stack and our new version
is focusing on dual stop this is a graph
where you see ipv4 the one that we found
sorry the ipv6 we found with ipv4 and
they are linked through their domain
right and what you can see here is the
difference between ipv4 and ipv6 what we
said before this is at port 23 that you
cannot find on ipv4 so just at a glance
we see what you saw before with enema em
up and everything else here it is all
represented okay just blinking now so
let me thank you for being here and I
hope you've understood something about
ipv6 and dual stock come to mr.
Lockridge calm lock in sign a block in
and anything missing there i will send I
will love to get an email from you thank
you very much
[Applause]