miyamura dias a todos good morning all
of you those of you who don't know me my
name is ricardo rodriguez i'm a PhD I
have a PhD of the Theravada University
and I do at research have many research
lines amongst others and malware
analysis today i will be sharing the
following with you i will be telling you
about a specific marwa the name of it is
post run scrapping malwa it will steal
credit cards from compromised computers
this is quite related to rubens
presentation I very much liked it like
that when introduced a number of
concepts so these would be the agenda
for my presentation I will tell you
about the problems what happens when we
take our credit cards and we pay at a
point of sale and also what I tell you
how you can access a credit card
information and what this mama is about
I researched I analyzed these 22 of
these malware families had tried to but
I studied the characteristics of it the
features of it and I classified them
then we'll move on to a demo and said
you about the tool demo of the tool we
I'll show you a real example then bit of
a related work and a few conclusions I'm
sure that you know that there is an
increasing number of data exfiltration
so here we may be referring to email so
accounts from different fora and then we
also have data exfiltration with regards
to payment and methods and means so this
is a photograph or an overview of all
these cases that are having on the FO
some time now so I'm sure that you also
know that nowadays credit cards that are
widely used I don't know whether you
know it or not but some countries are
even considering eliminating cash so
there is one country in the European
Union demak more specifically who is
trying to eliminate or not to use a cash
Singapore is also thinking about that so
we are at the time where it is more more
common and frequent for instance to buy
bread and pay with credit cards so
therefore we also seeing an increasing
number of attacks to financial entities
banks in an attempt to steal this
information which can be really juicy
and why is that sell well in the black
market information of a credit card it's
an element which is when traded it is
well paid so these are some data from
report and here we can see the US credit
card data the price of it may range
between 1.5 dollars of five dollars
fortunately if we buy a hundred cards
give us a discount if we are talking
about a you a credit card data these
information he is more expensive in
between five and eight dollars and if we
have extra information about the user
for instance I don't know social
security number date of birth that is to
say details that would help us complete
the fake identity the price goes up so
for instance if you have information I
don't know one of those high range
credit card such as platinum or gold d
that credit card data also increases its
price
so minimum data needed to complete the
payment cut her name expiry date and the
PA n that is to say the credit card
number some places on the internet these
two those three elements have enough to
pay soon for your passes well you may go
and tell me that there is a fourth piece
of information to use or to pay with
your credit cards that is the cvv
however there are other companies
especially US company where those three
pieces of information is enough to go
ahead with your credit card payments so
now we should wonder what are these data
coming from these data are what these
devices are more infected I'm sure that
you've seen a computer computer with a
card reader either embedded on the
screen or just as an external device
that is used to introduce the car and to
enter your PIN number this is the
information from 2014 report when it
says that thirty-six percent of publicly
known cyber attacks when they say
publicly known it means that they are
known thirty-six percent of them are
based on or related to stolen credit
cards customer data often most of them
take place at retailers or in larger
restaurants change and change of
restaurants and there is a reason for
all that that being that most of these
systems are running our run on Windows
any version of Windows
but it's happening here we are seeing a
change in the type of attacks that are
coverage out against a system in the
past we could see terminals and terminus
critical seminoles that often were
compromised I have a credit card reader
and then you could modify some elements
in set some elements so that by the time
the user introduces the credit card you
can read that credit card details and
transfer that information somewhere else
but let us say that that how were
tampering and is shifted to doing
something which is more common nowadays
that is to say network is sniffing if
you know that credit card information is
going through that Network you just go
there you sniff that just leave that
Network and then you find values values
associated with a credit card with the
credit card the best well-known case
took place in 2008 the company attacked
was a US company and group of hacker has
led by albert gonzalez living in miami
well found well they could see that the
restaurant was using a Wi-Fi network
with a web protection i'm sure that you
know the web Wi-Fi protection that
protection is highly vulnerable so these
group of people become compromised the
network from the restaurant then they
access to extended service of the
company some what they found in the
external service of the company the
company was the long list of Gorilla
Glass customer data what did they do
once they found those data they
exfiltrate data and then sold it
therefore it is estimated that they sold
40 million 14 million credit card
customer data so if we were to multiply
that by the one point five dollars that
we mentioned before you figure how much
money they made out
it Albert Kahn solid was found guilty
for these felonies and has been
sentenced to 20 years in prison so we
have shifted from having from doing
scheming terminals to now having a
specific malwa known as post lamp
scrapping because the main objective is
scrap strapping scrapping the memory
scraping the memory which is a terminal
or a device that is located in the point
of sale the objective is to find
patterns that much credit cards and once
they those patterns are found data is
expert rated as I said before this type
of threat this type of malware is the
greatest threat that these terminals are
facing nowadays we shifted from network
is nipping and now we are facing these
specific scraping man well what is a
little bit more about this in 2013
target target in the u.s. is kind of a
cover for large hypermarket a
hypermarket it was compromised by this
type of malware it was a belong to the
family of the black paws it is said it
is estimated that 14 million his records
of customers were stolen in three weeks
then in 2014 home depot's which is with
similar company to dodge it was
compromised by a variance of prior post
assembles the framework pause so they
said that the attack lasted for five
months we just don't know as a result of
the attack they installed 56 million
records so this study will tell us how
has been the evolution of this type of
malwa what is functionality like
how they persist and equipment so how do
they manage to remain in the machine
even if I restarted how do they process
such data and how the data is
exfiltrated first of all which is not
forget we should know what happens with
the our credit class information when I
pay when I pay when I have my credit
cards I pay at the point of sale and
then the information the credit card
data goes to the issuing bank of my card
or the bank to which the POS terminal is
connected to that van bank will
communicate with the owner of my card
but it is Amex Visa or MasterCard and
these companies will check with check on
the last bank that is to say my credit
cards and my account my bank accounts
they will check whether there is enough
money on my bank account to go ahead
with the payments especially if we are
talking about a debit credit card and
then that confirmation of okay or denied
intersection comes through here so
therefore well do we have the credit
card data but the credit card data will
be in four places in fornication first
of all it will be in the memory of the
equipment it may be temporarily stored
in any device so for instance at
motorways motorways
didn't happen to you Prince is going to
go somewhere then you had a motorway to
swipe your credit card and then you you
are not charged clear time the payment
doesn't take place real time as Robin
mentioned in the case of aircraft
because there is lots of traffic they
want to speed it up what they do is to
its store the information of all the
cars that I've gone through the tall and
then they just get all those data on
specific day and they transfer the data
to the bank et all those data or
together there are those who say that
for instance if your car kritika is
cancelled and nod hahas it's not expired
they said that day you could travel you
could travel on the motorways so I just
want to believe that the information of
my credit card when I go through that
all is stores in an encrypted manner and
in that place which is not easy to
access so it's not accessible to attack
us then my do my credit card data is
also in transit but fortunately we have
a payment standard payment card
industrial and that standard forces each
party's to use encrypted information
therefore even if my credit card data is
in transit it cannot be compromised and
then also does credit card data will be
present also in the actual application
the application running into the
point-of-sale systems so these are
places so this
different locations where my credit card
data could be compromised just let me
tell you that the man well that we will
be seen today we try to access
information right on these points you
will not mind accessing or get into
information in this other three place
location other 33 other locations so we
have to stand out as I say PC I payment
card industry data standard well there
are two sub standards the PCI DSS it
defines or it tells us how to protect
the information in transit data in
transit then we also have an elevation
they pa-dss that sells us these software
requirements that your system should
fulfill to comply with the prior
standard however none of the system
takes care how about what happens with
data in memory that's one of the main
problems of these standards and the
credit card data is in memory it's a
memory and that data is in clear so
therefore how to access credit card data
well you know that the first the way to
do it is to have the physical credit
card so physical data on the card name
expiration date in American formats us
format and then be a n primary account
number which is a credit card number
and then the cvv afternoon ranges from
three to four digits the annuities on
the back and he shows on the back of the
card why do buddy sit on the back panel
of the guard who has that answer but
basically cvd is what sales that you
have physical access to the credit card
if you take the credit cards and unless
you look at the back panel well this
means that means that you are having
physical access to the card because you
can take a look at the back panel then
other way to access to credit card data
is through the magnetic strip stripe
magnetic stripe there is an interesting
video made by Sammy Sammy was in cyber
camp last year he did they used to put
some as they don't add a stripe and they
could get access to that information to
that data so I'd like you to know that
there are three stripes okay or these
magnetic stripe is divided in three
bands each of these bands come with the
different formats so out of those three
bands only number one and two are just
bent number three was intended to be
used by some banks but in the end it's
useless has not been made under standard
only track band and track two are used
for information for you to know princess
if you have tragic bank account with
either kaha in track three you will see
that you have your bank account number
so track one track to these are the ones
we are interested in coming the specific
formats i'm not going to explain each of
them so not just so i can look at that
here we see the credit card
see but the bank account number and then
in track 2 we have the username and then
we also have the expiry date so there
were four decide the three minimum
elements that are needed to make a
payment so when you swipe the stripe
does well well they get but this minimum
information is already given to the
terminal not way to access to credit
card data I'm sure that you're aware of
these cars cheap cards they are also
referred to as chip and pin or e MV cars
they are widespread in Europe we use
them very very frequently when you pay
with your credit cards to introduce it
in the terminal then you have to enter
your PIN number and that pin number
authorizes alpha resists uniquely each
of these transactions uniquely
authorizes each transaction some people
are doing research on that and they have
proven that this is not true well the
latest fashions have a env has improved
that vulnerability but it isn't it
wasn't like that in the beginning so
basically e MV tries its intended i
authenticate the card as well as
authenticated the folder but in the case
of EMV no one authenticates the POS
terminal so you may be certain your cart
in terminal in a convenience store we
don't know who who is behind that
terminal we trust that there is a
sticker with the name of the bank but
there is no terminal authentication here
I'm saying that e lv standard was
created to fight counterfeiting
and now contactless cards and physicals
this is another way of getting credit
card data we talked about this type of
God at last year the previous year two
years ago so and I've seen it it's just
like one more door so I make a message
to the credit card either through the
cheap-o through the FEC but actually I
data I just get it from the chip the and
FC it's just one more door to access to
credit card data do you know that there
is a limit as to the number of students
that you can pay with an MP NFC card and
that amount in Spain is up to 20 euros
but you already know everyone knows that
have you see NFC cards I have a lot but
a lot of problems so far I know they
doesn't want to talk about malware well
these are the typical faces of mother
that having adapted to this type of a
specific malware so this Marvel is first
of all access to the system once it is
in the system it becomes persistent and
it will search both for processes it
does that in the first instance funny
the texts system or process that is
interested in he will scan the memory it
will gather information once it gather
data card data what does it do it just
exfiltrate those data very quickly I'll
tell you each and every one of the
features of this man well in the case of
binary the malware executable can be
protected or not if protect local have
several levels of protection then in
kinds of persistence in terms of
persistence how it persists based on
register based on the service or perhaps
it is not persistent if a marble is not
it means that it is the second phase of
attack of the third man where that is to
say someone will have to run it see if
it is not persistent it with not Severn
work I don't know perhaps the user will
do that regarding functionality so we
can perhaps it would only steal credit
card data or perhaps it will do
something else perhaps you would have
engage in any other type of
communication so regarding processes we
can distinguish clear whether it does a
selective search or not in the selective
one we could see whether it does
blacklisting or what listing so that is
to say whether there is only one type of
processes that is scanned by this man
well if this were the case this would be
kind of an apt that is to say because
it's not the process that it wants to
scan that is to say the systems that
wants to attack in terms of process
search here we could have two things
here either own implementation or system
implementation for a non implementation
in Windows we will need to have a root
kids but it disease yes it would be
technically feasible if we had that
rootkit so what information does it look
for it looks for even from a data on
track one track two or both how do they
match that information we could have
regular expression or specific
algorithms house data sheet great seats
well there are several methods for that
some wait for up until a USB is
connected to the machine once that
happens he will take all the credit card
data and then storage in that USB so
that means that samples assume that
there will be someone
gaining eventually gaining physical
access to that machine and then also
internet-based X filtration through HTTP
queries or through DNS queries regarding
connection how data is accelerated here
we could see whether the connection is
ordinary an ordinary one whether love
sound ordinarily or through tour through
toll network obviously chasing criminals
in tour it's more difficult than on
surface web so i downloaded 144 samples
from 22 non-families this is a table
summarizing each and every one of those
families each antivirus manufacturer
changes the slightly the name of it and
this is the discovery dates / years and
cordials so well i did not analyze each
of these 144 samples because i have a
life and i selected in specific sample
the one with the highest virustotal
ratio so I analyzed the highest VT
racial
and this is the evolution in the
beginning we had only one family twenty
street-based persistence then in 2012
two families showed up the next one
registry base the other one another one
service prevalence and you see the
numbers here well you could go and say
that the only few families for this type
of malwa but I feel that there is an
evolution in the years ahead of us I
believe that these bars will become
higher a higher well that would also be
good fun and we will have work to do so
regarding binaries you should note that
most of the binaries have been developed
with c++ or defi so only one of families
have been developed with dotnet out of
the 22 families only five of them
implement any type of security based on
Parker only three of them use any anti
analysis technique as you can see here
most of them are divided by future
anti-growth persistence as you can see
most of them despite EF features our
registry based on the few of them do
best persist and on a few of them are
service-based persistence there is one
which is very interesting the knit loved
one it persists in the registry but it
doesn't have a special manner instead of
storing itself in a file in this sample
or these family brother is a stored in
NTFS files so that's the only way from
the evil to hide data so that those that
are not detected in forensics
but information is still about data is
it stolen well in most of the cases in
data on track one and two are stolen
most of them if any focus on track to
only and most of them will do whitelist
what type of processes are those that
are excluded well often system processes
explorer but dot x a l as us so these
system processes as you know that will
not have credit card data or should not
have credit card data ah the process is
excluded by this malware here we'll have
some families such as these two here
that do whitelisting they focus on
specific processes as i say well this is
problematic this is a summary of how all
this is done and for to set processes
windows functions are used and well this
is typical otherwise we will need a
rootkit so no family has been found
using a rootkit however we cannot rule
that out from happening in the future
most of the families when they find the
process we will read the memory of the
process from themselves the process
would ask windows the mud well we'll ask
about the process that it is interested
in then we will take it and then it will
be asking the process for its memory
areas of what memories have you have
reserved and then it would answer what I
have these ones and they said would you
like to read them and the mother says no
and then it would read that memory
fragment that fragment piece by piece
however there are two formulas very
interesting families that will inject
code they will inject the memory reading
process indeed
actual process that I want to read what
do they get out they yes avoid jumping
an anti virus signature checking whether
there is a process that is accessing in
the process memory accessing the process
memory is not very typical it is not
very common so if the AV is trying to
detect that type of behavior I inject
out there for you make the reading from
your own memory space and this is not
detectable by the antivirus because for
the antivirus this is common so most of
them would try to get information from
both tracks or if any from track to and
none of them looks for information on
track one only so these are some
instructions that we find in some
regular expressions that we often find
in the binaries so they match the memory
with these regular expressions so these
are the first ones that we find for this
type of malware grass are W this was
fastest couple in 2011 let us take off
the top one here we can see that it is
really in the credit card number then
the name and the family name of the
person then the year and the month
notice from 0 to 9 or 10 11 and 12 but
notice the year 2000 172 2009 from 2010
2015 so that is to say in my work that
was discovered in 20 of 11 that's
matching with credit card that expire on
2007 to get me you know what I mean
so well if they did not discover that in
four years well they must have made lots
of profit out of it Iman unicamente then
it was most will have non-anonymous
connection and just a couple have this
other connection and then there's this
other one this other two that have no
kind of exfiltration outside so those
would be the ones that I said before
keep them on a file or else as send it
to and shared unit and a network some of
them tried to send it to a shared and
unit on a network and if we think of
safe and secure systems we can think of
the POS terminal system that it's
isolated but connected to the system
that is not isolated so I get it out to
this system that's not isolated and from
there it goes up outside most will half
HTTP POST connections and some have a
DNS queries as well or requests they
send this DNS request to villain or evil
systems and there they coat the credit
card information that they are x
filtering good let me discuss the tool
that I've mentioned it's best on the DB
our instrumentation principles a dynamic
reiner instrumentation I can run the
code when I want and when I say so so
have my code that will be run and I say
this is the code i want you to run and i
want you to run it here and there that's
it this is DB I'm we've just been finger
which is int'l developed framework so
you can have this kind of tool develop
easily that's the architecture and now
we're tools of far is called pink API
hook and that hooks some system calls
those that we are interested in such as
files registry processes and networks so
I'm monitoring
the MAL work execution or implementation
and what we do is intercepting the calls
and when we intercept them I write it on
a file all the parameters that it is
calling what the cold returns let me
show it to you on a demo I've prayed to
the gods so let me show it to you I have
this Debian machine with me running this
server and I find there is a given
website at a given directory this is a
file PHP that is there on the screen and
it runs everything and writes it from
the past into a given file and here to
comes also dashboards to control my PHP
this is the apache lock option to check
the options and on top you see the fun
information where it is writing that is
at a PP dot PHP sorry hot PHP and this
is a sample from Lena family so let me
show you the strings inside the binary
these are regular expressions that I
explained so far this sample here is
looking for credit cards from twenty
twelve to twenty nineteen both truck 1
this is truck 1 and traction as well and
I know it because of its format so this
is truck 1 equal means its truck too so
this sample has been modified as you see
it's been hard coded and it says what
act itself I don't know if you can see
it from here from there because it's
small print the IP is hard-coded that's
what the sample connects in and this is
what I request it from my system this is
the folder and this is the happy HP so I
get good a post with the information
this web is not working now but it will
be instructed to lock to my machine so I
have my own pee a web server machine
with card reader and a few people in the
morning have been here so maybe my
memory I've stored this kind of
information meaning that i have my POS
system running and there are some people
who've paid using my POS terminal I know
if there's a Roman sauna and other
people they've used their card and this
is stored in my memory so this window
stays open and running and this is all
on the process memory that's notepad and
this is the other sample that has been
modified Elena's family modified and
when when I run you will see what
happens this is what I think vogue I
will not dwell on that press ENTER and
there are some lock files with the
traces and the samples gone right and
this is quite typical of malware mal
will once the machine is infected itself
deletes so let's see what's going on
here system as you see this window
systems still running nothing's on there
and eventually if gods are merciful
we'll see what we get the ABS
information that has kept the cards data
on memory so this is a connection to the
apache server and up here you see the
files information there it is thank you
so here it's a connection from the
windows machine and HTTP pass request
for a fine and this this the data sent
back to me by the back you see this is
the beginning of an El Nino string and
all the information data that it
scattered and you can see well that
there's been previous tests from earlier
so HW ID so heartwood ID and a number
right if we knew about windows this is
so much so this number is a match to the
number expressing my heart dr volumes on
the infected machine so what the samples
is doing is a spot in where the data are
coming from and this specific machine
that is extracted information as you can
see there is this little file that has
been produced it is a fine and i guess
there's another one i can say this oh
here is so two files two files that have
information for the execution this is
all the requests to malwa so first mal
would try to create mutex and mute and
here you see open process calls as well
to start processes that's what it's
trying to do here sums are excited sums
are not but in the end you see some
readings from the memory are the
processes memory I'm not sure whether it
is here eventually all the way down it
should be so yes you you see the request
that it's been done this is the coral
the connection here it is when there is
a connection attempt this is the IP and
here you see the type of request this is
the send request you see and here is
what the what it is sending so next good
this is md5 of the sample left analyze
its been slightly touched to connect to
my server that's Warsaw then related
work so many people have looked into
different kinds of malware but no one
had looked into this kind of box baby
because it may be because it it was not
mature this sector and when it comes to
banking information or data you need to
know that some people has developed some
tools to sniff internet works to see if
your system fulfills the pc is s
standard PCD ISS and there is a scraping
with network packages and others have
looked into security are there different
elements pay Paul and others offer you
hard with that you can connect to the
audio jack on your cell phone and the
target is to read credit cards some
people have analyzed what the security
is for these kind of systems so
conclusions there is kind of mole of
malware that it's quite different that
stills information from credit cards
stored in the memory of processes within
an operating system this time windows
we've seen how they work first through
persistence then they gather all the
processes that are running and they go
into the process memory and find the
information the matches a credit card
haven't mentioned it but there are a few
samples where they implement the Luhn
algorithm briefly mentioned by Ruben
which is an algorithm that it's part of
being track of standard and it states
whether the number of credit card you've
read is valid or not you need to
consider that malware reads the whole
memory and it might happen that what is
being read doesn't match a credit card
so the format would be a match but it
would not be a credit card
our beers and that's validating
algorithm that is used to validate when
the information is found they just
exfiltrated in whatever way we've
analyzed 22 families and they were
classified based on their behavior or
workflow okay home messages well luckily
there are only a few families trying to
use some kind of anti analysis mechanism
luckily all persistent methods used can
be easily detected they are
registry-based and they are quite simple
to detect there's only one that's a bit
more complicated that would be neat love
using ntfs so those are alternate flows
for information and most go for process
blacklisting it's only normal because
system processes are not interested in
looking into them and most of the time
luckily as well they will use
exfiltration flows that are none
anonymous so it will be easy to track
down where the information is sent who
is receiving it and so we can crush the
villains system we've seen some other
two weird things such as a DNS
exfiltration or when you like are you a
USB to your machine I'm to more used to
remember that that's me know for me if
you have questions I'll be happy to take
them
[Applause]
oh so good morning first of all thank
you domen for your presentation very
interesting and let me mention for POS
or post terminal environments of those
companies that set those terminals up as
a restaurants and coffee shops are they
aware of it or is the solution different
I hope so this kind of companies were
they trying or should try to make the
standard otherwise you should get lost
but as I said before when we discuss the
standard would they ensure is that the
information in transit is protected but
as far as I know there is no solution
the things of a memory protection
because this is the local machine and
there is a a drum attack on the machine
that very machine so I guess that the
POS terminal pretty manufacturers should
have some run cleaning after each
transaction well they should do
something to make sure that if infected
with this kind of malware the data from
the credit card would not be on the
memory so in plain tex i mean and that
was that was a question about different
manufacturers i have not talked to any
of them so i cannot tell you for sure
but i have to guess based on the market
solutions that are out there and the
fact that this is going on especially in
the US where the credit card is widely
used with the magnetic stripe i would
guess that the memory date is not
protected because if it's a cheap card
this technique it would not be feasible
right well see the chip cards this would
be different kind of attack the thing is
if the information
out of the chief is a stored on the RAM
memory which this should not be the case
in Italy the problem would be the same
but again it should not be there so you
would recommend d stabling the magnetic
stripe right I recommend you to be aware
of what you do with your credit card
that was it where you tap it what ATMs
you use for sure thank you very much
good morning morning what's the current
the useful infection factor well as with
any kind of malware if you have a POS
terminal you work at somewhere and
you've got plenty of time I don't know a
tobacco shop you've got your your
terminal some people come in the shops
and other times you are alone and you've
got a computer with an internet
connection what do you do rip the
newspapers yes or apps or probably some
websites to watch some videos
not-so-legal videos movies that are on
websites weather's usually third-party
exploit to compromise your computer
basically what we see is that the attack
vector would be the same that we would
find with a commodity malware which is
regular malware it could also be
insiders the typical and happy employee
down flexing the the USB yes the USB
excitation is more less clear but if
they attack it all as if it were fishing
or maybe it's a bit more much more
targeted or focus no you can have a much
more focused or targeted attacks
actually
rule of the standard is to have highly
specific attacks because this kind of
websites we mentioned anyone could login
and so the percentage of people who find
themselves at a POS terminal would be
smaller but we could refer to much more
targeted attacks spearfishing but takes
you to a given website and then last
question any water Hollen attack that
you've seen watering hole in attack
where there might be a regular provider
and there it is compromised and so there
is like a skate effect no have not seen
it perfect thank you very much yeah
together Thank You Ricardo as always
you're so great at explaining what do
you need to explain easy to understand I
have a question and you see the
Etienne's that would speed out money
does it have to do with this kind of
attacks this is ATM malware and it's
completely different okay good maybe a
few years from now next to you maybe
I'll discussed that nothing to do with
Swift attacks either that are so trendy
recently any more questions so thank you
very much for being in this room in a
Sunday morning