the 14 I'll still be here this one onto
okay so
how many have you are new to Caroline
Connan still here
that explains a lot
I thank you
arm every a every other person that's
prolly been here for years no the
knows that attendance kind of wall
diminishes
on Sunday for various things that
happened on Saturday night so
arm dude windows just shut down
so
first I'm gonna show you how to rearm
windows 7 the this a
arm year network tester
on gonna complain again
I haven't had the same thing connect to
the network hope I'm it's a feature
I agree I'm just personal Microsoft
every
reaching your anyone hears from
Microsoft arm
I'd don't want me so don't try to give
you one
so are yet thanks for coming out
hopefully this'll
they in night get shut down for piracy
again
are so the Arco postinfection response
mitigation
what the hell just happened on the
network there may be a question here
quite often
shame on you may be questioning boss
asks you
maybe a question that you ask yourself
you think this is a lot dumber some shit
um in artistry
for Windows so
with the whole just happen on my network
are hopefully after
we're done here today I can help me find
out
so base in this park is basically about
having an IT department are or some
instance where you may have security
people but not really
arm love IT departments don't have some
other
someone that specializes in an hour and
demoted
are so that's basically what this park
is about
under the good stuff when ames Caleb I
love people call me chill
what people tell me to chill arm some
people say and chill
just depends on how much I've had to
drink when you catch up with me
arm right now I'm gonna see our I was
going to work out today
amatzia Mauer analyst a the media trust
them you trust those nothing
that has to do with the paw just in case
you know you wanted to know
are the me to trust those cummick clough
our mitigation
I you Mourinho's you know about critical
things in a play with them
if I know what to do and I tell our
customers what they do
and a stop doing them I'm the founder
the telecoms you know
I like to thank everyone for coming out
also if our
everyone's interested next year you have
in action again
every year strong for six years in
thanks for coming out
on Friday up dirty white house I
my opinion you can't really be in the
security industry without doing some TV
shit
if you consider yourself a string up
quite how
mmm I it I'm sorry you have to do these
things to be in the upper second history
you have to bend your ethics sometimes
to do things to learn more
are so just keep that in mind when
questioning yourself
sure I actually do this world can get
you arrested don't do it but if it's not
just on your home network
and test machines that like that please
do it learn more
arm and I'm your huckleberry that has
nothing to do with anything
just my favorite quote ever from best
movie ever made
and if you come this you know sometimes
I'm your huckleberry
so on to the good stuff
are we're gonna covers the gray area
which is postinfection
are a lot of people really doe think
about what happens after you get
infected what people think about
levels before then and a lot of people
think about what happens after the
infection is gone
there's no real talk about with the
whole happen just now
on my network so after that we're gonna
go over some our brief responses
awesome planning and our temple so
gonna show just a few tools that I find
really really interesting
and gonna go over some methods
to find new tools other than the ones
I'm about to show you I
so away we go why is postinfection
a gray area Inc can anyone tell me
why why it's such a weird place to
hang out yep
that is through its literally different
every single time whether it be the
perhaps files that you're dealing with
home infection
was your here is a restructuring
yeah although I haven't found one
Mauer author except contractors for a
government that actually populate their
software
correct
are and I'll get to that actually so are
I've outlined three main reasons why
it's a gray area
are good answers 1 I've main reasons is
over-reliant on antivirus
arm we got a we were good
you know we'll never did in fact in if
we do we can just call the V company
sweet simple as that will have an
infection
outta here in no time well the final
time and
you know you may have an infection in
network what the hell happened
armoured 8 anti virus is not what it
used to be it's not
the first layer security should have
against viruses
it's no longer that semantic and other
people say
your antivirus is dead it's not
unfortunately tonight
its it's kind of annoying but it's not
dead yet it still required as
security layer it's not what it used to
be used for though
in palmer's right now is used for a
breach a learning mechanism
while 100 times it may stop something
from getting on your network
as a whole their store backs though they
are going to get on your network
I'll anti-virus will alert you
want to block and that's only if you
have your admin console setup correctly
a all those damn emails they keep
calling your inbox that you made a
folder for that same our alerts
want to keep ignoring thats your AV
actually doing its correct all been
letting you know your network is
breached it's not telling you how it's
preached
it's not telling you why but it's saying
hey you know
you should probably check this out %uh a
lot of people just ignore that
are sauce you know if you ever saw per
year
organization great but not everyone has
that very large corporations that don't
have a saw
in the may contract their stuff out with
Amy just how I keep people
and a lot
the ministers actually art that the
employer's Mauer
you know how to handle it you know what
to do with it an
thats pretty much the base the start
another reason
a people there's a gray area is more
persistence techniques
appeasing hours on your system in it
doesn't want you to know it's there
you're probably not going to know if
their letter actually penalizing inbox
every day
if apiece from our is popping up in it a
fake antivirus in front view
and you know Jake in HR keeps trying to
the importer
obviously it's not trying to hide itself
trying persist trying to
store you in some way crypto Walker I
mean if you know a trip to lockers in
this room
start googling just don't get a Google
Images cuz you prolly get ripped a
locker
arm so yeah are persistent techniques
you not in the know it's there and it
goes hand in hand with a reliance on
antivirus
if you're ignoring these alerts and it's
telling you it's there
you know and you're not doing anything
about it it's actually your problem not
Jake an HR who keeps dragging the window
down
the corn screen doesn't know any better
of your fault for not training take a
little better
in restricting his access so third thing
is
really just lack have exposure in
training how mean you work
in an IT department at some level okay
only if you have I'm our person will
surprising
arm last time I do this there were no
hands
%uh so that's actually really good by
it's the IT departments that don't have
that person
and it doesn't take certification it
doesn't take anything like that I mean
you too is now serve occasion you can
find a lot of stuff on YouTube you can
find
lot of sites out there that just have
information about were viruses hang out
and just some stuff you can do to
initially looked every single removal
article you read about in covers
dis removing viruses its gonna start of
the same way and it's going to take you
through the same senate directories and
configure it seems that
the is the steps documented in with your
something is your organization
you know your're two steps ahead again
don't have call you baby
opening colliery be company on top
anything else
you're giving way a potential target
attack to an AB company that
really gives know shits that it was a
targeted attack they just want the
symbols
so they detected on other people's
machines so
yeah train people get them some exposure
to Mauer
on there's basically three
respond house you can pay one similar
infection
want you find out about one way or
another weathered some complaining
re finally check rebbe see ol hey it's
up to date
oh yeah by the way they receive 1000
alerts from a
you know home in finance to you with the
whole
looks like a worm aren t were those be
all this the automation
so if you have someone trained if you
have some exposed how to handle Mauer in
it at least
do kinda minor now sits on it it's
really gonna better put your
organization more than just
relying on your antivirus company or you
have contractors that are
doing security in you the No about an
hour
you know asked them or you know have
them release some information
here on stuff people about what to do in
the situation
its really common sense into getting the
not so common sense
when you encounter piece from our so the
three respond housing in part well
first 13 image seconds the ETF
on the third ones basically remove one
analysis which in my opinion
is the most proper way to go every
single infection no matter what
I'll I'm exhausted we are not were so
just bear with me
%uh the first how public talk about his
rematch
and if you have been a sysadmin or an IT
person in this room
you know they're it's the fastest way to
get someone
back into their work it's about this way
the
you may be required to do by your higher
ups you know
new campaign that thing get about maybe
a quick recovery
which is the plus by if your gonna do
this
theory into machines you know look a
little bit in the word image
are reimaging is basically your through
clean image on top reinstall the
software gonna go
checks back getting viruses on his
finance machine sweet are
to if your gonna do this practice only
seen in Kung Fu
and all easy man Kung Fu is is kung fu
make lazy man's
or admins are required to do this kind
of thing just be in a better place after
happens
so is Windows seven box you know there
tell me to reimage it
what should I do law take an image for
yourself
you know it don't know I mean don't just
in the Windows
to connect for travel you to a secondary
environment image that drive
you know image to partition image the
main partition
remains on to VM play with them a little
bit see what the heck's going on
i mean to you should know what's going
on anyway split
just have an image if anything if you're
not even gonna do anything with that
image
in your higher ups are staying at which
the prime explain to them it's not
because
if anything you have a organically
infected machine
that you can play with on your own time
and learn this stuff
so you don't have to call your TV
company you have like 45 images that got
infected throughout your
organization if different factions on
they may be targeted they may not be
targeted by
you never know unless you actually look
dumb look at what they're trying to
steal
or just you know have a central
withholding to do
in the first place when this occurs if
you see something
part in QuickBooks files not a good
thing but you wouldn't know
rebbe company is not going to tell you
that back not going to be someone else's
report
they're gonna closure case because
that's what they want to do they want to
get your computer
back to whatever kinda weird Workington
condition it was in the first place
an just you know close the case so
the second half a minute talk about is a
a path that a lot of people follow in I
don't understand
I use the leading our response team at
my former company
and so the W first saw
doesn't just and for what it stands for
why
and its sometime stands for
accommodation
what what because you're so perplexed
what you're being told
know what will well why what Lake
basically what happens a breach occurs
an ignore or you're admitting North
they keep using the computer like a the
example Jake an HR
polling the if they gave easy
watched under the edge in the screen
just so you can keep using the computer
I mean they may have gotten hit with the
word explain are still using were there
still typing directly into it
crazy and I've been on networks where
they have still been using everything
that infected
for months and then the cause and
they're like
know we need to know what have we lost
like point thousand dollars in last
month how
in all they gotta holdover Bank
Financial somehow
well in check the timestamps on some
this Mauer
it's been there for months and I mean as
much as Mauer can actually
manipulate the time stamp himself look
you'll find either compile or some
little while its gonna
indicate that these people have been
infected actively
with your non Lake this Mauer doesn't
even care that it knows
like is poppin screens a pre Mauer just
16 story in some way
but they keep using it in a matter of
hours notice
so they keep checking these connections
all the sudden there
away this is a company this isn't like
someone's grandmother
let's just remote in roadway
and in the world and Matt in the loop
crazy stuff
in your network because what else would
they do
that's whether there in the first place
have a question
understand but what the fuck why are you
still using it
like all I can say
when someone tells me they're still
using a machine with infection on
after months you important what
like I i've been using this machine all
don't worry it's just more runs our
QuickBooks
RTP is on the server no problem
configures barone here for like a year
so
yet don't be don't be these people
nonprofit I
if you find these people correct their
behavior
because if you know these people and
they know you're in the security in some
aspect
and they don't have security people in
their IT realization
polling in Astoria asking you some
questions an
you're gonna find it's a ridiculous on
the situation you're not going to help
them
or you're going to reconsider lost cause
because some networks
are so badly infected their freedom lost
cause
if they have servers are booting up the
oil patch on
Arts on talking about a a Windows 2000
Server
on Friday that you know they still have
to actively support
scary but legacy become one you know
from logging on public leader for 4 for
5 on your Windows 2000 Server and
use in like 10 twelve-year-old exploits
that still work
there's a huge issue so
the path I want to talk about the most
other than
arm sleazy admins and potentially
high-functioning individuals there are
very very special
are room one elses
every time you find an infection
or you get alerted to an infection this
is the path any
you should pay here in this room for a
reason became this care line upon
this weekend learn about security in
style please please please
now hours very prominent hours when the
biggest things
in the news right now because people can
stop it
it's not if your gonna get infected it's
when
if you're planning not to get infected
the 10 know what planet you live on
because everyone gets infected
doesn't matter if you know high-security
doesn't matter anything
are you're gonna get infected I give
this part and
Arlington I mean Abreu maybe four weeks
ago and I the guy asked well you know
I was Mauer get around perimeter
defenses like you by rampant anything I
would have
perimeter the blocks all this well
I think it's murder actually talked
about a little bit I inflict upon to
flash drives and drop in the parking lot
or I'd walk in in just Hannah flash
drive the secretary
or whoever was up there they don't know
all yeah this is for ball there's a ball
that works there somewhere
problem in the if you drop in the
parking lot
he dropped ten flash drives with an
all-around buyers
the parking lot guaranteed someone's
gonna pick one up
someone's gonna wonder what is on the
flashdrive
as soon as they put in their machine
bless you
Endpoint Protection which is ever take a
joke
arm you're screwed and you can't
pinpoint who isn't gonna pick up flash
drive unless you make your organization
where
don't think of laughter out in the
parking lot you know bring them to
the IT office if you find them don't
think about that stuff but it's not
if you're gonna get infected its when
you're gonna get infected again
it doesn't matter you get up people
bringing their own devices in
their are actively infected in the use
it as have a point they didn't even know
it was a pivotal point in
in toll all the sudden the pain with use
it like to be in with stats
on that particular right like all shit
you know it's connecting the speed test
comcast in like San Jose all the sudden
this
DSL connection formerly DSL connection
is able to transmit like
and make the second G you know
this looks good I'm glad we in fact that
the slut part you know let's
get on this laptop wallet active on the
fly and see what else is on the network
so some stuff to do basically in the
remote
myer blood removal and analysis are
power first thing is pains in their
memory dumps
are volatility framework is a great
thing
its not argues just for basic memory
analysis their tools
the Windows makes they are good for
getting these
are I'm gonna go over a couple East
Falls but
yet get a memory dump a lot of us have
remote offices and the remote offices
may have a crappy DSL connection or
something
you may have an instance where you have
to use TeamViewer to get on the infected
machine
now if you wanna transfer 6 King memory
dump thirteen-year
law if you have secure VPN stuff
though like setup still good luck it's a
16 gig memory dull
leisure analyzing on that machine you're
not gonna wanna rate went around for
this by the time he went around four
whoever's actually controlling them she
might see you doing this
in just set the machine 0 or I seen it
tripwire
and disable the neck so you can't do
that anymore are
some hours very aggressive if you can't
get a full member don't get a process
memory go
I'm gonna be gone over that period
shortly so
packet captures are very important or
people
take packet captures a new their minds
basically when they're doing
power wires RTCP don't be best friends
if there's an infection
on a business machine inside the
organization
don't you wanna know what it's talking
to that machine became organically
infected
it was infected in the way that it was
meant to
in fact basically is queen bee
is that machine if you rip them our of
machine in writing test environment you
may get skew results as far as like
packet captures go
or even memory don't because it's
running in an environment
the it technically wasn't designed to
run on less you can fully replicate
the infection which may not happen every
time question
just gonna say that
arm never do it on a machine I mean i've
seen. viruses that block
tools like Sysinternals tools and stuff
like that they listen for them they know
they're very effective
Wireshark is one of them are not even
sure if they make a TCP don't work for
Windows but
always do on a different machine I mean
always do it
the close as you can get it by you know
just gonna fall
capture if you work the organization
it's like easier
and if your contractor some like that
you have to get specific permission to
get
all capture for the network budget
something by
at the same time breaking their
connection to reconnecting is suspicious
activity
so you don't know alert they you're
actually looking into this
yet are into you actually get into the
nitty-gritty
I mean disconnecting and reconnecting it
that's fine by
they may have other machines are
infected in the just one blips on off
really quick
and they're actually part in that
organization it AMA Pro Mach they may
just
you know the kill switch in just knew
the machines are
other thing do some our main much some
our
bull meh the menu on our extraction
so every time I get on a machine now
that I've dealt with an hour for so long
I just have these enter a list of stuff
to go down every single pon
what directors to all again program data
on Windows seven
you know at the temp files early Tom
folders
everything even like the Windows Recycle
Bin
the directories on the back a bit every
time I find something
new well that Mauer goes to I added to
mine for a list
are a lot of people do with Mauer Mauer
now sits just how these lists of things
where they look immediately arm
so if you can actually get that X he
will file
play with it a little bit in a test
environment with no internet see what it
does
are the third thing is Carol on the same
track
have some kind of made in sandbox
environment setup
there's a low ones you you pay for by
there's
cuckoo have some cummick you set up not
just have
an automated sandbox environment setup
by
think about who has the potential to get
infected in
in your organization so HR runs a
certain so software
have an image with that software have a
snapshot a one hr without
if finance run special software
I know it's a little hard to get
permission to do this sometimes actually
even need after relations but
it's worth it run the software on the
finance image
so you can if you find a piece from our
this in your funny
former run against the see exactly what
it's looking for
if it's looking for stuff actively and
you can see the calls
like do some more investigation I mean
this is basically
berry simple things that everyone should
be doing
you know you should look in New what the
hell's going on with your network
of people though its new can pay
or you know it antivirus not he passion
antivirus it's still necessary it's just
not as necessary
are so battle planning
have plans made up like I said
don't plan to knock it in fact you're
gonna get infected someone
on your network is going to have some
weird little impact in even if it's a
pop
false-positive even if like no nope had
already eighty
automatically start showing up is
infected it might be a false positive
free antivirus
white if you're scratching your head
just standing there and you don't know
what to do other than contact your
anti-virus company
I mean no pad rahe if I found it was
showing up in my anti-virus
as you know infected I'll maybe
check the half against some numbers
total to see if anyone actually
infect ther has this as an infected so
nope had could get infected well if it's
a targeted attack
why would I want to upload the virus
total because buyers total is now
owned by people and we all know ok
you've always with information
by you can just check the hash get and
the five
in check it on buyers to all they have
the house good luck
you look people I mean no one else has a
house
in my view heart attack so just do your
due diligence
so how some response solution set up
have a little talk a
not everyone has a saw not everyone has
e-verify toolkit that they're supposed
to use for every single breach
not everyone has that the people do
awesome but the people that don't
should have at least a small pool walks
about locations
that they can use combat the stop
are how multiple defense methods like I
said AB
step 1: primer defense you should have
an email filtering stuff like that
I mean basic stop after Exchange Server
I mean it that's the fence you can never
tell
who's trying to get your network just
think everyone's trying to get my
network but how can I do that came out
are also audit your network
don't know Jagan finance running
15 burns a job law what's wrong with you
I've seen it
there's a record its 17 versions of Java
starting with Java Runtime Environment
5.0
it's basically a lake if you go into
eating contest for cheeseburger
how high can they start the cheeseburger
that's unfortunately that's the
attack vector stock on a lot of people's
machines because they have like 15
virgins a job install
how many factors do you need your
running Windows already you're prolly
have Flash installed 10 making a job a
party on top of that
so ought not work and don't install
dollar
question
yeah
absolutely
yep baselines are very important see
with the hectic right
see what your networks running first
before
infection occurs before something occurs
but are
back to my job a rant how many have you
actually need job in your organization
you need to have job install is it
because
your company runs outdated software yep
not run is a lot we run Java Runtime
Environment 5 we can install uninstall
that man sorry
but you're going to keep getting
infected this is
they surf the web on this machine
they're using Java Runtime Environment
in their browser to deal with this
legacy software that you're too cheap to
operate
you can't prevent that unfortunately you
can rent
public Sandboxie question that is great
for like a super corporate IT department
by
so
I understand where you're coming from 10
are I've just seen like nuclear
waste show up from situations like that
you can virtualize it it doesn't mean
it's not going to affect the rest your
environment they have a pivot point
they're gonna go after arm question
yep
like I said if you
if your company actually update sir
software to the latest newest version
that they're
probably too cheap to upgrade to because
the cost a lot of money in some cases
I feel bad for those people then
by I'm sane the point is this is
basically
if you have to run Java do it but keep
an eye on those notes
keep a closer eye on that network
implement something that may keep track
0 the people that have turned the legacy
Java you say they
basically you have have Java installed
its legacy
niche that's fine by not every single
person in your entire company
has to use the software like you check
your own machines when you back
you know you have to have the install if
you do you have installed
is it in a virtual environment up so
yeah
if you have to have Java fine well just
keep an eye on the boxes that you
especially the ones that have to run
legacy Java which
you know it's a lot different use cases
for legacy Java
and it's out there so
the government's poultry are
so I'm gonna go over simple the train
right now arm
just three talls that's it are
so the first one a lot of you should re-
have
experience with it is process explore
when the most beautiful utilities the
system internals makes
for Windows arm you never use
prostitutes or
its
past manager the way it always should
have been has major on steroids
all the way like big fuckin steroids so
the first thing I like to do an open
process for
is look at the execution free I just
came across a piece from our
last week where Bowers basically using
SMSs to execute and it was spawning from
that
and then it was wanting to interact to
explore early eighties
and it was using those I explorers to do
various things soon as I saw us
anything executing from S&S Estadio
CEO's what the hell's going on but even
just little simple things like you know
SBC host
doesn't have to be arm does
I'll a lot of people will look at this
and like
all you know this is just normal use
services
has in Estonian thursday or txt i've
seen
every single process in here injected
into if its executing weird shit or
explored ideas he is using like $800k
no on that one what to use an 800 K
that's immediately
well look at after that as an example
here
are you can do individual process stops
question
right year and actually that's where the
features
I was about to get into are but
verifying with Google
AK Bars total is fine way how often do
you see explore the AC running
$800k are if you look at the execution
free it just tells a lot about what's
going on
immediately are if you see me
if their exporters not open on the
machine and there's like eight of them
listed find out where the hell they're
extremely find out what is
initiating the Senate's word XQ balls I
mean
just looking at this even though I'm
just pardoning the VirtualBox
I guess that on here it a serious you
look at it
as a computer person should be so used
to looking at the execution free Windows
you sure are you know with suspicious
and what's not
are but projects for does have some
really
neat built-in tasks like you can create
individual product process toms
you can you in all model searches which
is
very handy especially in the case of was
xeroxes
I just use this as an example why a
didn't actually have xeroxes installed
on this but
your access for a long time had a piece
of its artifacts it was just that simple
and was hooked and everything so soon as
you get on here
everything will pretty much normal we do
handle search
in you'd find at some ball basically
injected and everything
in this weird directory that you can get
you through export or txt
traditionally are so if you find
artifacts
in my hour look for them look for them
internally in the system
you might see a file name in a few doing
in all search on a file name
you receive exactly what it's trying to
access or exactly when it swerved into
and then you can make a determination on
what to do next if
of if I like five different things open
the services the AC
guess what it's trying to persist you
not gonna shut down services da txt on
Windows
gonna crash immediately which is the
point
amid trying to persist through injecting
into that and finally
as you point out
arm properties on steroids
so as he was pointing out you can
actually do a buyer still have search
within the Properties menu for
prostitutes or nowadays which is fine
but just keep in mind targeted tax
you really want you wouldn't even have
the hash so
nine times i'd benefits randomly named
or if it's just you know to like try to
30 of the bars
if it's doing something if someone's
complaining if you're getting a be
alerts
don't bother with buyers total it's
already vires
are if you're just not ashore and there
are certain cases where y'all
with is this story behavior you know
verify the half the fires total it it
doesn't hurt if you're out of shims
if you can't figure out if its an I mean
in Barstow may not be a hoe
you know this but the six different AB
engines on their what if
30 come up and say the virus and the
other 30 said Queen
I mean the usually I only use bar stool
see if it's possible not
and old for the turn the major AB
companies to be detecting it
if northern detected in only difference
abe is detecting it
prolly false-positive by that's kinda
the last thing I go through
before actually dive into arm
that's kinda last thing I go through
before
on they are a I kinda
top how at that point on some other
things you can do
you can actually verify the actual
signature VX deal with Microsoft helpful
you can can spew that by it is a hopeful
little thing
you look at all the TCP activity and
stuff like that your process tho
it also look at the memory and the
actual execute will strings
from this properties Paul which
Mauer strings kind everything in the
past but not really
on you can see all the API calls its
making including tax
if you would the memory strings you may
be able to see
I site as connecting to I found in our
form one time just because I looked in
the strings inexcusable those actively
running
the system it was just some guy that was
like basically
showing everyone what he did on our
think it was open WS
by something it's no longer operational
but question
yeah
yeah an I mean again that's
kinda the Barstow ish I'd probably do
that in the background if I actually had
have the senate passes for every machine
some corporate environments are so
locked down
you know you use W w Slauson stop to get
the
updates on but in the world live updates
and exploits
up from time to hash list isn't the most
efficient thing to do
are but nonetheless a good start
2nd 2011 talk about his dump it
it's a statement at all dumped a memory
if you're going to do for me all memory
don't dump it
Alltel yes tools but this is a very late
we
when is excusable that even on the most
infected machines for some reason it
just worked
I it's not been blacklisted by EB
authors or anything like that her
sorry AB authors Mauer authors armpit
very handy tool will give you a a RAW
file and you can play with it
are you want afterwards are the third
tools probably the most interesting
though
and it's basically call PC hunter
AK and I'll the pronunciations way up
zeuner I called that because well it
hasn't
xtian are in it so when I was on a
response team
we're trying to find a lot of tools
basically that would
look deeper into the kernel are a lot
older only coated
were eighty x86 architecture so
when you're on a 64-bit machine you're
looking at
64-bit architecture there's somewhere
problems that come up
a lot of the tools that actually look at
the
MBR and stuff like that are made for x86
some you run them and the blue screen
window 7 64 bit
they're not made to run in 64-bit
environment is the problem
and you can just change that
change loan modification from the code
Aurora party says
it's a poor rewrite don't quote me on
that
don't know if it's true own up there
just sleazy admins by
it seems like a whole lotta work so I
was trying to find the stall
basically that would let me look
and see what the heck's going on colonel
while I was on a machine that was
actively running our
and like i've seen a lot of tools Mauer
will blacklist
PSS killer Process Explorer jeaner
if you're familiar with the matter all
these fools are so well-known
AB heard to sorry AB authors Mauer
authors
we're just gonna group I'm in the same
boat actually is they're both
a assholes so are so we were looking
on how do we prevent the smaller even
when the Mauer was
stopping our tools from running we knew
exactly how
at the call to make that saw but we just
couldn't get in because
x86 tools it wasn't meant for the
architecture
so another thing I'm going to talk about
is
basically our research told are finding
tools
are in don't take my word for by we're
gonna go through that as well
%uh so we found this PC 100 used to be
called just neuter
its available on zuber dot com slash
download
reason I've flash download is because
the entire website is
manger in being if you can remainder in
DRI
goes means late I'm they're probably
talking to a local said
I've no idea what they're talking about
but there's a dollar directory is just
an index directory can download there's
a free version there's a pro version
there's nothing cavers in whoever that
guy is order all the codes this
utility has gone against the wishes of
their people
being day a lot of chinese hackers group
hack into america
this is a tool that actually allows me
on a 64-bit architecture
lookin into the kernel I can look in a
ring 0 I can look in the ring
3 I'll I can look at all the cattle
calls not only that I
when I run this itself obfuscates
dropped its own driver
when it's done when you close it it
kills the driver
if you can see the the top I
there a blue bar up there every time you
run it
is a gives you different string so it's
not
identifiable to Mauer he s just killer
when you run it
and you look at it in a situation like
this it it comes off as the same thing
every single
you know them our knows exactly what to
look for unblock it
with this utility which is an
really good English as a matter fact are
you can just look so deep they
we've been highly these listeners in red
and you can just right click and delete
them and run your tools all day
white say why
why I'm not going to like this on on
North American soil I have no idea
why is this this person code this when a
lot of people are trying to break in
to American you government facilities
and what not
well
so through at they are debugging their
own to
are some other stuff you can do you can
actually look and see if
ring 3 if the program that's running has
written three axis
as you'll see I by the manner in on the
screen
it this particular tillery says it's
denied
but it does have your rates injuring
three something else you can do
that I found very useful in a snap if
you're in a hurry with the shit this
utility it has a
computer examination have the you can
just run a full report
every single have I mean this thing is
really the
in the system with the the information
it spits out it takes a bit
if you're in a hurry you needed you know
generated image the machine you want as
much information as you can
reexamination port you'll be surprised
at the results
arthur's a ton of other stuff in this
utility it even has
went to run it you can actually disable
other excuse and services from starting
up
are as the lead functionally word
doesn't just early
you can kill bully are and delete unlock
you know I could put a file with the
same power name
in place the following just deleted so
it doesn't come back
or tries not come back I mean worker
this
there's even a fire I add on
unfortunately which then they put out a
PT one report
on for so very very useful tool
white by
but
but look
exactly so all these tools agree
every single to lie fine I I analyze
like it's Mauer
like I put it in a ringer because I
wanna know exactly
we're going to use this on tones machine
specially corporate network or know what
it does for
you want all the survival shows nearly
you know
never buy a survival kit at the store
always make your own so you know exactly
what it does same philosophy applies to
finding tools
the combat now we're ni situations in
this fall does like
45 call-outs the China it's still a
killer tall
but guess what before I do anything I'm
gonna know all these eye peas on whose
by largely middle basse-bolle
does a I this last coming in this part
so when I actually asked me
if I was monitoring the DNS requests
they were going now
no I wasn't don't take my word for it
past the shuttle before use it
but regardless its killer tall
now since he's actually move this to
I PC 100 rather than calling is your
there is a pro version
the cost money apparently or yen or
whatever
I there's a free version and this is the
free version only 10
what it does differently because I can
understand the website
arm but it you know what
the free version in the paid version
both call about
or five times to various eye peas in
China 10 them I'm assuming is legit
update mechanism
the other end I don't care like I don't
wanna know what they are
a little block him the killer to one of
the one you use it I mean
the caveat that is also after you take
in the packet capture
all the PLO all the network cable
plugged that is
you know don't wanna call use it as
the portsmith be but always do research
on your tools
Sysinternals I wanna nope it's called
back to my car saw
I wanna know if Microsoft is actually
looking at hashes for every single thing
i'm looking at on our inspection
mean don't trust anything just because
Microsoft made it doesn't mean it's a
legitimate
in look at Windows money addition you
know is
only me think the current system for all
they actually bought from someone
arm tedious task killer from Kaspersky
then make that the bar
from RG murder I think it was a killer
routine utility but
you know it the same thing goes for PSS
killer
it actually calls out the Kaspersky
every time you write it
wants to know if it's updated so it
called back to Kaspersky
every single time you run it and you'll
get this prompt that says pay
are looks like PSS cialis other day
let's go ahead and update it before you
actually run
combat the smaller doesn't matter what
company you work for
at work for another TV company it's not
Kaspersky you realize how much data they
can be getting back just from
that update mechanism same with the one
on this only this is China
kasperski's Russia but arm
no same thing so if you're gonna find
dolls
fine tolls but analyze 'em don't trust
them even that bump it program
I went over to make an outgoing call
someone something like a temp file
the other day they won't know what if I
was its
associate with Mauer mostly are but it's
actually a lossless compression
I format photographers use to use
before well everyone starts but now with
tips
I'm pretty sure but there are no you
know what is this such third book in the
CP connected outbound
anything no doesn't make any funny
registry keys no
stuff like that every single thing
you're going to use
analyze it I there's a utility call sis
tracer I'm sure there's other utilities
says tracer basically takes registry
snapshot and then
you install whatever you take another
entry snaps I
you do different on he would happen if
you have an automated say about
utilities setup
kinda does anyways roll call everything
was created
and who has a shirt and i dont so
other stuff you should check out
now because they're awesome multi
course are all tilly actually has a
utility that
can grab onto the active memory in the
system
and Lee drop ship directly of it while
it's running I can recall the actual
name that utility but checkup all Toledo
minutes for playing with the do memory
dump on your machine
figure out your own passwords other R
Kelly Willis
I'm not even ask you all use it
or something I'll Kelly is actually good
for this kind of thing you can swoop in
as
you can do like anything's the wood used
actually hack someone with Callie
the motor stuff like this so in the in
the case of Lake
on PC hunter you could actually set up a
fake
in a server in catches the US request
with you believe there are rebuilding
the telly
are witnesses internals check them out
its them hours I
remove all all walks really and I hate
I just causes and pearls for saw only
Windows
kinda painted a bit up
Jimmer humors me I it's only x86 with
the rootkit detection removal tool
humor will either be a rock star or it
will be a
the blue screen or machine so it doesn't
initial scan to see you start up
some time that's can hit the trip wire
in you know in May
only script a walker on your machine so
were warning with love these
now we're cares if you're trying to
uninstall
Google obviously arm Wireshark
everyone in this room should at least
have some experience were short
anything download it because the logo is
a fuckin shark why would you not want
that
on so just some are some beautiful
utilities as well
I if anyone is familiar with kinda
forensic investigation
the utilities helix really going on lot
about forensic investigators
in the AM per second to use helix lonely
tools built in
while need imaging tools I deft is the
not so known
I was looking for an alternative to
helix art dept actually had actual
libraries built in that let me
mount the a Mac OS
in HFS plus image or something and
actually access it correctly as though
it were a Mac
rather than having to fiddle around in
basically do stupid stuff too
to make it the files about another
reason I hate Macs
arm no offense to anyone but I should
just be able to mount the fuckin image
instead of jumping they're a bunch hoops
nonetheless if you need to Def
re: houses live reason such built-in
there's nothing you need to install
irons boot CD they were no barns with CD
year Hearns is freaking awesome its
prolly highly illegal
are the tolls like don't take are you
from there's a mini version of XP on it
you can literally who to at the W I am
file
XP inside Windows XP shell which is
useful from our removal arm I actually
modified hirings it it's about 500
make I so I got it down to about 119
makes
and I made a responder disc actually and
we were able to boot into Windows XP you
were over the moon links partition
Saidapet
an the XP side actually made networking
automatically start up our wireless and
wired and
the background image was like
instructions on how to run TeamViewer
teamwork line on their and
it just had a her removal tools home
instruction als
for anyone to actually remove viruses
with it
why do I make that wall for Bill Walker
arm
got sick at home people take the machine
the look like you
I T store IT department there was no way
back before trip to water actually
infected and
encrypting the entire hard drive it
would just
for a while they are all ransomware it
would throw up
the screen it would just make like
walking on your system maybe turn your
webcam on mister
yourself arm but then it got a little
smarter and started using like a yes to
for the encryption on your files and it
became true ransomware
it wasn't just something you had to get
past to get access to explore selling
more
arm but irons very good has like
hearted person norton ghost on just
crazy good utilities all over the
least and by default on the DOS menu
when you boot to it you can do seven
layer
I 0 the the FBI uses you
it remove anything the you may not want
on
and also %uh ship workstation is just
IBM
there are scenes offers for free
download it
you know pump it up on your a on your
hypervisor just check into it
it does about the same thing as he licks
only it's an actual
are workstation that you just download
the image for think it's looking over
years
like a other things to check out like
honey drive if you've never heard of it
the drive is really useful thing if
you're used to run like I
like Knoppix and just anything you think
honey pie or analysis believe it's
re-building honey drive in it download
VM don't link so you have to google
and at it
i any questions any more questions
or comments about AB
company busing who
I think one question
you like us to war you get the fuck
outta here right now
well
so anyways thank you hope it wasn't for
up