I everybody
everybody away no
RA fight so at just to get some people
warmed up
if you're a developer stand anybody
developer you
come on stand-up your view arts we get a
handle on developing our developer you
guessed it out
re: how many people are operations
administration outside a house stand-up
yeah that's me too so Marty standin'
call thank you so just curious I'll
I'm largely going to be talking about
the operations side of things
for the stalk cell the talk is on high
personal computing
%uh the its kinda my perspective on
things
hopefully it's a perspective the you
guys will be able to learn something
from
I'll be going into the cinema in detail
for how these large operations are run
and what a personal computing as well so
and Nick Fury
if you don't know me I've been doing
this for a long time I
came to the very first Carolina
governor's staff
can make the second year in spoke on
robotics
I have done some other talks so long
very array of subjects so
I if I happen to mention a company you
work for or have friends that work for
please don't get upset and cry
I don't care I it's just how it is
so I had some these companies that I
talk about I'd
I have my slant on this so the way I
view things
as the only perspective I can really
give you so nobody's paying me to do
this
I used to work for one of the companies
I mention large depressed a dinosaur
I no longer work for them I work for
completely different company
that has nothing to do what so ever with
cloud computing
or hyper skill infrastructure at all
which is fantastic
so it's a hobby I'm really good at it
though
I think I think I gotta what an
interesting insights
other people have and where you guys all
want something from
so basic outline I I put some cat
pictures throughout the presentation
they're all animated up we'll keep you
guys distracted
you do get bored with the topic it's a
little
dense at times so my plan is to educate
and inform you
talk about some key concepts so talk
about the players in this space
I I'm also going to you
talk about the pretty pictures that come
up
so and I mean a look at some attack
vectors potential
areas exploit for these large
infrastructures I'm also going to talk
about the hardware and software side
potential vulnerabilities there as well
and there's all kinds of crazy theories
so simple its why you should take this
seriously
so the cloud isn't going away and when I
say the clout by the way you're more
than welcome to turn this talking to a
drinking game
with the cloud every time it said so
hopefully your liver Suraj
I it's not going away right
this idea that somebody else has your
data the idea that somebody else is
running your company's infrastructure
its
gonna keep getting worse so it's not
going to get better
so anybody who thinks that they can put
their security jacket on and going to
meetings and go
I'm never going to let our company's day
to go anywhere other than here
it's not gonna work for you you will
lose the reason you're going to lose
because it's becoming more and more
expensive
everyday to run the infrastructure that
your company
hands so and some love you might be
working for companies were it's probably
a drop in the bucket right now
you probably don't see the power bill
justly it's going to get worse
so as a species we are using more energy
every day
then we did the previous day and it
keeps getting worse
it's not going to get better game if you
think that
BYOD is just a trend it's not
it's gonna get worse again other people
on your data
used to it so that's how this is going
so the best thing I can tell you
is to learn about what these guys are
doing with their infrastructures
and start questioning them about how
they're running their operations
because that's as much control as you're
going to have so
the yep
by the way the NSA's taken it seriously
yet another reason to so what is my
personal computing
so it's a bit of a nebulous term I
basically it's
used in the industry to define very
large data centers
I don't mean the
let's say 2008 3,000 square foot data
center
that most you probably are familiar with
I don't mean that sixteen server sitting
in a telco Iraq but shouldn't be there
in the
closet your office that's not it
a lot of the stuff can be applied to the
smaller architectures but it really
doesn't
come to you fruition into you star
a quiet too much much larger set-ups so
I wall at some point talk about china
what they're doing in your
understand the scale so
the scales massive it's huge it's a
scale-out architecture is designed for
mobile processors
lots and lots of them so it's designed
to distribute data across
as many different servers as possible
it's redundant its
highly scaleable it's geographically
independent in some cases
said if they happens so Amazon for
instance with their stuff that happens
a data center in Northern Virginia for
some reason magically
the one in New York comes online or the
10 for
I we're also going to talk about
software-defined style
so I'll this is kinda something that's
been driving me crazy lately
is this software-defined everything so
VMware in particular
a really bad about it as hyped up at all
their marketing recently
so their big thing they bought on this
era which is a software-defined
networking company
they're trying to sell it Cisco trying
to get on board to you jokingly
said they were still doing hard fine
networking which is kinda funny
Cisco's gonna there there about to lose
a lot of money in the space there and
because they haven't kept up with what
the industry's been demanding
which is cheaper shit so in general as
consumers we all want cheap stuff
so companies want the same thing a port
so its offer to find its
commodity hardware it's cheap
off-the-shelf stop it's things that are
coming from
Williams anti-war so companies like was
tryna
a service there's a handful so
I'll on top of that there putting open
source software
so putting a distribution 1x and some
variety
and on top of that their implementing
standards when API's
so in the case in software-defined
networking waters
based on OpenFlow which is the latest
and greatest products
so they're applying these open API
Stewart
so they're documenting the API said that
the API's our way it's called by
the code that everybody's right for
these things
that was our model everybody knows right
seven layers
anybody know have no prizes to give away
so anybody wants call by the way you're
more than welcome to enter a plea at any
point during this if you guys have
questions
but the bottom line is that was a lot I
was on models getting a lot more complex
branded the model still applies I'm not
telling you that it's changing
what I'm telling you is the each one of
those layers is getting lots and lots of
it all
somewheres K and it's just getting worse
so that's not necessarily bad yes
that's parker what I'm getting at with
I'll talk about that went into the
attack vectors
abouts definitely your your getting
going in the right direction I believe
so you're gonna see that as the stuff
becomes more complex you're gonna see
vulnerabilities Leichhardt mean
hardly multiply so and you're not what's
really irritating i think is that you're
not going to know about it
because as a consumer in these
technologies somebody uses Gmail
whatever you happen used up go that
matter your
not gonna see this the guys who are
running the backend infrastructure
they're the ones who have to go in and
clean up this mess and they're probably
not even aware of it
so and it's just going to get worse so
the story of love high personal
computing is really the story until
so back in the day rate Intel main RAM
chips
K the name for a barge different
manufacturers for large
mainframes essentially so back IBM
all those guys rate so Intel comes along
though
with this magical x86 actually
wasn't but they came along started
manufacturing processor
right so the star manufacturing these
things they start going in the home
personal computers
when it comes along revolts comes out
with black cherry
rights it's a these guys who are banking
on you nixon's system 5 stuff all day
long can go home
and all the sudden they're able to take
their work home with them
and start packing on the whole on their
home personal machine
K using likes what's happened over the
last
really twenty years is that
it's come full circle where now taking
those technologies
we've all been taking home and we're
bringing them back into the workplace
so x86 is now the dominant force
K intel's outlived Dec they've outlived
IBM which is pretty much the law
everything wholesale
novo at this point and they've outlived
handful of other companies as well so
create cetera
so these companies use to make
mainframes don't make em anymore sounds
pretty much dead at this point
there's probably a handful you have to
deal with spark really sorry
I if you do it's pretty much dead
whites Sun losing customers or so
for spark anyway that's paper and
everything x86 they're starting embraced
me and we're finally
despite the fact that we're as the most
nonsensical licensing requirements that
I think I've ever seen
say yet the story of my personal
computing
really the story until so it's this rise
to dominance with so
on that no the largest customers for
these guys
or companies that we've heard so I'm
gonna do is
will game again I have no privacy away
and
some cricket suckers but the pure
prehistoric from
so the I'm gonna put up a slide
you guys can tell me somebody wants to
raise a hand and tell me reported out
here what company this is
so there's a first on an easy one
anybody
net Google
so right so this is Google's
latest and greatest data center what
you're gonna notice in these pictures is
there's a unique particularly Google
with this one this one's
couple generations behind tell my guess
is probably about three where they are
currently
arm what you're gonna notice though is
there's a lack of fancy black panels
covering
hard drives & systems there's a distinct
lack
wiring for the most part there's will
itself Google
as a company is all about something
called you re
for their data centers so pues power
usage effectiveness
what they're trying to do is get this
down to a ratio one which is the ideal
fantastic ratio they're probably right
now if I had to guess at a ratio
maybe one to 1.3 what that means
is series a ratio how
how much of the energy that goes into a
data center is used for
the actual it. work versus how much in
the energy is used for things like power
and cooling
and keeping admins alive and
whatever else needs to be me run in this
dataset
game Google is super super secret but
their data center designs
so they weren't the first company that I
know I love to have production grade
software-defined networks they've been
running their data centers on on it for
a long time now
you would never know this you're not
supposed to know this this is all back
in stock free
they do a very good job hiding the
slayings there one in Intel's largest
customers
so the latest and greatest from Intel if
you guys are familiar with the
semiconductor manufacturing process the
way this works is
until turns out ships K nonstop so they
make them on waivers
maybe something called bending what that
is they take
the chips that are on there and based on
the
quantities that they need they will in
turn take
certain shit saw based on the features
that are available to them
so in the case and some dyes some other
course don't work so
all the sudden if you've got one core
that doesn't work on a six-core chip
18 taking one or two of them all off and
defuse them
are a few things that are closed and
magically its four core chip
rate turn around and sell it so if they
couldn't do that then they'd be stuck
with the forty five core chip then they
wouldn't be able to sell it for anything
they don't do that smarter so
the latest and greatest from Intel
there's a very good chance
that companies like Google are telling
Intel one instructions to put on the sea
use I is a data center and then don't
know what the hell's on my chip anymore
K and it's really hard to find now water
its
so on and it's behind DA's that Intel
will make people sign
and
even then I'm not entirely certain that
I believe everything is there
in this whole shit when the USA recently
makes me question things even more
because if they've got guys working at
Google
there's a damn good chance they've got
guys working at Intel so
I would see a
a Google one of the great things with
them you can find out what information
about them just by looking at what
contributors are meeting code wanna be
open for projects that are out there so
it's a great way to find out how
to you whole information back so we said
but often meta-data yesterday
one of the cool things I found as you
can actually go with the meta data for a
wannabe opens work projects that exist
and you can actually look at where the
contributors are coming from
which countries there summoning code
from which companies there representing
which ones are was to his personal and
you can go
reverse engineer from there you want
more and more
detailed information so Google does a
lot of white papers
you kinda have to know where to look for
you have to know the name to the people
doing
researched actually by now so
art national now Facebook
so Facebook
has started something called the Open
Compute Project
so the story for Facebook is really all
about the Open Compute initiative
basically Facebook realize they were
getting creamed by Google in this space
and they weren't doing enough research
for it so instead of trying to
buy into it which is typically their
response to most things
they went out and actually found this
initiative
on the Open Compute Project Open Compute
is a
settled hardware specifications settled
standards
that they're using to build
you were and you were generations
adequately so it's basically that
that for the first generation in this
they created an Intel based motherboard
in any in the maze motherboard
to find some stuff on the back a bit see
actually orderliness
slotted into iraq in power thing on
wei-wei instant
you rate its getting more more complex
as the time goes on they're starting to
find more standard with the
define standards for storage their
defining standards for networking
there's defining standards for
interconnects to choke you later
so I have a feeling that before too long
you're gonna see
opens for specifications report I'll
little final
air further up together not super
familiar with data centers typically
you have hollow were you're standing on
top of it anywhere from one foot above
the ground
three-year five-feet some instances its
following air underneath
it's going up in front of the servers
the servers are sucking the cold air and
on the front side it's going out the
back exhaust
hot hot air rises rate see you have
stuff in the ceiling which in turn take
certain files back into the four
and kinda crazy alice is working
so Facebook's gotten really good at this
they've done this
Open Compute Project its kinda cool I
appreciate the fact that they've
down open source thing with it I do
question if it's
entirely the right direction to go but
I'm glad that I can at least go find out
information about where their app
with their designs and I know that
Facebook in their data centers isn't too
far ahead of what the latest and
greatest
debates are on project for
so talk about china
as I've got chairman Mel clapping so
China being China stole the Open Compute
Project
from Facebook and I mean girl he stole
damn thing and rebranded as project
Scorpio
the only thing that they really added
which is
very very interesting to me years later
player
that allied
there we go so
anybody read that says asa positioning
and management with GPS
game Chinese data centers are so large
that a guy with a flashlight and a map
can't find the damn server anymore
they can just go turn a little blue
light on
to go find out where it is hey if you're
familiar with servers management concept
there's a little
Information Line on most about rate say
usual sending
management tool I am and I'd rack
I will whatever the fuck they were
calling IPMI
well I PMI's actually the standard for
interfacing to its I PMI's a bigger
industry-wide thing all the different
companies have a
web-based we had some sort for these
things that actually talk to the server
might IPMI at least as I understand it
so so yes China
took Open Compute they said this is
great
let's add more so what are they at they
added a GPS chip
everyone in the servers so think about
that for a second
this is a data center so large that can
find a server
you need GPS K
trying to buy more right
yet there's there's also I I have a
feeling
this is just some slide from some random
ass slide deck up all of our foreign
and I believe it's legitimate far as I
know missus
if you go poke around and actually try
and find information about this
Scorpio stuff it's really difficult
following on
not the least of which I don't speak
Mandarin so yet anyway
I bottom line being GPS is
a method of doing this you can actually
within a data center's by triangulating
signals
so anybody super into radios can tell
you all about you can locate
money so Nick comes to mind
how they found Raleigh callin same basic
idea
art so known now night
have any pictures him on
you think I would anybody
now on Amazon we'll talk about Amazon
Twitter no wealth
more somebody now Microsoft nope
our Walmart uses IBM so it would be a
picture about you
random black boxes so nope
Rackspace to
are we've all heard them yes so
the story Rackspace is really the story
love OpenStack
rate so how many people work with
OpenStack anybody
couple alright cool so hopefully you
guys are contributors
the fantastic projects got some
interesting implications that actually
ever manages to
going the contributors to these projects
are familiar names
its del its HP I DM its
anybody you can imagine Rackspace got
into it because they were hosting
as far as I understand it nasa stuff
nasa was doing this
nasa has abandoned ship and flown the
coop
Amazon now which is a common story oddly
enough so
open stacks kind of an alternative the
VMware and hyper-v but not really
it's not a hypervisor it's more it's
it's a lot more than that it's for the
management setup for
hypervisors but it's more than that to
because it's a management setup
for software defying things
so its kinda nebulous which is funny
is parliament's anyway it its it's out
there
so on it's very complex I will tell you
that if you have not
taken me opportunity to go woke up
OpenStack previously good
that it's a big thing it's going to
continue to be a big thing right now
until companies realize the
posting their own shit is really
expensive the nation a somebody else to
do it
which they're starting to you arm
it was designed for massively large two
points
so its based around open for sleepy eyes
and in particular its compatible with
other
API's the latest and greatest from
Rackspace is that they're looking to
your partner or bball
out I don't know how that's going to go
yet
if I were to guess I'd say age here
tells a potential
person by the mail petrol companies to
buy the mail I
if IBM had any brains at all at the sea
level
and maybe they would the don't arm
yep so that leads me to these guys
anybody and isn't blurry as hell
and if you can and Amazon so the recent
blurry as hell
because finding out anything about what
these guys are doing
has been extraordinarily difficult
Amazon
is like everybody thinks Apple's really
good at keeping secrets
you know no I promise you
from adidas their perspective it's much
easier hide stuff on Apple
that is on Amazon so
everybody else in this space is playing
catch-up these guys
Amazon did this first K this is a
company
its sole books baby
IBM a company that has been doing
computers
since the dawn of time K
you guys didn't see the
CIA lawsuit that happened during so
CIA said we need some computing
resources I'd be in stepped up to the
plate and said
yeah we got that we need government
contracts no problem amazon also stepped
up and said
we will help the L IBM lost
ID and threw a hissy fit K they got
their butts kicked in court
and way cryin' and said Amazon cheated
Amazon didn't she'd it was wrong but
they didn't K
it's a little more complex than that but
the bottom line is Amazon morning
contract Amazon now running the CIA's
using their infrastructure and
technology so
it's really really really difficult to
find information about these guys
I tried so what are the ways that I've
learned to find information about
style is not my working for direct
sources of information
but by looking into resources and
information one of the most telling is
job postings
and HR people who are more than happy to
interview just about anybody is it turns
out
so if you talk to these guys
particularly the HR people and
mention certain technologies in things
and they know to look for
they'll respond accordingly okay
do you guys use axe oh yeah I've got
that on my list
see arm when you start getting past the
first level Hren to the management level
into the folks you actually run things
they'll give you even more information
so it's a great way to find out
information about you're running for
infrastructure and
turn yeah
go apply for jobs how you might get one
process itself
I mean is crazy as it sounds like
it's what to do Blake
so again this is a hobby for me more
than anything else but
it's very interesting to me the fact
that they're willing to give away so
much to people who are potential
candidates for the company
I don't know that they realize how much
they give away
so and I'm not saying they give away not
gonna give you password
you're interviewing now K they're gonna
give you information that they would not
normally be willing
share these companies don't publish with
other companies
so very common industries for
EMC to offer a discount to some company
because
they wrote up a fantastic review in a
white paper about how they're using in
sees latest and greatest storage product
whatever reiterate
you don't see that with Amazon Amazon's
not running in sees garbage
is offering their own storage
architecture so you have to ask
questions about
what it is where they got it from
Amazon's not a storage company
not a company that sits around and makes
hard drive to rate their
sitting around paying guys to figure out
what the latest and greatest open source
technology is
that they can go to morrow in and start
contributing to that
code base so again other way to find out
information about
so Amazon as a bee eyes for just about
everything as far as I know they were
the first
on the scene with Jeep you GBG
you so general purpose graphics
processing stuff
they're basically using in video cards
allowing you access to
have API's into its even stand up an
instance in while all you can
do whatever password cracking you need
to some like they've actually got
instances specifically for that
which is really cool me on Amazon's how
deep the ice for the stuff from the
get-go
they're built around which is really
really impressive when you consider the
fact that
VMware just came out with their BC %eh
yes the VMware hybrid cloud there the
HCS hybrid cloud solutions something
like that
I basically VMware's playing catch up to
these guys and they've created a cloud
environment doesn't have the PI's
yet it's silly like I'm I want to be
able to make arrest calling creativity
and instantly I don't wanna after
see hearing click buttons for twenty
that's not what I'm
it's pointless very bad so
initially Amazon was based off apps and
they've kinda moved on from there I
think
I don't know under percent I know that
they still use it but I think they've
moved on beyond that
so they have lots and lots of different
services you need
you you need database stuff they've got
red shift now
when they've got accelerated database is
the coolest thing that I'd seen them do
by for was they said that this is how
much it costs to run
an hour CPU time so one processor equals
this much money so 7 cents for one hour
game
then they said well you've committed to
having that CPU you're not using all
that so what we're gonna do
is we're going to offer a reduced rate
for somebody who wants to come in
use the CPU that you're not using
sinners they're taking the
the leftover bit the your wasting
because you're not using it they're
charging you for the first
even though you're not using it they're
going you're not using this
I'm going to you schedule a lower
priority task in that same spot
and charged them money you and their
charge them worse but I'm gonna charge
them money
is they're making money off the waist I
can really knows that
so there in tolls largest customer by
for
so their data center growing growing and
growing
or them largely because Netflix and the
fact that all
then you watch TV shows like you
wouldn't believe
Netflix is one other big its customers
so the Fortune 500 companies are all
starting
walk to them because they're realizing
IBM and HP and Dell
have stuff in this space so they're
going to these guys
so the best part is I can take a credit
card into my pocket without any special
fancy PO numbers are trying to pretend
to be a company in having a tax ID
take the credit card online the same
place I can get toilet paper subscribe
to
I can get a fuckin server K that's
really cool
so the others idea I mean the software
they don't have anything else they kinda
just bought their way into this not that
long ago
softwares knotted show
for it is not a very good one I
there not that big either so I don't
know that they're going to grow to be
that big they know guide me in the brand
name behind him
I'm sure somebody who's playing golf
with some exact is more than happy to
sign up for the services
but year now I i mean is also sold off
everything will never know if you look
online there are pictures of softwares
data centers
they don't use Lenovo equipment K
everybody's doing it and doing it
seriously
is no I using equipment from years
from companies like Dell like HP
him over lever they're not buying
servers like that anymore
they're buying servers by literally
the Creek fall from places in Taiwan
K there they're going overseas they're
saying hey
would you mind taking this Intel chip
that we've got that we worked out with
Intel you're gonna put into the server
for as
in just using their standard
specifications in creating a motherboard
and
putting it on here in San it back to us
in it that's in our racks
all they want K server gets there they
booted up in the
however they're bringing it up most the
time it Dixie now
there running things of the network I
think handful might be using Flash
locally on the system
attaching other lawyer words but I doubt
it I don't know why your local
us so anyway that's what these guys are
doing
so Microsoft as their Microsoft Azure
unless you're running exchanger office
I don't know why news on I guess you
want to put your domain controller Alan
and you can laugh but this is what
people will do so
they're starting to do so. stuff anybody
play with the SSO
Michael so it interesting
I Microsoft is putting that into you is
your as well
so Apple Apple's a little interesting
there's a lot of speculation that they
actually might be using Amazon
and they might be using sure involve
other services
I can for certain tell you that you xoxo
my for damn near everything
so anybody ever elected traffic from
iTunes
Marchar yet bounces off Marcum I goes
all over the damn place
I Apple built some fancy data centers
2011 North Carolina particular a
they've built these data centers but the
speculation is that they're probably not
really using there have been after
bill basically the time period when you
would expect to see trucks for equipment
rolling in
nobody's seen in trucks rolling so
handful here and there
and it's possible there is still
building out here some service that's
coming
me whatever whatever the new I which is
that they needed some
offer some service for but as of right
now nobody
reported a large amount of trucks moving
equipment out of this thing
so I don't know what I am
do what the
lenore area so
I can't tell you the square foot into
the days are in love to be able to I
can't tell you exactly how to make any
other stuff is it's really hard to find
this information
turns out they don't want the stuff
getting out so it affects
their numbers so Amazon by the way
doesn't very interesting
thing Amazon doesn't report the exact
amount of money
for how much they make awful ec2
so they they put it in the other column
so when they purport their
revenue numbers game because they have
to a quarterly numbers
they going to report them and they say
we made as much money and they break it
out based on services
their retail industry and some other
things and then they have this column
called other
mysteriously that other column keeps
getting bigger and bigger screen
here and so and we all know what it is
like everybody knows that
like everybody's really interested in it
to hell because its turns out there
on this really well and people are
starting to pay attention so
via its it's listed as other same thing
with Microsoft I don't know that they
report exactly how much revenue
generating office
so not big
it's not massive right now so everybody
doing this in
it's serious about it is moving Amazon
so I'm not saying about the right answer
I'm just telling you that's what the
industry doing yes
sure
it does it's using their services on the
back and so I don't know
enough about their special nonsense
so at the other so my point my
counterpoint to that would be the
PlayStation 4 is massively outsole
the ex parte 1 reno and continues to so
its there's I don't know that the demand
is there for Microsoft Services yet
if they can get the so the problem they
have and the problem everybody's got
with the space everybody's trying to
play catch-up Amazon right
so go look to read the news stories in
fact I'll tell you exactly what you can
search for in the boonies
go work for Amazon ec2 and then
the word its price reduction over the
last year and is on her knees prices
probably six times and they keep doing
it and the reason they're able to do
this is because the key buying more and
more shit
reducing the cost them what it takes for
ended one individual
instance to run so the more times you
can do that
the the more scale you can add the the
better your
able to take advantage in the economy of
scale K where you can go
you know what we've got fifty billion at
these one of them doesn't cost that much
so they can reduce the cost everybody
else is playing catch-up to this
because they can't get to that price
point so they need to go
way out either way and do what Google is
doing via the PC
anything trying to figure out how you
can get every last possible
energy wasting mechanism out of your
datacenter
and fix it said that you don't have any
energy that's wasted everything you have
in your data center is going to
it. awaited options so it's going to
you were overall mission who was
actually trying to do this and we're
doing pretty well with their
cue injured I think
so yet they
they do its computer engine is a commune
in
I does the name sorry so there's so many
of these names they all they all get
sort of
cloudy marine a see a
I i can tell you for certain Apple does
use a lot of that out
they have habitat hiring former IBM
employees
and a seem to have some interesting
CloudStack based on code
commissions yet are
fair enough
and so the Google Data Center here the
one in north carolina i think is
probably a generation behind the latest
and greatest from Google
I had yes so it hasn't seen any updates
recently
I'm aware of if you guys want to
this information I think one of the more
interesting facts you can find out
what's a lot of stuff about this
just by knowing through the
area and location around the data center
and what they're doing
so the local news and local commentary
from
from people in those areas is always
good yes yep
yep
allow yet
yep yep
they are they don't like to talk about
this stuff
so it's really really hard to find out
about it see a
the Apple also there a lot of custom
stuff
and they're really smart and their
super-secret the people who work for
more
all fairly brilliant when it comes to
doing these things they're submitting
code
patches to very low level
low-level applications
so their submissions turn up and a lot
of
the the work goes into the XE stacked so
X 31 X it's shown up in some other
interesting locations to you
so let's talk about the NSA
and all others yes they can hear you now
yes
I don't worry about backups I got you
covered
so they know why kids love cinnamon
toast crunch
and share everything plan watching you
who and were soon might be too are
actually listening T
care now so the NSA is involved in this
somehow I don't know it has not come to
light yet so the latest and greatest
that i've seen
was the news that came out earlier this
week I
about the Cisco switches
routers basically they have a location
where
these guys from the NSA wall hijackers
Cisco router in
on its way to some foreign country they
take the Cisco router out on the Cisco
factory sealed box
figured out how to cleverly open in put
a put a new Cisco label on it
rate because I'm sure Cisco's not given
arm
and put some custom stuff on there and
in turn it back to them
if they can do this then
I'm just gonna go ahead and guess they
probably have
people at places like Intel
I'm willing to bet that they probably
have places and somebody Orleans
anti-war and
I'm willing to bet that bear getting
involved a
lower-level what we know so the stuff we
know about is what's come the white so
far
I guarantee you their stuff we don't
know about its kinda creepy
on that note I'm still using email from
my
sorry Lisa K give it up too hard
I don't know I
that well that's an interest so he did
his poignant like fart for
work local manufacturing spiked by Chip
here for national
yearly yeah I don't know a I know that I
i don't know what China is doing either
so China they were
they were talking about china has also
been
talking about fracturing of from the US
for a long time creating your own see
use all this other nonsense they get to
do it kinda
kinda Cebu's are made worldwide now
so the should that happen to compare my
remember couple years ago or drive
prices went through the roof
so yes because of flooding one part in
the world
the air so that for all the hard drives
are made
yes when Intel realize a long time ago
right Intel had some smart people
working for their
that the sea level right more like you
know what we should really split up for
operations across the world
did so ships on come from one spot
morning all
yep No
so met talk about attack vectors on
some and with you definitely this is
good stuff snow
new again it to me in my mind it's
what the hell are these guys actually
doing because this is just the stuff we
know so
attack vectors if I were looking to
break into a data center
and looking to get involved with these
things I would start looking at the
developers
I'd start looking at where the code
contributions are going and I'm trying
to insert style:
that might be slightly areas and those
sources
so observe fairly open place there's all
kinds of interesting projects that are
going on
figuring out listening them not that
difficult I will tell you
Apple pierre Yves very cleverly doesn't
allow their employees to Sonic
code under the Apple very rarely anyway
they will either come employees to send
the code under the Apple
with your Apple email addresses so the
user in the water systems
so finding those employees is difficult
finding their contributions is also
difficult
so we don't know turns out anyway
a you can also talk to control point
which is where really the
entering code comes from so what is
environments have sort of two levels
so there's a level where all the data
actually is and there's the control
point so particularly what's offered by
networking
definitely a control point you have to
can avoid
I if you wilke at
that area I think that that is going to
be the most vulnerable spot
where you can insert potential abilities
where you can look for potential
normally attacking the hardware again
goes back to Los talking about Nina se
attacked the developers
on I guarantee you'd anybody in this
room read the Intel CPU around as they
come out
measures bill so see a
the CPU around as they come out theater
out like the bitch about if you guys
know
yes his no use
though head guy for one yes the here
which one for years whichever one
OpenBSD
there we go the 1i didn't name so I am
so the likes to complain about it he's
made a couple very very public pose
shaming Intel
until still makes crappy products that
have security vulnerabilities
attack something with the fuckin CPU G
see i can tell you what all the
instructions are on a CPU
these days there's so many and the
instruction sets keep getting
their added to you bit by bit so the
same thing
ran in the machines I if you have
systems that have
more RAM the nation problem we have
because they're not based on Intel
reference design
and you've got a six probably chances
are you've got a six anyway
a sixer ships that are manufactured for
companies like
HP Dell to put in the systems are custom
chips
so they allow the system to do something
unique and interesting fundamentally
different than the other
guy not really well as he sees the
memory checking for RAM
so yes you do it's not a sick though
because there's enough manufacture I
wouldn't I get sick is
I don't know I don't know where you draw
the line between sure there are some
technical
explanation we draw the line between a
second chip
I see by its to me
news again IPCC's there so many of them
but it's a great spot to start looking
for ability
potentially other controllers for any
other stuff
I'd start licking abilities their nope
potentially the Open Compute Project
they're using open source firmware I the
open source for
movement never really picked up that I
know of
so there's not really an open source by
its implementation all the vendors are
using
on but that being said the buyers the
firmware most it comes from the same
Orleans anti-one so yeah I potentially
go work there
and try and figure out what our
abilities if they're always here I'm
sure
back me up on that and say that that's
probably a fairly vulnerable spot
he's done a little better research in
things yes
yeah I am I
I know American megatrends there's a lot
about stuff I know they pop up all over
the place
so their research that i've done I don't
know
I'd be curious to see how many
vulnerabilities they publisher if they
publish anything at all or if anybody
publishes stuff for them
so I don't know so more intact vector
is the data itself so all these my
personal infrastructures
are based around the idea that there's a
massive data set that their crunching
so there's a lot more to numbers so you
can poison the dataset
so it's fasting can be fairly effective
and I know
gotta five minutes left so have my own
on c8 consumer surveys medical trials
burning data as more and more that
should give put out there
expected I mean I think people are gonna
start looking at the data rather
because it's easy rather than trying to
attack the actual
underlying infrastructure
so I suspect that's going to get more
more complex to do and
the skill set for doing it's going to
come or more specialized so as for
preventing attacks if you happen to work
for one of these companies
so things I will tell you a hard outer
shell the soft squishy center done work
anymore
K you so you have to protect
everything all-points communication must
be secured
so I don't know that that necessarily
means sooo anymore
I'd be very curious to see what's coming
along
soon to potentially replace SSL
Sydney there's a better
for me secure communication so and I
suspect these guys are working on this
for their data centers so you need to
verify the data
you gotta control all your control
points such that they're redundant
their independent yarder so there do you
separate it so that it once I get hit
still got something come up in sites so
the future
where things are going it's just gonna
get more dense so
Morsi using it crammed into a smaller
and smaller space so
Google's going to continue pushing Hwy
21.0 I suspect
if they are already at they are think
they're very very close though
I you're gonna start see more CPU types
arm has now come up
a lot smarter people were doing
development for phones and
no arm they don't necessarily fully
understand it but
your it's also come about the Uni
you have arms reviews available clouds
people can magically create developer
instances out
great yeah tenia Maria
Titanic on thank God they finally
about %ah anyway I it's going to be easy
easily switchable between Cebu types RAM
types
to get to that second things are going
to be interchangeable
so you're gonna start to see software
that's based around
typically Control Point Software is
gonna start do you what Google's been
doing with ads
and continues to do with YouTube videos
google has machine vision
processing that they've created that
literally just goes in crawls YouTube
for videos and descriptions and comments
and proceeds to compile all that data
and they don't
understand how this works they just know
that it works in the use it with google
translate as well
so basically every time you go to a site
with your trains Lee it's getting better
and better translating
be a so the new site potentially or its
new data and you can
up to select things and correct them
daughter whatever every time you do that
you're giving them more information
so Nikki buildings database of patterns
they don't know how this works
K I'm not joking like nobody like they
understand there's a pattern rate but
the
the pattern is generated by a computer
we don't understand what the pattern is
so it's just getting smarter and smarter
I'm not telling you that's going it's
coming maybe it is I have no idea
but 1 I'm telling you is the this is
going to get applied to
software-defined networks and going to
be applied so that if Traffic needs to
go somewhere it's gonna go there based
on
the the fact that it seem that sort of
traffic $17 billion times before
and so therefore it knows what to do
with it so that the warning patterns are
going to be applied
the setup same thing for virtualization
virtualized workloads and everything
else
so you're gonna see that stuff get
smarter and smarter all
little which is kinda cool intel has
this fantastic playing they're calling
the disaggregated rack
which is a call there so
basically there going back to bleeds
and if anybody's ever done work on
points and other stuff
you typically have a box it's like an 09
u11 you hire Achary
imagine if you had a 42u rack filled
with these things itself like believes
that having closures made of metal and
everything else he just had a circuit
board
K that's what the building on the
backend
you're starting to see fabrics converge
they're converging around PCIe is the
fancy standard
so its basically they're taking all the
work the infinite mana group has been
doing in there
in basically moving at one level lower
you level
it it makes it sad that you only have
one switch at the top iraq to get
plugged in
so you bring in Iraq war stop so
there's more on this so intel's doing a
lot of work for %ah picturing L
so I'll talk about this I these guys
right now they're talking about my
cursor vers particularly I don't know
why
pointless I a micro server is just a
server but
right now because they just started
doing this there judge me
they can't figure out a criminal ramen
listening to make it useful
so they're selling on the company's who
think they need lots and lots a little
tiny servers
I guess maybe some people workloads I
don't know
arm it
here anyway arm that's a tiny is one
computer
at the scale it's a little different in
my opinion arm
yet so intel's starting this all these
things kinda they're starting
no right now in these actually the one
that selling the microserver they bought
a company called see my group primarily
for their
technology interconnects so which that's
the next big area
research so right now interconnect
between stop it slow it error-prone
anybody has had to deal with
cleaning fiber optic cabling pain in the
ass free
so I hope so many as not alone in that
regard
so intel has literally redefined what a
fiber optic cable is
that things got I don't know 64 or 128
fiber connections inside a bit and
they're starting to use it
transfer PCIe over large distances yeah
I think my time is up
so I the blink sign in
arm see a the
its continuing to grow interconnector by
far the most interesting thing
I think bringing so micro servers
there's lotsa lotsa
tiny tiny servers putting on ships kills
it was a company was doing this for the
warm
they've gone bust now I don't know if
they actually managed to solve all their
assets to some money or not had a lot of
energy
interesting intellectual property I
don't know that they sold the law
the biggest problem they faced with that
army isn't
64-bit today Munich is nobody's got a
real 64-bit ARM chip out there coming
will be out within the next six months
that was by for calls it his biggest
problem
in the C my crew again so they started
to produce ARM chips to
which technical as a
so in with my Arthur C Clarke
as any sufficiently advanced technology
is indistinguishable from magic see if
you don't know how this shit works
you think the cloud is magic it's not
pictures using the same stuff
user home in applying it in a much much
more scale
right area that
thank you