welcome hackers to activity con 2021
hacker one's hacker educational
conference built by hackers for hackers
give me a shout out in the chat where
are you tuning in from in the world i
want to know i want to hear from you i
want to see the excitement
through these virtual walls which we get
to experience this conference together
my name is luke tucker i'm the vice
president of community at hackerone and
i have the privilege of opening up our
conference and welcoming you to the main
stage we've got a ton in store today
before we get into all the things today
i want to a continue to see that
excitement in the chat loving the energy
keep keep it coming the speakers uh the
hamsek during the hosting he's going to
feed off of that energy so really just
reach through the camera lens uh reach
into our twitter stream uh chat with us
we want to hear from you
together we hit harder
for those who know hacker one who follow
the hashtag this slogan
based off of our mission at hack1 to
make the internet safer together
security is better together we can make
a bigger impact when we collaborate when
we share when we coordinate disclosure
when we hack
and hackers you have collectively earned
over 60 million dollars through the hack
one platform since activity con 2020
and i want all of you to continue to
look at hack one as the land of
opportunity we're going to have talks
today and conference material that's
going to help you further your career
that's going to help you learn about
tools and tactics to improve your bounty
hunting and earn more cash
to improve your overall quality of life
your communication skills in the last
year we've had over half a dozen live
hacking events we've launched 20 plus
ctfs and many videos on hacker 101 to
help
achieve our mission as a community team
to be the number one source for
education support and financial
opportunity we also got to sponsor an
incredible team in perfect blue
number one team on ctftime.org currently
at the defcon ctf competition
definitely check out the socials follow
them congratulations to jazzy and the
entire perfect blues folks we have been
honored to sponsor you at that
conference
now
last year at activitycon we welcomed
thousands of you we had an incredible
ctf even had some social ctf stuff
hidden on our google maps and in
different nested areas on hacka1.com you
got to explore and experience that at
all levels of technicality through the
ctf and we're bringing the a game again
this year i know many of you have
participated um we have the winners that
are going to be announced on stage later
today thank you to ctf fire and john
hammond and his team for creating that
send him your love and your hate mail if
you will for the ctf
but
remember last year at the beginning we
actually got to watch the hamsek talk to
himself for about five minutes straight
when he was muted
so
let me hear it from my no homies let me
hear it from everybody in the chat uh
tell ben how much you love him how great
he's going to do today as our hostess
with the mostest
and i want to talk about a little bit
the speakers so i'm going to refer to my
notes here but right here on this main
stage we're going to hear from vickie
lee we're going to hear from shubs we're
going to hear from she networks we're
going to have some awesome panelists
getting new tools to help you earn more
bounties career and certification advice
we're going to break down offensive
security certs we're going to invest in
your mental health and give you some
tips and material to help that whole
self aspect
of you as a hacker and you as an
individual and a human on this amazing
planet
let me know
what are you most excited about what are
you going to be doing at two o'clock
pacific time today
are you going to be at the main agenda
here on the main stage or
guess what we've got some incredible
villages so let me talk about them
why villages at first so when we set out
to create one of the best virtual hacker
experiences and educational conferences
we reflected on what we love about a
devcon environment the villages just
create this excitement and and these
these niche groups that we all get to
see each other and hang out in that core
group but also the lobby con aspect so
we wanted to replicate that in a couple
ways
you're going to want to go to hacker101
discord and that's going to be like your
lobby that's going to be the area where
you're going to be in between talks or
checking out talking about ctf or going
to iot labs and seeing what they're up
to you can pop in and out the experience
is meant to be dynamic for you and you
can write your own story today
the villages we have in store include
red team village an incredible lineup of
content hack the box bring in their a
game awesome material they got set up
bug bounty talks hacktivitycon in
espanol we are
multilingual here thank you ariel garcia
for producing that it's got some
incredible presenters already lined up
iot village going to be doing some
awesome career work some awesome iot
hacking definitely jump in that village
and join them some really hands-on stuff
you're going to get to experience in
addition to the incredible main stage in
store at this and by the way for the
villages make sure and check out github
security lab team at the red team
village
now
that's the full con experience and none
of this is possible without the sponsors
we work with and they're not providing a
bunch of financial support we want to
make this available to you we want
always to be free and valuable but
they've brought some incredible swag and
tools and giveaways that they'll be
coming to you throughout this event so
keep an eye out to the chat
stay engaged you know keep that ear out
for twitter wherever you're going to see
some potential raffles or giveaways the
hamster is going to give you the scoop
thank you to no starch press hack the
box get github security labs red team
village iot village
offensive security all providing swag
and stuff i believe there's more at the
activity con in espanol village as well
for our ctf winners who here i want to
hear in the chat anybody who got to
experience the ctf have i hear from any
ctfers do i have any perfect blowers or
red poners or plaid parliament of pwning
or open to all if you're all here let us
know definitely give a shout out to your
tribe and your group want to hear from
you
40 plus levels in this year's activity
con ctf 5 000
in cash prizes for the top three teams
created by ctf for hire and sir john
hammond congrats john you have now been
knighted
and uh send again all your love and hate
mail whatever it might be to
john at i'm kidding
well reach out to him on twitter thank
him give him a high five we we
appreciate the hard work for ctf hire
team
and john now any conference that we want
to do where it's going to be some
surprises up our sleeves
and if anybody's been watching and
following on the twitter sphere you'll
have seen us at hacker1 and hack the box
teasing something big something exciting
and that's going to be announced here on
this stage right here
fairly soon so stay tuned
i cannot tell you how excited i am for
that amazing platform and hack the box
what they've created and how we're going
to partner to create some
incredible opportunities for you hackers
we want to be
a
bevy of educational content served up to
you and hack the box is one of the best
so we're very excited for you to see
what we've got in store we have even
more giveaways
all of our sponsors we reference they're
going to be serving up some incredible
goodies and by the way one more thing we
got a a certain teaser a certain highly
requested feature
that has been asked for in the hack one
product experience for some time i'm not
gonna give it away but stay tuned as
well for our chief product officer at
hakka one rand and some special guests
to give you some incredible news on that
in the past year
hackard has grown and the world has
changed
you all have lived through a pandemic
and are currently
living through it in this new normal
i encourage you uh to encourage others
i give a presentation at the hackard all
hands earlier this year about how
you can live your best life in 2021 with
seven life tips from hackers so check
that out live by those principles thank
you to stoke
and all the hackers that created that
content for us to enjoy
good reminders now i have the privilege
to wrap up my opening remarks and bring
to the stage
an incredible hacker and an incredible
content creator in vicky lee
now i remember first seeing vicky lee
come on to the bug bounty space come on
to the
red team apsec
content
queen
you're dropping some incredible long
form blogs that really walk through
topics that are not easy to describe but
she broke it down she wrote it out i
really give her
so much credit and that's just been such
a pleasure to see her growth to see
her take that library of content and
turn it into a book which is coming soon
definitely hear from vicki on that and
thank you to no starch press for maybe
some giveaways some discounts on some
incredible bundles including um that
special book from vicki so vikki's going
to be talking to us about launching a
career in infosec
please chat
raise your emojis give a standing
ovation and applause
to our keynote speaker for activity con
vicky lee