alright everybody we are back and we are
just about ready to bring in our next
speaker so our next speaker is andreas
fault
and he is a managing consulting managing
consultant excuse me for Nova tech
consulting so andreas good to have you
with us how are you oh I'm fine things
how are you there we go I am doing well
thank you so you're gonna tell us about
some of the basics with oauth2 yes and
open ID connect awesome well with that I
will bring in your screen and we will
send you on your way
thank you very much remember folks enter
your questions into the Q&A panel and at
the end of Andreas's talk we'll have
time to cover those questions all right
with that address it's all yours yeah
thank you very much so so so welcome to
my talk and it should see my slides now
okay we are talking about basics of our
to and open IT connect
so about me I'm andreas as already
mentioned I am from Germany located at
stood cuts working for a company called
neurotic consulting I'm also on Twitter
where you can contact me and and we also
offer some some epic offerings like to
open a to connect trainings and
consulting and also security for
developers trainings so that's all for
my side so we have much to do and today
so I will start with an introduction to
o out - so our - is basically defined by
- RFC's which stands for request for
comments and I see six seven six six
seven four nine or six seven five zero
are the basic ones
for all too so if you hurt maybe of or
two you may ask yourself why do we
really need our to and opener to connect
so the first question would be do you
really like implementing your own
authentication so you're implementing
your own authentication it's really hard
so you have to deal with different
clients like mobile clients like web
clients maybe some devices you have to
implement password policies so that
people don't use just short passwords
maybe you also have to introduce
multi-factor authentication you have to
deal with secure password storage with
dealing with crypto like like different
hashing algorithms which one is safe
which one is not also with other flows
reset password stuff around it so reset
passwords password questions and all
that stuff also brute force prevention
is a big thing so so lots of stuff to do
around a login which seems to be simple
but you can do so many things really
wrong and so it's not fun implementing
your own authentication and even even
it's not much fun if you want to do that
in multiple way locations like for
example in micro service architectures
in micro service architectures you have
to do that in for several times so you
have several servers in place and for
all these servers you have to implement
the same authentication again and again
and also your credentials flow to your
clients flow to the resource server so
they are spread everywhere these
credentials and every resource server
has to deal with password storage with
the same mechanisms again and again so
you implement it multiple times and in
one resource server may be more secure
than the other one for example so that's
a big issue especially for Mike
servus I texture nowadays we have
multiple resource servers in place so
that's the case for our to wear these
sneaks in so this sentence is basically
from the spec of IRC six seven four nine
so it's about what 2.0 I mean it tells
that the authorization framework enables
a third party application to obtain
limited access to an HTTP service either
on behalf of a resource server or on its
own behalf and so the important things
are the third-party applications also
another application like another client
and you can give this client limited
access and on behalf of a resource
server the resource L owner is typically
the user that is sitting in front of the
computer and so that's the main idea of
r2
um so maybe our two brings in a new
component called the authorization
server so we already had a resource
owner the clients we have to resell
server now we also have the
authorization server and we don't deal
with passwords anymore in that new world
we only deal with access tokens now so
and the only location where you deal
with credentials now is only the
authorization server only the
authorization server knows all the
credentials the passwords that the user
names and all that stuff so the resource
server the client and the resource owner
do not have to care about dealing with
that their to passwords anymore so they
just have an access token to access the
resource server instead so this is a
really basic protocol flow of our to the
first step is always better resource
owner authorizes the clients to use some
some data of the resource or not I'm
like his email address for example
for this the recess owner thank you sir
typically authenticates at the
authorization server at the first place
and then that what is called the
authorization grant is kicked off so we
will see that step by step now
so the first step you may be recognized
that you often have already used or our
- without even noticing that it is Oda
or - actually so so typically you do try
to log in to get out for example with
some demo github client as seen here on
the left then you have to log in give
username and passwords to get up that
the second screen you notice is also a
big benefit of using or - already you
get usually the two-factor
authentication for free if we use our -
authorization service yet the usual
implementation and bring in the - or
factor authentication by default like
github so you can use AUP key for
example as a second factor as seen here
you just use that and then you come to
the final step of our - you have to
confirm the consent page on that page
you can still deny access to the client
for your data or you can just prove that
it's okay that the client uses your
notification data or some personal user
data of yours and if that is fine you
can improve that and then you can just
use the application so that's the basic
basics of the first step to authorize
the client in or - so next step would be
that the client receives what is called
an authorization grant authorization
plant is the proof
while the authorization server that
Theresa's owner has authorized the
client correctly to use his data and an
authorization grant can be different
things so that's the most interesting
part of our - especially from the client
side
so it's typically credential
representing the resource owners
authorization and this is typically then
exchanged for an access token in the
next step and we come to the
authorization grant types in some
minutes and if you have this
authorization grant and the clients can
exchange this authorization grant to an
access token also wire the authorization
server on the right hand side you can
see the response of that authorization
server so what you get back is typically
an access token of token Triborough so
that's also standard with some expiry
times or so one hour for example and
your what you also get is a refresh
token um a refresh token is used to
always get a new access token if the
access token is expired so imagine that
the user the user experience will would
be really bad if you have to have to
login every five minutes because the
access token is expired and the Refresh
token deals to improve that user
experience in that way that if the
access token is expired you can use the
Refresh token to send it or or Tracy
authorization server and just exchange
the Refresh token to a fresh access
token again you never can access a
resource server if using the Refresh
token that's only used for exchanging
into a new access token if you have the
access token then on the final step the
client can request the protected
resource at a resource server which is
called a tobira token put in the
authorization header which is just a
normal HTTP header that has to be
transmitted to the resource server and
after transmitting that bearer token in
the header you can access what is the
protected resource
as I've mentioned the authorization
server is the central part here or our
two defines three different protocol
endpoints that are provided usually by
an authorization server you have the
authorization endpoint which deals with
all that authorization stuff with
authorization grants handling and this
typically only deals with the resource
owner directly so no client interaction
is involved here so no client will ever
see username passwords and stuff like
that so that's the target of that
authorization endpoint when you exchange
the grants into a token that's done by
the token endpoint of the authorization
server and the third one is it called
token introspection endpoint this
endpoint deals to validate access tokens
that are issued by the authorization
server so you can always validate sense
the X is talking to that endpoint and
check if that token is still well it so
I talked about the authorization grant
Ives for this I will just get back to
some odd history so oh I initially
started already in the year 2007 when
odd version 1.0 was introduced it was
then finally released as IFC in year
2010 as revision a because they already
detected some security problems in the
original specification and two years
later or out 2.0 already was introduced
because what one had some really nasty
drop back so it was used for for cases
where it was never intended for us also
r2 was invented to improved it a year
back later we already got the fret motor
for our two with new security
remediations 2015 was introduction of
the
web talk which we'll be talking about in
some minutes 2015 we got to prove key
for code exchange we will also talk
about it in some minutes and the most
important part now which deals with the
authorization grants now the next slide
is the security best current practice
which just was started last year and is
in the final steps of specification this
weeks now and also we will see a new
allowed 2.1 specification coming out
later this year and so that our 2.1
authorization framework specification
which is currently worked on really hard
will bring some really important changes
to or 2 so our terrorization code grants
will be extended by what is called pixie
proof key for kody exchange we will come
to that in the next slide the implicit
grant where you may know that this is
used for for the single page application
so far will be omitted from the spec
because the implicit flow is regarded as
the dangerous flow
nowadays and should not be used anymore
also the resource owner password
credentials grant will be omitted from
the spec so so the password credentials
grant contradicts all the targets of our
tool basically so it's it's the same
flow as before all the credentials flow
to each client with that flow and this
is really bad so it's omitted from the
spec and also redirect you or your eyes
must be compared now by exact string
matching there was lots of attacks going
on on to by allowing wildcards and
redirect your eyes which is always a bad
idea also refresh tokens should either
be Center constraint it by by a mutual
TLS for example all should should be
one-time usage only suits who also
reduced attack surface and also pure
tokens must not be sent in the query
string of you
anymore you can read all that in the new
spec that is coming up I have put all
the links in the slides will be shared
later so this brings us to the new
authorization grant as of or our 2.1 for
each line type except that klein cretons
blind Teresa's owner client we have the
same authorization grant so that's quite
simple now for all typical clients where
user interaction is involved where the
user has to type in username password
and stuff like that
always use authorization code plus that
pixie edition and there you can also
reuse refresh tokens with restriction
that they are only usable for one time
there's a special client type called the
resource owner client where you
typically have the client s resource
owners also no user interaction involved
this is used for machines and machine
communications then you have to use the
client cadenzas authorization so you
only have two different authorization
grants now authorization code with pixie
and client code engines so that pixie
stuff is an addition to the
authorization code flow and that's
because public clients like for example
single page application which runs in
the browser cannot hide static secrets
so imagine you have the client secret
which is required by the authorization
code flow originally stored somewhere on
your JavaScript code and the browser
everybody could just wrap the client
secret so it's not safe anymore and that
proof key for code exchange just changes
that it adds a dynamic secret instead
instead of the static secret so you
cannot grab the secret anymore
it's just regenerated for each request
in a new way so every client has to
create a random key that called a code
verifier
and when requesting the authorization
from the authorization server it has to
hash that coat very far we shot 256
which is called the code challenge send
that together with with all the stuff
that is used to get a authorization code
and then when exchanging the
authorization code to an access token
then you have to present the original
code verifier and authorization server
just rehashes the code verifier and
checks if it has the same code
challenged and for the first request to
show basically how the authorization
code flow basically works I have some
small demo prepared um mmm
I hope you can see that I have a typical
or 2.0 client the first step would be to
initiate your authorization request to
the authorization server so if I have in
it just click that button to initiate an
authorization request what you now see
is that we get redirected through the
authorization server which is a keyed
lock in that example now just login into
that server and what I get back now is
that authorization code so you typically
won't see this step in usual application
so usual applications do that in one
rush to get an authorization code back
and then they exchange it in the next
step
already into an access tool in that demo
client we can see it authorization code
it's a really long random string and the
important stuff here as well is that it
only has is valid for two minutes
exactly so because it's always done in
one rush the authorization codes can
have a really short lifetime so in the
next step I just regress the token and
what I get back is the access token in
that case it's a JSON web token
so so these are typical that these three
steps which we have the authorization
step arrghh and then that we get back to
code and exchange that to a tote so that
was basically allowed to r2 in fact it's
not an authentication protocol and as
always a lot of confusion going on by
people misusing or r2 as an
authentication protocol r2 does not
specify anything to use for
identification of an user so typically
or r2 has no jason vector defined so
JSON web tokens come into play with
almighty connect almighty connects
started to to make jason web tokens
mandatory as ID talks so I have a sample
prepared to to differentiate or two to
open ID connect so all our two is
typically compared to two what we call
the valid parking model in the US and
you have a famished delegation you just
give your car key to a the servant that
parks your car for just one reason to
park your car so with a limited
permission he cannot go on holiday with
your car or to his own things with your
car that's not allowed and the second
case is open ID Connect so if you try to
check-in in some hotel usually you have
to show your identifications so it's not
sufficient to give the car key to your
that hotel registration to check-in so
that's typically an open ID connect
model for authentication and automatic
Connect is based on our two
authorization framework which makes it
really important to understand or to
basically and but it brings also into
the table that JavaScript object signing
and encryption stuff like JSON web
tokens like the JSON web signature to
sign a JSON web token or JSON web keys
to get a public key to validate signed
to chasten that talks for example and so
what brings open ID connects so it's
based on or to actually it bring has the
same flows the authorization code club
if that pixie stuff for example or the
client credentials flow and the most
important thing now what is edit is the
ID token this token holds all the
identity information of a user I mean
and it's only to be used by the client
side never sent ID talking studio
beckons you still get an access token in
addition to the ID token that is sent to
the backends what you also get is the
user end for endpoint so instead of
putting all the stuff in the ID token
you can you may also just use your
access token and ask the user info
endpoint about identity information we
also have a hybrid grant flow
introduced by up mighty connect which is
basically a shortcut to the
authorization code flow so you get the
identity the ID token back without
further redirection and the access token
gets back with the redirected flow and
you also have an open ID provider
configuration information to look up all
the configuration parameters you need to
configure at line four of my reconnect
so this is typically a JSON web token it
says type JWT
he has a key ID to to look up the
correct public public key to validate
such talking because typical JSON web
token should also hold a signature to
verify that the token is issued by the
correct authorization server and nobody
has changed the token in between the
authorization server issuing and the
resource server and you typically have
some some entries like a subject which
is the unique identification of a user
audience and issuer for example the
expiration dates issued at time for
example and much more you can basically
everything in the payload of such
adjacent backtalk you need like
authorization information email
addresses first name last name and or
what else in up mighty connect and also
into r2 you can basically use two types
of tokens for access token so ID tokens
are always chasing web tokens but for
access token you can also use reference
tokens or you might use JSON web tokens
but a good thing for for JSON web tokens
are that you can be validated offline so
you don't have to contact the
authorization server again the opaque
token always needs the authorization
server to be validated um also a good
advantage for JSON web tokens they are
not protocol agnostic so so you can even
send a JSON web token to some-some BPM
process engine or you can send it to to
to Kafka or what else that's not
possible for packet ohms because they
always have to be validated or HTTP
somehow so that brings us already to the
last page to dirty up my reconnect or to
summary so always use Open ID Connect if
you want to achieve authentication not
only the delegated permission model of
or - so with with an end user always use
authorization code flow with that pixie
edition without an end user in place
before machine to machine communication
used language in Seussville do not use
implicit or whistles or no password
grunts anymore it's not advised to use
these anymore
ID tongs must must be Jason web talks
access tokens may be JSON web tokens and
all also important always validate
tokens and keep their lifetime really
short so access tokens typically only
have a lifetime of five minutes so thank
you very much so you have any questions
Thank You Andrea so yeah we've got a few
minutes for questions we've got a couple
here
four scenarios where a redirect is not
an option what's the answer from the new
spec if they remove the resource owner
password credentials grant yes that's a
big issue yes that depends also if you
need a user integer into place if you
have a machine to machine communication
then just use the language engine so
that does not need any redirection so
but typically you can only use
authorization code flow an hour these
days so which has two redirects or so
that's the bad thing it depends on what
client you actually want to use for for
that or two things also if you have a
really old legacy system then if you can
take the risk you may still use the
password credentials flow but that's the
only really the only exception to use it
okay another question that came in from
a pen testers point of view what are
some of the different test cases or
attacks we can perform to test off and
open ID implementations oh that's really
hot and regular master classes right yes
so the spec groups itself did a really
great job to to to do automatic
verification models for checking if the
our two model is secure and so that's
done pretty much these days so they want
to make sure that the next iteration of
our 2.1 is not becoming insecure in two
more months again so that's why they put
in an automatic verification model
already in place maybe go to it at
especially it's like like Daniel fete
for example which is a German guy which
is very nice we did all that model stuff
and you can ask him for example so just
contact Daniel Fett for example he's
also on Twitter
okay and I know - you mentioned the
threat model before that's out there I
think just that might be a good option
for people to take a look at that threat
model - and I may give you some ideas
from a pen testing perspective where you
want to look yes the doctor better
option is that that new security best
practice mod documentation that they put
out awesome another question this one
comes from slack hey Andreas where
should the refresh token be stored it
should not be on the client right
because if so I can see a need for an
access took or no need for an access
token at all if I have both am I not
seeing something yes that's a good
question so browsers are not a good
place to store secrets anymore so so
that's why we also look for other
patterns like like a back-end for
front-end pattern for example you might
have seen that pattern already so so
where the backend deals with that whole
'quran flow and you only have a client
which has the same site cookie which
then is transmitted to the backend for
front-end so I'll indicate so that's the
typical pattern to solve that problem
nowadays okay let's just disappeared if
I have an app like Facebook it can't be
another way to authenticate the user if
he doesn't have his credential I can use
password grant type for this case I
don't know if I got this right
yeah I think they're asking can I use a
password grant type
I'm not totally sure if they're asking
about using OAuth as authentication or
if this is a question about open ID
maybe while we take that one too slack
last question then I think before we let
you go I can we use open HSM solution to
store the credentials you mean that the
credentials on the authorization server
site yeah yeah the storing the
credentials this is it implementation
detail of the authorization server also
so if you have for example use active
directory on Microsoft Azure there I'm
sure they store that in some some HSM
already ok awesome so I'm sure you can
be available in slack for a little while
yes yeah of course yeah
so we've got a break coming up now folks
and you can definitely talk with Andres
more in slack I know there's some
conversation going on there already one
last thing to the person who mentioned I
had the question about pen testing
before we do have a talk coming up later
today that is going to discuss some of
the ways to hack or off and so perhaps
that might be another talk for you to
check out that might have some helpful
information for you there is proactive
it a more attacking stuff on that
perfect
now all right and various thank you so
much and thanks everybody we are gonna
go to break here and we will come back
soon
yeah bye