okay cool well thank you so much for
having me here and thanks to all the
organizers for organizing this and also
the attendees so my name is Ray I'm a
developer advocate for Google cloud
platform and I love Java and Java
campaign as well but I also like a lot
of the architecture and also deployment
in production systems and so I am also
very involved with the communities
ecosystem as well if you have any
questions about this session please pay
me on twitter which is at saben is it
okay since we only have about 30 minutes
I'm gonna move really quickly quickly in
the end of last year some more
information on other links too but you
know this photo though is very special
for me so a second technology I love I
love to travel
given the current situation I cannot go
anywhere so you know I do miss the
traveling but well I'm traveling I also
take a lot of photos and this photo is
very special to me I was a fat Packer
many many years ago I was backpacking
for about four months and came across
the city in China where if you don't
really have cheap places for backpackers
to stay they only had expensive hotels
and so as a backpacker had to ask around
like what do I do in this case and two
people two different people told me
independently that if you take a bus out
somewhere like a few hours out and then
transfer to a car that they will take
you to an entrance of a desert and be
walking the desert for four hours in
southwest direction then you're going to
find these oases and then you can stay
there for free and I heard the word free
in asked which bus do I take okay as a
backpacker danger was not in my mind
it's just about free okay so I don't
know if anyone here hiking does it
before but this is why it feels like the
sand is really really soft and when
somebody tells you that go Southwest for
four hours in the desert that you can
see that we have all these sand dunes it
doesn't matter what's in front of you
you go in that one direction okay and so
you're going up and down up and down and
you're going to pull your legs out from
the sand and take the next step up and
down these sand dunes with a heavy pack
with water in what stretchers it was
hard it was difficult they reminded me
of work as a Java developer writing j2ee
application and here I thought I was on
vacation
however the in was absolutely beautiful
this is the actual photo from the Aces
obviously I survived so I found always
this and it's beautiful and I said
engineer this is what I'd like to get to
for my applications as well I want to
get my application to production and the
road to production is not always easy
sometimes we meet these obstacles and
that we have to solve them along the way
and I see my job as you know hopefully
being able to help you you know through
this journey so that you don't have a
bad time okay so as easy as possible and
that's I'm going to show you today just
a few things I learned as I helped an
internal project to go into production
and there are many many things that we
need to check against to make sure that
we are ready for production system okay
and the first thing is that local
development is not production okay so
what I'm going to talk about today is
what developers can do on the local
development side for my application so
that my application is ready for
production however it will be almost
impossible to bring that production
environment down to my local environment
because production is just so hard
there's so many more things to consider
so many more things to run and if you
make your local development production
you might as well just develop against
production anyways right but in local
development what I want to focus on is
just the developer productivity and what
engineers should be focusing on is the
design of your application and we need
to start off by just understanding that
you know on the left hand side this
development on the right hand side is
the full production environment and
there are so many things that's
different so how can we actually bridge
these two gap well we need to understand
the contracts between your application
in the tool the order platform that's
orchestrating your application ok and
once we understand these contracts we
can go back and make sure that we
conform to these contracts in now we
will have a much easier time when we go
into a production environment that has a
lot more you know considerations that's
being built in but as long as you're
here to these contracts you're going to
have an easier time as you move upwards
to your environment and this has to do
with application lifecycle configuration
metrics log collection and how your
container image is constructed so I'm
going through some of these in more
detail but first remember
this all starts from your application it
has nothing to do with kubernetes in
fact if you recall you know years ago
five years ten years ago we didn't have
communities but your application still
run somewhere and you still have to
follow these design principles tomorrow
there may or may not be kubernetes in
which case you still have to make sure
your application is properly designed
and one of the most known patterns right
now and most popular is thrill factor
app still constantly surprised by how
many people who haven't heard about this
I hope everyone now understands this and
have heard about it
income factor apps there are actually 12
different things that you should look
for and implement a design for your
application and everyone here even if
you'd never heard about it you should at
least have one factor because the first
factor is checking your code it is 20/20
everyone should be checking in our code
and this is just one of the factors but
there's but everyone should have no
excuse not checking your code but many
of these factors really really also help
with being able to the point the
application into communities to write
this is completely just about your app
but it just so happened it's also very
useful for communities deployment so for
example being able to externalize your
configuration so you don't baking the
config or any of the secrets into your
app into a container image that is super
super important without you are able to
scale out your process we are the
process model and now your processes are
stateless right all these are just
basically some principles that happens
to be really really useful so number one
so make sure you follow and study some
of these factors and implement as much
as you can the second of this is that
again this is all by your application
you should be able to test your
application locally okay
now what I mean by that is that you
should not depend on allows the external
stuff in order to run your test even if
you are developing against kubernetes
you should still be able to test your
application repeatedly and consistently
even just from your local environment
and um but you might be asking well wait
a second but sometimes I depend on
another service sometime that depends on
you know another database where I do
need to test against a real database how
do I bring those things up well first of
all for services usually actually have
mocks right so make sure you
top marks services they can't just bring
into an application so we can do that
mock tests if you do need to use any
external components like for example
your reasoning post-crisis equip it
database were you using my super
database you want to test against those
databases then another tool that's
really really powerful especially for
java application is called test
containers and test containers can work
also for other languages too but then
let me just show you what this looks
like in a typical Java based unit
testing okay so in my unit test here I'm
going to test against a repository that
has crud operations to my database but
rather than connecting to our shared
death database or a you know a QA
database what I'm going to do is to use
test containers to in familiarly spin up
a container that has my mock data with
my username password that's completely
used for testing I can even use any post
quest images here that you might
actually want to use in your production
environment of course this is not a
production database but it's pretty
close in terms of version right and now
you can simulate a lot of the things and
then you can use this container metadata
to configure your own application to
connect to it and so if I were to run
this unit test right now everything is
self-contained it does use docker behind
the scenes but as I'll run this unit
test weather unit I starts is going to
start up the container for me bootstrap
my post quest database for example you
can start off other containers too and
then make sure my applications connect
you to that database with the right
credentials and now I can run my test
and then I can do this repeatedly and
consistently because I'm not depending
on any external data that could be
modified by somebody else so this is
super important make sure you can run
your tests locally and you can't do
things reproducible ok and fix any flaky
tests anything that's flaky that is not
good this is just a basic design
principles right however for the
application life cycle within criminales
this is something you thought you do
need to think about so make sure that
your application has the proper
lifecycle hooks and there are a few
things here a number one is how will
criminales know that your applications
is live and this is what we call the
liveness probe it should be a simple
probe that checks against your
application that
simply tells communities is your
application life and if it's not a life
is in trouble
failed its liveness probe so that
communities can automatically restart
your application okay so this is a
contract that you will have with
kubernetes in the second part of it is
the readiness probe the Rendon's probe
is a little bit different from the
liveness probe okay so if liveness Pro
fails then communities will restore your
application thinking that your
application will automatically recover
if we just simply restart it okay for
the readiness probe this is the profile
you will use if your application is
ready to serve but you might be saying
wait a second my application is alive so
it's ready to serve
right in some cases yes but many of the
larger enterprise application that may
not be the case why because your
application could be alive but it needs
to do some other initialization like
preload some beta preload some stuff
into the cache you know make sure all
the connections are established right to
gain to that ready state so that you are
actually ready to serve the very first
request if you don't have this then
companies will send a request to your
application and you might still be
loading this cached data from the
database so that your first requires
will be really slow potentially right so
you can use this kind of contract to
tell communities when to start serving
traffic as soon as you turn this on
then kubernetes will then enlist your
application instance into the load
balancer and then sending the request
over okay I'm gonna show a demo of this
later as we go into communities itself
but this is from your application
perspective you need to have lightness
probe and ready this probe that can't be
configured later and then your
application should also have some kind
of contract in terms of how to shut down
gracefully okay so for example if you're
writing a unlined transactional
application and you have all these
in-flight transactions that's coming in
and when could Nettie's want to shut you
down
because you're scaling in or that your
application is having trouble is trying
to restart you then it's going to send
you a six-term signal and you should be
able to respond to this signal and say
hey kubernetes trying to shut me down
and so let me go ahead and
up what that means is that you need to
finish all the invite transactions you
need to have any of the background
processes or thread pores to be shut
down and make sure that all of those
work is complete and potentially if you
don't want to receive any new traffic
you will then fill the rating this probe
right so if you turn that off then
kubernetes will then stop sending
traffic to you but you do have all of
these incoming connections that's really
established so these are unified
connections in flight transactions you
need to make sure that you finish
serving those requests as well and then
you shut down gracefully when you're
ready if you don't shut down gracefully
there are some configurations that you
can configure in companies that will
then forcefully shut you down
so in that case rather than sick turn 4
you're going to get this is sick kill
and that will just shut you structure
your application down and this is
configured through something called the
graceful period right so by default the
grace period is about 30 seconds if I
could recall correctly so if your
application doesn't shut down in 30
seconds if you would just forcefully
kill it and then you are at risk of
potentially losing some in-flight
transactions on the other hand you can
also increase this graceful period to a
number that is proper for your
application so these are the things that
you need to be checking against okay so
life cycle the hook with the lightness
probe and Ready's probe and being able
to gracefully shutdown as well and
receiving those singles another thing
that you need to check is just don't
write to the file system if you are
writing an application that is mean to
be in ephemeral like stateless and scale
out and scale in automatically and those
are running as a container definitely
please do not write to the file system
in most cases that's not necessary and
the reason I bring this up is because
many many of the more traditional
applications we tend to write logs to
the file system those are not the best
practices in communities what you should
be doing is to just string the logs to
STD out and usually the communities
installation like on Google Cloud
we will ingest whatever that you send to
STD out and we will send those things
directly to a centralized logger so
there's no need to write to the log file
another problem is that in a traditional
VM the law
are automatically rotated what that
means is that you may be writing the log
file but then only to a certain amount
certain sizes and then it gets garbage
collected because there is log rotator
behind the scenes in containers those
rotate a seaman that may not exist and
so your log file can accumulate and
definitely do not write data either
because your data is going to be straw
in the container file system which are
going to be ephemeral so the next time
you start your container of the data be
gone so just remember don't write to the
file system the easiest way to make this
check is to just make your file system
read-only and once you do that you're
going to see all these issue popping up
and now you can get rid of those things
that's right into the file system
so just to recap some other
consideration for the application to a
factor app repeatable local tests
respecting the application lifecycle
hooks having the health checks and the
course full shutdown now two other
things that's really important
externalize about configuration that is
really just part of this fill factor app
you do not want to store any credentials
in your container image or inside of
your application and the final piece of
it is the matrix right how is your
application going to relay the matrix
information like QPS latency information
or any of the other application specific
SLO so you need to define our strategy
somehow most of the people writing these
applications in targeting criminals the
metrics are usually collected by
Prometheus so make sure that your
application exposes the matrix be
Epimetheus endpoint and if you're using
Prometheus otherwise you know whatever
matrix vendor that you use make sure
that those things are in there too right
now then once you have your application
design properly respecting the contracts
then we can move into containers now
this is actually the most difficult part
however this tune is your easier way to
do it but this is what I usually see for
example for a Java developer to build
your docker file okay so they say from
open JDK copy the source
do the built-ins on docker for some
reason and then copy the copy out the
final boot or if
which is in this case a jar file and
then I have seen this in mini docker
file they tried to copy in some
credentials like a surface account or
some token they need into this container
image and then finally they run a Java -
our app that you are right and they ship
it to production and that is really
really bad we really really need to have
some more discipline in terms of
understanding and writing these darker
files and if possible don't write them
at all ok so let's see what's wrong with
this docker file or first of all on the
top which the hip which JDK version am I
going to be using without specifying it
is going to use the latest version of
the openjdk same thing for any other
runtime like node or go or whatever and
this is bad - because you always need to
know what version of the runtime you are
trying to use especially for open JDK
for Java applications the wrong gtk
versions may cause you a lot of pain
because they are now continue aware they
actually do not understand how much
resource you can use in the container so
you always want to know which version
you're trying to use and try to use the
newest one obviously and then it's the
second part of it is out the source file
ends up in a container I have seen this
before if you anyone gets into your
container for whatever reason however
they get into it you're going to see
your source code it's bad and then if
you're building in this way then the
package is anything that you download an
intermediary when you're abusing this
container we're also saying the
container they can go away in um the jar
file itself is really really big so it
could be 80 100 megabytes large and this
is not really optimized for container
either and finally obviously these
secrets or configuration they should all
be externalized you do not want them to
be in the container that you put into a
container registry right and finally the
most important part is who is the user
running this overwhelmingly all of these
space images are going to be running
your application as root and in the
production environment that's not the
best idea even in containers you should
do not want to run your application on
its root and nobody really checks
against these things so these are just a
few things you really really need to
check against right so here is a little
optimized version of this it's not the
the
best version of it but still somewhat
optimized so rather than you know
building in the same continent image in
this case we're using multistage build
so that the beauty of the fact is in a
separate container layer that will never
show up in your production container
okay
in the second thing inside we specify
the runtime environment with the tag so
in this case I really really want to use
Java 8 update to 42 that is continuing
aware and I'm also picking and choosing
whether I want to use a GRE which is the
Java runtime environment or the GDK
right if I run my application a java
application I just need a runtime
environment I don't need to do
compilation so I don't need to JDK right
and that's going to reduce the size of
your container image and then don't run
this size route so you specify the user
right and then any optimized other
things and this will get you to a much
better place however a friend of mine
Matt rainbow who works at octa it's a
security company that writes
authentication and SSL and he famously
says friends don't let friends write
authentication why because education is
tedious it's repetitive and easy to get
wrong I'm going to steal that and say
friend a lot friends write docker files
why because the doctor files are also
very easy to make mistakes and it's also
really easy to make wrong and also is
really repetitive right so when possible
use another tool that can automate these
things and then automatically implement
the best practices so there are two
projects out there like jib now you can
use with Java or you can use something
like a cloud native view pack in both
cases they are going to be able to
analyze your application and then feed
you through their own pipeline which is
already codified with the best practices
and it will automatically analyze your
application and out comes the container
so you can build your application
containers without any docker file at
all so for example I'm gonna go here to
my in this case a java application if I
want to use to build my application
all I need to do is to add a little
plugin and I just need to go to my
coming in line in this case and say
event Jude and I do not need a docker
file at all and
this will automatically analyze and
create the container for me with most of
the best practices and uh oh yeah I need
to you know specify the registry for
example let me just do that yeah we can
do this again okay
super easy and much much better than
having to write docker file over and
over again okay now for containers
here's the little quick checklist just
make sure that you know what's in the
container image I have opened up
container images before that somebody
else put used and there were source code
in there especially for compiled
languages that's not necessary that loss
of these intermediate build artifacts
like maven the entire maven central is
in there which is not necessary
potentially right or sometimes they get
the right reasoning there I don't know
how they even got in there but you know
when you say copy everything in there I
guess you get to keep directories so be
careful with this always double-check
and then you want to optimize a little
bit more and just make sure you don't
run as root and especially if you're
using Java make sure its container where
and that used towards whenever possible
okay now finally to kubernetes once you
have the container in your application
here's going to be the easier part now
you can use kubernetes to use the
contracts that you have just adhere to
so for example I'm going to open up my
communities file here there are a couple
of things that you must do number one is
this content emerge in production
environment always version your
container image with the tag so rather
than running latest always do like the
one or you have your own version scheme
so make sure you always have your image
with the container tag here and always
externalize your configuration using in
VAR config map or secrets and here are
the two very important thing one is
called resource
okay so resource is how much CPU and
memory your application can use this is
super important why if you don't specify
it then your application is going to
think that it owns the whole machine
okay so if your machine has 16 gigabytes
of RAM your application will fail
that you can use all 16 gigabytes of RAM
but in kubernetes we will be bundling or
a bin packing multiple application
instances into a single host so if every
single one of them thinks they can use
16 megabytes or gigabytes of RAM then
you're going to run into out of memory
issue very quickly okay so in this case
where you want to set our two things
once the request so this is the minimum
amount of memory and CPU that your
application needs so this will be used
to make sure that hey I'm going to
schedule you to a host that at least
have this much memory and CPU available
okay but you also want to set a limit
this is how much you can use at maximum
so this is how much you can burst to so
even though I give you one CPU
allocation at the beginning but now you
can actually use as much as two CPUs
when you need to okay similarly with
memory now one thing to watch out for
here is that for the memory if you
exceed the memory that we will kill or
try to shut down your application
because memory is not compressible so if
we see the memory limit will shut you
down
going through the sixth term signal but
if you do exceed the CPU allocation will
just throttle your application so you
just become slower okay and then you
need to remember the liveness probe in
the redness probe that you created
earlier you need to configure those with
kubernetes as well so for example live
this probe I need to use it via HTTP GET
so I can hit the end point and render
this probe I do the same thing however
this is the most important thing you
have to really think about every
application may be different which is an
initial delay seconds which is when
we'll deliver this probe start to check
and how many times will count as a
failure and how often do we actually
check okay so if your application takes
ten minutes to start its true story it
could happen or even five minutes you
start then your initial delay second has
to be reconfigured zero will be too
short ten second will be too short if
your application takes five minutes to
start maybe you check after five minutes
right so that will be 200 seconds and
then you write because otherwise if the
liveness probe kicks in too early and
within the first 30 seconds you fail
three times but your application is
still starting you
were going through this infinite loop of
restarting you will never start and you
definitely have to watch out for it I
have seen application going to this
infinite a failure loop restart loops
just because it starts to slowly and
this configuration hasn't been
configured wait okay
and then you always want to check in the
mo file this is the final bit I'm gonna
gonna talk about all the mo files that
you create for companies always checking
them in somewhere I cannot stress this
enough this is going to save you if you
accidentally wiped out some environment
then you can recreate this environment
very very quickly with the same Yama
files that you used before because it
because you check the name now you can
just do keep CTO apply and then you can
get the same environment up and running
in no time okay so I think that's almost
the time that I have with a couple
minutes for questions so I'm gonna go to
their last slide here which is a just a
little more obviously 30 minutes it's
really short but if you want to learn
more with the more advanced topics here
are some of the links you can try with
recorded talks and even pro laughs okay
cool awesome rate thank you very much so
I do have one question so when it comes
to using the jib tool so like that makes
sense it's like I'm definitely not an
expert when it comes to putting together
docker file so kind of unloading that
off to like some sort of tool that
introduces best practices and all that
into it it's good but what can you do to
kind of make sure that you know like
something suddenly doesn't change your
docker file and then all of a sudden
something that was working before is all
sudden breaking and you don't know why
like can you kind of set like I want
this specific verse in the Java or
something like that but what is the
configurations you can do with that yep
so if you're using a docker file then
where you set this you know think
version off Java or at the base image
the echo seems moved from block if
you're using did before example we also
have configuration here so I can say
from inmate and then I can say open JDK
for example 8 you at 1 2 42 here are
nice limb right and this way whenever
this image is being beaut you'll use
this same base image over and over again
and I will give you
consistency okay great great yeah and I
guess there's there's pie I'm guessing
just a lot of options when it comes to
this configuration to make sure yeah
anything that you need you can pass in
there as if you're writing your own dico
file but you don't actually have to
specify all that stuff if you don't need
to that's right yeah and and similarly
here I do need to go out like what user
do I want to run this application s even
which you need to call this out because
also by default is going to use what's
defaulting this face image and every
base image from they have a different
user and group that you may need to use
so you do need to configure this as well
nice yeah this is really useful
particularly the jib tool becoming a bit
more familiar just before you Paul
Sarkozy I kind of mentioned it but now
you know a very good I guess you could
say layup and that you mentioned it now
you kind of went further in depth into
it so I apply I actually have to
consider using that and some of my tools
are some of my tests right one question
I do also have is like I really love
test containers have you done anything
when it comes to like how to share like
data volumes or something for like a
database or any like that may be back in
beta you maybe want to have your test or
have you just also kind of mostly just
filter around it with it as well yeah so
for the test data depends on the
framework that you use right so for
example in spring boot you should be
able to depend on spring boots to be
able to run through the innate sequel or
data sequel and that would just be
pulled out that spring boot data data
container oh sorry the spring boot data
a people component sorry and which you
could be always being able to re
reestablish the same test cases how you
expect otherwise you will be you know
testing against either steal data or
data that somebody else changed yeah
great yeah that that's good at this test
containers one of my friend Rob Lynch he
introduced me to that about two or three
years ago now and it's been really cool
to see that tool growing popularity
because like it just does exactly what
you want and
it solves like a really important quote
issue kind of like oh you want to
actually test against the Postgres
database but you don't want to have like
your testing to go missing or whatever
it might be or the database me down when
you run your test so any violin watching
like definitely consider using test
containers for your integration test it
will definitely help a lot so I think
we're at time that we also have a break
after this so if there's anything else
you want and maybe cuts on we do have a
couple more minutes if you want or we
can just go ahead and end it here yeah I
just want to say thank you again for
hosting it and thanks oh the organizer
is for putting this together it's really
impressive what everyone has
accomplished so far yeah all right thank
you right and also make sure to consider
buying tickets help donate I believe the
funds are going to who and obviously the
reason we're having this is because of
the Cova pandemic and you know donate
you can I also help with resolving or
help maybe mitigate some of the problems
with Cove at 19 or maybe hopefully
actually more convenient you're out
there pretty or vexing out here pretty
soon as well so all right thank you very
much ray and thank you very well sand I
think we're going on a like said about