yeah we are we are now going back to
sessions and uh
with me right now we have uh billy
corrando billy how are you
hey simon i'm good how are you nazi bad
not too bad holding up all right so far
so um yeah good to have you on billy
this is this your first session
on the on the on the conference today
yes it is
it is normally so i'm going to spoil
with this one
and you do in fact you're doing some uh
you're doing some track hosting a little
bit later for us as well right
that i am so looking forward to that
excellent so you're seeing it from a few
sides today
yeah well welcome welcome to the
conference um and that billy you're a
developer advocate at ibm
yep that's correct i'm a developer
advocate kind of focusing on cloud and
spring
and we're going to kind of just see a
little bit of both of that here in a few
minutes so
wow wow that's awesome to have a having
a spring advocate
yeah i know you always expect that
yeah absolutely i mean remember when i
was years and years ago when i was at
ibm
you know full fully behind the the the
java ee as they are now of course
but uh yeah i wouldn't wouldn't have
thought there would be a spring advocate
but it's wonderful to see support in the
wider ecosystem and it's a great
great great thing to do um so uh billy
you're also a big community person right
you're you're one of the co-leads of the
kansas city jug
that's correct yep and actually we're
gonna i'm gonna be uh doing some more
live stream hosting with that tomorrow
so definitely uh check that out uh you
can find us on at caseyjug
on twitter and uh micah silverman with
octa is actually going to be doing a
presentation on spring
and ujs tomorrow about a couple hours
later from now tomorrow so it'll be
pretty good awesome and so today you're
talking about collaborative contract
the ribbon driven development billy
what's that right
what does that mean billy so pretty much
uh we're gonna
get into it and we're gonna kind of look
a bit at um
what is contract driven development
because even though it's been around for
a little bit
um it's probably still something that
hasn't really penetrated that far
into the development world um and then
we're going to look at to see how we can
actually do it in a more collaborative
fashion to where
it's not just you have to have a bunch
of very specific java idiomatic
uh tools to do it that anyone can do it
um whether you're a javascript developer
c-sharp developer
python or whatever it might be you can
actually
uh do contract driven development and
kind of help your organization be
a little bit more agile a little bit
more following good like
continuous delivery practices awesome
that sounds that sounds awesome well i
won't check up any more of your
time i'll hand it over to you and i'll
leave you in the most capable hands of
brian as well he's also
also here in the background on this on
this session so over to you billy
all right thank you very much simon so
yes uh
our presentation we're gonna be looking
at collaborative contract driven
development
you can find me at billy crandall on
twitter you can also feel free to email
me at william.corando at ibm.com
um at the bottom of the screen here you
can see this is a link to
this presentation so you can follow that
i will also have a link
um at the end of this presentation to
the github repository which actually has
more
full presentation from this because i've
had to kind of bring it back down to fit
the format
um and it also has the code examples
that i'll be getting into
also if you leave this presentation with
an intense desire to know more
i do a lot of blogging on my personal
blog at billycrander.com specifically
about automated testing
so you can check it out there i've
specifically covered contract dividend
development a couple of times
and i probably will have some more here
in the future as well so
if you kind of want to get more in-depth
on it definitely check that out
so as i kind of mentioning with simon at
the start of this
is while contract event development
isn't particularly new
it hasn't really seen widespread
adoption within the software developer
community
so before getting into the depths of
this presentation just to give you an
overall idea of what contractor
development is let's just take a very
high level view and pretty much what it
is is you have your service
you have your client and of course they
interact with one another so
if a client sends a request to some sort
of endpoint and maybe even like a post
request that's going to have some sort
of request body
within it that's going to go to the
service
and the service is going to respond back
you know it could be 200 in this case
or it could be 400 500 well 500
when they really put this within
contract of involvement um
but you would have some sort of response
based upon that kind of request
and what contract driven development is
this actually writing this out in a
programmatic fashion that can be tested
against
um as to what's going on without
actually having to interact with a real
live service so
what does this mean how does it actually
help you with contractor development i
kind of think back to this scene from
it's only sunny in philadelphia when one
of the characters charlie
is going to go burn trash and a couple
of other characters mac and dennis try
to stop him
and he's like i'm going to burn this to
turn into stars
but they're like you know what that
doesn't sound right but i don't know
enough to
say it's wrong so how can we relate this
how does contract driven development
actually help us
based on my career um i thought about
three common things i ran into
and how contractor development could
actually help with that so let's kind of
go
through these scenarios using my
favorite thing gifts
so in this first one we're going to be
looking at like a existing poorly
defined service
like this like some sort of generic
customer service it doesn't matter
too much so we had here and so it's like
they need customer information
and this client and it's like okay
here's this customer service
did you read documentation yeah it's a
word doc and you're calling called get
customers to get customer information so
hp get
good customers but it's post endpoints
so
nothing's going back and eventually
they're going to get back here a 405
error
they should be using post okay so they
try doing posts to get customers
still getting nothing back well there's
an aussie header of course so they send
that
and now it fails to 500 and it fails
because well
their database was brought down for
maintenance and they get back like a
http 200 but it has an error code in it
but nobody knows what the error code
means or what it really means when an
error like that happens
so it's just like a poorly defined or
undocumented
api so you know it and maybe it's also
within like a bad format like a pdf or a
word doc or something like that that's
not really
easy to kind of translate into
programmatic use
uh you could also have inconsistent
behaviors of patterns so like you have
an endpoint called get customer info
but instead of being a git it's actually
a post which
you know if you want to follow rush or
not that's fine but it can be kind of
confusing
for some client or some user of that
service to see that
um and then they're going to get the
wrong idea and it makes it really hard
to just kind of
actually use that service and then
finally
you have problems when you're testing
against a live service
some back-end service could go down like
a database or maybe some other service
that
that service depends upon that causes it
to any request to it to fail but it has
nothing to do
with the requests the client are sending
it so it can be very difficult confusing
when you're developing against it to
know
wait is this fairly happening because
i'm using it wrong
or because there's actually something
wrong with the service
so that's kind of one set of problems
another one is it's like okay we're
gonna use some new development we kind
of went through our whole
like design process and now we're
actually ready to get going developments
and oftentimes what happens though is
the backend service developer
they everyone has to wait the clients
have to wait until that service
developer kind of has something ready so
they can test and build again so it's
like oh is that api finalize that
well now they're updating the model and
you know they want to do some work but
now that service developer got pulled
into a prod issue
so while they're on work and that pride
issue all these
features order summary address form and
so on
they're all kind of stuck while they're
waiting for that service developer to
kind of get
back onto the project so kind of what's
going on here
is you can't really develop in parallel
the clients really
i mean they can maybe do some work ahead
of time but really they're dependent
upon that service developer actually
having at least
some nominal you know minimal viable
product service available
for them to actually work and develop
against
and what this means is now your timeline
giving that service about
feature out to production and used by
users is impacted by delays in both the
service and client developers so if a
service developer is pulled into a
product for a week or is on vacation for
a week or sick for a week
you're back you're the way bye week if a
client developer
is similarly going to be impacted by a
week because of something coming up
you know that's going to add two whole
weeks to that timeline whereas if
they're both looking in parallel
you know maybe you we won't be impacted
by that at all
or maybe only impacted by a week
also then like once a service developer
finally
has some minimal service available a
client developer maybe has to get back
up to speed on how
they want to actually consume that
service because they kind of forgot what
they're going to do
because it's been a week in a month or
longer since they actually had a lot of
those design
meetings finally
we just have like this actively used
service there and sometimes you know
someone makes a change to a back-end
service you know
someone like perhaps myself uh when i
was still actually doing real
development work
you know they see something like api get
customers and like oh that's that's not
properly restful they're going to change
the customers
and they just push it out and they don't
tell anyone about it and so sometimes
like this happens
a change gets pushed to production oh
when did it go to pride
it went last night well at least now you
know what all the predators are about
but now this poor client developer is
going to have to stay late to get it
fixed
and oh yeah by the way that service
developers also pushed up a customer
model change
again without telling the client
developer and they're always the last
one about these changes
once they get to production and now they
have their hairs on fire
trying to put out this production issue
so again you just have a breaking api
change not caught
in pillow production because maybe just
no one knew
a new change was going to production or
just didn't know that this change
was going to have this sort of impact
maybe the developer
when they were making that change then
themselves realized it was going to kind
of have this impact
and then also another problem is just
like the service developers they pretty
much have the full
control over what the api design looks
like and that can be maybe an unpleasant
experience for client developers because
maybe that model
maybe the end points aren't set up to
work that well for what they need
so this is the overall case for contract
driven development and what it is
so let's start digging into a little bit
more looking at spring cloud contracts
so why should you consider it well it's
a very active project uh
there's ongoing changes and features
being added so it's not something that
was
just had an initial release a couple of
years ago and hasn't really been touched
since
it's ongoing and in active development
it's also interoperable with other tools
and standards like open api
packed swagger it also has really great
documentation support with spring red
stocks
which is backed by ascii doctor and it
also has polyglot support which kind of
gives you that collaborative portion i
was talking about early on
when i was talking to simon at the intro
anyways you can read more about it here
at the project link so what does this
contract
look like well there's a couple
different ways to write contracts
initially when spring crowd
spring cloud contractors are miserably
released it was on groovy
and here's a very simple contract
showing an example of doing a post
so here we have like a method post to
api persons with a body of
name john doe and he's going to give
back a status of 201
which means creative and then it's going
to have a link
to that new person's object here's what
the exact same kind of request would
look like
if you're using yaml so there's groovy
there's yaml
i believe there's kotlin and i think
there might be
one other i think it actually could also
even be in now native java as well
as a contract writing service uh but i
haven't done that i've
only done work with the groovy and the
yaml
so there's so this is what the contracts
look like so who's actually writing them
so there's actually two different ways
of writing contracts well they're both
the same kind of contract but there's
two different methodologies
so one of them is the producer-driven
contract where the producer of the
service or the developer of the service
writes the contract they'd be like hey
the apa will look like this the client
and the client's like okay that's good
they have something to develop against
that's awesome
another way is consumer driven club
contract where a client says hey
i need this from the api and they write
out a contract
and then the server or the producer uh
the producer developer will then write
those out
so it's important to understand though
that whether it's a consumer-driven
contract or a producer-driven contract
the contracts will look the same they'll
both have this request
and this response look and so on it's
just
a methodology but kind of a push versus
pull
for how api should be developed and
built
if it's producer producer-driven
contract the producer of the service the
producer developer is going to be like
saying
pushing out what the contract is going
to look like
whereas consumer driven it's the
consumer kind of pulling
that api in ways they want it and need
it to be
one advanced consumer driven contract
over producer is
maybe going to avoid some of that yagni
that you're not going to need it
because all the api features and end
points are being built based upon a
specific need for clients
not the producer trying to assume what
the clients actually need
by the way both methodologies work and
both are much
a much improvement over not doing
contract driven developments
but also if you want to do actual uh
consumer-driven contracts a lot of times
they're not going to be java developers
that
are going to be writing them um so you
need to have language independent tools
so java developers are going to have a
jdk they're going to bathe in to have a
java friendly ide
that's probably not going to be the case
for javascript developers
or other type of developers but now
docker has become fairly universal
and of course every developer is going
to have a text editor
so about two years ago spring cloud
contract
developed some docker images that can
encapsulate all the java
and spring cloud contract logic within
these docker images
and they have it for both doing the
producer and the consumer side of it
and so with that you can then use it to
validate the contract so you write these
contracts out
you make sure the service actually meets
that contract you can also use that
using the docker image not necessarily
depending again upon like having
java and maven and stuff like that
and so if these contracts work then what
you get
is a subs artifact that combines all
these contracts together
into something that's shareable which
then you can put into your artifact
repository whether it's
internal or external to your company
because maybe have external clients
which are using your services
all the same you can kind of do that
there to share it to have the current
state
of what that service looks like
or the api you can also again create
documentation
based upon these contracts and again
because these
contracts are being validated against
the actual current version of the
service
you're gonna have a lot of uh confidence
that this documentation is gonna be
up to date with what the actual service
currently looks like
you're not going to have documentation
that was made when the service was first
released but has since become
badly out of date
and then finally you can have these
clients they can actually then test
against these stubs artifacts um
or you can and you can also again use
docker to do this
or you can even have them test just
directly against the contracts
which can help with doing that parallel
development so that way
once those contracts are actually
written both the producer
and the client can actually go ahead our
consumer
and go ahead and start developing and
just develop to meet those contracts
so quickly just to kind of review all
this we can write the contracts to
define the behavior of the api
and the contracts validate the api
matches the behavior
you can bundle the contracts as a
shareable artifact you can generate
documentation from the contracts
and the clients can test and develop
against the artifact
and what's critical is is those last
four points
except for against the develop portion
would all be
automated so that way you're always
checking against it so that way
if someone trying to make a change to
the api or change the contract
you're not going to actually break
people in production or something like
that
all right so that was a whole lot of
words what does this
actually look like in the real world
so here i have a really simple produce
service
and i have a few endpoints a couple of
gift endpoints a post endpoint
and so then i based upon that some
contracts
so here i have my code repository
and again um in this i have both the
client the producer and then the
contracts i'm writing against and again
you can access this you can kind of look
at it all
later but um we're going to look at this
one so we have this one contract
it's called find produce by specific
name and so what's going to do is
do a get to this endpoint
and it's going to expect that a couple
of apple items to be returned
now if we go back into my code we can
see here
we have a git mapping for name
and it's at api v1 produce so
that's how that relates to this api v1
produce
in this case taking the variable apple
in
and that's what it does here so if i was
to comment this
out oops don't want to delete comment
out
and then execute these tests and while
they're executing i'll show you this
so in maven if i was just doing as a
java developer i would
configure this on maven and here i'm
saying
go look for the contracts out here at
my github w grando produce contracts
and a run and test against them
so we had four test runs and that was
because
we have four contracts out here add
produce add failed find all and find
produce by name so four contracts
four tests and then one failed and that
failed because
i commented out this git mapping for
producer
so now the contracts don't match what is
written in them
if i uncomment this out i can run the
test again
analysis succeed because now the api
actually matches
what's in the contracts
so this is great so this is a good way
of making sure
a good ci cd process where if i make a
change
to this code here and i commit it to a
repository and have it go through our
cicd process
it's going to test every time against
those 16 contracts and make sure i'm
going to actually meet it now let's
think about it from the client side the
client is going to
want to be able to develop and test as
well without maybe necessarily having to
wait for me to actually get a service
out and running so
let's see let me make sure i'm in the
right area
yes there we go so
here as i mentioned the
spring cloud contracts team they created
some docker images
to encapsulate all this logic so let's
let's see what it looks like to actually
um use one of those so here i created a
script
for just running one of these docker
images and so
you have the spring cloud contract um
docker image and um
here i'm saying i'm gonna be you're
gonna use these
maven coordinates of com ibm developer
producer service
and this is the same like use the most
recent version out there and it's going
to be running at port 9876
and then it's saying to look again to
here to my github repository
um to pull in these contracts to
actually run this produce service
now if i quit out there and i run this
i'm going to get a example or
a big service behind or a
mock service running behind us under
spring cloud contract
you can see here is actually using
wiremock it's kind of
reading in those contracts consuming
them and then using json
um to kind of mock out those requests
so if i go here to whoa the host
9876 produce and apple
i will go ahead and kind of get that
response back based upon that contract
and now if i quickly start
up a little service that myself and a
colleague helped put together
actually let me just go up a couple
there we go
um so yeah npm run start run contract
it's just going to start up a very
simple
angular application
if we give it a couple of moments i'll
get started here
but one of the things that could be
really interesting about this is
one thing that's totally a little bit
difficult about doing
uh automated testing on front-end
applications is sometimes they depend
upon
some back-end live service and sometimes
that data can change
on you that could cause a test to fail
but again that test is failing
not because something actually changed
in the code but because of some
back-end data change that could have
just happened
and so now you're having family test you
kind of lose faith in those tests
because
um they're uh just giving you false
negatives
about failures when they're not actually
broken
so anyways here these four returns are
coming from
this mock service here
uh whoops
that fingering there we go so here we go
like these four
returns in json and that's what we're
getting back here so like this service
is
actually talking to this mock service
here if we put in
apple we'll get two requests back here
this is a very simple example but i
think it's a pretty interesting
use case for how contract testing
can really help in other unexpected
areas beyond just development and just
beyond just the
testing the validation of the api itself
so some final points um while all this
presentation
i kind of focused on rest and http
examples uh you can also use
spring cloud contract for doing messages
and event driven messages and stuff like
that
um it's also totally okay to change
contracts you know we have at least in
the us like contracts are written in
zone and so on but it's fine to change
them
um they're there just to make sure that
if someone either changes an api
then the contract has to be updated to
change it
um it's just making sure unsolicited
shapes can't get to production without
anyone knowing is pretty much what it
comes down to
um also contract tests they're not
acceptance tests or replacement for
end-to-end tests
they're just going to be part of a full
test suite
so not going to be testing things like
resiliency timeouts performance edge
cases and so on that's not the goal of
end to end test it's just so overall
what the api looks like what it's
supposed to do given certain requests
and response
it's not trying to again test its cases
you definitely can't stand
performance because it's a mocked
service all right
so we're at the q a point so i hope you
stick around for that
um here are some links to all that and i
will also
get uh this um slides out to everyone
here pretty soon and like the slack
channel and on twitter so people can
kind of get to this code and check it
out for themselves
so all right any question hey man
yeah i just i just took over from uh
from simon i mean uh it's european time
zone
and um some people do need to sleep i
however will
go on for the for the whole night
yeah i've got the big cup of coffee
going on and we are um
we're going straight on but the first
thing i want to ask you personally is
like
if i want to start with that contract
contract testing because i see the
benefits of it but
um as you know if i'm running
a somewhat older application
um house and well we do we do have
services
though and so i so it it i get it
that that things like contract testing
you should be
uh can be interesting for me how should
i start i mean i find that difficult
so how would you like um
so it's like a new service or maybe have
like an existing service you just kind
of want to write some contracts for
it yeah probably probably some some
existing service because
most of the time it's not the case that
you run
something from a clean sheet or you can
you can start from the beginning
but well a lot of us need to maintain um
older applications absolutely absolutely
and and so for that
is um you could just kind of go ahead
for even an existing service out there
just kind of go back
and um knowing how your service
looks write out some of these contracts
and
make sure that they um test them to make
sure that your api
actually matches to them and
once you feel like the contracts you've
written actually match the current
behavior the api or the expected
behavior the api
you can then actually then start using
them to test to make sure that the api
is continuing to meet
um the expectations of those contracts
and then you can start using
those contracts kind of as i was sewing
here at the end
as a stand-in for testing um against
that api without actually having hit
that live service which again kind of
comes with that
problems of like a database or some
backing service being down which would
cause
some tests to fail uh of course you know
kind of retroactively going back
can sometimes be a little bit more
difficult um
but uh it's definitely not impossible
especially since this can be somewhat
black box type of testing where you
don't necessarily
have to have you know re-engineer your
code
to meet all the ends and needs of the
test
what do you say is the biggest pitfall
uh
people take when doing contract testing
uh so some of the biggest pitfalls is
i guess maybe giving up halfway through
or like not trying to test out
every um well i guess a pitfall would be
not actually having the test represent
what the eight
behind a behind behavior really is and
maybe only say like doing happy path
testing um stuff like that so like here
this is like an example of a successful
request
but you aren't limited to only doing
successful requests you can also do
what happens if like um here
like the client doesn't send like a
required field like name or something
and then i can send back a 400 saying
hey there's a missing value required so
you want to make sure your contracts
fully cover the full behavior of the api
that accurately represents what the api
is supposed to be doing
um if you just kind of hand wave it or
don't you know really
make an attempt to follow what the api
is supposed to be doing
then yeah those tests aren't going to be
of much value to you are there going to
be limited value at least
okay um well that that is that is about
it
i get it awesome so um yeah we have we
have one minute left and i'm actually
just like
waiting waiting for the for the next
speaker i'm waiting for uh
let me see who's next rafael uh
uh will be next so uh billy i want to um
i want to honestly thank you for uh
absolutely
uh let me see if in the meantime there
are new questions because i don't
see them on slidell so
nope okay all right
oh oh there's one we have we have still
one minute so uh
is there any way to know how many
clients are consuming a particular
endpoint or resource
uh uh
i don't know i guess you can maybe
design a system
like there wouldn't be an intrinsic way
of doing that within spring cloud
contract but maybe you could kind of see
like how many people are pulling down
the stubs or something to test against
it
um that's about the only thing and that
would probably be some more advanced
orchestration in your ops
or um pipeline
all right well let's cut it off thank
you for uh
for joining us and uh thank you see
y'all later
absolutely