hey there hey doing welcome Jeffrey and
Douglas squirrel we're gonna tell us
about when we're frustrated how do we
transform conversations and improve our
culture so I'm guessing you guys have
some slides to share that was a good
guess now we also though we do typically
when we do this live we have an
interactive bit that we do with an
audience oh we've never met sure own
yeah okay so we were wondering if you'd
be willing to at some point in our talk
when we have that live interaction that
we could ask you a couple questions some
of the answers yes absolutely
okay so feel free to start that Sharon
and we'll get your slide set up yep so I
think I should have the slide shared now
is that are you able to see that just
appearing there they are fantastic and
I'm gonna have I'm gonna opt out of the
stream and let you guys take it away
from here but I will remind folks that
there's a donate button and the founder
of snick will be matching all of the
donations until the end of the show so
you will have definitely more impact
with your donation from now until the
end of the event so please do keep
donating we need to find a cure for
Kovan so I take it away folks all right
thank you
so hi everyone thank you very much for
joining I wonder does anyone who's been
doing this for you know 20-some hours at
this point I'm not one of those people I
got a good night's sleep last night how
about you squirrel I just woke up so I'm
all set we're in England so Sun is
finding the sheep are out everything's
good
yeah although I don't know quite a good
as sheep view the Sheep as you have so
just a bit about who we are so my name's
Geoff Frederick and I'm a longtime
software executive I've spoken at DevOps
days a few times so Peter talk in the
DevOps track isn't minim I'm excited
about and we're here in part because we
were
invited by Patrick Dubois he had we've
known Patrick since 2008 when we met at
Kip Kahn and scribe known each other
since 2006 something like that we met
kick on to if you don't know what take
on is coming like what will tell you
about that but that to introduce myself
I'm squirrel that is my name but you can
also call me douglas if you'd rather and
i live in england i'm a consulting CTO
which means I work with lots and lots of
different companies without eighty in
the last five years and for all kinds of
conclusions from them which we're gonna
try to share yeah and we're gonna talk
about stuff that unites us grow up we've
been sitting for about eight years and
we're exciting because we've been able
to distill this into a book that we have
this committee coming out in May which
is which is just shockingly just next
month after a couple of years journey
we're almost there and and it's really
the lessons from that book that we're
going to be highlighting here today and
in particular if we kind of go from the
the the high-level version like the
major message that I want people to get
away from this is that there is if
they're frustrated that's a very
valuable signal that there's something
that you that you could be doing
differently and in the key word in that
sentence is you yes exactly and and and
that's our hope is we want to give you
something that you could do differently
today that this is something you could
apply today
I suppose unless for those people who've
in a different time zone and you're just
about getting close to midnight
maybe that's tomorrow would be okay
tomorrow's fine but you shouldn't have
to wait this is not a long-term plan
this is something they can get results
very quickly and it may not be obvious
exactly how this is linked to DevOps
although if you were paying attention to
the last speakers that actually should
be pinging in your brain right now but
we'll explain as we go how this is
linked to DevOps agile those sorts of
things because may not be obvious
immediately yeah one of the ways I think
that maybe some people who are listening
with would understand that the
connection is if they understand that
they're in a religion that's going to
under-eye DevOps transformation now I
know that people have been do that
DevOps for a long time that might seem
like a
a strange idea but there's one thing I
can guarantee you that no matter how
familiar that DevOps might be to you
that there's other people who it's just
brand new - and who it's just there it's
just blowing their mind and this may be
why hire a DevOps I need a DevOps what
does one look like you know how do I
write the job description for a dev ops
yes exactly
it said so there are people there who
are just at the beginning of the
transformation and if you've already
come through it and you've come through
successfully well in a sense you know
kind of why are you here maybe you're
not frustrated maybe you're like no
everything's great
I'm just worried about why those other
people are frustrated which that's fine
but we'll say this for usually when what
I've seen when people come in to do
their DevOps transformation it doesn't
have to be DevOps it could be an agile
conversation it could be a natural
transformation it could be a definite
summation these days you heard a lot
about a digital transformation they
people often it frustrating and the one
of the key reasons that they end up
frustrated is they come in thinking that
it's about different practices and
different processes and it turns out
that's actually around about people and
it's about changing the culture and and
that ends what do I need I need
kubernetes and one of the stand up
things and yeah good we're all set we're
all we're all ready everything's good
this leads to disaster and I know one of
our motivations here about writing our
book and dealing with his issue around
transformations was a book called five
dysfunctions of a team and where they
said something very similar which is
it's really important that you have if
you want to change the dynamics and your
team that you're addressing the culture
and in fact they they talk about the
very first dysfunction do you recall
what that is squirrels certainly yeah I
talk about it all the time so that's
trust
so the first destruction is to not have
trust and I was very excited when I read
the book because and you probably read
books like this or you haven't read this
one it says oh yeah so you're supposed
to fix trust and here's what trust is
and here's how bad it can be if you
don't have trust so definitely have
trust and then I was like where's the
part where I learn how
to create trust it wasn't there actually
it turned out there's this thing way in
the back that I found years later and
and it describes like going on a ropes
course and I didn't convince me that
that was a good way to create trust so I
threw the book across the room I was
really frustrated I wanted my money back
so I was definitely frustrated you know
so we're gonna try to link that that
frustration that you had and the
frustration other people might be
feeling with this larger question of
culture a lot times people are saying
yeah we want our culture to change
because the problem is those other
people you know they they have they have
the wrong culture I just have to
convince them to do the right thing and
then it'll be fine that's right now one
of the things that's interesting thing
is you can start with like what's the
culture that you're starting with and
we're using here the model of Ron
westrom and the three cultures which I
mean I first came across in accelerate
with Jean King Noel front enou Cal ha
Nicole Fras Greene and another in this
model of the three cultures is really
interesting it to me
and now there's a bit of a tell about
which one's the good one in which one's
the bad one it kind of the choices your
culture is pathological bureaucratic or
generative now
yeah with if you know nothing else or
than the names which of the three do you
think you'd want to be part of oh I
guess I gotta be pathological Jeffery I
love being pathological so great know
you always know that the first two are
the ones you don't want to be and the
third one is the one you want to be this
is the classic plot of any talk like
this yeah exactly and the thing is you
whatever company you're in right now you
you are within some sort of culture and
when people are frustrated it's usually
perceive other people as behaving is one
of the first to they say you know people
are either pathological this is a
top-down hierarchical organization or
it's just bureaucratic and all that
matters are rules and and and people
protecting their turf that why aren't
people focus on the mission why don't
people focus on being better and that's
kind of the source of their frustration
now the thing is I stuck a pole in the
tap in the tractive suck-ups channel
appreciate it if any
who would like to we would respond to
the poll which one do you think you're
in now excellent so will well have you
good if you switch over to slack you can
go ahead and fill that in now and and
we'll check he doesn't go up it's okay
we don't mind but we like interacting
with our audience so we'd like a sense
of where you guys feel you are hopefully
you can do both you can you can still
listen to us while there if you if
you're quick you won't even miss the
slight change but let's say that
whatever culture you're part of when you
go to transform when you go to make this
change odds are you saying we want to
end up with a generative culture however
your approach to that transformation
will probably reflect the culture you're
part of so on a pathological
pathological organization the
transformation is typically directed
top-down and just you know imposed and
you're just going to be writing
roughshod over the bodies you know this
is what we're doing
and if you don't like it too bad and
then at the end of it turns out that
that doesn't generate that doesn't
create a generative culture a
bureaucratic culture is one that I've
come across more and more frequently and
I think it might be something that has
to do with people who are later coming
in being people who are sort of at go
saying like well this is the standard
now we're supposed to do the DevOps
standard thing so you know where are the
forms where our DevOps forms do we do
you know how we is this in the scrum you
know rulebook that's the you know 72 or
page 79 they don't seem to match that's
right I have my ITIL guide to DevOps so
it's all going to be okay as long as you
just follow these forms and go through
this process and and again following the
rules isn't a great way to end up with a
generative culture so ideally you want
to be approaching your transformation
the same way that you want to end up so
if you you may be in a pathological or
bureaucratic environment but if you try
leading your transformation that way
it's unlikely to end up in a generative
result and this is where this connects
to you because you might be saying well
what is it that I can do
to change the type of culture I mean if
I want to move from pathological and
bureaucratic what is it I need to do to
end up at the generative culture that
I'm aiming for and our claim is that you
can do that by changing the
conversations if you change your
conversations you change your culture so
you place if you type the poll correctly
you get the right poll so I just
realized I did the poll wrong so
apologies I redid the poll if you want
to go in I'm gonna vote for one choice
that was not a very huh there's gonna
pathological with me apologies right to
choose from this list and there's one
yeah that wasn't very good let's try
right again keep going okay so so here's
the thing is is it you are part of your
culture and your behavior will change it
now what we're gonna be talking about is
some theory that goes back into this
into the 70s so this is not in a sense
new that what's what's new what I think
is is it being brought into we're hoping
is to bringing it mainstream into the
way organizations work today for people
to understand that that they can
personally start changing the
conversations and generating that
generative culture that they want and
the good news here is that you don't
need to learn a new philosophy in a
sense you you already know what the
results look like you you know how to
have a conversation that's one of these
positive generative conversations that
lead to good results and this is the
point where you know we'd really like to
be interactive so if Shirin was
available this would be all right so we
have a question for you yeah you are
going to be deciding the date of next
year's all the talks conference it's
it's up to you to decide the process we
should use and we're gonna use everyone
on who's listening right now to the
stream to males animation decision that
sure owns in charge of how we make the
decision yes have to be super
corporate can I use a doodle hey Elle
it's up to you alright I would probably
crowdsource it I would see who the
organizers are I got a general
understanding of who would be on board
with the logistics and things of that
nature and I would try and understand
engage you know the best dates by giving
a few options possibly if we were
targeting a few like keynote speakers or
folks who would want to target probably
check with them also and to see that we
can have an intelligent mix of you know
the people that would need to organize
and folks that we would want to have
speaking available on specific great
make sense but if I can check that then
you'd share your own opinion like your
opinion about who the keynote speakers
might be and who their keepo people were
to talk to and so you'd be transparent
about what you're gonna do and you'd be
curious about what everybody thought
because somebody might know like a
conflicting date right yeah you win the
award you're like everybody we talked to
answers on the next so I'm no I'm
special because that's a very human
answer to say that's how you like things
to be that's how you would like today
yep and according to Patrick you you
have the job he'd like she likes your
approach so the thing is a and I think
you should that was interactiveness that
we needed and I think is it when
scrolling I've asked this question of
lots of people and I mean not always you
know where we're gonna you know the date
for next year's all the talks but it's
something usually we ask people like
we're gonna go to lunch or something
some much more important but but the
thing is we always get this answer about
well I would be curious and I be
transparent so everyone already agrees
that that's the best way to make a
decision and because everyone
understands that well guess what if we
want a diversity of opinions and that
strength the if we want to be able to
share their ideas we want to have them
to share how they got to those ideas
share their reasoning and that you know
that we should have some back and forth
some some productive collaborative
conflict and that's the best way to get
to the best possible answer now everyone
says that the thing is that this is not
how humans behave
when there's something that they care
about but another way you actually do
behave that way when it's something that
you don't care about if you get brought
in to mediate for other people on a
topic that's not rangin to you you'll
you'll recommend that but if it's your
own decision that you're part of and
you're really concerned that you get the
right answer and you have an opinion on
what the right answer is then suddenly
you're your mindset changes I think you
imagine could we ajan that you were
going to come in and advocate a
particular soft piece of software and
I'm not going to touch the debate but it
might be kubernetes or it might be your
favorite after tool or whatever it is
I'm not gonna get myself in trouble by
picking one because I know what people
would say is well I just have to
convince people I just have to give them
all the information and then once they
have all the information then of course
they will choose the obvious correct
choice which is still in technology X
right and in that's and so that that's
the problem is that when we would we've
have a decision we care about and we've
invested time energy to come to position
we're now attached to that position
we're no longer seeking the best answer
we're seeking to have our answer win and
now instead of diversity being a
strength differences are a threat and
and as a result we no longer behave in
that generative fashion we no longer are
transparent and said we don't share
everything that we know we don't share
how we got to our decision because we're
just looking to say no this is obviously
the right thing to do and we don't
listen others we're no longer curious
about what they believe what what's
going on here we're gonna give you a
very simple model again this is not
something we created and it's something
called the ladder of inference and it
could be that many of you've heard of
this before or just might be your first
time coming to it if you were to go
search on the googles and look for a
ladder of inference you'll find lots of
pictures of ladders with lots of
different rungs
the details of every single step here
isn't really the important part the the
key elements of this and why we the this
model and what we like about this
particular picture is that it makes it
clear that most the ladder is inside of
your head that there are some parts that
exist in the real world like things
happen and then we take action in the
real world but between stimulus in the
world and our response in the world
we go through this instantaneous step
from selecting data assigning meetings
making assumptions come any conclusions
and beliefs and guess what the beliefs
we have go back and influence even the
data we see at the beginning and at
people who are familiar with that sort
of feedback loop II that sort of
selection bias they can er send there's
cognitive biases at work here so we have
this process going on in our head but it
it's we're not aware that it's happening
and said it feels like there's something
that happens in the world and then we
have the right answer and it's just
objectively correct that this is the
right answer that there's only one way
to interpret it so Jeffrey I observe
that we have about eight minutes left
before Q&A and the meaning that that has
for me is that we might need to
accelerate it a little bit and I assume
that you agree with me and that you
conclude that we should move on to the
next slide is that is that right that
assured by water effectively that was
what I didn't do was say we should move
to the next slide that's right because
then if you had just said that that I
might say well no I you know I'm I I
think we should stay here but you had
some other way of reasoning to with it
that we would not have shared and that's
what winds up happening you're on this
slide you see this on chat shows all the
time where you have one person who says
we should close the borders and somebody
else says immigration is great and they
just argue about it and what they never
do is come down the ladder and try to
understand the other person's position
and the latter gives you a nice guide
I've had people even write it down on
their hands so they can refer to it and
say which we rely on assumptions of my
own meaning where am I in the middle of
the discussion and so and this slide
essentially caps encapsulating back to
our title here if you're frustrated our
expectation our belief is that you're
probably in a situation with dueling
ladders where you have some opinions
someone else has other opinions but you
haven't shared all of the steps of your
ladder and you haven't inquired into all
the subs there so you haven't been
curious and you haven't been transparent
you haven't been behaving the way they
showed it earlier in you know how we
should approach making a decision how
any of you would espouse other people
make decisions so that's the the paradox
here what we're gonna talk about next is
what you can do about it and we're going
to give you a very simple
model you can apply called the four R's
whatever we forgot something we forgot
to tell people to bring equipment I feel
terrible
there's this important equipment that
you need but I hope our listeners will
flip it around it's a piece of paper and
a pen so I hope everybody is because
that's those rare pieces of equipment
that's right it's it's it's very it's
very very high-tech and we're gonna walk
you through now the steps we're gonna
that it takes and again this is me you
should be able to do today so when
you're gonna look at your conversations
to understand where you can improve them
you're going to go through these four
steps there's a the record step and this
is why you need the paper and pencil you
need to reflect and we're gonna walk you
through how to do that there's different
ways to reflect we're going to talk
about something very simple which is
just this issue of are you curious and
are you transparent then having
discovered where you fell short and
you're going to revise what you've done
and then ideally you're in a situation
where you have someone you can talk to
and you can roleplay your alternative
dialogue and by the way along the way
you might discover that once you've
revised that you can repeat and reflect
again to say did you actually improve it
and did I roleplay could I make it
better
oh and then if I do role reversal and
hear what it sounds like okay so there's
six four R's okay yeah yes just counting
I think somehow our master isn't good
right so let's go first three chord you
need some origami need to fold your
paper in half
all right you can do that now on the
right hand side you'll write the
conversation that would have shown up
like on a video recorder so they said I
said they said I said maybe they stood
up left the room I pounded the table
whatever things that would show up on
the left hand you're gonna write down
the invisible the thoughts and feelings
in your head right and then normally
would give you five minutes but we don't
have time for that so you can be doing
it now and I think scroll you're doing
this real time I certainly am and I'm
already done
great there we go I just finished so
that's how long it should take you right
after write down a little bit of what
they said a little bit of what you said
and that's only the things that you
heard and then what the thoughts were on
the left-hand side that's right so you
get those elements are frustrating and
then you reflect on what you've done so
you go back and just if there's real
simple we're gonna look for curiosity
how many questions did you ask on the
right hand side to circle the question
marks and then ask yourself were those
genuine questions for me I didn't ask
any questions that's normally that's
very curious in this conversation now
sometimes people who ask questions but
they're they're not very genuine
questions
Jeffrey should we finish in two minutes
we've got the Q&A right that's nothing
more new in question that's more of a
there's only one answer that's right and
then on the left you'll say what was I
thinking and feeling that I didn't share
and this is where we often find okay so
I'm not being curious about asking
questions about their letter inference
and I'm not sharing my letter I'm not
sure what I know how I got there I'm not
sure how I'm feeling exactly and if as
you do this over time you'll tend to
find triggers you'll tend to find
repeated patterns of you know this seems
to happen again and again and so that's
really that's what you find in your
reflection so then you go to revise and
when you revise you now say well how
could I be more curious how can it be
more transparent is there a way I can
ask a genuine question meaning a
question where the answer might actually
change my mind yeah so I might ask
Jeffrey I'm curious do we want to go
into the QA or do we want to continue
now I'm open to either that would be a
probably a more genuine question yep
well I'm very keen to get to the QA but
I do want to similarly given you are
done no that's no that's great that's
fantastic is it but it's good for us to
get to the last of the four hours would
be a shame to give them three of the
four I agree so you so I says if you
look for the questions and then you look
on the left to say was I able to bring
some of the thoughts I had and some of
my feelings into the dialogue on the
right so a key tip here if you're
frustrated very often you can start
being more transparent by using the
words I'm afraid as in I'm afraid if we
were good on this route that we might be
missing XYZ so I'm afraid our vision
could say I'm afraid that I haven't
answered that question before that was
how I was rising my particular
conversation right and so then last if
you have been able to unless you got
through you created a script and you've
you've revised now maybe you've gone
back around the sort of the revise and
reflect cycle multiple times until you
have something in writing that you like
then you try role-playing with someone
and say how does it sound oh I am I
happy saying this now it's grow you just
got to roleplay yours yep
so how did that feel to you you felt
okay I'm not sure I had the freezing
quite right so I think there's some more
to improve there but it was helpful to
share the feeling I had which was
horrible any idea how they answer for
this and and and this is where the real
reversal is if you have a friend you're
practicing with you might have them say
it back to you because sometimes things
that you find just totally natural
saying when you hear them you go oh I
don't like the way that sounds I
wouldn't want someone saying that to me
so you have another chance to revise so
that's it that's the four R's record
reflect revives and role play and the
thing is the outcome of this is very
predictable this is that this is
something that was is there in the
theory that squirrel and I picked up the
from Chris our juris and it's something
that we've seen in our own practice over
the past eight years has made a huge
difference for us now it's not something
that comes instantly this is a skill
you're developing Chris Archer said it
takes you about as long as it takes to
play a passable game of tennis the good
news is that unlike tennis unless you're
a tennis pro this is something you
couldn't practice every day every every
time you're in conversations of time
you're in meetings at work and rhythm
you're frustrated you can think oh this
is a way for me to go back and say how
am i contributing how could I be more
transparent how could it be more curious
and we think you'll get better outcomes
as a result so this is one of the
elements for a book in our book we go
through five other types of
conversations will reply this same
theory where we reflect in different
ways and revise to different outcomes
and you've got up these slides so you
can have a look at this in more depth
and detail then we have time for today
right and and so with that I think we
should go over to took you a
so that was fantastic first of all you
guys are a dynamic duo it's really fun
so a few questions how do you convince
your colleagues to be open about your
sloppy right there
so the problem the problem I've already
defected inward number four so when you
start a sentence with how do you
convince the problem is it's your fault
that's good news so you're frustrated by
something and it's your fault so you're
what you should do what you should do is
recast your question so instead of
trying to convince them to be open what
you might do is have a conversation with
them in which you share your reasoning I
have been through this crazy talk at
some crazy time in the morning and these
insane people told me that I should talk
to you more would that be helpful what
do you think about that my reasoning for
that is that I think we don't have very
good conversations and here's an example
from last week if you have that kind of
conversation
the result is likely to be better they
may not be convinced so it may be that
you get convinced that's the whole point
of the dueling ladders is that on the
track shows you never see somebody say
you know you're right actually we should
close the borders I understand that can
I join your party that just never
happens so we are looking at where the
option of having that kind of change of
mindset and when you do that you're more
likely to get a better result
so words matter your nod to the right
words and in your own mind so this is
your own mind how do I convince so you'd
stop thinking that okay so as a manager
how can I foster this open culture and
what if what benefits is given me as
manager also I guess to the team yeah so
I think that the benefits are better
decision-making as a group also that
that people are are happier the result
because they feel that they're part of
it it's like adding your own egg you
know the people are its if people
usually are happy not just if they get
their away but if they feel like they've
been heard so they're quite happy to go
along and commit to things that they
weren't there idea as long as they feel
that people have heard them out so
that's I think one of the big benefits
here both transparency and curiosity you
get more ideas from people and and it's
so therefore you're better decisions and
people are more committed to the result
because they've been heard and how do
you foster it is the main reason the
main thing is to be transparent and
curious yourself much look like you
modeled for us earlier on the question
of where we we when would we host the
calm
if you go with it that idea like we're
here to get all the possible information
people generally I find are quite happy
to take you up on that invitation and
let's say that your manager isn't you
know the type that would be as
transparent or you know so so well yeah
we're not the trip that the manager now
we're going with somebody matches us is
that right so if you're in that
situation I claim that you're gonna be
net better off if you you don't go to
the top of your ladder if you don't
start dueling and the reason is that if
you just join the other person at the
top of the ladder and just argue there's
no chance whatsoever that anyone will
find out what your reasoning was that
you'll be transparent or that you'll
have any chance of finding out what the
other person thinks if you ask questions
and you're open to them and you might
like for example find out their
reasoning they're really interested in
telling you their reason they aren't
much interested in hearing yours but
that's still hopeful to you that's still
ahead you've got half of it you've got
the curiosity haven't got the
transparency and and that's still a net
win I've never heard anyone of to hear
an argument for why it could be better
to simply not share anything for have no
sharing either direction for arguing
that that simply presents the dueling
matters problems I'll say this is this
is a common question we get in our we
tell people is if you if you start this
way you'll change the way other people
behave they will react differently when
you act differently they're not
guaranteed but it's more likely and
there's there's no other we don't know
another way to get to that change
behavior
so exactly and the theory is called
action science that means you can go
experiment so go do an experiment try
this out we're right if we're wrong
please get in touch with us and tell us
we're wrong it went by very quickly
we're on conversational transformation
calm so you can come and find this lots
of place they're awesome and very last
one how would you see this improving
team stand up Geoffrey can you take that
one I thought that you would jump on is
your first one says here okay I think
the the stand ups a lot of it would
probably be in the retrospective re
describe your stand ups because this
question is are your stamps already okay
yeah the real thing question is are
people sharing the relevant information
and are they curious about what do
people are saying if people are showing
up to stand up just to say that a bit
and they're not listening then you're
you're missing that on that you're on
that front of curiosity you can also say
well are there important elements that
you're not sharing in the stand up then
you might be missing transparency so
it's a good test there and a fun game to
play is to think gosh if we had some
secret information somebody's holding a
secret key and you've got an award if
you found out what it was imagine that
during the standoff your goal is to find
out what that is and that's a fun game
because it makes you be very curious
about the other person and in fact it's
usually true that there's some piece of
information in the group that you don't
know it's just that you don't know about
it neither does the person I was
fantastic thank you both so much for
joining us at all the talks every every
kind of speaker and panelist helps
contribute to charity so thank you for
taking the time and sharing with us