ask our AJ are you great how are you I
am doing wonderful so with that I am
going to turn it over to you folks just
a quick reminder before I do put your
questions in the Q&A panel next to the
stream and at the end of JJ's talk we'll
get to your questions and make sure that
you can get those answered so JJ with
that I will turn it over to you
sounds great thank you so much hi yes
I'm JJ I work for IBM as you can see I'm
wearing an IBM t-shirt that's how you
know but I am going to today talk about
using inspect to validate VMware
templates if you don't know VMware
templates are a way to create clothes
machines to stamp out VMs basing this
out of VMware now I was originally going
to send some slides and all but due to
the time restrictions I'm just going to
jump right in and show some some code
and hopefully that's what people want to
see and then you can take my repo if you
so choose and play around with it and
then maybe even edit it to make
yourselves a little bit easier the goal
of this talk is just basically make sure
that you have something to start with
there's so many people out there who
have no idea where to start when it
comes to this and this is just a simple
example to get that done so let me start
sharing my screen and we'll share in the
screen now let's see oops there we go so
I would be remiss by first not
mentioning call for code IBM gives me a
lot of leeway to be able to speak at
different conferences and and and
supports me and being able to tell the
tell the story one of our big pushes
right now is something called for code
which allows you to help use software to
fight including many other disasters and
issues around the world but we are
focusing this year on kovat 19 so just
humor me go to call for code.org and I
kind of just poke around that would help
me there validate me being able to come
and speak at things like this
okay so now let's talk about the tools
we're going to be using well your boss
or your your company is decided we are
we need to have some way to start
validating our templates in a an
efficient and efficient manner
well I'm gonna put together something
called using something called ansible
which will do some automation for you
something called Packer specifically
which will actually automate and build
the templates for us I'm going to use
the VMware plug-in for for Packer which
will actually build the ISO for us and
then at the very end I'm going to use
something called chef inspect which will
validate the templates to make sure it's
what I expect it to be if you've ever
seen this is actually a VMware console
on the IBM cloud because you can get
VMware on IBM and we are going to play
around in some of the templates I have
this repo here which I can give out
after the talk inside of slack if so if
you so choose where it has all the code
that we're going to be playing with and
the beauty of this is that it really is
just stripped down so we you see the
there bare minimum to get the things
done which is nice and then finally
we're going to be using Jenkins because
everyone uses Jenkins at some point in
their career and it's kind of just a
nice universal way of explaining all
this you can either ollie different
other CDs CI CD systems out there but
specifically I'm going to be using
Jenkins because I thought was more
Universal okay so I am going to minimize
that to make sure I have my notes so the
first thing first I truly believe that
the templates you should have and use
configuration management to build up
from the ground up is so we're going to
take this golden image which is just a
base install of Debian I'm going to
create a new template for it and I'll
just in called AoE you because I'm a
nerd and type in Dvorak and I'm going to
build this this template very simply and
power it on it'll take a second to do
because you know computers but as this
comes up I want to prove to you that it
is a blank template with nothing on it
and what we're going to do is I am going
to first install
using this playbook right here I'm going
to install nginx so we're just going to
run the run the the pipeline to make
sure it all works and get nginx on that
but first I'm gonna prove to you that
there is nothing there so bring this up
and then is this up and running are you
there
refresh tu-tu-tu-tu-tu-tu waiting for
VMware tools like you always do
come on VMware tools or open-vm-tools I
think it is now because open-source
singing a long wait another thing -
there we go so it's a 225 alright so I'm
going to do SSH admin E or Metheny it's
a 216 and 225 here we go so if you don't
know the first thing that nginx does is
creates an engine X directory and as you
can see here Oh sh oh and Gen X it is
not that cool cool we all agree that
this is a blank blank type like very
very basic debian 10 and it's all it's
going to show there but now what I'm
going to do is this is going I am going
to kick off this build and I'm going to
build master because that is what I want
master so I'm gonna build him after here
and with that run well that's running
I'm going to talk a little bit about
inspire ansible if you don't know as you
can see it's written in yellow you'll be
able to make sure that using the after
resource that it'll pull in and jex and
make sure it's the latest version and it
updates the cache to make sure that we
have yep get repo there also as you
notice very importantly it starts engine
X on there this is very vital for later
the this narrative where what I'll end
up doing is island of creating a PR
where I'll actually end up adding a user
and then I'm going to show the actual
security portion of it which is the
inspect making sure is how it expected
to be so as you can see here we are
actually building the main Packer image
now and there we go it's calling the VM
again waiting for VM tools to come up as
this goes in spec is basically a
compliance language where you can write
in very simple English like language to
make sure that things are the state this
states you expect it to be in
specifically what we're going to be
doing is very validating very simple
profile which is making sure in nginx is
the state we expect it to be in which I
will show you here in a moment
and then also you can pull in other
profiles from other other people or
other companies or good straight
defaults which we'll do here in just a
second to make sure that for instance
Etsy host isn't set to seven seven seven
for instance that's usually a bad thing
as you can see some sanity checks there
is a Linux baseline right here to make
sure that Etsy shadow exists and the
states we expect if you look here
there's a bunch of good open-source dev
SEC Linux baselines so you can just
swoop in to make sure that your your
profile is that pause to saying defaults
again this is one of those things that
if you just put it inside if your
pipeline instance in this case my Jacobs
pipeline this will always run this will
always make sure that my my repo or my
template is exactly as secure as it can
be by these open source standards and it
as you can see it took no time at all
which in turn allows for you know one
less thing to worry about
and then as you can see it's pulled in
the nginx profile here and I'll bring up
nginx well as going just one last time
we are going to validate that every
single time that this directory should
exist here this the actual nginx
application is up and running and has
various permissions and most importantly
that nginx should be actually running
this is due to later on the narrative
here and as you can see we do some
PowerShell and make sure everything's
built and we see that we have a green
pipeline yay all good ok cool so what
we're going to do now is I'm going to go
back to that exact same file here and
I'm going to put in a PR here where we
are going to it's going to add an ops
user so as you can see it's the exact
same code nginx and now we're on top of
the same code we're going to put inside
of this PR user so I'm going to come
over here and go back here get checked
out that's pjj a good PR ok oops
PR too because I'm lazy ok git status
get good comments I'm a good a good PR
push origin PR q ok because I have
ancient or my Jenkins instance tied up
against the repo no we will take it but
took about a minute or so for the actual
kickoff to happen but again this is just
making sure the pipeline is doing what I
expect it to do which is you know at
this new user the beauty of it is as
you'll see here in a moment when this
kicks off I actually have two different
JSON files to tell the and to sell
specifically Jenkins what to do what
we're going to create is actually
another template with the name of the
machine Debian - PR which you'll see
here in a moment
so I can actually go validate it myself
even though I have all the automate
automate occation but if the PR breaks
for instance it'll put it into a state
where it'll be broken but I can only see
why it broke so instead of blowing away
the template after the fact I can
actually go do the investigation on the
machine to make sure it's what I expect
it to be which is wonderful okay it
should be happening any minute and of
course there we go as you see it's
pending and it's going to pull this in
just a moment we will see here it takes
about two minutes as you can see which
isn't too bad again this is just a demo
so as we'll go and we're installing no
you don't actually to install a lot of
this stuff every single time if you
don't want you can I make this quicker
um oh no what happened here
Debian gold not found that's not good oh
it's because I didn't actually create it
okay I need to change the name one of
the beauties of the the thing I do is I
actually you notice I take a steam stamp
and create the gold image so I can
always roll it back every time I push
out master I create a new stamp of the
original gold image so if something goes
horribly horribly wrong I have that
actual template there to run run
backwards so what I'll do is I will
delete this first and I was actually in
my notes - story of hope I've demos I
guess and then I will take this delete
that okay okay if you haven't noticed if
you are VMware user you're probably
wondering JJ that should all happen like
automatically why you keep refreshing it
turns I have to go through a proxy but
that's a different conversation for
another day okay let's try that again so
I will go ahead and come over here and I
will because I am paranoid I am going to
do this because I have actually seen
that go awry before stage commits oh man
because like all good hops guys deep
down inside I write the best the best
comments I'll try to make a joke I'm
thinking now yeah
urging PRQ now i'm kagaz of the time i'm
trying to shoot past this stuff as
quickly as i can to make sure that we
have some time for questions of if so we
so desire come back over here show me
some come on come on so let me go ahead
and while this is running I will show
the actual Jenkins file that I have is
an example here
Jenkins files are running in groovy if
you didn't know as you can see I this is
very honestly kind of hacky but it does
it does what we're expecting you to do
which as we saw in installs Packer it
makes sure and sees what branch it's on
if it's anything other than master it
grabs in a variables file and then sorry
if it is if it is master it grabs in my
default variables file which has the
names that I'm expected to be and then
the PRS and then if it is anything other
than master it pulls in the not master
one which I'm again naming his heart
then it runs Packer as we've seen and
then it goes ahead and builds the other
version and then it runs a very simple
power power COI script to make sure it
changes the names force which as this is
going as we can see as we see we're pet
building the Packer image right now
because it's starting to be nice to me
oops starting to be nice to me while
that is running I will show you the
convert to cold machine police don't pay
attention to that password as you can
see it does just some very basic power
COI things again you can't actually get
to this V V center so you know I'm okay
we're showing that please don't steal
that password
let's see here and the next goal which
if I have my timing down properly we
will be going ahead and you know what I
will just go ahead and prep that now um
we're going to go ahead and say that
that was successful but it turns out
because the world is an evil place
sometimes we've had someone decided
oops beep decide someone has decided to
move from nginx to Apache and they went
ahead and changed the the playbook here
to stop nginx of remove nginx and then
ensure that Apache 2 was installed and
then make sure we start apache 2 now if
you notice this system just changing the
playbook so they went along and push
this in and we're like hey wait a second
that's enough that's not great but okay
go ahead and do that cook and as you can
see we've had our inspect we've
everything everything he's built up how
we expect it to be and then gift master
hip check out let's be bad dr2 so come
back over here they come along and
decided to push this in yes yes I'm a
bad actor
it's Bush organ your to somebody's come
along and decided that they really
really wanted Apache instead of nginx
but as you'll notice here in a moment
it'll actually push everything out build
it exactly how we expect it to
and double check that we still have that
debian gold here we go good
I just lost the repo copy-paste and go
so we'll create this repo again I'm a
bad actor and I again I apologize for
shooting past shooting through this so
quickly but hopefully your signs see how
all the different pieces to come
together where we'll have the actual
good good process with the inspect
checking to make sure that it does what
we expect but now when we have someone
who has not updated the inspect profile
because we're already just running it we
make sure that the status is there and
everything will happen we should keyword
should good PR as you saw it was
successful which is what we wanted we're
finishing and come on so we're gonna go
ahead and just pulling off that same
golden image where you're going to make
the changes to attempt to make the
changes we're going I see this run and
it's gonna fail not that I'm spoiling
this or anything but you know gotta
gotta tell that story to do oh no what
happened there
oh come on come on JJ the template one
already existed so obviously you need to
write some better clean up around this I
had better clean up I will admit but
computers they're not always the nicest
things in the world but with a little
bit of work and a little bit of
robustness everything kind of works a
little bit better and make this modified
you do push origin let's try that again
go back over here we should see 44 going
come on 44 44 I got 42 it's been 19
minutes and 45 seconds so I want to want
to make sure people have time to ask
questions we'll say so choose but I want
to show them it actually does what I say
it does come on
maybe me me
maybe computers do your work maybe we've
seen it kick off a couple times now I'm
a bad actor there we go pretty good
triggered triggered there we go
I call him Kiko by the way if you didn't
notice Piko Piko but but you know i have
kids
he goes very helpful if you ever seen
Dora the Explorer here we go
bad actor we're quoting the VM and we're
powering on the VM oops
we're waiting for that IP because
open-vm-tools is fast um well this is
going I strongly suggest taking a look
at the tutorials for a chef in spec it
is unbelievably powerful and because of
the there's many many plugins to run
inspect with other things it will make
your life significantly easier
especially for security and validating
things that you need to you write it
once and it we can just run and you
never have to worry about the checks
again as long as you put it inside of
some type of pipeline to validate things
and I will show here because we have
decided to install
playbook come on - Nikolai our enemy
here we go
ensure nginx so it's installing because
it's inside impotant
it's installing it's making sure I'd
nginx is that and then we install our
ops user which I never actually showed I
mean I guess I could now but that ops
user is there so I could actually SSH in
as it that's my public key now it's
installing Apache - and then it's going
to run our sanity checks because sanity
checks because we have policies there we
go now running in spec and then ah wait
a second did you see this ha ha ha
because we did not change our our
profile at the same time and because we
had stopped engine X and due to that
they pipeline stops and then blows
everything up which is exactly what
we're hoping to see right it gives us
that opportunity I guess I missed a flag
that's not supposed to destroy the VM
but I guess it did this time again this
is exactly what we're hoping for so you
don't sneak in things you don't expect
inspectors your validator and make sure
that things are what you hope they are
so hopefully hopefully that was
educational and maybe as you saw it was
just a bunch of code flying back and
forth but my Reis what my access our
police never hesitate to reach out to me
I literally do have the email address of
Awesome at IBM calm and I just lost the
screen uh where did it go when I stole
here hello nope you're still here but
yeah we looks like you stopped sharing
your screen yes that's what I meant um
so I'm one to be cognizant people to see
if they have any questions or thoughts
um we have eight minutes left is that
right yeah a little less cos we'll
switch over to the next speaker but
before we do yeah if you've got
questions folks again Q&A tab to the
rates
and I know I just pointed the wrong
direction cuz everything's backwards to
the right side of the the stream go
ahead ask your questions or are you
gonna be JJ are you gonna be around in
slack for a little bit too that people
can connect with you absolutely
III again said I'm sorry that it was so
quick and there was a lot of information
there but hopefully it got the point
across of using inspect to validate your
templates which is if you in the VMware
world normally configuration management
the building up these templates aren't
something you do you don't write the
code to get the template to be done well
people are starting to do that but
they're not doing the second side of the
coin which is validating they are just
writing the code and saying yeah it's
done I'm cool it's all good yeah but no
no you need to have some validation you
need to make sure because in six months
time that person's going to change nginx
to Apache and then when you get that
template out to production because you
just cloned it out because honestly
that's what you're gonna do you're gonna
be like you're gonna have a production
outage and that's usually not a good
thing for your boss to find out about
all right well I don't have any
questions for you showing up in either
the chats but we will let people connect
with you maybe they're being shy and
they're waiting for you to show up and
slack so we'll we'll let you hop over to
slack then thank you very much JJ it was
that was actually really enlightening
and you know of course the you know live
demo always there to pop up and bite but
it was I think it allowed you to show
some good examples to of some of the
things you were doing so thank you again
and everybody catch JJ he'll be in the
slack channel you can go ahead and ask
him any questions you have