hi Susan I'm gonna add you to the stream
so we can Chad now how are you good meet
you finally
yeah it's nice to meet you also as two
people with the same last name within
two hours it's interesting yeah you know
how how fortuitous does that name mean
something cause like I don't know what
that would mean their last name um it
we're brother and sister
and this is the first conference that
we've ever done together so it's sort of
a Wow big milestone that for me anyway
he's done a lot yes so we're super happy
to have you I'm and I guess we can get
started
maybe yeah I'm going you wanna yeah
share your screen um alright so I'm
gonna share it now and so it's my
pleasure to introduce Susan who's gonna
be talking about how did GRC your DevOps
thank you get started sure um so yeah I
gave a talk similar to this at RSA
earlier this year this one's a little
bit shorter and hopefully a little bit
more focused for the audience but like
Sasha said I'm su la la Pomeroy I am the
senior manager for the compliance team
at fastly and I've been doing security
and compliance for over 15 years now and
some people think I'm crazy for that
before that I taught at University and
I'm a published poet so I bring a lot of
different skills I guess to this to this
space so today I want to talk about
DevOps and GRC collaboration but to
understand sort of where I've come from
I want to start with a little story I
left a doc of audit job and entered into
a tech startup and when I did I had a
very lively conversation with an ops
person that I know about change
management and it went
like this I said you can't have change
control that's effective if you don't
have manager approval and a meeting with
all of your stakeholders so they can you
know of course tell you what's wrong to
which he replied what's better is if you
have peer review and automated tests and
I said yeah but all of the frameworks
say that you have to have manager
approval and he said but the managers
aren't really close to the changes that
that you're wanting and it's safer to
have engineers who are closer to that
code to do reviews and to have those
automated tests well we've continued to
have this conversation on and on we
continue to learn from each other to
this day and that's the key that I want
for us today is to stir this
conversation and to continue to have it
between those folks who end up doing
audit and those folks who build the
systems that we are auditing so all of
this started when James Wickett asked
this question on Twitter a little while
ago and I sort of kind of shook my head
because I've been working in tech for a
while I've been sitting next to my
engineering and operations departments
in meetings with them pretty much every
day and I thought everybody was doing
this and it turns out not so much right
gr C's bin next to DevOps through the
past decade of evolution of DevOps
practices but GRC has been very busy
adapting and evolving on their own based
on data breaches and lots of new
legislation and GRC has been sort of
more reactive instead of being able to
look at and evolve with the positive
change that DevOps has brought to the
industry so this short version of what
I'm here to tell you today is that
DevOps and GRC collaboration is going to
make audits smoother for your auditors
and your engineers and everybody will
end up happier in the end I want to
challenge any auditors in the audience
to think about how they're viewing those
traditional controls and that we have to
change those views and we should change
those views
but the key that I really want us to get
a come away with is that when we
calibrate how things work between our
ops and our dev and our security and our
audit organizations that is going to be
the foundation of more resilient systems
so let's start with why I think security
frameworks are your friends they're
built on very sound security measures
and tenets that everybody wants and
they're meant to be and they're written
to be flexible to your business based on
the risk profile of what you do for your
business they're also there they also
enable engineering teams to get what
they want which is visibility and
tooling that they need to do their jobs
better security frameworks also give
your business the reason to put in the
security programs that you want to do
anyway as you know security usually cost
a lot of money so having a framework
that you're audited against sort of
gives you that reason
however framers have also been
advertently been very unclear on how to
implement the very sort of nonspecific
requirements that that they have and and
if they're implemented in a way that's
super complex or in a way that's at a
risk level that's maybe higher than what
the business needs that has the
capability to create some some serious
business slowdowns security frameworks
can also be interpreted as being super
rigid and when you implement a lot of
rigidity in those controls it makes
folks do things in a way that's contrary
to the way that they would work
naturally I want Anna caveat here some
security controls have rigidity to them
so this is an entirely misplaced and
then security frameworks also make a
whole lot of paperwork and as a as an
auditor I this is very true and this is
the part of my job that I hate I think
everybody remembers what cab meetings
were like right so let's get down to the
basics of what we want auditors we want
something super simple we want effective
security controls that can
evidence and that are repeatable and
engineers well they want stable systems
and when the systems aren't stable they
want to be able to improve and respond
to super quickly they also want to have
a common systems understanding across
all of their teams across engineering
and operations and they want to have as
much visibility into the systems as
possible so that they can see how
they're operating your security teams
want well they want secure enough
systems they want a tested code that
includes testing to the OIC top ten they
want visibility to unusual activity but
they want to be able to define that
specifically so they're not woken up at
2:00 a.m. when someone's pseudos into
production and they want rule-following
with systems and with people so that
when somebody does sudo into a box at
2:00 a.m. because of an incident or an
outage they're not necessarily broken up
because that might be that's considered
maybe normal behavior this list of what
we want for all of these different
organizations isn't a full list of
everything that we want but it does
highlight some areas of similarity we
all want resiliency we all like
visibility and an ability to respond
quickly and we all want quality in the
systems that we run but how we want it
is super different engineers don't care
that they can evidence that they've done
their job they just want to be able to
do their jobs and auditors don't care
how fast we fix things or do things we
just want them to be super methodical
and documented remember perfect is often
the enemy of good enough except for when
you have to explain an exception on your
sock to report to your customers and
your executive leadership the key here
is that we all want to make our jobs
easier and our goals are to force our
methods so when I say our I mean
auditors and engineers and security
folks we don't want to impose the way we
think on other
the business our goal is to calibrate
with the other areas of the business so
that our common goals right we're all
working toward the same business goals
which includes risk reduction we want to
be able to reach those and that's really
the goal of any compliance framework in
order to do that though we have to start
minimizing the gap between work is
imagined which is how security controls
and frameworks are designed and work is
done which is how security is actually
accomplished so where we position
ourselves within these mental models of
how things work is going to be the key
to how we get the DevOps principles in
the GRC principles calibrated and
aligned if you haven't read the
varieties of human work by Stephen Shrek
and I've put a link here please go do so
this is it's super seminal and and I'm
mostly going to focus on work as
imagined and work as done today so
workers imagined starts with how we
design frameworks and controls it's
usually starts with in a perfect world I
would do something this way and then we
draw a process flow diagram and we write
a wiki page on how to do this and then
as auditors were like this is great
it'll work all the time this way right
unfortunately the way work is actually
done is like this it's super messy we
may start with a process flow and a
process document and then an operator
will start seeing some getting some
other indicators or getting additional
information and then they'll start
deviating from that process in order to
meet their goals
remember it's visibility into the system
it's keeping the system's stable it's
understanding what's going on in the
system and those things meeting those
goals may or may not actually follow
procedure so you all may remember in
2009 when Captain Sullenberger landed
sorry US Airways flight 1549 in the
Hudson after two bird strikes this is a
prime example that I always like to use
about an operator using their expertise
in their adaptive capacity to keep a
system safe in this case the system was
the aircraft and the passengers and crew
on board this isn't something you can
write into a procedure right how this
crew was able to land this plane and and
not have any any fatalities is testament
to their adaptive capacity it's not
something that we should react to like
we have with certain data breaches etc
and adapt it into a framework either
Sydney Decker says procedures are an
investment in safety but not always
procedures are thought to be required to
achieve safe practice yet they are not
always necessary nor likely ever
sufficient for creating safety and
that's the key here nor likely ever
sufficient for creating safety but we
seem to want as auditors is for
processes to be performed accurately and
consistently all the time but that's
antithetical to keeping a system safe if
the question is dealing with whether you
have an exception on an audit report or
you have an extended outage that's going
to affect your customers in your Avenue
I promise you procedures and controls
are going to change because reality is
always going to trump procedure so when
you're designing a security control or
process ask yourselves and by yourselves
I mean auditors and engineers what is
the risk you're trying to mitigate what
are the goals for this process or
control I promise you what's in your
head as an auditor isn't the same thing
that's in the head of yourself as an
engineer and is also different from
what's in the head of your product
manager and your security engineer so
once you explicitly answer this question
across those across those boundaries
you're going to start a
Publishing that common ground you need
to reach the same goal which is that
risk reduction and more resilient
systems so these are the two things
we're talking about reasonable assurance
that a control is in place and timely
detection when that control can't be in
place now reasonable and timely our
normative terms so you're going to want
to define this because what's reasonable
for one company is not going to be
reasonable for another and what's timely
for one security control isn't going to
be timely for another either back in the
day when I started in security the cloud
was a super scary place and no one
wanted to go there especially the
government and so this was one of the
funny things people would post on their
cubicle walls right the best security
control is the is the one that keeps us
disconnected right especially from the
cloud so reasonable assurance isn't
looking for a control that works a
hundred percent of the time but we do
want to know when things go wrong I love
this tweet by Jessica divita who's
speaking later today the safest aircraft
never flies the safest anesthesia is
never given all operators and risky
domains must find and adjust the balance
between acute faster better cheaper
goals and chronic goals such as safety
this is where we as auditors have to
realize the adaptive capacity of our
engineers are one of the best security
controls that we can have in place so
let's talk about one of my favorite
security controls and my favorite I
don't mean favourite separation of
duties so according to nest separation
of duties addresses the potential for
abuse of authorized privileges and helps
reduce the risk of malevolent activity
without collusion sort of the key there
is without collusion this can this
control typically has been used in terms
of financial systems and fraud right you
don't want the person who requested the
check to process the check or sign that
check but it doesn't really all
translate that well into our IT systems
which we have traditionally translated
it
- so in the past we've seen this
cardinal rule right of Deb's write the
code and Ops deploys and maintains the
code in it you know the past decade has
shown us that it hasn't worked so well
in DevOps has worked really hard to sort
of change that paradigm and yet GRC
still insists on imposing this as a
security control so what's happened is
we while trying to implement this
security controller separation of duties
were enabling and enforcing more risk on
our systems so the problem has always
been that separation of duties is
assumed to require multiple humans as
primary operators of different functions
and this causes this conflict between
audit and engineering right one reduces
risk and the other ends up reducing
productivity right it's a slowdown and a
risk potentially two systems resiliency
so there's a whole lot of complexity
that's associated with separation of
duties and oftentimes we don't end up
telling each other the stories that we
the stories of what we need out of that
work so you may have an engineer who's
who's saying in an outage I have to be
able to fix the system without a whole
lot of people I have to be able to be
fast this is important for the business
is important for my goals and then you
know your internal audit team is saying
but we have to have separate people to
develop and deploy because the
regulations say so your product people
are saying but if we can't move quickly
we can't beat our competition to solve
that customer problem then the meantime
your CEO is sort of stuck in the middle
right if we get a finding on our audit
we'll lose the trust of our customers
but if the systems are down we're going
to lose that to a couple of other
challenges that we see related to
separation of duties is when a control
or process activity is written for its
process for process sake right and
Decker refers to the systems as
malicious compliance that means that if
when you're following a process to the
letter it removes that capability to
adapt it
really causes more of it to your systems
it reduces the capability to adapt to
situations that the process wasn't even
designed to cover and it couldn't even
consider it because they because they
didn't know when they were developing
that process to begin with close behind
that is the idea of checkbox compliance
which is when you've got controls that
are in place and procedures that are in
place and the only benefit that they
give to the business is that you pass an
audit is that it's it's only for past
well it's only for audit eventually
you're going to have situations where
the reasons and the context behind why
you do that thing is completely lost and
when that is lost and that sort of
communal knowledge isn't passed on from
one team or one engineer to another that
thing that seems meaningless just
doesn't happen anymore and that will
cause some visibility issues and
additional risk right both of these
equal hire business risk so ask
yourselves when you're trying to
implement separation of duties what is
the risk that you're trying to mitigate
is it fraud is it authorized access for
unauthorized activities are you trying
to sort of mitigate that insider threat
how how likely is that insider threat
considering everything else that you
have in place you're never going to have
the same answer especially depending on
what you're applying separation of
duties to but you want to dig in and ask
those specific questions what systems
what data what teams what business
drivers are the security control trying
to answer for it may be financial risk
it may be availability risk sometimes
human separation is really the answer
and I've you know sort of but grudgingly
you know accepted this over the past few
years but it's not always the only
answer so how can we be okay with
engineers deploying their own code I I
get this question a lot from other
auditors who seem
really scared about allowing engineers
to deploy their own code well first we
trust engineers use their expertise to
adapt right there we actually have
controls in all of our security
frameworks for this we ask for
background checks we ask for performance
reviews we want to make sure that though
that folks with the right qualifications
are hired to do this work that is
allowing folks to use their expertise to
adapt the other thing that we can do is
make sure that we have a safe and
transparent environment so that when a
procedure has to be deviated from in
order to meet those goals folks can come
forward and talk about those deviations
in order to change those processes to
become more efficient but more efficient
the psychological safety is super
important because otherwise you won't
know when folks have deviated from a
particular process and again that causes
more risk this is putting in place some
guardrails for folks not speed bumps but
you can't audit trust right so so we do
have ways in which we can make sure that
we verify that things are okay for audit
we can do that through transparency
right we have lots of logs we have lots
of evidence and artifacts and we have
visibility into how this how our DevOps
practices work we can also make sure
that we understand as auditors our tools
and our our people involved in these
processes so we can utilize the CI city
pipeline for deployments right and
thereby have lots of logs to show
exactly what happened we can also make
sure that we put in place the knowledge
share of people and tools doing code
review we can also invite our security
friends to make sure that they're in on
the story by reviewing anomalies sharing
that information with our engineering
and ops departments and audit as well
and so how do we get there we get here
by having effective communication and I
know that sometimes communication can be
super difficult your compliance team or
internal audit may sit it makes it under
your finance team or your law team
sometimes compliance sits within the
security team which is nice sometimes
security sits under engineering and so
there aren't that those silos is to
create sometimes you have an internal
tools team sometimes you're small enough
you don't have a tool like that so we
want to make sure that we try to break
down these silos and I'm going to talk
about a couple of ways that we can do
that so yeah communication is hard
typically some of the challenges that we
have are when information is shared it's
shared among a sort of managerial level
and it doesn't filter down the same way
depending on who that manager is right
that horrible game of telephone we also
have worked for audits is usually
requested in haste during an audit very
short audit timeframe and it's without
context please give me that screen
capture from that config tool and
because I need it for the external
auditors but that engineer probably
hasn't done that in a year if it's even
the same engineer who did it for you
last year the other challenge that we
have is a time right we're all busy at a
hundred percent or 110 percent doing the
job that we're there to do so how can I
make more time to meet with folks of
these other organizations that I maybe
have an idea of what they're going to
ask me to do right so I beg of you make
friends with your compliance teams and
do this by not inviting them out for
beverages but invite them to your
meetings put them on your engineering
distribution lists this way they learn
and understand more about how you work
which makes them more empathetic to
designing those security controls and
processes to match how you work right
and hey auditors make sure you go to
those read those emails go to those
all-hands meetings and talk to folks in
those organizations the next thing is we
want to establish common ground right so
what
Engineers know about your security
controls and frameworks sometimes it's
only what you've you know what they've
gleaned from those audit requests
what do auditors know about the systems
and engineering and tools that your
business supports make sure that you as
an auditor know what your tech stack
looks like you don't have to code it you
just have to know it and ask each other
what's going to make your job easier and
this way we can design those processes
better the other thing that you can do
is establish workable internal checks so
this means and monthly or quarterly
recurring activities make sure that you
work together when those when those are
there so so that you can oh so sorry so
that you can find ways that those
processes are maybe not working so well
for folks but the key with this one is
make sure that psychological safety is
there internal checks aren't to get
people in trouble they are to help
improve those processes if you have an
infrastructure product manager make sure
they're in your audit planning meetings
because they're going to be able to take
a whole lot of information back to your
organization and share your controls
matrix with engineering publicize it if
you get a lot of questions about it it
means they don't know a lot about it and
you have got some work to do right and
then go to product meetings the best
thing you can do is understand what's in
the planning process so that you can
feed those security controls in at the
front end of your development so I'll
leave you with this systems break
processes are deviated from this is
normal work what we have to understand
and rely on is that people's ability to
adapt to adverse situations is going to
be the strongest security control that
we can have I have a lot of references
at the end I will make these slides
available online and I'm happy to talk
about any questions that you have
so we're we don't have a lot of
questions coming in right now but we you
have a couple comments saying that
people love this talk well thank you I
will say so for now I want to ask about
my own question so I've seen like I've
seen organizations where people just
don't trust each other and so there's a
lot of this like okay I can't let my you
know engineers push to production and my
usual answer is like you you hire these
people like what why would you hire them
if you don't trust them right but
there's also like the non-biological
state where people are required by some
type of government regulation to follow
procedures that don't make sense anymore
like how do you how to get over that um
so typically the way that I've addressed
this is to ask typically our security
frameworks to say they don't say how you
do something they say that you have to
do a thing to achieve an end right some
of them again are pretty prescriptive
but you know you can you can have
separation of duties with machines and
not people and so you know DevOps is
sort of built on some of that automation
and stuff and so the more visibility you
give to auditors the better they feel
about the security controls that they
think are supposed to be in place and so
I it's kind of like I changed my mind
moment right and so I've had long
conversations with external auditors to
kind of show them we've remembered
what's the risk that we're trying to
mitigate why are you asking me to have
this thing in place if we've reduced the
risk that this thing was intended to
mitigate I want to show you that we've
mitigated it it may not be the way that
you thought that I should mitigate it
but we've mitigated it so another
question great talk um any
recommendations for the first steps on
this path to follow lots and lots of
talking and lots of listening so I think
that the best thing that ever happens to
me was to make a lot of friends and
listen a
in to our operations group who told me
how our platform worked and so just as
an audit if I'm if if the person who's
asking the question is an auditor go to
your engine areas and just listen to
understand how what is their day like
how do they do their jobs right and if
you are an engineer or like really go
ask your auditor folks how what how do
you do this job every day what is this
you know why are you asking me to do
this right and and have those just
honest conversations they're not a lot
of the challenges that we have are that
people bring assumptions right about
like you said about trust right I don't
trust auditors to know what I should be
doing
I don't trust engineers to do the right
thing I mean if we if we start with a
basis of of trust and develop that sort
of that common ground right that
understanding then we're gonna come a
lot closer I so another question that
you kind of like saying to what you just
said um do you think auditors and
security should be members of the to
pizza team um so I have had the
privilege to work with as on as a
compliance person within a security team
and I have had the privilege of working
on a compliance team that does not
report in directly have direct reporting
structure into the security team I
absolutely do you think that it's very
effective it's more effective to be sort
of embedded in that security team I know
some folks think that there's a
separation of duties issue and
especially with some frameworks that's
absolutely true so it's really going to
depend on what the need is of your
business but there is the question if
you and John got along growing up and
also a request for you to finish with a
poem oh my goodness yes we we got along
some day you can ask him about his
breakdancing capabilities and
short Wow I wasn't actually prepared for
this but sure uh do we have we have one
minute okay how does this appropriate to
read on that so this is a poem called
swallowing Antarctica it's a sonnet when
we round the bend in Charlotte's Bay
when the bough breaks through ice like
sugar candy in a child's hand when light
breaks over snow-capped mountains like a
heaven or a miracle I prefer this side
starboard
where the Sun licks first and where if I
were to jump I would not be missed for
hours and if I were to jump catch an ice
floe and right at North or sink into
that sky where penguins fly I would
swallow all Antarctic relics men and
science alike embody ancient ice and
waters teeming with life caught in
evolution and frozen a blueprint a map
on which to chart a course Wow it's
beautiful and thank you so much this is
like I I'm ending my hosting for this
conference right now someone else is
gonna be taking over so this is just a
perfect and thank you I appreciate it
thanks so much this has been a great
experience
thanks all the talks as well all right