up next is Aaron Peretti who literally
wrote the book on ooofff 2.0 he's the
author of OAuth 2.0 simplified you may
have seen him in Wired magazine or Fast
Company or at octane please welcome
Aaron perky thank you very much so so
I'm happy to be here this is a really
cool event excited to be sharing this
with you I'm going to talk about how to
hack ooofff and just an FYI this
presentation is actually recorded I'm
live right now you're gonna see my
recording in a minute and that means I
get to be on slack with you all
answering Q&A live so feel free to chat
with me on slack while this is going and
I'll jump in at the end and answer
questions that have come in as well so
thank you and here we go hi everybody I
am super excited to be here today and
talk to you all about how to hack oo-ahh
I'm Erin perky I'm a senior security
architect octa I'm also a member of the
OAuth working group at the IETF and I've
been in the web standards space for
quite a long time now
if you've ever Google anything about
OAuth you've probably landed on the
website I maintain which is Oh a net
it's a good list of a lot of great
resources for finding things about OAuth
and if you ever see anything wrong with
it please feel free to contribute the
link is at the bottom and you can add
your own resources and things you find
on there alright so a couple of
housekeeping things please feel free to
ask questions as we go I will be keeping
an eye on the Q&A here as we are working
through this content and I will be
answering questions there also the slide
from this talk are on my website at Aron
PK comm so feel free to go there and
that way you can find the links to all
the things I'm mentioning in these
slides so before we talk about how to
hack ooofff
I want to talk a little bit about what a
auth is and set the scene for how some
of these things take place if you ever
tried to re anything online about OAuth
I apologize because it can often feel
like trying to find your way through a
maze of content and is not obvious how
these things fit together Oh auth is not
just one spec it's made up of a whole
bunch of specs so it can be pretty
overwhelming trying to figure out how to
navigate this and where these things
line up and how they fit together so
instead of going through the specs we're
actually gonna take a step back and
first talk about how we got them off in
the first place
so do you remember seeing this kind of
thing online like I don't know 10 years
ago or so this was a very common pattern
on the internet a long time ago we look
at this now we say like oh hi I would
never put my email address and password
into some random application like Yelp
right but it was very common at the time
to do this because you know this new app
like Yelp would launch and it would ask
you to enter your password for your
email address in order for it to go and
find your friends to see if they are
already using Yelp which is like a very
cool feature but this is a terrible way
to do that and we understand that now
but it wasn't limited to just yell it
was also like Facebook doing this can
you imagine if now Facebook would be
collecting people's email addresses and
passwords that would not go over well
but users were happily giving their
logins should be services because they
actually did want what the application
was promising which was the ability to
find their friends so what we're looking
for is a solution for how do we let
applications access the contacts in
their API but not have it also access
the person's emails and that was the
original problem that oh I set up this
hall which was how can we let an
application access data in an API
without giving that application your
password and originally it was always
about third party access to data it was
about Yelp wanting access to your Google
account or last.fm wanting to access
your listing data in Spotify or buffer
wants to post to your Twitter account it
was always about that third party access
and the result of the OAuth flow is that
the application that has an access token
which it can use to go make API requests
after the OAuth flow is complete and the
user has allowed the application access
their account that application will have
an access token which is a string of
characters that doesn't mean anything to
the application now a string of
characters is then used in an API
request to access that API what's
interesting is that nothing in this
process actually tells the application
about the user doesn't actually tell the
application who logged in and that's
totally fine both was not created as a
single sign-on protocol or as a way to
talk about user identity it was created
to access API so I like to use this
analogy of checking you down a hotel
which seems like a funny idea right now
you go to the front desk you give that
person your ID and your credit card they
give you back this hotel key
you take that hotel key and you swipe
the key on the door and the door lets
you in now in order for this
to work the key card doesn't actually
need to represent you a person it just
needs to represent that you have access
to this door so the door doesn't even
care about who you are door just cares
about whether this key card has access
so in terms the person at the front desk
is the authorization server the key card
is the access token and the door is the
API with that kind of background out of
the way let's now talk about how of'
works just enough so that we can see
where some of the holes are because
they're poking out in order to actually
break it so all of oh uh is modeled
around these five roles these are roles
to find in the spec the terms at the
bottom are the spectrums for them those
are the words that you'll find the spec
like resource owner and resource server
those aren't typically things that we
use in a conversation when we talk about
this instead we talk about users and API
is and applications but they're
basically interchangeable and we have to
remember that these are roles not
actually components so the application
might be a mobile app but it might also
be a web server app it doesn't matter
where that application is running
we always model it the same way and oh
and talk about that application getting
an access to
similarly the OAuth server and the API
are sometimes part of the same piece of
software like how github has a built in
OS or as part of its same software but
in some cases you might be using an
external server either as like an open
source project or as a service like
octave or auth0
but again it doesn't matter how these
things are configured we still talk
about these roles the same way so let's
start by going over the most common oaah
flow the authorization code flow so the
flow starts off with the user visiting
the applications website or launching
the mobile app and then they click the
button that says login and that is them
expressing interest in using this
application so they are saying I would
like to use this application the app
says great don't give me your password I
can't use your password so instead go
over to the OAuth server and log in
there and does that by creating a URL to
the OAuth server with a bunch of stuff
in the query string that describes the
request things like its own identifier
and what kind of data it's requesting so
that causes the user to land at the
OAuth server where they then login and
then they will see this prompt asking
them do you allow this request if they
click yes the OAuth server generates a
one-time-use authorization
code and sends it back in a redirect to
the users browser to have the users
browser deliver back to the application
now this is an important step because
what's actually going on here is the
OAuth servers trying to get this
authorization code to the application
but the only way it has to do that is by
telling the users browser to deliver to
the application itself so once the
application has the authorization code
it can now go and get an access token
and does that by making a post request
back to the OAuth server to exchange
that this is a step where it can also
include a secret its own password so
that the OAuth server knows that that
code was not stolen in that redirect
step so the OAuth server validates that
request checks the client secret and
creates an access token and returns it
in the response now the application can
go use the access token to request data
from the API so the blue lines on top
are really called front Channel that's
the idea where we're actually using the
user's browser to move data between
parties the pink lines are the
back-channel and that's the sort of more
normal one where we're sending data from
a client to a server over HTTP there's a
lot of benefits in the back channel that
we often take for granted even because
it's over HTTPS we can validate a
certificate so the client knows it's
talking to the right server once that
connection is established it's encrypted
so that data can't be tampered with in
transit and the response becomes back
can be trusted immediately because it's
part of that same connection that was
established I like to think of this as
hand delivering a message where you can
walk up to somebody you can hand them a
thing you can see them they can see you
you can say they took it you can be sure
that nobody else stole it in that
process sending data over the front
channel is more like throwing it over a
wall and just kind of hoping they catch
it where you can't actually be sure that
they caught it you can't tell if
somebody's stolen mid-flight you can't
tell if it just landed on the floor and
on the other type is a similar problem
which is that on that side you can't
actually be sure where it's coming from
you don't actually know if it's from the
real OS server or from a fake OAuth
server so you might be wondering well
why do we use the front channel at all
then if it's so risky or insecure it
does have a few really important
properties that it turns out is very
useful in o1 it's the way that we can
actually be sure that the user was in
front of their computer when they logged
in because it's the OAuth server that is
collecting their password but also
import
it's a way for applications to be able
to receive data even when they don't
have a public IP address which for
things like mobile phones or JavaScript
apps turns out is really important okay
so that was a quick overview of what a
lot is if you're curious about more of
how that works and the different
environments I often run in do check out
my videos on YouTube search for aquifer
developers or just search for my name
Aaron Becky and you'll find a bunch of
videos about OAuth that talks about that
part in more detail now let's move on to
the hacks so it turns out there's a lot
of ways Tac Toe auth in fact most of
them are documented in the specs
themselves there's a handful of attacks
documented in the core the original
document there was a later security
document put out there was a document
put out about specifically OAuth and
mobile apps which again talks about some
of the particular aspects unique to the
mobile app environment there's also a
new document called OAuth 2 security
best current practice and that is a huge
list of other ways that this can kind of
go wrong so I'm gonna save you from that
because those are well documented and
well understood instead I want to focus
on a couple of attacks that happen in
the real world that actually resulted in
some pretty big press headlines so I'm
gonna start off with this one which is
well understood now and in fact a lot of
security has been based around the fact
that that's happened a long time ago but
it's a good place to start so Twitter
back in 2013 there were a bunch of
headlines that came out about how
Twitter's API keys were stolen or leaked
or whatever you wanted to call it so
what happened was someone went and
downloaded all the Twitter apps on all
the different platforms like iPhone
Android Windows Phone and then we
compiled them and extracted the strings
out of them and then posted all those
API keys on get up the result of this
hack was that basically anybody can now
impersonate the Twitter apps so what I
mean by that is that any of the
permissions that the Twitter apps
themselves might have that other
third-party developers couldn't get now
anybody could get those permissions and
the lesson here that we learned was you
can't put secrets in native apps it just
doesn't work there's no way to do it
because anybody who downloads that app
is downloading that secret and can just
you compile it so this was actually one
of the major problems with OAuth
which that it was entirely based around
this idea of using a secret for that
application to sign requests and that
secret was always provisioned by the
developer and then put into the
application which works fine for
web-based apps where users don't have
access to the source code
but when we're talking about mobile apps
these users download those apps download
the secrets with them and can extract
them like we saw so that was a major
problem with OAuth 1 and that was
actually a huge motivator in deciding to
start a new version of the spec so both
to avoids the need for a client secret
in cases where we can't use one because
of this additional extension at it - Oh
pixie pkc II which stands for prove key
for code exchange is basically a
solution for how to do OAuth with
applications that can't use a secret so
if your application can't use a secret
you might remember that that first
diagram we looked at of how o F works
that one of the last steps there
included the application using its
secret to authenticate to the OAuth sir
we don't have a secret so what are we
gonna do
let's now walk through the flow again
but look at what's changed so it starts
off the same the user clicks on the
application and says I would like to use
this application please login now this
time the app first generates a new
secret random secret for this request
stores internally and then calculates a
hash of that secret then when it builds
a URL that it's going to launch the user
into a browser it includes that hash
value in that URL so that causes the
user's browser to deliver the hash to
the OAuth server now the OAuth server
still again gets these err to login and
prompts them for permission and then
issues a temporary code but it also
remembers the hashed value so now the
user's browser delivers that temporary
code back to the application and now the
application is ready to go and exchange
that code for an access token this time
because it doesn't have a pre registered
client secret it does have that secret
that it's holding onto from when it
started the request so it includes that
raw secret value in this request and
what that does is it lets the OAuth
server say okay well when I issued that
code I remember seeing this hashed value
so that means whoever's gonna get this
code now has to prove that they were the
ones that started the request and to do
that if they include the secret they use
to generate that hash Yohan said we're
gonna hash that value itself and compare
the two hashes to see if they match
and then it can respond with the access
token and then we're done and everything
moves on the good news is this is often
just handled by a library for use of the
app off library for ios and android and
javascript does this for you often times
if you're using a company's product it's
sdk will also be doing this under the
hood all right let's talk about the next
one and this is about hacking JSON web
tokens or J WTS so these headlines were
going around around 2015 when a whole
bunch of libraries were found to be
vulnerable to the same problem and that
was that many libraries were actually
not validating JSON web tokens properly
so let's dig into this a little bit and
see what's going on Jayson web tokens
are often used for API authentication
where your access token might be
adjacent web token here's what a basin
web token looks like it is a long string
of characters it always starts with e YJ
and if you look closely there are two
dots somewhere in there and those
separated into a three-part token
there's a header of payload and a
signature without being able to validate
this somebody could go in here modify
the payload the middle part change data
change a username change the permission
things like that and then repackage it
up and then send it to the API and try
to make API requests if it's not
validating it properly it would then
just read whatever data is in the middle
and then the attacker is in so the thing
about JSON web tokens is that the header
part talks sort of about the token one
of the things in the header is a
description of how the token was signed
and there's a couple of different
options available to you if you're
creating a JSON web token one of the
signing mechanisms is rs.25 six and
that's an asymmetrical algorithm where
you use a public key to verify and a
private key to sign now it just so
happens so there's also a signing
algorithm called nut and that means
there's no signature
so the hack here is a you go get a real
access token that's probably signed
using rs.25 six then you go inside the
token you change the data you want in
the middle part the payload and then you
change the signing algorithm to none and
then make an API request and then if
that server first looks at the header to
decide how to validate the token it'll
see the signing algorithm none and it
will skip checking the signature at all
and now it'll just believe whatever you
put into the token which is clearly
wrong and that was the problem there's
another more subtle version of this
attack where you actually put in
asymmetric algorithm into the header
instead and then what happens is you
send the
server your modified access token
telling it that it's asymmetric signing
algorithm it'll go then find the public
key which it was gonna use to verify the
asymmetric signature but it treats it as
a shared secret instead which basically
means you can use that same public key
to actually create the real signature
because if it's treated as a shared
secret you can create a signature just
like anybody else can with that key that
one's a little trickier because your
resource server will think it's actually
validating your signature because it is
it just happens that anybody could have
created that signature so it's
meaningless so what's the takeaway here
takeaway is that that JSON web token
header which talks about how to validate
the token is untrusted information
before you validate the signature and
you have to treat it as such basically
what that means is never actually let
the header determine what signing
algorithm is used instead when you go to
validate adjacent web token you should
only use signing methods that you know
are safe and that you know you're
expecting which is probably just the
asymmetric ones thankfully most recent
web token libraries around 2015-2016
actually fix this by requiring you to
tell it which signing algorithms you are
expecting when you go to validate a
token that way you can't be tricked into
accepting assigning other than from the
header itself all right let's move on to
one of the more subtle ones this is what
I like to call an OAuth phishing attack
so in 2017 there was this attack on
Google's ooofff which resulted in
headlines like this it had various names
like an OAuth worm or a phishing attack
but let's take a look at how it worked
first of all do you see anything wrong
with this picture I'll give you a second
to look closely you might notice that we
are really on the real Google OAuth
server it's accounts.google.com there's
a secure lock icon in the address bar so
we know this is actually a page served
by Google this is not a fake page but
it's a little bit suspicious that Google
Docs is requesting access to my contacts
for example one
why doesn't he access to my contacts but
also why does it need permission because
it's Google and theoretically Google
already has access to everything inside
right but how about if I click this
little arrow next to Google Docs and
then I seen the application developer
who built it and also the URL I'm going
to be sent you when I authorize this app
what is Doc's cloud on info well I can
be pretty sure it's not actually Google
whatever that is it looks
vicious now if anybody clicked that it
we pretty obvious that this link is
wrong at this point the problem is that
it's too easy to skip past this and not
actually click that so in OAuth in order
to start a flow you just need to create
a URL and get someone to click on it
typically that's the link that says
login but you could actually deliver
that link any way you can think of you
could send it in a bitly link over SMS
you could put it in an email for example
and get someone to click on it and
because anybody can make this link you
can transmit it to anybody and start an
OAuth flow when they click it so the way
to spread was that the attacker just got
one person to click on this link and as
soon as one person did it granted this
application access to that person's
address book and the ability to send
email from their account and then this
worm can go and use the Google API is to
actually send an email to everybody in
their address book and now that email is
not actually a fake email it's not spam
it's coming from a real Google account
going to a real Google account and that
was probably why this was so convincing
because Google's spam filters couldn't
flag it because it looked like
legitimate email at first and what's the
contents of that email it's this message
that says so-and-so shared a file with
you click here to view it in Google Docs
now if you got this email it's going to
be from somebody in your address book
and it's actually a real email - not
from a fake address it's from them so
then you go and you click the open and
Doc's button and you get taken through
Google you're not even taken to a
phishing site you're taken to the actual
Google page where you're then prompted
with this and then and because you're
already thinking about Google Docs
you're more likely to just click through
right here and not even think too much
about it and as soon as you do now the
attacker has an access token to your
account and can repeat the process and
that's how it spiraled out of control so
within about 40 minutes of this starting
it had spread so far that Google
actually had to tweet this out and be
like hey we're investigating this don't
click on that link we're looking into it
meanwhile on reddit where this had been
reported there were Google engineer
that's chiming in being like okay we're
looking at it oh we found out what's
going on and we disabled the app and at
that point the next time anybody clicked
that link they just saw this error page
because what they did was they just
disabled the client ID but if you think
about it that didn't actually solve the
problem that just
that particular instance because the
problem is actually a lot deeper the
problem is that it's a phishing attack
and phishing attacks often don't have a
technical solution because it's all
about teaching users what to expect and
not to sort of blindly trust things and
a lot of the reasons that worked was
because that screen that asked for the
users permission was so convincing
because it was Google's screen and they
didn't do a good enough job of
preventing people from impersonating
Google Apps so how could they have
stopped this well for one they can make
sure the developers can't go and name
applications with the word Google on
them because really only Google should
be able to do that but they went a few
steps farther and this is now having
ripple effects throughout a whole bunch
of related products
shortly after this attack they launched
some pretty big changes to their API
policies one they actually now require
that applications request only the bare
minimum permissions they need to
function instead of requesting a broad
range of permissions they also now
recommend requesting permissions in
context so instead of clicking a link to
log in to an app and having it request
everything all once you first just log
in and then when it needs to go send an
email for you it will then request that
permission we also call that incremental
authorization one of the other things
they did was they actually called out a
few specific scopes as restricted scopes
and those are things like sending email
from a user's account or accessing files
in their Google Drive and for those
restricted scopes if your application
needs them your application actually has
to go through a security assessment
which is a manual review process and in
their documentation they actually say
that this process might cost anywhere
between fifteen thousand and seventy
five thousand dollars so basically what
this did was a whole bunch of these
smaller services that use Gmail for like
email marketing automation they all just
suddenly have a shutdown because they
couldn't afford that kind of fee so
that's not my favorite solution to this
problem because the fields have been
heavy-handed and I recognize that it's
really a design problem which is very
hard to solve but we can look at some
other companies to see how they've
handled a similar problem this is github
authorization screen and if you notice
on this one it looks very different from
Google but down at the bottom next to
that green authorize button it actually
shows the website that you'll be taken
to when you click it and that's super
helpful because then as a user you might
recognize
oh well this clearly isn't the real
application I thought it was going to
because I don't recognize this web
address so really this problem is all
about just making sure users are well
informed when they're granting
permissions to other applications to
access their account overall so it's a
hard problem and there are several
different kinds of solutions as you can
see some more heavy-handed than others
all right the last one I want to talk
about is Facebook this made major
headlines in 2018 50 million accounts
were hacked now normally when there's
like a large-scale hack like this it's
actually something pretty silly like
it's somebody left the database publicly
exposed to the Internet or someone just
stole a password dump and then try it on
some other service but this one caught
my eye because normally companies will
just sort of write a high-level apology
email and send that out via the press
releases but this was actually so
serious the Facebook put out a lot of
information about exactly what went
wrong here so on their security blog
they actually have a lot of details that
we can look into to try to learn
something from this so from their own
post this was a phrase that the VP of
Product used to describes the attack the
vulnerability was the result of the
interaction of three distinct bugs and
this is also very interesting because it
wasn't just one problem and when we look
at these three bugs you'll see that
individually each of these doesn't
actually seem that bad and seems like it
couldn't cause something at this scale
it's only once you stack them up it
becomes the problem so let's dig in and
that was really useful for being able to
test out your privacy settings you can
make sure that this one post you made
was hidden to these particular people
and confirm it by checking out what your
page looked like to them so that's where
this all starts so here's the text from
their statement first new as is a
privacy feature that lets you see what
your page looks like somebody else this
is supposed to be a view only interface
however for one type of composer the
little box lets you post into your
profile the one that lets you wish
friends a happy birthday the view as
incorrectly offered the ability to post
a video but again bites off whatever
right that's not a big deal worst you
can do is like upload a video to your
own wall okay so hold that one in your
head for a second now second they
launched a new version of its video
uploader and that version had a bug
where it generated an access token that
had the permissions of the Facebook
mobile app now this is starting to sound
a little bit suspicious because what do
you mean a generator
an access token that sounds to me like
they're letting one part of their system
just sort of assert things on behalf of
some other part of the application
without actually checking it but again
by itself this wouldn't be so bad
because all that really could happen was
that you could use that access token to
post to your own account or read your
own data okay so hold that one in your
head
third when the video uploader appeared
as part of the view as it generated an
access token not for you the viewer but
instead for the profile you were viewing
now this is bad this is clearly bad
because now I'm able to get an access
token for somebody else's account but
again if it were only this it wouldn't
have been that bad because the view as
was supposed to be a read-only interface
so I would have ended up with a
read-only access token to their account
but when you stack these if you use the
view as feature that somebody else's
page you end up with an access token
belonging to that user that had the
permissions of the Facebook mobile app
which basically means it can do
everything and that's why I started
cascading out of control so what's the
moral of the story here this is again a
pretty tricky one because again each of
these bugs did not seem that bad on
their own but I think the thing that
kind of ties it all together is that
it's really important to keep clean
security boundaries between these
different parts of your application
don't let Park with your application
pretend to be other parts or pretend to
be users we have the OE framework for a
reason and that's what lets us make sure
that the user was involved when issuing
an access token for that user and that
is all I have for you today I hope you
enjoyed this please feel free to get in
touch with me on Twitter or via my
website if you have more questions or
would like to chat more about this you
can get a copy of my book at OSU
simplified calm the book goes into a lot
more detail on all different things you
need to know about building co-author
applications and servers I also have cat
stickers available on that website as
well thank you so much
all right thank you all very much any
more questions to answer here yes so
first of all and we got a lot of
discussion about the examples you
provided which people were very enamored
by those examples the first question was
was did you have permission to talk
about each one of those cases oh this is
all based on public information that I I
was not involved in any of these myself
these were not things that I was I was
not working on at the companies where
these were involved so this is based on
my own either speculation based on
public information or just understanding
of the OAuth framework so let's talk
about the Google one for just a second
if it has a Google Docs user or as a
Google Apps for domain user you actually
interact with that dialog several times
a day if somebody sends that you would
document outside your domain you may
very well that may that screen may very
well pop up would Google have been able
to use the github strategy somehow to
have mitigated the users being used to
clicking through and approving that
every time what's the github strategy
where you show where it's coming home
and I mentioned on that context I guess
um yeah I'm actually so I don't I I do
use google domain at work but I haven't
seen that maybe because I don't usually
share files from outside of that domain
so I'm not actually super familiar with
what you're talking about there okay um
but the if it's like authorizing one org
to get data from another org is that the
kind of thing you're talking about well
I think it's just as a as a heavy user
you get this screen up that pops up a
lot where it just basically asks you and
you know it's Google because the domain
is correct at the top right but it just
asks you to basically approve several
times a day and I'm just wondering if
there's a way to train the users not or
when that is legitimate and when it's
not because of that yeah that's a tough
one especially if it's if it's multiple
times a day and you kind of get
overloaded with that prompt you're more
likely to just click through without
reading it which is a problem so I'm I'm
curious about that I'll have to look
into that one a really easy one is how
do you pronounce and now I don't even
know how to pronounce it cuz I don't
know how to say it but that's JWT the
official pronunciation is jot I would
say I'll probably say
ja or JWT 50/50 depending on I don't
know what but job is the official friend
well you're you're the author of the
book so whatever you say is you know
that's gonna be absolutely authoritative
so and how do you build protect or air
build protect or build a safer robust
JWT so the main fix there is to not let
the external that the header which is
essentially unsanitized external data
don't let that affect how you validate
it so have a an own list of algorithms
that you use have an own list of keys
that you know how to go find without
having to look at the token before you
go and do the validation and if you're
doing that then you're you're safe
there's also a new spec JSON web token
best practices which documents a lot of
that kind of things and more so
definitely look that up oh that's great
so and then the final question is is
given the jeaious libraries have the
fixed JWT issues are they still
recommended as the kind of token to use
or is there another perhaps safer kind
this is kind of uh this is kind of a
controversial one right now so jason web
token was originally it was made for
open to connect and it's being used in a
whole host of things now even sometimes
out of the web space like that it's
actually being used in telephone
networks now it is also used very often
as though OAuth access tokens like I
mentioned an example and there's a new
spec coming out very soon which talks
about best practices for using JSON web
tokens as access tokens now if you're
following all that correctly and doing
everything right and you know as
documented you're probably fine there
are however some other token formats
that might be like easier to not mess up
is what I would say because like if
you're doing JSON web tokens correctly
they're fine but there are those kinds
of things that can mess you up and and
make these huge problems so there are
other token formats you could use that
are maybe less easy to mess up there's
also options of using of making access
tokens that are not structured tokens at
all just random strings at you store in
database which is also a fine option
there's different trade-offs but yeah
well thank you very very much that we
had a lot of folks asked about videos
being available there these week talks
are being recorded we really do
appreciate
joining us today and it was a fantastic
talk all right thank you so much