hi John hi hello I can hear you now it's
ooh all right so this is John auspi and
he's gonna be talking about incident
analysis how learning is different and
fixing and I'm super excited for it so
I'll let you introduce yourself and kick
it off all right thank you
well hello everyone my name is John all
spa I've spent most of my career trying
to understand how engineers solve
problems whether or not I can help with
it or it's a different story
I don't have much time in this talks I
don't want to spend too much talking
about myself so here's the the main gist
the high-level points that I want to get
across the first is I'm going to assert
that current and typical sort of
conventional approaches to learning from
incidents have very little to do with
actual learning from the title you can
understand that my opinion is that that
learning is not the same as fixing and
it we'll talk a little bit about that
and what I mean by them and also assert
that most post incident review documents
are documents that are written to be
more often filed not written to be read
that has maybe some obvious or not so
obvious implications on what's learned
from them I would also say that that
changing the primary focus from fixing
to learning will result in a significant
competitive advantage now it's going to
be quite difficult to sort of make a
switch but let's see what I mean by
fixing and learning and see see what you
think
we can talk about it later in Q&A so
when as engineers are you know we're
somewhat hardwired to some extent our
core rationale for being is to fix
things is to build things is to adjust
things of that sort of thing I'm gonna
say that when you focus on
seeing things they tend to get fixed
pretty quickly and and that is sort of
expected right but I would also say this
is that the quality and effectiveness of
this fixing and otherwise preventing
future issues is going to be
proportional or certainly influenced on
how well you understand how the thing
works to begin with and this is a real
this is a real distinction again the
point I will keep sort of trying to
hammer home is if your goal is to fix
you're gonna fix something whether or
not it was the right thing to fix or
fixing it in the way that that is it
possible even if you were to take a step
back a little bit to get a broader
understanding is really up in the air
another way of saying this is that
attention paid to learning will always
yield higher quality fixing that is that
I'm feel very confident about if instead
on the flip side you focus exclusively
on fixing that can be a barrier for
learning because you're you have you as
soon as you have presented a plausible
way to to fix something then it tends to
shut down under the under sort of time
and production pressure shut down any
other options so I wanted to take a look
at sort of the conventional view on
where post-incident analysis how it
usually goes it you know there's an
incident and our sometime happens maybe
somebody will do some work to make a
timeline this is usually at least
typically conventionally where the
industry believes the work happens which
is this meeting by the way it's a very
expensive meeting the burden on this
meeting to sort of solve all of the
problems so that it never happens again
is very very large maybe somebody will
write a report hopefully somebody will
write something up because there are
people who will be in positions where
they weren't there at the
and they weren't at the meeting but the
were the tendency to think that they're
only our greatest value is here on these
these action items now if the action
lands are the only goal you've got then
I would throw out go out on a limb and
say that you're missing out on a
significant amount of what you could be
getting out of the incident so learning
let's talk about learning for just a
minute here I would say that learning is
happening all of the time it's a core
part of being human not just engineers
the thing that I would say is there is
no there's no world distinctions no
crisp line up there's that people are
not learning all we're not learning from
incidents or we're learning for this is
the fact is that learning is happening
the question isn't whether learning is
happening it is the question there's
what is learned who is learning Leonard
nerd a learning Howard and how they
learn all of these depend on how well
practices are set up to support it if
there are conditions set up by peers and
technology and leadership and all sorts
of the sort of the business support that
makes it a priority to learn from
incidents but then then it's possible if
it's not then it's not this might be
reasonably obvious but I think it's
definitely in the modern complex
software applications no one can
understand everything about everything
no single person can do this we should
be surprised given this that things work
as the as well as they do you think
about this for just a moment no one has
an objectively comprehensive
understanding of how everything is
supposed to work
they collectively with their peers
recalibrate how they understand things
work incidents are a big part of that
and it's still
comprehensive the fact is that they know
enough about it to make it work as well
as it does finally I would just throw
here that the frequency of incidents has
really nothing to do with how well an
organization learns right it might be a
signal of something but if the number of
incidents the rate of incidents is going
up that is not evidence that the
organization is not learning if it's
going down that is not evidence that the
organization is learning a conventional
myth is that we have an incident and
we'll think of it as and this canonical
set of lessons can then sort of
extracted like a concentrated write from
this incident that's the whole point
right which is then sort of shared or
sort of sort of transmitted to a group
when we have this idea which is we've
here's this incident here they are these
beautiful delicious lessons they're
concentrated so you know be careful now
consume them this when we have this
perspective the perceived problem to be
solved then is how to somehow share
better it must not be because of the
lessons but because of the sharing now
on say that sharing is a little bit
funky here right because in in some
contexts if I were to share something
with you and you did take it or didn't
even know it was there did I share it
really or did really I just make it
available to you
that's a digression the reality is that
different people will always have
bearing understandings they have
different perspective before and after
an incident and what questions or
mysteries remain for them can't be
captured in some sort of one size that's
all that that goes to sort of the masses
if I tell you something that you already
knew did you learn it did you learn it
from that lesson I'm not entirely sure
that's true what is important or notable
or interesting - somebody will differ
from person to person and can also be
valuable to each
those people you can know something that
your peers knew and you still learned
that this turns out what's important or
notable or interesting is what they ask
what actually remembered now this might
be somewhat controversial I'm going to
say this that if you can't remember
something you can't say that you've
learned it
I'm feeling very strongly about this
since my kids have been home learning if
I asked you and we do my organization
when we talk to organ teams we talk to
engineers we always ask them about
incidents we ask them we say can you
tell us about an incident that was
significant tell us a story about an
incident well the first thing to come to
mind is I think in the hundreds of times
we've asked that there's not one
engineer who has failed to come up with
a story and here's the thing they're
amazing
not one story did I ever think that's ok
that's fine they were all amazing when
we asked people about incidents couple
things are common one is they've become
very animated when they tell the story
oh yeah listen to this let me tell you
here's this one I can tell you about
this one story yeah let's tell you about
this one story they also tend to include
some sort of elements of suspense and
how they say it right even engineers
they wouldn't describe themselves as
storytellers absolutely put a lot of
effort whether they know it or not into
how they tell it that's what makes for
the story
they include elements of surprise like
for example what we didn't know so so we
went to you know fire up memcache but we
didn't know at the time was there also
some sort of give us some sort of
backstory right so so while this was
going on remember we were streaming the
Super Bowl and this is what was
happening or remember we were
you know we were two hours away from our
company IP owing this is what was
happening they recall it most amazingly
in ridiculous really fine detail even if
it's many years since and all of this
fits with what we know about learning
from incidents from other domains
stories that people remember have
elements of challenge struggle and
difficulty so therefore if you want to
broaden and deepen the the understanding
of how things work that surround an
incident in your organization you should
consider doing that one way of saying
this is that interesting incident
analysis documents let's set aside the
meeting interesting documents get read
compelling incidents get read and they
get shared with others you know you're
on the right track when engineers say
listen to their colleague you've got to
you got to read this I don't care what
you're doing just if you're not
deploying to Prague just just and when
you're done deploying it's five you got
to read this gotta read this check this
out fascinating documents get read they
get shared with others commented on and
asked about they get referenced in code
comments and in pull requests you'll see
them referencing architecture diagrams
in other incidents will refer to them
we've seen it we've seen compelling
write-ups so demonstrative so
illustrative of what's happening in the
in the software in the end in the
organization is in that it's been
included in new hire onboarding here's
what's important is that interest
uninteresting documents don't any of it
some of you may have seen or heard of a
movie called green lantern the point I
want to make here is that just because
something's made available to open and
everywhere doesn't mean it's any good
the reason why nobody went to go see
Green Lantern is cuz it's terrible
incident write-ups are the same so
making efforts to highlight the messy
details the messy details are what makes
people wants to read want to ask more
questions what was difficult for people
to understand during the incident what
was surprising for people about the
incident
how do people understand the origins of
the incident what mysteries still remain
for people there are mysteries that
always remain nobody has a comprehensive
objectively true universally understood
understanding of how an incident came to
be and how it took place and what to do
about it later I want to know what was
difficult about an incident and I want
to be able to ask questions about that
this is something that all engineers
could consider internalizing one point
that I'd like to throw out which is
because it's quite typical is that you
only pay attention or pay deliberate
effort to understand the incidents that
have high severity or high customer
impact but here's the thing customer
impact is not equivalent to the
difficulty of solving the issue they're
orthogonal second point is that multiple
difficulties can exist in the same
incident and field and questions about
was about what was or is still is
difficult is that's the gold that is the
critical in that is how lasting memories
are formed and that is how people who
weren't there and were at a meeting all
sort of maintained throughout throughout
time so multiple people have multiple
stories we talk a lot about mental
models but mental models are really
stories they're not pictures they have
there's a an understanding and people
can quite often feel as though until an
incident happens be pretty confident in
there how it works is how how I think it
works is how it works
what incidents do is allow us to take
what we have in our mind and superimpose
it and come sort of contrast with others
and a great deal of it overlaps with
what other people think about how it
works it has to overlap otherwise it
wouldn't work to begin with but when we
can contrast this and what we can do is
use incidents to allow wait a minute so
I I thought it was like this but it
didn't it looked like there's this other
little thing that I missed or orderly
these things that I knew but my
colleagues didn't know this and I
thought they knew and because I thought
they knew I never meant it never
occurred to me to say what I know about
this thing
this is using this opportunity for
actual learning so what are some fine
goals for a post-incident meeting when
participants in a group meeting this big
expensive meeting when they leave the
meeting knowing new things they didn't
know when they entered and new things
they didn't know about what their
colleagues know about the incident
things are going well ideally they'll
also have an understanding of how to
continue discussions and where to
capture it if you think about it for a
minute if the default is you've got an
hour or two hours or some common regular
cadence for how post mortem or post
incident or after-action or learning
review whatever you would like to call
them what these meetings are that seems
strange to spend the same amount of time
in every incident despite the fact that
the incidents can vary in so many
different directions so continuing
discussions and where it's all captured
is significantly important the same
thing happens for write-up when you're
done reading a write-up if you know
things now that you didn't know when you
started
and you know things that you didn't know
about what your colleagues know and how
to continue discussions and where to
capture this is what makes and post
incident review write up something worth
reading
now something worth sharing and
something that could be valuable to
people in the future because you're not
writing it for now you're writing it for
people who will want to read it and need
to read it in the future so here are
some things to experiment with separate
the generation of follow-up action items
from a group meeting right instead of
having the whole goal of that meeting
where people are rushing to get
follow-up items separate it make that
meeting about understanding record in
the document who responded to the
incident and who attended the group
meeting this is supporting your reader
capture things that were done after the
incident but before the group meeting in
the document give write-ups to brand-new
engineers and ask them to record any and
all questions after they've after having
read it link this is an easy one link
jargon terms to documents that describe
them in the incident review document ask
more people to talk diagrams visual
representation can be really important
and make it easier for people to read
and understand have someone who is not
involved in the event
lead the analysis Brian kitchens wrote
this for the blog post that I've linked
to here he says this if the incident
analyst participated in the incident
they will inevitably have a deeper
understanding and bias towards the
incident that will be impossible to
remove in the process of analysis if you
were there you're not necessarily going
to investigate things that you are
pretty sure you already know
lastly resist focusing on reducing the
number of incidents Ryan continues on he
says the cliche idea that we would do
this work to reduce the number of
incidents or to
lessen the time to remediate is too
simplistic of course organizations want
to have fewer incidents however stating
this as an integral actually hurts our
organization's indeed it will lead to a
reduction in incident count not from
actually reducing the number of
incidents but rather lessening how and
how often they are reported I would add
to what Ryan says here and say instead
focus on increasing the number of people
who want to read these reports and
attend this post incident review
meetings so that's the talk that I've
got I hope people have questions I'm not
entirely sure if they do but that's the
that is the talk as it stands all right
I'm gonna come off mute I was not
expecting this so um let me see I don't
think there's any questions in the
channels right now so if anybody has
comes right now please share them this
would be a good time um I'm gonna ask my
own questions right now
so one is so I know you've been talking
about this for a while now right now but
I I still see a lot of people handling
incidents and in ways they're opposite
of sort of the ideal way yeah it seems
that no matter how much we talk about it
it kind of doesn't trickle down so is
there something we can do that is a good
question I will be the first to say that
that I would certainly it would be more
satisfying to have seen progress in the
in the industry I would say a couple
things one is my guess is more
organizations have much more leeway than
they think they have in some cases how a
there's nothing that that says that
at least nothing that I've that I've
seen you you know sort of has a
procedure for how to run a post-mortem
meeting on a minute-by-minute basis
there are still as much as I'd like to
rail on on constraining post-mortem
templates to fill out
most of them many of them have you open
text fields right the here's the thing
stories like I've described are
happening they're just not seen as
nothing right there's an official
bookkeeping sort of accounting and you
you know you fill up the form you do the
thing you say don't you say why you know
a certain number of times root cause and
all of that I can say that I'm certainly
not a fan of sort of declaring
organization-wide that something new is
different and and and you're flipping
from some world to another world what we
see more often is enthusiastic
individuals inside the organization
doing things just a little bit
differently in addition to what they're
already doing over time people will be
engaging with that extra stuff moreso
than the stuff that they had been
previously doing because what they're
previously been doing is terrible and
and and you just have to you just have
to give someone a post incident review
you know I ask people all the time we
say well do you have Jim post mortems
and they say they say oh yes so you know
of course we know you never won a good
crisis go to waste and sort of insert
some cliche there and then I say well I
said oh that's excellent I say well who
reads them and nobody has an answer for
that but I can tell you that I well you
know what we hear is that nobody reason
because they're not there's nothing you
can't get much out of it it's easier to
go to your
colleague and say what happened
interesting I'm so another question is
how do you convince upper management not
to reduce number of incidents oh you
probably can't I mean you probably can't
that's what I'm saying
a summary when we know someone we know
quite well has done such a very good job
of continuing to provide the reports the
charts the graphs that management has
continually asked for but what she's
done is to add alongside it the deeper
narrative of what is of what was
important and what was difficult what
was what was notable about a given
incident and over time that they started
looking more at that extra stuff asking
questions more about that and less about
you know is that why isn't that you know
why the number going down and in that
way I'd say it's a little bit of
subterfuge a little bit of you know it's
a little sneaky but it's it's it's
effective another question is um do you
have any recommendations for improving
the quality of storytelling right so any
reference has to read or something to
learn from I mean so so yes here
incidents are really are palpable events
Engineers don't drop their you know
their memories they don't drop their
experiences of having been in the
incident trying to work out what's
happening what does it mean what can we
do
asking engineers who were there about
what was difficult ask them ask them
what what what was what stood out for
them record that stick it in the in the
we've never found an engineer who is shy
about tell
yes about what was hard and what was
difficult the question isn't about
whether or not you can persuade somebody
to give more detail Oh
although that is and if you can set up
it is a challenge to do that if you can
set up a situation where they're giving
details about what it was like for them
and that and that you can you can
demonstrate that you are going to to
keep those details in confidence you may
ask them if you could if not perhaps
quote them but certain paraphrase
unattributed in an incident review but
the the the content generators are there
and and you know that they're there
because these are the stories that you
hear after work these the stories that
you hear during lunch these are the
stories that you hear over drinks these
are the stories that you hear in the
hallways of conferences and yes so when
we find engineers telling stories about
interesting outages every engineer in
the room is quiet and wants to listen
very carefully so that I believe the
powers there I'm another question how do
you encourage or introduce incident
review meetings or a new team I'm a
tester so it's hard to influence or of
course I'm but they're really helpful
you mean having I'm assuming that going
from the world where they're either
having that where they're not having a
meeting can trying to convince them to
have the meeting I'm a sermons note area
yeah and I mean that's a great question
if asking questions you don't have to
have a meeting to ask questions and if
you have if you have some if you don't
have some way of gathering data from
people
qualitative sort of you know just
reflections on what was hard what was
surprising that sort of thing then you
know if there's not a meaning you can't
convince somebody to have meeting you
might be able to convince somebody to
talk to you for five or five or ten
minutes at a time once you what we have
seen is somebody doing that and then
sort of synthesizing what they've heard
into sort of the document at which point
later people you can use that as well
you know we could you know we could have
a meeting we could you know just and we
could experiment with it worst case is
it's a terrible meeting but I'm sure we
already have terrible meetings and we
can't get rid of them so how about just
adding trying one more and trying to
make it a good meeting so I um I will
sort of summarize I think a couple of
questions because I have the same
question is there like a framework for
gathering this data right because um
like there's good questions to ask and
bad questions to ask very Jessica's
gonna be telling you I would not to ask
like one yes you know so um if I'm new
to base I'm approaching this I would
like to know how to even structure this
data gathering point yeah I mean again
if you were to go and I'll put the
slides out there and there are a number
of talks that that I've given that I
could sort of include links the
questions you ask are very important
they are they are primary primary way
that you can get you know really
critical and important information and
you certainly can do it poorly what I
would say is there's there if you if you
Center your questions on what was
difficult what was straightforward what
was surprising and what still sticks out
for them as mysterious you can't really
go wrong
you'll hear you will hear more the
better answer is watch Jessica's talk
that's the kind of answer
all right
we really slightly vary on it same so um
thank you so much for the awesome talk
and I know people can't find you online
and probably can find us slides online
so thank you John
Thank You Sasha thank you and thanks