ah we're back my mistake hey phil
welcome welcome back everyone
uh we'll say uh thanks for joining us
today uh
please do pop along to the slack so bit
dot lee
slash atto dash slack to join in the
conversation
please also feel free to donate to the
coverage 19 solidarity response fund
uh we're raising some fantastic money
for that so please do pop along the
website learn more about donating
i won't take up too much for your time
there phil because it's a short session
but the title
sounds superb yeah kubernetes unscared
which i think we could all benefit from
so without further ado let me add
your screen in there i shall disappear
uh
and over to you all right thank you very
much
uh thanks to all the talks for having me
i've never done this virtually before so
this is going to be interesting
um hope you'll bear with me i hope you
can all see
my presentation if not uh somebody will
have to poke me
um to begin with a little bit about
myself my name is phil taproger
i am the um sre lead at
sneak i'm also resident nerd
and a certified kubernetes fanboy
i am i've been into sort of
infrastructure and cloud computing jobs
platform engineering jobs for the past
five six years
um and i genuinely believe kubernetes is
one of the
most profoundly game-changing
technologies that has come about in the
past
decade so let's talk about kubernetes
um there's a lot to talk about strap in
and bear with me
um i'd like to begin with asking and
then answering my own question
what actually is kubernetes and
you know as a question a lot of people
kind of sort of know and if you look at
the
uh sort of blog posts on the internet
and whatnot
you'll find many high level explanations
and they all
boil down to pretty much one thing
and that is it's a container
orchestrator so what's that mean
well it runs our containers for us to
which i then usually ask
so what does docker do so obviously
there's there's more to it than that
uh daniel riek from red hat once
famously said
openshift red hats kubernetes
distribution is the new enterprise linux
and as there's a big statement right
kelsey hightower once famously tweeted
kubernetes is not the colonel it's
systemd
and i think kelsey actually was was spot
on
with that remark because at the core
kubernetes is just a bunch
of state machines just like systemd
what's a state machine well it's a
mathematical model that helps us
understand compute
it's a system that has states and it has
rules for transitioning from one state
to another
in kubernetes there are control loops
they
have states and those states are
represented by the api
objects your deployments your pods and
they have rules for changing from one
state to another that are driven by
changes to these api objects
a kubernetes control loop looks at state
in the api server when that state
changes
it does one of two things or both
it either interacts with an external
system like a cloud provider or the
docker daemon
or it writes a change to the api
itself so let's look at an example for
that
and just a word of warning i did try and
find a better diagram that
visualizes this unfortunately i couldn't
find one that wasn't copyrighted
so i had to make my own and you'll
quickly see that they don't pay me for
my
graphics design skills but um bear with
me
so what happens when you create
deployment say the deployment
in kubernetes you'll probably know this
is a
high level object that expresses a
desire to run a number of containers
somewhere on the cluster so how do we
get from the deployment
to a container you create a deployment
either through cube control apply or
through
a client sdk or even just a curl with a
post
and the api server will receive your
deployment and it will write that
to etcd persisted and that's all it does
the api server doesn't actually do
anything it gives us authentication
authorization it gives us validation but
it doesn't
do anything as such for that
you need controllers and most kubernetes
controllers are bundled up in a thing
called controller manager
but they're all independent pieces of
code each one doing just one
thing in our case there is a thing
called the deployments controller
and the deployments controller is
interested in changes to deployment
objects
so the develop deployments controller
will find out that there is a new
deployment that was just created
and they could have happened a second
ago it could have happened five
hours ago it doesn't care it always does
the same thing
it knows for a deployment there should
be a replica set
set that matches that deployment it will
check is there one
in this case there isn't so it'll create
one it'll write a new api object it'll
copy some of the details from the
deployment
like the pod spec the replica account
and write that into a replica set object
persist that through the api and then it
goes back to sleep
there's no containers there is however a
replica set controller that now wakes up
having been informed that there is a new
replica set and it does a very similar
thing it knows
for every replica set there should be a
number of pod objects indicated by the
replica account
it checks are there these pod objects
and if there aren't
it will write some to the kubernetes api
but pods aren't containers pods again
are just a desire they express a desire
to run a container somewhere on the
cluster
so we need to find the compute resources
to run those containers and that's where
the scheduler comes in
the scheduler has a bit more of a
specialized taste it looks for
specifically pod objects that are
instead pending
and that do not have a value in their
node field
when it finds those it looks at the
nodes available on the cluster
it picks whichever way it does a node
that is best suited to run
that particular container it looks at
things like
node selectors it looks at resource
requests it looks at what the nodes have
to offer
and it will then pick a node it will
write that node's name
into the node field of the pod and it'll
go back to sleep
now i hear you cry what sort of
scheduler is this that doesn't actually
schedule anything
but in fact it does because by doing so
it gives cubelet which as you probably
know is the
node agent that runs on every node in
the cluster enough information to
realize
that this pending pod with its name on
it
is something that this particular
cubelet should be responsible for
and cubelet has another control loop
that says for every pod with my name on
there should be a docker container on
this machine
there isn't one currently so it will
construct the
docker run command that will make that
container appear
it'll update the status of the pod
indicating that that is now running and
now
finally we get to a point where we've
actually got the container that we're
looking for
so why is this sort of convoluted
process so
powerful it's because
every one of these components by being
so independent
is by design and by default
self-correcting
everything will eventually fall into
place when
the stars align as it were there were no
timing or orderliness guarantees to
begin with so all of these control loops
have to look at the world afresh every
time
they run and when something goes wrong
once that problem is resolved everything
will come back together there's no need
to restart anything
these control loops don't carry states
so they can fail and can come back and
just pick up where they left off
and they don't talk to each other they
only ever communicate
by way of changing state in the api
you know looking at the previous example
what happens when the scheduler wakes up
and there are no nodes available for
your container they're all busy
well it will mark that part as unskilled
unscheduleable and then it goes back to
sleep it recues it
basically saying i'll get back to you
and from that point on it will retry
for days and even weeks if it has to
knowing that eventually there will be
compute power again and when that
happens
it'll run the container and everything
will come back together
why am i telling you all this mainly
because
there's actually two reasons the first
one is because it makes kubernetes
incredibly extensible
each one of these control loops is
independent it does one thing you can
rely on it
and you can add control loops into this
mix that will all
play nice with what's whatever's already
there
in other complex systems if you want to
make a change and have it work
you have to understand a lot of
how everything plays together how the
communication paths work
if you've ever tried to contribute say
to the linux kernel
uh that's a lot of work with kubernetes
all you need to know is how you need to
manipulate
state in order to get the result you
want that's the only way communication
ever happens
the second reason is because you have to
do monitoring differently than you used
to
in a system that consists of you know
discrete hardware
you know something goes down you want to
know about it so that you can go and fix
it
on kubernetes you really want to have at
least two of everything
okay kubernetes makes that easy and once
you have two of everything
and you have a system that is
self-healing
you no longer want to alert on the thing
is broken
but rather the thing has been broken
for longer than you would expect and
trust that in the meantime
you know the the other one of the two
that you should have um
will take over and you ideally don't
have any
customer facing impact as the system
realigns itself and things come back
together fall back into place
this extensibility is important
because kubernetes like many things that
came out of google
strictly follows an 80 20 rule it does a
lot of things for a lot of people
but not everything will always work for
everyone just as it is
also there's a couple of areas where
they kind of forgot
a few things that you know aren't really
very well covered and we'll look at a
couple of those in a minute
um but because of the way it is built it
is actually quite
easy for anyone to add custom
controllers
into the mix and with relatively little
investment you can unlock
a lot of potential if you're interested
or after this talk will be interested in
doing something like this i recommend
you have a look at cube builder
which provides you with a framework on
how to
build custom controllers for kubernetes
with a lot of scaffolding
that makes it even easier um
but to look at an example of this
i'd like to point at managing
configuration
you will probably know that pods can
consume config maps and secrets
either as environment variables or as
mounted volumes and
that's great you know we love separating
code and config
but what happens when the configuration
changes
well if it's consumed as environment
variables we're kind of screwed that the
environment for a process can't really
change
after the fact so the container would
need to restart to pick up those changes
but cubelet doesn't know that that
restart is necessary
and even if you're consuming the
configuration as files which
will eventually change on the container
file system
to represent manifest that change
it is now your processes responsibility
to monitor those files
and reload on change some process can do
that
some processes can't so the results are
very inconsistent
and in my my previous job this this bit
us a few times
early on and um you know after a couple
of incidents
i decided that enough was enough and i
figured you know what's a platform
engineer to do
well you write a custom controller and
that's where wave came from
and wave is a surprisingly simple
piece of code that really only does one
thing it looks
at all the conflict maps and all the
secrets that
a deployment port spec reference
and it then calculates a hash over their
contents
it stores that hash with the pod spec in
the deployment
and then it watches for changes if
someone now
changes a config map it will update that
hash
and write that updated hash into the
deployments pod spec
and because the pod spec has now changed
we get the same effect that
that as when anything else in the
deployment changes say you change the
the i don't know the command line of the
container or the container image
it will trigger a rollout so the
deployment controller will kick in it'll
make a new replica set the rep like i
said will make new pods and it will
honor all of your
min available and max surge and you know
that we didn't need to reinvent that
wheel
at all the only thing that wave does is
it
triggers that well-known well-understood
process
by making a change to the deployment
another of these gaps is secrets
management
kubernetes secrets aren't really very
very secret they are
great for consuming in cluster because
they're just basic d4 encoder plain text
um but they're not very great for
storing or managing outside
and there are a number of solutions for
this but all of the good ones
follow the same pattern they give you a
custom resource that is a proxy to your
secret that is
safe to store safe to handle but
contains enough information
for a controller on the cluster to
recreate the actual secrets object
on the cluster itself and keep them in
sync
one example is bitnami's cl secrets
controller
which uses asymmetric cryptography with
a
key held on the cluster that allows the
cluster to decrypt an otherwise
encrypted sealed secret object that you
can store and get
um and that is is safe because only the
cluster
itself has the key to decrypt it another
one
is the external kubernetes external
secrets which can
keep a secret object in sync with for
example
information stored in aws secret manager
but in both cases
you have an object that is kept in sync
with another object and that's done by a
controller
speaking of cluster state you know i
said storing in git that in fact
is one of the big challenges you have
when you want to run kubernetes
in a large deployment in production how
do you manage
that desired state when everything is
changing all the time and so many hands
are involved
and the best practice that is emerging
on that is using git
a practice called git ops where your
operations are triggered by changes to
git
so you have a git repository that is
already versioned
you put your for example your raw yaml
objects into that repository
and you use a controller to continuously
keep the cluster in sync with what's
in that repository one example that does
this is argo cd and it would strongly
encourage you
to take a look at that approach if you
plan to run kubernetes in a
large production capacity
another thing you'll have to look at is
obviously monitoring and alerting
there's a lot of moving parts a lot more
than
you know systems of old used to have and
there's a lot more data that you need to
understand what really is going on
you don't want to just deploy prometheus
and grafana and call it a day
spend some time actually building good
dashboards that tell you a story
i promise you future on-call you will be
very grateful for those
and you want to build your alerts around
persistent errors
not spikes not short changes that should
really be correcting themselves
you know ideally you want to look at
leading indicators things like
increasing latencies increasing
requests per second these sorts of
things so that ideally you can take
action
before something breaks a lot of this
stuff can be automated
for example you know horizontal port
auto scalers allow you to scale out
your compute capacity as your
load increases but where
those systems fail you want to be
alerted of those
trends and lastly of course
you want to make use of your error
budgets nothing is ever 100
up and understanding how much down is
acceptable to you
allows you to build alerts that only
really fire when it's necessary
and don't distract you and leave you
time to work
on things um that are more important
lastly i did promise in the blurb and
answer to the question should you roll
your own cluster
and i guess i should probably come
through with that uh the answer is it is
complicated but
i will say nothing that i've described
so far
requires you to self-host all of the
stuff that i've talked about writing
custom controllers
uh doing your alerting based on uh these
their metrics all of that can be done in
gke can be done on eks it can be done on
openshift any
sort of kubernetes will do but
do remember the 80 20 rule basically if
your
payloads are reasonably similar
to what about 80 of everybody else is
doing
you're probably going to be just fine
with
gke eks what have you
and if you're doing something
particularly unusual
you'll have to do some extra work
anyways to make kubernetes work for you
and you'll need good engineers for that
and if you have those
self-hosting kubernetes isn't actually
all that difficult we used to do it we
had four five production clusters
we managed those with a team of three
engineers
and we had maybe one on-call paged event
a month thereabouts so so that can be
done
but really it comes down to what your
payloads look like
you know one example when we started
using kubernetes that was like one
five times we didn't even have ingresses
yet
and at that point we discovered a
um a problem i would argue a bug in the
way that container resource limits
were implemented that led to in the
worst case
an almost 100 millisecond delay being
added on every hub of a request
through a network network of
microservices
you can imagine if you've got to go
through 10 plus microservices in order
to service a customer request
and in the worst case you add 100
milliseconds at each hop
that quickly adds up so
for for us at the time we were doing
real-time communication
apis that wasn't really acceptable and
so we ended up
actually running a fork of kubernetes
for a couple of versions
until a fix for that got integrated into
the mainline code base
and we could only do that because we
controlled
the control plane the api server the
controller manager
cubelet if we had been on
something like gke we wouldn't have had
a prayer
so we made that decision because we knew
real time stuff was fairly new and
kubernetes was fairly new
and not many people were doing it it
turned out to be the right decision
but really that's the question you
should be asking yourselves
am i doing something unusual am i doing
something
new or am i just doing what everybody
else is doing in which case
host it will serve you just fine and
with that
um i hope there should be some time for
questions i did not look
at the time maybe perfect phil perfect
yeah thanks very much for that
that was really good and yeah you've got
uh we got like seven eight minutes
luxury amount of time for questions
yeah so i've got a couple uh racked up
the first one
uh from chris scotsman said uh phil you
mentioned monitoring
uh investing time in building good
dashboards are there any existing
grafana dashboards for kubernetes
based on best practices
i'm sure they are there are uh i'm
afraid i don't really know many because
as i said when when we started using
kubernetes uh back in my previous
company
that was fairly early on so we built our
own set of dashboards
and so i never really had a need
to look elsewhere um it is always a good
idea though
to have a look around um these sorts of
challenges
are not unique to you um
you know running kubernetes is something
that's becoming more popular
so more and more people are looking into
solutions
to common problems dashboards are one of
them um
i know there are resources out there
unfortunately i can't point you to one
right now
no way i'll just quickly check in i know
um the prometheus folks have got some
really good stuff the gravana website
itself has got a bunch of cool things
and some of my friends are talking if
you're running service mesh like istio
kiyali is well worth looking at
oh yeah yeah yeah we did run kiyalikali
is great because it visualizes the flow
through your service mesh in a way that
makes it a lot easier to pinpoint where
problems are
yeah i found that very useful and what
the other question here
is you mentioned a lot of cool stuff
there if there if someone is
investigating communities where should
they
start investigating as in you want to
play around with it
or looking to run sort of in production
i guess is the
is this i think if you're new to
kubernetes
running kubernetes yourself to begin
with is
always a good idea um gke makes it
incredibly easy
um just spin up a cluster and within
minutes you can run your cube control
and you can try out whatever it is you
want to try out
um if you want to run kubernetes in
production
really that that's where where i would
start and then add to that
all the things that make a production
ready monitoring alerting
um looking at you know you know what
sort of
workloads are you going to be running
you'll want to think about
what sizes and shapes of nodes your
cluster will need
um but it is because everything is is so
componentized
uh it's a system that is very easily
sort of sort of
you know built out of building blocks
you can start simple and as your needs
evolve
you add bits to your cluster
another question from tim nicholas can
you give some other examples of what
now might be non-standard or off the
beaten path when it comes to running
workloads on kubernetes where is the
edge of normal now
i would say the edge of normal is moving
very very quickly
so it's as kubernetes becomes more
mainstream
and more companies look at moving their
existing payloads
to kubernetes they are investing and
thankfully sharing a lot of effort
in in how to make that happen when we
started
really the only thing that worked well
was something like
you know your your ecommerce
applications you know a web shop or
something
trying to do real time on kubernetes was
very unusual
that's changed now um
i think the the niche where you're
really doing something new
is becoming smaller and smaller i would
say one thing
certainly that is not very
commonly done is running
things like databases of large large
scale databases
in cluster and that's because cloud
providers make it incredibly easy to
just
buy in your rds or your cloud sql uh
database as a service and sit that next
to your kubernetes cluster
if you're running on bare metal or or
for some other reason
you can't or don't want to use that
that's an area where you may want to
invest some time in engineering effort
to build good solutions that allow you
to run those payloads
in the same sort of automated
self-healing way as everything else
super time for one more question uh phil
if i was going to run kubernetes
locally what's your favorite tool or
recommended way of doing this
oh so um
what is it what is it called this kind
is what i would kind is is relatively
relatively new um people used to use
mini cube a lot but mini cube
fiddles a lot with with vms and is
very heavy weight and can be more effort
than it's worth sometimes sometimes
kind instead tries to build a kubernetes
cluster
out of docker containers so each node
becomes a docker container running
docker in docker
and as long as your machine has enough
resources it's fairly quickly to spin up
it works pretty much instantly and
it's very good for experimenting we use
kind
for like end-to-end and integration
tests of kubernetes
payloads and certainly i think that's
where i would start if you don't want to
go to a cloud provider and spin up a
hosted cluster there
super thanks so well really appreciate
your time fantastic presentation would
please join me in thanking phil on the
slack
uh we'll see you on the slackville
there's more questions there if that's
okay with you
absolutely thank you very much thanks
again for your time