please to present our next ger a Nimrod
Corps who is going to be talking to us
about migrating existing I am to lease
privilege I am as an IAC so I will leave
it to you to take away did you have your
presentation and ready to rock and roll
or are you just speaking I do I'm ready
thank you very much good all right yep
all right so hello everyone I'm really
happy to be here I hope everybody is
saying safe during these crazy crawler
times I mean rather I'll be talking
about how you can use open source and
automations to help you least privileged
your current existing areas I am and how
you can simplify using these tools so a
little bit about myself I'm a solution
architect at bridge crew rich who is the
cloud security startup found out about a
year ago with a mission to make cloud
security simple I can talk about it a
lot but let's leave it for another talk
generally I've been working for a couple
of years now on AWS
I love open source I'm an active
contributor for a few libraries mainly
around AWS and terraform and I'm also
the author of air I am which is a new
open source I hope you will all be a fan
of by the end of this talk but let's
take it slowly let's start talking about
I am so I am or AWS I am is the service
AWS gives for you to manage all of the
privileges in your account that includes
what all of your users and servers can
and cannot do to put it in simpler terms
but you have the AWS aside to ask more
questions about it so I like to view I
am as kind of a root system it allows in
its essence access to things be servers
API is actions and so forth generally
when you start in the cloud you usually
start out small with a simple set up
maybe you deploy an ec2 instance you
have it with the public
and you let it serve some request from
your app the reason or the big advantage
we all use the cloud is that is the fact
that the cloud allows us to scale and
grow without the overhead of hardware
and servers and all of that stuff so it
is very easy to see that when the
instance starts getting scaled out you
can simply maybe add a little balancer
put an auto scaling group create a more
robust infrastructure but that will
require more than just one or tweak
users and on a c2 instance right
it will require a set of rules a few
users maybe different privileges for
different users someone only have access
to the code that the instance is run
some will need access to manage the auto
scaling and the load balancer and so
forth if we take it a few months or even
years forward we'll have a lot a lot of
extra endpoints and resources we would
have probably grown so we have a lot of
users and roles you might have a
database system you might want to have
more micro services that these instances
talk to and this distributed system
requires a lot of roles a lot of users
all having different access sometimes to
the same resources with different levels
sometimes different resources and this
creates a network that is very hard to
control and see so since this is a
security talk the main question that
arises from I am is who has access to
what right if this service allows giving
access and revoking access the only
answer I want to get from it is who has
access to what let's turn on with a
simple example the question who has
admin access to the account is a
question almost everyone who wants to
look at the privileges in the account
asks so the natural answer would be to
go to the administrator access policy
and I am and see who uses that policy
who has a policy attached so for this
example
count that I used a few weeks ago but
you can see that the administrator
access policy is attached to a group and
to two roles that doesn't completely
answer our question because whichever
user is a member of that group will also
be an admin so you have to go into that
group and list all the users that are
part of that group great so we have
eleven users in the group or admin and
two roles so now I believe I know who
all the admin users in the account are
right well almost
see I am allows you to write custom
policies in JSON syntax just like this
one this is an example for a policy
that's been that I found on a specific
role in the environment and you can see
that it allows all actions and all
resources that's what I call admin this
policy will not make this the the role
or the user that has it be flagged as
admin anywhere in AWS so you have these
rogue entities which you will have to
find to know all the admins in the
account arm so this example shows us two
different recurring issues in I am first
is that I am is very easy to be bypassed
you can have a user have its own
policies and it can be limited but if
you just attach another policy or add it
to a group or replace a simple condition
with the store you might make that
entity at that moment over privileged
without knowing the second thing is that
I am supports complex relationships so
let's say you have a user of course the
user can have the privileges directly
attached to him but as we've just seen
it can also be a member of group and get
the privileges that are assigned to that
group relevant for him but that's not
all a user can also assume a role which
has its own set of policies and that
role can assume a role and have that set
of policies and privileges so A to D
complex to understand what are the exact
period bearers of each user and broening
the account
another issue that is hard to solve is
the enforcement of patterns in Aiea for
example let's say I have 8 employees who
are working on my AWS account and I made
sure one day that all of them have FFA
enabled because they use console for
access using their passwords and then we
brought onto new employees and to enable
MFA you have to do it yourself so until
they said it they don't have an affair
enabled and I'm not getting notified
that they don't have an MFA enabled I'll
have to find out about that by myself
another problem is that it's hard to
trace and verify usage just a pheasant I
gave someone a specific set of
privileges doesn't mean he actually
needs them today and he actually uses
them let's see in a simple example that
hits these two problems on the on the
nail so we had this list of 11 admins
right these are the 11
Esmond from the group we just saw before
and if you look at their access key age
will notice that 10 out of the 11 users
have all the access keys access fees
should be up to 90 days old that's why
the one with the 70 days has a green
check box on it all the rest are all
that's easy that should be at least
rotated if not deleted but that's not
everything we can also note that there
are 4 users here admin users who have
password and do not have MFA enable so
all four of these are prone to
brute-force attacks it will be to
account takeover
they are admins in the account and last
but not least we also have to add means
here who have now who have not used
their credentials for over 200 days bear
in mind that they have static AWS
credentials available and active and
they haven't used it for over 200 days
ok so we found a bunch of problems we
found a bunch of things that we need to
take care of how can we solve it so here
is a simple manual kind of process that
can help you resolve all these problems
first the first phase would be to get
all the configurations get all the usage
and
the entities so you know who uses who
has access to what and also who uses
what then the first question is very
easy whether the entity isn't used or
not the next question we want to answer
the next task we need to accomplish is
to analyze which privileges are both
given and used let's say a user is being
used does he need all of the privileges
that he has or can that be scaled down
next thing we need to do is create a
recommendation that means not just well
this user doesn't need access to VPC it
means we need to group the users who
need the same level of access
maybe modifying policies in our
fine-grained level and not just remove
the entire policy and then the final
thing is also of course to get approval
from the relevant stakeholders you don't
want to miss other people's stuff just
because you they aren't using it right
now
and finally implementing the changes so
how long will that manual process take
you well these are approximations that I
from my experience of running this few
times so collecting all the data and
building it in a good Google sheet or
Excel or whichever tool you like will
take you about an hour because you need
to make a few API calls collect the data
organize it and so forth you also then
need to analyze which privileges are
both given and used you need to go to
the console you use the assets advisor
you need to go through every policy and
statement and see what are the services
and the privileges that that are being
given by every statement in the policy
then it takes a little while to create
the actual recommendation if you build
everything up to this point
well the longest part I'd say was to get
approvals from relevant stakeholders
this means finding holes in the calendar
for the relevant people usually they're
very busy because they are the
bottleneck and finally after you have
their approval the action changes will
take you well that depends
what you use but if you use the console
it will take you about an hour because
for example you can't delete multiple
rolls at once or multiple users at once
if you use the CLI you can delete
multiple rolls but you have to make sure
all the policies are they attached
beforehand you'll have to go bow and
roll off the Roll and detach all of the
policies so you can delete them at once
so it takes a long time and after you've
done this once or twice or four times
like me or even more you understand that
things that are happening again and
again there's no reason to solve them as
if they're it's the first time we meet
them so today I'm really happy to
announce I am it's a new open-source
tool that we launched we as a bridge
crew it's completely open-source you can
find it in the make over there let me
hop over to my browser and you can see
it's a Python tool it's completely
open-source feel free to contribute to
use it to test it we'll walk through it
and see how it helps us in this workflow
to resolve our issues so let's start
with the what we want to achieve using
the automated cleanup so first of all
want to identify the unused entities I
think that's the easiest and most
productive way to start with your
cleanup and right-sizing by entities I
don't mean just unused users and roles I
also mean finding policies that are
attached to users or roles but their
privileges are not being used secondly
we want to detect drifts that means
changes in your environment policies
that were edited policies that were
added and also enable rollback so let's
say you don't like to change or you
don't like the change that you made
afterwards you want to enable a simple
and easy rollback that will make
everything work again you want to be
able to handle scales of over a thousand
entities and I can guarantee you that in
most environments if you include all the
policy attachment and all the user
memberships all of the roles you'll
reach that threshold
very easily and it's hard to manage that
using the console or the API you want to
support stakeholder approval you want to
be able to talk to them not using email
or slack or meetings you want to be able
to do it natively in tools that they use
and finally if you want to reduce the
time to right-size the previous manual
cleanup timeline that I showed you is
way too long so what does this to do
what does air I am do air I am pulls
data from AWS I am api's and AWS access
advisor ApS analyzes them and produces
in the end turn phone code that you can
use to deploy and remove and edit and
update all of your I am infrastructure
what the what are the people resist is
to you needs so it needs read access to
I am and that's it it does not do any
modifications by itself to run the
modifications you need to apply the
terraform and that it will be used using
whichever credentials you choose but the
tool does not do any modification to
your account by itself great so let's
dive into the tool the first command is
called find unused and what it does is
collects all the entities from I am and
reaches them with usage and checks
whether the entity is in use or not so
it's the first part of our workflow it's
very easy to codify but it's hard to do
it when you do it manually so let's do a
quick demo what do you think about that
watch the terminal will hit err I am
fine unused so I already run it once so
I have data locally and see it says it's
so here you see it says we using local
data that's because I ran it locally
otherwise we'll have a few minutes of it
collecting all the data from all the
api's and then it starts telling me what
it found so you'll see we have four
users in this account who are unused we
have
we have no unused access skills which is
good we have no unused console.log in
profiles we also have three roles which
are unused to groups which are redundant
one policy and even one policy
attachment which is unused all of these
should be can be deleted without
affecting your AWS environment at all so
we found what what the unused next up is
to create the permissions baseline so
the next command I'd want to show you is
called recommend groups what it does is
take all of your users filter out all
the unused of course and then split the
users into groups according to logic the
current logic today splits it into three
groups the admin group which are the
active admin users and roles the second
group is student only users so the
active admin users the second group is
called power users it's all the users
who have any right access to the account
and the third group is read-only so that
group will have only read access to any
type of service that you use in AWS so
that command will create the permissions
basically we need it will also help us
create a recommendation but it's not
there yet why not
because as you'll see in a minute the
recommendation is not something that we
can act on it's all outputted in CLI or
maybe it has playbooks but it's not
something that we can go to the relevant
stakeholder and tell him that's the
recommendation that's a plan so let's
jump over to the terminal real quick and
see it in action
so the command err IM recommend groups
so what it does now use the result of
the previous command the find unused and
outputs well we found two active users
in the account one is an active admin
and the other one is called s3 user one
and requires partial write to the
account so it's in the power users for
this specific account we did not find
any read-only users so that was not also
recommended but it would be if
were any users like that great so we're
almost there we already have a
recommendation now we need to build it
into something we can talk about and not
just wave with so the net the next and
last command is called terraform and
that actually creates a recommendation
in terraform let me jump over to the
terminal real quick so it's called air I
am terraform and when you run it what
will happen is it will take the results
of the previous commands it will create
the terraform code and start inputting
the entities if you'll take a look right
now you'll see that I'm getting the
exception that the resource is already
already managed by terraform that's
because I ran it beforehand to save us
waiting for 53 API calls and creations
of terraform state files so I'll cut
this off but let's try it without the
import and see what it says
great
so now it should just create terrible
files and as you can see it says it
migrated the current I am set up to
terraform it migrated 6 users for groups
4 rolls and 18 policies to terraform i
can specify my own custom directory but
for now the default is called results so
let's open results and you see that
there are actual teraphim files for open
one for example groups know if you can
see that but this is the telephone
configuration of all the rooms in the
account including the unused including
group attachments and so on if you're
wondering about user memberships
that's what are the users file but if
you go here and search for membership
you'll see all the memberships for
example my user name Arad is in the
admin and so forth cool so now we can
create a terraform how can we talk about
it with the relevant stakeholders how
can we take it to the next level and
actually get their approval or their
change your quests and move forward
since we are moving everything to
infrastructure its code I
a see you can use code now and your pcs
of your choice I like github but
whatever you like to create a pull
request and start working through there
which is a native tool for more DevOps
and developers it's something that
everyone can see and completely
understand from via so I'll show you an
example of what I did what I did is I
created a new repository for my I am set
up in terraform I committed the output
of the first error from command two to
master so now I have all the groups here
as well
so let's go to groups at TF you'll see
the code that I just showed you in my
home computer and what I'll do now is I
run the command again but this time
without unused so what it does now is
filter out the unused and create new
Terra from files in place to see it
filtered out eleven entities from
terraform and it finally created
successfully two users
two groups one roles and seventeen
policies so let's open results again so
you see the same files exist but they've
edit been edited just now let's dive
into one of them and you see that we
only have the groups that are still
active with the relevant policy
attachments if you'll technically note
that the users will see that also the
unused users were removed and all DDA
only the active users remain here so I
can commit this change to a different
branch which is what I did and now when
I open a pull request between my branch
and master you can actually see the
changes that I would like to incur in
the attack on the account I would like
to delete it without members I would
like to delete the group without
policies I would have to detach these
policies from this group and I can
actually start talking about the
policies directly from here with the
relevant stakeholders so let's say the
stakeholder doesn't want me to remove
the organizational account access role
you can just type it here I will copy
this code back into this file roles
committed and
when everything is approved I can merge
it to map to master so the last part is
how do i implement the changes so there
are many many tools in many ways to
implement to apply the terraform changes
see ICD pipelines and so forth so that's
not something that we it requires high
high level of privileges and it's
something that everyone does already
everyone deploys changes to their
production so we that's not part of the
tool the tool is only for building their
recommendations and gathering all the
data for that great so let's say I ran
area and once I got all the changes I
got it approved I ran it what now what
do I do next
so my recommendation to you guys is to
Brennan run it on a regular basis why
well it will help you identify drifts in
existing configurations are changes in
usage status so that the user uses a
specific privilege but he he stops
because he moved to a different team or
they move to a different architecture
the only way you would know this is to
run this again once in a while it will
also help you identify new
configurations let's say someone
modified an existing policy and made a
mistake of replacing everything with sir
now everything works for him you won't
know it until you run this tool again
that's the second thing I really
recommend for you guys is to start using
static analysis tools to identify bad
practices in your inner infrastructure
is code so let's dive a bit into that
I'd love to recommend to over create
open source tools for this one is Chekov
Chekov identify the bad practices in
terraform in general and also I am in
terraform Jerome specifically also
integrates with your CI CD to avoid
general security issues in terraform
before they are deployed to the real
world so it's recommended
regardless also another really cool tool
is sales forces policy sentry policy
century helps you create new policies
from scratch so let's say you have a
service and you feel that it has too
much
and its privileges are too wide you can
use policy sentry to create using simple
crew than llamo syntax the policy that
you want copied in its output is in the
policy JSON you just paste it in your
role and you're set and you're good to
go next time you run error in that
policy will be refactored in to
terraform and you can follow the changes
from there I do want to call a few other
great tools for I am right sizing and
identify problems yeah these tools are
good for your actual AWS environments
and not for infrastructure it's code the
first set of tools cloud tracker or
Artemis repo kid they use crouch real
data to identify specific API calls and
specific privileges much more
fine-grained than AWS access advisor
used by err I am the problem is that
cloud trail isn't a hundred percent
doesn't have a hundred percent coverage
of all the calls and all the API is in
AWS so if you need to take extra care
when you take action based on these
tools another really cool tool is called
P mapper principle mate mapper by NC C
group it allows to identify all the
possible privilege escalations in the
account what does that mean so I'll give
an example this is a great part of a
graph that's the output of Pima per and
what you see here is that these three
are entities you have two roles and one
user can assume these for example these
roles you can see that through the
arrows so you know that all the people
is that this user has you can also
assume this role and I have all the
privileges that that Bowl has so this
helps you build a graph of all the
privileges privilege escalations in the
account and identify which connections
you want to cut that's all for today I
hope you enjoyed it
do you have any questions that was
tastic thank you so very much I am
looking right now we see her to see what
we have for questions and right now I'm
not seeing anything in the QA and I am
not seeing anything in slack are you
going to be sticking around in our slack
for a little bit I will for sure
fantastic alright well thank you again
so much for being with us today
and have a good one we're going to be
moving to a break shortly and