good morning okay if you can unmute for
me and we can see if the sound is
working I think the sound is working
right yeah good morning Brian can you
hear me
I can't hear you perfectly so that's
that that's the the the the good thing
of having a few minutes mins left we are
live on stream but that doesn't matter
if you can share your screen already I
will I will mix it in whenever we are we
are ready to go you will be instructed
how how this will work and I will just
give you a short introduction in a few
seconds and now we just keep rolling
because the stream is rolling anyway so
you know what the time frame is let's go
for it right and I see your screen is is
coming up amazing so again we already
have the second order the first talk we
are up to the second one already it's
going way fast faster than I would
imagine but again we have a few more
hours to go I would say picking up a 24
hour conference is well we will see
afterwards how I will be at the end of
this whole Trek welcome Jorge I love
that you being here and you're going to
talk about async javascript error
handling I cannot see your screen yet
have you shared your screen or did you
if you want to please try to do it again
and in the meantime I will just keep
keep talking I see Jorge screen and I
will add it to the stream right now and
we see his screen alright Jorge the I
pronounce correctly yeah that's correct
Jorge Jorge Jorge this is Spanish right
the name is Spanish amazing ok amazing I
would say the floor is yours to give it
a go and I will jump in five minutes
before the end with questions that are
coming up in the slide Oh or in the TREC
JavaScript thing it can be that somebody
else will come up but one of the hosts
will come up probably will be me so
let's give it a go
thank you Brian
yeah so hello everybody good morning I'm
very proud to be part of this welcome to
my chalk in the all the talks online
organizer by snakes and other partners
so today I'm gonna be talking about a
bit dissipate it's a very introductory
to async error handling in in JavaScript
and some snippets and some helpful
tricks that you could use when working
with JavaScript Nadia's async traces and
errors in general which always comes
handy right so yeah I think so I'm
basing the in Spain at the minute and
it's 11:00 in the morning so hello and
good morning good afternoon and good
evening to everyone that's listening and
the hostler industry more that will join
later Sydney Singapore Shanghai New
Delhi School London San Francisco New
Zealand lots of people from New Zealand
welcome to my talk now I need to breathe
usually when I'm delivering talks in
from a wider audience I I usually have
to breathe like two times or three times
before I come into into the topic but
now it feels like I'm talking to the
wall you know and I stay good I know
that you're you're back there listening
to me I hope you appreciate this talk
and you learn something new today so
yeah my name is Jorge so if I haven't
introduced myself yet the Brian did and
I'm an engineer I am working at the
moment at a Dyson and with the connected
products and I'm a senior engineer
trying to trying to make the connection
between the Dyson products like the
robot vacuum cleaners purifiers etc and
to connect to the cloud as seamless
seamless as possible
and yet my background is no J yes I can
do a little bit of seashore
Leo : and yeah this this time it's gonna
be only JavaScript right you can find my
webpage and there on the corner and also
my twitter handle feel free to visit so
when I start a talk I usually have a
whole time where I ask the audience to
raise their hands and get starting to
the topic to see and how what's the
level of the audience but this time is
not gonna be possible so yeah please use
the comment sections follow me on
Twitter like and subscribe all that
right let's get into the topic I'm gonna
talk a bit about try-catch blocks in
JavaScript how do you handle errors and
then what is a synchronous programming
and how do you do
how do you do a synchronous programming
inside no yes then a little bit about
arrow stack traces and new functionality
from node 12 that was released last year
I hope with this asynchronous stack
traces so this is a how simple
javascript code looks like we have a
function we say it's go to the beach at
the moment if the location is pained you
cannot go to the beach because we are in
lockdown as most of the most of the
countries are there but yeah else return
true right so if I try to go to the
beach in the Antarctica continent
I can else if I if it gives me a if it
returns force
I'll log a failure right so this is
simple code we all know this is a the
way you handle the errors in synchronous
code so we are not throw in an error but
we are returning to all force and and
then we can act accordingly right now if
we want to do this if we want to get
into their async wall it's gonna be a
bit more complicated given that when you
schedule an asynchronous call you know
from where it's coming where it's going
who who called it and at what time
before what afterward it's very
complicated
right so first let me quickly explain
the synchronous programming as most of
you know is a design pattern which
ensure that non-blocking code execution
so when you schedule an async task you
can the code can continue execute
executing all the tasks synchronous or
asynchronous while be a single stack
task is in the background and executing
itself so JavaScript is a synchronous in
nature and so is know so if you are
trying to get into JavaScript I know yes
you should
it's it's a mess that you learned how to
the basic of asynchronous programming
and and yeah the code executes we had
without having any dependency and no
other so it doesn't depend another
course it just you trigger the action
and it's us in the background executing
and then it will come come back when it
has a proper we saw and this is in this
improves the system efficiency on top
because you can do several things as
synchrony synchronously and if you type
a little bit born into a Singh work in
JavaScript and ideas you you should
realize there is no really a synchronous
it's no it's not like you are doing a
lot of things in parallel but it gives
you the feel I think of an async task
and it won't block the main threat so
the method is it's gonna continue
spinning and when the background task
has everything ready it will be turned
to there it will return to the main
threat so in the beginning there was
callbacks
there were callbacks and using callbacks
is how you will program a async
functionalities using javascript on
ideas but then that's that's that's way
to all I think it was es6 so yeah under
introduced it what they call promises
which are a way of better understanding
the callbacks so in this code we have
the function go to the beach that
returns a new promise that resolves in
one second or a thousand milliseconds so
whenever you call go to the beach it's
gonna wait one second yeah it's gonna
wait one second in the background and
then return so it's taking you one
second literally two to go to the beach
right I don't know maybe to
teleportation or whatever but and so yes
we have our async function go to the
beach and then we have this little
snippet that is top then and which helps
you concatenate actions so basically
when you call go to the go to the beach
function it's not gonna block the main
thread the method is gonna continue
doing whatever it needs to do serve in
HTTP requests or and any other things
and then when go to the beach resolves
after one second the function does
inside the den it's gonna be execute
that's why it's called then so in this
code we have is go to the beach
Antarctica then success right so what
this executes is it cause go to the
beach it waits for a second and then it
prints success so this is the very basic
sample with promises now we can
introduce more things as I explained
while you're doing this icing task when
when you schedule an async task you can
do things on the main thread so for
example what if we want to go to the to
the beach but you need to turn the radio
I do want to turn the radio on in the
meantime so while you are driving to the
beach you want to be listen to the radio
so that's that's why this is useful this
asynchronous programming so in here we
have go to the beach again Antarctica
then success and we print we have that
line console.log turning on the radio in
the meantime which appears to be appears
that it's going to be execute after go
to the beach but because go to the beach
is an a an async function an async task
is gonna be on the background and it's
gonna last one second to resolve the
console.log walk on and will be printed
before they go to the beach
because console.log is a synchronous
function and it's not waiting for
anything so this is when an async
function comes to - to help us being
more performing and having more output
and executing more actions in the same
in the same amount of time so what we
have here now let's let's keep adding
things now using this async stuff we can
continue adding more and more actions
into it for example and well I'm gonna
skip this because this is nature code
and we don't have much time left
basically when we go to the beach after
we write to the beach we console.log CSS
and then we make pocket a little pita
pocket a tortilla is basically a Spanish
language right with tortilla most of you
may know what tortillas so yeah when we
write to the beach we print success and
then we make pocket on a tortilla and
then when boca del tortilla is done
which is we do it in one second we print
ricotta is ready if there's any other in
here we catch it with the catch
expression and we print the lock with
Quinn failure right so the problem with
this is that we you're not in control of
what the errors and what the single
actions and how to respond to the single
actions you can have all this dot then
and do it like a waterfall to the end of
the end of the end of the end on that
and they catch all the errors it's going
to be difficult if you want to action
over go to the beach or over make a
tortilla if there's a failure in dos
it's gonna be cut in the main catch
section so how can we make this better
basically because this promises to be
it's a bit difficult to understand and
to work with the errors
and a new operator if you want to call
it like that it was introduced to no js'
and JavaScript which is async/await
now what async/await is it's a lot of
people define it as the sugar on the top
of promises so we still have promises in
the background but this is an easier way
of writing the code so we have this
awaiting here and it's gonna wait for go
to the beach function to finish before
executing the next line of code so it's
similar to that but we don't need to put
that dot then it's always gonna be await
this function away these of the function
await this function await this function
and everything is gonna look it's gonna
be executed sequentially no J's is going
to wait for each of their a syntax to
return to execute the next time now what
happens in looking at this code now it's
not that easy to catch the errors in the
promises we have this dot catch we will
catch the error thrown by the promise or
the failure thrown by the promise in
this code now we have a single line an
expression that is a wait go to the
beach so it doesn't have any dot then or
any dot catch how do we do that well now
it's when they try catch expression or
try catch block or logical block comes
into action on the left-hand side you
have a simple block so you have a try
and in a catch try it's gonna try
execute whatever is inside that block
and if there's any error is gonna throw
and it's gonna be handled in the catch
block so this way we can have on the
right-hand side a try catch over they go
to beach fun function so if there's a
minute if there's any error we
console.log the error now how does this
work if we want to do several action
like for example male cat on a tortilla
so we have a way to go to the beach
after that's execute whippin success
then
wait maybe cut a tortilla after that's
done then we print pocket a tortilla is
ready and if there's any arrow we have
this try-catch that's going to print the
failure now we have now all this
sequence of events that we execute one
after the other but what about if we
want to try and catch arrows on the
maple cutter a tortilla function not on
the global try-catch block we will end
up like something we will end up with
something like that where we need to put
two different try catches one try catch
for the function for the action of going
to the beach and another try catch for
the action of make a tortilla right so
now this code is easy to read and but
after some time writing if the code is
complicated and you have a lot of
function a lot of actions you probably
are gonna have a lot of try catches and
your code is all gonna look like try
this try this try this try this strategy
Scott Scott Scott Scott Scott so it's a
little bit unbearable when when you have
a lot of functions now this whoa now I
start the landing go :
and I'd year ago are year and a half ago
um and I've always been a I've always
wondered how the error handling was
different to the other scrip unto their
language that I knew and so this is an
example of how to handle the errors the
Golan way where you have this function
data based or query and that function
will return to objects or two variables
it will return data and it will return
error right so now we could easily check
if error is it's Nolan or and then at if
there is any error how is this different
to the try-catch we had well the
behavior is the same but you get rid of
all the try/catch palaver and then just
have only one line that acts if there is
never so the execution will continue and
yes we just do a check if there's an
error then I do something we don't have
this try block and then catch the error
and get the catch block so it looks too
much to me it looks a bit neater it's a
short way of defining things this is an
alternative way of handling the errors
I'm not saying that usually and stop
using try catch e try caches are always
useful but this is I just wanted to
share with you another way of handling
errors so this is how you're doing the
Gollum way now if we want to apply this
to JavaScript this is gonna be a little
bit difficult to explain but basically
this is the same code we had but now the
functions would return an array with two
values the first value is the error and
the second value is a respond so
whenever something goes right we send we
send back as have we solo the function
the error being no and the result and if
something goes bad then we we just
return the error so in the code we can
do what we saw in in the Golan way we
execute the function and save the error
and the response and if there is any
error we act else we continue the
execution you see now the difference
between the two patterns so we don't
need a try caches but we need to
implement this we a way of returning two
values one if the arrow and the other
one is that we saw so in loose
convenient but may be a little bit
complicated or combo leti so then also I
took this idea from from a blog written
by a guy whose last name is ghost name
I'd know who's first the first name but
yeah you have the link in in that and so
he came with with this little function
which is called - and it's a promise and
it will do
the return it will handle there it will
handle returning the right values for
you so you don't have to return this
we array you just call this function a
will handle if the promise is successful
then it will return the error as new and
will return the data if the promise or
the function the async function was not
successful then it will be shown the
array with the arrow button or return
the data so that's exactly what we want
now if we use this function the code
looks like this a little bit easier for
implementing the function so you can see
they go to beach function and they make
work identity a function no longer have
this return array weird thing now we
have it in the main two function up here
so whenever in our main code when we
call go to the beach we call it with a
two function which is going to convert
that result of the promise into this a
new format that we have with the where
we have an array where the first object
is the arrow and the second updated at
a-- so this is how it looks like I think
it's pretty it's pretty neat and I
encourage you to to try on your own
projects to try it on the no triple or
quit and no Jes program and and just
play with with it yeah this is a
comparison where before we had so before
it's on the right hand side you can see
the Tri caches and now we have this led
error response we save the around the
response and then active there's an
error so yeah I found this on the on
this block from Dima Dima Dima and say
hi to him of me
and so the my Grossman came up with this
nice blog post explaining all this
better than I have but yeah you can you
can go to his blog and and check it out
basically at the end of the post he says
that this is a different way of looking
at how to handle async/await
errors for no reason you should not use
try catch and start using this this is
just another night
a way of handling the errors and it's up
to you to choose either of those in the
right situation now let's jump to a
different topic now that we so we have
handle now errors in JavaScript async
errors in JavaScript using this golem
way and this golden snippet now let
let's look at let's look now at how to
what happens with the stack trace with
the errors when you get the errors so I
mentioned before that when you were
getting errors if when you call a Nation
function right it's executing the
background so now the main thread keeps
executing things and when the TAS in the
background finishes it returns a result
to the main thread so now the main
thread can continue and act on the
result of their of that background test
the thing in here is that the main
thread have lost context of what was the
background test I mean when was it
called for what was it was it called and
what is the expecting when was it
executed everything it has no no
background to it or little background to
it and you have to come up with all
sorts of code and patterns to to be able
to tell what's happening with that
request or they dot then and don't catch
that we have been seen but if there's an
error right when when the background
tasks a raises an error it goes to the
main thread and then the main thread is
gonna go okay I had this TAS in the
background that has thrown an error okay
I can see the error but I don't know
what it's coming from so I don't
remember who called it I just know that
it returned an error so I'm just gonna
show this error to the user but really I
don't know what it's coming from so
that's the problem with async functions
I when they are throwing errors so in
here I'm gonna try to explain how can
you get more context or tell the code to
get more context about your error to be
able to debug your code so when you see
the whole stack
you can see okay this function was
called by this function that was called
by this function that was called by this
function and then you go to the code and
find about right so this is again the
simple go to beach program with the
Antarctica and now we have the maple
cattle a tortilla inside they go to
beach function what happens if we
execute this code because mate pocketed
a tortilla function is not defined they
go to the beach function it's gonna
throw and now the main thread wants one
no-work
where from where did it come from and
it's gonna print this I hope you can see
it when we execute by the stack trace we
get preference our maple cat idea is not
defined at go to the beach and the mud
stack trace line four so it's telling us
okay
maple kata a tortilla Dakota fail was
inside they go to the beach function but
I don't know anything else I don't know
when was it call it doesn't show what's
this line right this line here inside
the main async program it's not telling
us where or who called they go to the
beach which resulted in an error because
may balk identity is not defined now
that's a problem because it's difficult
to debug now so what can we do this
little bit of a trick that you can
implement in node and so you have the
function go to the beach
another very beginning of the function
you save the stack trace so you're you
saving a variable was a context of that
function so you know so the program
knows who called a when when did it call
it with with permit what parameters and
what line and everything so we create a
snapshot of the stack and we save it
into a variable now when we try a maple
cutter a tortilla
because make baccata a tortilla is not
defined then we're gonna catch the error
and we're gonna say okay this function
it's not here I'm gonna add it to my
statuaries do I'm gonna put it on my
stack trace so that they the arrow
contains hold information possible and
I'm gonna throw the whole arrow up
now the main function will have all the
context because you will see the whole
stack trace because we save the stack
trace the moment we call the function so
now the stack trace and all information
about the context is a store in a in a
variable right and and we can use it so
it will look like this when you execute
pet a stack trace it will make Bach
identity yeah it's not defined and you
see the whole stack trace and you can
tell from where go to the beach was cool
and it was go in this line at users
where the stack trace line 16 go to the
beach go to the beach that's never in my
pocket that idea so that looks a little
bit better and easier to debug than this
right now this was happening on all
persons of know up until no 12 so what
happened with no 12 which is now LTS by
the way so you should be using it it was
released last year on April last year
and a new functionality that he brought
order it brings is a in now stores there
it does for you this way of storing a
stack it does it for you in the
background in the behind the scenes so
you don't have to do this saving and it
will do it for you so you can see in
here when we execute so this line is for
executing my code with different
versions of node inside the local
container so you could see when we've
run my bad stack trace with no 10 we get
this party started which is not telling
us anything but when you run it with no
12 you can see this new extra line which
is telling us from where or who call
they go to the beach function now this
is a lot better so you should be using
no yeah no yeah yes 12 and and now it
looks in this is simple it looks a very
it looks very simple because it's sample
is very simple but now if you have a
more complicated example for example
this one from there from the rising
stack blog and what we have server
function that called themselves you lost
the stack because they are always in
conscience in here you can see a
comparison when you secure a with with a
noble thing of note it's gonna it's
gonna it's not gonna tell you from what
it comes but when you're security with
no 12 it's gonna tell you that you was
go from the function way to and that was
go from the function wait one and that
was called from whatever functions so
you have the whole stack trace now that
looks better so basically if you are not
using no idea yes but yet you should
migrate or yopo yes or no yes 12 which
is the LCS now I don't know how many
times we have left I think a little bit
sir I'll carry on
so yeah doing a recap and there's a
beautiful alternative way for everyone
huddle in JavaScript which is they go
long way I'm not telling you not to use
the try-catch blocks but you should
definitely give this a part in a try and
also if you're trying to if you your
program has a scene functions
you better use no des 12 which has
better support support from for acing
functions and for acing stack traces be
happy be kind and stay safe these are
the resources I use I'm gonna be sharing
the slides later on in the in a slack in
Twitter and I'm gonna update them to
jihad to my D hub - you can go you can
visit all those blog posts and get more
insights and more details from what I
have explained here I hope it was useful
and you'll learn some today something
today
now it's time for the questions please
use the comment section I don't know
where you have it here here yeah it's on
the right which is I guess ways that
maybe this this way maybe on the screen
yeah what's the point in different
directions and anyway this is a really
really awesome there's a couple of
couple comments questions one I'd love
to hear what you think about the the
alternate
we alternate to some of the things that
you've shown is is tasks either have you
seen that on github is that is that
something that you're familiar with or
or able to kind of compare the two
approaches right so I haven't used this
new approach in any production code
I've just used it for my little toy boy
yet I'm very happy with it
so far I haven't seen any like big
drawbacks to the new approach and I I
have to say that I quite like it because
it you can you don't have to write the
whole function the whole TriCaster is
less lines of code and I think I'm
already tired of using try catch you
know all over the place and so I'm
personally and this is a personal
opinion I prefer the way of having this
if error and then do something so I just
encourage everyone to to give it a try
and and see which option fit better to
each project or to each programming
personality I guess awesome question
about the error dot stack G are you
aware of any performance penalty that
introduces and no I'm not aware of that
as I said I haven't I haven't tried this
code in production no I have perform any
performer no load testing on this maybe
if you try googling for that you might
find some articles that are doing that
but no I haven't I haven't done that
check by myself okay awesome and in the
in the final minute just a quick
question what do you think of the
biggest gotchas for people who are who
are doing async programming for the
first time compared to the normal
typical program alright so one of the
one of the main problems that I found is
trying to understand how to how this
stack traces and the errors were working
and how to handle them that's why I'm
making this presentation yeah I'd say
that was one of the main hurdles but if
you said this was a very big inner
session so if you are learning
javascript or Nadia's and and trying to
get into the async/await wall the more
blog posts you read and the more the
more samples you write sample code you
don't need to write a whole application
but I I really encourage people to write
their own little programs and play with
it play using a way not using a way
using promises promises here promises
there and they will after some tries
they will understand and realize and
come to you and the idea will come to
your mind and say oh now I understand it
because it's a little bit tricky to
understand and sometimes you can say
okay why this function is triggering now
I wasn't expecting it or yeah it should
be waiting for the next function because
I told it to await and it's not working
but yeah after after playing with it you
you you'll be able to grab that
knowledge and and yeah and basically
also with a lot of articles I'm
conscious that the articles within
several articles might be a little bit
confusing because each article has at
some point of view on this thing but in
the end this is code this is it is what
it is and it has the same behavior for
everyone so no matter from which point
of view you are looking at it you
probably always have the same if you
understand it you're gonna be able to
write code in this way awesome oh hey
we're out of time now but thank you very
very much for your session I really
really appreciate it and thank you for
supporting all the talks next up we have
what do we have we have a break next up
and then followed