hey thank you so much for having me so
today I'm gonna give a talk on
typescript called nothing generic about
it how do we switch to my screen as
opposed to me thank you cool umm cool so
today's talk is called nothing at
generic about it and it's about kind of
generics and intermediate features in
typescript so Who am I my name is Mathew
Kurtzman I am a software engineer at
Dropbox Dropbox has been using
typescript since I want to say 2014 so
we have a lot of experience with it I
live and work in New York City which I
love even though it's not doing so hot
right now when I go outside I have this
great face mask that you can see it is
of just you know a face people like it
but yeah you can find me on Twitter at
Matthew Grossman that's usually the best
way to contact me when I'm not giving a
talk and you can find these slides at
generic stop Matthew gerstmann calm now
I kind of want to call this talk is very
much a spiritual sequel to a different
dog I used to give called typescript
seeing past the hype which is very much
the pros and cons of typescript and why
you might want to use it and how it gets
in your way this isn't really an intro
to typescript talk this is a hey let's
cover the intermediate features of
typescript talk so I kind of like to
frame it with some questions you've had
unfortunately there's a little bit of a
delay between me and you in the stream
but I don't really have the luxury of
having live interaction from all of you
so the best we can do is the all the
talk slack so if you are in the track
JavaScript kiss channel can I just get
several people or typing right now just
anything I don't care what you type or
what you say it's just it's kind of the
best way for you to react to me so
there's about 10 seconds between you and
me so if you if something resonates with
you please just several people are
typing respond to gifts it's I enjoy it
so let's let's cover some questions you
might have had when you're working in
typescript how do I create a function
that returns multiple types feel free to
just start typing if you've had this if
you asked this question how do I get the
type from inside of a promise can I use
different types based on some
to see how do I tell typescript that I
know something is wrong and then finally
how do i type the shiny new javascript
pattern right like who remembers HSCs
and ReactOS we're in nightmare too tight
and then render props got a little bit
easier and now fortunately hooks are
very easy to type but you know these
it's kind of we have to keep up with
these patterns and figure how to type
these things and you're first getting
into typescript one of the first things
you learn is it you can use any which
you are initially told is trust me I
know what I'm doing by the way if you
are a Doctor Who fan please just type in
the slack about Doctor Who it makes me
happy so it's very much don't worry
trust me but if it's less of a trust me
I know what I'm doing and a little bit
more like a trust fall right you learn
that pretty quickly you need someone
there to catch you because in any will
start propagating through your codebase
and surely after that you are and it's
not actually a trust fall there's no one
there to catch you any is just going to
start breaking things and the reason for
that is because any is a lot less like
saying hey typescript touch trust me
it's a lot more like saying hey
typescript turn off as far as this
variable is concerned or this argument
is concerned so the first thing I want
to tell you about is Enys twin which is
unknown I like to say that any is the
evil twin of unknown so what exactly is
unknown unknown is the set of all
possible types and the reason I bring it
up is because a lot of the time you're
using any when really you mean I don't
know what type to expect here so unknown
is this option where you can say hey
this could be any possible type we're
gonna figure that out
I got this slide from blog rocket and is
the only slide on set theory if you pull
up these slides you can click on that
but don't worry we're not going to cover
set there today now unknown has some
interesting properties first of all it
has a value so it's it's not like a
valueless type it really does have a
value any value can be assigned to
unknown but we have to determine the
type of it at runtime in order to start
doing stuff with it and I'll show you
what the ergonomics of that look like
now
so let's say I have a function which
takes X and X's of type unknown if I try
to set a number to X it'll complain that
unknown is not assignable it's a type
number if I try to do X plus plus it's
going to complain about arithmetic and
if I try to do X plus seven it's gonna
complain an operator won't work on
unknown but the second I narrow down the
type I can do all these operations just
fine because now typescript is aware hey
this is a number but that was just a
number right like we have a simple check
for that what about more advanced types
well we do that with a process called
type narrowing so what is type narrowing
well we have all these dynamic checks in
our code that can give us information
about values at one time type narrowing
is the process of reflecting this
information in the type checker at
compile time so my goal today is to give
you the tools that you need to reflect
this information in the compiler I don't
expect you to memorize all of this or
really digest and just like internalize
everything we're going to talk about
today what I really want to do is give
you a lot of tools that you can google
in the future so you know roughly hey I
need to go solve this problem this is
the thing that I need to go to do it but
before we cover any of that we have to
talk about the fact that typescript is a
structurally typed language so what does
that mean exactly well I have two types
I have a person and an elf
and they are structured the same so they
both have a name property as far as
typescript is concerned they are the
exact same type so I have Harry and
Dobby who are my person in my elf but if
I could just get several people or
typing for Harry Potter references that
will make me happy and if I call this
function get person name on a person
it's gonna work just fine because
they're structured the same I'm not
gonna have any errors when I do this but
if I add a property to person once they
add this wand property II it's good a
complaint immediately because it is
missing a parameter on type 1 on
person we can also use structural types
to derive other types which is pretty
cool so let's say we let's talk about
intersection types so once I have my
person in my spellcaster now more HP
references and I can do an and on them
to combine these two types into one type
that contains both of them so in this
case wizard which is of type person and
spell caster is the combination of the
two thank you so much Matt for the Harry
Potter gift I appreciate it and if I do
this in one time with person and spell
caster I can splat over the person and
splat over the spell caster and it's
going to produce that wizard for me
similarly we have union types where we
can have a wizard which has name and
string name and spells spells as an
array of strings and then we have a
muggle muggles can't cast spells and
muggles are people too so we have tech
person is wizard or muggle and I made
this function called say my name and it
returns the person's name and this works
just fine because we are using the one
shared property which is name and we're
keying into it if I needed to get more
advanced and figure out is this person a
wizard I could make a type guard
function which can take a person and
then return a boolean whether or not
that person is of the type we expect it
to be which in this case is a wizard now
it's worth noting this is kind of a
runtime type assertion if you've never
used the as keyword keyword in
typescript it's very similar to that but
it's allowing us to be a little more
methodical about when we're just saying
hey I'm very confident about what site
this is total sidebar when I made the
same my name function I tried really
really hard to find a gif of Beyonce as
a wizard and then I stumbled upon this
horrifying thing which I just never want
to see ever again so we're gonna move on
I never want to say that but also never
is a type and even if you've never used
typescript how many of you left this
comment in your code this should never
happen right so never is a type that
allows us to tell typescript hey I
expect you to break let's look at the
ergonomics of that
so let's say I have this assert
exhaustive function right which takes
never so anything that's past two this
will break type-checking
and it returns never so if this function
has ever returned from somewhere it's
gonna also break type-checking so I have
a test exhaustive function which has an
enum over Wizards which right now is
Harry and Hermione and the default case
is assert exhaustive and if it ever gets
to this line this function is now going
to return never and it's going to break
it's also going to be taking wizard
which better not be of type never so if
I go and add a third type to this enum
it's going to complain because it knows
I'm trying to assign a wizards not wrong
to type never and what's cool about this
is you can imagine that we probably have
this enob you know deeply nested inside
of our code base and then we have the
actual function that's using it on the
other side of the code base and two
engineers who never talk could both be
modifying this code and it'll catch
these types of errors which is very cool
now never an unknown have some really
interesting transitive properties so if
we look at a number and something that
should never ever happen well it's gonna
turn out to be something that should
never ever happen that's what that
intersection works out to but if we look
at a number or something that should
never ever happen or string or null
cetera it's going to produce the type
that can actually happen unknown is the
opposite so if we do the intersection of
a number and the set of all possible
types it's going to produce a number but
if we say hey
this could either be a number or the set
of all possible types it's gonna be the
set of all possible types these
properties hold up with net when you use
never an unknown against each other so
never and unknown is never and never or
unknown is unknown but any ruins
everything
fact for the for the few Harry Potter
fans in the audience and he just like
cobblers everything up it's polished
potion it's terrible I actually went to
go see what does any do against never
and unknown interestingly enough the one
time any fails is when you do the
intersection of something that should
never ever happen and any and I have no
idea why so if if you do please let me
know
cool this we're going to move on to
generics which is the namesake of this
talk I am very excited about generics so
I am going to bring in a gif of my girl
Tay because that's this is my feeling
when I talk about she thinks and
generics are like passing a type as an
argument okay so let's look at a basic
example so we have this identity
function which takes an argument returns
it but also in the type layer it's
taking T the type as an argument and
it's returning a value of type T so if I
give it a string it'll return a string
if I give it an array it'll return an
array and if I give it a number it'll
return a number now we can combine these
with some of the features we talked
about earlier so I have my person in my
elf now right which come up with my name
and one just name on the elf and now
spellcaster instead of being its own
type is going to be a generic type that
does t intersected with this object
spells of string so it adds spells to
the object pasture so now when I produce
wizard and house elf it's gonna compile
down to spells and person or spells and
elf and it'll produce this object in
total with all of these properties now
that's a little contrived but you're
actually likely using these in the real
world if you're using typescript so for
example let's say you have a react
component when you give it the props on
that component that
generic when you say hey this is what
this promise results to that's also a
generic we're passing that number as an
argument in the type layer we net
constraints to our generics which is
pretty cool
so a lot of the time we want to say we
only want to be able to pass like one of
these few types so back to my person on
my elf
I just keep using this example now my
spell caster however has this constraint
he extends person and if this doesn't
evaluate to true my type checker is
gonna complain so when I do spell caster
of person is just fine it produces the
wizard but if I try to create a magic
carpet which I'm very proud of this line
I thought it was clever it's going to
complain type string does not satisfy
the constraint person some way for house
elf this is the exact same error when we
tried to pass an elf to that get person
named function when it was missing a
property so it's telling us exactly what
property is missing and why it doesn't
match this constraint let's go to the
next level player we also index in the
type layer and then we can do it with
generics so oh you have another talk on
types code splitting a type tree next or
and I probably spend ten minutes in that
talk on this slide but we're gonna give
a rough overhead of it a review of it so
let's say I have this Redux state which
has people and elves right I can look at
the key people similarly to how I would
in a real object in JavaScript and it'll
return type for me so it allows me to
index into the type layer and then I can
use a generic and do that with a
variable type so I have this function
called get key from redux store and it
takes the type redux state which is
these people in these elves and now i
have a generic
t extends kiev redux state what is key
arenak state well that is a union of all
the keys on redox state so we're now
saying that this key has to be one of
the keys inside of the object that's
given to it
and it's returning a type of one of the
values on that object by doing Redux
state at T which will be whatever key
we're looking for just pretty cool in my
opinion
so a lot of that was type narrowing
where it's I want the compiler to figure
out what type we have but sometimes we
want to go from Taipei to type B we
watching Doctor Who right now so I'm
just like really into the doctor here
yes so map types are an interesting case
for these so we can do loops in the type
layer as well so these two functions
partial and pink are very popular in
typescript and you can see here we're
doing P in K or key of T so we are
looping over something in the type layer
so I want to look into how each of these
work will start with partial and then
then we'll do pick so for Dropbox we
think about files a lot and let's say we
want to have all the properties on a
file will be optional right like maybe
we have the name at the beginning but
then we need to go fetch the size and
permissions of the file so partial makes
all these properties optional the way
this works is partial take some generic
it takes an object or type and then it
produces key of that type inside of it
which in this case is going to be name
size and permissions so we are going to
loop over that where P is each of those
we make it optional and then we index in
the type layer and return that type at
that index look at one more example of
this heck here's a function that allows
us to get a subset of the properties on
a type so we pass it file and then we
say we want name or size and it gives us
just the subset of those properties this
works very similarly it takes T which is
an odd generic but now we're doing now
we're producing that array that we're
going to loop over in the type signature
because we have to have that constraint
K must be one of the keys of there and
we're doing that the signature so before
we were doing into the body now we're
doing this up in the signature we're
looping through
okay p NK and then we index into the
type layer again and return the specific
type now I know that was a lot like a
lot of advanced typescript and yeah
my brain was pretty fried the first time
I gave that so I just want to give
everyone a mental rest can y'all just
start posting gifts in the slack shadow
with any of your favorite things I don't
care what just put some gifts give your
brain a break
cuz we're gonna move on to some even
more advanced type scripts short light
cool I'm like waiting for the catch it's
happened yes thank you damn cool
conditional types so we can have types
and perform if-else logic in the type
layer so I have this type number or null
and it takes my generic and now we have
a constraint t extends number and if
this predicate evaluates it's true it's
gonna return a number otherwise it's
been a return null so if I give it a
number it returns number if I give it a
string a boolean or even no it returns
null and we could do some pretty cool
things with this so we could say hey I
need the type I need to either the
promise of a type or the type inside of
it and we can say this is either going
to extend the promise and it's going to
return the promise or it's gonna be
never sorry I skipped ahead so in this
case we're saying hey this is either a
promise of anything and we return the
promise of anything or we return the
type inside of it that's kind of weird
right because like this is the set of
all possible types and maybe we want to
actually get the type out from inside
the promise and this is where we use one
of my favorite features of typescript
this is called inference types and this
is the last thing we're gonna cover and
I like to think of inference types as
what's in the box
so we this func leave a type now called
unwrap promise we have the sync string
key extends promise but now we have
infer a and what this does is as long as
T extends promise it's going to return
the type inside of that promise
otherwise the type checker will break
so when we look at a promise of string
or number and we go to unwrap the
promise it's gonna give us that inside
type if we give it something that isn't
a promise it's going to fail that that's
the check and it's gonna break in the
type wire it's going to return never we
can use this for other things too like
we can get the arguments of a function
so if we can say hey if this T extends a
function we can infer the arguments of
it and return them so let's see whether
the argument or we break the type
checker so when I give it this function
that takes a or B a and B it's going to
return a tuple of titin number and
string you knew this in react as well I
had to have one more Taylor Swift
reference so assuming that it is of type
react component we can infer the props
so now it'll return the props break the
type checker and if we give it a taylor
component we have the list of albums as
props and this is effectively a function
that gets those props out of the
component in the type layer which in
this case will return albums so let's
review shall we because we've just
covered a lot covered structural typing
or two types of the same and covered
never where we can tell typescript that
something broke become an unknown where
we can say hey I don't know what type is
here we covered unions where we can look
at type A or type B recovered
intersections or a combining types we
covered generics where we're using types
as arguments recovered indexing we
covered map types we covered conditional
types and inference types and that is
way too much I don't expect anyone to
actually remember all of that here's
what I what I hope for you here's the
slide of everything we covered today
this is what you can Google when you are
digging into typescript code and you
know how an overview of these things
here's what I actually want you to take
away from it from this I want you to
avoid any at all costs I want you to
start with unknown and see what happens
and I want you to use never to tell
typescript that something is broken so
thank you so much my name is matthew
Gerstmann and i think we can move on to
questions we have a few minutes for
those
hey Thank You Matthew that was pretty
awesome thank you and I also like the
Harry Potter references now always for
my own amusement so so a little
philosophical there start from the
unknown and see what happens
yeah a little bit so so what are some of
the disadvantages of typescript you you
you gave us a really good picture of
what's what's awesome about it and I
loved it but what are the things we
should be careful about the kind of so
if you're new to typescript which this
was very much not aimed at those at
those people um the biggest thing I will
tell you is that typescript will get in
your way for the first few months and
then it will quickly turn into something
you can't live without so there's a lot
of stuff where just like it's telling
you in your editor what isn't isn't
broken but when you're first figuring
out how to type these advanced patterns
or you're like like the first time you
dig into a library and you have to look
at all these generics or all these crazy
features you're just like what is going
on here um so it's really the the
learning curve is the worst part of it I
have no other complaints about
typescript actually okay that's awesome
types good compiles down to JavaScript
right yeah so typescript is a superset
of JavaScript
it supports compiling down to you es 6
es 5 or even es 3 there's a whole bunch
of flags sometimes people use it with or
without babel depending on what they're
looking to do be guess it runs in the
browser as JavaScript okay is there some
some mismatch between typescript and
JavaScript in that case where maybe
typescript compiler down to something
that isn't quite directly matched with
JavaScript is that still the case or um
so it's funny so theoretically and for
all practical purposes the answer to
that is typescript always compiles down
to exactly equivalent JavaScript so
typescript is a superset it's not really
like CoffeeScript where there's
different syntax is the exact
same thing now I say this was an
asterisk on it because funnily enough a
security engineer at Dropbox found the
one case where you have valid typescript
that produces something different in
JavaScript but that is a bug not so much
a feature so let's go ahead and let's go
with ninety-nine point a lot of noise
well that's good that's good to know
excellent where the things that you wish
typescript did not have interesting so
there's there's both interfaces and
types
I personally lean towards types I don't
think it's very clear to people when to
use which one I think that's the I think
that's the biggest thing where it's like
uh people are like I don't know which
feature to use here and I still don't
know which one to use most of the time
um there's a great book I write called
effective typescript and it pretty much
the guidance in there was pretty much
use whatever your code base started with
um so I guess I'd probably kill one of
those if I had to pick yeah well so I do
agree with what you're saying it did
throw me a little bit off especially
with angular interfaces are so important
and and to a great extent I would say
typescript having you know interfaces
kind of favors the angular way of
developing things but it can get a
little confusing as to like why would I
need it so yeah excellent
well that was an amazing talk really
enjoyed it so thanks for your time
let me check really quickly if there's
any more questions I don't see any any
more questions so thank you so much
appreciate it cool thank you so much
[Music]