so um up next we have shift
left shift right the devops hokey pokey
uh i'm in love with the title alone so
i'm really excited to uh bring out our
our speakers and i'll let you guys
introduce and take it away
sure so yeah i appreciate it so uh yeah
like you said
uh thanks jeff shift left shift right
the devsec ops hokey pokey
uh we are gonna talk today all about how
we employ strategies to bring security
into this devops picture devops has been
around since 2008
we've pretty well know what that animal
looks like at this point but we still
struggle to make security a part of it
so first and foremost couple
introductions my name's alyssa miller
i'm an application security advocate for
sneak
i am a recovering developer for
i spent 10 years in financial services
as a dev
before i moved into security where i've
been for the last
almost 15 years of my life so
um i have the fortunate uh
position of having seen both sides of
this
well at least two of the three sides of
the equation and quite honestly i've
seen the op
side too but i've got someone really
cool here with me as well
hey there folks uh my name is garrett
gross i work as a technical advisor
doing application security at rapid
rapid7 my background is
your typical script kitty starting from
a young age and
somehow honed that uh that into a trade
so happy to be here and i love speaking
with alyssa what this is our what
third time speaking together yeah we did
a
couple events at rsa earlier this year
and
who who knew those were going to be the
better times right i'll go back in the
old days right yeah
right yeah so the long long ago um
yeah it has definitely changed a lot but
um you know it's not just our world
as we know it now that's changed a lot
um software development
has really changed a lot and
our attitudes towards software
development have changed quite a bit too
when we talk about security years and
years ago we would
have conversations about security and
the message always was kind of you know
the security team was responsible for
that
the security team they handle it all
right um
we've grown with this message for years
now
we've pushed out there this idea of okay
security's got to push left we need to
get
further into the sdlc and then devops
throwed up about you know a little over
a decade ago and then it was like oh my
gosh
these developers are moving faster and
faster how are we going to keep up with
security
and so we've put more and more pressure
on developers
and indeed we see that in the attitudes
across the industry sneak last year in
our annual state of open source security
report
we asked a question on our survey
who should own application security in
your organization as you can see the
results
overwhelmingly they picked developers
so this wasn't a pick one this was a
multi-select as you can see from the
the percentages here and yet developers
stood out
far and away more than security or
operations or anyone else
garrett i assume you've heard this
before too
yeah i mean this is consistent with what
we hear all the time i think every time
you and i ask this question
it's about the same split and you know
my experience was
we only had so much influence you know
you started to see how much multifaceted
uh buy-in you needed from other parts of
the business not only just the
the technical stakeholders so we see
this
this you know trend shifting now to
where developers are
thought to own security but you know
we're starting to see that it's uh it's
kind of shared amongst the organizations
so that's not the only thing that's
changed about development
you know i think back to when i was a
developer
right and if i wrote an application i
had an application that was a hundred
thousand lines of code
i pretty much wrote a hundred thousand
lines of code yeah maybe i pulled in
other redistributables and things that
were in you know whether they're in dlls
or other libraries or things
however you know depending where we were
programming at the time
but that's all changed now and it's it's
really
become exacerbated by this devops
approach
and really that's led to this growth in
open source packages
so i can take an application like this
example
java pack or application three java
files 80 lines of code this developer
wrote
but they included seven other packages
you can see
the the spring boot framework here and
being included and what happens is now
those seven
dependencies that i have in my
application
well they've all got their own
dependencies too so
that turns into 59 additional
dependencies that i may or may not even
know about but that's
713 000 lines of code
my 80 lines turned into 713 000.
that's almost a 1 000 increase in
application size and the worst part is i
might not even know
all of what's there well and you could
say well okay why don't you just
dig into it why don't you just check out
what what that code base looks like of
all these dependencies but
you got to remember the nature of devops
the speed at which we now
operate uh prevents that it would be
absolutely impossible and your your
business would not support
that level of manual introspection i
guess
you could call it that yeah i mean if
for anybody that's ever see this is
where if we were live i'd be asking you
who's ever tried to like manually walk a
dependency tree
it's night marriage and so that that can
be something that's truly difficult
but it's not just developers who have a
problem it's the op
side so here's this is a great tweet
from kelsey hightower i was debating how
i was going to quote it
and ultimately we just decided you know
what we'll just take kelsey's
tweet directly you know if this is the
reality when you want to spin up an
application environment
you're going to roll that that new
infrastructure
this is everything that's involved but
yet we're expecting the developers more
and more as we move into
this you know containers and
cloud native environments all these new
paradigms we're expecting developers to
be able to write
code that defines all of these
components
to the infrastructure that their
software is going to run in
and so now we're saying okay devs you're
responsible for developing code
you're responsible for making sure it's
secure and all by the way
it's up to you devs to take care of this
whole upside of it as well because
hey we're doing a devops culture here we
you know dev and ops you're all together
so you all work this together
and this is just adding further
complexity
yeah and on the security side you almost
have to be an expert in in
how each of these interoperate and who's
sharing which permissions and
you know kelsey's talking about uh you
need
you know the rest of that as well bring
servers people in glue
well i mean i don't know what you think
alyssa but that glue to me is
communication
and kind of like a a shared buy-in and
that's uh
that's quite the evolution in in that
relationship i mean yeah we're seeing it
today and and we're seeing folks that
are
really executing and firing on all
cylinders but for those folks that are
in that
you know transition to a devops or
you know in the security auspices a ci
cd type
uh integration uh it's it's tough and
it's not uh it's not the easiest path
yeah so you mentioned security right i
mean
oh my god talk about complexity
we're adding more and more technology
every day that security is now
gotta be aware of we're adding all of
these things in terms
of compliance factors and
audits and and all these layers of
security that we're looking for
so now add this on top and this is what
we're talking about now when we say
devsecops
we're looking for people who run a
shared responsibility
across all these areas and indeed i mean
you know you've got two security people
here sitting in a devops track
which should tell you something right
away that
all right there's more work to be done
here
well and i mean again that relationship
kind of getting this going
not only relies on mastery and uh just
an awareness of all these technologies
but
also relies on your ability to execute
uh in a time frame that you know you've
already committed to and like alyssa
said i
i'm not a developer i've never done been
a developer i have the utmost
uh most respect for dev teams but that
motivation of getting stuff out quickly
is much different from
my motivation which is i'm culpable for
the security of this product so um
timing you know and and speed and stuff
that's
it's kind of a meeting in the middle and
trying to understand each side and each
other's motivations
is also kind of what comes into play
here yeah and and so
you have kind of that what we've always
felt
in these silos is those conflicting
priorities right so if we look at the
reality of what's happening in devsecops
today
we've got developers trying to push
right because we're telling them hey
you've got more and more of the
infrastructure
you're writing code that's defining the
very
infrastructure on which your stuff's
going to run whether it's in a cloud
whether you're using some other
container environment whatever it is
as a result of that we've got ops
pushing up the stack
because more and more this is now
code defined less and less of the
infrastructure is actually physical
hardware that we're worrying about
and then you've got security who have
for the last two decades
at least has been trying trying trying
to push
left and so the thing i really liked in
kelsey's
tweet i think we're gonna referencing
back to that a few times
is you know he mentions people
so often when we talk devsecops we talk
about
we get hung up in technology and maybe
we think about process right we think
about a devops pipeline we think about
ci cd and we think about how we can
automate that and make it faster
all too often we forget that devops and
therefore dev sec
ops is really all about the culture so
how do we bring these people together
yeah there's only so much that pizza and
drinks can do to
to heal that that relationship that you
know it just traditionally has been
tenuous um i know that what i've
experienced in the past is
something gets pushed out it's you know
pushed out to production
you run some sort of external scan you
know pen test or a desk scan or
something like that
and then you communicate those results
back to this
somewhat voluminous format and just adds
a bunch of work and you know oftentimes
the dev teams
spend a lot of time poking holes in the
tools and kind of proving why
why they don't work that well is you
know rather than then chewing through
the results and kind of abiding by your
remediation guidance and it's that
feedback loop right that slow feedback
loop
that makes this traditional approach
that you see here not work anymore
yeah this is why security is struggling
so hard with devops still
over a decade later it's because we've
always thought of security as we're the
gatekeepers
we have these gates between the various
phases of that delivery pipeline
and there's this big feedback loop and
like you said
we create these huge reports of here's
all your vulnerabilities you got to fix
them
we don't enable developers to address
that as
part of their processes and what we need
to do is we need to give them
the knowledge and the ability to make
decisions
so that they can do this as a part of
those phases of their development
so rather than having these gates
between
phases how do we make security practices
a part of that phase how does threat
modeling become part of the backlog how
do
sas and das tools become part of our
build and test processes
how does container security fit in with
our deployment process and so forth
yeah absolutely and again that
relationship
uh proving that you're there to augment
it in a positive way
rather than hinder it is key and you
know
what better way than to actually put
this functionality
uh in the hands of your development
teams rather than abstracting and you
know kind of
kind of making them play by your rules
offer that same functionality and that
same
reach and visibility through like you
know the ide
or uh deploying an automation framework
like jenkins
it goes a very long way and again it
uh kind of in tandem builds a little bit
of responsibility
in the development team of security yep
and that's that concept of frictionless
enablement
this is what makes devsecops work
when i can enable my developers with
security practices
that bring them the tools and the
decision making power that they need
to be able to do this in a way that is
frictionless
to their existing development processes
this is kind of the holy grail
of devsecops so how do we chase this
down
well we need to start by just reducing
the noise and fatigue we talked about
these large reports
and how getting that at the end of a
development cycle when we're ready to go
deploy
you know if we're in a ci cd pipeline in
particular we can't afford those long
feedback loops
so how can we start reducing that why
mention threat modeling
how do we bring threat modeling into the
backlog
well make it part of the user story
why doesn't the user story capture
the threat model for that particular
user story
think about it this way if you've got
business people you've got business
analysts or
whoever it is that's writing your user
stories
why are they aren't they the most
capable
actually of being able to put context
around what the threats
are that that user story introduces to
the application
now with that information as part of the
user story when i pull that user story
into my sprint
i know that okay i can prioritize how
i'm going to design
you know as i'm coding this like i can
start to
prioritize based on the risks that have
been identified through that threat
model
and now as i'm designing for code
i know what the requirements are the the
security controls that i need to address
that are gonna ultimately mitigate those
threats
to that user story that i'm now working
to implement within my application
and of course this continues flowing up
up the line then through the pipeline
it hits ci cd if i've got that
information from the user's
story onward and i'm constantly building
off of that
now i've already defined my unit test
cases
that are at that first level after
commit within my ci cd pipeline
so i've now enabled the ability to
automate
we've heard that term a lot and we it
that's another one that feels like the
holy grail that we never quite achieve
i can automate those tests in a whole
new way just by bringing that threat
modeling information so early in the
process
yeah and that way it's not perceived as
an interrupt again it's a
positive augmentation of their process
um and you know you talk about
automation um that's thrown around a lot
and uh oftentimes the the
i don't know the process involved in
getting automation going the process
and i mean just getting a dev team uh
aware that this automation is happening
and you know used to
the cadence of maybe receiving uh the
vulnerability reports and then
remediating them
um just you know getting there again
it's a process but once you get there
that that trust of we're kind of we're
all aligned in the same goal is a lot
easier to elucidate than
hey here's a 400 page report good luck
so and that's a really good point right
if i want developers to adopt
my security initiatives my security
practices and i say that as a security
person that's the my my my
right i need to come meet them
where they live i need to be leveraging
automation
how do i you mentioned jenkins before
how do i bring
into that continuous integration
environment
these capabilities and it's looking at
how do i select tools that are going to
fit into this
automated pipeline and so from a
security perspective
this needs to be part of our focus so
as we're looking at this grand scheme of
all right
here's everything that's within
a devops or devsecops pipeline
i need to make sure that those elements
that i'm
asking my developers to implement
integrate with these technologies that
they're using
yeah absolutely and again that's when
you're looking for these tools look for
extensibility look for the ability to
you know drive these tools using api
calls rather than having to
to operate within a ui even if it's some
kind of you know single pane of glass
type pitch that we're all familiar with
as developers you're used to you know
interacting in a
in a much different manner so things
like you know these jenkins automation
or
integrations it's all api driven and so
you can even roll your own automation if
you're
if you're savvy uh and then the the
feasibility of using those tools is
still the same
and you even see the ecosystems up here
so you know thinking
again in terms of shortening these
feedback cycles looking for
tools that instead of providing
a report at all what about having those
tools integrated in the ide
where i'm typing and in real time if i'm
making a call to a vulnerable package
why can't i have a tool that tells me
right there in my id
hey you're pulling in something here
that's got a vulnerability are you sure
you really want to do this
and then give the developers that
ability
to react to that in real time now you're
not
saddling them with outside processes
that create friction
that create these slow feedback loops
that ultimately at the end of the day
cause developers not to adopt the
practices we want to do
so go ahead oh sorry i was just saying
not to
provide counterpoint here but i just
want to you know bolster that with a
healthy dose of
you know don't put all your eggs in one
basket and realize that these
integrations and these tools still
require some some hand holding for
especially when you're kind of getting
off your your feet you're going to need
to
work with dev teams and then again i'm
speaking to security folks because
that's that's where i come from you need
to work the dev teams to understand
uh maybe what these what these
exploitable vulnerabilities are and how
they manifest and
what they look like because something
like a sas
tool is going to show you a very
explicit you know piece of
uh of the code and how we've signature
matched that to a known vulnerable
database but
something like a das tool is going to
show you how that vulnerability is
manifested
in http so again you may have to do some
uh some some enablement for for your dev
teams to kind of get this going and vice
versa for the dev teams
you may have to do some enabling on the
security side but i think the point is
with these tools they really make that
whole process that
whole cohesion process a lot easier
exactly and that feeds perfectly into
the last point
i mentioned before kelsey hightower's
tweet and
how much i like the idea of the people
and i also mentioned this idea of
meeting them where they live
when we're building a devsecops culture
that is a culture of shared
responsibility
where everybody is responsible for every
element
of the pipeline we've we've put it out
there
there's plenty of noise being made about
oh security is everybody's
responsibility
well what about dev isn't delivering
code quick
just as much a responsibility of the
security
practices as it is the dev practices
isn't delivering stable infrastructure
that's on the developers and the
security team as much as it is on
anybody that has an ops discipline
and so what we need to start creating is
this culture where
we all understand that devsec and ops
are responsible for
devsecond ops that shared responsibility
sure you've got people
who are very specialized in development
and that's their key focus you've got
the security team who's very focused and
has that niche knowledge
and you've got the ops folks but how do
we start to drive
more of that mutual empathy not just
not just the security team having
empathy for developers which
is lacking for sure but how do we also
get developers to have that same level
of empathy for the security team
so a couple ideas here the first is
doing a walk a mile in their shoes
program
really tying your the various
disciplines together
and bringing them into a mutual
engagement where
their daily activities are tied together
they're in the same meetings they're
going to the same stand-ups
and then we've already mentioned from a
tools perspective
paving that road make it easy to get
code from the backlog to production
but do it securely and stable yeah and
you know some some operational tips here
like it says up there
um when you are selecting your security
tools involve your dev department i mean
again for some folks that's an obvious
one but
you should definitely have their buy-in
you should uh at least help them
understand
um you know what these uh what these
initiatives or approaches are gonna do
how they're gonna augment or i mean
let's face it change the development
life cycle and
um what the results are gonna be um
security folks go to a dev stand-up just
just start attending those meetings i
mean you know maybe ask first but
you know show up and and and listen and
and you know don't be a know-it-all
don't try to be
security you know person in the in in
the the meeting but just sit there and
try to understand and get used to the
nomenclature and i and same thing for
dev folks come and
join our security stand-ups and and try
to understand
um maybe where we're coming from and and
just a little bit of that uh you know
bridges built from from both sides
uh it helps out a ton absolutely
so i know it's a short talk today not
you know a little 25 minute slot here
but definitely appreciate
you all coming and joining us for this
certainly open to continuing the
conversation uh both of our contact
information is
up there um easiest way to get in touch
with me you see my twitter handle there
please by all means feel free to jump in
anytime and follow me on twitter shoot
me a dm
i'm always happy to have these
conversations
all right well thank you for that talk
um we
we do have a couple of questions a
couple of them are by me because i was
sitting there taking notes like yeah
yeah
that's what i'm talking about um
security people talking about devs
fights yes let's do this
right i'm pumped um first question do
you have any recommendations on modern
books about securing code
boy oh that's a tough one um
actually for modern books i can't say
that i specifically do i know there's a
number of them out there i can think of
a few publishers
who do really good work in that area um
you know i mean manning and wiley are
two that come
right to mind who are doing a lot of
books right now focused on
uh not just learning code but learning
code securely and so forth i don't i
don't have a specific title though i
apologize
um maybe not secure coding because again
that's that's not the perspective i come
from but
uh definitely devsecops the phoenix
project
is a must-read uh it is awesome it is
about a
fictional company and if you uh read the
book you'll you'll know what i'm talking
about
but it's awesome it really talks about
um the evolution
of integrating security into development
kind of the trials and tribulations
lessons learned because again
that's the unfortunate side of it is
it's a change
and change is sometimes fraught with
lessons learned yep absolutely
um do you feel like the tooling has
gotten better
becoming more accessible and i think the
quintessential example
the question we gave was licensing costs
prohibiting widespread usage and
adoption right so it's like ah we can
secure this pipeline but not this
pipeline because
we don't have the budget yeah so that
that's a really good point right there's
two questions that you actually asked in
there one i think the
the tooling is definitely becoming more
accessible um
you know but there's also a lot of
niche point products out there and so
figuring out you know which ones
fit best into your pipeline what we're
really seeing though that's really nice
is there's a lot
of uh different vendors out there now
who have community editions that are
available
um you know not to toot any horns but i
happen to work for one right
um so you know
there we're seeing more and more of that
i think the other thing
uh that we're going to start to see more
of and it's really become a focus are
these
these devsecops tools that really come
at it from a developer perspective
again you know i can sit here and talk
about sneak all day long of course but
this isn't a sales
pitch there are others too that we think
about a lot of those logos you saw up
there that are in those
pipelines a lot of them are starting to
address this now not just
from a security perspective but from how
do we create
tools that developers actually want to
use
yeah and you know working for a vendor
that also produces
uh open source software metasploit right
for that
um you know it's it's kind of both sides
of the coin
um i would say to answer this question
we see these kind of operations side of
security
moving to more of an operations team and
maybe the
security process enables and creation
moving to more of a concentrated infosec
team at least in these devsecops models
where
these tools can't be so security focused
kind of like we're talking about meeting
people in the middle and being just a
little bit more
usable across the board so um some folks
would say they're becoming easier to use
i don't think so i think they're
becoming more streamlined because we're
able to make
maybe a little bit more assumptions with
uh the configuration
of things like you know integrations or
you know app scans or something like
that
but i will say that some vendors aren't
aren't thinking in the right
way as far as how the products are
licensed um but you know a good vendor
will listen to their customer base and
make changes
to to better suit their use cases
awesome all right well we're out of time
but the next session's mine and the
questions are mine so i'm going to go
ahead and ask it
uh does product own part of the security
posture since they are typically
prioritizing the backlog
garrett knows that i love this question
because yes
i am all about threat modeling so i
mentioned threat modeling in the backlog
before
that i've actually in other talks used
the term and i hate myself for saying it
but i'm going to say it again
bizdevsecops i really don't want to get
in the business of just continuing to
grow that terminology but
but really bringing business into this
is crucial
having the product team be a part of
early on
they're the ones writing that user story
they're the ones that understand okay
what is actually most important in this
application what are the
critical assets the critical
functionality and speak to that in terms
of business impact
you know you think about threat modeling
with like stride and dread and all these
frameworks they're great but they're so
technically focused
they lack context and so you know being
able to bring
that stronger context up this is what
this threat means in terms of our
business and in terms of this
application
and making that a part of the user story
now you can rely on well-trained and
especially your senior developers and
architects to say all right because of
that we have to have these controls
well you can draw a parallel to just
regular security i mean you need to have
different perspectives to really make it
work
awesome all right well we got to cut it
there hey
thank you so much i really enjoyed the
presentation uh and i know our audience
did as well
uh so thanks again yeah thanks jeff
thanks everyone
take care