ray tang and robert halter if one of you
wants to share their screen
and i can blend it in into the stream
okay uh yes i see the screen and the
screen is
up it is all yours good luck all right
well thanks everyone for attending and
joining this and uh
you know it's tough times and uh i'm
very happy to be here i'm ray i'm a
developer advocate at google cloud
um and i am doing a lot of work around
dependency management
uh here for our con libraries and so we
created the site called glbp.dev
and we're going to talk through some of
the things that i learned and i learned
everything from
robert schulte thank you
so my name is rose holton most people
know me from apache maven i've done a
couple of
conferences uh and do a lot of talks
about it
uh just to explain uh how strong
maven probably is but also sometimes how
hard it is and especially this
topic about dependency management it is
tricky sometimes
and uh well we only have 30 minutes so
let's go yeah and for the record robert
is in netherland i'm in the usa and
we're doing this
session jointly so this is pretty
amazing
so let's see the code so i have some
simple code here to demonstrate some of
the things and by the way
these are all the issues that i
personally ran into when i was using
some of our client libraries are talks
to google cloud platform and la
has changed a lot has been fixed and uh
i had to go back in time
to figure out okay what happened which
which with what old versions and uh
to reproduce some of these issues okay
so first of all
uh this you know this is not the current
state it's definitely much better
uh but then uh but these are the issues
that people run into constantly
and with or without you know some of our
libraries right
so this is a very simple test uh i just
created a test
that simply uses a client library in
this case which is a dependency
and i'm using two different dependencies
here i'm using the client library and
also truth
to do some validation right so in my
maven palm.xml
i have just two different dependencies
here i have truth for validation
and you'll have the api client library
uh and robert will probably code this
out which is that well if you're doing a
test first of all
put your dependency in the right scope
so that it doesn't leak through the
compile scope right so
let's say the scope to test and uh we
should
the only two dependencies what could
possibly go wrong right
right well let's let's give it a try so
i'm going to go ahead and run test
from ide uh there we go so it's running
the test right everything should be
working but of course it doesn't work
uh and this is the type of arrow that we
always see
when we uh at the wrong time when we
have some kind of conflict with our
dependencies
and uh let me go back here um i'm not
sure like how many people on the stream
actually see these arrows no such method
found
or no such method arrow no such field
arrow or a no class def found arrow
what happened robert why do these things
happen and how do i fix this
so uh probably what happened is that you
are picking up
a different class than expected so there
used to be some methods
i'm not sure the czech argument
and it doesn't exist anymore and what's
kind of amazing it starts with
com.google right
yeah right yeah come down google the
comment that's usually guava so at least
we have some
detective work here that we know that
it's probably in guava somewhere
so so there's probably a dependency
conflict with this particular artifact
how do we find out more well most
most of the time what you do is let's
see a dependency tree
okay so i'm going to use maven
dependency tree to show
me like what is the result dependency
that maven is actually going to be using
right
so i'm going to say even dependency tree
and
i don't know man like everything here
looks i mean obviously there's a lot
but there's nothing here that tells me
hey
by the way something could possibly have
gone wrong now so this is the resolved
dependency tree and you see also all the
transitive dependencies
even though you specified only two you
will get
also all the dependencies of those
dependencies
so right
so what we can do is uh we can add for
both
to give you more information about
dependencies
so let me do the verbose uh this way we
can see
a lot more information let's see here
uh-huh so for example i'm going to find
any one of these things with this
interesting line right so for example
above java
right uh it says 3.9 but it was omitted
because it was conflicting with another
dependency that's in the tree
yes so so
i guess we can figure out okay do we
actually have some
issue with guava in this case so this
one i'm going to do i'm going to say
maven dependency 3d verbose and
let's do a grip right i usually just
grade for the output here
almost everybody uses graph almost
everybody uses grip but uh but the
result the result of this is really
weird because now it feels like guava is
dependent on guava which is depending on
guava
that does not make any sense what
happened here right so
you're missing context and
what you see is that everybody first
prints this to a file and then
do a grab over there but there's a
better
solution and that's by adding the
parameter
includes
the path to that specific library you're
looking for
so i can give it up the group id and
also potentially the artifact id right
yes
you can do that so let's take a look at
it this way and this is a really really
good way for you to figure out if you
actually have an issue with one of these
artifacts
and wow look at that um all of these
guava
versions are being imported by another
translator dependency somewhere else
and they are all over the place um
now i guess one of the most commonly
asked questions is
why don't we just use both why can we
have both of them
right so how does the class path work um
i guess in the class path if you have
multiple classes uh
it will pick the you can only pick one
right exactly
so it will first one it finds and
maven has a similar strategy and
it works like looking for the nearest
dependency
so the deeper you go into the in the
tree
of dependencies uh the the
less likely it is that's the one being
picked up
so if you specify your dependency
directly in your bomb file that's the
one being used even though
a transitive might have a different
version
uh-huh so for example if i uh in this
case i guess
a older version might have been picked
up because it was closer
to my uh my dependency uh tree
and so the newer version got omitted in
this case um
and so we were potentially referring to
a method that's only in the newer
version but not in the older version
exactly but um so one of the issue with
this dependency problem is that it's
really really hard to find especially
you only discover it when you're running
the app right
you usually get it when you're running
the app and go through that line of code
because the linking
is dynamic and it will be what are some
of the techniques that we should be able
to catch some of these problems early
especially for this particular issue
well in this case you're you probably
want to use the enforce plugin
most of the time if there's something
you want to enforce
during build just have a look at the
enforcer plugin and it has a huge set
of enforcer rules and you can also write
them yourself actually
but this one is interesting because the
dependency convergence
is one that verifies that all the
versions of the dependencies are
exactly the same which is kind of tricky
but sometimes it's possible and the
other one we have written is the upper
bound and that ensures that you're using
the
latest of the specified dependencies but
that ensures
that it requires that all those
dependencies are backwards compatible of
course
right so let's uh let's give it a try uh
very quickly so here we have the
dependency
convergence plugin and if i were to add
it to this particular pom file
uh during the build in the build block
viewed
in plugins and like that right and now
if i go back and do um even
i'm gonna do maybe clean still is that
right may even clean still that's why
everybody does come on come on
why why clean why install what we should
do
i want to make everything work right no
no verified it's more than enough
it's never been verified okay so don't
do never end queens though
uh you know what's after the discussion
if you ask why and also you can ask
andre some era
uh we do not want you to use maven
cleaning still uh in most cases maybe
verify works right
yeah okay so let's verify and this will
run through the enforcer plug-in as well
and it tells me right off the bat
that i have all of these libraries that
is having
multiple versions in in the build and so
we need to go
ahead and resolve it uh or we can do the
upper bound here
uh with the upper bound rule in which
case it only tells me the libraries
that's using the older version as
opposed to the newest version
but let's say we have these issues how
do we potentially resolve these
right so there are in general there are
two
one is dependency management where you
say okay
i'm going to specify globally which
version should be used and the other one
is
exclusions which is kind of dangerous
because you
if you exclude some code you are
responsible that it's included somewhere
else right
nicely so by exclusion we
uh we would explicitly exclude the
offending um
artifacts so in this case for example
guava is the one that's offending
we can go ahead and use the exclusion to
exclude it explicitly so that
in our maven tree we don't see this
anymore um in like it
i would look something like this so i
can extrude guava from
truth and now i only have guava 21 in my
in my tree uh now dependency management
though how does that look like
it's uh management it's it looks almost
the same as
you specify dependencies but it just has
an extra
tag around it and in the in the end it's
just a lookup table
so it's looking for a dependency
based on the group and art factory and
okay if you have a specific version here
that's the one that's being used
i see yeah so for example if i want to
overwrite
all of the transitive defense dependency
version for guava
i can potentially use dependency
management here and so now when maven is
resolving come google guava with the
guava artifact
it will come here to see what version it
should be using right
right so um if that's the case let's go
ahead and
go to this example directory 3a
uh 3 3b sorry 3b
and if we run through the dependency
tree again
and c guava we should be able to see
that all of the guava versions are now
being managed up to in this case guava
28.1
right the original version may be this
one but now with dependency management
all of them are now aligned to the same
version right pretty cool
yeah so uh we can use dependency
management to overwrite your translative
or even direct dependency
versions if you don't specify it and
that's probably one of the best
practices
and you can say hey let's upgrade all
the version to 21 or let's upgrade older
version to 28
uh and they will just go ahead and make
that a reality
that's pretty neat um yeah it's
definitely one of the one first thing i
learned from robert
in solving all these issues
okay now another thing though is
that sometimes we run into issues where
maybe
we're using two different versions of
guava that's not exactly compatible
right a really old version like guava
eight and then really new
version they're just not going to be
compatible and sometimes you may
actually need to use
both versions um and this can be the
case where the newest version doesn't
work with the dependency you're using
but you need to use the new version
anyway
what do we do in those cases because
that's really really difficult
right so this is really the last thing
you should think of
uh but we have the maven shape plugin
and what it can do it can relocate
uh the cluster which means that it will
change the
package name in the end and also inside
your code and based on that it is
possible to have
multiple versions of guava next to each
other
i see it's really tricky because from
that moment on you cannot update
it anymore
so that you cannot update the guava
version through your dependency
uh transfer dependency anymore because
it's now
embedded encoded directly into your code
as pos
it's part of your code now right
excellent yeah
yeah but sometimes there's really no way
around this especially of using hadoop
i think a lot of people probably run
into these things when using hadoop they
do have
a really old version of guava in the
system class path uh and if you
use anything that uses the newer version
uh there are going to be dependency
conflicts because of the
things that robert talked about right
because in the class path only
one these one of these guava classes can
exist
and it will choose the system class path
one uh overwhelmingly and now you're
going to run into issue
in this case you have to shade guava
that's in your application so it does
not conflict with what's in your system
class path
okay cool so that was pretty cool so at
least we have enforcer plugins that can
help us catch some of these things early
which is super super cool you do not
want to wait until later
now let's see the next example uh 3e
um let me see here 3e suspiciously named
clash i wonder what that means
so here again we have a bunch of
dependencies where i'm using two
dependencies here
uh firebase uh you know a real-time
serverless
database that people can use which is
great and pops up which is messaging so
we got two dependencies here
i'm following the best practices here
i'm using dependency management to
override some of the versions that was
causing issues and i also have enforcer
rule here too so i'm
using the reinforce rule okay so let me
go ahead and go through exception 3d
oh which one is that one example 3e
clash and we're just going to do a
compile because this will also kick off
the enforcer
and everything is fine which is great
right so we follow the best practices
using foister and now we do live and
test
to run one of these tests and let's see
what happens
okay now again what happened
robert i follow all the best practices
what happened here
we're seeing exactly the same message as
before right
so yeah and again
com.google.com so it's got guava again
it's always that way if you run into one
of these issues you gotta find a package
and
you know it's it's qualified this case
what happened what i follow everything
we fixed previously why is it still
happening
well my guess is that there are multiple
versions of this class on your class
path
uh-huh so even though we require upper
bound we should only
have one single guava artifact uh
somehow another class is being
introduced
so again i guess we go to dependency
tree and we see
the verbose with the package for guava
and let's see here
that's pretty good but let's drop down a
level right so let's remove the specific
artifacts and let's go to
just the package the group id and see
what happened here
and by the way this this particular
thing was one of the hardest thing i
ever had to troubleshoot
because uh it's really
weird that this actually happens but it
does right
and um and i think one of the things
that we noticed was wait a second
we have an artifact that's called guava
right in this one
another one that's called guava.jdk5
now because it uses a different artifact
name there's no way for maven to know
that these two things are
actually the same thing they're just
different inversion and so
now we are potentially introducing two
artifacts to jar files
but they both potentially have the same
classes and
if we go back to the class loading in
the class path only one of these will be
picked up
so both of them will be in the classpad
but only one of them will work
and now we are potentially using the
older version again and
this one was not picked up by the
required upper bound um
the enforcer rule what do we do here
this one was really really difficult
yes this one is uh really difficult
because even though i said it within
five seconds and it was right
you're definitely right yeah
this is this requires quite a lot of
analysis but
um also we have now that we know that it
was caused by a duplicate
class there is a specific rule for that
as well
oh yeah yeah there you see oh there it
is
paint duplicate classes so what does
this do
well it goes through all your jar files
and it's just a
registering uh the classes being used
and
at the if it discovered some duplicates
it will
print them out and also mentioning which
classes are duplicated
and in which multiple jars they are
located
uh-huh interesting that's good so let's
give it a try so i'm actually going to
add this plug-in too i'm going to copy
and paste
as is right so i'm adding the spam
people get classes you can configure
a few other things um so let's uh try
ahead let's go ahead and try to compile
again and uh hopefully this will
uh at the compilation time we see this
issue right off the bat oh look at that
all these classes are being duplicated
in potentially multiple artifacts with
different artifact id
and by the way we do have a java library
best practices rules now it's called
jlbp
so if you go to jlbp.dev there's a rule
that says
you know no no no new node 2 artifacts
you have the same classes
you should not duplicate classes in two
different artifacts and uh
this is uh something that's new that we
added so we shouldn't see these issues
anymore
uh but now we can see the result of this
look at that
um yeah yeah so looking at the
dependency
tree was really hard but now in with
this enforcer rule we can see the two
offending artifacts right off the bat
and this is really really good uh yeah i
would highly recommend this for
every one of your projects as well in
case you want to avoid some of these
issues
okay cool so let's go back to the
examples
um let's uh let's look at example 3c
that's another
really really interesting one 3c
suspiciously called misalignment so i'm
going to go ahead and
um again do my uh
test here so i'm going to maven compile
with some of the first rule so we added
the required up and bound reinforcer
rule here
and we can see that the inverse rule
actually failed and we can tell you that
in this case
there are two versions of this thing
called grpc stop 1.0.1 and 1.10.1
and because we need upper bounds so we
should be using 1.10.1
right and so i go back to dependency
management here i'm using dependency
management to override the version to
the newest version
so now i'm using all the things that we
learned in the past
15 minutes and let's do a compile again
right robert i'm again following all the
best practices that
you have said so far so everything
compiled
and let's do another test yeah
oh boy oh oh no okay not another one
yes it's not guava anymore thank
goodness right but
uh but what is this now this is that no
class that found
so it's not no method found but not
there's no class
definition found um
this one's difficult too it's um also
difficult
and you need to know a little bit about
uh this project because
this is a set of libraries that are
always released uh
at the same time right so what you would
expect is that all their versions are
exactly the same
most people recognize this also from
spring
spring framework spring boot that these
are a set of libraries and
in general they should always have
exactly the same version
right because they're tightly coupled um
i think another example will be
neti right there are many different neti
modules but they all have to be the same
version
otherwise you get into issues sl4j
right some of these projects they have
multiple modules and you should always
use the same version of the
the for all of the modules so in this
case uh
it was again very difficult but we had
to go into the dependency tree
to read this line by line and say okay
here's the jrpc net version that's a 1.0
0.1 but then the stop version is 1.10.1
because it was introduced because we
upgraded to the newest version
but it obviously wasn't compatible with
this other version so we have to upgrade
all of these other versions too
right they have to be aligned and this
issue is what we call
dependency misalignment so in this graph
you can see that for grpc we have
1.0.1 but then for one of the modules is
1.10
and they're misaligned in version so we
haven't aligned it
now what do we do in this case right i
can obviously go back to dependency
management but now i have to add these
things
myself as a user uh over and over again
that's really annoying
yes and you don't know if you're
complete
if you hate all the dependencies um
right right now most uh libraries uh
also provide a bomb file a bomb file
file is a list of dependencies that are
all part of
this set of libraries that should have
exactly the same version
uh and you can add that to your own pom
file it's in the end
just one manage dependency and you add
your project and that ensures that all
the versions are in line with each other
okay so in this case let's take a look
at the grpc bomb
so what's in the bomb file
okay um yes
so the bomb file is really just a set of
dependency management
uh blocks where the bomb file
so rather than adding the dependency
management in my own pump
uh i can have this dependency management
in a bomb
and then i can then reuse these versions
right
yes uh-huh so which was the
to do a copy paste of this and put it
inside your own palm
but that's kind of ugly of course so
that's why
bomb file uh concept and okay
huh yep so let's take a quick look on
how to do that
so in this case uh what we can do is to
import the bom that somebody else
already created right in this case the
grpc
libraries have a single bomb that can
then override older versions
and align them together so like here is
the bom file this is the palm with the
dependency management inside
and then to consume it we can use in our
dependency management
rather than copy and paste all of those
things we come to this block
and the important part here is the scope
is import
and the type is the palm and now
everything that's in this file becomes
part of yours as well
is that the first way to say that yes
yeah that's pretty much how it works yes
nice
very cool so with the alignment then uh
this thing then should work and compile
as well so that's uh that should be
pretty awesome
uh and by importing this bomb we can
then overwrite all of these uh grpc
libraries
um but you know everyone should probably
create a bomb like what are some of the
practices here for creating the bomb
right it all depends on if you are a
library creator or framework creator if
you're working on
applications it doesn't really make
sense i think but
those librarian framework creators
should also provide a bomb file if it's
not there please ask them to
also create one for you because
as you can see it can give you a lot of
headaches if you are not doing it right
right so um and for library creators if
especially if you're doing a
multi-module project
that's tightly coupled in this case jrpc
neti
and many many other things all of these
things if you're creating something
similar
you should also create a bom so that
your user can
import the bom to configure the library
versions right
right now what should also go into the
bom
um it should um like for example if i'm
using
uh if i create a library that has that
uses guava as the transfer dependencies
should i be adding guava into my bum too
so my user can use the same version of
global that i want to use
now you should only add those parts that
are part of the
multi-module project so those that are
in sync with
have to be in sync with each other i see
so like in grpc again if i go back to
this uh this example for grpc
they only include the sub modules for
grpc
but not their translated dependencies
right right
um yeah very cool very cool
wow that's amazing uh we are about
15 what 20 minutes in 20 25 minutes in
and uh we done a lot already
um now the final thing here is that one
of the things i do want to mention is um
if all things fails another thing that's
really really cool is linkage checker
so this thing is created by the team
here at google uh to help solve some of
these problems
and what this is surprisingly yet
another enforcer rule like what
robert said you can enforce and check
these things with the reinforcer rule
so this enforcer rule will do static
analysis
on your code to make sure that all the
calls all the methods are reachable
okay in the current resolutions so that
you can detect these things early during
the compilation time
as opposed to runtime you don't want to
figure these things out during runtime
because that's already too late uh if
all of these other best practices
still doesn't find you the issue you
should add this static
analysis tool so you can find the issue
early so you can definitely check this
out
okay so with that being said uh thank
you so much for being here
i just want to add that a lot of the
things that you sell if
especially if you are creating your own
library all these rules
and best practices are documented in
jlbp.dev
so please please go check it out it's
got all the best practices in here
all 20 of them that you should follow
especially you are creating a new
library
so please please go there and check it
out um but
also very importantly for robert and
maven uh i think you have something uh
to add that's even more important
well do you think i think brian has
something to say right
oh i have something to say that first of
all we have to go in q a we've got three
minutes left but i know what you're
going to say that is that
everybody is using or a lot of people
are using maven
and unfortunately we only have a handful
of contributors so
if you are using maven and you want to
and you depend on maven
just like the dependencies you bring in
you wanted to want them to be healthy
make sure that you also contribute to
maven because
we need your help if uh if we want to
solve all the issues and just with for
instance
10 people that work on that
and millions of people are using maven
that might misalign but let me quickly
go to a few questions because we have
two minutes left and then the next
speaker is all we're already
up in my uh my backlog first of all
always do we have always the question
why shouldn't i be using maven clean
install and i've got the question over
here as well but the
good one is the the good question is
okay is there some
cheat sheet or something which maven
command i have to use when
and so this person like i want to learn
and i i think a lot of people are like
that
so uh how do you robert do you got any
resources on that
yes we have of course our website but it
is an overload of information and it's
probably quite hard to find
especially this kind of questions
i think uh if you understand the whole
life cycle stuff
and what clean does and what install
does then you probably
should understand why you don't need to
clean and why you don't need the install
so the short answer is clean will remove
everything
you've already done so it will remove
the target directory
and it will recompile remove of re
uh add all those resources you already
touched probably
so in general it's just consuming
resource consuming you don't need that
and the install
only what install does is copying
those jar files to your local repository
why
you don't need it there yeah so
basically
so basic so basically what you say is
make sure that you know every step
within maven
and what every step does yes all right
um always got this kind of question as
well
are there similar things in gradle but i
think you are the wrong person to ask
but i do want you to announce it i mean
robert is the chairman of maven
and probably not using grade also uh
i'm sorry to say that this this question
is probably not going to be answered in
this stream
um guys i'm i'm moving forward i want to
thank you for this
uh this talk we are on a tight schedule
so um it was a pleasure to have not one
java champion but two java champions in
my stream
amazing to have you here and i will
bring
i will