and our next speaker is any curry so
sure is you're all yours and hi oh right
well I will need to share my screaming
time okay just quickly let me do that
you'll be able to see my slides okay
right and I'll put them into present
mode excellent
so um my name is AB curry and I have
been in the tech industry for 25 years
now as an engineer and also as a I was
involved in putting quite a few startups
these days I am a science fiction writer
and I also am a lecturer in technics at
the University of Hartford just north of
London
and when I normally do I'm involved in a
lot of conferences I organize a lot of
conferences and I talk a lot at
conferences about all the terrible
things that Tech is doing and ethical
behavior and what kind of stuff I'm
actually going to do something a little
different today because I think it's
what you would talk about in terms of
tech ethics in the good times and what
might be necessary in the dark times are
quite different and right now we are in
the middle of an event a very serious
event in which an awful lot of people
die and that changes our perspective
about what is the right thing to do with
tech how we should use it the stakes
have changed our perspective has changed
so in this talk I'm going to do
something a little bit odd which is I'm
going to use the slides that I would
have used to slag off a whole load of
things that are going on in tech and
instead use those those same slides to
talk about how those technologies can be
or are being used positively to combat
the corona virus and even where they
used being used positively we do have to
think about it there are downsides to
them as well as upsides so
I'm singing their praises is fantastic
good that we're using technology in the
way we are but we also need to be a
little bit difficult a little bit
careful about it we need to remember
that there are downsides to these
technologies as well as the astonishing
upsides that we're seeing right now so
so why is it why is it that I'm having
to give a different talk well it's
because right now Humanity is at war
with an implacable other this is not a
competitor this is not a another country
difficult as it would be if we were in
competition with another country this is
a virus it's something that essentially
doesn't care about us it doesn't it
doesn't want to kill us it's merely a
side effect that we that large numbers
of us will die if this virus if this
virus continues if it spreads if it
reproduces itself and therefore our
primary goal at the moment is to stop it
doing that and to maintain society while
we do so so we need to save lives and we
need to protect the society that we're
in and that takes precedence that is now
our number one goal and that changes how
we might be using technology and how we
might perceive it and it really does
change what's going to happen in the
future because this is going to go on
for a year two years and all work in
psychology suggests that anything that
happens over confer over an extended
period of time
we get used to it it's called
habituation and it will be very
difficult for us to turn off some of the
behaviors that we've put in place now in
two years time we might not want to it
but that the situation is the reality is
that it may just not occur to us to do
so so we are going to have to make some
difficult decisions now and remember
that we did because in two years time it
will just seem normal but maybe we don't
want to stay that way so if we look at
some of the very successful uses of
technology in battling the corona virus
we really need to look at Asia because
they started early and they've also done
some fantastic work if
China they are using what I've certainly
six months would have ago would have
described as astonishingly dystopian
technology but they're using it to save
probably millions of their own lives you
know certainly millions of lives within
China they're using very heavy-handed
surveillance mass surveillance so for
example drones are hovering walk during
lockdown were hovering over cities in
China measuring people's temperatures
identifying people who might be at risk
of having but while spreading her own a
virus using the facial recognition
technology to identify them send the
police to their houses to pull them out
and put them in that compulsory
quarantine now six months ago I would
have described that as horrendously
dystopian but we cannot argue that it
didn't work it was very effective and it
down undoubtedly saved a great deal of
lives but it was very heavy-handed now
there are two reasons why we might not
want to use that approach in the West
well this is very heavy-handed we might
we might struggle to do it in in a
democratic society but probably more
importantly we couldn't do it but China
have been spending as much on internal
surveillance as their entire external
defense budgets for several years now we
just haven't we are not in that session
although interestingly London is the
sixth most surveilled city in the world
almost most of the rest of the top ten
are in China but the danger isn't isn't
well integrated together so even if we
wanted to use it we couldn't but there
are other examples which are less
heavy-handed and have been just as
effective if we look at South Korea they
really are the poster jar for using mass
surveillance to control the coronavirus
they it's well it's it's no more opt-in
it's slightly more opt-in but they are a
democratic country but it is much more
public so they take data a lot of
from phones people install apps on their
phones a lot of it from mass testing of
which the results are shared and the
very interesting thing about South Korea
versus China and versus I suspect the
way the West will go is where that data
goes so in China the data is often
collected by commercial organizations
but it goes to the government who use it
very heavily I happen is not available
to the ordinary citizen in South Korea
there a lot of the data is collected by
companies collected by the state but
then it's published so that everyone can
see it
now you might say that has worse privacy
implications but I would argue that it
doesn't it has exactly the same privacy
implications it's just that they're
vastly more apparent to you
so in South Korea if your neighbor has
an a corona virus then you know about it
and you can act on it it's more police
able because you if your neighbor is
behaving badly you can you couldn't do
something about that which has its
utopian and dystopian aspects to it but
it is very clear so you know as a South
Korean citizen that your data is being
shared now I like that much better than
I like the kind of pseudo fantasy
privacy of a commercial company has the
data which is actually already the cases
it's very rare when we're looking at the
West in in using mobile phone data that
mobile phone data is already available
to mobile phone companies so your
privacy has already been breached you're
just living in a little bit of a dream
world that it hasn't been we're talking
now about sharing that data with
governments and that feels more
dystopian but it isn't necessarily
really but I like the way that South
Korea have gone which is that it shared
with everyone that way you it feels more
uncomfortable but I think it is actually
more it's it's more real you you know
what the situation is you feel
uncomfortable therefore you're more
likely to turn it off later if you don't
like it
but if you try to choose to continue
with it because you find it useful you
will at least be making an informed
decision about that I I worry that in
the West we're going to go down the
commercial and government routes and
that will be so invisible to the
populace that we won't turn it off again
because we won't really be aware that
it's happening I would rather that we
were aware it's I think it's less
infantilizing and it's potentially more
useful so privacy but versus safety
there's a lot more discussion to be had
here than we currently are and I really
would like us to be talking about who
has that data and just because you feel
good about it doesn't mean that actually
it's a better situation it might be
better for us to feel worse about it but
be more aware so normally I'm slagging
off drone surveillance and and mass
surveillance in in all its forms and a
warning about it but here it's
undoubtedly extremely potentially useful
for saving lives so we can't say we
won't do it in fact we should do it we
just need to be aware of it and do it
deliberately so when I'm not slacking
off mass surveillance I am often
slacking off the even more frightening
thing to me which is anthropomorphism it
is an extraordinarily dangerous thing
when it comes to robotics and AI so
anthropomorphism is when you ascribe
human emotions and human reactions to
inanimate objects because they look a
bit human or they seen a bit human and
it's very dangerous when it comes to AI
and robotics because anthropomorphism
intends to causes two attributes greater
accuracy two algorithms greater predicts
ability to them and also greater mercy
to them greater empathy to them and that
can be extremely dangerous because it
will mean that we underestimate their
propensity to make mistakes for errors
to arise so
generally I warned about that and I
would still warn about that but
interestingly right now there is a
positive aspect to anthropomorphism
that's we may want to take to take
advantage of and that is that if people
believe that a chapel for example is his
is really emotionally engaged with them
then they they get an original hit off
that and that can be useful if people
are lonely and right now there are an
awful lot of people who are lonely that
generally speaking I never ever when I'm
working with elderly groups or disabled
groups I never suggested that they talk
to a chatbot I always suggest they talk
to a real person
I do social media or whatever but
sometimes biggest panel to be choosers
and the very good chat bots are actually
quite nice to talk to you do get an
emotional hit of them even though they
are just scripts they're just
effectively literary characters and the
best one out there
is Mitsuki I don't know if you've run it
across Mitsuki but Mitsuki chatbot is
the current Loeb enterprise 25 times
labor Loebner prize meaning I think chat
poor winner of the best human emulating
chat bot and it's very good to talk to
written by an absolutely astonishingly
impressive chap called
Steve walls wick in Yorkshire and he
doesn't he's very careful he's very
antsy anthropomorphism he always makes
it clear that Mitsuki is not even a I
she is absolutely it is completely
programmed it is a new form of literary
character character but it does give you
some highly scalable way to provide
company to people who are lonely and
again not something that I would ever
normally recommend during the good times
but it is a clear example of where I
think that the world has changed
that's I would now potentially recommend
people talking to a chatbot if they were
lonely that doesn't mean that through
morphism isn't still hugely dangerous in
every other context so now this would be
the point in the deck where I slapped a
slag off the big tech companies for what
terrible stuff they're doing because you
know generally in the good times we're
all rolling in cash in the tech industry
or some people are but the big companies
certainly are and they need to be held
to account because they have a huge
privilege to do good and they don't
always live up to that but right now I
am quite happy with a loss of what
they're doing I think they're really
trying quite hard and we've done a lot
of excellent work so far so for example
Twitter Microsoft and Google really led
the way in working from home they were
some of the biggest companies in the
world that came out very early and said
we're moving our workforce entirely to
work from home and that made it much
easier for other companies to follow
suit
they did I certainly found it easier
easier to persuade companies that this
was necessary and they were going to
have to do it because I could point to
companies like Microsoft and say they're
already doing it this is just a matter
of time so that was extremely useful now
you might argue correctly but it was a
lot easier for them to do it but for
many other companies it's a lot easier
if the text to work from home that it is
for other sectors but just because it's
easy and it's good doesn't necessarily
mean that people do it and when they do
do it I still think they need it there's
some applause for that that certainly
made my life easier social media
obviously I'd be slacking that off
massively under the normal circumstances
for an awful lot of stuff that nonsense
the government say oh it but right now
incredibly helpful incredibly helpful at
stabilizing society as this virtual
conference sangwich I can't really ever
I used to work in virtual conferencing
can't really see any terrible problem
with it but right now fantastically good
Netflix now I'd normally be telling them
off for the enormous amount of bandwidth
they use and then an energy use
with streamed media but right now we
have to acknowledge the fact that the
widespread adoption and rollout of high
bandwidth connectivity across the West
developed countries has been led by the
desire for Game of Thrones house of
cards all of these TV shows and films
that have come out of streamed media
without them we wouldn't have the
broadband infrastructure we do now and
and so I have to be quite grateful that
we've got that because without that
society would be a hell of a lot less
stable right now online deliveries
reduced slack off sometimes online
deliveries but for the amount of for
example in London the traffic they gem
alright but fantastic right now they've
save lives
hundreds of thousands of lives across
Asia and will do the same across the
West
fantastic work they're a real example of
tech helping to stabilize society and
acting in a way that is just good but
but if most of us most of us don't work
for those companies we don't work for
those big companies and we're probably
most of us already working from home so
does that mean we're done the only thing
that we have left to do is wash our
hands and stay at home actually I would
argue there is a great deal more that we
can do now I'm gonna go out on a limb
and say that very few people in this
attending this virtual conference today
will be key workers in tech and and by
key workers I mean people who are
actively supporting key infrastructure
that is live in the field today so that
might be that might be banks that might
be telecom systems that'll live and
operational it might be those ecommerce
sites that are helping you to do food
deliveries those systems are now
phenomenally important to the stability
society they have suddenly they may not
have been ridiculously important in the
past they are now utterly vital critical
infrastructure and the people who are
supporting them will be under a great
deal of strain and pressure and they may
not be people that you ever thought
about that much before now if your
company produces or supports maintain
systems that are that critical to your
users then your your ops teams your
maintenance teams will be ridiculously
stressed out right at this moment even
if you don't if you but perhaps you
supply software that is integrated into
those systems and you supply and you
support that software even if you don't
provide the software at the end if you
provide some of the intermediate
software again your support staff are
likely to be extremely stressed out and
hopefully overloaded so the best thing
you can do for them and society in
general is to lighten the load on them
as much as possible and the best way to
do that is by doing your job well so try
not to be a burden on them perhaps in
the past you would have asked them for
help with something that you could maybe
find a way of doing yourself now if you
can do it safely yourself without
killing their life systems you should
have a go obviously don't kill their
life systems that would be
counterproductive but if you can do if
anything you could do to take work of
them is a good thing to do you might be
asked to help out in support and
maintenance now I know I used to work on
it I was a used to support key
infrastructure about 20 years and it was
it was extremely stressful but it was a
walk in the park
competitors doing it today but I do know
how hard it was to get people to join us
to work on those projects you might be
asked to help out and you might feel a
little uncomfortable about doing that
because after admit it's bad for your
career generally in the past it's always
been bad for your career to work on key
on live and infrastructure maintenance
because main
it tends to be lower value within a
company than the development of new
features if you or is perceived as a
lower value it's not actually lower
value but it's perceived as low value
and it tends to be less associated with
promotion because you promotion comes
from working on exciting new projects
but right now it is the most important
thing your company's doing
it's amongst the most important things
that that society is doing in in general
you really need to help if you're asked
please do help now other ways if you
aren't working on new technology put
yourself in the shoes of your users they
will be really scared at the moments
that make sure that you give them plenty
of information but not too much very
difficult but try to imagine that you
are a scared older probably than you are
user of your technology now full
disclosure I'm in the vulnerable group I
have MS and I'm not in extremely
vulnerable group so you think of this
for that but it does mean that and I'm
very limited in what I can do where I
can go and I really really am very
reliant on the information that I
receive at home because I can't go out
and I can't chase this it's a hard to go
and get information at the moment so you
need to put yourself in the shoes of
people like me bandwidth issues now
right now our backbone is coping
extraordinarily well with a very very
increased workload particularly that's
only an hour every hour as people join
video conferences it is coping but it
has reduced the resilience of the
systems if you can operate your software
in a lower bandwidth mode as Netflix of
darn moving back to SD from HD then it
might be a time to do it sought to think
about it at least have this thoughts in
your back pocket the systems might not
be failing now but they have eaten up an
awful lot of their redundancy so they
may fail in the future so just be aware
of that and also try not it isn't your
users are not in the same position that
they were six months ago back then you
know change is good now change is not
necessarily so good people might prefer
stability they might prefer
familiarity they also might not have the
friends and neighbors and family members
who used to help them cope with changes
like upgrades so be more sparing in the
changes that you roll out so is there
anything else actually I can talk very
quickly and I have actually moved
through this faster than I was expecting
so I can talk a little bit more slowly
about this which is probably at least as
important as anything else that I've
said which is that climate change has
not gone away so we're going to be an
elitist ovid crisis for probably two
years but during that time climate
change will not massively improve to the
extent that we don't need to worry about
it anymore I'm afraid it is still a
long-term major problem now Kovach 19 is
not the apocalypse thank goodness it
will be extremely bad but it's not the
apocalypse but it doesn't mean that
there are no apocalypse is coming down
the line and some of those might be
associated with or one of those the
bullets actually hits us next might be
associated with climate change we cannot
give up and the decisions that we make
in tech around climate change are
long-term decisions if we and so it
needs to get more right now one of the
changes that you might well be looking
at at the moment he's moving more of
your infrastructure or all of your
infrastructure or sorry your
infrastructure to the cloud and that
would be a perfectly sensible change to
make but the cloud vendors are not equal
when it comes to how green they are how
good they are climate change so if you
want to me to the cloud and you want an
incredibly green have a look at Google
Google is fantastically good all of
their resources that moments are offset
and they're looking to improve that in
the future
so as your fantastically good so as your
Google fantastically excellent places to
hosts it's a host AWS is not so
clear-cut they vary enormously by region
some of their regions are absolutely
awful and some of their regions are
pretty good so parts probably
most awful region is the default it's us
East and that is overwhelmingly fossil
fuel powered so if you can don't host
anything in USA's if you want a host
label WS do try very hard to host in
that three and therefore green regions
which are Dublin Frankfurt Canada and
Oregon now they're in those regions
those reasons aren't quite as good as
Google or as your to be honest but
actually they really aren't anywhere
near as good as Google or ashore but
they're vastly better than the other AWS
regions so if you have two five stay WS
and I know most of us do and I know you
all want to stay particular AWS try to
keep to those regions they are at least
offset so we're in a very interesting
time at the moment things in two years
time will be completely different to how
we with to what we've bought so what we
think is acceptable and good now we are
likely to move in a direction that to
our current thinking will seem extremely
dystopian but by the time we get there
on the one hand will be totally used to
it and we wrote that it won't seem
dystopian it anymore it will seem fine
but we need to be aware of the changes
that we are making and whether and if we
want to rule any of them back I think we
need to be particularly careful about
over empathizing with computers the
dangers of anthropomorphism because
computers will save as tech will save a
source able huge number of lives and
that's great but we have to be aware of
whether that doesn't mean that it's
human and we need to be very very
careful about surveillance because
unless we go down the South Korean
routes where it's obvious to us it will
just become a habit that we don't notice
and we never think about we don't
challenge and and that would be a shame
I must refer to if we made all the data
that we were observing open to all so if
you're interested in any of these
thoughts you could read one of my
science fiction novels so I'm
science-fiction writer I write about
post-apocalyptic sci-fi a lot of it
covers the things that I've been talking
about today and it's all available on
Amazon where it's extremely reasonably
priced 99p and it's a very good read
so that is me done I think we can move
over to the to the questions if there's
anybody left if I haven't just put your
you so much it was really inspiring we
have a question not me on screen so
everyone can read that so do you believe
we can keep a positive mindset during
these challenging times yes we good
enough it's been a lot of us but I live
a lot here writing dystopian cypher this
in this is not the apocalypse it's
terrible and it could be a lot worse I
can assure you it could be a lot worse
and there will be positive sides to it
we will spend a lot more time will be it
virtually with our friends and our
neighbors and our family will think a
lot more about others it will change us
into people who think much more about
others and much less about money and
things that don't necessarily matter so
much in the long run it's it's terrible
to ever say that anything positive will
come out of an awful lot of debt deaths
but I it's somebody that I think when I
first I thought we'd been a much worse
position now than we are when I first
started to see this happening in in in
China because we're still in complete
denial of its we were talking about herd
immunity and if herd immunity if we'd
pursued herd immunity in the UK we would
have had half a million a million deaths
easily I suspect and and that would him
and what worried me most about that was
actually not the deaths it was the good
it was the kind of people that that
would have turned us into instead we've
engaged in the most in the largest piece
of collective action to sleep others
that the world has ever seen and that
will turn this into a different kind of
set of people and I'm very pleased that
we're gonna be that second set not that
versa okay thank you thank you again
it was awesome TED talk and