hello everybody
i'm melissa miller and i am an
application security advocate here at
sneak
and we are all set for our next speaker
we're going to jump over now from
javascript and we're going to
hop into the security track
and so our first speaker comes to us
from auth0
her name is anna sidre and she's here
today she's going to tell us all about
web components and how we can leverage
them for authentication in our
applications
so with that i'm going to turn it over
to you anna
welcome to my talk about web components
for authentication
the what the why and the how just before
i dive into my talk
let me introduce myself a little bit so
i'm anna sidri and i'm a developer
advocate for all sierra
or xero is a flexible drop-in solution
to add authentication
and authorization services to your
applications
so if you have any questions about all
xero about implementation
about this talk or just want to say hi
feel free to reach out
on twitter my twitter handle is at
anesthesia
outside of work i'm pretty um active
with community
so i organized several events
and meetups one of those is ng spain
it's an angular conference
in spain but because of the current
situation this year we don't have a
conference
but hopefully next year we'll be able to
run with them again
and i'm very passionate about women in
tech therefore i help a lot
in this sector and i organize events
locally with my
gauss tech group and also on a more
international scale with the google
admission initiative women techmakers
so that's enough about me let's get
started and like i said
um this talk is about web components for
authentication
so i think a good starting point is to
ask ourselves
what is a web component so a web
component
is a component that is completely
platform agnostic
this allows us to have maximum
interoperability because
we have to share it across themes and we
can use it as many times as we need to
another cool thing about world
components is that they allow us to
be encapsulated right so this
prevents any styling or behavioral
leakages in or out
when we think about web components we
tend to think about dumb components
but that is totally not true and we're
going to see later on in this talk but
we can also create smart components with
them
so what do these web components actually
consist of
well they consist of three main
technologies html template
custom elements and shadow dom html
template is just the html tag called
template
in which we place the template of our
web component
and then with custom elements what we do
is actually create the html
tag or we can extend or improve an
already existing one
but we do have to be careful when we're
creating html tag with the naming
like best practices in all languages we
should
probably keep the naming understandable
so we know what we're
dealing with and also when we're writing
our code we would want to know
um for our future cells and for other
people what this component actually does
right
also when you're naming you have to
remember to add a dash so it has to be
web dash component for example
and last but not least shadow dom so
shadow dom is what's going to allow us
to have that encapsulation that i was
talking about
earlier okay so to get a better
understanding of what our component
is we will start by building a dumb
component
and what we're going to build is a
simple login button which we can style
from the outside
so let's dive right in first of all what
we're doing is we're creating our
template tag here
and we have a simple button with an id
login button which will relate to staff
then we are creating our custom element
and we are extending html element
because it
allows us to inherit all of the features
of this html element obviously
and also it will be recognized as a dom
element then we're calling our
constructor and in there we have super
so we have access to all of the apis
next what we need to do is add our
shared domain here
and this is a very simple process all we
need to do is add two lines of codes
so we're attaching the shadow and we're
calling
mode open we call mode open
because we want to um give the
possibility
to the users to manipulate the structure
of the component via javascript
now if you didn't want to do this you
could put closed here
where where my cursor is and um
[Music]
this in general i wouldn't recommend
closing it because
even though you have intentions for your
web component to be a certain way
developers might want to use them in
different ways and have different
structures
so in general i would advise to keep it
open
and then what we're doing is we're just
cleaning our template and instead of
adding it to the dom we're adding it to
the shadow dom
cool and last but not least we need to
define our custom element
i remember how i said that we should
give it a name that's legible
well in this case we're going to call it
login button
and then we just call the property login
by saying element
so we're basically done but right at the
beginning when we created the template
i didn't show you how we could style it
now
i wanted this pause here on the styling
a bit because
it's a very very important aspect when
we create a web component people will be
using it and implementing it into their
own applications
so we need to think about use cases as
how they're going to be styling these
they should have the possibility to
style them accordingly
to their application whether it's
because of corporate identity design
or whether it's just personal
preferences i think styling is something
that
really needs to be thought about so
there's two ways to go about styling the
first
is called css custom properties and this
is the preferred way just because the
browsers
are almost fully stable
so what we do here is we to allow
css custom properties we call css
variables on rcss properties
so you can see within our login button
we have a background color
and then on the background color
property we're calling bar
and then within the parenthesis we give
it a variable name
and a default color and then
the user from the outside what they can
do is then style the web component
through the style attribute the html
style attribute
and they are calling the variable name
and then the color of their choice
that way they can change the background
color to
fit their application and this can go
for as many variables as you want to
but as you can imagine this can tend to
be a bit buggy
because you can always have a typo um
also it's a bit tedious because you have
to add so many different variables there
and start attributes
so there is another way to go about this
and it's called css shadow paths with
the part
pseudo class um i'm going to briefly go
over it but if you do want to have a
better understanding of this
i really recommend that you check out
the article
that you see there below that source um
because this is an article by monica
from the polymer team and she explains
it really and does them really well
one problem with css shadow parts
is that the browsers aren't stable i
know supplier is working on it so that
will hopefully turn green soon
but you can see that um css custom
properties are a lot more stable
so the cool thing about the um
css parts pseudo class is that we can
allow
developers to just we can decide what
parts of our web component developers
can
style now i know in a button there
aren't very many
different parts but say for example in a
form
or in a card you might have separate
sections and you might want
the users to just start for example
a div or an input however you don't want
them to start a different dip for
whatever reason
now you can give them access through the
part attribute and then give it a name
and then the user when they decide that
they want to style their component
all they have to do is in their css add
the web component name
uses the part cedar class and then give
it a name
and then they can just change whatever
properties they want to so
it's a lot nicer a lot neater it's a lot
more readable
and it's also a lot easier so
how would we implement it into our
button well we can
and all we need to do is cause a part
here
and then the user would
call the web component which is the
login button the password class
and then the name of the part which is
custom button
right and that's how we allow how that's
how we create
a login button and we create
that star attribute from which people
can
style however they want to
so now that we have a basic
understanding of what web components
are let's move on to authentication
so what is authentication authentication
is the process of confirming identity
it's when a user or an application or an
application
proves that they say who they say they
are by
providing valid credentials which tend
to be a username
or a password however there are many
factors we can use
to validate these credentials and if you
have
more than one um process
one factor authentication say you have
two-factor authentication
what multi-factor authentication this is
going to make your application
more secure and these factors
tend to rely on they fall into like
three categories which are what you know
what you have or what you are
now um authentication and authorization
tend to be used interchangeably however
they are very different
so whereas authentication is the process
of
validating a user well
authorization is the process of
verifying what a user has access to
so in authentication in authorization
sorry
a user or an application is granted
access to an api
and after the api determines what extent
like what permissions it should assign
to that user
so this is the part that comes after
authentication
and um yes it's true that access to a
resource is protected by both
authentication
and authorization however for
this talk we are just going to focus on
authentication
so now we've got a basic understanding
of what a web component is what
authentication is
how can a web component-based ecosystem
help when approaching
well i'm authentication to talk to you
about several things that i think
that where i think her web components
can help
and we will start with maximum
interoperability which is something that
i talked about
at the very beginning of the talk now
let's put a use case say like
for example there is a big company and
there are several products within the
company
and each product has their own team and
each team uses a different framework
maybe one team uses the angular another
team that uses view
and last but not least we have a team
that uses polymer
now they all need this login process
and it has to have the same feel even
though the design
isn't necessarily the same because
different products can have different
designs
the user experience should more or less
be the same because it is the same
company
so how could we go about this well
instead of having each team to build the
same login process
like three times in this case we could
create one web component
and then share it across teams or
however many
web components we may need for this
login process but then share it across
teams and we're not starting from
scratch
every single time so this will save a
lot of time
and a lot of headaches now if you want
to know
if your framework the framework you're
working with
allows you to use web components well um
i would go check out this
website custom elements everywhere by
rob dodson who's on the part of the team
he created this to show you how web
component friendly
frameworks are next web components are
very very easy to implement
now normally when we have to do some
sort of implementation it comes with a
very long and
tedious way of doing so we have to copy
code we have to paste so we have to
change we have to do this we have to do
that
and sometimes things don't go as planned
and
we have to look for another way of doing
it and it can cause a lot of time and
headaches
like i said before so
with web components all we need to do is
use the code that's on the right
the login button for example
and then we do an mp install we have to
also add the attribute attributes
obviously
and then you save it and that's it
you're good to go
so it's a pretty pretty simple process
another cool thing is that we can have
as much flexibility
as we want whether it's through the head
through the html attributes
oh sorry a little bit faster um here we
have the domain and the client id
attributes however you can add or remove
whichever ones you want
and gives the user as much flexibility
as you want to
so that's pretty cool and talking about
flexibility we've already talked about
styling
i'm just going to mention the two
stylings that we have but again
the user can design and change the web
component however they
want to because there's css custom
properties and here's the shadow part
and last but not least we have slots
so slots act like a placeholder in which
the user can then decide whether they
want to actually add a piece of html
within their web component or not let's
see what i'm talking about here
so as you can see we have two buttons
a login one a log out and then we have a
slot
which might be for example to allow the
user to add a description if they want
to
or a name or a role or whatever they may
want to hear
when you're dealing with slots it's
important and always good practice to
add a name because if you have more than
one slot then the dom needs to know
watch
which slot you're talking about and what
where to add it basically
so remember to always name your slots
even if you just have the one
and then the user would then through the
auth element
after adding the attributes whatever
it can just add a div for example and
then add the slot
and um the name of the slot and then
whatever
they need to there so that's a pretty
cool feature
next web components we could create to
make authentication simple
now here are a few ideas that i have
to make this authentication process a
bit more simple
through just using web components one of
them
could be a login screen and we have
social buttons here
it's just an idea it could be
maybe the name of the logged in user
and then maybe when the name is clicked
or the images clicks
it takes the user to the profile or
maybe we want to add the user's roles
here
or it really depends on what you're
looking for
and then this is what we're going to be
building in just a second
it's a web component that is a login
button which we've already seen
however it's going to deal with the
whole authentication process
and to do so we're going to use all zera
now remember how i said at the beginning
we were building a
dumb component where we built this some
component had no logic to it
so let's make that dumb component smart
now to make the the dumb component smart
i have used an all serial sdk to help me
so let's see what i did first of all
i imp i installed the all zero sdk
spar.js because for this example we will
be using vanilla.js
later on i'll show you other options we
can use to build web components but just
for
simplicity of the talk i have built
within airjs um
then we're going to import it like you
see here
and then when we created our
login button element previously we're
going to add the domain and client id
properties which are going to be the
attributes that we are going to allow
the user to add
so here we keep them empty because this
is what we want to allow the users to
add
the information we want to add and then
we have some getters and setters
so um we have these on both the
domain and the client id and as you can
see
i have a build or xero client method
there at the bottom
and this is so that um because we need
to rebuild the all zero client whenever
the values
of the domain or the client id
properties change
so we need to invoke this method and we
need to do it last
we then have the get observed attributes
so the get observed attributes is a
static property that returns an array as
you can see
and it has the names of the components
attributes which in this case the domain
and client id
the property is asking the browser to be
notified when the value of
any of these attributes change
and then you can catch capture these
notifications from the browser by
implementing
the attribute change callback now the
attribute change callback
is a custom element reaction and
you can implement it to handle some
events in the lifecycle of the
component and what what we're doing here
is what i just said previously we're
just
capturing the notifications from the
browser
next we have a connected callback so
this connected callback is also a custom
element reaction
and it's called when the component is
added to the pages dom
now here what we're doing is we're
creating an instance of the osiri client
we're adding in a listener for the click
event which we'll go into
this in just a second we're then
managing the result of the
authentication and updating the ud
ui based on the current authentication
status
so let's take a look at our event
listener and here
we have that it's just getting the um
current authentication status of the
user
calls the login or logout method and
then
let's look at to see what these login
and logout methods actually have
so these have a login with direct
and a logout method of the your serial
client
that's pretty straightforward here and
then
we have that handle redirect callback
and the update ui
so let's take a look at the update ui
it's just
displaying the correct text on the login
button
based on the current authentication
status and
handle redirect callback is managing the
response coming from the all serial
server after authentication right
so we're basically done um
as you can see we did a very
simple process um it's just a login
button
that we have two that has two attributes
the domain and client id
um these you will find in your austere
dashboard on your application
so you can add those there if you want
to take a closer look into my
code feel free to it's on github.com
i'm constantly working on it so there
might be changes when you go check it
out and i know that
um a friend of mine is also helping out
and sending in some pr's
so if you have any suggestions please
feel free to do so too
so let's take a look at our login
button so our login button
is this and it's then going to take you
to this login screen so let's see if
that works
going to our code this is basically
the same as we just saw but instead of
being on slides it's in an ide
i did an npm mpn start sorry
and then this is what it'll take you to
you click in your
you click on the login you continue with
google in this case
i choose my xero account and
there we go and we get the update ui
working nicely
cool so this all works pretty nicely and
[Music]
remember how i said that i had actually
built that
with vanilla javascript sorry
well there are other frameworks and
libraries that we can actually use to
create
web components so let's just take a
quick look at these because i'm running
i'm running for that time so we have the
lit element
library which is my favorite but then
they're skate.js there's hybridges
lens stencil angular elements and
so forth now it all depends on what you
like
you can test out different ones they're
all very special and there's been a lot
of work put into each and every one of
them
so that's pretty cool and that we don't
have to
build everything with just vanilla js
so one thing that tends to worry
us developers is the browser
and i know that years ago when web
components first came out browsers
weren't ready
which really put people off web
components because they had to add loads
of polyfill some of those polyfills
weren't great
um but i have news here and good news
uh the browser is fully stable as you
can see
um and also if we want to use older
versions of the browsers then we do have
really good polyfills so
go ahead browsers are not excuse go
experiment
i'm very excited about web components
because i can see they have a lot of
potential
and i hope you are as excited as i am
after my talk
so just before i go into questions i
just want to thank you all for listening
to me
i hope you've enjoyed this talk um i
have
it's been quite an experience and
feel free to all reach out now asking
any questions
or on twitter there's my hand in again
and thank you
all right so this time we've got just a
couple minutes here if you guys have any
questions for anna regarding
her presentation go ahead enter those
into the q
a tab at this time or if you want to
enter them
into slack as well we can we'll take a
few moments
here just to pass those on to anna
and i guess you you just did a really
that good job because i'm not seeing any
questions right now
um but
they can always reach out to me on
twitter like i said no need to rush into
it
i'm always available terrific and are
you gonna be available in slack for a
little while afterwards
yeah definitely i'll be around until
this evening so
okay well terrific so if you guys have
any questions for anna be sure that you
reach out to her catch her in slack
or use twitter as she mentioned and uh
we'll let anna go and and take care of
that and we will be on with our next
speaker in just a few moments
okay thank you thank you anna bye
bye