hi my name is Matt I'm a writer at
hackaday and today we're gonna do a
hackerspace
tour this time around we're gonna check
out Pasadena City College and see what
their Fab Lab looks like so let's check
that out
I'll show you the PCC Fab Lab so this
area is basically the workstation with
Fab Lab where design tech pathway uses
along with the Engineering club along
with machine shop engineering department
everyone comes here and work any project
physically choose any machine team some
of the engineers students are at the
rate art center race so these are the
parts and prototypes and finals that
they have been working on for the whole
summer
and yesterday it was the during the
competition of the race the last day
it's our Arab early laser before we had
an error vanilli outside but it was
causing too much toxic for people who
were just walking past my so he finally
got to validator and the purple ones are
older ones so this one's for the newer
laser cutter and then repairs on
machines out where mostly people who
have taken machine shop are allowed to
use it or has an instructor visual so
the chainsaw the scene sees what mostly
student use to use the computer lab
you
you see as a computer and then the lathe
not much students use it because most of
them have been taken the machine shop
except the older engineers so we also
got to talk with the design technology
pathway director let's see what she had
to say hi I'm Debra bird and I'm the
director of the design technology
pathway and this is our Fab Lab we're a
program here at Pasadena City College an
innovative program based on new
technology we're preparing students for
the wide range of design fabrication
technology careers for the future so the
model that we're using is one really
based on developing collaboration and
teamwork students come in they work on
project-based learning so they're
solving real problems in the real world
so for example the models for visually
impaired students for campus maps etc
the goal is to have the students develop
the skills of collaboration and
communication soft skills and also to
develop a lifelong learning approach to
technology so the technology is taught
not as a standalone element but more as
an integral part of the design and
problem-solving process our students
come from a wide range of backgrounds
we're primarily working with incoming
high school students but we're
increasingly expanding our model to
include community access to the Fab Lab
and work experience opportunities that
are also problem-based so students can
come in and expect integrated academics
math English College Success we use a
series of stackable
that move towards transfer so students
can anticipate coming in and getting
real world work skills right from the
very beginning that can then
increasingly pay off as students move up
and transfer to four-year and and
further educational opportunities now
one of the projects that Deborah was
talking about was a map for the blind
and we wanted to find out a little bit
more about this project so we asked a
few students what it was like working on
it so let's find out what that is about
so on the top version you see you see
the first prototype that we did it's a
we use um no and you see it like this so
we use wood as the back because we
thought the plastic was a little bit too
weak but we found out that the plastic
was well it was pretty strong so so the
issue was um the weight and we also um
had people had a visually impaired
people read it and they seem to like the
texture they seem to like the doorway
you know all the stairs they can they
can read all that the only issue is um
they wanted us to change the ramps here
do you and also um the triangles here
they weren't they wanted this to be a
bathroom and also the letterings were
confusing and then some of the Brill's
were a little mixed up so on this final
product we changed the ramps here we
also simplify the letters here we also
change this to an arrow and the restroom
became also going triangle what I found
most challenging about this project was
was the design element who's like was
trying to step out of a visual world
trying to step out of a sighted world
and really trying to be in the footsteps
of the visually impaired like how do
these how do these textures translate to
visually impaired people trying to
understand scale thankfully we have the
disabled students program here on campus
and we went to them for a lot of help
and show them our models and yeah it was
very very interesting just stepping out
of the realm and just imagining what it
would be like to experience a space
without without vision from the looks of
it it seems that PCC is bringing
together an awesome combination of tools
and resources and education techniques
but where are they getting the money for
this our funding model is based on a
series of grants that we've received
both from the state and federal levels
we started with a very small in-house
front from the Innovation Fund at
Pasadena City College and that bought
our very first piece of equipment which
was a laser cutter and that was about
three years ago and since then we've
been really fortunate we were awarded a
title five grant because we are a
hispanic-serving institution about 25%
of our students
Hispanic we have a lot of students who
are first-time college students and also
we have a lot of students who are coming
in with major financial obstacles so
we've provided a lot of wraparound
services through this front including
including tutoring mentoring we have a
college success course that's part of a
structure pathway the students have
priority enrollment so they get access
to the classes they need when they need
them and we also provide lab facilities
and the technology that you see around
is intended for student use and the Fab
Lab is intended to create this community
which the students really need then you
replace that is their own in order to
really have a meaningful college
experience we know that if students can
persist through the first couple of
semesters if they get to 30 units of
credit they are much more likely to
complete their degree at the AMA level
and move on to transfer we've also
recently been awarded two additional
grants at the state level through the
Career Pathways trust one is in advanced
manufacturing and that will be in
collaboration with Long Beach Community
College and the other for which we are
PCC is the fiscal lead is the Career
Pathways trust grant for information
communication technology and that covers
a broad range of technologies all the
way from entertainment arts media
through to computer science this is this
ground is part of a much larger
consortia with eight different community
colleges and six
my schools so the funding model is is
great we have assured funding for the
next four to five years but we intend to
increasingly institutionalize the cost
of running this program through
entrepreneurial activities through work
experience for the students and so a
little that is built into the financial
models of these grants as we move
forward so that was our hackerspace tour
hope you enjoyed it and look for the
next one
you