hi this is caleb a pack a day and today
we are at arch reactor in st. louis
missouri and Darryl here is going to
show us around the place it is Easter
Sunday so there's nobody here they were
nice enough to open it up just to give
us a private tour all right Darrell okay
it's starting to take around here you
never found area we're all members to
chill out this is the music or watch TV
either and they can also watch our
security system to see who's coming
either down guys leave workshop have our
vinyl cutters laser cutters and various
assorted 3d printers in various states
of operation I don't cover laser cutter
pretenders I noticed over there you have
a 3d scanner that Ryan I take it apart
but that's pretty cool it's been used if
you have been handed operation in our
ever-present growing drinking junk pile
which members projects a various states
of disassembly all kinds of good stuff
back here and what's that over there oh
that's the icon or station soldering
revelation what not to keep doing poison
by herb zadar zhu's oh very nice
granddaughters of course you have our
Pete work table here we're beautiful
three times larger than normal chess set
yeah okay very cool good stuff and of
course you have back here or me workshop
got a cool bar to
the main vari workshop you see it's
kevin of busy right the moment but the
projects you went in here 24 hours seven
days a week mini leg woodworking tools
that's not see machine over there let's
see me she all right that seems seems
like you got a really cool place here
thanks for giving us a tour but we have
a little bit of a full 32 managers help
me about like a like a party place on
the roof let's check that out flickr
party former on this goalie oh very cool
alright let's check that we're walking
along the hall and he surprises me with
this he opens the door and there's a
whole freaking shot a shop of art
bicycles and air-cooled vehicles now
many of you know that know me know that
this stuff just drives me nuts i love
this stuff so check this out we have all
these bicycles for parades that they've
done a freaking turtle bike this is this
is fantastic and it's just sitting here
next to the hackerspace you know this is
wonderful stuff look at this and what
was the name of this group again but in
a bicycle per game the banana bike
brigade this is great they brought me up
here and i was just floor you'll see in
a second it was just beautiful up here
and I just appeared out of nowhere as
far as I'm concerned I didn't expect it
one of the thing
love about st. Louis is everywhere I go
people are doing all of this work with
reclaimed materials there I'll tell us
about what we got going on up here well
the only this building basically
scrounges and recycled materials from
over now Billy's the Timbers that from
visa that hold me supports were
reclaimed from a building that burned
down since the wood was so old road
again they couldn't burn so he basically
bought it for scrap cleaned enough and
repurposing to hold the canopy of the
bargain beautiful and what about the
what we have on the floors here is
reclaimed granite that he picks up off
construction site he reassemble them
back into a mosaic and even then puts in
designs if you can see over in the
corner they're close up but this entire
structure with the fireplace is also all
reclaimed there's a will there's
everywhere we clean break and don't work
oh it's fantastic beautiful
you