this is kaleb craft here in Huntsville
Alabama the makers local 256 this is tim
heap and he's going to show us around
real quick say hi Tim hello all right
this is makers local 256 front entrance
front hallway we do have a kiosk that we
put together from an old arcade cabinet
it gives us a way to get to IRC or we
even have a guest book on here but it's
it was a great way to get a computer
that just lives here that anyone can use
and it's right next to the office we do
have some office space we've got one
Jennifer working on an LED cube we have
our servers are in here we have AC and
heating in here that's the the big
feature nice and then out here we have
put it kind of a lobby we've got maps up
and a great thing on the maps these are
pins for places that other hackerspaces
that we visited or that have visited us
oh very nice in both the the US and the
world so we're really happy to interact
with spaces and get to know people looks
like you've already had one from
Springfield correct other than me yes
interest don't remember who I wasn't
here that day but we do have a kitchen
we have a working oven and fridge and
all the stuff you might want out of a
kitchen we have two bathrooms which is
nice and then we have our main area
which has a lot of work tables a lot of
space vending machine this is actually
just set up a new desk today
we also have that we called our
electronics room or Fab Lab and here we
have a specific workbench for
electronics work soldering and reflow we
do have a laser cutter which is a lot of
fun we do we're working on 3d printers
as well MakerBot reprap a few pinchot
settings back out in the main area one
new vending machine we've bought the
other been efficient was donated but
it's it's nice to have on hand sometimes
to lariat in the back where we have
drills mills welders and screwdrivers
radial arm so most of this is is either
donated or on loan from a member and we
say that they bring out people can use
it people can play with it but it still
belongs to somebody very nice we also
have a Dalek which was completely
crafted here very nice ones fun and that
one drives correct you somebody sits on
it and pilots it it doesn't yet but
that's probably going to have it it's
probably going to be remote-controlled
but we are working on drive technology
for it nice uh-huh we did another recent
acquisition was a four-by-eight cnc
machine all right you know I'm drop in
the the forebay sheet of plywood cut it
build stuff out of that we we've got
bikes for people to drive around we're
in a we're in a pretty good neighborhood
for for people to be able to get to
other shops or other local landmarks and
restaurants so it's good
if I built a little scooter this
actually had Snoopy's doghouse as a
frame around it but I'm already on to my
next thing I'm going to share this one
down oh that's cool when you have member
storage shelves we encourage members to
bring a bring a bucket store their
projects their tools that nobody else is
really going to take away from nice and
then we have loft space
all right up in the lot we've got this
is general storage this is hackable this
is take it do something with it make
something make something new make
something old we do have a bit of a
lounge in a library we're putting
together books and such for people to
use beyond that is the AV lab we've got
a lot of various audio and video
equipment that we've taken apart or
rebuilt or done something with very nice
that's most of what's here at the shop
fantastic thank you very much thank you
you