you
[Music]
thank you very much good morning we're
going to start the dynamics with
previous talks which were inspirational
but also technical well women we work in
cybersecurity and we would like to talk
to you about our experience to see if we
can we can encourage you to work in this
industry I'll introduce them although
they've already been more less
introduced by she's had a either we he's
who was born in Santiago de los
Caballeros in Dominican Republic she's
been living in Spain for 20 years
half of her family in-laws in Seville
she has three children baptized in
Triana and her wedding was here in
Natalia she loves the Andalusian
character she's an experienced of 28
years in business consulting in IT
systems and before introducing them I
asked them to to tell me about some
personal success
motivated then and that could motivate
people to work in this industry
she loves challenges overcoming
challenges and many people think that
perhaps it's going to be complicated to
make it here she's passionate about
cyber security and without it our lives
would be completely different
she likes being an example for everyone
who wants to work in cybersecurity and
technology to show you that you can do
it it doesn't matter how old you are the
sex you have thank you
I would like to thank Soledad she was
born in antequera
she studied law
she worked in a locked cabinet and then
in a consulting company one of her most
important successes was when the day the
legislation data protection appeared
well her life changed
[Music]
there was a time when she was considered
someone weird she's worked for the
public administration she's tried to
translate what an IT system means that
is it is understood now she works for
Seder she's very happy there because she
can work from home too and thanks to
technology we'll find a new ways working
she defines herself as a multi potential
cyber woman and here have MA she was
born in Zelda and she lives in Malaga
she's in love with the city she was all
smiling today
she's a different person today she's
delighted to be here we are delighted to
have her here
six years of experience in the national
security department in charge of
security
and she points out that her work is a
passionate challenge but it's quite a
responsibility she considered
cybersecurity as a game of strategy and
some sort of escape room where we face
different challenges complicated
challenges but we need to escape however
we can thank you very much and Conti
Concepcion Corazon she was born in the
province of Granada
and when she was just she moved to
Malaga
she has always 30 years of experience
I'm the oldest one here
[Music]
she's achieved something which is
really nice she said that was a little
girl she wanted to be a doctor because
she could save lives and now she
believes that by working in
cybersecurity she's also saving lives I
would like to thank you all for being
here and sharing your professional and
personal experiences we wanted to reach
conclusions messages to take homes that
you become attracted to the world of
cybersecurity right now there's a
significant demand of employment jobs
regarding site related to cybersecurity
so we'd like you to comment on
professional opportunities how can you
dress this well I'll start
first of all I would like to thank in
Seaver for inviting me to take part in
this wonderful session in a wonderful
city I'm delighted to have you here
it's listen to us we were talking
forward we said okay there are so young
because well so old they must be
thinking what can we tell them about
cybersecurity well I don't know whether
all of you come from the technical side
of the engineers mathematicians I'm not
familiar with the profiles but cyber
Security's open to any profile what do I
mean by this my professional experience
remain trained experience I have a
degree in business administration
and I'm managing a cyber security unit
and national cyber security so you can
be you need to learn you need to keep on
learning you need to study but it's open
to any profile and with regards
employment you're aware the technology
is moving forward very quickly we have
insufficient artificial intelligence we
have big date
well facing cyberattacks illegal use of
technology which means that the other
side who need cybersecurity
professionals that face the challenges
you've mentioned with cybersecurity
escape room and Monday and Tuesday was a
world of chrome experiment didn't even
they said that more than 3.5 million
jobs in cybersecurity we will create it
in three years time so you have the
opportunity before you so it's three
years and 3.5 million but if technology
advances the demand would be higher here
we don't have cybersecurity
professionals we need professionals and
it's up to you to respond to this demand
we're not recipient and it sounded the
booth
so this is quite a van Eco here I don't
have much to say when you hear that
figure 3.5 million jobs in three years
I don't think AI or robotics
[Music]
we're not receiving any sound at the
booth well you got that Oh No baseball
well this is like it's Inga the
technology positions that exists now not
the same future competitive cyber
security because cyber security is the
basis of our digital life now we have
IOT domotics everything is connected if
you don't have the foundations the basic
the base of cyber security our digital
lives are not safe now well living a
digital lie we have our smartphones with
us all the time we do everything through
apps everything we do in our daily live
working and detainment buying tickets
paying our purchases we do this through
smartphones and this should make us
think that cybersecurity is embedded in
any step we take every day and very
often you see us here but we're not old
we just started as a very early stage
[Music]
sometimes when we talk to young people
they tell us well cybersecurity the
event I have is well hackers in a
basement
with the hoodie eating pizza and we say
no sometimes you need to realize that
there are different profiles like ma has
explained before I'm an industrial
engineer we have people working with us
that come from the marketing world
criminology lawyers say cybersecurity is
cross-cutting and diverse and sometimes
people considered some something related
to freaks something this does not affect
me there's not improv an impact on me
but every time you access your computer
you've found you need to think about
cybersecurity and you don't just have
you can't be satisfied by being
self-taught you need to train train is
trading is pivotal because there are
many lines many profiles for
cybersecurity the hackers of course
which are widely known they're more
mediatic they have more impact in me the
other side for the cyber security
incident that make it to the news
related to hackers that's what the media
shows but there are a lot of people
behind that with the more technical work
marketing work foreign stick work
identifying
profiles of cyber criminals not just
from the standpoint of fighting against
criminals but also protecting criminals
every day when we connect we need to
take the basic measures not just us work
in cybersecurity it has to be in society
as a whole it's education at home with
our kids they need to know how to use
social media something as simple as
covering your webcam on your computer is
very useful simple things that make us
safer in the digital lives were living
Selina I would like to thank you Siva
for inviting me I would like to thank
Madras for introducing me I would like
to tell you that if you see that we are
very familiar here on stage it's true
we are women and we explain what's going
on in the world of cyber security so
that you can have the opportunities you
deserve why am I saying this I'm going
to explain my personal experiences
retreat has said at the beginning the
data protection law changed my life back
in 2001
lot 15 / 1999 had been ready enacted I
was a lawyer in a log cabin 8 regular
job as lawyer and I had the opportunity
to attend a talk by one of the main
persons relay man-made people related to
cybersecurity which is dr. Carlos Gallup
back then when I attend the conference
dr. Gallo spoke about a law and as a
lawyer I was used to hearing about
different piece of legislation but when
I was listening to him about the data
protection law I had a feeling that it
was not just any law for me was the law
of capitalist
because when the legislature enacts a
law regarding blessing it's a trust to
very particular population people have
to do with ly6
if it's the law related to divorce well
this is address of people that are going
to divorce but this is not the case for
data protection law this piece of
legislation is addressed to any of us
natural persons
it protects basic right that actually
touched me as something there and it was
not until a few years later when I had
the opportunity to focus on new
technologies long and I did decided to
take the leap
as a matter of fact it was just studying
a different law in a different area
I had a possibility of working as a
consultant of new technologies law in
order to apply data protection law and
there I started to work with colleagues
who were had a technical profile IT
engineer and communication engineer who
spoke a different language I spoke the
legal language but we need to understand
each other
can you imagine how this was a lawyer
spin in sign language as an IT engineer
I was the weird person some sort of
translates between what law says that
the IT people could understand it as
well tree has said there was a while ago
and now I have a different
responsibility now I work in cyber
security I'm in charge
business and cybersecurity of a Spanish
company called Seder it has offices in
more than 60 countries across the world
more than 30 offices at national level
more than 4,000 employees across the
world and in Spain were close to 2,500
and play years why am I saying this
because if you're sick in a job well I'm
offering jobs that's the reality the
reality we have is that we need
workforce we need initiatives
capabilities knowledge we want you to
come to our companies to demand a job
you have the potential in the near
future we need profiles right now so if
you access Saders web page there's a tag
which is work with us you can include
your CV you CV both for job offers which
have already been published or you can
leave your CV because sometimes we check
for specific profiles and we're looking
for people so thank you for being here
thank you for listening to me and I'm
sure we'll have the opportunity to talk
because I'm the older in this front
table I can say that I have significant
experience so here there are very many
digital natives as well as other people
so in terms of needs that we have had in
Siebel so it is very important to work
with everyone even with parents parents
that are members of parents associations
I am a native I'm cyber secure and as I
say I learned one of land
as I direction to go and as I say I was
about to become a doctor I wanted to
become a doctor and I decided to go to
the IT engineering school so we were
well I was the first promotion of IT
engineers here in Melaka and then as I
said there is no entry exam I've been in
Malaga since I was 2 years old
I consider myself to come from Malacca
and I come from
Milana so to speak and
when I graduated I was very passionate
for this topic and my colleagues I had
been studying a lot for the intrigue
some did not pass the exam and then
assess it as I said we were the first
promotion of IT engineers and then I
said okay I'm going to take this
opportunity I'm going to take this
opportunity and to go in the IT world so
I as I say it was very difficult for me
to go into the IT world security world
but once I discovered it and I could see
the huge opportunities in it I became
passionate about it so because
everything is related to cyber security
of very many things I'll give you very
real life example so you've seen the
debate about implants now these days of
well there is a civil side to it because
some implants will be mechanic will fail
because of their mechanics or sometimes
when implants fail there is a cyber
reason behind it because they are
connected nowadays everything is
connected everything that we use is
connected anything which is connected
has cyber security the resurvey security
behind it so the first book on the
dangers of the communication networks
and privacy so we tend to think that
data privacy law is a new law back in
the
60 or the 70s
[Music]
has it lots of development and
advancement have we made ever since the
first time privacy in the networks was
discussed so everything is connected to
the internet our refrigerator
anything which is refrigerator and as I
say a mother can be a perfect
stakeholder to be recruited as a cyber
profile we all have accountability the
moment we buy a smartphone
I want a smartphone and I wanted to have
specific features so the cyber comes in
comes into play and we are all cyber at
the end of the day data protection no
the new GRP t it's about data security
how we are going to build up protection
and then well the other panelist says
that data protection law changed her
life and also here we have to talk about
critical infrastructures so the
different terrorist attacks they also
were a breakthrough in terms of loss
average legislation to about security
one of the definitions given out by
United Nations of cyber security is I
like very much this is defined us
Security's the well-being state that
individuals feel perceive and enjoy so
we organizations and entity all of us
working in the field of cyber security
we need to deliver that trust that
perception of to citizens
it isn't as when you come out to the
streets you need to feel safe so we are
all cyber security cyber security
works at all levels and every any
studies that we do nowadays have the
cybersecurity side to them or
cybersecurity cross-sectional subjects I
would like to invite you to analyze and
to reflect upon any topic that you may
see around you they may see in the news
and there is cybersecurity side to
everything alright so we've been talking
about the different elements and they
are pointing at the same thing well we
should talk about professional profiles
and also skills and aptitudes that we
all need to have and that they are also
very important in the world of
cybersecurity
yes it's very interesting to talk about
cybersecurity profiles so here there is
room for any type of profile at the end
of the day all companies and need to
have experts to recruit resources we
also need experts in communication
journalists nowadays have the
opportunity to bring their knowledge and
know-how in line with cyber security for
instance when it comes to reporting
security breaches or reporting any other
type of incidents for instance I'm
talking about how news were posted when
our news are broadcast
whenever Facebook or any other company
suffers or is attacked so this is
nothing new
I'm as I say I'm talking about communic
profiles in the communication world but
now let us think about other profiles
that will also be needed
giving the example of psychologists and
linguists neuro linguists now are
working in line with artificial
intelligence psychologists philosophers
saikhan linguists will be needed at the
end of the day we have to bring ethics
in line with development of Robotics so
that at the end of the day the troubles
that are manufactured and not equipped
with an artificial intelligence that
will go crazy so we really need to have
different profiles different type of
people working in this field but we are
talking about profiles I would like to
refer to the need to have diverse
profiles we also wanted to talk about
diversity in this roundtable I'll give
you an example
we at Seder we have some four thousand
employees all over the world I could
tell you that we have two percent of
young people and two percent of senior
employees and the sinners are very
senior so we also have to work on that
so that to look into the profiles that
we want to bring into our company so we
need to finance a bit find the balance
there
[Music]
when I was reflecting upon this topic I
decided to talk there would be a good
idea of these type of soft skills these
type of skills for instance team working
and well this is not very these are not
very hard skills technical skills but
they also allow us to have but working
diverse teams and who cannot want a
disciplinary work we also talked about
artificial intelligence so we have also
would like to open the floor to
questions and answers so please take
that opportunity think about your
questions and well before we move on to
questions I'd like to say that
cybersecurity is sexy as well as very
cool
miserable says I work in cybersecurity
say oh wow are you a hacker no I'm not a
hacker and as we said before there are
very many stereotypes that will have to
do away with
so as Oliver says no in the attacker is
very important so therefore the
viewpoint of psychologists to find out
about who is the attacker what
personality is god that's a really good
point we also need economists to
convince our boss that it is necessary
to invest in service security will have
this is one of the most important roles
in cybersecurity it's not easy to
convince those who are in charge of
deciding on investments that cyber
security investments is all the more
necessary and we'll have to open up this
field so the scenario is the cyber space
where we are all connected I'm not
talking about this baby we are talking
about Chinese Americans Russians Lincoln
that is a game as we said before and I
don't want to refer to it as a war of
game sorry a war game and at the end of
the day we have taken this to reality
and we can see them in real life and
professional profiles have to be broad
and diverse no years compete working in
marketing to sell the cybersecurity
product they have to be economists
psychologists doctors we have talked
here about replacements and in fact you
can remotely control a pacemaker and
actually brand that we will not be
naming here had their insulin pumps
attacked and well the world is open the
world is open to endless possibilities
and we are talking about his skills it's
very important to know how to translate
the technical language how many of you
have a technical profile who
okay you are not technicians who have
not received that technical training
well you technicians should use the
language that we those of us were not
technicians can follow I've been
learning throughout my life what
cybersecurity is about value technicians
need to know how to explain to those who
are not technicians what do you do what
is necessary to invest in what you do
and why your time is of so much value
and now I would like to share three
messages takeaway messages first cyber
security is diverse second cyber
security is responsibility of us all and
then to work in cyber security you need
significant training lots of training it
is very interesting of course to self
teach yourself and to have lots of
curiosity parents of that you need
training you need education and yes you
need to have the curiosity curiosity is
extremely its crucial and it is very
easy nowadays to fill our curiosity
because we have lots of information
about the internet but as I say training
also very very important
[Music]
so the global level we need all type of
profiles but we also need significant
well with specialization I don't know
whether you are being trained in IT
security how many of you are studying IT
security how many of you are in between
development development of Java websites
[Music]
have you been told about the secure
funds for each language programming
language that you know secure functions
who is aware of secure funds so a
secured function edit prevent you by
being but not being attacked by the
vulnerabilities over for not having an
SQL injection you should finish your
strain with an asterisk okay have you
been taught that have you learned are
you ok as I say lots of a specialization
so in the future we will need
specialists in development a specialist
in forensics specialist in hacking so
you need to have like an overall vision
but at the same at the end of the day
people will be highly specialized the
Philosopher's the psychologists all
these profiles will be mirrored in
service security with this I mean that
cyber security is open to everyone
so also managing uncertainty we don't
know who
we'll be facing up okay so therefore
we'll have to be creative in terms of
how to respond to the attackers - we
also have to be to welcome our
creativity also lateral thinking
out-of-the-box thinking well Marge you
are very good at explaining that lateral
thinking out-of-the-box thinking we'll
have to be creative
well lateral attacks you are aware of
tired of lateral attacks well that
should be contracted by lateral thinking
now we are talking about going out of
the box I do not worry you were in the
of the last Winter Olympic Games in
China not sleep who was from the US and
then she became Turkish to take part in
Tallaght games
her name was Elizabeth strain her story
is a very interesting story because she
was obsessed with taking part in the
Olympic Games but she had a problem
Winter Olympic Games and well often well
skiing is one of the sports and what she
didn't know how to ski and what did she
do to fulfill her dream well she started
learning and then she produced the plan
and to see what she needed to end up in
the Winter Olympic Games and according
to the regulations one of the
requirements was having taken parts in
other competitions for her to get a
score she was to her that a scorer in
those competitions where there were less
than 30 women participating in it and
she looked up for those competitions
with less than 30 women in them she used
to join those competitions and then to
get the scores or that she needed or the
points that she needed and then she sum
up all those that is Kareem and then in
the end she ends up being the person in
Hungary with the highest number of
points and then she ended up in China in
the Winter Olympic Games do you know
what she did well that is in YouTube and
in the end she took part in the
competition and she was bending okay she
could not stand a pair of skis and then
well because that didn't say in the
regulations okay she just ensured that
he would take part in the competition so
what she did was thinking out of the box
this is the way we should think in cyber
security because the situation's we end
up facing are tremendously unexpected
when we are managing events attackers do
not let us know oh look I'm going to
look for the back to Iran because you've
got a vulnerability they don't know that
you not tell us about that so therefore
this is the reality that we face so
therefore had skills such as know-how
knowledge and English English language
careful English is widely used in
cybersecurity are the skills of perfect
women welcome that they are all the time
needed however soft skills are
tremendously important to me which is
the most importance of the skill of
communication and why because in
cybersecurity where we are managing
events well you do not only have
well with your member members of your
team also with the management of your
company and also coordination and in
collaboration with other national or
international teams the first o-silk
network started of us to fulfill the
need of managing incidents in the best
possible manner and as I say
communication empathy cooperation they
are essentials of the skills and then of
Kerswell being sympathetic working with
teams all right so we would like to open
the floor to questions and well before
that I'd like to mention the following
topic one of the five one of the things
that you'd like you to take away is that
security is not exclusive of it's not a
world of fur of men and for men when I
went to university well there were ten
women and we were surrounded by very
many women volunteer beginning it seemed
okay our colleague has told us that when
she went to the IT school and there were
50% women are 50% men then later on I
went back to university and then the
percentage of women had
those schools haven't reduced
dramatically so Pedro Sanchez Cordero
has a wonderful presentation this
afternoon Cuckoo's egg I recommend you
attend his presentation is very very
very good
I've always been following ongoing
training so federal census Cordero
is one of the best in the world you will
have the opportunity to check that by
yourself this afternoon he has also been
attached teacher in one of the latest
Martin's courses that I followed when I
said when I went to the IT school 50%
women 50% men and now you are teaching
at the AG school how many women what is
the percentage of women well in my
master's course a master's course where
I teach there is only one woman
[Music]
Syme all the time learning I've trained
myself all my life but as I say I'm not
seeing very many women recently getting
trained in cyber security service even
has a firm on cybersecurity and gender
and country that's why we are making a
significant effort from different women
associations to promote participation of
women in cyber security so that women
understand that this is a fascinating
world that there is a significant future
head and we through technology can build
a better world and actually here today
at Malaga we had the recent event known
as women challenge with 1,500 women from
Spain this is an event aimed at
promoting the participation of women in
the world of technology then very many
women here but please pass that
information on to your friends to your
relatives and to please pass on you
passion about cybersecurity and
technology to them so service security
by design that's a fascinating topic so
all of us here are in love with
cybersecurity we would like to have more
more people more women interested in
working and contributing to the world of
cybersecurity
well hopefully next year there will be
not only five of us but thirty of us so
time for questions we have two more
minutes
come on don't be shy all right there is
a question there hello
we are students from the system's cycle
of vocational training on systems
so what will be the itinerary that we
should follow we are just ordinary
students so we are not wealthy we cannot
really afford 5000 euro training course
what is the itinerary that we should
follow well that's a wonderful question
it's a really really good question very
approaching and so I really like to
answer these type of questions who here
will have colleagues from community
groups which is community group is
companies we have from Malaga they have
an educational itinerary offering 204
training courses with 35 labs so we know
that theory is not the only thing that
we need we also need to practice to put
things in practice to make sure that you
are ready to face up to the attacks that
you may be receiving and now if you
visit their websites
so you will get access to all the
training courses that we offer we are
also working with San Pablo fellow and
Polytechnic College University we are
offering our courses on ethical hacking
and others we don't only train people
and red teaming and on the actual
hacking work but as I say we are
offering a technical itinerary to work
in communications in networks as a basis
to basic training suitcase further
specialized so you may discuss that with
Antonio Lopez and Tony Lopez his company
from Malaga and we are very happy to
work with them because we strongly
believe in training and education so
regarding training because self teach
myself well many occasions I had to pay
for my training other occasions called
my training paid and well there are very
many training courses online of an
organization offers training well those
of you who work in systems so systems
[Music]
when we are talking about systems ok
well
contained 50% security I don't know
whether you have been trained on
security or not obviously lots of
training the same as in female offers
manuals best practices and it has a long
list of masters courses they are all
different they are all on cyber security
as I said for my training for my
education is very interesting but we
should not forget about soft skills and
then common-sense the common sense that
you need to work in cyber security we
already have that and then we have to
apply know how to apply it there is lots
of training and well free training and
out there which we can take a very good
advantage of so we Ayrton Siva we are
strongly supporting talent Cybercom is
one of the proofs of that this is the
fifth edition of our summer camp the
idea is to identify talent and to help
you out from us from a public company
specializing in cyber security
we would like to help you find the
education and training itinerary that
you need we also have an improvement
forum also lifelong training workshops
competitions but it is very important
when the phrases for all targets younger
people all the people because at the end
of the day this is a global topic
security cyber security is not a
trending topic anymore it is a real need
that affects us all
so actually we should this give to cyber
security the treatment it deserves we
should all be well aware of what happens
with some security and the connected
world where we live and well other than
the education and training itinerary
itinerary search do not forget about
becoming an analyst and researching and
reading a lot ok do not forget to read
about what is happening in the world
after curiosity fuel that curiosity well
other than the interest that you may
having following formal training and
education by learning you can learn by
reading you can learn a lot read and
read and read and research and research
and also take advantage of the
communities communities of developers so
do not limit yourself to formal
education only go beyond there come out
of the box
[Music]
so all the progress that I made in this
field is because anything that was new I
got trained on that if no one wanted to
get training on that I always
volunteered to be trained
well now what do companies look for in
terms of profiles
my companies have needed to fulfill
vacancies were well either because we
are growing our business because we are
offering more services and what we do
have is like internal its inner area
internal training itinerary for our
stuff through our personnel so the
people that we hire are required to have
basic knowledge basic know-how that is
to say hard skills and then once a
person is in the company we work with
the person so that the person knows how
to work in a team and we work a lot in
soft skills so for instance I follow
training on teamwork conflict management
and many of these things that are many
of these soft skills that are very
important in cybersecurity once we have
hired personnel and as I say we produce
that in that training itinerary and how
do we do that well by specific training
or for instance I do not propose into
other stuff to get international
certifications or well diploma as as
needed
any other questions in the room well no
more questions
so me I'd like to say
that for more advanced profiles or even
beginners profiles we are our platforms
we offer the possibility to produce and
I'd seen early based on an Aes this is
what Secretary of Defense in Department
of Defense in u.s. use so you enter your
skills to debilitate your knowledge and
based on all these questionnaires that
you'll fill out when you create a
profile for yourself then you can
produce and training itinerary that best
suit the cybersecurity profile where you
are or where you want to be so this is a
nice very good way to start
so that is tells you where you are and
then you can project where you want to
do so then you decide whether you want
to become a hacker or that you want to
be in the red team you name it all right
so I would like to finish I would like
to thank our four speakers who sing a
pleasure being with you
and also is being wonderful to share
this roundtable with you people who are
very passionate for what they do people
with lots of curiosity highly creative
people and as I say it's been a pleasure
thank you very much everyone
[Music]
[Applause]
you