[Music]
Cadell we wanna start a good afternoon
everyone I hope you enjoyed your lunch I
hope that you're full of energy ready to
start with our afternoon session a very
interesting workshop we will be hearing
from a peasant they are a leader and
Carlos says that those they will tell us
how terrorist organizations organize
themselves to make the most of these
foreigner abilities please access a are
in Phoebe and on Twitter with the cyber
camp hashtag I'm not going to take any
of their time well Carlos is an analyst
villain Vicente was the founder of the
Spanish chapter for his organization and
the author of the info leak - I hope you
enjoyed their presentation good
afternoon
let me start it with a word of thanks I
want to thank in C Bay I want to thank
the organizers of the event in general
and logically I want to thank them for
inviting us to be here today to tell you
about techniques and tools that can be
useful when we investigate potential
suspicious profiles for different
terrorist individuals or organizations
that's the topic for our presentation
today
Carlos and I will take it in turns there
will be some for more explanations some
more practical work we will tell you
about a hadees' terrorism well here we
see the table of contents for our
presentation starting as I said with
jihadist tear
ISM and Carlos will tell you more about
this site or things those of you who
work with cyber intelligence and
jihadist profiles Carlos is a true
specialist we hope you find our workshop
interesting I would also like to thank
the organizers and all of you for making
it here nice and early
straight after lunch this is a little
bit of background here we see this piece
of infographics the Spanish Ministry for
the interior summarizes the different
operations they have been covering in
2017 I don't want you to think so much
about the I show details but I just want
you to see that there is a very
homogeneous distribution of the
different operations on the eastern
coast Catalonia up in the Northeast and
in Madrid the capital city logically
there is a higher volume of people
who've been arrested accused of he had
his terrorism let me just tell you about
this study covering the period from 2013
to 2017 where 234 people were arrested
accused as suspected terrorists
terrorists
well 51% were accused for disseminating
propaganda on social media that's the
new scenario because a hadees' terrorism
then people tend to think about attacks
against the police bombs
[Music]
so how does that have to do with cyber
jihadist terrorism well is everything
that has to do with ehad is terrorism on
the cyberspace attacks where the
cybernetic attacks where the motivation
is a hardest ideology and here we can
see this poster that was published by
one of the groups that later we will
refer to them during the presentation is
a group of inverted commas hackers and
they published this that they posted
this poster this is terror not just from
a physical point of view like in the
terrorist attacks in Barcelona or Madrid
they actually mix that with the virtual
environment and statistically we know
that about 50% of those arrested had to
do with physical terrorist attacks
whereas the remaining 50% it had to do
with trying to capture new members and
also with propaganda here we can see
this piece of infographics that tells us
how at the top we have the dice
propaganda organization here at the
bottom we see shall we say the content
consumers and originally their objective
was meant to be attracting combatants
that is convincing them later to travel
over to Syria or wherever they were
needed to wage their war well more and
more they're trying to attract cyber
competi combatants that is people who
and not go and physically battle or
fight but actually to disseminate this
propaganda and also for attacks
to take place in their own countries of
residence are we just talking about
terrorists in general well that's not
really the case here we can see how
there are people who are followers or
who sympathize with that ideology who
followers who then some of them I showed
terrorists there are people who remain
for a long time at the same level of
that pyramid whereas in other cases and
people start at the bottom but then they
climb up that ladder quite fast in some
cases now we will continue to hear now
from within them so we'll be talking a
lot about the social media we will be
talking about physical social networks
as well physically so because before a
virtual social media started this was
the scenario somebody was connected with
different people but a limit connections
and nodes were not those many whereas
the social media more and more has
extended the number of contacts and
nodes that we have contact with which is
very relevant in the case of terrorism
we know that a little bit about facts
and figures talking about social media
and the title of our presentation a part
of it has to do with soap mint because
some 80% of intelligence generation
nowadays has to do with
analysis and interpreting data that are
connected with open source computing and
social media how play a very relevant
role the level of exposure that we have
for other people to know what we say is
completely different now with social
media when we talk about identifying
people who are more relevant in this
network for instance well that's very
different now with social media in as
far as investigation is concerned so
there's the social network circle the
social media circle and what we're
interested in is that a overlap between
those two circles that's where we like
investigating and identify an individual
at that area of overlap here we can see
what investigations used to cover in the
past not so recent past
investigators would work like this
that's right because in the past you
would be investigating you would have
your sources for information so during
the investigation you would try and find
which member of this group was most
relevant for efforts to be focused on
that particular person and make the most
of the resources but that has been
changed recently that's right with
social media now that system is much
more dynamic much more complex so what
tools and techniques
can we use so that we can make the most
of any information that we can access so
that our resources are better used this
is the cyber caliphate
what do we mean by that well we talk
about dice but it could be any other
terrorist group well when they declared
their Caliphate they were talking about
something that was very much physical
geographically physical but then more
and more in the social media there's
something called the cyber caliphate
a label they quite like because the
number of the groups that have been set
up have been named according to this
name so what do they use normal social
media whether it is Facebook Twitter
Instagram blogs then the zero zone for
content dissemination telegram what's up
less so and threema and then the Tor
network free net I 2p not so much
because their identity is much more
easily identified in those cases so they
tried very very hard with manuals and
handbooks about how to use the Tor
network and so on
but they also you know perfectly well
that their users find this a lot harder
that anonymity is a lot harder to
achieve much harder than if they used
telegram say so if they use a virtual
number to set up a new account with
telegram you just need a phone number to
register a new account telegram never
asks you to access your account ever
again so I start a new account I then I
get rid of that phone number
there's no way to again connect that
person with a particular account that's
why the Tor network is a lot harder to
use for them than telegram telegram
allows for up to 1.5 gigas it to be
transferred it allows for backup
channels you have your own sort of cloud
as well so no matter how much we make an
effort yet they're always ahead of us an
administrator can be in charge of a
number of different channels so when the
police close a particular channel oh
they lose is their followers then what
they would do is again disseminate their
link in the rest of the channels they
operate and the channel is active back
again so no matter what we try and do to
stop these channels they as I said
sprout back very quickly back again
because the social media disseminate
their messages and either hide their
identity messages are very very easily
disseminated through the social media
that's right so from January sorry let
me stop and starts again
so as far as we can see telegram and
Twitter are the two main platforms
terrorists use for a doctrine nation and
dissemination of their messages there
are other platforms that are used as
well but volume-wise these two are the
giant so from January to November this
year just to give you an idea we have
been monitoring channels that might have
to do with terrorist organizations well
I actually monitored over four million
messages in my opinion this zero zone
for dissemination means that all the
contents go on telegram first and then
from telegram and they're further
disseminated a and spread through other
made through other channels for instance
from telegram to Twitter and then on the
Twitter account again you would have
links and connections with other social
media with other storage possibilities
back and forth so out of those over four
million messages that were analyzed we
found that over 1.5 million of URLs were
shared initially published or posted on
telegram and then on to Facebook Twitter
Google Drive a long list
of them this image is a an infographic
that stands for the share of information
that we shared through the different
channels so again it's telegram that is
the largest to start off with but for
instance if I have 10 journals as soon
as I set up my 11th channel then I
disseminate they contact for that new
channel on the other day on the first 10
logically so the the following main
channel for dissemination would be
Twitter so most of them start on
telegram then they go onto Twitter and
then sometimes back to telegram again to
it through to a different channel on
telegram they have a very clear specific
target now we consume multimedia and
Technology very very easily and apart
from having all sorts of different
messages well services sorry
we can see the type of messages they
disseminate it which only last year
almost 300,000 videos a 1.2 million
images 11 111 thousand audios that
almost 35,000 zipped files forty-four
thousand five thousand documents and
almost 15 thousand applications so
followers of terrorists logically find
it very very simple to have a mobile
phone and if a URL has been
there's no need to go to the computer at
home and securitize or secure anything
let's just watch it and share it on
their mobile phone that's their normal
target and that type of individual and
that's why they publish these types of
contents and telegram has no storage
limitations particularly they don't need
to count that is under 140 characters or
they don't need to make sure that is
only very short videos telegram makes it
very easy for them that's right and also
their service for storage on the cloud
that's right for instance films are not
particularly shared on torrents very
much these days
it's becoming more and more common doing
so on telegram why because of the
storage capacity there's no limit really
for a content storage they use telegram
for storage and they have their
handbooks and instructions explaining
how when a channel has a lot of
interesting content there should be
backups of those contents so that they
can then be uploaded again very very
easily if anything went wrong they also
often ask their followers to make sure
that if a channel goes and there's
always email address or an alias or NIC
why because there are different types of
channels we haven't explained that yes
if I might let me just summarize that
side of things because otherwise you get
a little bit lost their system for
propaganda is distributed in my opinion
into four groups for contact content
dissemination one is their official news
channel for instance when there is a
terrorist attack anywhere in the world
they claim it
they have agencies for instance this is
Mac one of their agencies but they have
them all over the world in all sorts of
different languages they do their
translations from Arabic which is the
normal first language into all sorts of
language languages and dash says these
are independent agencies that they only
publish information that has nothing to
do with terrorism but we know they do
really this type of channel is just in
charge of dissemination because there
are other channels that are not just
about dissemination but rather
dissemination with interaction there is
no interaction on of official channels
you need to be invited to be there and
then you can be a consumer of their
contents but there's no interaction with
admins or with other users
what else do we have well the non
official or unofficial news agencies
they pick up on news published by
official agencies and apart from
disseminating that content they do more
than that they translate into different
languages whether it's pieces of news or
handbooks or instructions a lot of the
times from English into different
languages for instance this agency
24-hour caliphates publishes in lots of
different languages to again disseminate
their messages now this channel allows
for interaction you can read and share
contents posted by other users there are
sometimes internal debates about the
quality of a particular content or about
the purpose for a particular event here
we have the third type of channel which
is the fan boys boys channels what is
that well and they repost news both from
official and unofficial channels but
they do so quite freely shall we say for
instance also posting posters and
infographics and multimedia content
which are quite
quite controversial trying to encourage
their followers to do certain things and
their contents logically can be shared
but also you can debate you can add
additional contents you can add links to
other sites and so on so just for you to
get an idea how important these fanboy
Boise channels actually are because
sometimes people say well this is not an
official officially terrorist channel
terrorists don't actually own these
channels were here look at this image
here these two police officers the image
has been taken from the back and right
behind them there's a fan and here is an
armed with a knife this is an image
where the message is those two police
officers are being threatened with a
knife some of you might think well so
was why is that important well when in
Cornelia
near Barcelona there was an attempted
knife thing of a female police officer
at the door at the entrance of the
police station but this poster had been
posted only three days before that
attack took place is that relevant or
not when I talk about posters pop is a
label I've given it this type of image
here on the right we can see a poster
here it says that dice is beating Spain
one middle well that was just before the
Barcelona attacks the other type of
channel are groups of hackers that
organized actions on the social media I
can tell you that in this type of group
there's a massive scanning so that
Facebook publications it can be used for
their own interest they also try and
post and repost a content airflow taken
from other channels
so this is a way to follow and
understand the ideas they promote and
disseminate that's right they sometimes
use mass media to try and attract new
followers new combatants so they can be
a doctrine ated and become full members
well in this case - hackers what do they
want well new members because some of
them have been eliminated or arrested
and sometimes because they have internal
divisions here we can see that two of
them have disappeared over a period of
just a few months months so groups tend
to come ago and what do they what do
they do well sometimes to become a
member you need to go through different
filters and prove that you can do
different activities to explain what you
can contribute so I explained about the
propaganda organization how they try and
attract new cyber jihadists and what
they want over and above anything else
is users consumers of those contents
with reason telegram on Twitter whatever
and once they've been attracted as
followers or sympathizers well they can
go up that ladder that pyramid I showed
earlier to become full terrorists this
is the kind of thing that will look out
for here we can see how this man says
clearly hello people in Spain I'm
looking for people in Spain sorry so
they can carry out a terrorist attack
this is the kind of message that we look
out for this piece of infographics we
see shows us the different elements that
are involved in these activities on the
social media with different nodes
different members this is the type of
information and data that we try and
analyze and process so that is not just
information but true intelligence so
when we try and identify individuals and
connections and nodes that's where a
social media and intelligence tools are
ideal what do we need so that we have
true high quality intelligence we need
to combine products from different
disciplines
we'll see later
about a different mints ument
for instance humans is one of the
products that is working quite well for
us so if you asked what intelligence
analysis actually means well we
immediately think of films that we've
watched we think of the CIA the the mi6
Mossad and yet I just wanted to realize
that nowadays you don't even need to
think about that high level of
organization for us to talk about
intelligence
a lot of individuals devoting the
necessary time and resources can access
information and turn interval
intelligence and disseminate it for a
third party to consume honestly anybody
at home from their home with very few
resources with access to the social
media can access and disseminate
intelligent information I'm not going to
give you a lot of definitions about
ocean and segments in the case of oceans
open source intelligence its information
data facts and figures based on open
source technology gathered from publicly
available sources for the purpose of
meeting specific intelligence
requirements the beauty of oesn't is
that we can supply all of that at the
right time because late is too late
obsolete information won't be useful for
the purposes they have maybe it would be
useful to prevent future problems or
whatever but not to carry out a
particular terrorist activity now sock
mint would be very much the same thing
but focusing on social media monitoring
social media extracting information
interpreting what it means to reach
certain conclusions that is identifying
profiles and individuals in our case so
for this we need to start at the virtual
world connections
remember the image we showed you earlier
where there was that overlap between the
two circles so we can find people who
are within that overlapping area and is
that an easy task not at all but there
are ways and means and tools to do so
and later on we will tell you more about
those that's right
because sometimes we just have
indications not evidence but at least a
little bit of an indication that will
lead us where we go kommen Todd oh
podemos say podemos llegar so we forgot
about the CNI sorry about that but we
will try next you reach out to users
base as we said on the way they use the
social media or Internet as a home about
as we will see we can try and reach them
through the content they Eve disseminate
they post and we will see a few examples
so we will have a graph so this is a
graph let's figure this is a nice
structure we got plays well there's a
series of people here and what we are
interested in in learning which one we
want to interact with or which one we
wanna address or look into was in other
two years more resources a b c d
l depend on what our intentions are not
the same to try and reproach someone yes
if by using social through
formulate I can see who is the one on
which all the communications convert so
that's the way to learn what's going on
there and so I might the warranty in a
Cell the--wait come and approach them
that if I'm interested in working on
with this speech because that's the
person or the channel that has a radical
speech or that it's increasing that
which is a I might be interested in
coming closer to a or someone else
indirectly to try and have an
influential action in order to reduce
the or narrow channel philosophize this
speech or the actress but if we see that
a B and C are in an argument
I can also approach C to incentivize
that kind of a problem inside of the net
it will always be dependent on the kind
of interests we want and the time we
have you know that you approach a
profile like this it's not Facebook and
I befriend you it takes lots of work and
environment and context and it takes
time and based on the needs we have and
the time available techniques will vary
so here you have what we said how we at
first when we were talking about
official agencies which was one of the
main disseminators of content II a
doctrine Nader to indoctrinate or
convince the followers for to change
their mindset or become radical we refer
to you the Mac a a Mac agency up until
recently it was available um telegram
and with this agency
as soon as it was parted it was reported
to Twitter but it took Twitter several
days to close it down here because well
that's the screenshot and we've seen
information is very volts high
it is usually everywhere but even more
so in social media worries and now
online might be gone tomorrow or even
within a few minutes it'll be locked
deleted so we are interested in that
information we need to recover it and
start it you know that you have it later
on
as for Twitter let me see if I can show
it to you but we'll try and show to you
what info leaks look like for which will
you Mac net us at all I developed myself
and helps much with this investigations
so it is a search inside the database
that I have stored with the content
published and then it scrapes for social
media or accounts mainly telegram
Twitter Instagram and Facebook that
process we've said so for 2018 that
would be over four million messages so
figure what the Preston time can be for
this you know the to save as the 20
minutes of process and to get the date
of birth screen we got the foot clip
where you can see it
so first front roads would you want
managed to see match path if you're
lucky enough to see the scrim you would
see what we're talking about won't move
so let's get out of here
well I don't think that will be can we
can you see anything actually what we'll
do here is look into the database where
we keep it there all the information
here we see several options these are
some functions available here and so
what we will say is get us Instagram
Twitter and telegram account so here
what I want is to see accounts on
different social media and let's say
November takes us a minute it says so so
go grab a cafe well we will not be
grabbing a coffee but I rent here it is
working right so here you have it you
see let's see whether it moves and so it
gives gathering and posting the generals
that it's finding will stop here but you
know that you get the information that
we collected again telegram Twitter
Facebook as well as Instagram we will
test the features of tea Forex in a
visual way this world magnet he'll
allows for a distraction of this
remaining of this information buffer
sells views as so screenshots and user
distraction we'll see that later but Tim
Felix is much more info leak is much
more powerful
well actually magnetics excellent and
later you will seem the power in that
too
now what I'll do is I'll use my own
laptop let's run
Timberlake so that you see some features
so this is magnetic we're we've got the
users here this is telegram that was for
you our else abstraction that are being
shared so we would get Twitter messages
and some specific accounts this is all
distracted magnetic one of the resulted
produces is a file where we have all
these users right yes well in order to
optimize and dynamize what we've done is
we've extracted it and within has a
dater and she he can process it
Australia and see if we can see it I
don't see here you can we alright
see now let's be realistic and okay kick
the air okay
or else the front road doesn't it to
take so to believe what we say let's try
this or else I will run it blindly
so I'll run it from here I'll explain
what I do next but same here you cannot
really see but what I'll do is as I said
wood used in phallic created a few years
ago and it's evolved what we had
well what our version has not been
released yet but it'll be released and
if you've seen version 2.4 is similar it
has a graph in graphic interface and it
allows for so many operations and you
can look into Twitter and then have the
same results that can be whatever CS Evy
performance or other output formats so
what we'll do is starting with those
users on Magneto
so following these channels close to
terrorists so they're potential users by
the way let me say something I forgot to
mention we said but when we talk about
different types of channels apart from
mass media for propaganda
we have channels for sale of weapons
merchandising specific channels
Tec channels that helps others learn how
to use girl targeted Oh tunnels where
sometimes gave or whatever so when you
drag all that information post it within
that information you can find but
there's one person on a given channel
we're a radical that may be first and a
link from BBC al mundo all those
newspapers where they refer to the
attack and I've seen these piece of news
and the BBC so they ask half-wit tenant
so there's also enhanced debates but
maybe what take town and claimed the
attack and if not um so you see there is
this internal debate sorry sorry about
my intrusion actually
so users can be active so we have
Twitter accounts and these get shut down
quite fast maybe not as fast as we would
like but thousands of users produced I
have been important to Timberlake and
one of the features it has so it's been
limited for this and demo only ten so it
uploads all ten users here yes to see
the proof of concept so out of a
thousand as you can see well some are
non-existent now so there's not an
existing user Niners still active so we
can go to Twitter and visit each profile
but doing so manually when we have
thousands and thousands of users it's
not doable it's not realistic so we can
upload it here and we can have a clear
overview fast overview of these users
features and on the profile pictures
background picture that kind of gives us
indications on the kind of users they
don't really need to be profiles of
interest to us because here you see some
such a sports person news agency maybe
they are just referring to a piece of
news but that's not what we're
interested in so we should also consider
that these are very volatile these are
accounts which usually have only few
followers and little interaction so we
will curate we have thousands of users
and let's filter out
those that have ten followers 100
followers sorry so we do filter and we
find he/she one has no follower and ha
is following no one and this other one
has 57 followers this is the username
and their own features so out of those
that we've seen we could select some
this one that has no picture this other
one has a picture but this other one
doesn't even have a profile picture a
background picture with this second one
let's see what's going on let's pick it
up load it into our interface and the
tool allows you to look into three
larger groups so if we have three
targets first group would be about a
user profile seeing who they're related
to what about the followers apps they're
using time postings second group it beam
looking into specific geographical
locations of Walternate finally what's
happening at our March or a protest or
somewhere why there's been an attack we
want to see well the time is the hours
before the attack and everything else
and we can get information from there
and maybe it is through we're focusing
on the hardest terrorism but let me
highlight these informations is that
analysis can be replicated elsewhere in
other context settings maybe the
reserved advertising campaign and see
the impact we're not given district
years of them of that kind and then
there's a third group to look into info
like team Felix re and that is global
timeline so it's not a profound that we
have it's not a location that we have
but we want to see for example
information regarding words mentioned
with a cache
who's talking to him and get the
conversations out so when we don't have
a clear idea and it's all a bit bird
blurred so we had users and as part of
the users we chosen some that we thought
would be interesting for our
investigation and so what we're going to
do is okay first of all let's well we're
interested in finding out contacts so
this is the account information first of
all we'll get that every information
produced here is all the big leaves and
pictures and teeth CSV as well can be
sent to visualization for do you have
graphs so here we have this user
the location can be tampered with but
well here we have Saudi Arabia 57
followers and just one Twitter post and
this was done in June and once this is
new information and is still an active
account as for the cases that we will
discuss today I don't want you to have a
number of users or a specific case I
just want you to understand it globally
you need to understand same as we said
before Telugu it uses backup channels
built at a given time and published they
yes created them they store the content
and when needed it is posted
Twitter's the same they have the count
built maybe they haven't published a
theme for they can close it down fast
and well there is an incidence or an
attack or a claim that account gets the
avatar and I'm content and disseminates
for long as it can it's true
here we would like to see what the
environment of the user as you can see
there's barely any follower only little
information shared but there is a
feature on this tool to see who the
contacts are people that have interacted
with them so we can understand that the
information of prettiest and we would
see that would be users that are aware
of each other's existence so these are
in interest maybe it's not that they are
following each other about they post
seed or replied or any other kind of
operations such as adding them to a list
maybe didn't write them to them but
added to a list with a given description
where there are other users that share
given ideology so what we'll do is
we will what limit versus bro this is
real time this is right now let's narrow
it down the number of contacts and so
now we are looking into it get
information out of surfers friends but
as I said before if it's been added to a
list or if this user who is included who
what users have included our target and
to their list were this reading a
mention if someone has said the message
or can reply so we'll see what we have
this is a list of users this is done
fast and we have every detail here we
see the relationship towards our target
that we got and what it has to do with
everything else so we have followers and
friends and people they've interacted
with and that have been included in some
list and so we have the users ID we have
the background picture at any given
point we can click on the user and we
can see the profile or the twit post and
little movement here see only few
followers little activity would start up
very much to what we would say as in
that's how much interesting followers or
friends or lists I will focus on
messages rather let's see who the user
has interacted with here you see that
just by clicking and filtering those
that have had some kind of relationship
we see the picture their user
so this first one if you don't speak
Arabic that'd be easier for you but here
we see a twit sent by a user rich we
didn't tweet for a Maori target let's
check it out and is it I can not speak
Arabic Arabic bad let me translate it
for year using Google with Google
Translate not reliable but at least we
will get an idea war the messages so
here what it says is a
if it's a I can an Islamic connection
they should not be charged with
terrorism a kind of a message that might
mean nothing or maybe it does we are
interested in it because it's about an
event recent event all right
so following on this profile the one to
be reached from the previous one so
these are clips and pictures published
and there you could get automatically
all that content out to look into it
later on but let's visualize it because
right before the presentation it was
working and I wanted to comment and add
[Music]
lots of pictures and cleaved
well there are references to bumps here
might be interesting right it gives us
extra information so I cannot copy paste
this one but with mag metal will see how
that weave will look into this picture
that we can download we feed it onto
magnetic and with OCR techniques now
that several techniques it is stretched
information minds it out translate it
and then we can perform searches on it
that will expedite sense all right back
to the tool we can keep pulling the
thread rich other users and other
followers with them and get the list of
the followers for a given user we could
see what topics are being discussed I
don't know the first 40 words mostly
used on a given day we can use those
filters and when we can filter per date
for a verb for number of tweets which
include a keyword or another one that
has been published on a given app for
example published from Instagram or
Android or iPhone and with multimedia
content that can be retreated so there
are several parameters what about words
for the last two weeks that's what's
preset that's the default value butter
we can choose whatever we want
from five years ago because we want to
check out a specific time that's
important because that way as I've said
before we can look into something that
has already happened and Paris attacks
that was Friday the 13th
some years ago so there was an analysis
back then of what was going on
so the broke into the area or the
locations where the attacks had happened
as you probably remember there had been
several attacks at several locations
simultaneously all miscellaneous list so
we can mine those locations out mind the
contents are actually wig out videos and
pictures that is right before that and
that's
the attacks on the soccer stadium their
videos from just a few minutes before
and maybe on the video with someone of
interest a person of interest and see
who they were with whether they had a
backpack or maybe a red jacket so you
can imagine that would be information
that we're interested in analyzing and
accessing what else can we find
information on protected accounts which
maybe you can't access the profiles not
so much the case is that we've told you
about right now so far and yet there are
different types of investigations
for instance in social engineering pen
testing or analysts who want to go
deeper into detail for a private
individual so we might be able to access
accounts that are protected and then see
maybe user activities in this particular
case here what's been the activity in
the last year
let's run a search and let's see what we
can find this particular user not very
interesting only one trees had been
posted but we can check and see if he
retweets horse videos or images or at
what times of day or nice so that that
might give us a clue of where they're
located geographically located trying to
guess if he tweets at night or during
the day so the most interesting area as
we said at the beginning of the
presentation for us is that area where
the physical world and the virtual world
overlap imagine I start with a Twitter
account in 2015 but I become a radical I
abandon my friends I make new
acquaintances and if I go back on time
if the police goes back and takes my
account
well they might come to that conclusion
and find some more signs and indications
for them to devise a particular
hypothesis and eventually find somebody
of interest right we were telling you
about this user that we had found
indirectly through another user let me
just run a demo here for you to get an
idea how we can extract the multimedia
content this is the user
and I'm now going to extract multimedia
contents only focusing on say the last
50 tweets this man posted in this case
the system is going quite fast
downloading images and videos and
associated details and this is what we
would see for instance images of videos
that have been posted which application
he used for those posts if it was
multimedia content that were a response
some other some other user who likes or
how many likes or retweets and who by or
seeing where the content originally came
from at what time if it was straight
afterwards or maybe the following day
all of us they can give us some clues as
to where the contents have been posted
is it just very quickly for you to get
an idea I wanted to show you that
example so we could do something that is
for the last five years say and those
images could then be analyzed by magneto
okay we can talk a little bit more about
this too if we have additional time at
the end I hope that you're getting an
idea of what kind of work we do
as author of Tim Foley geolocation was
really valued at the beginning
extracting information and then using
Google Earth and that's interesting
right true but there's more than that
using public information because there's
information that doesn't depend on us if
I see a tweets sorry if I post a tweet
because I like running for instance and
I post something and the police would
know if they investigate me that I have
that application that I use that
application for running oh dear
unfortunately the large screen doesn't
seem to be working as a shame
okay the presentation now continues
talking about Thimphu leak and I just
want to encourage you to download it and
to make comments that will hopefully
contribute to make it better not only
that there are different Linux
possibilities whether it's Kali well a
number of them along
Osen turks so if you're familiar with
one of those you can use that particular
version or you might want to have a look
at the most recent version that I have
on my repository if you access my
website out there I don't know if those
smaller screens are working
maybe we can enlarge glass so you can
see it's a little bit better using the
full screen that's better now this
uh hora locum or Fisto hasta este
momento ha sido como okay so magnet oh
you can see has extracted some profiles
for us in this case Twitter was our main
interest so the extraction is very
similar to what Tim for leaks does
generating a particular type of file and
again we want to see that overlapping
area where the physical world interacts
with the virtual world we're going to
see that with information and very
visually after processing the
information the tool then needs to know
what specifications we want to give it a
for it to work in one particular way or
another you see we need to specify here
because it's an open source tool we can
give all the information on profiles
that we've investigated or well not
investigated sorry dragged really so we
can then investigate them well what we
do then is importing them graphically so
that through network analysis techniques
we can then see visually see that
interaction that overlapping area that
we saw between those two circles
[Music]
I'm sorry
ahsoka I was having some rough Oh static
OH
in this case we're going to see a static
graph so first of all we get information
from different profiles communicating
amongst them that's all we had and then
because we had raw data you can't tell
what the network looks like which
elements we want to go into more detail
into but now look at that oh there
the mouse doesn't seem to like me I want
to zoom in but I don't seem to manage so
what we're trying to do now if I manage
I'm going to stop it first and then try
again but anyhow the idea is that
depending on the information that we
gave we've given it it seems to have
crashed but anyhow just to give you an
idea every one of those dots is a
twitter user and then the lines are
messages that are shared posts that are
shared and where that goes you can see
that others on the top left there are
great big nodes with a lot of friends
or followers and depending on what the
theme is for that particular post well
we might then select out of the maybe
thousands of users maybe seven or eight
that we think might be potentially
interesting apologies because the
interactive infographics didn't work but
you we just wanted you to understand it
that it really helps us understand the
history and fluctuations of a particular
communication system so let me try and
show you now a little bit the same thing
but more visually because the previous
graph it was a little bit static right
it was a given point in time you don't
see who follows who for instance over
time so
show you now we have that head well
that's our user and in that white dots
there is content whatever type so
depending on the extension of those
contents that are posted that can give
us a good idea of what type of content
they are being tweeted whether it is
images or videos or what and then the
green ray that stands for the type of
dissemination or transfer so you see
different people sharing contents in
this case images you see how that
spreads out they come and go different
messages different images and that goes
on and on to give us an idea of the time
involved in those connections
this is like a slow-motion version just
for you to get an idea of how it works
for you to efficiently or and truly
understand the power of what this can-do
vamos a ver lament a como Syria Esai
fusion pore over como algunos alimentos
en este caso prehab lo que hace via como
el es sólo a formado este grupo de como
a fun do to s taken tenido sol
comenzamos interior meant a como una
sola persona de acuerdo puede go hair
mr. nadir esos diverso al canal de los
cuales si puedo server como de fundin
diverses personas diferente contree doe
en cambio y otras como para hey bleep
way ver como este peso knobhead aquí el
sol la si esta esta Hernando el canal
poder como se bah poka poka Momofuku
Ando como Bank rondo sido diferentes
canals con say bang creando la
diferentes
yes tipo de Caen tenido que van - Hondo
Mara te puedes fish armisen uno de fer
tipo akin our REO demos como
hypereosinophilic mile otros a la square
antigua tambien man fusion de la franja
or aria de caña eun-suh says oh no que
debe ser de interés a que podemos hacer
con owes podemos yo viendo lo y ver como
en toda terminado puede ver con este
tipo de de fun phenomenon ptosis repair
a Carlos yes L AM la indeed este año
para todos de estrella sido la totally
da de lo que Mo's comment' abba Presidio
de los cuatro millones de Madiba - yo
dementia 'has a que lo que se ha sido
utilidad una forma grafica vara especial
meant a para esta para este anuncio
como como interlock to von Maur a como
se vamo viendo como como fluke - Aniki
say Varian comme un canal Avanza como
crease a moscow samira steve o el
contenido mara demos Elton Lonny podemos
your cam Biondo la fecha yo invention
when total monado komova lucy Oren SI
fuera Mo's see decimos que tenemos
tiempo y que hacemos que pase todo todo
el el perrito say durante podríamos o
serve our como scab si el el árbol Syria
siendo
cada vez más importante
for mando estos una forma de forma
visual yo okay most Oviedo ver como de
forma estatic a sonido grande Oh aquí
está Claro Akio yopo domina pother zoom
podo Brio Mendo terminada ver un tipo
una y de que pueden teresa por el tipo
de Caen tenido por el tipo de mensaje
que pueden buscar esto por ahem no Tommy
no PO hacer de hacer for my globe are
para esta presentation de todo lo que
sería telegram say Puerta mentaiko con
to eat se passe semente con un carro del
Pacifico se passe suru no Suvari o para
ver el tipo de Caen tenido como como
interaction a con con los demás
personaje de della della red ahi ahi ho
estamos viendo el tech Mandy todo este
she knows me knows I do mo Vera a mess
concrete o UN official news interesa
Eva fear pono percent rest a DI stevia
como Sam Oviedo cuando se que este canal
okay my canal estimate eCos a aramean
tha's element analysis mess compresses
la mayoría so ESO de pavo donde la forma
visuals para see de pero te permit a
permit a fuccinelli dades como imagine
our own ambassador datos yeah padilla y
SI righto lament ando al alamin Tondo
para poder o tener monitor monado uni
Stojko essa de información para la que
NOS Cohen Tod O's la segunda parte cake
wanted Ora Mara yaki
so here see tip I hope you can see that
okay
we saw the process dynamically earlier
and now this is the static version on
this graph what is particularly
interesting for as well each one of
those dots would be a user is a user
posting and disseminating contents so if
I don't have enough resources to
investigate all those profiles what
should I do
well logically focus on those that I
consider are the main notes and then I
might say right I want to focus on
spanish-speaking channels or a
particular thematic channel and then I
would be really effective right so I as
the same
as we can study how it all works we can
also see heat maps for instance for a
time of day seeing how many messages
were posted at that particular time I
don't know if you can see it now you
need to move on to the next one is that
working now now it's stuck on the
slide it's not our day right today
not technically speaking anyway
well he's a cadaver and Avila you know
Amy already suffered other selects
available in the fuel
how does he see Molly early working with
us now he's working so as I said we
could see changes and fluctuations on
different channels and here we see a
heat map if we want to focus on a
particular time of a particular day and
see how many messages were posted or
shared and so on we can do so also
focusing on a particular channel like
Twitter or a particular user or the time
of day or nice well we know that user is
most active that's that's interesting so
that I can keep an eye at those times
can you tell them a little bit about
space that's true I'd forgotten about
that can you see that gap there between
let May and late June there's like a gap
of information and when we first looked
at that heat map
I remember we said hang on a minute why
our message is missing from that period
of time
well that was Ramadan that's what it was
and on the social media people were
asked to use the social media less in
this case it was telegram so they could
abide by Ramadan more more self so that
kind of heat map can give us clues and
so that we can go from data and facts
and figures to true intelligence
so as I said we need to with this we can
hopefully track and find the most
relevant individuals we've been talking
about user profiles that we might be
interested in monitoring right so now
how can we get information from the
contents they post or share in this case
our website we can see this website in
Spanish it was a shooting competition
they were talking about so this is a
case of propaganda they're advertising a
shooting course and explaining how
they've gone about it in the past then
on their next section they talked about
bias and how they look after their
members and followers because when we
talk about propaganda it is not just
them saying they should go and cut
people's heads off they also talk
wonderful things about themselves
sometimes messages are texts often in
Arabic with hashtags so he can then be
shared and reposted and retweeted
or so that users can find them more
easily one of those images is a threat
in the case of the Barcelona terrorist
attack the other one talks about shehide
training camps in Iran sometimes
documents look more like this where
there is an X excel sheet or a txt
excels often have to do with the
so-called
kill lists that is lists of individuals
they were there they want to target and
eliminate are those kill lists
objectives sometimes they've hacked
public organizations and published those
lists or posted those lists in this case
if I have an American company that sold
instruments and they dumped that
database under fortunately ten Spanish
nationals were included on that list so
when you monitor profiles we also try
and be proactive as much as possible we
depending on what information we find
for instance we found this file where
Spanish Nationals
might be in danger or it's a threat
right well we want to make the most of
that and act upon it in the case of the
Spain IP file wow that was a die
a pro - channel because there are cases
where channels are not there on behalf
of actual practitioners sometimes they
just published propaganda or sometimes
they give them logistical support and
some 60,000 IPs were published in this
case a threat of remote desktop
vulnerability I said at the beginning of
my presentation that they love posters
and they posed in different languages
Spanish is one of the most popular
languages I also said it earlier that
they also publish handbooks and
instructions about how to encrypt
communications the one here on the right
for instance
explained step-by-step how to build this
device a very simple device but it can
actually make a train derail
if you wonder would a follower go home
and build something that isn't do
something like that just a couple of
weeks later after this was posted there
were a number of incidents in Catalonia
where large boulders were positioned on
the rail tracks so sometimes they don't
copy exactly what was proposed but they
adapted at the top we see the video with
no time for authorship of the
Barcelona's terror the Barcelona
terrorist attacks and the one down below
is a video explaining how to manufacture
chemical weapons
they also use browser extensions this is
a program they used in the past for
communications encryptions some
indoctrination publications or posts in
this case on how to find IPS or phone
phone books or and also explaining to
their members how to increase their
communications and data in this case
Bitcoin addresses were posted why well
because they want to access financial
resources so we've been talking about
files and images and audio and video
because in the age of big data what they
do is try and use all that information
turn into intelligence and that's what
we try and do as well to understand what
they're doing so because there are so
many messages and information that we
need to monitor I I knew time ago that I
we needed an application to be able to
handle all of that and that's why I
designed magnet all this application so
that I can find the most extract the
most interesting part of all that
information and one of the main elements
that we often identify with social media
are phone numbers so I'm going to show
you now how a phone numbers can be
extracted from social medias so social
media
we want to try and get as much
information as possible from what we can
access that's right because sometimes it
might be something small
well it looks more right a phone number
or a picture that might give us the clue
for to move ahead in our investigations
works and we'll see some of the elements
that I have visible now we have a few
more features but it didn't fit into my
display so I had to shorten it what if
we are interested in is mining phone
numbers are fears of what we can ask is
the kind of information of prefixes that
we're interested in here what we have is
let's try what we are most interested in
here that would be Spain so let's see if
we have a Spanish Paris that we can get
out of the database since we've been
recording who will mask the numbers so
that they cannot be identified so here
you can see there are seven phone
numbers from Spain that can be located
on this medium so 33 I think that's
France again well we have some first
this is the very last year that's right
but all the data again yeah this is the
same last year but what information can
we get we are interested in the phone
numbers I'm from here onwards we see
there are different techniques and with
the phone number you can reach users
social media all the kinds of
information so there is an interesting
element here as we said before at the
beginning of this presentation and that
is the large number of people arrested I
think I didn't say it but most of the
people arrested were from Morocco first
or second generation and so we will try
to find those phones from Morocco and
why is that we see there are a few of
those why because that's easy for them
they can keep using Moroccan numbers in
Spain and then we've through the contact
network whether it is family or friends
they can still get money on the card
from from the source country
what about the US yeah that's right
it's rain only a few would show maracas
there were many more and and then the US
so we've said so it is easy to use those
virtual numbers because most of the
virtual numbers are from the United
States but if we check how many numbers
start with a one that it is the prefix
for the US we see there are a few of
those and that's where we see that there
are some that use their own phone number
and that's an indication the area code
that's an indication we need to work
with but we can produce a list with it
so we've said and I've said Vicente said
how after analyzing different kinds of
profiles whether in Twitter or telegram
we have twitter we have in steam for
leaks and magnetic so there is tracking
of users followers and also pictures are
mined out not just a profile but those
posted because maybe a text we miner
find something relevant on text but we
can follow keywords and have a list of
words that we might be interested in to
have constant monitoring and here we
might be interested in reading or
interpreting the pictures that are being
posted using old sphere or other
mechanisms this is a real example that
it was processed we mined the contact
and so this is not we have blue shades
and we have pictures and there's a whole
range in there and from there onwards
there's the first mining and then we
translate it and that's when we can
based on the kind of search we want to
conduct I will be able to see if any of
those profiles that well because of the
user name or maybe the profile that we
didn't find interesting but with an
automated analysis of the pictures
posted it could be interesting here you
have
because they claim the attack in
Barcelona the same way here as we see
this kind of a content we've also said
there are some posters here what we see
is well see this
we have Messi what an Emer here you have
the information available in English and
you can read the image the picture
interpreted and from their own roots
with different filters so if I use Messi
as a keyword we said that already
these are not just about what so these
are tools that can use for detection of
these profiles but also to detect
brands or other kinds of information
that you can find a useful so here you
have a test that I will run for you if I
manage this is what we said before let's
try and find what we come from pictures
so we said the attack of mouse on all
right we've mention it so of all of
those pictures this try and see if in
any of those pictures not as text but
actually embedded text let's try and see
if they show Barcelona right so if it
all works out for us should give us yeah
it does
ok so it should stop at some point here
I showed you the string it interprets
the picture so there's a world there is
a sky diagram and the text from the
picture it seems to be in English but
then the translation this is what we
have this is a map of Europe as
translated from 2017 and so
if I get the URL and I'll look it up see
this is a world map and there's not such
information published here so see this
is Spain in small print it says
Catalonia and Barcelona if I had looked
up Madrid probably that but been similar
all right next one same thing here so
first interpretation probably Arabic
right so it's structured like this it
says it's advertised and it's a poster a
butter and it says that was the cutest
operations that says thumbs let's get
the easiest one get the URL and search
through the database and see what what
is it it's making a fool of me
so it's 4.5 million messages and imagine
what it would be like to do so manually
it is not doable to have so many people
translators and people just downloading
images and pictures on going through all
of them this cannot be first one I've
read it so
we haven't read this but what was it
nine darkness and here you had materials
Barcelona's struggle video so
distraction here you can see that it
helps you add is an indication that can
help you see this so if you've got this
kind of a picture or a rather profile
that would be it if you're sharing these
link and this claim of Barcelona's
attack so that it would be interesting
to monitor it all right can you see this
can you so also following the process
what we find interesting is metadata
I haven't said yet by telegram what it
does is it's a deletes metadata from
pictures but not from other documents
with that in mind we've all said so
utilize in the oh the overlap in between
physical world and virtual worlds
usually when you set up your office
server old windows rather you have a
username and here's something that you
will something that describes your site
and they will say hello covers but most
applications were the word or PDF it
embeds it and so here let's see here for
example you see how on the top of it you
have the app the author of all files and
with this name this Arabic this is a
headline when it's been change and with
that trying to gather information number
of users and then different social media
with the different apps that we are
familiar with and that's
how we find out other social media where
the NICUs is used doesn't mean that this
is the evil bad guy here but this is an
indication that will help us and with
that you can have an email address and
maybe access to other services and then
all around the environment and the
setting it's about pulling the thread
once again connecting the dots as it is
says let me give you another example
often when you're on a channel or medium
and looking for a profile you come
across information which visually isn't
useful anymore
magnetic could use could be used here
but visually we realize that after an
attack in the family say in France
there's this medium that posted a
picture well a piece of news I didn't
know whether you can say I see that but
if you check out the picture it is not a
photograph it's not been done bloated
but it's not been downloaded from the
internet it was just a home TV picture
so they've taken it from their home to
be and that's a Spanish TV and this was
all Arab Arabic so one of the
administrators is in Spain so we see the
number of resources and social media
that we need to come through
so it is simpler to focus and some
channels and we already said are there
different kinds of channels one of which
would be weapon sales I think I've said
it before it's not just about following
targets was actually you need to try and
be ahead of them and see how they work
and how can you make the most of it and
take some advantage and this looks like
an ambulance right I don't really know
why but it got my attention if I look at
it
in further detail I realized that it was
from Granada so had been taken down to
Syria or Iraq or wherever the ambulance
was but the same as with this one there
was another one from Viteri in northern
Spain in case you don't know one of the
systems they follow for attacks
terrorist attacks would be a small one
in a public space and emergency services
go there to help victims and law
enforcement and ambulances and they go
investigate and there's a fake one it's
a forgery filled with explosive and once
the ambulance is there in the area they
kill themselves and the damage is
greater
not just for civilians but mainly mainly
military and police forces this is
another example we've set it already
this has to do with the hackers and
there's a list as we said with
vulnerable IPs where we can see there's
the 60% that were very vulnerable to
remote desk attacks and we could see
there was the public company Korea red
and there were some that were with the
ministry for defence and so we try to be
proactive and these are data that we can
use but when we got the this information
we reported so that they could check
whether those IPS will probably set up
you know that you avoid other problems
we've talked about Twitter and telegram
but let's talk about Facebook sometimes
it's not just what we said before it's
not just using tools while this was a
dissemination activity in 2017 the
French authorities were searching for
this person we've just crushed out they
redacted the name because they thought
it would he was a conflict returnee and
there was a threat and after this first
picture I tried to find information on
several social medium here I found a
piece of information that I found was
him interesting on Facebook so this is
the picture and it might seem that is
quite dissimilar to the person right but
if you pay closer attention what we
realize is that the picture by the
French authorities is just a cut-off of
the profile Facebook picture so at least
we know that this Facebook profile is
what they are looking after that's what
the French authorities are looking at
before sorry we keep on on social media
and we find another profile quite
similar but not clear about it different
name different location different
country so it's not just about using
tools but also the expertise and
analysis techniques we have three
pictures here's we might say that this
is what I have and this is the same
person and this is the Facebook profile
and this is what's published by the
French authorities this from the right
side are the overlapping ones are the
same so we give this here
so if we start
again we can see some features we see
there is a freckle right above the
eyebrow
well it seems it could help us identify
him
so both left and right pictures show an
interesting eyebrow end and if we check
another feature another freckle or a
mole next to the nose we see there is a
perfect match and without a expertise
forensic report so we might still see
that this is the same person and also
the the the kind of the beard and it's
an indication this is Van Dyck veers an
indication and why is it so interesting
because in the profile he was using he
said that he was living in córdoba
córdoba southern Spain so if he's on the
run and had been living in Cordova it
might be that that's at a given point he
could be in court about to try have
support from his friends and kin they
for suppose did Bitcoin addresses not
usual but sometimes they do publish it
in order to try and get some funding as
you know a bitcoin is traceable and with
that what we do is learning that account
where does it get the money from
what other accounts are feeding it and
as you can see from for
here we have the character flow or
string brother and even if we don't see
the income deadlines or times but still
four check for cut from four times they
got money coming in so if we see the
arrow they paid back to the so called
mother account starting with a fifteen
if we do look into the other accounts I
don't know if you can see but those have
a circle where the first account that
paid to the mother can but each of these
accounts in turn has gotten money or has
withdrawn money which indicates walked
we all know and we said it at the
beginning you might have used social
media or an alias that even if you
change in three sub history there's a
background but so you've tried to
analyze I even have it on Facebook but
you can also have searchers in different
areas different places to try and see if
any of this has been published and from
there try to D anonymizer first possible
this kind of a transaction in the end
well this is all about is trying to
weather with magnetic in it team for
leagues or whatever the type of
mechanism
it's about finding with same as with the
Oh st. or sacrament or you mint these
are techniques they will always be
complementary it will be a support but
it might help us get some clues and
science show in to us the light to try
and find a profile or Trainmen and
monitor some items to be proactive and
not wait just wait for that kind of
attacks or threats anything else
think we're doing right in time okay
yeah and we've nail it haven't we
so this is what we wanted to say there's
not just about social media but actually
it's a matter of time dedication and so
we need to understand that we need to
use tools and methodologies but also our
analyst skills is important to try and
distract that because that would end
with that product that is then finally
delivered as we know for us thank you
very much for your attendance
[Applause]
[Music]
you