[Music]
you
love it up close for booty yo
bigger uno mas out as you can see Allah
blows over understand Dakota
[Applause]
segundos voice ah como Dondo empezamos
dia who la première and relative
premiers knows almost directamente i
crea Comique first press well now we
move on to crea comic we have three
pathologies junior people below 70 years
old the price given to the winner is
photographic printer and our winner is
Angela
because
[Applause]
give a hug - what do you
congratulations in Korea comic we also
have this group between 8 and 13 years
old the price will be also a
photographic printer and the winner is
[Music]
Vinita risco Medina congratulations
is he around big applause for him now I
can see that Olivia Melek Monica has
arrived please come up to the stage so
it's time to ask questions our winners
yes actually we were not talking to the
voice of the attendees that were in the
family area enjoying all the activities
congratulations to all our winners so
tell us how did you enjoy summer camp
and what have you learnt about service
security it's just a know what to answer
to be honest didn't about cyber security
these days well I learned
you
since and now the two of you here now in
this stage how did you experience these
things so you have a good time oh yes we
did have a really good time as well as
good fun we enjoyed all the activities
the championships the presentations all
the talks very very interesting also
with learned loss about cybersecurity
this event has been comprehensive very
complete week well has been very helpful
to everyone so now we now have clear
comment in here
for seller Pia congratulations
congratulations have to do feel when I'm
a bit anxious because I see so many
people in the room where I can say that
I'm extremely happy surely do the savage
enjoy it
big applause for him now with which
category Hakkasan prices
[Music]
mentioned to best team of students has
will be next generation tablet uber
notes they are the winners
[Applause]
Oh hoist spokesperson here
well what was your security protocol
communicating a mobile phone with an
electronic device and what does this
price mean to you well I doesn't know
well okay I'll answer that well we are
very thankful to to the organizer for
giving us the opportunity to take part
in these events to take part in these
competitions it is a way for us to prove
what we can do to show what we can do
also then a lot for many many other
people and also make friends okay and
that God thank you very much
congratulations big applause for them
and now we move on to third prize
Ultrabook that's the prize and the
winner unique content
[Applause]
just until you told us that it was the
first time that you were participating
that you were real excited about it how
do you feel now well we are extremely
happy well actually we were not
expecting it it's a big surprise will
you come back next year well we would
like to of course all right I wish you
all the best second prize goes to well
professional laptop price goes to film
congratulations
[Music]
[Applause]
congratulations have a seat man can you
tell us about this hard work ongoing
work well it has been intensive this has
been kind of him one marathon actually
hackathon so we are very very proud to
have achieve we achieved okay of the
development that we made okay we made
important relevant decisions key
decisions and that was took us well yeah
I would like to thank the university of
málaga especially those of you of us who
are following specialization in
cybersecurity I would like to thank our
teachers they have encouraged a larger
game and with will have to submit a
malware analysis ok papers so hopefully
I will be right on time tomorrow of the
best and now number one number one
we never hackathon gaming laptop goes to
a security bug
congratulations
[Applause]
[Music]
so how do you feel I'm very happy now
I'm relaxed
yesterday's it was high tension a big
tension so the level of hackathons Asia
was very very high all the participants
were of high level hackathon is grown
alas is becoming increasingly important
competition I would like to thank the
organizers everything has been crates
soda press all the way to here at no
cost whatsoever device gave us the
opportunity to be here we've been
treated very well and we are extremely
happy and also I would like to thank the
help that we received from other service
activity experts congratulations
so congratulations
and now we move on to the last set of
prices its EF 5th position would be next
in duration tablets and goes to rivera
ma congratulations crystal so
congratulations crystal how did you feel
and how did you get ready to come up to
here when it is the first time that I
take part seeing the tissues who
actually has been quite intensive had
worked eight hours come round and round
our game thinking and I'm very very
happy I was not expecting it and I just
kind of believe it all right
[Music]
the freedom village with us can feel a
bit applause fourth price not rebuke
goes to adran de Paris for America dough
[Applause]
congratulations adren how do you feel
the competition yesterday what about the
test it was very wonderful interesting
all the testing lots of pressure lots of
tension has been really really good
congratulations and now
third prize laptop
surprise goes to force Ignacio Romero
also known as possible
congratulations which was the most
difficult challenge
well I solved many of them in two hours
but I was blocked for six hours okay
that was a big challenge as for the rest
everything went very well well would you
like to share a few words with us well
that was it okay once you win then you
generate expectations expectations that
are to be kept up in following years
okay we expect you to have respect to
happy back in fear next year second
prize soon Ultrabook for dinner
Raghava Don Tomas
also longer cereals
congratulations the challenge for Sperry
very tight to finished second how do you
feel I'm very proud of the work that I
did and all the training that I have
received during the year and I'm very
happy to be here and to have him here so
congratulations
[Applause]
another prize the winner will get a
professional laptop first prize goes to
Baja Martinez Dafa also known as the
father
congratulations
[Applause]
congratulations maja I guess it is an
honor to win a c TF is have a combo
doesn't mean to you well it is quite
important
CTF nationally and this is a door to get
to other assets we have some of world
recognition such as they've gone another
and I guess that I become will reach up
to that level in few years time I hope
that this is a platform that will help
you to get very very far big applause
for him
congratulations
will you please help out word to you to
come down pick up laws for wadiya
everyone in here everyone in the stage
have returned the state is yours
thank you very much
Cheryl good afternoon everyone we are
about to put an end to our cyber come
2018 over these four days Malaga has
became the capital city in the world of
cybersecurity people from Malaga and
Spanish people in general have
positively taking on boards our call our
invitation invitation to bring
cybersecurity closer to everyone to
everyone to our citizens and this is
unquestionable I have a number of
figures that proof that cyber come is
gaining momentum momentum which is
unstoppable more and more people become
increasingly interested in these events
which is just a big preference to raise
awareness of families about importance
of cyber security also to attract talent
all the more necessary in our country
and to face all the challenges that
cybersecurity poses as ongoing
increasing topic and field so I would
like to highlight the significant and
important participation of women as
sector as of data of cyber security has
been participated by many men than women
in the past we've seen many
participating women in hackathons and
other challenges as well as seen the
talks and as attendees so
congratulations is we are very happy for
that
once more hackathon has brought together
young talents families public in general
and again we have exceeded our
expectations one more year in our 28
in addition we have breaking a record in
terms of followers we've gone over the
figure of 20,000 followers both
one-to-one and remotely we organized 17
activities workshops talks cybersecurity
games and activities for families and
public will have has 64 outstanding
experts international speakers who have
shared the experience and know-how with
us they have encouraged us to continue
working in the field of cyber security
as well as sharing their knowledge with
us we have also broken record in Hakata
we had this cell 17 teams that have
reintroduced and submitted high-quality
propositions and actually I talked to
the jury and the jury had told us that
this is the year but they have received
the highest level propositions in CGS we
have had participation of 400 people
internationally and we had had the 45
best participants here in Malaga cyber
Olympics having participated is hereby
2232 schools accounting for nearly 1,700
students with ages between 14 and 18
years old another breaking record figure
this year so out of all these schools
they tell best participated in the last
stage of summer camp last Friday and
whose first prize was borne by the
secondary school effective raffle Agata
from Cadiz in the improvement forum we
had the participation of 20 companies
and 20 is academic institutions offering
200 jobs so those of you who are looking
for a job now it is very easy for you to
get a job this forum will continue open
up until the 10th of December encourage
you to visit it online and 67 people
have received
I advise to re pivot to the field of
cyber security and to be better prepared
to fellow or and to take a job interview
all these figures give us the fuel that
we need to continue working in the same
direction to bring cyber security closer
to citizens it is the time to thank you
for all your hard work
first of all I would like to send the
Council of the Council of Melaka for
opening the doors to us and when for
their supports thank you very much for
hosting these events Malaga as I say
consul of Malacca for giving us this
beautiful space - for our events i also
would like to thank all the experts that
have been with us for sharing their
experience expertise and reflections
with us i also would like to thank all
the entities all the companies and all
the professionals that have worked
really hard with us I have made cyber
camp possible this is not the work of
only of the professionals working at in
Syria I would like to thank all the
participants all the attendees everyone
who has participated in technical
competitions one more year we would like
to thank our contactor senator de
Alberta thank you very much for you work
congratulations
and also added an amazing people only
kavaja and the Libyan again for your
wonderful work we hope to have you back
in here and your teams in the future and
also our mascot booty your husband
around all the time moving all the time
this by the overweights so
we also would like to thank the media
for echoing these events for
disseminating each Cybercom with not
possible if it doesn't reach half
citizens we need media for that also the
36 Malaga schools I'm from Andalusia
that were with us for the first two days
of our event and of course one more year
I would like to deeply congratulate and
thank the whole team audience even for
their excitement for the great day for
some hard work to make this event even a
better event so still many challenges
ahead of us many many seven editions up
until the day we will retire I encourage
you to continue working with such a high
level of excitement and good teamwork
congratulations to meet this also and
not and a pleasure to work with all of
you thank you everyone congratulations
for the big success and success that
belongs to all of us Cybercom in civil
is under only project is a project is
not our project it's a project of all of
us working for the cybersecurity if you
have a country I'll see you back see you
back in 2019 and as a way to acknowledge
all the hard work I would like to play a
video where we see all the hard work
that has been made
[Music]
[Applause]
la vez pasada my lives original video
colobus pasado muy mal well we can see
in the video that you had a great time
so it is time for me to extend my thanks
to the organizers for inviting me one
more year to be part of this big family
a special thanks to do alberto director
general of infidel for trusting me one
more year for this new edition and i
would like to congratulate each and
every one of the people working in MTV
for the wonderful work that you have
carries out for the last four days and
for that trial work which is not visible
that no one mentions which is essential
to gain the success that we'll have
achieved in this fifth edition of cyber
camp thank you to my colleagues Olivia
and Monica for all the dissemination
work that they have carried out with the
joy and the excitement that
characterizes you I would like to thank
all the speakers for the wise knowledge
and know-how that they have shared with
us over four days I would like to thank
the technical teams our hostesses
everyone to make everything ready and
set at all times I would like to thank
my representative Isaac for all the
great care that he kind of gave to me
when my voice was kind of hacked so to
speak so I'd like to thank everyone the
public attendees and those all of you
following us on this dreaming because
all these make sense
thanks to you wouldn't make sense if you
won't be there
therefore we wait for you back in here
back in seven come 2019 the world is
changing at a really fast pace and we
should not be lagging behind
year time we would like to need to get
together again to continue having a good
time and to go and enjoy and experience
as beautiful as experience that we will
soon see in this video
[Music]
[Applause]
bueno muchisimas gracias never come
doesn't it
thank you everyone sever from 2018 has
reached this page because this stage is
a bit difficult for a family photograph
it will not be asking you to do that but
we will ask everyone to go outside
because there is a surprise waiting for
you as I think you everyone has seen the
backstrap edition
[Music]