[Music]
Cadell we wonder the administer the
quarter yield amok
good morning everyone welcome to our
fourth and last day for cyber camp 2018
we're starting the day today with the
winner of the Spanish seminar on
cybersecurity research they were the
winners of the last edition and exhibit
organizes that seminar with them because
in C Bay very much believes in the need
to do R&D and I and mikela Dube is here
to tell us about how to detect security
attacks in industrial networks and why
that environment is different from
others he is a lecturer at the
University of Montreal a warm round of
applause for Mika thank you so much
huggable
welcome thank you very much for coming
to my workshop and hackable
has very kindly introduced me and told
you that I'll be addressing how to
address security attacks in industrial
environments from my own viewpoint in my
own experience because in my research
I've been trying to compare how we've
been learning about security from
different points of view in different
environments and I've been looking into
all of us for my PhD dissertation I will
start my presentation tell you a little
bit about our research group I will tell
you why industrial environments are
different from
IT environments I will also tell you
about different contributions made over
time about industrial environments and
cyberattacks we heard about Stuxnet and
things have changed very very much since
then and I will finish my presentation
with some resources and guidelines there
for those who want to start research
about cybersecurity in industrial
environments we're very fortunate now
because compared to what was available
five six years ago we now have what a
lot of tools and resources so if you are
keen on this particular topic I will be
pointing out where you can look into it
I hope I hope we have time for a Q&A
session at the end of my presentations
but please I encourage you to stop me
and ask any doubts I want this to be
interactive I would like to hear your
feedback during my presentation where
needed as well so let's get started
as you know my name is Nicola Torben I
am a lecturer and researcher at the data
analysis and cybersecurity research
group at Mondragon
University so that's what we do we
analyze and try to secure data in
industrial environments trying to solve
issues connected with manufacturing
problems modelling apart
we're how to use less power in
manufacturing detecting attacks and
intruders consultancy for best practices
about how to better secure industrial
networks and so on
apart from that I'm also a member of the
euskal hack Association which is the
Association we have in the Basque region
on IT security and we also organize our
own conference at the end of June every
year so what is it that I do
specifically I did my PhD on industrial
intrusion detection and I was very lucky
because I was given the first award the
first prize at the J and IC seminar this
year I work with cyber security as you
know in industrial environments part in
fact in our group we always try to be
very very close to companies whether
it's industrial firms or cyber security
companies and here we can see up on the
list on the screen a list of recently I
also work with data analysis in
industrial firms although that takes up
less of my time preparing this workshop
I thought we should first cover the
brief overview of some of the industrial
attack detection approaches from an
industrial point of view as I say said
when I started my PhD things were pretty
different it's an area that's much more
mature that has matured very fast in the
last few years so before we get into the
nitty-gritty of this topic what is it
that I mean when I talk about industrial
environments are you familiar with this
or not very much so what is an
industrial control system well I'm
talking about systems that automate
control and administer or manage
physical equipment so in a manufacturing
plant for instance there is an
industrial control control systems so
we're talking about PLC's what we'll see
about that later on so when we talk
about critical infrastructures well
those are the ones we need for our daily
use of power and transport a critical
manufacturing and so on a lot of us is
automated processes connected with power
generation for instance that's all
automated so they've course these
industrial control systems that's very
much under control
automated controls and why is that
special or different because the main
objective of control systems is not
keeping something very confidential so
their main core objective is for the
process to continue to work
for instance in a thermal power station
what the main point for those systems is
for the power station to continue to
produce energy no matter what happens
their second objective has to do with
the real interaction these systems have
with the physical world so any problem
that may arise whether it's voluntary or
involuntary there are consequences in
the physical world whether it is
intentional or not there are
consequences like people being left
without power at home for however long
or a manufacturing plant not producing
their goods and maybe machinery being
ruined because of that so we have to be
particularly careful in industrial
environments problems don't just have
cyber consequences shall we say they
have real physical world consequences
and that's why security is even more
important so in industrial control
systems and we talked about PCs these
years SCADA systems there are different
systems
drue but they're all fairly similar so
when we secure these systems
brands and names of systems doesn't
matter that much so I will be talking
about industrial systems as if it was
all the same thing a distributed control
system in a TCS is different from a pcs
or from a SCARA
but I'll be referring to them as if it
was just one homogenous single group so
what does an industrial network look
like well it's very very much a vertical
structure divided into very well-defined
layers at the bottom we would have the
process that needs to be controlled that
is hardware and physical environment and
motor with sensors and whatever all
those pieces of equipment and devices
and physical systems and hardware so
that would be the foundations at the
bottom of that stack then we would have
controllers getting information from
there the layer before so that they can
then ask and make machines do whatever
for instance imagine we have in a
catering firm a large pressure cooker
making soup
so in that boiler pressure cooker or
whatever it is if the temperature rises
over and above a particular threshold
then the heat it would have to come down
and that's what the controller is
checking for it to work we will see that
the main control system in industrial
environments our PLC's what our other
control systems would we have there over
and above that in the same layer and we
would have the SCADA controllers is like
the supervising layer because we have
controllers down below in charge of less
important tasks and then the higher
layer in charge of them more advanced
controls then we have data historians
gathering and recording all that
information so that it's available for
whoever needs it whether it is to keep
an inventory or what or or whatever and
then we would have the human machine
interface HMI checking that the process
is working in a high on a higher layer
so we're talking about rather complex
systems mostly in critical
infrastructures and facilities which
means that operators have to be
supervising everything works correctly
24/7 non-stop operators people who check
if the PRC's for instance I can't
respond well to a particular threat well
then operators would take charge and
have control of the system of the
otherwise automated system
this is a PLC which is the core of
industrial networks is the heart and so
they're in charge of first scale control
this is not a new modern PLC it says
been working for a number of years and
look at all the inputs and outputs on
that b LC well they gather information
from the field then they're in charge of
distributing information to the field as
well or for instance to open or close
flows all those actions would be done
they would have
Ethernet connectivity more and more
these days so that they can then
communicate with the layers up above but
anyhow PLC's are the main leading
character as it were in this story for
those of you who are used to this type
of hardware well we're talking about
remember is not Giga size but mega size
with very limited processing power and
very very expensive believe me why
because they have to work in very harsh
environments surrounded by dust by very
harsh industrial environments and
logically we want to have them last at
least as long as the production line is
going to be operating so I'm talking
about lasting maybe a life of 10 15 20
years then the HM eyes human-machine
interfaces they're supervising up above
that everything is working correctly so
that's a brief over line of how
industrial networks work so what happens
if something goes wrong and I'm not
talking about science fiction I'm
talking about when things have gone
wrong what happens then the first
instance in that we know about about an
attack to an industrial network in fact
it's a little bit fuzzy it was back in
1982 we're not even sure if it actually
happened it was an oil pipe in what was
the Soviet Union still at the time there
was an explosion and one of the
hypothesis was that the software that
controlled the pie
join the oil pipe was a hacked version
an illegal version of the original
Canadian software the American Secret
Service's said there the CIA said a
Trojan had goes into that hacked version
and that's what caused the explosion
although the second hypothesis was that
it was human error due to an operator
and in fact is quite peculiar because we
don't even have confirmation is the
explosion
finally and actually took place at all
anyway that's the first possible
instance now the second one to 2004 in
2004 this one did happen a company that
was in charge of wastewater treatment in
Marucci Marusya water breach an employee
stole some radio communication equipment
and in his vehicle he went to the
different pumping stations and as a
result of that there was a spill of
thousands of litres of wastewater into a
nature parks and with no control or that
sewage at that time people everybody
thought that radio equipment was ever so
expensive so nobody would be able to do
anything like this because of user
writing authentication security but it
did happen he actually went round and
opened the taps the flood gates
he was course and the case went to court
and
he ended up in prison so and the third
instance is the most popular example
that everybody knows about is Stuxnet
the Stuxnet incident apologies if I'm
going to bore you telling you about this
apparently is the most sophisticated
malware ever written for zero day
vulnerability affecting two power
stations in run
problem here is that the spinners the
centrist centrifuge machines were the
uranium centrifuges were working faster
than they should have been but operators
didn't know about it as far as they
could tell the centrifuge system was
working fine until one day they just
stopped working they're very expensive
pieces of equipment and as a result of
this there was a big this was a big
problem for the Iranian nuclear power
plant and system then the following
attack that was confirmed after Stuxnet
was in 2004 it was at a steel iron and
steel mill works in Germany we don't
know where exactly or which one and in
2004 and there was a spear phishing
attack an executive from the company
received that email and as a result of
that they got into the system accessed
the information system and and they had
access to the furnaces there was a fire
in one of the blast furnaces as a result
of that and that caused massive losses
the fire took a long time to be
controlled we don't know if malware was
used we don't know if that was their
actual proper target we don't have that
information we then move on to 2015 and
this was the large the first large-scale
attack
to an electricity transmission lines as
a result of that some 230,000 people in
Ukrainian suffer the blockhouse for a
number of hours with 30 substations
switched off similar start as far as we
know spearfishing on the IT Network and
then that's how they accessed the OT
network well this is the first lesson we
need to learn we need to really clearly
segment and separate the IT Network and
the LT network in a company so how can
we protect industrial networks
what should the procedure be because
most of us in this field of security are
IT experts so our idea is that we have
to divide the network into different
layers we know that we think as IT
experts that the main points there is
our data confidential data that's why
they should be at the core of their
protection then the following layer to
be protected most protected would be the
application then the host or hosts and
then last but not least the network
person for us the core our focus what is
it is data and data confidentiality if
you go to a company to an industrial
company and you ask them hey what would
you rather not have access to your data
for a whole day or for the big wide
world to know about all your data for
your competitors to know and so on well
I can tell you that rather not have
access to their data for just one day in
Surrey
non industrial networks or company non
industrial companies whereas if it's an
industrial environment it's the process
that's important what would be at the
core it would be
the process is different from what we
think as IT experts they want to
continue to produce their parts not some
boats whatever it is and traffic data
hose network is very much secondary for
them why because it's the process that
has added value for them because
Industrial cybersecurity as opposed to
IT cybersecurity the cost of a
cyberattack is very very easily
calculated they tell you straight away
who if it was one week it would cost us
this much whereas if it was an attack
from an IT point of view not an
industrial point of view it's much
harder to calculate that how much does
it cost if a company if the web line for
a company crashes for a week well if
it's an online shop it's hard to
calculate but in an industrial
environment well it just cost a counter
the nuts and bolts they won't be selling
that's the calculation so again it's a
process availability that matters most
the process must keep going and working
no matter what so when we prepare
security measures you have to we have to
be ever so careful and respectful not to
compromise the process first and
foremost so again what is the main
difference between the industrial
Network and an IT Network what a number
of differences but first and foremost
the in IT networks we mostly care about
communication and data processing
whereas in an industrial network is the
process that matters manufacturing
process because let's not forget that
security for a manufacturing point very
often means safety safety of operators
or of people around them can you imagine
how nice it was in the Ukraine when
people had this blackout thousands and
thousands of people in the middle of
winter particularly depending what
boilers and heating systems they have it
can't be nice right another important
feature in an industrial network is that
timing is always shorter mostly if we're
talking about the automotive industry or
where PLC's are very much present we're
talking about 200 microseconds that's
timing for them whereas if we're talking
about a wastewater treatment or sewage
treatment for instance POW time is
important as well a little bit less but
still very important so when we deploy a
new security system we need to take that
into account we can't go and do sniffing
with a man-in-the-middle and then that's
going to cause some latency that would
add a few more microseconds in latency
and that would have a big impact for
them in the manufacturing process
the timing industrial networks also have
other differences and peculiar peculiar
elements there we don't have users that
go to see the newspaper morning early in
the morning all that traffic comes from
PLC is the one saying to the control
server this is the temperature this is
so every half second every second I
don't care a little state like that and
every now and then the operator will do
something but industrial networks are
much more aesthetics and deterministic
then the IT Network topology does never
change country to a Wi-Fi network where
users lock arm and add at all times
it doesn't change almost ever oh that's
good cuz if we see something changing it
means that there's something there that
is not attitude and that's what I'm
indicating here and then what I said
before PLC's and the nodes as well so
computing power is minimum and then we
are using equipment that is way all the
the ones we're used to so what can we do
let's try and use these features that
industrial networks have trying to
detect attacks if they are so
deterministic and the static let's dive
into that and explore it and this is the
state of the art for attack detections
and let's see this from a personal point
of view before stack next which seems to
be the pleistocene well things were
being done and have been done this was a
field of research that was quite limited
contrary to what we have now but things
were done and we are talking here about
solutions that were already existing
such as ideas based on signature already
on i.t that were translated into the
industrial world but mainly these were
proof-of-concept proofs of concept and
part of the standards and the good
practices we have for industrial
networks were non-existent back then
what least whitelist and as we call it
now very much recommended but was not
that advanced there were new industrial
fibers by wall sorry we didn't have the
network isolated from the item and it
kind of a privat concept part without a
dream need a real neat by the industry
through ancestry deed in indeed conduct
a survey of the existing papers that was
2010 and it summarizes all that had been
done before stud snacks and they
discussed some terms that will later on
become more important
and there is model-based detection which
basically we built a model of what the
network or should be or the pressure
should be in order to detect things that
are out of the pattern out of the model
and then specification based detection
where we create some manual standards or
rules stating that there are some things
should not be as they are which is a bit
more simple than the model based
detection this is before 2010 there are
already some papers a discussing it
there is a start in research field
there's a few workshops on the topic but
it is a still a bit far from where we
are headed then we have stacked necked
everything is on the media people get
scared and it becomes a feel of research
that is a bit more fashionable than it
was in the past
there's more on the topic more workshops
and everything having to do with
industrial cybersecurity we don't think
about some 10 years ago and so people
start working on their seriously but
mainly to fails with our network
detection attack detection so I see how
the network behaves see if there are any
packets that do not comply with those
rules but then field detection so I
don't check the network I don't care
about the package or the
flows or the services what I'm
interested in is knowing what's going on
with the process and if the process is
not working as it should
that's what I care about and so that's
where with the stacks neck I'm beyond
sore setting that's when I start my PhD
dissertation first of all with my
dissertation I came to realize there
weren't security visualization tools for
industrial networks so what we did was
built one using strain diagrams
that's circle which indicates that there
are several industrial hosts and they
are all arranged there we have PLC's
that's blue then edge aim eyes that's
purple and then control servers that's
orange
I said before that industrial letters
are very deterministic if a host is all
the same communicating with another one
this will not change if PLC has one or
two controlled service associated would
only send send information there doesn't
need to send information elsewhere the
PLC is just an automated process that it
is producing the traffic it will not go
on the journal or the newspaper to see
how the soccer team's done that traffic
will always be static so and we said if
it's static let's go and see what about
the network flows which should be static
as well and that's what we need those
lines connect in different parts of the
circle our net worth was the Whizzer of
those strings show the number of packets
per flows or the wider the flow the more
active the traffic and the narrower the
flow these narrower the string so what
we did was decide to build f1 list who
is encountered with whom and whoever
does not meet the parameters we will
label them wrapped and that's what we
did see the flow between H M I and PLC
where we should not have any traffic and
we see it is blue this was done with a
car paint in blind
it is a real example and then as the
reference you will see some other use
cases where we detect EO as and it is
not just the existence of abnormal flows
or the non-existence of a network flow
if a PLC is offline we need to know why
because that's also important we don't
know what's going on with the process so
that's it and then
after having done this therefore the
life crisis as it usually happens with
the PhD dissertations and there we
change our focus not just at the network
but also that what about the fields just
the network well for IT people this is a
bit more intuitive
these are flows and packets and these
are things we're more comfortable with
when we go to the field we are talking
about temperate temperatures vibrations
pressure so these are physical
magnitudes the ones that we are
monitoring these are a bit more
complicated for IT for industrial
backgrounds but that's easier for
control I mean in the field that's a
truck floor but for the net where
sometimes the existent equipment weren't
allowed to have many things for example
Network flows for those we had a
mirroring of a switch and that was
doable because it was good enough but
most of the industrial switches back
there
it's still operational now but cannot
you cannot be used with mirroring so
what about flows such as as flow or net
flow these are top range actually so
when we talk about industrial equipment
which is expensive by the way it becomes
even more expensive so sometimes that
Edward electronics existing it's a bit
more basic so in the field we know the
data are there and and we do monitor
them the operator monitors everything
temperatures and everything so there's
something going out that should not so
you don't need to buy expensive switches
you do have the information out there we
saw there were several papers based
mainly on physical models I have a
process and I'll describe it using code
I need to scrap everything the process
does this is um amazingly complicated
collecting all the information from the
physical world into code it is actually
it's a difficult we do the
interdependence says and it isn't simple
it takes lots of expertise and it's
costly and whenever the process changes
the model is useless
so we focused mainly on attack detection
which would be data guided we only get
data we do not build a physical
complicated process that will not well
that yes it would work but it would be
too complicated for what we want to do
as long as we can get that information
out of the data
so first we focus on attack diagnosis
and why is that there were already some
interesting proposals in attack
detection or anomaly detection so it
says hey but mmm
oftentimes we didn't know or operators
didn't know what was going on something
was wrong they knew but he didn't know
why so this is an example so figure this
is a pipe and there's a fluid inside and
there's a flow sensor on the left side
if the flow is flowing the sensor knows
the flow rate per oh I don't know
falling per hour or per minute whatever
right side and bottom side we see two
cases where there's Neal that's a flow
rate one because of the valve is closed
so it doesn't flow through and the other
one for whatever the reason there's a
problem and it doesn't reach its
destination so with those two variables
so there's a drop in the incoming flow
so we need to know why this is
interesting there's been an attack where
someone tried to close that valve or
maybe there is a problem with the
provider and we didn't get the raw
material in by checking this graphs is
not doable all the details out there but
basically with a modern with main
component analysis and then also cut
production graphs well we saw that for
some conditions that was doable with
some drops well on the left side D is
seen and there is a negative bar which
is large one stating that the incoming
flow is lower than it should be and on
the right side what we see is that the
opening ratio for that valve is lower
way lower than what it should be so it
is closed
interesting isn't it we can see if
there's been a malicious attempt to
close the valve or maybe not what's
interesting is that doesn't need to be
network-level
it doesn't need to be an command is
maybe an operator who's tired gone to
the valve and manually closed it and if
we check the network level we would not
be able to detect it or diagnose it
either
so these went on and we had some other
Network parts integrated or embedded but
there is another more recent proposal
after my dissertation this was published
on CSS and this was a detection of more
advanced attacks in the field
this is Passat doesn't bazaar that's the
name again if you wanted details
you can go to the paper and we can get a
signal whatever that is a vibration
change in temperature change in pressure
whatever and with the blue side you
learn and that like that you build a
cluster which is green and then once
we've learned we see how it's doing and
the black side the black part keeps
producing it's okay and the black part
of the dots are inside the cluster then
it's the blue part but as an attack is
don't the structure of the so-called
temporary temporary series is change and
the red spots are dot moved to the left
side of the cluster that information is
protected with just one variable which
is a detection variable the one that you
see on the bottom left side and if the
attack starts and it all changes that
attack indicator is pipe spikes over a
threshold and we get a warning that is
something wrong
all right so we run several attacks a
chemical process that I'll explain later
also a gray water treatment plant and
then a water distribution plant on the
left side we see an evident attack
especially an operator that it's
checking the variable and can say well
there's something going on going on here
but it is detected so there is a spike
in the signal and an alarm would go off
what's interesting here is the one in
the center the middle case the red side
in the attack and it doesn't vary much
when compared to the other graph it's
such a subtle attack that it is masked
inside the signal noise and the bottom
graph maybe you cannot see but with
comparative methods the black one which
is a previous one previous method and
then the blue one ours and we see that
the prior method cannot detect it but
ours can the reason is that many of the
proposals nowadays what they do used to
do was a no wind war the process of
status is now let's calculate or
estimate let's estimate the next reading
read so we kind of predict the future
and then if the prediction and the
reality look alike no problem there many
attacks that are so subtle that don't
change much we will not be able to
detect like this and so what we do or
what we've done is try to see if there
is any structured breakup as part of the
temp structure so that we see that in
surgical detail then on the right side
we checked because these were attacks
that we performed on laughs environment
but we wanted to see whether they can be
translated into a real plant this was a
water distribution plant and yes we saw
that if there's something weird with the
processes in it to be in the sack
because we don't have any more
information on the spikes but still we
see that we do detect them
from before Stuxnet this film already
had some you know there were some
proposals mainly that were IT based to
detect attacks on industrial networks
then they've used that specificity that
the term monistic nature of industrial
networks do detect those network attacks
and then lately the network intrusion
detection in the field that would be the
process level is quite quite active
where is this headed well I guess this
is my own forecast here we will come
closer and closer to machine learning
based solutions we will find more and
more proposals using that information
that we collect from the field for
intrusion detection and I feel they will
be integrated with the network proposal
so if we see something wrong in the
field or in the network these will be
fed back and we will take actions on the
network and that's where I see the
greatest potential for software-defined
networks with a central controller
having all the network objects and there
it will face the attack in a dynamic way
but always always again always with that
touching or interfering with process
availability this would be otherwise
secondary what what matters here is
having process I'm available the team if
we can make sure that the process keeps
producing that's positive if it doesn't
help us with that it might not be useful
so if there's someone in the audience
who likes this topic and thinks okay
industrial security I like it so there I
would like team discuss some resources
that helped me back in the day now we
have many more but let me encourage you
to use them so you can learn especially
from the IT point of view we need to
change our mindset we need to play
around and learn and it takes effort so
read as many books as you can there's
two you've chosen there are a few more
but on the left side that's a classic
it's some years old and it helps with
research and also helped me learn water
an industrial network is how it behaves
etc right side you see something quite
similar these are not books that explain
where the field of research is now
that's not the goal but it helps us
understand what the problems of
industrial cybersecurity are why we
cannot use an anti-virus and I'm on a
PLC for example PLC does not have enough
computing power for that but if you
don't know you don't know these books
help
then for research and mainly academic
research I would recommend this other
book
which might not be so much focused on
cyber security industrial cyber security
but it helps us understand the language
that is used in academic journals and
false positives false negatives and all
of that I would really recommend it then
there is another but there are so many
repositories on github I will mention
that but first there's a list a resource
list to learn industrial cybersecurity
from the behavior of PLC's to peak hubs
with Network captures it is good to have
a look at it it might help you find
tools for industrial cybersecurity some
as grass Marlene I don't know if that
rings a bell but sometimes for service
recognition or NetWare recognition
errors recognition it is not advisable
to use nmap contrary to IP networks
knowing that there is something similar
not that intrusive which is more passive
that's grass modeling and other hundred
tools there and then there's a couple of
industrial processes first one is the
bottle bottling plant virtual plant
that's the name we have the process on
the one side that's the top-left side
there is a tap fill in a series of
buttons all the way up to a level on the
right side you see h mi where it's a
separator how they're doing and both
communicate through a industrial
protocol and then there are some preset
attacks that you can have with your own
money
buzz attacks and where you see that the
bottling plant does not work in is not
filling up the bottles otherwise if the
plant would be flooded and it's easy to
see it's Python so easily understood and
as a first step it's okay and then there
is a process which is a bit more
complicated but I really like it
the chemical process I said before it is
a real chemical process this one it is a
plant that produces some chemical
chemicals and here we can have these
surgically accurate attack see the
process into dependencies and actually
it's complicated because it takes some
learning about control theory and it
takes some chemical engineering as well
but it is such a powerful tool you know
that she drive attacks and also fail
detection there's a framework where you
can close valves spoof enough sensor
signals very good but complicated though
and as such it takes time all right
and just to finish here so that you get
a general idea and Sharon - Annette was
a strategic it is important because of
the risk it entails and because of the
cyber security features involved but
there are some specificities we need to
consider some play in the favour of the
cyber security researcher and some
others against us solutions that are
based on machine learning or artificial
intelligence or whatever is very active
research field for the field and for the
network both
I'd like to encourage you if you want to
learn it isn't impossible yes the
mindset has to be changed and many
things need to be learned on maybe we IT
technicians were not so used to it
but it is doable I managed it and so
that means that I guess any of you cared
that's been all if there are questions
I'll be happy to take them
sure microphone please
my answer would be it depends the top
range companies already have wireless
sensors and that kind of thing that is a
reality reaching up to you those
companies with more resources but even
smaller more traditional companies where
lines are not changed that often there
may be it remains to be seen when and if
it is a very conservative sector it's
true and the mindset would be if it if
it ain't broken don't fix it so for the
oven got companies I think there is a
change but for other companies it might
take longer but yes it's the reality is
not sci-fi okay
oh there's one
[Music]
what about security controls that should
be implemented the basic ones that is to
safeguard information assets I would say
to monitoring network because if we
wouldn't know what's going on we think
we know what's going on but oftentimes
it is not the case we need to see what's
going on first and second segment in
segment in and segment in almost total
segmentation between the control network
and the IT Network and the operating
Network so all accesses are well
controlled because they will always be
some access chain because any remote
maintenance and everything has to happen
but it has to be tightly control and
then as a class segment it inside the
industrial network for different lines
for example production lines or also
business divisions that all has to be
very nicely segmented this year I find
our basic and then some as usual
it's not just technical it its
cross-sectional awareness raising and
training of the people the employee is
involved and then monitoring maybe
you've had an experience by using some
kind of a tool you mean off the shelf
what open sores are I personally haven't
had some people in my group yes but I
haven't so I'd rather not say much
because probably I would mess it up
all right thank you very much them for
your attendance I hope you enjoyed it
you
[Music]