[Music]
well we'll let you know how long you
have left for every presentations five
minutes after you start it will let you
know and will also let you know five
minutes and then one minutes before the
end so please be respectful with the
time you've been given right then we're
ready to start we're going to let you
know about how far you we've gone we've
almost completed our objective which was
capturing the whole spectrum the range
of Wi-Fi and Bluetooth although we had a
little bit of trouble with the Bluetooth
of them at the last minute you'll see
how so we're just going to do the demo
on Wi-Fi because of the Bluetooth
problem we had when we finish at the
Bluetooth code we will upload it to the
repository later today here we see the
diagram you see we have four ESP devices
sniffing or the Wi-Fi traffic they can
find and collecting it the contents will
then be sent to the reception probe and
from there to the server where the web
interface and the database is why
because we want to find any malicious
agent anywhere we don't want to generate
intelligence or correlate data once the
objective has been identified that's it
now I'm going to connect onto the
application panel because in the room we
have now four devices distributed here
in the room they should be collecting
information this is the type of device
we can see it up on the screen they're
connected through batteries
the application has this panel for
access is so safe with logging and as
HTTP with a signature as we said at the
beginning we are using Django admin
power for data management editing and so
on basically well you can see like this
better up on the screen this is the
basic jungle interface which is very
simple to install we use the token from
the API to ascend the information with
the devices then the application has
these four areas one is bot list where
max that we detect as malicious will go
then the device's collect the ESP s
nodes would be the ESP s with the
firmware images and then the managers
would be getting well we've used
telegram we wanted to use SMS s but the
API was not coping with it very much
it was taking too long users with this
application then you see this is the
type of information that it collects we
have identified the nodes with a name
sending the marks then detecting what
they are they are as I think if there
are there's a authentication network
authentication if there was not no
control as to when devices can connect
to send the data there could be the
authentication and the information would
not be transferred so that's another
value that's important to detect
I'm now going to show you a real-time
detection how it works here we see the
working devices except for the Bluetooth
one because we didn't have time to
finish it now receivers there's a Jorge
and myself a we used the telegram board
for our IDs to get the alert my device
would be getting those right now
the blacklist is 0-2 let's get one of
the max that we have detected this one
for instance we're going to edit so we
can get the alert right it's on the list
now once packets get to the devices
those who have not been processed though
those will be the last one to come and
then I should get the alert here on my
telegram
right one minute has elapsed and the
devices should be detecting it now right
the notification then notifications show
it so I'm going to leave this open for
you to see the next alert this is the
type of message you get presence
detected for the device and then the
probe that detected it numbers three two
and one so that's a short time detection
you see is coming again on number four
the idea is that we would be using now
the errors RSSI for the devices knowing
the range the distance on the time with
an algorithm we could then geo locate
that particular device although we have
to take into account the rebound effects
and other values that would be a
detection of a blacklist device the
alerts will work whenever there is an
detection because I often think that
when you have a light warning you about
something in your car and you ignore it
then something will go badly wrong so
it's best not to deactivate alerts after
a certain time a module will be designed
later so that it's not too invasive so
that if there are 15 different alerts
you don't get 15 messages you would get
it all together as one so that would be
Mac detection what about the
authentication
alert I don't know if you can see this
up on the screen because of the letter
type and size we have launched our
packets
you didn't detect it this time
on this side that bar
thanks to jungle filters we can detect
for every Mac checking for the
authentication you see here it detected
it oh I know why it didn't work I forgot
a ap needs to be set as the objective
the target otherwise the alert will
never come up this time it should work
for the neck next the authentication
there you have it you see ap has been
detected good so that would be the
system Jorge has been working more to
integrate Bluetooth and Wi-Fi and he can
probably tell you better how that went
the Bluetooth chip was almost ready for
our USS eyes and so on I must confess
that I'm not very good with 32 SP with
that a particular multi-functionality
for multitasking I had a problem for
tasks not to overlap and that was the
main problem why we couldn't finally
implement Bluetooth we could see 8 max
if that's as far as I could go really
unfortunately you can't see how it would
work it would work exactly the same as
for Wi-Fi but for Bluetooth
also because of the different issues
that have come up from other teams well
first thing we checked when we started
with the project is for it to support
MFP we checked the chips mostly for the
the authentication side of things
sometimes we don't know whether the
support is working because of the chip
but we open the ticket through
expressive so hopefully with a 5
gigahertz and that will be improved in
the future so that's all from us thank
you very much for inviting us to be here
and for letting us take part
okay
hola nosotros good afternoon
here are our names al Jose Ignacio but
the four of us and here we have the anti
shoulder surfing attack platform what is
our target for this - warning a user
that somebody else is there trying to
see what they're doing with their device
why is this - any different because we
want to defend the end-user which is the
weakest link on the chain we have three
main objectives one is for the
application in the long term the second
one we want to do well with a hackathon
and then you will see what we have
managed so we want to develop a
multi-platform application that can work
on Windows Linux or Mac so that when
there is an attack and it's detected and
it can then use different models of
machine learning both online and offline
because we are taking part in the
hackathon we wanted to design an MVP a
simpler way to work with the application
so that you can use then later to also
make the application grow the hackathon
asked us to use different models of
machine learning so we wanted to compare
online and offline possibilities with
pros and cons we also want to find a sub
set of actions so they can be
implemented on MVP how far did we go
did we guess well facial detection is
working and for that we have used
machine learn
models that have been trained over a day
why because of lack of time during the
hackathon and also because we can't
access those models very easily we've
also done the mud multi platform MVP we
have compared online and offline
possibilities with pros and cons and we
have selected two offline modes models
for the application with configurable
actions that can be persistent that is
even if the application is switched off
there is still selected we also want the
screen to be blocked when the attack is
detected and also for brightness to
change and notifications to be sent
let's compare the models for the cloud
option we have checked iru as a
recognition by Amazon and then offline
to other models the latency obviously
it's a lot slower on the cloud you first
need to send your request to the cloud
and be told if there is a face detection
or not weather whereas a offline the
machine does it all and it is much
faster the cost well the cloud service
if you need to send your request and
Amazon's is quite expensive so who's
going to pay for that users well there's
no scalability there or we could offer
the Amazon service with that
infrastructure as a premium service for
the application but we're not convinced
by this either so we decided to use the
offline models which are free of charge
in the cloud mode you always need the
Internet Amazon Azur or Google whatever
whereas offline you don't need the
internet you just need your device
for training well the cloud model hasn't
no training needed whereas in the
offline mode you can either either use
pre trained models or you have to train
them yourself about an accuracy the
cloud model allows not just face
detection but also knowing if two faces
are the same or not and you only need
two pictures for us with very high
probability about prediction accuracy
well offline it very much depends on
which system you select about a user
knowledge the user needs to configure a
configure the Amazon account whereas
with the offline mode is all transparent
and the user don't need to know what's
going on what are the drawbacks well
firstly there are very few libraries for
phase recognition with machine learning
which are non je s because most
applications are Python or reiatives we
used phase a P dot J S which is a very
new library in on beta with a very few
documentation and that was a limitation
because it doesn't allow for models to
be offline you need to first load a on
the Internet
so first time you run the application
you should always use the internet mode
when developing the tool we also found a
security issue on Windows when you run
your application it doesn't ask for
authorization for the camera to work it
just starts recording
whereas on Mac it does ask first time
you use it for your authorization what
are good ideas for the future for this
well identifying the user we didn't have
time to include that unfortunately
because the eyes I
so is more complex than face recognition
the second idea would be using different
cameras for depth and angle change or to
know if there's a camera behind
recording we also wanted to check when
you move away from the computer for it
to detect it and block it also plugins
or whitelist
for apps so if you're using sublime it
would know that that's the API and that
device wouldn't work and also shortcuts
maybe in the future for the brightness
to change just with a couple of clicks
and now my colleague is going to show
you the demo we've got the github video
of this demo if you want to watch it
online but we're going to play it live
here let me just wait for the
application to start first there it is
have a look at that top right hand
corner that's the application window and
we wanted to have that design without
edges so to make it visually more
attractive we decided the window should
be small so that is not cumbersome it
doesn't take up screen too much and you
can move it just in case where it is by
default imagine it's blocking something
important let me just check get a little
bit closer to the camera
well it's recognizing my face that's the
blue framework and down below there is
the confidence a percentage that a
about my face so there's phase detection
first and here is the menu on the top
bar is again not cumbersome so that it
doesn't stop us from seeing what the
camera is recording then we have the
recording control you see i press the
button and the recording stops and my
laptop says the LED says that it stopped
recording and then you have this other
button here for play and start recording
again then on the right we have the
settings so that we can change the
machine learning model we're using
because developing the application we
have checked different models some have
worked better than others and the one
we're using now is part of the
repository and it's loading now for face
recognition why is this nice because in
future if we have a better model than
this all you would have to do is include
the that models URL here and our
application would load that model here
we have the different actions for our
application for instance sending
notifications if somebody is coming
approaching from the back lowering the
brightness as well of the screen so that
people wouldn't be able to see it
properly or block the screen completely
my colleague is going to approach
approach me now stand next to me you
didn't detect your face very fast
can you just die just a little bit
longer because sometimes the
notification takes that little bit
longer oh dear it doesn't seem to work
sometimes it takes a little bit too long
let me go to the menu now let's check
the brightness so that it detects a
different face a different from mine
then the brightness will be lower I
don't know if you can see that the
brightness is much lower now there is a
keyboard command that we have included
so that you can go back to the initial
config a brightness one brightness in
this case and the rest of the methods as
well what about a scree scree blocking
roof is going to approach me again you
see the screen blocks automatically as
soon as it detects the other face so
that's about it logically the demo video
is available as I said for you on github
if you want to watch it again so if you
are happy with this project and you want
to contribute this is the repository on
github for you to do so on take next
okay preparado seven eight
por favor the next team CB nets can you
start getting ready
good afternoon everyone
the competition has been so exciting and
so tiring and everything else but here
we are all happy to tell you about our
work we've developed a tool that can be
used anywhere on the Internet
but because we had very little time here
we decided to just focus on some domains
round about 6,500 domains we've got a 2
now then with a back-end made up by the
core that connects up to the web sites
and collects data for further analysis
at the backend we also have the plugins
or structured in files and then we also
have a directory with configuration for
each or settings for each blogging and
then at the front end we have the GUI
for the user where you can include the
URL that you want to check and different
options to choose from then we have an
in-depth standalone area that we've code
ender render in charge of a report
writing in two different formats and
then we have a browser selenium that can
be automated which is what we use for
while browsing the web sites because
it's a local demo I've got it here on my
computer on my laptop but we want this
to be a tool that will be scaled up in
different modules so that we can have
in front ends sending requests launching
a - in cores each core within instances
of selenium so that the system capacity
could be greater we've used selenium
connections as well so we don't have to
design too many of them and also its
cache and means that when two requests
are sent and you're not a sent every
apply then the last one will be valid
what's the idea for plugins well the
input is an object in cascade it just in
case information it has to be shared
then the output for this would be its
name at the output we would have their
name and the score as a percentage
seeing if that truly scores or not and
also if the plugins have to be stopped
and then an area for messages for human
interpretation what plugins have we
implemented a dummy which is a little
bit like a framework in case you want to
develop it further we have two automatic
plugins the SSL and the online
confidence one to check if the SSL is
present or not if it still valid or not
and also the confidence one if it's
present or not and nobody needs to
intervene what about the plugins for
cookies for those work
semi-automatically recovering the
cookies first and then there should be a
blacklist and a whitelist to know if
they're harmless or not is there some
infringement or not although that is a
manual process a process to feed all of
this we should also feed other plugins
that have definitions for legal laws and
regulations for the ssl one apart from
finding the URLs is all also going to be
checking for contents within each URL
and we call this blogging definitions
because it can't be automated and this
is a tool that has to be fed a little
bit like updating the database for
definitions in this case like very much
like an anti-virus would work or works
let's have a look at the interface for
the website we've prepared these
screenshots person we can actually
launch them later if there's time so
here the URL that domain we press scan
and this is the results this is zero
percent so that wouldn't score for the
total at the end then for other ones
we've got different percentages here it
tells us which cookies are allowed or
not with prorated percentages and a
final score if I press here on ODT or
PDF well the report would come up in
whatever format in a more visual manner
this website it doesn't have online
confidence the score is zero it doesn't
count so it's in orange in red or
whatever seems to be problematic in
green or whatever seems to be fine this
a scroll down menu and allows us to
choose which plugins we want to run in
this case we have not marked and as I
sell confidence for instance so that it
can skip whatever we don't need for the
reports
this is another example with a different
website and this is an example that we
prepared specifically to make sure 100%
would be scored you see there it is what
about the back end well it allows for
statistics to be there statistics that
have been stored it looks a little bit
prettier life like this
here we have some examples that we've
prepared what can we do here we'll send
it to graphene uh because he said J son
then we can continue to feed the
statistics for the different processes
that we cover there's also an individual
service for each and every analysis in J
son in case you want to integrate with
us well we've got this other prettier
display it gives you information about
time about the different details using
you could access this and then work
automatically what about the proof of
concepts with a hat we've prepared an
add-on for Firefox to be able to connect
up to the surveys and do the reports so
when we visit a URL and how do you know
well this is the URIs icon with the
percentage you see 25% for this website
must rent this one 87% it's it appears
as amber and green for this one because
the total score is 100 percent so as you
browse and visit different web sites you
this tells you how much you should trust
that particular website now for the
website where the score was 100 percent
this
is the report it would be great to
continue to develop this tool which is a
bit of a shame when when you do
something like this at a competition
like a hackathon you might come up with
an interesting project like this and who
knows and some organization in C Bay for
instance might be keen on helping this
go further because imagine if the system
gives you a 100% score in that case the
system could offer you like a quality
label that your website could display
just to tell surfers that you comply
with the URIs requirements I think
that's about it
so that's all from us thank you very
much for your attention and all the best
for the rest of the team's well because
you have just over a minute left can I
ask you a question could you show us ads
internally how the plugins work how they
check detection for the final score to
be calculated
I mentioned earlier that there's this
area here for config settings for
instance for cookies
that's a manual process it has to be at
the moment I mean it could be then that
in the future there might be something
like in 90 hours and where updates they
are automated and then the plugins are
here they're independent let's have a
look at the LSSI one we get the driver
that is the instance we sent to selenium
then comes back for that website that's
processed to find links that are defined
in the config file in this case we've
got these three so when you visit when
it visits those three it then searches
for keywords we have included those here
that's the number of the particular law
the trade registration those formal
details and if those criteria are
complied with that's when the 100% score
is calculated well and this is where the
message is waited for the final report
and here are the functions one
processing on the basis of the different
links I showed you at the beginning and
the other one loading the configuration
great thank you very much for that
it's see we net the next team
çb net air the next team the Tigers
let's start then with a presentation of
this demo and showing you how far we've
got our main objectives for this project
were security because it's resource
intensive we need a lot of memory a lot
of CPU resources and in order to improve
that we want to focus on performance and
on a distributed solution in different
layers and with feedback so that we can
have a network device with a layer how
far did we get for more security we have
managed to communicate as so that if an
attack takes place and it's identified
and that will be like an HTTP request
without a host and if that condition is
messy the system finds the clients IP
and that is fed into the system on NF TB
we have this property with whitelists
and blacklists and also traffic
limitation and have the threshold for
each origin IP we've also got functional
tests to then see if the protection is
actually working during the tests we
have checked the scripts we have created
the scripts sorry for pen testing and
verification
we have and to see the efficiency and we
have managed to have a tool that behaves
in a distributed manner as if different
users were connected at the same time
we've also tried to use new libraries
we'll see which ones later on the
extraction when the extraction went fast
here we can see lib nml lib nft and live
n ft tables those were the libraries
that we've used we have compiled the
load balancer for n f TB and we've also
worked at the backend these are the new
parameters that we've added to the API
we've identified them with the values
and the demo will later show which ones
they are and how they work we have used
different objects a guest and post we've
identified them what problems did we
encounter we have used technologies that
are still under development life because
we want to help the community use some
of the new libraries we've also
communicated from a wife to the API we
have managed to have an SSH tunnel so
that information can go more securely we
have also found new proposals for
attacks for TOS later we will see how
although that was not our main objective
we don't want to have a seventh layer
objective but how we had a little bit of
time and we had to we try to improve
that side of things as well as my
colleague was saying what we found about
a evil Regis is that mod security has to
for configuration one that limits the
maximum size for the fire so we can
either process that amount or reject it
we have also managed to define the
maximum number of matches that can be
found with a generic expression and then
on Apache - we've got keep alive time
out that means we don't allow for
connections that are over the timeout
time so if an attacker wants to send
very large attp
requests the system will stop that now
what about future developments for the
future we want to migrate the solution
to ssh supported by HTTP we want to
generate the api key which is more
robust and also the hardening of the
load software which is going to quickly
show you the demo just for you to get an
idea how it works
just for sites here we have the client
site where we simulate a connections to
those two IPS connecting on to one which
so far only called the packets and
distributed them acquitted equitably
between the two different arms I'm going
to show you a one of the attacks that we
managed to stop the flux one and then
another attack to send up get protection
that will be identified as malicious at
the server side and that will inform the
load balancer for the request to be
included within the blacklist so let's
go for it
so don't worry that we can't see the big
screen we've got the smaller screens on
the side so forget about the larger side
not having big time sorry a big enough
letter type one of the participating in
a party superior to name the cleantech
on the top side you have the claims
getting the connections and then the
bottom side that it cannot see because I
will focus on the top side of it so that
I can extend it
my lip went off the hockey put to
another Louis have you got it this is
one of the surface you've got here so
here you have the load balancer I have
the set of bready I'm showing this to
you I'm sharing it with you here you
have the current configuration on Jason
we have a virtual server and default we
have a 500 limit and the bust limit is 5
then on the other hand this is our web
client which sends connections
concurrently at 50 so here you have this
short clip and you will see how 50
connections are spread with other
servers see the server going up we will
get some 50 connections on either side
this is my system where identified that
there is a TIA vs. hack here is my IP
ready the API that is and it will move
over 500 there's a volley I've loaded
and I set it at 5 I call the device
and you see the values though it means
that this is decreasing so we change
connections and so we see that this
value will be at five and we've realized
that the value of 60 concurrent
connections and here we stopped at five
this is the 60 second time there's about
this fire this is the first EOS and the
work it states that we've changed X
connections in or within those 60
seconds this would protect us from do s
attacks and then this other attack
so these are black layers that I'm
loading same as before but this is a
black list so the back ends can check it
here
I just got this request here and if I
tried next time
NFC list and right now this is a
blacklist
karyam 5780 the device is there so I
cannot get on until 10 seconds from now
that is the brief thief predefined
volumes and now that I got the blacklist
I can use the system and gain access to
the system and that's all so so if we
stick to time is that an extra point
well I think about that you need to know
that I'm having a terrible time here but
I'm forced you controlling time sorry
about that
Tigers Tigers Tigers Lions Lions Lions
I'm an old-fashioned guy next one get
ready
fish and chips
fish and chips are you ready then fish
and chips for my year reason it's health
reason so we move on to the next group
good afternoon everyone we're fish and
chips we've developed fast fish for
efficient detection large-scale as the
competition started we said we would be
working on these items minimum domain
collection minimum structures you cannot
find fishing under unless you find new
domains also analysis a structure you
need to sorry structure analysis because
you need to look into the data there's
no point in mining data when you don't
make the most of them and then on demand
request you need to have the data but
someone needs to check them or at least
check them in an accessible way and we
will also have a database integration
we're interested in persistence finding
if it's 15 seconds and the program stops
and this is a 24/7 and then basic module
compatibility so people can add their
prioritized solutions or contribute to
it in any way we think if we've nailed
it but we have a minimum collection
structure basically it's worth pausing
or it's a difficult certificate parsing
also minimum structure analysis we
follow something like Hamming distance
or some minimum trick on demand request
or structure we have to api's Express
one is HTTP for coming users and then
one on jeep RPC for high performance
minimum integration with databases here
using ret is because it's easier because
it's widely tested and only rarely it
will cause trouble and money module
communication with it we said it is G
RPC protocol buffer so that is agnostic
if you want a module impatient or Java
or whatever you can as learners protocol
buffers has a compiler to throw the
language and the protocol buffers that
we distribute are used our program will
get the message we've also added some
more things that we did not introduce at
first such as TLS communication these is
a cyber security competition so it would
be pointless to have an unsecure
communication - we use CLS for both
sides
communication and client communication
both modules internally need a TLS in
case you host the tool on Google cloud
or AWS or a zoo so no one can read it
and then client communication our
communication between client and server
needs to be closed as well
we've also added add-on JS and modules
could be any other format but we chosen
change them because it's simpler number
of cells sources for certificate
transparency also diffused logic to see
whether it is anything like it and some
collectors here the certificate
transparency is generic so if it matches
our FCC we can use it then we also have
a website with the data sets of the
domains recorded today the day before
today and a few more days before today
or just by reading a file that you can
parse a generic interface technologies
we've used D RPC and protocol buffers
for communication is agnostic also go
for this purpose because we like it it's
simple and concurrency is cheaper than
other languages and that it is
multi-platform and relish for the
database because it's simpler next we'll
try to run a live demo it'll be my
colleague to answer
as my colleague said every connect
connection is TLS protected we have some
certificates as part of the project
naturally these are sign
aren't without a valid key but it works
for the demo here we have the binary
that is useful the filed we'll be using
that later and we also have the setup
the convicts that we discuss our
colleague discussed and I say it's been
saying we have Reddy's as a database and
let me show you what it has now there
are a few domains already uploaded first
we start the database module it's old
modular we said that those are different
binary codes and we could start that on
different servers a different computers
same one doesn't matter we've already
got the config there we got the API
ready which would be the access point
for any user or outside software the
first name i'll i'll run is one of the
api's that we've implemented through
HTTP on cur is open and connected to the
api and we also
and the module to be analyzed that is
using this algorithm similar to Hammonds
and we can use it for domain analysis we
send the curled request
we checked whether it's Twitter or
Twitter like and see if this is phishing
we send it and it says probably fishing
it's a 90% confidence interval and it's
been received by the analyzer which
check it accounts domains that we've set
up and see what domains were born to
look for for example if we're a company
we can set our domain to look fishing I
went I guess I would company and you say
this is fishing against Twitter for all
others
the score is way too low and here
everything's gone through HTTP as we've
done before locked in tej
gone through the API because it was a
user and then if we go back through
Redis it's been stored into the database
see that the score is there if I
send it again nothing's change they will
not lose waste any time on analyzing it
it just got this cool that we had
already saved if we sent a request to
have valid domain it'll say this is
envisioned because Twitter is a valid to
mean
we also have a client with the API for
example an email scans of words and then
of the kind and we send it there is this
battery that we've program ourselves but
this is definitely more we would not use
it
this is Twitter we've seen it we just
got the score from our database
everything else facebook.com or every
comes been locked into same here keeps
him here if we try it again this is not
analyzes and database that no need to go
through it
these were all on-demand requests this
is also a collection module let me show
the certificate transparency to you and
I'll cut it off because it's running on
my mobile Wi-Fi so just a few seconds
and stop bet and you get all the domains
compared them against those where we
wanted to check whether they were
fishing or not we were unlucky here
because they weren't fishing they polled
burning through here actually the
repeats it didn't analyze them again
they are on database and see that
they've all been checked
well we've met every goal here so we
just need to have more analyzers but we
have an interface that can be used for
any language so it would be negligible
more collectors same we have the
certificate transparency so database
files easy to implement more API as
we've seen just 2g RPC and HTTP we can
also implement some kind of a cache that
is half way implemented but we need to
have one that is more efficient a deeper
configuration because we have one as my
colleague explained we can set some
variables but we would need to set some
of the ports to start services and also
an automatic diplay the deploy if we
wanted to use it at home as well
[Applause]
never was perfecto
tigress power alone next Tigers and then
so
but one of the other most eligible
degrees
we had Tigers and our product is error
hit in case you don't remember it's an
improvement on air crack Sylvia boom mmm
and myself ricotta we were starting from
scratch we had not written any code so
we had to make some changes for example
data captured from the suggestions we
got we've been using air crack that's
the name of the project the name we were
taken after and then these are the two
this well known on Wi-Fi and then we had
so many problems with the graph
libraries for JavaScript for the heat
maps because we had the idea that we
would use a leaflet but then we ended up
using Google Maps and I'll explain in a
minute
we had some trouble with a server for
Python so data captured it has two entry
points where we change would we've
captured
second-by-second on gps on a csv file
that's the one that we treat and process
and move into the database and then we
have quiche mints a facial output even
though it's way more fruity as we can
use it for heat maps with our tool and
see all the tables with everything
having to do with that because well
actually we wanted to go further and
keep information on clients and all
second-by-second for client monitoring
or projects a bit more focused on
clients which you cannot have with
kismet
so as I was saying it is a kiss miss
baised capture so we didn't have to
touch it just a python script so it
reads the file and goes into a database
and then the aircrack change on written
in c and we added two outputs one for IP
another one for client which is a csv
with the GPS position every time is
found so these are two python scripts
that greet the files and save them to
the database the database do you have it
so this one here that's the database we
have the IP and the client tables and
the relationship between which is
connections and then the probes in every
client and then the aps and the clients
were never seen so this database is not
complete when we have not feel every
field and that's one of the to-do items
but what we are most interested in for
this project for this stage it's on here
some that so these are SQL query is
quite simple that help us recover
information
we have four drawers done that is
database production we can produce
several result which is most visual and
that's what the client will see for the
web app we've used a node server we were
using a back-end on C sharp but we were
in trouble because we were not familiar
with it and so we moved to node which
seems simple and yielded us better
results on faster results
apart from J JavaScript
it says JavaScript framers well it's
actually CSS frame prayer framers with
use admin and bootstrap and then the
graphic libraries to show the results
for the interface and the result
displayed let me play the demo for you
as you can see there's an interface
on the left side you can choose access
point information collected client
information collected or heat map
generation so if you move here you can
see and choose the name of the network
that we audit him let's say this is a
pentesters view with that Wi-Fi audit
when we click here we see data at first
we only had our as as I and so we were
suggested she has set the average the
maximum the minimum that we see here and
same time but from born how we've done
it with the name we can also use the MAC
address in case we were looking for
information for a specific access point
and just like this now we only have
these few results but we could add a few
more same way sure
same way we can find all the information
we can gather from clients we choose
clients this is the first one but as you
can see in the traffic capture we had
their database produce has many
different types of networks
this is cyber camps and there you see
that's the route MAC address routed
macros used the client ID and the time
this is all Wi-Fi because well as you
will see what it is we could not include
the Bluetooth here you will also have
them up heap heat maps are a generation
and we've been using google maps as we
said mainly because it was a suggestion
and also because we had some problems
with leaf left that we had chosen here
just in case it doesn't work we prepare
the video
a formal video yes even from a video or
just because of time constraints we're
going to play the video instead instead
the name of the network in this case
cyber camp and now we can see what role
has done he's the one who was in charge
of the capture we didn't have time for
the legend but look at those areas in
red which is where the RSSI value is
higher where the root was in the
building or a roundish well you can see
it in a very visual manner you can have
different modes satellite mode or
straight street view you see this is our
building Avenue for cyber camp so in the
past we were selecting tables for the
different names or the MAC address so if
we look for information of a particular
router look at that that corner there it
says that's the router we're looking for
so if in a particular organization or
the routers are the same brand and in
our inventory we see that in a MAC
address the bytes are look different on
the beginning then we can find it so
that's about it for the interface
what else would we like to do Raoul said
it the database could have more fields
so that we could have more details about
the maps we didn't have time to include
the legend having the different paths
for the dots but we did do it and for
the other library leafless let me just
quickly show you you see the different
points that Raoul covered where the
samples were taken and we have the
coordinates and the RSSI value that
could be added to Google Maps and last
but not least err we still need to add
their Bluetooth module so that's all
from us we want to thank you for your
attention and we'll be happy to answer
any questions you may have
[Applause]
just as a reminder we will have a
general Q&A session for all the teams
and that's why we're first listening to
the presentations no questions we did
leave time for just one question in the
case of the one team that has still had
time to spare presentation time that is
can we now hear from uber newbs
No
CPC who uses your premium provider
it's really annoying because it works
beautifully this morning I was the first
one to test it and it worked just fine
now it's what it works
don't touch anything good afternoon
everyone this is the name of our team
zell i'm alvaro even and myself we are
together we're studying a university and
we find that sometimes a universities
have certain rules and just to improve
the situation we have developed stock
this is a tool to provide safety to
systems admin admins and to users in
this case it could be a facility in at
university maybe a laboratory we want in
the systems admin has the safety that
ports won't be open by default but
rather for them to open as needed
through port knocking mechanism and also
users students in this case having a
factors for double authentication we
prepared a demo for you
here we have a users registration screen
you see let's say yes a van my name that
would be the screen for registration
we then activate the double
authentication for the QR code or the
rather the OTP key to be activated for
that particular student we scan the QR
code and it's a shame you can't see my
mobile phone now but it shows me a code
that refreshes regularly for us to
verify and I'm the only one who can
verify that on the application because
it's my mobile phone that's where I have
this code I keep getting these codes so
let me access with an admin user admin
of the platform that is right this is
the user
that is going to let us access whichever
machine my logging was even three and
that's how I let the machine that I
selected earlier be accessed
now I log out my admin and then I log in
with a normal user it then asks me again
to identify myself right as the log in
done and see how I can now access the
machine that I selected as systems admin
so I then download here across a client
for that machine and I then download the
profile for that machine this is the
profile with user details which then
connect up with the supervisors
information so that through SSH or
whichever other surveys I can then
access the machine so let's see how this
works how the port knocking can request
works this administration portal doesn't
assure actually handle the machines
it just has information on users the
mapping so the infrastructure admin
would be in charge of all the rest on
demand so of course the template which I
downloaded and here I can run stock
which is the name for the administration
was that code right now at this time
right I've typed in the codes and this
is the top the supervisor who gets the
package given by the firewall so we can
then identify the poor knocking sequence
and get the token then with details on
the public password and the user name
and this is the response ah
it tells me that that the code has been
refreshed which is the new one six seven
oh right
has it expired again well apologies we
need to be fast here man
well this just shows how is not easy
pretending to be somebody else you need
to be faster with those codes that
aren't refreshed all the time so the
supervisor doesn't act on itself but on
the machines and that I want to be
accessed through firewall rules the
window opens and then jointly it
administrates the public keys so that
access can be granted without the need
for a password so all of this the
settings can be changed we can also use
a NIC to access the machine for instance
I'm going to now access through SSH I
should have access here let me just go
back to the presentation a moment let's
see if it lets me show you the
presentation up on the screen now these
are the technologies that we've used
Ruby and Python Python mostly for the
clients Graper and then connections are
done through sockets not with KP or we
didn't think that would be correct or
even feasible and then what about this
supervisor level we did you skip it as
KP there for interpretation and then
Ruby mostly for authentication to work
with the users to check that the key is
correct so all of that works on HTTPS so
the supervisor there would be checking
if the key is correct the key that's
generated regularly all of that has been
done just with virtual machines we
wanted to make it nice and simple so
this is the more detailed explanation of
the sequence how it works
it tends to work at on different ports
from firewall that forwards to the
supervisor the packets so they can be
identified as port knocking once that is
identified then the side gate is open
for the token to be sent logically
encrypted and with a certain integrity
so that the supervisor can then work
with administration of those keys after
a certain time
because this is a hackathon we wanted to
analyze a vulnerability x' and there's
one main vulnerability here it would be
the authentication server that's the
only element that users can access
directly so that would be the main
target 42 attacks our system is not
compromised because you can't access the
machines the authentication server when
it crashes it can't identify if the keys
are correct so you wouldn't be able to
login the rest of the infrastructure is
protected as I said because the user
doesn't have access to machines because
the ports are not open and because the
machines delegate all the traffic
so what about possible future
improvements we would have to
double-check details and members of the
jury mentioned that some detail should
be improved but we will also would like
to have a new authentication system for
instance the Phaedo key I believe he
said we have implemented the key but for
the moment only for the client
application that connects up to the
machines we should still work on us
but at the supervisors level what else
can we say well we've had a such a good
time it's been a wonderful experience
being here for these few days thank you
very much to all of you
you see now continue with uber newbs and
the following team will be security bag
I think
[Music]
right our team has developed the blue
fingerprint application
well we haven't quite finished it we
only got half way through we have been
using the age co6 module that we can see
up on the screen what are the different
stages of the communication that we've
been developing my project was actually
more complex than we originally thought
so that's what we found has been the
first conclusion the idea is that a
message is sent from the mobile phone
from the Arduino to the Arduino with a
fourth username if everything works the
request gets there and if it's been
saved and then a challenge will take
place then a deciphered number or
decoded number plus one would go one way
and Arduino would then sent a message
send the message as well that we have
verified a with a LED and led there are
different modes for opening and closing
but unfortunately we have time no time
to finish that we've prepared a video
for a use case
this is the list of defined devices you
can see how it starts stops blinking I
didn't say I'm a master we then get a
challenge we then send then the
following 1+1 and that's when the light
comes on so the next case is pretending
I'm an intruder I sent a different chain
that hadn't been saved that means it's
not a valid M user and that me and as a
result we are denied access the wise LED
means the request is being generated so
we didn't have time to cover this stage
this new step you press the Open button
there's a new session started there's
the exchange between both ends and just
to check they have it a new number
random number should be generated and
encrypted and the packet would be
encoded and decoded M to check it's
there only the master could do this this
has to do with a user list Arduino would
send 1x1 messages with users under
little finishes the file or the process
and then the master device would then
send the message for delete whichever
number of user out of the ones you sent
me and then
the last step it would be from Arduino
to the master a message for okay or not
okay the odd us they would work
similarly from the master the chain the
string would go to the arduino and then
depending whether the information is
there or not or if the addition was
correct or not the message would go back
as okay the initialization of
communication has a protocol that
includes bluetooth communication which
is very well covered then there's a
database that's managed through Malu
tools and because Arduino works at a
very low level well we found that really
complex and we didn't have time to
implement it user ID is correct is
working okay and the mobile phone and
the Arduino have been communicating fine
we found a way to process information
both at the mobile and and the Arduino
and let's not forget that they work with
different types of data it's always a
streams of characters from for
communication and then we still have to
work with the files for passwords and so
on we have no time for that
unfortunately we couldn't find
compatible libraries at the mobile phone
and and we still need to find an
algorithm that works well with this
project
also for multi-user use of this
application we still need to work more
honest a main problem has been having a
very short time and also maybe the crude
encrypting we should have been faster
with that just an idea for the future
would be having a time key imagine at
the moment you need to stand close to
the Arduino whereas in the future and it
would be nice having different users
with keys so they can access without
having to be close to the Arduino
Arduino sorry when a user is logs in
yeah we were thinking about how
sometimes you might otherwise have to
lend your key to somebody for them to
use the system first and then you would
need to have master signature to verify
ID maybe we can run the demo I have
other different stages now right let's
do it
I live in difficulty on the loose word
in Astoria now for user ID that has to
be registered on the Arduino database
that's the first one the first step and
if that doesn't work if it's not correct
what is the case now what happens if an
unregistered user tried to connect up to
the Arduino from the very beginning
Arduino would reject the service and
connection would restart would be
restarted but let's imagine something
went wrong and communication continued
on to any of the following stages the
user has been detected as valid in this
case and there is a correct challenge
response and that logically includes the
encrypting so let's imagine I know of a
username that I can then cheat the
system and pretend I'm that user
registered user
go through the first level there's a
proposal for a challenge but that's
encrypted so I won't be able to respond
to it correctly so there would be denial
of service and the system would restart
so that's all from us thank you very
much for your attention can I just ask
you a question just to make sure I
understand about the encrypting is there
encrypting or not because you are
talking about challenge and response is
that not encrypted is it just a
challenge and response situation any
message coming from the mobile phone
except for the first ID message is
encrypted with aes-256 so whichever one
we implement eventually because we
haven't done it yet and for arduino
encrypting works because we have used a
predefined library but because javi
works with java that doesn't allow for
bytes and we were a little bit limited
there we still need to work on the
encrypting more but confirmation
messages from arduino as in okay or not
okay that goes flat so that it can't be
discovered
[Applause]
CNP island or let's continue with IOT
vigilant with their security bag let's
continue with IOT vigilant with our
security bank
sorry Esther damn B&S tablet
okay
get out get out I wanna start this
right let's get started let me tell you
that remind you that we all have secrets
right we all do for instance a happy API
key a password a pin code access for
details for a credit card whatever
information we want to protect for
whatever reason but starting today I can
tell you that we are all going to have
secrets fine but we will all have
somewhere safe to keep them this is it
guarded box logo that has been generated
from a random system that we found on
the Internet so what is guarded box is
an online application with the server is
up on the cloud and so that we can store
our secrets and then access them
anywhere anytime from any device and use
them because secrets are going to be
encrypted at the server encrypted at the
user's device and with a key that comes
directly from their passwords so secrets
will never use your device and at the
same time they will be protected we can
then share secrets with other users
using an cryptographic system which is
useful if you ever want to send me your
bank card details and we think the main
feature here is that it's been
implemented following the most stringent
security practices and guidelines and
with a mechanism to guarantee that
passwords password and the P to encrypt
and decrypt our messages are is nowhere
in particular just in your own head
which makes it a lot safer this is an
open source application
on github so that you don't just need to
trust me you can see how it does wash
and all of this in a container so that
any company can then download it and
deploy it so you have all the
instructions to deployed or if you don't
feel like disappointed and deploying it
and you just want to use it you have it
on the cloud in the cloud and you can
use it anytime you want and free of cost
do doesn't go to card it rocks calm when
I say it so a volunteer up here because
I need someone else
so I don't know what it is
well I cannot fit it in their status and
WLAN are mistakes in Berlin super okay
Monica not a smellinator do you know
male in a tree it gives you males so
built one with the name whatever you
choose just choose a name
alright so the other top well maybe
you've chosen and dressed with lots of
crap because anyone can use it so you
better use a different one because a
longer one so this is the other top here
police use your new email
so a smellinator dot-com as if you'd
wear your normal one mile inator
mailee nadir that come so I captured
this is the security one good girl
please now it's not the time so it says
you will get an email with instructions
to sign up so you use yourself your
email now I'm sorry about that
you should get an email so click it and
you have a token on the URL you can see
that and let me just tell you okay use a
password not not a usual one any other
password it has to be longer there it
measures the length of the password so
click on the eye down there that you can
see there's a lengthen entropy measure
if you to something like that you will
not be able to you've registered to sign
up it has to be a bit more solid robust
so as you can see you need something
that is longer twenty characters whoa
twenty so okay here it so how to letter
small letters you can copy it if you
wish you can copy/paste it if you wish
bit longer
you
okay you can have that one copy it for
later and just fill it in anyway so
choose longer thins but
you
all right so sign up now it's produced
an ecliptic a fifty depends on the
password and the other one depends on
the question so you've your sign up now
so click anywhere and you will go on to
login and say remember yes or else you
type it not difficult but yes in case
okay get code because we have a second
authentification factor that will be
emailed to you right now same
cryptographic key as before so we'll be
using it so email next okay so if you
have it
all right so a secret anything you want
doesn't matter
it'll measure the length and that's not
compulsory do you just need to see
whether the sicut erat in aids got the
strength that is needed or not and
that's your secret so if you press
reload you get it from the reload and
you get it from the database so this is
coming from the database and this is
encrypted you need to press decrypt so
there one under volume there you have it
leave it there and you copy then on the
right side that's my cell phone that's
my account so move the window away so
that it you can see so there you have it
on the right side you see my cell phone
these are my cigarettes and so I'll move
to the tickets here with me and there
you see roll wanted to share cross-site
scripting thank you very much for your
audit by the way and share the secret
then you just produced with my account
you have it there you can share and type
by email which is Hong Hong tota
Torres Garcia that's what it stands for
89 at hotmail.com
I got it here hello you've shared with
me that's a secret thank you very much
[Applause]
I'll finish in a minute so what is the
development the deployment on on in the
cloud so this is an a cell for sealable
container I don't have much money so if
you add lots of things maybe it's easily
scalable but so far the free version is
more than enough what have we not done
the password recovery didn't have time
it has all been planned into database so
we have the responses to security
questions and everything else he's
already but it could not have that and
what else has been done we had I crypt a
challenge locking which adds a good deal
of security because they that never gets
the password and also the key word and
entropy expansion thank you very much
and some future plans for the future and
thank you very much yota vigilant
yeah continuation is security
see
take me out light
para los equipos que quieran es
conveniente cane open - la pantalla nest
indeed oh so please do not get the
extended display because you will need
to use the main screen and you will see
nothing used your laptop and we will use
all other screens we're ready
we are IOT vigilant and before we start
let me think
the organizing per minute for inviting
us with this idea that we came up with
and thought was would be interesting and
we had so much fun the Valentinian even
though we're tired but as you can all
imagine IOT vigilant is a project we
conducted with the idea of modeling
behaviors and devices with a low
interaction such as IOT devices and
because of the massive increase for
these devices and I think we're all
aware of the dangers they entail we
would like to offer some kind of aid to
improve security of those devices so the
idea would be to monitor those devices
on the network on the internet see if
there is any kind of weird behavior with
the device that we're monitoring and
there we would get an alert so the
architecture with thought out for this
is several IOT devices on the same
router this would be a Russ Berrie PI
the Raspberry Pi is connected to the
Internet and then connected to a server
on which it sends met to it it sends
metadata we thought were most
interesting from all the packets capture
from the IOT devices then this data
we keep them on an elastic search for
which we have an algorithm with behavior
modeling the idea is to find these weird
behaviors to report the database the
adductor stretch database and then show
a nice view to the user of how good or
bad the shape in what good or bad shape
the network is we've thought there are
several technologies that can be used to
capture metadata from the packages seen
by the router and so we decided to use
scalping so that any device that can run
Python can run our program our sniffing
and thanks to the years suggestion we
decided to conduct a short rid of
conflict that maybe is a bit more
widespread and it could help us if there
if we see that it is useful and helps
that keep development developing in
which we would marry very much like this
is neighbors yes send data to the server
and we see if there is any kind of weird
behavior with the devices we've already
to discuss this information back to the
server the local server can have an API
rest waiting on this gate as copy to get
all the metadata from the packets
detected and then kept them on
elasticsearch or maybe the server has a
net flow server waiting on them do you
invent them on elasticsearch it
indicates regardless of whether we're
using net flow or scabby for this
elastic search we always skip the same
data and the same structure
and normally detected thanks to the
years help as well it uses a Gaussian
algorithm and Victor will explain what
that means and since I'm running out of
time let's start the demo so first demo
we have several docker files to show you
first the infrastructures using Scapa
and NetFlow with a dia of scene that
they do work and then we'll have a bit
more exposed a mo where we'll say the
full their behavior of the system so
here
we get the Raspberry Pi to send packets
in NetFlow format to my server and the
Raspberry Pi will get all the packets
from all the devices connected and will
send the net flow form of packets to my
server on my server which is a docker
compose that we will get life using just
this so we will use a graph panel these
the server for the net flow data that
will then will be saved in elasticsearch
we don't have time but believe me it
does what I do it does and all three
containers are on and then next on to
the next test same test assess the same
we will use graph Anna Griffin
elasticsearch and the host waiting for
the data but here as inside the RasPi
will be running scaping for that to
happen
so we need to go to the russ berrie and
run the sniffer with the IP the port how
often the interface is not in its to
check and we can also have Mac filtering
so that we can decide what we are
interested in looking and what we are
not so interested in looking into and
inside the server remain machine just to
go live let's use a compose again quite
fast by the way and here we have an
elasticsearch grave funnel and a web
server that allows to you acquire all
those data from Scotty and keep them on
elasticsearch so you could see how we
are saving this insight but we are
actually short of time and we still need
to discuss what's most interesting here
so great and finally
let's discuss a fall full deployment
which does work by the way and for that
all we have to do is in sight the rest
Barry we ran the same commanders before
but here we've added certain protocol
HTTP 5 so that it's locked
using HTTPS we've used a self-signed
certificate because for our demo we
would not do anything more professional
than that but we wanted to show that we
can do this the safest way please
encrypt in traffic so I have it here and
you can see every number indicates they
metadata from a packet capture is sent
to the server that will look into it and
it will see if there's any kind of
anomaly for which we send we changed the
connection and meanwhile we explained
the algorithm we used model it the
starting idea was to use an anomaly
detection algorithm that would be based
in intensity but as discussed with the
euros because of memory years we were
recommended he years got him mix
algorithm we decided to change and so
that you understand what we've done in
order to choose the number of course in
components with swept wanted 10
components with scant 1 to 10 components
and then with minimized it and this is
the number of components were given
let's see if it connects we with some
we've tried with a small setup with a
limited setup we found changes in the
behavior this is great phenom and this
is a short dashboard where you see up
there the traffic that we get from the
sniffing and what it's not too
complicated but down there what's that's
what's interesting that's the behavior
of our network what we're measuring here
is how weird the data we get from the
network are using the DMM model and
there you see for example for a value
that is 0 here this would be the regular
behavior and with an increase like this
this percentage how much is it these are
30 percent right we thought that from 30
percent a change in behavior we will
start an alert and this kind of data we
got them through the presentations for
which we had the lab and we've managed
to produce this change this detection
and by downloading Netflix films and
nothing or doing that or just scanning
with nmap on the network and that's all
I security and cyber watcher
of course it's not working as a with any
demo this is off so let's leave our
friend little frontier does it work
doesn't matter so we still beat out of
the room so okay so we are intelligence
security and we had the monitoring and
management of security for SMEs so this
is a service because that's what it is
with lots of technologies we were very
ambitious I guess we are the most
ambitious team ever since the avengers'
and trying to provide security for
people who don't have it so ever since
Avengers we are more tearing the given
security people who own a business but
are vulnerable and don't have the
resources or the knowledge to face that
and first thing I wanted to say is these
have been too heavy days at cyber camp
we've sweat blasts we had fun we've met
interesting people and we've seen so
many interesting projects so we were
three people
and after the hackathon it's two of us
but but we had someone who deflected
last minute and there's a new team that
we want you to meet and let's go and see
if we can hear me
so Google Toxie security agent okay this
is the latest version of security agent
good morning
something you are I'm a virtual
assistant that using lateral language to
report on the security of your company I
can detect several threats thanks to
other components that I set up in your
infrastructure even the right now I'm
not very intelligent and ready to
incorporate new attack detection
techniques and learn faster better than
my former colleagues that for sure javi
she's all done you here we have it as
well
we have many reports
okay this one is going on so this is a
demo well this is state of the art we
wanted to discuss child at the
challenges achieved or the landmarks
achieved it's been C days we were
studying from scratch we learned about
new technologies we've been touching
modules here and there and so many
repositories and only three people and
in the end we wanted to divide it into
three parts which is the application
that the fraud and the virtual assistant
and then the backend so how do you read
all an app for the move I'll add more or
less we got something that is decent
enough we have an app we will discuss it
later on but here you have it not
working oh here it is on the Internet
[Music]
so we've reached it all almost
everything you see the alert and devices
and users and even alerts from alerts
from the users then we also had the
version virtual assistant that we
present it now we've managed for the
assistant to be able to answer what a
lot of questions provide quite a lot of
details and also it's quite interesting
that if somebody knows nothing about
security like my parents for instance
they've got me they think I know
something so they have a doubt they can
ask me well people could ask the
assistant I've been working with javi
on the back at the back end mostly
working with different technologies
because happy we've covered most of the
components and we set out ourselves to
do
an infrastructure with different pieces
of equipment communicating with a
central server at the beginning we were
thinking of using spark we then decided
to use elastic search at the hillside
and so on
and a server on frosh I'm working with
elastic search and so that Lukas our
colleague could then pick pick up on
that for mobile details so we've covered
that as well or most of that we also
proposed a number of different
capacities that we can see up on the
screen now
for instance alerts and logs have been
covered we've also called a qivana to be
able to visualize real-time reporting
and then threat threat hunting and
security intelligence for threat
detection we haven't done so much of
that we've covered some modules we've
got the infrastructure for more modules
to be included but we didn't have time
to cover all of that why because we
forgot offer about a basic capacity that
is the infrastructure we thought are
we'll just set it all up on
elasticsearch and Amazon and that will
only take a couple of minutes well it
didn't we were wrong there so I think we
can run the demo No
and I'm first going to show you here the
central server including elasticsearch
this is where our detection system is
running it's like a small driver with
different plugins to detect a number of
things there will be a config file so
that this is more a little bit more
simple so that collecting information
from the servers and alerts will be
generated that will be stored on elastic
search and then sent to the smart
assistant on the mobile phone so let me
just show you some more or less real
examples now on the demo
for the detection service to work it
just needs to be hidden and then we can
modify the config file which is not what
we're going to do now anyway
let's run that you see that initial
modules are working one for detecting
different injections on web applications
for instance as a very simple module
covering the whole range depending on
the data well
scripting file Traverse or that type of
thing running for the time that you
specify on the config file we have
prepared a web application with a
cross-site scripting is called
multi-lane this is a fire pit and SQL
and that sends details to elasticsearch
and then the program I showed you
earlier will work with that so that the
alert can show it's quite simple
properly their letter size is too small
so the service is now monitoring
everything parsing the logs and the
information on elasticsearch so look at
that let me stop it right now
is detected there has been a call on a
new a URL so it gets the parameters
getting the contents of each parameter
and then it starts comparing up against
a set of data there are metrics that
allows it to see similarities and
differences between them and then it
gives you the likelihood of it
correspondent corresponding to the
cross-site scripting and there was the
notification alert did you see that it
says hi there has been a new alert
coming to the system this is the
injection detector poor javi has been
suffering all the tests on his mobile
phone and in that case it would be
associated to the user who might have
been the source of that threat there's
also a dashboard that talks about the
general status and then general
information for people to read and check
up on google l can I talk to my security
assistant sorry I don't know how I can
help you I'm still learning
okay Google please tell me what do you
want me to talk about
I want to talk to the security agent
sorry I can't help you talk to the
security agent Google ok then I'm going
to find the last version of the security
agent tell me the status of the
company's security and the injection
code attack has been attacked detected
what is and what is that a code
injection means an attacker might be
trying to compromise your company's
security including unexpected values in
some of your web applications you see
that's how it works
[Applause]
cyber watcher the next team and the
following team just get ready because
you'll be coming next is cyber Spartans
we know when I started this I that good
afternoon
there seems to be a slight technical
hiccup let's hope we can overcome it
we asked the cyber cyber watchers that
the name of our team Santi Javier and
myself three of us so as soon as it's
all ready we will continue with our
presentation
I see market I would be very sorry my
laptop seems to have crashed it was
already but it was but I probably waited
too long with his own
yeah just better title
I can go confidently simply
hello he's no other screams working only
the smaller ones I can't send anything
on my laptop
okay we can all see now what we're doing
not something apologies and thank you
for your patience
Molly ela presenter first align
when is it good now he's finally working
that's right I corrected it yeah I've
done it thank you
so as Miguel Anka said our name is cyber
butchers
we wanted to design a platform that we
are calling as soap so that users cannot
be identified for logging purposes or
identification purposes on websites so
that there can be a centralized platform
and we can use it when logging in or
having to identify themselves as users
so double factor identification so we
couldn't make the USB to work properly
we had a library that supposedly would
do that for us but our browsers couldn't
identify the fingerprint identification
for some reason so what did we do use
the user credentials username and
password and then as extra security
sending a PIN number to users so that
they first register then web sites that
want to use our platform for users to
authenticate would need to register with
us as well and then that would all be
matched so for IT management we used the
ID standard which we think is the most
mature technology at the moment
what have we been doing here well mostly
learning how to use the fingerprint
detector as my colleague said but
unfortunately the internet doesn't seem
to know that we have iru 4000 so that's
why we couldn't use it
the authentication service finally will
work with an SMS with the additional
security given by the pin number and
then we had the idea that the cyber camp
teams could take a vote on how they
think this authentication might work
because our platform would get up users
registering just once giving their
details and whatever we think is
necessary and then the platform through
open ID would give websites a
information in some cases maybe the
email address is wrong but otherwise
very basic information and the voting
application the idea is that user would
log in you would have their email
address just to make sure that people
that you know people have voted or they
don't vote twice or that they don't vote
on behalf of somebody else as I said
because the pin code will be sent by SMS
that will be added security I think
we're going to see this better here on
this diagram this is a flow diagram call
it what you will you can see there the
three stakeholders users with their PC
the soap s SOP platform that's us and
then the voting platform that would be
the third party system so the cyber camp
website in this case I would have to
register as client with us as the SSL P
platform you
would also have to register with us at
the platform and then when users start
their session then the cyber cyber
voting website sends the logging to our
platform and if the user name and part
and password are correct we will send
this the text message with the ping code
and that's when the platform could say
right
authentication is correct and let it
through or we've also studied situations
where when the website could even keep
as I said earlier the users email
address and use that as added security
and control we didn't have time for the
registration well with Jango we did
cover a little bit of that we have got
as far as the token point there so that
access could not be doubled or repeated
so what would happen next well the user
would fault shall I run the demo next
but just a couple of comments one of the
advantages that the SLP platform offers
the real innovations are was well
avoiding data redundancy you don't need
to have credentials stored at different
data bases we think that's really
positive the disadvantage is that they
sent the system is centralized so if it
crashes
everything goes or is halted that's why
security has to be super tops for
storage to really really not be
vulnerable what else originally we
wanted to implement biometrics as
an added element with thoughts and
thoughts and finally came up with other
possibilities for future improvements
for instance parental control apart from
your mobile phone number you could have
somebody else's phone number for
instance in the case of minors or
youngsters with for instance a betting
addiction or gaming addiction well there
might be some limitations for certain
individuals that to be defined so this
is our standard bootstrap template here
we have the teams to be voted and this
is their sights on a thousand and one
just as an example website this is the
admin button to access jungle itself so
when starting your session Open ID means
that the website 8000 would come on and
this is where we validate with our
username and password that means the
user would know that the cyber voting
application is going to ask for his or
her ID must be because of a token right
let's accept us then the second token
and apologies for the design because
it's not very pretty so
my colleagues mobile phone has been sent
the pink coat that's right I've got it
here all I have to do now is it okay let
me tell you six six seven one seven five
that's the code sorry six seven one
seven five double six sorry Wow let's
take advantage of this I'm going to
enter it wrong I'm going to get it wrong
and that's with a random keypad by the
way next one one four eight three one
four now the next one I was sent just
now so that one's correct I entered it
correctly this time something went wrong
what was it
I lost my token because I entered it
wrong first time round or I took too
long must have been something let us let
me just try and do it again just quickly
sometimes the token seems to go missing
can you give me the new number four five
top of five sorry four five double 5 9 6
right
you see there's the token we had huge
problems with integrating with open ID
use USB all sorts believe me but I know
we now have the token and the voting
website could then register access the
vote and then see as our session oh
sorry the closing session button doesn't
exist yet we have no time to do that
what would we like to do in the future
well adding biometrics fingerprint
authentication for instance improving
also the registration process for users
and websites reinforcing the security at
the SSO P server and also use
registration of identity for users we
would like to improve that thank you
very much for your attention and last
but not least we will now be hearing
from the last team Spartans
what
well nosotros somos Yanni Spartans live
I mean that so our team cyber Spartans a
wanted to design water to prevent and
protect against the times attacks
through a point or scoring system this
is the infrastructure on docker stirring
the logs coming from the machines the
container with Python and the
application and then this area here to
save the tables the auxiliary or
ancillary tables let me run it because
at the moment is still a little bit slow
and in the meantime as the docker
compost M is working let me just remind
you that one of those is going to work
as in it attack Ram if the other two
will be sending info to elasticsearch
the demo is too long and because it's
playing in the background I will have to
skip some pieces this is the v1 machine
sending requests and a having access on
the other two virtual machines later all
from v1 we will see that v2 works with
you
RP tables you can see there are no
written rules at the moment that means
we can still have access and in the
meantime the rest of the infrastructure
is getting ready to run so elastic is
going to pick up on all the elements
and this is what we need for the
application to use later this is the
window with the indices at the top
coming from the two virtual machines
with the file bits at the bottom we have
the containers running for the
infrastructure to be maintained as logs
are sent you see that at the top it says
that 4364 documents have been covered
and now the Mongo table here just to
show you how the scores are stored at
the moment is at fifteen and no actions
will start until it goes over 100 so
what have we managed to cover during the
competition during the hackathon
collecting the logs then the analytics
and sending that to Mongo for the score
to be studied and for actions and
decisions to be made in the background
we'll have a process can we see the
whitelist table up on the screen right
because analytics first checks if an IP
is on the whitelist and then nothing
happens but if it's not on that
whitelist then we have to check the
scoring table and decide which measure
should be implemented and when that
happens well we've covered the
distribution of actions the IP table
that the rules so that the rules can run
on IP tables for that attacker and then
well this is something we did wrong
because we've got this particular one on
the y
list and then is not going to work so
which elements did we not have time to
cover because of errors we made for
instance we have not analyzed the logs
we had problems with parsing the logs
the elastic didn't get the Jason's as it
should have done
we couldn't compare with a blacklist we
had to externalize configs because at
the moment technical users are on the
headers that should be improved for the
future we wanted to do re-indexing of
the elastic indices and we haven't done
that so when we analyze the logs they're
raised logically in the future and we
should have re-indexing of those logs so
they're not lost there should also be
some triggers on the Mongo database so
that there's panning or D by deepening
we're needed so there I made another
mistake I removed one
I shouldn't have removed so now because
I run it twice then is there panning and
D burning is not going to work properly
so if the system gets blocked and this
is the way to deep and I have to add the
one that I'd removed before otherwise I
will be burning myself on the background
this is the deepening task checking
which ones are bad and which one are
going to the whitelist we need to have
the heart or the bore of the changing of
this one but still we don't have the way
of doing it Cyndi's on docker we can
dump that the container and go life
again but before I do ban them yes I
defined it too fast let me show the clip
again let me say about the future and
lets me talk about the future we haven't
discussed the future yet but we want to
see that the well the idea is that every
machine sends the same file bit and we
have one index on elasticsearch and so
maybe the key would be too long so the
idea is for every mission to send the
index and with multi-processing we would
gather one of the index and then treat
them individually i had banned this one
and from the IP tables in the machines
and we see that the virtual machine one
IP had been bantered several times and
when added to the white list steel band
and then removed them and when we're
back it works a must be too fast and
maybe too messy and that's
enough
bueno hey como yeah I must have in our
last present a few nerves he since we're
done with that well we have 13 extra
minutes this is a first
actually we got 13 minutes because
there's a team missing I'll check but I
think there's no one from a Blix here so
that you see that we had measured it to
the beat let me thank you for having
stuck to time when was the time to be
over which is painful on us but for this
hackathon we thought it would be three
hours but because of a larger amount of
teams we had to stick to the time that
we had had for some time and we would
have liked to give you more time for
final presentations where you're risking
it all but it wasn't possible so let me
well we do whatever you want we can
start with questions here and use all
the time but I think a break would be
better so that you clear your heads and
see you back at 6 now the hackathon room
and that we will have the Q&A right and
ready for sentence thank you very much
to all of you
[Applause]
you
[Music]