[Music]
smell you see our us simian Odyssey
Valley benefit o noble title when I am
good morning everyone thank you very
much for coming so we are perfectly
conscious that we are very close to
lunchtime okay we will try to be
entertaining when they call for papers
for several camp was published our
company was very young only one and a
half years still we were very clear that
one of these our objectives were was to
make ourselves known and one of our
objectives were were one of the things
that we wanted to do were to participate
in call of papers and then at the time
presentation ready presentation that I
delivered the university of málaga third
presentation lasted was a present 20
minute presentation and this time we
have an hour so therefore I decided not
only to talk about my experience but
also to share with you the experience of
my partner and then I mentioned that to
my wife under my wife said well my but
my profile was a purely technical
profile and perhaps not everyone would
be will feel related to it but because
my partner has a different profile so we
decided also to share that with you well
yesterday well short ago we heard about
talking about different profiles working
in cybersecurity you can tell from our
clothing that we are too dramatically
different profiles
and then when we take partying projects
okay we often who can introduce
ourselves as it says on the screen okay
this is myself this is my partner Jose
and now because we are kind of in well
very close to you okay we would just
want to be warm in our presentation
I come from Granada I live in antique
areas so therefore I am playing home
today I went to I to school in Grenada I
love data I love beer and I fit in very
well with these prototype of especial
who had a vocation for service security
a vocation that started as a very very
young age and I have hacking blood one
of my Gary Gary is my me ancestor so
what I said is that I have that I
carried that in my blood so I come from
Delta I'm living in Madrid I'm a proud
father I'm a follower of athletic
football team I love traveling and
nowadays I also became a businessman and
now I would like to ask you especially
young people here while hearing this
play many people dreaming of becoming a
civil servant but nowadays being an
entrepreneur is also trendy how many of
you in this room would like to be an
entrepreneur well there is a good number
of people who want to be entrepreneurs
and that's why we are here for today we
are here to talk to you about
entrepreneurship if you have realistic
well weaving her company is a young
company only one and a half years so we
do not have that much experience but
still we feel that we are in a position
to share something with you and to help
you out when I gave this presentation at
the University of Granada the person who
asked me to give that presentation I
told this person I don't know very much
about entrepreneurship and then this
person said no no no don't worry do go
over there and you just share his story
with your audience and I said ok so and
say well my story is hackers which is a
movie that was launched in 1995 at the
time in 1995 I was 12 years old and I
was fascinated
well first of all I was fascinated by
Angelina Jolie I'm still in love with
her and I was also fascinated by
everything that was happening in that
film I wanted to become a cyberpunk and
then to carry a backpack with a 5
kilogram computer in here running across
the city
chasing the bad guys having a Chinese
friend I loved it ok my field was
Braveheart I'm not going to tell you
about any of the words and the struggles
and
[Music]
well I feel I can i still like to watch
it
I very much like to go back to the time
where I discovered the world of hacking
through that film
now I play some of the frames of the
movie precisely what you will see is
what Xhosa myself are doing nowadays so
no it is especially the part when they
talk about the color boots
different places thank you
they play video
mr. vinegar is in d.min Dovahkiin
position baek-moo Japanese money on the
pitch or we'll see you Logan
no tenemos nombre es muy no Mercedes
Antonio's Phyllis una parada a serial
killer there's no moon but another
technical skills can get internal
Sonic's internationalism furiosa normal
everyday informatica departamento de
vincennes commissioner selig EI bay mare
ever taste the merciful love like a mr.
prosecutor van tol about that there's a
liberal el diablo navi-x mr. lee brother
draconian colleague or twenty I see he
is not a liberal internationalism
tambien yamadharma literally broke a new
covenant standing as Apple EQ like a
Havilah flip that movie that javi loved
talked about that orange book that us
orange book the which was the first
standard for system evaluation criteria
so well it is started in the US and many
other countries George it and
implemented as a computer system
evaluation criteria it was well javi
myself have been dealing and working in
their computers using evaluation
criteria for 11 years now okay when
having watched the film for the first
time ever he would have never have
dreamt that at the end the in few years
time he would be working in that field
so the importance of that
movie has been seen in few years time
and then when we talk about
entrepreneurship often we talk about the
world of ideas that you need to have
like a breakthrough a disruptive idea
innovative idea an idea that ever end up
changing the world but look what
happened to me actually I have no idea
yes I don't think I ever heard a
destructive idea well I just had a
business model and I tried to business
model and I tried to replicate it as
best as possible but what I always had
in my life was a dream a dream which was
quite simple that was to say to devote
my life to something that I loved
something that I was passionate about
and I also want to
fulfill my dream and to live in the
place where I want to live I come from
Ranade and I love Granada and I want to
live in Granada and I also wanted to
fulfill my dream and to work with the
people that I wanted to work with
and now a dream that you put a day to
becomes goal a goal which has his broken
down in the steps becomes a plan and
implemented plan can turn a dream into
reality okay this is the only complex to
follow a step in from the self-help book
but at the end of the day this is true
this is the way it is we all have dreams
but we really need to put a date
deadline to fulfill our dreams we need
to give a timeframe to it
if we don't do that we will leave most
likely be bitten or by laziness or by
the mandates of society or by what the
others expect from us and then was
extremely important having a plan if you
want to achieve a goal the best way or
easiest way to achieve your goal is to
break it down into steps the steps that
you have to follow that ultimately will
take you to fulfill your dream and this
is what I did step number one work in
the field that I want to work have you
heard about a key guy this word here
it's a term a Japanese word that means
what makes you wake up every or get up
every morning it became very famous
after TED talk I guess you're familiar
with TED talks they it was talked about
longevity they carried out a study and
they saw in which regions of the world
people lived longer and they saw there
was a bunch of Isles south of Japan
Okinawa region where people lived longer
it longer than the rest of Japan which
is the control with highest life
expectancy in the world and besides the
climate food and other factors one of
the factors that made these people live
longer is was that everyone had a clear
idea about their ikki guy the thing that
made him get up every morning later on
psychologists have developed this idea
and they say that EQI is the crossing
point for the combination of the things
you like things the work needs the
things you can be paid for the things
you're good at the crossing point
between these four areas is your ikigai
here's you we say passion your passion
your mission your vocation and your
profession if you combine these four
things and you can do that apparently
you're going to live longer in order to
find your ikigai
they say that you need to ask yourself
four questions first with which things
you feel really comfortable there are
people who feel really comfortable just
picking him in front of an audience but
for other people they have it's horrible
other people risky sports is really
great and for others well they would
never do it
another question with which activities
time goes by really quickly I'm sure
there are things that you started to do
them and time goes by very quickly it's
3:00 a.m. and you still sit in front of
your computer and you say oh I can't
believe I haven't realized how late it
is what things if I'd easy did well have
natural talents natural skills some
people draw perfectly well and others
like myself were poor drawers so the
natural abilities that define your et
guide for example I cannot prepare a
PowerPoint presentation I can't live it
the last question was what did you like
when you were a child that's very
important in order to discover your icky
guy as
we get older society teaches you things
they force you through towards the path
which is not necessarily yours but one
year kid you just thinks more naturally
and you devote your time to things that
make you happy in my case it was perfect
here when I was a kid I like this
I was super freak and I was lucky
because when I was a kid my brother was
eight years older received this device
as a present and three months later he
was sent to a boarding school so I got
to keep the computer
I was very young back then I didn't have
games but I wanted to play with a
computer I had that book that handbook
with a series of games it was a knockin
idea need to edit it to copy it and once
you had copied you executed copy I mean
six seven pages of code and if it was
correctly copied you could execute it
and then you could play I didn't know
about print coat or anything similar I
just copied what was stated there and
then I could play my game
then we had the Golden Age of Spanish
software there were plenty of games you
could I could play with plenty of games
but that my mother bought me department
stores were in flea markets there were
cracked games they were like this it
looked like they were great with the
graphics the graphics back there were
more or less like this so there was a
difference between the cover and the
actual game and my first contact with a
hacking world was pokes this is before
the Internet era back then we didn't
have internet at home
and the only way we could access this
type of information with the magazines
that reach your neighborhood if you were
lucky because if they didn't you had to
go to the other part of the city to look
for the magazines this comes from the
English verb to poke which means to
change when you change memory address it
was code exceeder sibling cold and you
modified the game so that when he
detected that you had crash into your
enemy well it was as if you hadn't
crushed into it and things like that so
you can imagine after all of this when I
was 15 I was studying at high school I
thought I was God with my Linux is
diskettes to install it I just watched
the film hackers I spent the whole
nights in IRC remote session I did
everything I could I used to tell my
parents I'm going to be self-taught
hacker a study and going to learn much
more than at university my mother was
terrified at the thought that his child
was going to end up in prison robbing
banks poor woman
and one day she said you're going to go
to university you didn't study computing
science so I went there to grandmother
to study that I didn't like it because I
want I wanted to be a self-taught hacker
but with time I thanked it because I
know the love of data structure
mathematics that were essential to
understand more complicated concepts
notes so the naps I took and the friends
I made we were a thinner in that picture
but that's us and I have nice memories
from that time we studied at University
for five years to you not bad
we didn't like going to class but we
managed to finish our studies in five
years but I wanted to continue in the
world of cybersecurity but unfortunately
yet another was not a good place for
that in 2006 the world the word
cybersecurity was not something you
would listen you would hear in Granada
so like many people from my class I had
to go to Madrid I started to work for a
consulting company and after a while I
received a job proposal a job offer in
which a job was offered and they
required knowledge about assembling
regular expressions and for me there was
the big up to nity so I went for it I
got it and I started to work there with
that orange book I remember then when
they told me that I was accepted
they sent me for PDF files for me to
read is for books and for me was the
dream come true because I could finally
work in what I wanted my life was
simpler when I was a kid I used to play
football
perhaps I watched football with my
father and TB but I was it I had never
heard about cybersecurity I was doing
what I wanted but it's true that when
you're a child and adolescent a teenager
that's important for you there are some
things that happened and have a
consequence in the future I would say
there was mainly my parents my father
used to say this walk the talk I could
just say that I had studied but I had
fail the exam no he wanted hard facts
and your life you want facts
another thing my father said you have to
listen see and shut up you I would
change it I think you have to speak of
when it's the right time not at the
wrong time and this sentence is from my
mother nothing in the world can replace
being constant it doesn't matter how
good you are if we do not continue to
work in the world of cybersecurity what
we did 10 years ago is completely
different from now you have to recycle
yourself all the time so the education
received when you're a child even it has
nothing to do with cybersecurity it laid
the foundations for my training I've
always looked for challenge for
challenges I remember I was at school
and so I was very happy but I saw that I
received good marks even I didn't do a
good job I got bored and I remember that
when it was time to move on to high
school I told my parents I was I wanted
to go to private to a public high school
I went there it was a very good for me
and my little brother went that high
school after me then picking up a degree
at University I studied computer science
speakers when I was in high school there
was a psychology there and he told me
okay you're going to become really rich
with computing science I didn't have
much I said okay why not
perhaps I think I've let myself low
until I I decided to to do what I was
going to do with my life I started to
work with a consulting company in Madrid
because they come to an employment fair
in Granada they showed us a job first
experience and back then it was quite
fashionable working for a consulting
company we just spent the same six seven
months are you familiar with culture
over time well 12 years ago the cool
thing was staying after working hours
because other times it would look like
you were not you were not good enough
after while there I said these guys are
crazy and I wanted I left when my
working hours were over
and in consulting world the usual thing
was for bosses to be really hard on you
as I've said before my football team is
at lady and our trainer coach says the
people behave in the football pitch same
way they behave in the personal life I
think that this situation has changed a
lot
cyber what
after six months in a consulting company
my friend told me do you want to come
and work with me in cybersecurity
I said well I don't know maybe things
have changed a lot in CB was born in
2005 and this happened in 2007 no one
spoke about cybersecurity ever I knew
something a little bit between you know
having a beer with him perhaps he said
something but I had no clue about it why
did I go to cybersecurity what would
they paid more you work you're working
hours and you it wasn't frowned upon and
he said there are nice challenges here
you're just not copying and pasting and
a website for another client they're
very interesting things here so I liked
it we had with the power start
challenges we were given time to
understand products in product
assessments and I started to love it it
was the first time that I thought ok I
could work in this it's very interesting
and my past was basically playing
football
met Rita was nice I think I went every
possible theatre musicals don't get
fooled his wife lived the south of Spain
yes my wife lived in south of Spain and
I had a dream I wanted to do this but in
the south of Spain not in Madrid so the
date came closer I worked in Madrid for
five years I learned what it was getting
up early in the morning in order to go
to work
traffic jams managing teams teaching
people junior people learning from
people with more experience being humble
and accepting that there are people that
much better than you are
that those were things that had to learn
and those here in Madrid
they were very useful for me then I was
lucky to work with Xhosa they were
friends from from University those if
you have done things like this one there
are few feelings which can compare to
overcome a challenge we dance when we
make made something explode over making
something overflow and we had fun a lot
of fun but time went by and one day I
said this is it and I quit I am I had a
good salary a promising career but it's
not what I wanted so with the contacts I
made I wanted to I went to run Anna and
I had a part-time job in bio tronic my
sister-in-law's company well that's life
she worked in microcontrollers and I
helped her
and at the same time the other part of
my day was devoted to cybersecurity
consulting as a freelance so I could
work in something I liked in the city
and light in the middle of the crisis so
he was very brave and I was with my
girlfriend back then she's my wife today
so it was great wonderful years however
there's something that they don't tell
you when you decide to become an
entrepreneur and it's paperwork you're
not aware of how how many things we have
today
since you're self-taught yourself taught
for everything and you don't go to a tax
advisor you study the law Social
Security the tax forms everything
self-taught
well I received some fines because I
made mistakes in my paperwork
and besides there was the commercial
side of it I needed someone to sell
myself I'm not good at selling myself
I'm good at the gate board and I
realized that I needed help
what did I do I heard another friend
from university his company has just had
just went into bankruptcy and I realized
that he did the cool things and I was
his salesperson I did the paperwork but
he did the coolest things
I spent seven years doing technical
things but at some point every time I
woke up in the morning was worth because
then a little boy when they have to go
to school I'd liked learning I had the
foundations but I was bored and you
don't know how sad it is to wake up at
the morning in order to go to work
without wanting to you and I wanted
something else I wanted to lead teams I
wanted to move forward as a professional
and I remember one of my bosses he said
just a soldier and I said well that's
hot and the sahabis
says it was a good salary good working
hours when I explained this to my
friends it laughed at me they said
what's your problem
you're privileged person perhaps I was
but every morning it was very hard
and my god an angel came to me it was
LinkedIn I would have never thought of
sending surveys to companies in the
industry and one day a company called me
and they said it was a competitive and
they said do you want to be in charge
the Common Criteria who service but
beginning I said that crazy what do they
see in myself now nowadays link eating
is it's a very common thing but four
five years ago wasn't that common in
fact they coded us through LinkedIn but
they called the the company they called
my company and asked for me and that's
how many adventure was born in your life
I would say
they told me that I had to be a
technical manager I'd said that's
perfect
I have the project
I help with the projects I had trouble
at the beginning it was really cool once
you start to travel all the time you
didn't like it that much but I was young
so I had everything in control managing
teams it was okay I like being with
people I like that part but no one told
me that I need to you carry out cell
tasks the first week when I arrived they
said tomorrow we have a meeting with
some Chinese guys and we need to sell
this to them what do you know who you've
hired perhaps you're wrong and no one
ever trained me about how to sell and
now I sell my company's services so my
only solution was being myself
I'm not interested at selling techniques
what I did back then and what I do now
was being honest with people being
myself before explaining offering before
explaining a problem I had to make my
problem mine and then I had to provide
my client with solutions I have a story
with a client from Israel they called on
a Sunday they were very angry we guess
we had made a big mistake and we
accepted it we started work on it we
solved it and that same client has
continued to work with us because he
would say perhaps
someone else would have blame others
read the small things in the contracts
but we just accepted reality there's
been a failure we fail all the time
cobby tells me I'm bipolar I say one
thing then he talks to me and then I
changed my view and I say it's okay I've
just changed my mind I tried to be
myself all the time I happen to prepare
this talk we made the slides
representation and then I go with the
flow and that's how I like to do things
so when I arrived there they told me my
position was common critique criteria
leader I thought my boss is crazy how
could he come up with his name I still
think that he was a bit crazy a very
good person though
and one day he said this and for me it
was quite affirmative ation he was
motivated to see that people below him
in the company he was motivated to see
them grow I'm sure he's happy for me and
I have that with people working with me
I always try that they grow to make them
grow and if you manage to start in the
future you'll see how satisfactory it is
I love the job but the truth is that
sometimes you love it so much that well
sometimes I thought they come the money
earned by the company was mine have you
ever seen this video have you seen it
that's how I felt when I was given the
job
[Music]
when I was given the BlackBerry my
company's blackberry I felt like this
you're just no one with a blackberry
that's it
and for a while I was that and if you
haven't worked in the consulting
industry well I believe that
so I saw that my life was not a normal
one it was very important to have a
personal life to have a balance and with
the what does I have in my company I
have weird office hours because I'm
taking care of my kid and I sent emails
at weird hours and when they answer me
at that time I get angry because I say
you shouldn't be answering that at that
time you need to protect your personal
life you know it's hobbies turn Y Jose
was living
there's experiences I was working with
the friend I had
where did cool things we had some sort
of infrastructure but we were working in
a small room in my flat it was our
office was not a garage but it was the
idea it was like Bill Gates garage yes
where it was second floor at some point
I wanted to do something else I wanted
to stop being under a Raider I wanted to
start doing bigger things
and also I was given the opportunity to
be a teacher in the master's degree in
cybersecurity the University of Granada
so I thought that the pieces started to
fit together to do something bigger
Arvind
talking to cross it for a while saying
well why don't don't we create something
together we've worked and we were a good
team and he represented the commercial
side of things he had the ability of
talking to clients and he has a good
technical background so partly the
pieces of this puzzle will fit him
little by little
he hasn't said that he was very scared
at creating a company and I had a bit of
a disappointment I think that first you
have to give and then you have to
receive but requesting well if you just
paint two months in a company you can't
request I like things to come naturally
after two years the company had grown a
lot the department decided not to
increase my salary I said okay I have to
travel less and say okay Jose better and
Monty please come to Barcelona because
we have a very important meeting
I requested more resources for more
people and there were promises that were
never fulfilled at some point I felt
like was being a fool we weren't
thinking and being interpreters
just life brought me here
but at some point I took the decision
Abby and I hadn't discussed the details
about work was going to a group we were
going to grade but I said that's it
enough is enough I called my boss and I
told him there's a set I quit I exploded
but in a controlled way you have to be
very elegant in life into my old company
well they hire us it's our main customer
why because I left with elegance I
worked for five months in the company
after saying that was living she lived
things in order I think you always have
to be elegant so we started to talk more
seriously with Hobby we had to make our
calculations we have a couple of napkins
our business plan was very simple
because it was just being brave but I
had doubts what happens if it goes wrong
I had worked in two most important
companies in the field ad we were
working I saw I had to go abroad but I
wanted to stay in Spain and then a
foreign multinational company offered me
to work from home and I said well there
are other opportunities out there I
never thought about that then
I decided to go on a holiday and well
when your holiday is that is almost good
Freddy and at that time I was reading
that book as a working week of four
hours and then well I will did not stick
to that to those four hour quickly hours
oh and then there is a list in this book
about advantages and disadvantages and
everyone talks about entrepreneurship so
since but we have some saved money so
those people who become entrepreneurs
and they ask her to the bank for a loan
and everything they are very
praiseworthy but we didn't we didn't do
that we didn't have to do that and this
is javi and then well he decided to quit
his job and then to go into partnership
and then to set up our company and well
he at the end I twisted his hand and we
assess a setup our company
what is that it's it's
it's a problem with a presentation okay
do you know that the more effect is
exactly the same thing and as I say we
started to build the team because I was
teaching the cybersecurity master's
course then we offered people to come
and work with us and then we also hired
someone to take care of administration
and say well bureaucracy okay and then
well hobby was from Granada
he lived in antequera he wanted to
create the company set up the company in
antequera someone else ed and then we
also sort about Malaga as possible days
for our company and then in the end we
decided for Granada
and I continue to live in Madrid who
knows perhaps in few years some things
will change but nowadays many of there
is a significant business activity in
Madrid so therefore we have that
structure will have the actual office in
Ranade and based in Madrid so I love
living here in the south of his brain
here in the South of his face very easy
for me to go for a few drinks with
friends and well it doesn't ever
happened to me in Madrid ok so I'm not
going to go and live in Madrid so what
are we doing nowadays and what do we do
well I take care of relationship with
customers
well another the other jobs are ihara
also worked indeed lots of teamwork our
company's a very small company our sales
force is just about building up great
working groups and what this is what I
do
teamwork building up good teams and
doing good team work and then as much as
possible we try to deliver presentations
to attend conferences so that to make
ourselves known because we do not have
any sales reps in our company we also
give very good level of service to our
clients to our teams I treat them the
way I would like them to treat me
now I also like to have a life other
than my professional life I spend time
with my kids the time that I could not
spend with my kids if I were to work for
a multinational company I pray so
they're my clients pay me on time or
Juli and then what do I do
well I have fun breaking things this is
something that I always wanted to do now
I'm doing it and I also lead a team of
hackers which is even better fun there
being a hacker yourself
and then we also do R&D we do well small
research we know that this is important
for team-building and now it again well
because of research and development that
we do we are offered to give
presentations at conferences and
congresses and we also take part in
competitions such as CTF well at the end
of the day our company is driven by
three values technical excellence also
commitment with our clients in some of
the projects that we carry out we lose
money and but we are sure that we want
to implement that project with work with
that client and then time to market this
is what we offer as competitive edge and
these are the outside values but when we
decided to create our company we decided
also to stick to a number of internal
values so the first project our be
carried out together was in Malaysia so
the two of us decided to fly over there
12 hour flies than a few years later we
were in Thailand Thailand and then in
that in the trip to Thailand we decided
to
write down the ten values that we
believed were cool for our company and
then in the end we end up with this
Decalogue with this list of ten values
so having these values in place is very
very important because sometimes you are
very busy and then you tend to forget so
if we ever forget we come back to those
values and these are values that we also
share and communicate with our employees
so we just don't want our company to be
just pure machine to make money and now
tips for successful company be
surrounded by the best people the thing
in all the projects you require to have
multidisciplinary team someone who is
well hartle-hawking the other one who
knows about reversing other is about
exploring so it is just impossible to
know it all also motivating your
employees help them growth make them
growth something our company there are
ready to people who have already
delivered presentations are hacking
conferences
so we wanted to go back to their
families and to feel proud of the
company where the work and to speak good
of ourselves or the company they work in
and then we never had any disruptive
idea any breakthrough idea about any
breakthrough product will have our
business model we believed that we can
be better than our competitors and this
is what has taken as where we are now
look for challenges for challenges of
the time you need to challenge in
yourself worth the time has to keep
going - so now we have now turned up Tim
welcome we will be taking part in the
European lympha series for the last
month I've been the problem director of
two congresses we are all the time doing
new things things that help us to drive
ourselves to develop ourselves
professionally so not always things are
take place immediately thinking in the
long term is always important you have
to be elegant you have to be sure that
what you will do today will bear fruits
tomorrow if you treat a client badly if
you treat an employee badly you will see
the negative impacts of it very soon
taking risks but with some control with
some level of control it is good to make
decisions but timely the right time
mainly well you want to become
entrepreneurs and then but perfect but
be entrepreneurs when you are ready for
it when you have all the necessary basis
for it there well many startups are
created but many of them also fail very
soon after being created and I feel that
that could be really disappointing also
her wealth firmament takeaway message go
for that that you actually love so we
may get trained that they finish
training at 20:20 result and get retired
at 65 life expectancy is set at 84 years
old so it means that you will spend 42
years at work working looking forward
for Friday and time off so balance
between work life working life that is
just essential believe it
this mic Hut you have to believe it
yourself be yourself clients like that a
lot
the other day I was with a client was
and he told me well he so he just played
the same joke and I said I just don't
want to work with this person and then
the markets globally say trouble markets
you can do good cybersecurity from
malama from security from Granada from
your small town 80% of our invoicing
turnover comes from work that we do
outside of Spain
so Grenada is a good base for our
company but very very agency that we all
have learning English speaking English
you have to have a good level of English
and this is my personal tip improvise
when you improvise something things flow
when you see a problem when you see
challenge go by your guts okay and this
is something that your clients also can
see and appreciate and do those things
your mother would be proud of if my
mother were to understand what I do
surely she would be very proud of me so
this year I delivered a presentation in
a conference and my parents went over to
Canada to see me delivering that speech
and they were extremely satisfied and
well thank you very much for putting up
with us up until now so we wish you all
the best in everything you decide to do
in life and then well as long as you are
happy right thank you very much
you