[Music]
Cadell my ass today's a todos good
afternoon everyone welcome both to new
faces who've just joined us now and to
those who are here to the bitter end
this is going to be the last session for
the day today and we're going to be
hearing to Santiago but before I
introduce you to him let me just remind
you that you can participate on Twitter
with our hashtag we encourage you to
share pictures comments contents
whatever so let me give you a little bit
of background air for the next session
we have more and more threats to
information security and this struggle
makes it very clear that we need to
further protect our data as much as
possible
well handling information can be
enhanced through machine learning and
we're going to be hearing from Santiago
and Monday's promise about how to do so
effectively Santiago is senior security
analyst at cyber shock at Deloitte he
has a master's and PhD on information
science at the university of zaragoza
i'm sure that you will make the most of
this workshop decision and welcomes at
you the floor is all yours I hope you
can hear me okay
let me thank you for joining me at this
workshop I want to thank the organizers
for inviting me back once again so let's
start with the title of such which is
machine learning our new ally for
information security is this a true
statement
well not quite I say what is not quite
right well the fact that machine
learning is not quite a new ally it
hasn't come up or popped up in the last
couple of years it was there but because
in the past we couldn't capture
information or process it as fast as we
can now what it hadn't boomed the way it
it has more recently this is the table
of contents for my presentation I hope
you can see it ok from the back we'll do
our best
so I will start telling you about the
current situation on cybersecurity
connected with artificial intelligence
and what is machine learning is a buzz
word or a buzz expression we'll see what
applications are possible right now
we'll see something about linear
regression or linear sorry regression we
will see how algorithms can learn I
don't know if learning is the word I
think that is a buzz word in that case
and then more advanced techniques like
classification clustering anomaly
detection and
very simple techniques that you can
probably use for basic security in any
company I don't think we need this
information because I've already been
introduced to you before starting so
let's see the current situation
what is our starting point for cyber
security here and now very briefly at
least I would like to stress a number of
points for instance even though in the
last few years there there seem to be
many more cyber attacks more companies
impacted and at a larger scale that's
what we hear but in fact threats have
not changed that much in the last few
years so that's good news right for us
to detect them it is true that they're
more large-scale more people and more
companies are impacted but still malware
run somewhere different types are the
same very much the same or very similar
at least I also wanted to tell you that
the fact that we have more cyber attacks
or more larger scale cyber attacks led
by maybe mafias shall we call them
rather than by loners as Charlie Miller
says behind and over and about and above
all of this what is at the end of it
what is it well is the bottom line is
money its economy that matters Miller
said that there is a strong evidence
that the best researchers in cyber
security are now motivated more by
monetary gain than by prestige that is
how much money can I make
out of this particular vulnerability
that's why we have mafias that buy
vulnerabilities they launch them
large-scale and they make good money
from doing so
so before we start talking about machine
learning I would like to tell you a
little bit about artificial intelligence
what is the difference between AI and M
a ml sorry they're connected but they're
not the same this is a report from the
American government we see two quotes
from 2018 from this year how artificial
intelligence is changed the American
lifestyle thanks to that we can now
diagnose pathologies better financed
work better transport and mobility has
been enhanced for instance we have
autonomous vehicles to prove us as the
first quote up on the screen and that
very report also said experts forecast
that rapid process in the field of
specialized artificial intelligence will
continue but we don't think that in the
coming 20 years cognitive capacity for
AI will be the same as human cognitive
capabilities so that means that
artificial intelligence is improving
many processes but we should still have
our feet on the ground and understand
that artificial intelligence is well
below a human cognitive
skills and capabilities not now and it
won't be in the coming 20 years probably
certain tasks will improve and some
might even exceed a human capabilities
but not for the global number of tasks
so artificial intelligence and cyber
security this is nothing new this is not
a new field and no matter how some
people are still reluctant when they
hear about machine learning we have to
acknowledge it is used here and now
although not for global complete
solutions but in traditional
cybersecurity processes we can get a
part of it and replace it by machine
learning with a final global improvement
of the process in American report said
the following today's AI has important
applications in cybersecurity and it is
expected that it will play that it will
play increasingly a row both in
defensive and offensive cyber measures
that means that in the coming years the
offensive role will also be present not
just offensively but offensively
attackers using artificial intelligence
and machine learning to develop new more
harmful attacks I haven't seen a lot of
literature connected with a offensive
cybersecurity paired up with AI and AI
now but that's certainly a field of
research for future papers so now let's
see the connection between AI and AI mal
well more and more in recent years
successful applications of artificial
intelligence most all the time they're
using machine machine learning or some
sub disciplines within marshy machine
learning that means that machine
learning is part of artificial
intelligence so which part of artificial
intelligence does it equate to not all
artificial intelligence issues can be
solved through machine learning why
because for machine learning we need
data that subsets of artificial
intelligence machine learning what it
does is uses statistics and processing
but always on data it needs data what is
machine learning in fact well this is
probably the most common definition for
machine learning we see it up on the
screen machine learning is a subset
within artificial intelligence that help
systems learn and improve automatically
on the basis of experience without
having to be programmed to do so it's
based on different hypothesis underlying
the model and it tries to improve it
adjusting with more data within the
model over time the most important part
of that definition has to do with the
fact that we're working with mathematics
and data but then we can infer certain
features that will help us make
decisions in the future make forecasts
and all of this importantly without
teaching the system or programming is to
make those
predictions and forecasts so we now know
what machine learning is although some
of this is quite complex and adjusting
the model or the parameters of the model
we will see more about that shortly and
what types of machine learning do we
have one of them would be supervised
learning we'll see later how we define
learning but let's just remember that
one of the subsets within machine
learning is supervised learning that is
machine learning where there's a mapping
between input and output based on pairs
that means that we have a set of data
where we have an input value output
value we give that to the algorithm we
then give the algorithm an input value
and it will automatically come up with
the output value for us we'll see more
details about that later
and then supervised learning is divided
into two different types classification
and regression was the difference
between them an algorithm using
supervised learning and using
classification it means it tries to
predict or forecast a discrete values
that means they're clearly limited for
instance is an email spam or not that
type of classification whereas in
regression the prediction is or
attempted prediction is for continuous
values or neighboring values for
instance how much does this house cost
well I tell the algorithm that is a
three-bedroom house and then it can
predict
or forecast a costume let's see now more
about regression within supervised
machine learning let me give you an
example we want to predict the cost in
Euros of handling an insurance claim
depending on the system or the equipment
that's been affected for instance in a
security auditing we find a security
failure that involves 100 different
pieces within a company well how can we
calculate and forecast what cost would
be involved in an attack to that system
we need to start by finding other
security incident incidents that
happened in the past see how much those
cost and a check up against the number
of PCs were involved then on a graph how
would that look something like this this
dot here is an incident where 50 pcs
were impacted and the cost was 100,000
euros this is another case with a cost
this is just a way to portray the data
in a group more graphic manner with that
line so the machine learning algorithm
basically builds a model for prediction
look at this very simple example where
the model seems to fit quite well
like so that line would join the dots on
the incident that we've had in the past
and that would be that line would tell
us what the trend is
so let's predict how much a security
incident would cost where 5075 pieces
were involved I have the input variable
there are 75 pcs and that's the result
one hundred and seventy-five thousand
zeroes that would be the predicted
costume this is linear regression where
that straight line is the function for
that forecast for that prediction what
about supervised learning in this case
focusing on classification as opposed to
regression in this case we are
predicting a discrete value is this
particular email spam or not in this
case how am I going to predict it
depending on the spelling mistakes the
number of spelling mistakes and the
number of the on the exclamation marks
on that particular email
why because spam tends to have those two
right so in a small success of emails I
study and see which ones were actually
spam or not and count the number of
spelling mistakes in the number of
exclamation marks on real emails right
this is just a very tiny example with a
very small subset look at this email for
instance with for spelling mistakes six
exclamation marks and it was spam how do
we know well because we've classified it
we know it's not a prediction
well our function could then predict it
like so this would be the function
we're a particular email has to be
checked for those two elements so if
it's on the left of the function
function it would be alleged email
whereas if it falls on the right-hand
side it would be classified as spam
simple example another important area
for machine learning is non supervised
learning in supervised learning the idea
was that we had a set of pairs for
inputs and outputs that is pcs affected
and costs involved right
what about non supervised learning what
it would be machine learning where a
function would be predicted with data
that have not been tagged that is not
classified or categorized that means
that we don't have the output value
let's go back to the spam example we
have a set of emails we don't know if
they're spam or not we categorize them
for exclamation marks and spelling
mistakes and we had the line or function
so that information was given to the
machine learning algorithm as to what
happened in real life
so that it could then predict it not in
this case it's not supervised so the
algorithm doesn't know which emails are
spam or not which is give it the data
and the set of emails in unsupervised
learning machine learning we would end
up with a structure that makes sense
let's look at this situation illogical
grouping it would be having ending up
with these two clusters can you see how
the points there the dots kind of
cluster up together in one area
and the same for the other subset that
would be non supervised learning machine
learning so let's go more in-depth now
for linear regression for us to
understand how learning takes place
don't panic this is quite a common graph
for instance Coursera uses it for their
machine learning courses this is a new
way to define supervised machine
learning in this case we see that we
have the training data sets and that are
fed to the learning algorithm as a
result of that the algorithm creates a
function that we label as a hypothesis
or hypothetic function based on previous
incidents so after that we can have an
input variable the number of PCs that
were affected and then the function
would decide on the forecast or the
prediction based on the training
examples let's go back to the idea of
costs after a security incident how
would a linear regression algorithm work
with his totally made-up set of data
with a number of PCs that were affected
the cost in thousand euros after a
number of incidents where we had those
problems in
whatever company or in a number of
companies so this table is exactly the
same here it's just that on the right we
had a graphic representation in the idea
what this means this is the function for
a line on a graph
straight line
the machine learning algorithm then is
fed the input data and then on the basis
of that it adjust is adjusts a function
so predictions can be made so let's
start with a very simple function write
the straight line something that we
learned back in primary school let's
start by replacing with random
parameters the function has two
different parameters the slope and the
point where it Criss crosses for that
linear function so this is the graphic
representation
we've been plotting here the same is the
same function so if I showed you this
and the number table and I asked you how
how does this represent the trend is it
a good representation or not well you
would have no idea right whereas if you
you look at it like this you get a much
better idea because they are subsets of
data looks like it had a different trend
while the machine learning algorithm
starts like this it generates a line
that doesn't stick to reality and then
the error is calculated what does that
mean well the algorithm gets information
from previous incidents it then portrays
them on the graph and then where we knew
both the input variable and the output
variable well that helps us calculate
the error through an error function
mathematically that works but you can
also use an optimization function what
does that mean that parameters are moved
and changed so that the error can be
minimized how well for instance if I
move it this way it looks like the error
margin is lower it does so as much as
possible until the error can't be
reduced or limited any further what that
would be a pretty good representation of
our data subsets until the error has
been minimized as possible as much as
possible why because it's a straight
line on the graph but is not quite
straight on reality right so now we can
see how algorithms learn in machine
learning quite simply by getting a
particular function in our case the
linear function then seeing which
parameters are important for that model
of function and once that is ready then
it tries to calculate the error present
in our training data subset and try and
optimize it until error is at a minimum
and that would mean the function would
be good for predicting on that
particular data set it's more simple
than you thought it might be right for
algorithm learning so once the error has
been minimized for the model parameters
then we could get the function
we could forget about the data we had we
would just keep the function that means
we would keep the model has been
generated and then use it to predict new
situations for instance when somebody
asks how much would it cost if there was
a security incident and 100 pcs were
affected well we could then go to our
hypothetical function the X will be the
number of pcs affected or impacted a and
then let me remind you that the model
was used just to get these parameters
here once we've got them then the
training of the algorithm is over the
prediction would be reliable for they
said the success that we used for
algorithm training so that's the most
simple size of machine learning how al
gore-ism x' work how supervised learning
gets the data both inputs and outputs
where as non supervised learning doesn't
get the output output variables now we
are ready to talk about classification
which is the part of supervised learning
where we want to predict discrete
examples if an email is spam or not we
see the linear regression that help
predict continues values such as the
cost of a security incident incidents is
this an example I gave you we could also
use it to forecast how many 15 emails or
span emails will be receiver to given
Organization for a month we can even
forecast
within a company which one would get
most of the spam email so the
classification here if you check it out
and you think it through this would be
our daily activity as professionals in
cybersecurity for example for every
email that we received an analyst can
see whether it is phishing or it is not
for every file on the network whether it
has malware or not also any query for a
command and control and these are all
predictions discrete predictions of
forecasts is it a command control yes or
not is a bank transfer yes true note
these request is a do s attack yes or no
we also need to consider when we talk
about classification is the fact that
many companies nowadays gather data such
as logs and events and processing all
this data and the search for requests
for threats can be done down in a way
that is not machine learning the fact
that we are using data to predict
whether an email spam or not doesn't
mean that were using machine learning if
we use it to see whether a URL is
malware or not does not mean that this
is machine learning
what about gridforce onin attacks on our
side in our organization as analysts we
check the server there's a force brute
attacks and when we see ten requests
from the same ip it's probably that so
we create heuristics and we say that if
there is more than ten requests its
brute forcing and so you blocked out
this would be a way to attack it all
block it based on data from the locks
generated and this is not actually
machine learning so where would we start
thinking that something is machine
learning from the previous example as
you can see we might say okay how come
we've decided that 10 was the optimal
number why a minute of time this is done
based on the analyst experience over 10
requests in one minute has brute force
and from machine learning that
subjectivity does not exist machine
learning is using algorithms process in
the data history as I said before in
fearing inferring optimal classification
standards following mathematical
principles the difference between days
and days here were contributing that
part of subjectiveness by our
subjectivity by the analyst bad with
machine learning what we are doing
actually is that every parameter out
there are inferred by the algorithm
[Music]
through a series of mathematical
principles and here let me show team
this exercise and how we can use this
very simple algorithm were the same
which is a classification algorithm
logistic regression for spam detection
here for detecting spam
and use a set of data which is track 7
you can download it from the internet
which was collected in 2007 as users of
real emails if I'm not mistaken in
75,000 and that are made public so that
the spam detection is improved we gather
all these emails and if you see
wait fruit
this is raw emails you have fun and
return and everything the email has if
we just need instead of how it is
rendered by the email client
what's the problem now problem is that
we have a set of data that is a bunch of
email 75,000 but in their will they are
wrong and we have all the headlines we
have HTML all the numbers and characters
and automated algorithm would get a set
of data that were numbers that will then
process and there would be an equation
so we need some pre-processing so that
we can get all those emails and turn
them into a rendering that is the right
one for our machine learning algorithm
to build the equation so one of the
first things to be done when we use
machine learning is to have the
pre-processing on our set of data if
we're using it on real examples odds are
that our set of data that we got them do
not show like a table this is the
feature and these are the numbers if we
use it to detect Network abnormalities
or anomalies we will have lots of geekus
and if we use it for URLs of to download
malware probably we will have a dataset
with a half million your app URLs and we
say once we have it what do we do with
it how do we feed them into the
algorithm that's pre-processing so we
will get this we will send the emails
and we will take out several things we
will remove the headlines so far we are
not interested we will just keep the
body of the email if there is tax or
html's
we will strip it and we will just keep
what's inside of it whatever is going to
be rendered and once we have it all
we'll be using
will is a given equation of function
getting the whole text strain vector
turn it into a vectors so that all those
words are represented as a number and
once we have the number we will send it
to our machine learning algorithm that
will get the parameters us using the
logistic regression which is a simple
equation same as with linear equation it
will equate the model parameters and
with that we will build the function we
saw before and as we send the same email
passed the same way that is spam or it
is not so if we were to run
this software first thing you'd put cars
emails one by one till it's done at all
on the one side stripping every HTML and
headlines and and once it's done that
would be it
it's not the headlines for the header
sorry so this is what we have once it's
over so this is the algorithm here we
see again linear regression and we see
how the code works but it's trained the
algorithm there's been a focused or
prediction and it said that for a set of
data that had not been classified
previously even though we had classified
them to see whether it was a good
prediction so we had our set of data for
training another separate set we've said
well this is also labeled and I know
whether it is spam or not leave it here
so once I've trained my algorithm
calculated the parameters and they have
the function and the model I will get
that set stand-in there I'll send emails
and then and see whether they are
properly classified so after having
trained our algorithm in a logistic
regression very simple algorithm and
having tried our set of data we have a
99% classification right as part of
those set of data that were several
thousand emails they were properly
classified at a 99% probability so
that's good
I just refer to how this works but it
had not gone deeper into explaining the
code let me explain something to this
way simpler let me show the set of data
first first plan was a real set of data
real emails were probably you saw the
potential and here you have a set of
data that I've built myself I've made it
up trying to represent the example we
saw before for linear regression here we
have a set of data which is CSV a column
with the number of devices
then the next one is cast of the
security incidents how do we program an
algorithm for machine learning to build
it to build a function you see with the
existing libraries with Python this is
simply straightforward and you can do
just like this this is how we build a
linear regression model as the one we
see in the previous example that would
be adjusted first we input two libraries
that are very well-known in the field of
machine learning panda which is a
library to distri managed set of data
this is silly one because we only have a
few examples I would say 20 year 34 the
emails there's this worth 75,000 there
we need two library where we can process
all those eight and grow and do some
fishing means if instead of 75,000 it's
a million what we need is something that
is truly efficient we can not just build
a loop to go through the file one by one
because it would take days
once we've imported both libraries all
the things we do is we reach our set of
data here is data dot c sv and usually
this is a data frame that's the name
it's given once imported the set of data
you see pandas can read the CSV format
right away and it's turned into an
object of its own and so we cut them
our input variables so we stripped it
out of the failure class just the number
of devices and then we also keep the
output variable once we have both sense
we split to the set of data and why is
that why do we split it what we do so in
order to do what we did before we have a
set of data and with that we will build
our model but once built how do we know
that it's properly built and not just in
any way since we have a set of data from
which we know what the right answers are
we're gonna split it and leave part of
the data to verify that mother has been
rightly done with the other half of the
set of data usually it would be 20% 30%
33% for testing and the other
percentages for training of algorithms
here you see this as X techs and eat X
for testing and extraneous any training
what I will use for training how do you
trade an algorithm with one of these
libraries is very simple we just import
the algorithm this is regression linear
regression as you see here and we've
said it so and with the fit method we
train the algorithm what does it need
for to be trained easy-peasy our
training data and the responses as well
to calculate the mistake and adjust the
straight line we feed both things and
once we've done it I can start
predicting what's generated here
basically this is a model right same as
saying here
I need the function this is a straight
the linear function down here the
parameters as we've seen based on what I
feed you for training and once you've
adjusted the parameters I have the
object here with the function and the
parameters already adjusted with its
model I feed what I want to predict and
you see what I'm feeling is just
tist so only the first column so that's
the number of devices impacted and the e
predict is the replied the second column
the cast in which they have for every
device based on the training once we
have that what we do is well here I just
got on the screen the prediction and
what's real so what really was as our
set of data and what was predicted what
do we use here and we've seen that these
are metrics these are metrics that are
be used to assess how our models behave
how has been built there are so many
metrics kirisame and precision every one
score many many of them when we checked
the class rain we will see we have
silhouette proficient and many others
used to assess different what the
results mean one might measure the false
positive to true positive ratio some
others the false positive rate etc so if
we run this algorithm very fast why this
one so first and the other one service
low because I had to parse the emails
and I had to train it using so many
examples training example seventy-five
thousand which are not this many but
here we had a bunch see that the
prediction of the forecast when I split
it into twenty percent
we only got these examples here is just
one two three four
so we had view training exams and if we
compared forecast with reality we might
see that it's not properly adjusted is
not a problem much for reality we had
227 that took us on our first incidence
as we predicted using number of machines
is over a hundred thousand and over ten
thousand the prediction was sixty
thousand 65 55 thousand so it seems that
the ratio is preserved but it's not
properly
well fine-tuned it was not the right one
and why is that well it happened because
we only had a few training examples
actually so fear that we only had team
point placed in a random way and with
the straight line we cannot really see
was the trend of our set of data if we
did have some more spots or points that
would truly represent the relationship
between the number of devices and the
cost we could have a much more accurate
prediction okay then next topic a bit
more advanced clustering clustering
takes us back to you the relationship or
how we understand for any examples in
our daily life a cyber security analysts
and paper why would we use clustering
nor why an analyst with years flustering
malicious activity oftentimes happens
with groups or sets see this example
here if an attacker tries to gain access
to your network they will need to scan
and have traffic with similar features
so try to come in so recognition of the
network and so some network scans that
had produced high traffic why TCP or
whatever but it is pretty similar so
malicious activity happened within a set
of data they're very similar then if an
attacker tries to exploit an SQL
injection they will try to try several
similar sequences before they find the
right one so
the name of the table or the parameters
that are the right ones if an attacker
hat it performs a first force Britain
they will be trying several of them
brute force and that is several of them
so probably they send similars phishing
emails to many employees
this happens with sets and that's
clustering for security clustering is
just another kind of algorithm for
machine learning which is based on
unsupervised learning here our set of
data we will have so many data we don't
know whether they're good or bad because
we're not have not Dib fat type
classified them before what's the goal
here so if we have a large amount of
data so let's say that we have a large
amount of logs and we'll be using the
clustering algorithm to bring together
all those data and locks into groups
that follow similar features and when
looking to them we can start somewhere
and it is easier as we think that
malicious activity happens as part of a
group or in groups probably one of those
small clusters of our millions of locks
we will have some locks that are part of
a malicious activity so if we are
developing a threat hunting we are 300
him for a company and we're trying to
check threats in the company with that
know into what we're looking for and we
have many instead of Lux to look into a
good starting point would be clustering
techniques as we will see in a minute
so here you have it the idea is to have
the grouping of data as I said before
and something important here once we say
these data are grouped we need to see
how to give them these would be through
the proximity concept and I prefer to
proximity here but you might say okay
percerin II but what do you mean how do
I know that these you are L is closer to
this one doesn't make sense as it so
this is measured with metrics metrics
would be a specific way we use to assess
the proximity between points or spots
let's see there's a basic example
something we can see in our dating knife
but it's not considered machine learning
in our definition we would choose one or
several dimensions and define every
facet as a group of elements that share
values in those dimensions when you hear
the matches what we are saying are this
columns in the back before we had on two
dimensions in our set of data so we can
represent it there we had the number of
devices and the cost of the incident it
thats easy to represent and usually our
set of data will not have to you but not
many more 10 2013 this cannot be
represented graphically
[Music]
so we can use a clustering technique
which says two dimensions okay one is
the number of devices and then or
endpoints and then everything else value
shared or a group these would be as a
basic example of what's used by the SQL
example a grip let's move on to more
advanced cases this is the first machine
learning or clustering algorithm
probably one of the most popular popular
algorithms which is k-means k-means have
several features the metrics to measure
distance this is a but measure and
proximity between points and bring them
together so they are quite the closest
so understand it that scenario of
premise that it all happens in groups so
proximity concept is measured with that
instance with the euclidean instance the
great feature here is that is easily
scalable to larger grapes so it's an
algorithm that is used for production
centers because of that because we have
million of date and maybe other advanced
advanced algorithms and also useful for
scalability reasons but then there are
some other considerations we need to
consider and I'll refer to that and how
does came into word game Ian's works as
it follows there's something that we
will call centroids which are points we
will set into our map randomly do
remember that as we said that there is a
table and a graphic representation same
here so these would be our state of day
so we have a table and we will randomly
initialize some of this data we will
decide how many little beam all of this
once initialized and once they're inside
of our set of data we might say that
they will be assigned data that are
closest to them we started there and the
closest our
allocated this is will all on the blue
because they are closed there once all
those points have been assigned to the
centroids that we've looked into you
will calculate the distance of every
spot and take the average and move it as
close as we can and back again to the
beginning so we move our centroid so
first it's all on one then we calculate
the average and then back to the average
for everything then some here and then
to the middle or the average again and
then we stop moving that around when we
see that they are not moving anymore
when it comes that point where they
don't move anymore we think that every
of those has to reach a state where
every point that have been assigned to
them are part of a cluster and you see
that they're all of them combined Eric
classroom because we've moved the
average around the centroids so what is
to be considered when we're using this
algorithm
I meant to share this with Eve but I
wanted to make it clear so the animal
isn't it to know we helped beforehand
the number of clusters since it is asked
to indicate the number of clusters need
to be initialized and we'll remove to
rent beforehand we need to state the
number of clusters what's the problem
here well if we're looking into a set of
data such as locks in our search for
security threats and we truly don't know
how many clusters are in there it is
difficult to say well I'll initialize
how many three four I don't know how
many are there and if we had a set of
tagged data or we knew what we're
looking for on the results we're looking
for we can choose one two three times
the number of tags we have if we have a
set of data where we say well inside of
this I know there is 1 million items but
there are three threats in it we would
get those tags they're all those and say
initialize one to three clusters right
three times the number of threats here
it would be three
- six or nine mine 9 as well and we use
them seeing how they grouped together
and then we check the clusters then we
also need to use streamlining or
standardization this is a bit more
advanced but is we referred to
standardizations a lability
has to be used if we have a set of data
that are out of balance so we get
several dimensions as part of our set of
data there's a first line where the
valleys oscillate from 1 to 5 and the
second one has valleys and they are fed
values from wanted to million maybe
because one here it would be the number
of rooms that's one of the features in a
how they're the one the price of the
home or anything of that kind so there
are features inside those set of data
that are out of balance this is AG
Lydian distance as I said and if they
are so wide apart it doesn't work so we
need to follow standardization
mechanisms which keep the data trend but
somehow equalizes every features so that
they have similar valleys what else we
cannot use k-means with a categorical
data or one hold encoding either
if we have one of our features which is
no number but categorical numbers so a
category if something is good or bad we
cannot feed it into the algorithm
because it only understand numbers one
hold encoding it would say but one is a
zero and the good one is a one these are
very low numbers by the way you were
similar in value so it doesn't really
work k-means doesn't work with states
that are have several dimensions
number of rooms etc so picture this case
machine learning on network traffic we
can get so many features out of this
package we can see number of incoming
bytes or a number of the package we get
that and we can get the number of bytes
through the floating coming outgoing TCP
UDP and so on and so forth so what if we
have many columns that algorithm won't
be working properly we would be needing
dimension reduction algorithms I'm not
going to go into detail because those
are more advanced so k-means works
better if the centroids are randomized
most implementations they're initialized
randomly and very importantly caming
k-means it takes it for granted that
there is very cool look at this example
look at those clusters how they look
like circles right when i say it's fira
co i'm talking about a graphic
representation so that is an assumption
and if when they're not spherical then
this technique for k-means grouping or
clustering it just won't be working
properly
let's look at a different type of
clustering because clustering is quite
generic
is based on proximity and k-means uses
euclidean distance but there are other
possible distances if we have problems
with that in this case we're going to
look at DB scan a clustering algorithm
that doesn't use euclidean density but
actually it works really well with non
spherical distributions let's see how
the algorithm works for a DB scan here
we have four clusters and we can see
this round cluster that has been colored
in red but we have three more smaller
clusters with Euclidean distance
centroids and k-means well if we start
to assign values and it all moves to the
center the outer cluster won't be
detected why why not because it's not a
circuit that's particularly spherical DB
scan works differently because we have
to indicate first an epsilon parameter
that would mean is like a radius around
which it looks for neighboring values so
we would initialize a point on our data
set which is get one of those points and
research within that radius so if it has
four main points or over that number
neighboring points that will be a core
point as the start of a cluster and that
is done again for other neighboring
points if we if there are four of them
again we go on and on until the point
comes when no more neighboring values
are found so we then look for points
that have not been added to that cluster
we start again we initialize a different
point this one for instance it doesn't
have four points so that is an anomaly
again here we see that it's got the
number of number of neighboring values
that we defined and recurrently doing so
until we find no more and then we would
move to on to a different point we see
then a density for clustering to be able
to cluster points even if they're not a
spherical DB scan doesn't work properly
when we have different densities
logically then the selection of epsilon
and main points parameters are the basis
for correct functioning of this model
the radius and the number of neighboring
values that define a cluster that's what
we need we don't need to define the
clusters beforehand but we do need to
define those parameters so that will be
the basis for the algorithm to work
properly or not it doesn't work properly
where we have many different dimensions
for that type of data set before I show
you an example I want to warn you that
would you need to be very careful not to
alter the density if the set is
subdivided into subsets we have our data
set we need to check how the algorithm
works so that means we need to leave
some data for supervision or monitoring
without a tag or at least the algorithm
doesn't need the tag for clustering
classifications in this case but we
could have the tag and then a feed both
the data and the tag and then on testing
during that phase we could check to see
how the classification into clusters
want to see for malicious examples it
went into a cluster and then
into a different cluster or if they're
mixed together so if we you in those
cases we need to be very careful again
not to alter the density of the dataset
because if we split it is split them
randomly we might end up with data that
are very good representations for some
of those data but not for the rest why
because we altered the density and that
would be wrong
there's look at a practical case an
example that is a little bit like threat
hunting in a company a team working on
threat hunting what is the normal cycle
then well starting with hypothesis of
what we're looking for or presupposing
that attacks will be of a certain type
and see how it works with certain data
sets we then collect the data that we
think will be interesting for the
attacking techniques for us to explore
that and then we start discovering the
TTP's sometimes datasets are huge with
so many different imports and where can
we start well that's what clustering is
useful if malicious activities happen
with cholesteric we can start analyzing
smaller groups or clusters to see how
the activity works there let's have a
look then at the example
and let them look at the Moblin delicacy
in them here is our example I start with
a set of URLs legit URLs and then I said
of URLs that are used for malware
distribution overall it's about half a
million URLs which one's belong to
malware distribution which ones are
legit that's the exercise the threat
hunting exercise might be caused because
some devices have been infected and we
want to find which malware have been
used imagine half a million pieces of
information where can we start well if
there has been classification the
algorithm clustering algorithm won't see
this URL this has been tagged so that
once I have my clusters I can get their
tags and show you which URLs are
malicious in a cluster which legit URLs
are in a different cluster does this
work properly or not very importantly we
have the pre-processing step
here we have a URL set with text
characters numbers and with the same
problem we saw earlier the machine
learning algorithm gets numerical
information but what we have is text
change so we can't just feed that and
expect a perfect perfect URL clustering
how can we turn the URLs into numerical
information representing legit URLs and
malware URLs we need to do
pre-processing of our data set and get
certain features that we call dimensions
those are the different columns look at
the ones I've extracted firstly Anthropy
what is entropy
Fannin's entropy says the following well
it finds the amount of information on it
takes chain which premise can I use this
is my own idea extracting the entropy
from the URL and that will finally give
me a number that's the idea so the
premise is the following well we have no
more behavior on a website on an domain
by a user the idea is that the user will
be browsing from one area to the other
for instance opening a YouTube videos
what would change just some numbers
right because information is quite
similar for those URLs when we calculate
entropy we see how and that result is
then clustered quite nicely for legit
URL but when we exit a malware URL and
we download dog fire whatever Kanta
we would click and we would end up on a
weird URL with a very long address with
a lot of numbers with very little
information and the entropy is quite
weird right err there might be some
legit ones that will read like that as
well but very few II this could be a
good start for classification as a
feature to measure distance what else
can I use TLB o TLD sorry to see if it's
a part of malware TLD set so I would
have my column with TLD malware and I
would score a zero otherwise it would
score as one I would also extract the
type of resource that is accessed with
numerical coding I would see if it's an
IP address or a domain because sometimes
well we download malware it's an IP
because they haven't even got their own
domain so we with the data I would then
need to make it readable by pandas or by
CSV in this case look at this here this
is a way to justify to you here what I
explained earlier the functions I
defined are applied on the URL set with
the apply panda function
I'm not a developer right I work with
cybersecurity but the first thing that
came to mind is that I have defined my
functions I could have my loop for loop
so that I can extract the entropy of the
function the entropy of the URL and so
on well when I did it I estimated 13
days to cover those half a million URLs
but using panda it took how long four
minutes for the half a million URLs can
you see how having good frameworks for
data processing loading for a large data
sense like half a million right which is
not the biggest we can come across at
all this is the script that we use on
our URLs and this is the result this
data set just see how the data set now
looks much better it looks much more
numerical still some categorical data
that we will later work with not horse
encoding because k-means doesn't work
with that very well and also we're
including URLs here why because when I
process with the algorithm I won't be
classifying only the clusters with
numerical values on top of that I will
then have the URL on the corresponding
hosta so that URLs will be in different
files belonging to different plastic
clusters and I can then analyze that
let's have a look at the file in charge
of that analysis
is the same thing we saw for linear
regression if the same frameworks I used
earlier this is our new URL data set
that we calculated earlier we use get
dummies which is a panda resource for
binary encoding we have loaded some
variables that were not interested in so
I'm going to do a drop of the URL the
entropy now not the entropy I'm going to
leave that out and the label so for the
URL and the label so that the data set
can understand it it can't understand
the URLs right and then we will leave
the label out later because is if it's a
malicious URL because it's not
supervised learning they don't need the
label it just works with a structure so
we do reprocessing we've done scaling
before because some entropy is standard
for point something six point something
then we have the encoding with values of
roundabout one so there's quite a
difference right if the scaling will
help equate equalize that because we're
using k-means and it might work wrong
when the data set is not properly
balanced so once that's ready all we do
is we instance Kami k-means very simple
low garage
we need to indicate the number of
clusters
looking and trying to differentiate
between alleged and malicious URLs I
have between one and three times the
number of URLs that's reasonable so I'm
going to say that's four clusters so
once we have the number of clusters here
we do feed predict that means we don't
need to feed the labels just the data
set and then that will contain the
clusters and the examples the loop then
gets the URLs into the right cluster and
we end up with the files and this is the
metrics that's a bit weird
what are we measuring at the end of the
day we're not measuring probability of
it being right or not we're measuring
how well the clusters are defined that
is containing as many instances of a
particular type and as few instances of
a different type so that's where we use
purity score getting both clusters that
have been predicted and also real labels
that's why I have my labels and it will
check if the clustering is correct
there's another type of metrics that I
can show you in a minute there's a
silhouette coefficient to see if
clusters have been found correctly on
the basis of some mathematical
properties and it doesn't even need the
labels for the clusters to know if
they've been described or found properly
or not
if we have time later time later we will
see how this compares with labels in one
case without in a separate example and
the final outcome is pretty similar
we're going to run the scripts now
here it is and look how it predicts
k-means is often used in production
environments because is ever so fast so
fast this is how long it took for half a
million URLs this is the classification
it says there is a cluster with two
thousand seven hundred and eight
instances where over two thousand are
malicious as an amazing classification
most of the examples are malicious then
we have three hundred and seventy-nine
thousand euros worth thirty four
thousand are malicious URLs that have
been included this is with simple
parameters right the only complex one is
entropy the rest of the parameters are
very simple and in two more clusters one
with six hundred and forty instances
where 628 are URLs for malware to be
downloaded and then another cluster with
over six thousand URLs with again most
of them being more where excellent
classification where we have less data
we will find URLs with common features
that have been used to download malware
and always on a real data set the purity
score is north point nine percent
logically so and this one is 34,000 but
as opposed to almost 400,000 original
ones here we have our clusters it's open
data set zero that had some 2,000
malware URLs
these are URLs that have been used at
different times for malware distribution
they all have IP addresses as domains
look at the resources that are accessed
I'm going to show you now a different
one another cluster cluster number two
how was that group together look at that
URLs that were distributed for malware
distribution this is the indicator the
real data set it has the number for
every instance Kansas City hotel dot XA
for some of them or dot zip that might
not look very obvious right probably
because of the domain so the algorithm
was fed some parameters and it then uses
function just like we saw for linear
regression earlier but not the same one
but in
similar operation mode it adjusts
parameters it clusters URLs together and
with a brute-force attack you don't need
to say well over ten predictions that
will be considered as brute force no it
just needs mathematical calculations so
that's it for clustering and now let's
see something well the last section in
my presentation that's very popular in
cyber security and is anomaly detection
I'm going to start talking about a
intrusion detection which falls into two
different categories when we find an
intrusion it can be based on heuristics
that type of rule that most companies
use it finds false positives but it
doesn't work very well for unknown or
totally new attacks through heuristics
rules help this happen and then there's
a different way of doing this based on
animal anomalies profiling normal
behavior in a system could be a website
host whatever and it can find new
attacks because it can assess events
that deviate from the norm that is
anomaly evaluation or assessment so when
we talk about anomaly detection we need
to first define what an anomaly is it's
an event that deviates from normal or
expected behavior expected from a
security perspective
because anomalies don't just have to do
with security sometimes they have to do
with performance problems for instance
we have NIH D s finding anomalies on a
host for instance a system might have a
huge load because we're rendering a
video well that's an anomaly
compared with no more behavior for the
processor not caused in this case by a
security breach
how did anomaly detection start well to
detect intrusions proposed in 1976 by
Dorothy Jennings in her famous paper
people are still saying this is new but
back in the day this paper proposed a
anomaly detection for this very purpose
so how is machine learning connected
with anomaly detection here we have a
definition in English and it says that a
machine learning algorithm attempts to
recognize complex patterns in existing
data sets to help make intelligent
decisions or predictions when the
pattern deviates from the norm and what
it does is finding non-trivial methods
to find them so this a new category of
machine learning that is semi-supervised
learning because some algorithms will be
completely fully non supervised but some
of them need
at least your set of alleged data not
labeled with alleged or malicious
examples but a set of alleged examples
the system profiles a function and
whenever there is an out layer then that
will be studied as a possible security
breach
so is semi-supervised because the
supervisor system needs both legit and
malicious examples from the real world
the non supervisor examples doesn't need
either of them we don't need to
differentiate between them and in this
semi-supervised learning it needs to
know at least some of the legit examples
are legit legitimate the most simple
example is a Gaussian distribution which
is a probability distribution for
continuous variables here we can see the
density graph representing a Gaussian
distribution poisson distribution says
the following don't panic when you see
that formula it says for this particular
point if I get an example their
probability will be far higher than if I
get a point here at this end of the
curve so if our data are distributed
according to Gaussian distribution then
we will adjust parameters just like the
linear function we saw earlier but in
this case a parameter is a
depend on variants the metrics and
typical distribution so let's do
something similar now but starting with
legit examples a-brewing air the curve
the function then adjusting the
parameters and then this function this
will then give back a probability we
would then set a threshold a limit so
that when there's a new example it will
be assessed according to Gaussian
distribution according to the model that
I've described and adjusted for my data
set and if the probability is too low or
under my threshold then it will be an
anomaly but if it's within the limit or
larger than the threshold it will be
considered as a normal example something
the threshold is here to the left if
most data are to the right then the ones
to the left will be unusual or non
typical so malicious behavior the idea
is that is normally quite different from
legitimate behavior I bet you've often
seen situations where you're you have
the logs of our Apache server for
instance and we try to do detect SQL
injections and normally when that
happens the requests are well defined
for instance with the same reserved
words quite predictable but in an attack
in an attack SQL SQL injections are
longer they might use unions they might
add other requests for the database or
using reserved words that are often
not used so logically if we have
profiled our normal requests then we
will easily find anomalies and that will
tell us something odd or nasty is
happening how how does the algorithm
work with Gaussian distribution we would
select characteristics or features that
can determine an example or define it as
anomalous then we would adjust the
parameters for the model well the
algorithm will do that and then given an
example we would compute the probability
if it's below epsilon or threshold then
it will be classed as an anomaly let's
see a practical example for anomaly
detection applied in this case to
banking fraud with credit cards this is
the normal follow when we pay with a
credit card this is how I've imagined it
I don't really know the details we pay
with a card for authorization then the
merchant bank is involved the issuer
approves the pavement and then the
reverse route until the payment is
confirmed we can use the anomaly
detection algorithm where here at this
point with an anomaly detection
algorithm if the transaction is classed
as anomalous on the basis of the
transactions that individual normally
makes then it has a high probability of
being malicious or a fruit
very far Esteban's under that I'm gonna
use this set of data this this set of
data here is real we got several
features of a transaction using a credit
card this was published by a company but
mainly those our number is very close to
get that and why is that and how can
that up there we have visas and v7
because they follow a dimensionality
reduction algorithm which is PZ a PCA
gets our data set and builds the main
components and with those it produces
the same columns that we had with the
same data and the Trent is somehow kept
but different values which are scale
Aidid standardized and the data set is
an anonymized because if it were an
anonymous we could not get the data
because there was a favorite data but
once of an anonymized we have all these
red Sanchez classified as zero legit one
malicious we will not be using malicious
crooks actions but is still good to see
the result actually this is an easy
classification for a bank because if a
client comes and is not complaining it
is legit and if it claims that they been
stolen or they've been robbed the first
thing they do is call and say some words
but something with my credit card and so
you can classify it as a fraud and then
you use it for training your own
algorithm
let me show you what should be done
whatever
in this region we said that one of the
premises is that our dataset has to be
distributed according to a Gaussian
distribution which is a gauze Bell shape
is called Bell because the density
distribution as represented shares like
a panel and what we also said is that
for it to work we need to use features
where the malicious examples are
different from the legit ones to the
naked eye this is good when we see the
data but when we have pz8 and everything
has been anonymized to the naked eye
it's a bit more difficult
usually we graphically represent the
distribution of data here I've
represented each of the feature Orange
you see the examples for the malicious
feature and in blue that between legit
sir I see what feature follows the
Gaussian distribution almost all of them
and we also see or I also see which of
these features are more differentiating
between a positive or a negative example
here the negative examples are very
different but this one here is always
the same this would be a full featured
she used for an anomaly detection these
would be for well this one would be
quite quite good with this here what I
do is okay I will keep those that I know
are good because they are differentiated
and follow a Gaussian distribution all
others will be removed from the dataset
and so I train my algorithm
okay but so that you'd see that this is
the Gaussian distribution that has not
been implemented as a machine learning
and saying you need to implement it
yourselves but it's pretty simple
actually if you want tape to test it
just email me and I will send it to you
but we do what we saw from previous
example so let's run it
this is something I haven't told you
since I need to have a dressy Oh a limit
above which I would think it's an
anomaly but I don't really know what the
limit is here so what I do is I try
different limit I get my data set and
split into two or two or three and one
of them I use this for testing so this
is forecasting I see the labels I see if
they much a malicious example and I say
yes isn't much here so this is a good
for us we know there's too much a
difference this is a bad one so I keep
the best one since their days I said
I've been using it for deliberate
selection I cannot use it afterwards for
testing and why is that because it might
be there's been what's known as
overtraining which means that the limit
is nicely adjusted to the subset of data
but not for the generic subset and so I
get just the same set for the limit or a
throw so and observe my protesting so
it's a good test because it's been
selected for it but when deployed real
time nothing is detected and that's why
it is important that when any of the
parameters are gathered like that you
need to use a different subset for
testing afterwards when you're going to
assess it final result if you check it
out and you will see that it got sorry
it actually detected the anomalies with
an 80 plus percent accuracy not so bad
is it
so these are the different sections that
belong to real back in 82 percent of all
cases so so many because there's been
thousands and thousands of transactions
it's been a match and the anomaly
it was actually a perfect match for a
fraud or legitimacy so if it's a fraud
or malicious we can follow other
techniques we've seen before for
supervised learning that helps us truly
verify that it is a fraud and reduce the
number of false positives not so many
here and so the last algorithm I got you
here we have 25 minutes left from
questions so this is for an early
detection and country it's a Gaussian
detection does not need to have the
legit or the label data set for
profiling here we have a an algorithm
which is for trees following two
premises here the abnormal subset it's a
minority can curve to the regular data
and the features are very different from
normal data before I show you in a graph
how it works and see the practical
example that I have for these network
attack detention detection let me tell
you that this algorithm is very good
when you want to use it for network
traffic abnormalities real time or for
detection processes without high load
why is that because it only uses a few
training data for good results and even
if we use a very large set there is a
subsample with just one to examine with
one example it can decide which ones are
abnormal and which ones are not so it's
very fast and it is not many data and
doesn't need labels
it's unsupervised so it's good for
real-time Department and in order to
have the real time process same in
reasonable within reasonable deadlines
how does how does it work first the
graphic representation how it works and
you can find on any site or anything
doing with isolation
and then shortly I'll explain what this
is all about let's see let's say we have
this data set we have two features and
it shows like that on our table and we
see human being is quite good at
spotting abnormalities in sets and
everything and we see there's a large
group this one can be thought of as an
abnormality and up there probably it is
compared to ours dataset so what about
isolation first first horizontal and
vertical cuts or slices so we split it
here then this one here then this one
here right here it would be done as
isolation as a function I salute in
first counts the number of lines
vertical and horizontal needed to
isolate an item from all others based on
the number of the lines needed for the
isolation it's considered at animality
or not the threshold here would be the
number of lines or katzie's said to say
this is an end up not animality and only
animal in Emily because these are
isolated this one's been left outside
but this is not because they've not yet
been isolated by the cats it would take
many more if we were to choose this one
here and we would use random lines we
would need many more to isolate it
compared to this other one so we've
already said probably you cannot say
that but we've said it already that
actually isolation forest is using
decision-making forests and how does it
work you get your data set you get the
features of that size it looks into the
features following some scores and
metrics this would be the din score
which is another score
and I will get this value and I will
split it
following this feature and valuable this
is on this one side and then the other
side and this is branch and another
branch and all the way up to the
absolute purity in one branch that is
would be a Pierce part this is a
classification algorithm that is super
fast so you need to know what's legit
and what's not to keep assessing it so
sorry it's unsupervised because it does
calculate the gender score based on the
cluster density and everything else as
we were doing so what does it do it
builds decision trees based on our set
of data data set and so it will think
that the cats here so what we represent
it as Scots well you see these are
actually separations from our dataset
and so it becomes subset so we have two
dataset is split into two subsets we
have this one here and there's one here
translate it into a decision tree we
would have two branches one here one
here with this data with another card
actually we are translated it into
having a card on previous cards and so
we have more branches created with this
algorithm under interfaces our normal is
all those sets that have a lower depth
or a few branches all the way up to
purity and that's why it is tree based
how can we
kind of algorithms on a real example for
animal detection on a network we can use
our network our local network small one
at home wherever use a tab between the
router and the devices or use a switch
through V fry and redirect all the
traffic of the internet on a machine
where this algorithm is run real time
and see whether the traffic sets are
abnormal anomalies or not we will not do
it package by package because it would
be pointless but maybe some closed
traffic flows with a 10000 network
packages or sessions or login sessions
that is and we can group them anywhere
and any way we like we can have net flow
standards that starts and many other
mechanisms
so all the traffic in and out of the
network we can check and see when there
can be some anomaly on the network our
network so the mechanism we I have not
deployed real-time but I got here a set
of data
so I've got a dataset here which is
already ready with some features of
several Network flows and it's
classified as well here we see this flow
here which is a regular one you see it
says Numa regular and then the features
that got here would be let's see
incoming or outgoing iTunes many more
things
[Music]
TCP passive open outgoing requests from
T as if he so so many features and
different flows for the network traffic
you just get it pass it as we did with
the emails to get the features are you
dump them into your data set and this is
offline but online you would get the
flow and send it into our system real
time and it would give us the odds that
it is an anomaly or that it is an
isolation forest is easily implemented
as well see here I've used a feature
selection algorithm priorly which do
what we've done with the Gaussian
distribution see what the best
distribution is but here it follows some
statistical mathematical method says so
this one is the one with the best
results are usually and I kept this one
so we change our isolation first
algorithm same as we did before and here
we haven't implemented and we fit it
into our dataset and the result are some
scores
come here I'm detecting brute force and
brute force in a web app I have it on
the network and these are easily
detected because you have someone trying
user password and everything so this is
very different from regular queries and
requests and those flows if I choose
those flows so if it's a five-minute
flow that flow work there's some brute
force brute force in this different form
what's normal because it might be one
per minute or even less than that so
here I find that there's brute force in
on my network and for my set of data I
had some two hundred or thousand items
or lines but then I split the dataset
into 800 for verification and 200 for
later purposes and then f1 score that
it's the score or metrics that will give
us the percentage of yes the percentage
that is for the proper classification of
anomalies that were malicious examples
and anomalous that were false positive
there were legit example studies a 92%
which means the 92% of all the flows
that have been considered abnormal where
match two flows that came from full
brute forcing so that was eight so we've
actually seen that there was an abnormal
behavior so we need to give it real-time
well all well profiles and when we do
see that there are some real
abnormalities we need to suspect there
is something going on and so you get the
flows you get the network traffic you
redirected elsewhere to a different
system and so we have other mechanism
for machine learning and
reclassification are all based on
malware ramzan were for example that
it's distributed on the network it will
be easily classified or also brute force
inner denial of
service or RPS roofing tax or all those
attacks that actually Eve we go into it
we will be able to classify it by
properly selecting features but if we
use a classifier just on a large network
we've got plenty of data we will get
many of false positives really taken
abnormal ease we move that elsewhere we
can classify it and the results are way
better
[Music]
that's me know for me folks thank you
very much for your attendance I hope I
did not bore you with my lecture and
formula and everything else and so I
have 10 minutes left for questions as
requested if you want examples of or
anything of this kind or advanced
questions you can ask me on Twitter or
in my email thank you very much
[Applause]
analyst Odin he gave us an example for
isolation forests and you said that was
about isolating a node right that's one
it is something no there is
decision-making trees and it would
consider that an anomaly is what follows
and depth very shorter so when does it
stop building the trees it depends you
can indicate it well maybe when the know
disappeared so you only have one kind of
an example or else so you might have a
set of data set with lots of times it
would be a huge tree
huge and unmanageable tree so you can
say I don't need the data set or node to
be pure but I needed to have an 80%
purity so when it says that in through a
series of techniques such as the ciliary
coefficient using genus core and it says
that the cluster is pure enough it stops
and stops producing anymore branches are
normally since they are very much
different from everything else or
isolated first because that's a
difference that's associated when we
said isolation forests there were two
premises first the abnormal subset has
to be minority and then they are very
different compared to ordinary datum and
so they're isolated in just a few
branches all right but graphically those
are the cuts that we follow right there
or your card second one is more than
enough right that's right there's what I
didn't follow yes here the second one
would have been enough for isolation
purposes but usually it would take on an
arm
if these were a tree we would keep with
cats all the way to the end to see
what's significant because maybe out
here it would work any more questions
guess what I said must defeat it what's
more difficult for machine learning
information classification are choosing
an algorithm to tackle a problem whoa
the most complicated part of it would be
to get a good dataset good quality
getting a good dataset it is so very
complicated for example you want him
here's isolation forest it could it
could be done for example to detect
anomalies on a corporate network so what
about your home how do you get data
because you don't have access to your
business network and at home with a
virtual environment you cannot have
something graphic as on a corporation
because they have priorities and they
have more nodes and Habs and have
different structures within the network
so in the end problem is that you don't
know whether you've got a good model
well there won't be implemented because
you don't have access to information
data to test your algorithm so if I were
to say something I would say the most
critical thing would be to get good data
and there are many researchers in
artificial intelligence think that
artificial intelligence has been a hit
for the last ten years ago - before that
we could not get a good data there were
no mechanisms for a good data collection
and it really hadn't had enough time to
have big enough data or good enough data
now everything is faster and it's all
expedited and it's easier to get larger
volumes than in the past that's why I
say that data are critical now
what's your name my friend us if there
are no more questions
that's me I don't thank you very much
[Applause]
[Music]
you