you
[Music]
well these C's summary of my
presentation or the table of contents of
my presentation
so I hope that my presentation is
entertaining so if you are not on the
technical side did not get discussed
about my presentation because we will be
looking at security elements that are
very important such as not pivoting
basic ipv6 and then we will finish off
with demos and we will be using broken
and skydive to to see the network
configurations that we have in these
elements okay so today I'd like to
introduce myself to say that I'm
passionate about network security I've
also been doing research on ipv6 for
many years now I've also founder of a
start-up mr. Luka I've always had a very
close relationship with encima they have
supported us a lot when we created our
startup this was two years ago when we
received the third prize of startups and
we have always had the significant
support from names even easier we have
received support between receiving the
support in the program for Business
Accelerator so he and I in the
photograph you see my partner my partner
and myself took this photograph in
Athens
so athens has its headquarters had in
Asia Asia
Anisa the European agency for network
security has its headquarters in Athens
Athens so we produced the paper and part
of the content of my presentation today
comes out from that paper that we
produced about security implications of
ipv6 we will not be focusing purely on
ipv6 and still will prefer a refer to it
well from our startup and is of top
concern to us and that we are trying to
communicate at the time is the
importance of considering taking into
account those elements are exposed to
the Internet and this image is intended
to represent but we internally imagine
when we expose a service to the internet
when we open a port 80 port of SSH port
or any other port which is secure but
that is also open to the Internet the
moment we come out to the Internet it is
like if we were at work and trenches
waiting for anything or any attack from
the enemy dmz so when two Koreas reach
an agreement and in the the militarized
zone
still there was a frontier there when as
you penetrate it you could go to reach
area and that is a social area that most
strongly protected
so I could talk about murderers and any
other security incidents this took place
four days ago only says that a new data
breach exposes 57 million records from
citizens companies etc more specifically
it says that this is an elastic search
service that was poorly configured
during auditing it was found out that I
didn't had any authentication in place
and anyone could access it and then if
you go to each other it tells you how
you can gain access to that party and
trade wealth you could listen through
that purge you could do very many things
with it
so regarding simple concepts such as
this one if you configure elastic test
please include authentication if you are
going to offer direct access to not
exposed to the Internet it is just a
database and only a web app or an
administrator should have access to it
if you are updated on this type of
things and in this type of research very
often we find this type of data breeches
so in terms of nuts network address
translation everyone is familiar with it
many say that not may be a solution to a
problem that is to say well everyone has
heard about how internet started it was
a network created between several
universities and it was never expected
to grow as much as he has grown it was
never expected to be a breakthrough
through our societies but still
continues to be based on IP protocol and
what is the problem as internet grew as
internet evolved there were not enough
IPS for all the devices that wanted to
connect to the internet and therefore
not was created that is to say a network
of internal addresses that will be
connected to the Internet through
internal
forwarded so here we have three internal
networks so here represented with these
circles all these are internal networks
private networks at your company's
organizations and they are logging to
the internet through few or several IP
addresses can be routed to the Internet
the rest of the routing and internet
coming
connectivity is done through the dark
cloud that we can see here what Internet
Service Providers connect with each
other through the router and offer
connectivity end to end but what happens
with ipv6 ipv6 is not often do stand
actually it is recommended not because a
PVC
huh that was known to be a global
network where millions of devices were
already connected and many more millions
will be connected in the future and what
of Detectives of ipv6 is to restore
entrance network connectivity
that is to say allowing all the internet
devices to connect with each other the
idea is wonderful and ipv6 is here with
us and allowed us to do large simplifies
connection of all these devices to the
Internet now the concept of pivoting so
this is a definition from BBC II about
NBC about pivoting after stopping with
the ball pivoting allows you to change
the direction and look for the past Oh a
shot
how can we translate that into hacking
world or exploiting and post exploding
time well often takes place like this
we'll have a private network here on the
right we have two devices and then on
the Left we have the internet with a
public address so internal traffic
cannot be routed to the Internet that IP
will never reach the internet you may
try it for a given point in time it will
be cut off for that IP addresses are
being juiced and then it will use one of
the ranges that are not reserved for
internal directions so what happens in
exploitation impossible ization face
when we want to pivot imagine that the
service the victim machine is exposed to
imagine that will manage to exploit it
then I take control over it but the
concept of pivoting is very powerful
because it allows us to reach victim to
therefore it allows us to change the
address and therefore to reach the
internal network and for that I may
launch attacks right over and from
victim one or often then is that the
routes of victim one changed so that I
can pivot hand reach victim two right
away and this is one of the things that
you always have to do especially when it
comes to exploiting and this is very
good fun especially when you are
carrying out an audit
again I leave it there now ipv6 well I
could talk ages about it and it is not
relevant for today's conference still I
would like to show and ipv6 address any
addresses starting with two could be
router to the internet so those dots are
stands for zeros and often we always
have these sections with zeros unless
these directions have been randomly
produced so now I'd like you to focus on
these two parts the blue one and the
green part so on the Left we'll have
blue on the right we have a green
what does that mean the first basis
stands for the network address and the
second bit stands for the host address
so what does that mean that if I'm given
control of an X Network the rest of the
64 bits could be redirected as I would
like to in my network 64 bits 2 to the
power 64 how much is that that is a lot
so there is also debate in ipv6 about
the following some administrators says
why so much free directory to given to
ordinary users because the 64 bits is
the ordinary access that you give to any
network and in network we should have a
minimum of a prefix of 64 bits
Ayana and our i as recommend using 64
subnets everywhere in your network and
including point-to-point links this is
when hosts connect to each other through
a network and the work in between them
to the never has two addresses
so in ipv4 we have the address and the
broadcast addressed and these are the
two addresses in between the two devices
how did you direct that for large
customers often large customers Gary -
48 prefix medium customers care of 46
prefix well we are not going to go into
all the detail about subnets somebody's
an ipv6 will reach your homes if you
don't yet have it you should have been
given that 64 prefix which is very good
to play around with it I can assure that
to you and I told you before there are
very low costs
to a land having a good I be v6 with a -
64 prefix all for you and vertical we
post it to github this paper that we
have produced and you may download it
and has the project is based on the demo
that I will be sharing with you now well
it is based on docker
so you will have to install the relevant
dependencies and it is based on skydive
which is a project I would like the
large another nice to see the topography
of a web browser in all the machines
that we will be starting ok I will start
with virtual machine I have an eye cell
with VirtualBox here and I will start it
well it has projects and all the
components installed you may install it
locally or in a virtual machine the
virtual machine that I am using now well
I could install it here but it is not
very difficult to install it is based on
Kali
I just love that you can read or not I
am starting with script with a setup
you see all the environments being
started we have the elasticsearch
skydiver everything is automatically
configured then we are starting the
different machines we have referred to
them as victims and now
I will show you these docker compose for
those of you who are not familiar with
it this is a file that when you set up
taka you ask this system to you tell the
system the machines that you wanted to
start for you so these are all the
victim machines these are all the docker
images and this is configuring the
project you don't have to do it yourself
and then I tell him that the hosts a
victim will have two IP addresses and
ipv4 which is internal and an ipv6
address and everything is ready
okay and this should open automatically
so this has specific attacks of ipv6
that representatives in our project but
because they are not the object of this
presentation and this window is the way
we will close it so this is my colleague
machine and I will expand it now so we
are here we see all the nodes at the
beginning I found it a bit messy I
thought that this design was not user
friendly so to speak but I'll explain it
to you this is my Cali machine
represents a local host of the virtual
machine and each of these red pink
circles is Stanford token machines with
the own network configuration that we
have defined in the docker compose I
will continue to extend it because these
things that we are seeing here in jello
well these that I'm pointing out is an
intermediary device it's a bridge but we
consider it as device you can see it has
its own ipv4 address as well as its own
ipv6 address
each of its machine has and IP address
sorry network address okay
victim five starting back five three and
then in these pink square we have a
symbol for interface then we click on it
and we see the network configuration ten
sixteen 253 to a zero to sixteen 33 this
- 64 means that the first 64 bits are
for the network address and the last 64
bits are for the host address if we were
to click another one for instance this
one here you will see that says 82 so
this is the fixed part of it the first
part the first 64 bits are fixed because
they belong to the same network and what
changes it what comes at the end of the
address the good thing about it is that
I have started my environment and now
go to machine process to this machine
here
the conductivity I can do in a map 1016
to 5 3
so some services are open so therefore
that means it could be any host so you
kind of see it just read it yes I'll be
no
I could also - SSH
and this is ipv6 address I'm starting to
have connectivity and then SkyDrive is
very nice when there is connectivity at
any points then you get these red lights
now I'm going to configure in my
interface an ipv6 address from the
address that have been started in Dhaka
so that I can gain access to ipv6
address of those hosts okay I will
assuming
I'm victory ipv6 addresses this one here
what we cannot go into this one how you
have config it is zero I asked it to
configure ipv6 address for me
okay we'll go back to network
configuration so we see with that we
have ipv6 address configured with a
prefix that we have and this gives us
access to a burnt ocher machines so this
is a pv6 address LLL see if I can do be
pink
that machine well no problem and do that
another assimilate let's change the
configuration of these environments like
if it were to configure the DMC the
public part and that private part in my
Callie I'm going to configure a public
IP before a v4 address and I'm going to
change these public address with another
public address
therefore I go to interface I do if
config and interface and then I would be
sixty six seven seven eight four four
and you'll see how network configuration
changes can you see it has changed and
that network element which is this one
here and that will communicate with our
colleague right away in my IP v4 has
given a public directional pretty
similar in that it is an IP of our DMC
who a server that has is exposed to
given service and then we have Holly we
have a icon for our interface 0 this one
here
so we see the never configuration that
I'm entering I will be changing that and
I will say instead of this one instead
of disentangle bun I want to I will be
entering a public address six is seven
seven five four point eight nine as you
wish I will be changing that and what
will happen now you will have access to
six six point seven seven eight eight
all right and what will happen if I try
to do ping to Joe start having
internally redirected here can you
remember some of them for instance okay
let us go for this one okay this one
here since 1653
[Music]
I can see that I cannot access them
because it tells me that destination the
book cannot be accessed
so the configuration and the language
behind it simulates the internal
configuration of organization which is
in the nut and outside we have different
nodes communicating to the internet but
an existing ipv6 you don't get nuts so
therefore these network configuration
that we see here can continue to be
routed to the Internet and what as it
often happen in the world of ipv4 if
from my Callie I want to attack any of
these internal machine well I move on to
pivoting concept I attack this public IP
then I check these services in it Syria
support some of them a filtered I have
one open I could attack a good lunch and
exploit and once I'm inside I can access
any of this machines but as you can
imagine with ipv6 if there a director
and this is behind may I may access that
perhaps so let's see this one here let's
see if I can arrive with my current
configuration
so I arrive I connect and I can lunch
and an aim ap discover the ports they're
open so I connect can connect to that
host through SSH
and we see that we have a private
rerouting and we cannot arrive the place
where we are and we have access because
we have the ipv6 address which is
exposed and we're connected to it and
you can see how we're generating this
traffic through this call machine which
is here and I'm connected and I didn't
have to exploit I pivoted any questions
so far and you lost
I have a question of the back am I
allowed to take questions before the end
I guess I am now
let's see other real cases then we come
back to this environment whenever you
want we have this environment here Cal
has an eye a public address this one and
also a public address but the others are
internal
but ipv6 addresses when they come to a
network went when we want to reroute we
do this thing F Justin with regards the
firewall and other issues well we can do
it I think it's rather well you were
scanned with ipv4 you were given the
same service and with this can do an IP
v6 same host use you had a different
services now okay I'll exit this I
cannot well I change the configuration
and I will see it
this is this machine here 53
53 we can configure this with 10 this is
an interesting question
because I'll explain now the notion
I'll use 1016 here I use this so that we
don't have collisions let's see if I
arrive there
what was it 53 right and I'm ap I think
it's regular right
22 for 43 Friday and map by an MEP 253
this is the same one in the network
configuration they were not confused and
address is the same for ipv4 and ipv6
you see is the same one
it's interesting that you say that
because a dual stack concepts present
that the host at the ends as ever said
the end are the same ones but very often
the exposed bolts can change why because
the filtering you do I before does not
take place in ipv6 and that's the mess
because how many of you know about cyber
tables I'm sure most of you or at least
you've listened you've heard about them
but you know how to configure out to be
tables an ipv6 well less because it's
ib6 tables
so unfortunately ipv6 has a series of
advantages and is rich in many
environments and inference structures at
this cloud environments but people do
not have the skills or it's hard for
them to see did your speed they don't
bear in mind that when were using ipv6
when it's a bear in mind that it's a
different interface with a different
routing that offers an access to the
same machine and we'll see examples in
which the open ports in foreign 6 do not
coincide in real environments
real world what about ipv6 what this
doesn't exist in Spain we don't care
it's the future protocol but it hasn't
here yet it regardless of the statistics
you see in the internet Google to the
25% of its traffic it's in ipv6 or one
out of four connections as ipv6 and
their carriage is just T Mobile which
has 90 percent of the traffic in ipv6
most likely you know companies
organisation to have things in Amazon do
you know anyone that has something in
Amazon well this is what Amazon says I
was a little private cloud is the famous
VP sees
we can have availability sounds which
are the sound in which Amazon generates
a sort of data center availability for
creating virtual machines this subnet
10-0 something internal but see the ipv6
it says /x de for start with 2 so it
inaudible to the internet and it says
that the that the machines raised here
you have to be careful with this because
the main cloud providers has her Amazon
Google cloud platform have ipv6 and many
machines many V pcs have been raised
without having security considerations
that's is something else that people say
when they face ipv6 they say if I can
figure my ipv6 addresses randomly
they're difficult to guess perhaps the
attackers want to know what my machines
are located the notion of pivoting is
not I exploit a machine to get to the
others I can get to all of them I just
need to know where they're located how
can I know which machines belong to a
specific organization well I'll ask this
question later let's see how some
organizations are working with ipv6
rerouting they do things such as this
one a certain domain at work scope
change it from one seven three to four
five six zero one eight three two it's
very accessible and it's included into
the ipv6 address they generate this is
the network address and this is the host
address
how do you think we can know whether
another host and other ipv6 address
belongs to that same organization let's
imagine analyzing that organization I am
cannot but I'm doing pen testing and I
already have this ipv6 address how can I
know whether this one belongs to the
same organization with the network
address of course let's see another
example other people have assigned to
these prefix 2001 41 D whatever they
take their regular ipv4 address the RAF
traditional traditionally have they've
been administering for a long time and
they include it like that if you
translate into bits it's not different
because this is decimal and this other
thing is hexadecimal but so that it's
more legible more manageable many
organizations are doing this so this
could give us a clue if we know the
public ipv4 address of organization we
can check whether it is in ipv6 there's
something interesting here these are
real domains I'm not showing sensitive
information
deme domains
that of nothing in common apparently at
first iced this like intelligence test
find the differences well if you see
ipv4 addresses in ipv6 ipv6 in a
beauties for we see the same three
blocks are the same ones but in ipv4 if
you give me two addresses I cannot know
if they belong to the same organization
never I'm not using additional
techniques just with the IP address I
cannot know
however with ipv6 what happens if you
try this if you try to solve this you'll
see that the prefix is exactly the same
what tells you what does it tell you
from an infrastructure management and
network point of view they all this host
in domains are related
and what happens these are virtual
devices that are generated in this
environmentally known maintained in the
same infrastructure the routing goes to
the same place
could we guess or the house there well
it shouldn't be too difficult the
internal domains generated for it I P
are quite predictable and now based on
the question if asked
this solution we have a mr. look at
experimental level they started we
created the what we do is combining ipv4
and ipv6 this is not available in the
Internet we expected to be available
over the next weeks and I'll show this
to you now it's important to show the
concept there's a host an element final
docket talker in this case with this
weird name that may have two interfaces
and each one of them has different ports
you get there through different parts
you filter here perhaps you're not
filtering the other side and device
versa
babs you filter in a before but not a 96
and it's very often what we see is that
these security policies are not being
considered are not being properly
considered the goal of mr. lecoeur
project
is combining ipv4 domain IP v6 to show
that the device behind it is the same
one and therefore it is important to
apply the appropriate filter the
appropriate network configuration this
host is domain if you fly in map or you
solve ipv4 address and then ipv6 address
and you apply and mapa to it stack
you'll see there are differences we
wanted to point this out and that's why
we mark in red ports with scene one side
and we don't seem to the other ones
doesn't mean that it's safer in IP 4 and
I've been and not in MV 6 it doesn't
make sense for it to be different as of
today if they have the same network same
access through the internet why the
configuration is different in stock ipv6
and ipv4 other examples that I want to
show
I've
I have some queries here let's try with
this one with another one who has open
polls and now you would say well it's a
compliment it's it isn't better or worse
it just complimented a vision I love you
let's take an I piss ipv6 address which
is there's one and it's carried a search
I don't know whether we're going to get
something but could anyone tell me what
I'm trying to do with this query as a
matter of fact I could remove the host
address it doesn't it's not necessary
I'm trying to obtain all the hosts that
may be somehow related to this other one
why because I'm using the address and
the prefix to search I don't know what
I'm going to obtain besides the one I
already have
well we have seven different machines
have been different IP addresses we have
this case we have this domain there's
nothing in IB v4 in ipv6 we have this
address and we have an SSH port which is
open with a good vulnerability
this has a potential because if you
don't have the right security policy
you'll have a problem because if someone
knows one of your IP v6 addresses and
they want to pivot because they're not
interested that machine they can guess
whether that organization has other ipv6
addresses which are exposed to the
Internet they just need to discover ipv6
addresses which also belong to the same
ipv6 prefix and look how simple it is
sometimes to find security breaches when
you find open ports well this was my
presentation we have five minutes more
we can have a Q&A or we continue with
the practical side of this any other
question comment down to the example and
pivoting we've seen we've seen that when
we have a network configured as private
we access the first machine and from
that we can pivot in the second one you
know be visit six if I access a machine
with an address can I then access a
network is configured as local link can
I jump from one IP to the other yes
let's imagine
we have our environment
I'll use the ssh access
I'm inside the machine
we have internal routing ipv6 public
address but also dealing local routing
this routing starting with F II is the
one you can see in a BB six both in
Linux and Windows systems with the
productions this routing is it's not the
equivalent to ipv4 because it behaves
differently this network addresses how
to automatically generating generated in
any interface has an a local address in
ipv4 we have to configure it ourselves
but as soon as we happen interface we
need an ipv6 address in link-local it's
usually generated based on the MAC
address of the interface what do we need
this interface in order to have
immediate connectivity with nodes in the
same domain in the same land connect to
the same switch so LIC MVP's six
protocols are used and I'm going to try
something I'm not sure it works
minotaurs Estolano I don't even have net
tools and stored him if you access
usually the very basic Duggar machines
didn't have net tools installed that's
what you have the pin and other things
so he type in the proper commands and
you have the network address and network
turns this is cool in order to discover
elements in the same ipv6 elements in
link-local because it's a multicast to
trust in our baby 6 and deport any
machine compatible active for ipv6 have
to listen to that ipv6 address if I pin
30 tries all the active machines have to
answer unless it's filtered through
firewall at host level Linux today I
think most of them answer but up windows
but from this machine even inside were
compromised we get launched
I queried to see what machines are
available at Li local level but we may
be more limited compared to the other
approach when we go from the outside
will be limited to the switch to which
we're connected and because very often
there are services which cannot be
accessed from the link-local at the side
there only active on the public side but
yes we would have a ways to pivot
once we've pivoted if there's public
ipv6 we go from the outside maybe have
your ipv4 we go from the inside and it
would be a nice idea
see point one and you'll see that some
machines will answer thank you you
always say sick off its IP
a level rerouting is complex than many
papers written with recommendations on
how to manage a rerouting because you
have to change your mindset so far I
think it was slash 16 that the network
subnetting
that's what you learn when you're
training networks
and based on how they block sir
structures and I forgot the question
when he installed a router you connect
to a device
everything goes automatically through
DHCP what about ipv6 can be configured
without me knowing you've explained a
server when there's an HCP server a
router at home but there's a server
which is internet worth listening to
provide the ipv4 address to the devices
being connected you save your device
you're answered and you get the ipv4 bit
in ipv6 you don't even need the HTTP
server there's a Dresden link Naga
already configured if you configure an
environment in raspberry you connect
machines but you don't have any router
you have to access and configure manual
you can figure the address the IP but in
ipv6 and LAN level there's going to be
visibility with at least one ipv6
network which is local if it's
configured automatically even more
automatically than I believe for
we're talking about public routing
different services which proactively you
can figure this additionally traveling
local ends you can see there's an
important change an ipv4 interfaces can
only have one ipv4 address that you can
change the nappy v6 there several
addresses one hundreds of IPS which is
another attack you falsified saying that
a router and some interface there's
several ipv6 interfaces and you can
create a denial of service yep you've
answered but there was quite a job well
you need to see the other side if you
take security into account we have more
connectivity potential you were more
agile when it comes to configure devices
and many of the organizers have
standardized the internet they want end
to end
connectivity with no intermediate
elements like cg map that covers
implement this type of technological
solutions they don't want them to happen
they want to have a flat and flat so to
speak flat network in terms of
connectivity and to end and it would be
more efficient it was simpler and some
services wouldn't be so complicated when
trying to connect machines behind a LAN
network they have to show their
communication protocols what we want
with ipv6 is into end connectivity from
a security point of view of course
that's what we want to explain we have
to bear this in mind but ipv6 comes with
many advantages from a network point of
view if there are no more questions
either your death your sleeping or you
didn't understand anything thank you
very much
[Applause]
you