[Music]
you
Oh No me llamo Jose Ignacio
good morning my name is Jose Tanana
we'll be sharing with you the design of
a platform for cybersecurity sinners we
aimed our learning and training well
this is me I am an IT engineer and my
participation in the world of cyber
security has been through CTF
competition challenges etc I have taken
part in the European cyber security
challenges in 2016 and 2017 the first
one was held in Dusseldorf and the
second one here in 2017 in Malaga
actually we were the winners so we had a
great time okay
and then now CTF cyber camp which will
be held this Saturday I participated in
all the editions and I want the warning
2015 and I was second T in the 2017 so
therefore I am very much due to take
part in competitions in hacking and CTF
set cetera and well this is related to
the platform that I will be sharing with
you this is me this is a company where I
work SGS accessories companies a
multinational company its present in
1066 and it employs some 400,000 people
why a platform of these characteristics
well previous speaker told us that in
the Spain or well all over the world
the attitudes of people working in the
field of security is extremely important
and then the aptitude and the attitude
has to be focused on in learning in
training in cybersecurity do you have to
get training and then and that training
requires having a number of resources so
this is not about studying only this is
not theory so every one part
well little creatures plumbers very many
professions have to put things into
practice have to practice and we have to
practice at a cybersecurity world so
that's what I have said active platform
offering see simulation and sense
platforms or scenario similar to those
that we will be facing in the real life
that here we have two elements
scalability and final costs well for
perhaps for company's cost is not a
significant problem but in the world of
Education cost is a crucial factor and
this is what I try to optimize the my
platform and I believe that cyber
security training is based on three
pillars nowadays there are very many
well-known days and in this sector there
are many self-taught people there are
very many competitions competitions are
helped us learn a lot and also we have
university training University training
it's getting better and better in this
new field it is quite new fields and
then the universities are adapting to
real world but still we have
small gap between University and real
life and then we also have professional
certifications and I believe that these
are the three pillars when it comes to
cyber security training so no well there
are other challenges platforms out there
where people learn all by doing a very
much like hack the Box platform I'm sure
many of you have tried it out have
several challenges and work to it to me
this is a significant source of learning
very interesting ok so what is the focus
of hack the Box well has a base with
thousands of users and these users are
updating contents all the time so there
is a new washing every single week at
5:00 p.m. every Saturday new content is
included or offered so these are virtual
machines well has number implications
that we will refer to later on but to
summarize there is a high cost of
infrastructure we wanted to replicate
this model at a university so now it is
the business model of hacked box this is
based on a subscription so you have the
option of not paying anything and to
share to share a scenario of machines
with very many other users some but
sometimes sharing some of those machines
is an actual problem is a big problem
well your training capability is quite
reduced however you may go subscribe to
it and you share that laughed at a
scenario with 20 people the problem with
this type of a scenario is that the
advancements and progression of people
you are sharing the platter
we may either benefit you or be a bit
well detrimental for you but anyway it's
a moral it's a modern which I feel is
good and the problem a fear is the high
cost of it if you want to implement it
yourself and then also another downside
this is not an open platform some
motivation for me to work in the
platform I was doing the dissertation at
the end of my Master's course and then I
decided to focus on this topic for my
dissertation so the challenges platforms
that are open source do not manage the
infrastructure of the challenges that is
to say the virtualization
these platforms only manage these corpus
how to insert the flags but they do not
manage the challenge infrastructure and
then there are also other of the shelfs
platforms I would not say out any names
I've tried some of them and actually
I've juiced some of them in competitions
very sustained here at incident but they
leave a lot to be desired
they are not that good so therefore I
decided to improve whatever is available
up there and I said well is this
business opportunity well I decided to
go for it and I'm quite happy with the
outcome so this is the work that was
presented at the GIC 2018
we got a diploma so it's in the word to
the first the best article about
training and innovation so now let us
move on into the platform and its design
well the technical architecture
technology just is quite simple which
works is based on NYNEX
the front-end is its angular GTS its
angular GA s so I have thought about
rewriting it in a different technology
Google or other but that will be in the
future and now I want to shift it into
something which is can be compiled but
the prototype that we use is no Delta J
s and angularjs and the performance of
far so good so in terms of
virtualization maneuvering costs the
main proposal is using docker containers
these implies many things so we should
be based on Linux it is lightweight and
it is scalable and as it is designs can
be configured in from module of cluster
module it is plain and simple so the
platform allows you to set up many
parallel servers when we say many we
refer to four or five remember that the
objective here is to lower costs and
it is an API rest controlling the
infrastructure very easy to implement at
university you will Francis with
authentication at University features
and everything and then it proposes a
standard design of scenario so everyone
knows how to do token any students who
want to produce dissertation can provide
content to the to this platform so well
there are also some sausages only few
platforms can be virtualized but well we
are not talking about virtualizing here
well perhaps Linux and Windows 2016 you
may introduce applications that network
but there are many possibilities
alternatives are also proposed through
support other platforms the main problem
is the kernel is shared any kind from
durability makes your platform
vulnerable and you cannot depositors in
the scenario because it doesn't give you
the necessary protection or installation
but here we find an offset in between
comic how hard it is for you to make it
and but you can do for instance P
because if a student is doing something
which should not be doing okay well you
can also get to know about it so it is
quite an acceptable trade-off ok you
know what people are
doing with it it is like copying in an
exam okay and now well we will be
discussing ot later on because this is
an interesting proposition
IOT devices can be used through a shift
system often will have five devices from
the same model and students will
candidates or those who are getting
training have to share these devices and
then also hack the box model so while it
is known as booting fruit and it is a
virtual machine with a snap shell and
then you configure the challenge and you
may reset it as many times as possible
to reset it over and over and then you
set up five or six in parallel for each
scenario but as well that means that the
cost will grow exponentially
but if needed the platform would also
support it and then we have
infrastructure as a service why having
no convert realization when you can
start the machines when the students or
whoever is getting training needs them
so if you need a hundred machines for
three minutes or 40 minutes then you
will be invoiced only for those 40
minutes and then the platform will be
internet dated with the i-s platform
whether it is Amazon or you name it okay
so this is idea it is not fully finished
but it is quite simple to implement
logical architecture well but it is
important first of all to have the logic
of the competition and then on the other
hand the logic to manage the
infrastructure and which is the main
driver for this project some recent
improvements feels that a jet already
tested and tested them in Luzerne Swiss
Swiss Atlanta the past weekend and my
well if the
allow me I would like to implement it
the Polytechnic University in Madrid
support for virtual machine
infrastructure-as-a-service
controlling costs well we will see
whether we will succeed in that then a
number of a couple of keys have been
generated for the equipment everything
is unified well two keys will allow you
to access all the scenarios all the
challenges also it automatically manages
the VPN access if needed for instance
indirect as the Polytechnic University
will put the Technical University Madrid
Wi-Fi is available to students so not
all the ports of entry or inbound or
outbound ports are open so how do we
resolve that will resolve that through
VPN VPN allows us to control all the
activity that is carried out on the
platform we can produce analytics we can
produce retrieval interesting data so
well this has been integrated in the
platform it's up and running and works
very well and then supports first
physical devices and I hire a hardware
side channeling et cetera and management
of the different shifts
now let us look at the scenarios that
are supported by the platform especially
the docker model and we start off with
the most simple environments okay so
containers is started they use a long
time against that container so to decide
the challenge system the only
requirement is that the docker container
but you may have whatever you want to
have in it but it will have entry node
in the one three three seven port and
then the user will have to log on to
this URL and to this port have random
port and every time to start the
scenario the port changes and then what
different ports four different equipment
so this provides us an insulation
between the different isolates the
different devices but all the members of
the team I can access to the same
scenario to the same container so that
they can work in parallel all on the
same container so this is what we was
very much decided and then we attempted
this is very simple you can do that in
ten minutes you don't need a platform to
manage that for you but what is actually
interesting is this Wellum this more
complex setup I hope you can read it so
you have entry point in the scenario and
then the scenario have several network
with several containers in this case so
do you go into SSH container or through
the web and then you pivot from there
and then you escalate privileges in that
machine then you move on to the other
users you get more information from the
other you said you move on to remain
access to the second network and only
through the container the user cannot
access that network through the device
has to call mandatory through this
intermediary node and then there are
other services and other visible
containers that led you to access more
networks and how to
design these exercises well in theory
this is quite simple you have festival
to define the networks that you have the
networks to which each container is
knocked in and then an entry point and
the entry point has to go through 1 3 3
1 3 3 7 port which simplifies content
management and now the complexity and
well at the end of the day cost okay
which is were driving this project
so all these depends on the complexity
of this scenario because we are talking
about containers is is quite can be
easily scaled so at the end of the day
you will have students grouped in three
or four teams so at the end of the day
training professionals working
individually well that's a different
story that we are not talking about now
so to summarize at the end of the day
you will have less than 80 teams less
than 80 instances in this scenario I'm
trolly this scenario in the best case
but at the end of the day we will have
in like eight containers so it is cheap
it is cheap in terms of resources in
terms of machines so an example change
scenario such as this one on the screen
with 40 people 18 team consumed reduced
up 1 gigabytes of them with 2 CPUs that
were virtualized CPUs from Amazon
basically it went very well performed
very well users did not complain at all
12 euros for 24 hours affordable
now examples of exercises exercises that
can be supported by this platform I will
be sharing three categories cryptography
exploiting web analysis three different
types of fixin areas and the most simple
example is statement headline you enter
the solution and that's it
any open source platform can do that for
you this is a cryptographic puzzle this
is the statement and then this is the
solution so you have a base64 chain to
code it and then you have fake has hex a
chain and then the secret message is
this one this is the flag then you
insert it here and that's it okay so
very no no mystery behind it now a more
complex exercise would be an exploding
challenge do you have a bite in binary
but you don't have to download it in
your computer and trust it no you don't
have to do that the platform gives you
an environment but in this case a
container you launch the container and
then you get on detail login details
some hast purged username password this
is an SSH chain
so you first configure the private and
public key and the actual platform gives
you the command that you need so you do
current paste and then you just go
through you log in through that SSH and
then tells you you have binary in - a PP
gives you the tools that you need to
debug the binary to do overflow whatever
you want to do so this one we will
resolve it later on in our demo this one
and the next one which are simple
success cases well have I applied this
platform and I give you the most recent
example I applied it in and events last
weekend in my louse hug in Lausanne
Switzerland
it was the Polytechnic University in
those an discipline 19 challenges
including 17 coyote challenges so I will
show you a few photographs 17 teams 40
participants
the consumption of had resources to CPUs
and one gigabyte of RAM so invoice world
less than 15 euros 24 hours so that was
the objective and the user experience
was very flowing but I've seen in the
last five years in competitions is at
the end of the day in virtualized
environments as user experience is not
never too good because well everything
is no you are just I don't know do
typing in one language and then you then
you get like a serial Aiken language so
not a good user experience but not last
weekend so IOT so the problem with IOT
often you have your own never for each
device has of devices that you know what
you can see it ok top left is in
lightbulb then this is an IP camera on
the right we have radiofrequency so we
take a hack RF and then they had to
communicate or broadcast a walkie talkie
communication so there was an emphasis
NFC reader for control access presence
sensor and then we have this electronic
lock the temperature control temperature
sensor
driving fun and then the presence
detector activated an alarm this was a
result of doing that man-in-the-middle
attack will had a Wi-Fi network for all
these devices here at the bottom and
basically these works through HTTP so do
you apply RP spoofing and then you
hijack the connections and you can do
whatever you want to do with the sensors
actuators so the objective of the
challenges were these months these were
basic challenges that were not advanced
challenges so there was quite a basic
training for students at this university
there were not cybersecurity
professionals although I should say that
some professional jointing and then well
they did all that in two to three hours
and the students took 24 hours to
resolve the challenge in the case of the
camera was very simple API land mode
control just send commands and then IP
camera this vulnerable to a well-known
exploit rather than as Proteus impactor
do sent in a command or every quest HT
to the best which is Parliament do
connect unit then get logging dot CTE
with no - intro intro and what you get
back part username equals this password
equals the password that you gave to it
and then you go into the cameras and
admin then you see the Wi-Fi password
and then taking advantage that there are
like some hundred thousand cameras
connected to the internet so you have
access to some 100,000 Wi-Fi all over
the world but but that's a different
topic
so these are oil tea challenges we gave
the students half an hour for each
device however that can be multiplexed
so if when a team was working on the lap
of and another one on the camera and
another team was working on the button
devices the button devices cannot be
multiplexed because they had to do a net
spoofing and you don't really want to
multiplex it because you cannot do it
okay you cannot work in parallel so what
is the what did you get what do we get
from the platform but it does a platform
deliver well it allows you to manage
shifts so let us say a team gets an
appointment from the 3 to 2:30 for this
challenge from 5:00 to 2:30 for this
other challenge from 6:00 to 2:00
success into this other challenge and
for this challenge you have to read this
document for this other challenge you
have to read these other documents well
which is good way to start so these
students resolving the challenge and the
winners and now
well let us see whether the platform but
soon we can see a live demo
okay that will be brief
[Music]
so there are two panels here a user
panel and admin panel and we are
primarily interested in the user panel I
am NOT ready logged in so there is a
profile itself where you run it for each
category where your team is where you
are in your team and then you may
download the VPN config file which is
the solution choose for VPN in this case
is not needed may be needed
yes you just log on to the public URL
for this web app you don't need VPN but
from here you may download the file then
you import the VPN piano pin and then
you may access challenges right away and
this is the team public team well
actually there are a couple of keys and
then Jews I know the private key I don't
know whether you can see here bottom
left
it is very simple so this is the panel
for the challenges we started off with
the easiest one
well resolving this challenge was very
easy so this is a string at the same
place 64 for sure then you code it do
one did you put it into practice when
the students first is difficult to
resolve this one and the next one was
much easier well I thought it very
strange but the thing is that because
they couldn't read I don't know that you
can read her not this is an exact XML
chain and while they found it very
strange and they did not continue
believe they were to read this is the
secret message and this is the exit
decimal chain if they had done that they
would have resulted very quickly so it
took them an average of an hour to
resolve the challenge which is quite a
strange
okay 25 points okay
[Music]
so this is the scoreboard that we used
last weekend so this is scoring this is
a horizontal line standing for a week we
see the well but each of the teams did
the progression and it's quite user
friendly platform and now when you need
a virtual environment let us go to the
first exploding which is easy to resolve
to click on it hook is very quickly it
gives you the environment you copy the
command or you just type it in while you
that you can copy it then gets locked in
I don't know how to enlarge the screen
so that you can follow it so do you see
binary there there are many ways to
resolve it well gdb is one of them and
then it uploads in front and gdb
that is to say gives you the tools that
you need it also has radar and other
tools you don't really need to download
the binary or having anything installed
in your computer
so I'll show you how the binary works so
you run it and then it says okay give me
a password then you enter the passwords
and then it says no now that is not the
right password then we debug it very
quickly then we integrate it an argument
we see there Naugatuck the disassembling
we are doing step by step okay this is
basic thing to do in exploring well
actually do you kind of consider this
exploding
then here right on top we see part of
password
okay we have the logs stuck and it is
comparing that to the all the contents
that have entered okay give me a sec
okay we should be getting it now here it
is this is the password okay password it
is just a random password
okay and then give me the flag important
this is a dynamic flag if I pass it on
to different to another team it will not
work for them so flag is generated every
time and launch the launch and scenario
so this is good because it helps it
people not to cheat another an easy way
to resolve this challenge because this
is a string in the binary to do a great
flag or crack password and then you get
the password it is faster this was yes
an example for you to see how the
platform manages that you may buy a hint
and you use the string commands and well
you resolve the challenge very quickly
well there are other challenges that are
more complicated because this other
thing help to contain access to content
through SSH and it says connected easily
are L and I I know is STP and don't
answer it yes there's the container just
for you in this case you solve it it's a
felt the database table
and you have like it's easy to solve etc
it's a web panel dashboard
you push the button we have URL you
click and you have the environment to
solve it so it's trivial
[Music]
it works correctly because the
environment is only active if you're
solving it if you're not solving it the
environment is not as Human Resources
and once you solve it the platform
throws this away the user does not have
to do it and if it's open for more than
one hour it's also thrown away so it's
configured say that after one hour it's
thrown away so that does not consume
resources the administration panel
which is in Spanish here
you can see active environments in this
case there's no nothing
but you can more or less check what's
consuming resources the flags that have
been captured when who in the team you
see the seductive environment here by
demo device
it shows the state you can access the
environment and you can check the logs
of that container the platform has an
event record the events that I think are
interesting have recorded it takes the
time to load because there's there are
recordings for 24 hours
basically demo device has logged in at
this time this challenge has been solved
the clue was bought the hint was bought
and there these are the types of events
we're bit behind schedule
I'm going to solve a couple other
challenges array you can see the spirits
of the competition for those of you who
are not familiar with it
this one is interesting
only one team solved it last weekend is
an exploiting event exploiting
environment but it doesn't give you the
binary code know whether sage it says he
have to connect through his socket
cities at the binary response how do you
face this
you connect gives you a user all up
give me a password Paulo it says no
incorrect credentials
I'm open text editor so you can see this
easily
with this little script we solve the
challenge so basically for exploiting
challenges this is a framework in
Theismann which is quite useful upon
tools I strongly recommend it
as listen to there are two points you
send string format which is
vulnerability and basically I tried to
download the block of the process memory
which is what you're doing here the fly
is transmitted as an environment a
variable or the comparison is in the
memory the password against which you
are comparing to the memory it's going
to be shown in that piece of memory
you've downloaded so for each position I
connect I send the command I want and it
returns eight bytes memory which is
interesting
so I'd show the vulnerability here
the percentage P memory pointer first I
were going to give him give one which is
a first position
this is the first position is the memory
in hexadecimal so I do the same thing
and it gives me the next piece of memory
so to speak so I execute this solver in
the port given by the platform
it starts dump the memory until it finds
the flag
takes a while a few seconds
well step-by-step
there's not much left I think
and then you find the flag it finds the
flag so it's walked
simple challenges with very basic
notions
we've seen a series of environment there
are more this one for example
it was solved with just one Tim its
handbook buffer overload didn't have the
binary to do period
to debug it sorry
and no one tells you you have to go to
this direction within the binary code
SLR is activated perhaps is not that
easy this would be the solar in this
case with palm tools it's easy to do the
only difficult thing is finally the
offset it was a small buffer if you
iterated the opposite in which you
control the red in this case was 38 the
direction is given by the binary code
itself you code it as you should and
and then you get the flag in this case
we execute it to see how it is
I don't know if you can see it but this
is the flag quite simple
if you asked for a hint
his binary a function called scanf which
is vulnerable to overflow attacks
[Music]
another example because I haven't shown
any complex environment scenario a
comfort scenario a very and as example
boosie's one if you connect to a
container through as a sage the
environment says this I continue down
the network if you put DNS challenge
it's going to route to you there's a
token problem which is that you cannot
control I peers you cannot use fixed IP
so you need to use the internal DNS and
docker which is the name of the
container move less and it's routable so
the environment is called challenge it's
going to invert but you have no idea
what the IB is so every time you launch
it a different IB and it's very
complicated to use fixed IPS it doesn't
make sense in this case whether you work
within internal DNS and that's a that's
what the platform does it has
disadvantages too
in this case machine is responding right
this to see something and in this case
you connect to a server it says access
deny this is your token this was great
idea if you realize there are with
numbers and consecutive numbers the name
is certainty cotton alternative and
Spanish it's authenticated based on your
so sport I can't remember the name of
the parameter I think it was this one
I can't remember the name
[Music]
local port
I can't remember
this one if you send the HTTP request
with a specific port which is 3 1 3 3 7
you realize that it was sent to getting
against your local port you we were
given the flag and that's it
to measure that shot out of the box
thinking of candidates its platform
beside training and education it's
designed also to hire staff I'm a
company I have a red team at pentester
testing team how do I know that
candidates or that are arriving have
knowledge or not but they have the Exile
but they do it themselves that governed
the team of the company I need them to
know this to have the skills I can have
specific exercises with the specific
topic and as a company as team leader
Canada I can assess their skills and
whether they they comply with the
requirements I have for a specific
profile or perhaps it's more generic
move that I make profile what I want I
can measure this with it say can you
please go back there to presentation
these are my conclusions
the cost visualization strategy is
pivotal more particularly for teaching
environments which was the main goal of
this project well it was that any
question what everyone that no questions
well that's it thank you very much
you