[Music]
Here I am it is a pleasure to be with
you I would like to thank a cyber
compound in Siva for having invited me
to be here and to deliver these
inspirational presentations
my presentation will not be technical
about the work that we detectives do but
my presentations I'm telling you the
importance or the relevancy that we have
at our offices and agencies to hire
highly qualified personnel so this is a
quick presentation about myself I am a
private detective security director in
terms of Education have an engineering
degree also Diploma in forensics also a
words that I have received and I am a
co-founder and organizer of the cyber
security conference in healthy in
federal that Kampala
I'm also co-founder and cook and SSL
Jackson Keith which is an
awareness-raising workshop who also
awareness-raising workshop for IT
security for young kids and kids okay
where we raise awareness about safe use
of IC devices this is the content of my
presentation
very quickly will tell you about what a
private detective is
how a private detective get trained how
our profession is regulated then the
relationship between private detectives
and cybersecurity also what we currently
need highly proof highly qualified
people in cybersecurity and our private
detective companies and then cases
associated with cybersecurity
characteristics are a cyber security
professional should have to work in a
private detective firm often these
characteristics are shared by many of
the needs that our requirements when it
comes to becoming a consultant for
instance one of them being availability
however I would well I also would like
to talk about the advantages and
disadvantages of it then also what can a
cyber security professional expect if he
were to work in a private detective firm
and then how can I contact private
detective firms to offer my candidacy to
work there and well I have to say that
there is no there are lots of well and
regulated jobs in professions so
therefore I just wanted to offer this
information for you to know whether if
you are sending your CV whether you're
sending that CV to a legal company and
license company so let us start off with
well what is probably detector and
regulation of our profession first of
all the private detectives are the only
professionals that are legally enable
enabled or qualified to obtain and
provide information and evidence about
behaviors of private matters
so we to investigate on those people and
any one working in our team has to have
legal license so how many active
detectives are there in Spain 1,400
1,400
there are like some 4,500 licenses but
only 1400 active detectives 70% of them
are men and we have an increasing number
of women now starting staying at 30%
so prime investigation services they are
about having out necessary
investigations to obtain and provide
information and evidence associated with
behaviors of private matters associated
to the following aspects often we have
cases where a person calls us wants to
find her about the vasa passages that
his partner hapana is sending out to
someone else or for instance finding out
about type of lifestyle of a neighbor or
wants us to take photographs of a person
he is maybe related or not so therefore
we cannot carry out those type of
activities actually we cannot carry
those type of investigations actually we
were to do it that would be unlawful so
what are these aspects that I mentioned
before those associated with well
financed labor and economics so
therefore we have we can investigate
people in those fields fields as
economic financial labour American child
or trade field with the exception of the
activities that are carried out in
homicides or
reserved places okay and then we also
obtain information and guarantee the
normal development of trade fairs hotels
exhibitions events conventions so places
were a significant number of people and
where the there may be people like has
not wearing a uniform and ensuring the
normal development of performance of the
activities also we also carry out
investigations to obtain information and
evidence relatives to crimes that can
only be prosecutors after being on the
request of subjects that are legitimate
in criminal process that is to say we
need to have a person accusing it we
just that cannot be an ex-official
prosecution on the part of the
government and then whatever important
qualifications of detective well it
seems that anyone could become a
detective or claim to be a detective now
private detectives in Spain one of the
best trained detectives in Europe and
actually our degree is an undergraduate
degree and there are also training
courses given out at university for 180
credits that enable or qualified the
person to work as a private detective
what are the universities offering these
degree volunteer competences Salamanca
Alicante oedema
Pablo la Viva as well as other online
universities where you can study
and Patrice today
well we study Constitution under
criminal law Criminal Procedure and Oh
Civil Procedure
no civil law like if we Birkin too
similar to in law school we also study
social psychological and criminal
science the ontology and then in the
last year we do practices we practices
in firms in detective firms so that is
students when they graduate have some
practical training experience
requirements to be qualified and
licensed as a private detective very
quickly so first of all you need to be
Spanish national or European then
psychological aptitude and physical
capacity what does that mean it means
that we need to have the same well
obtain the same aptitude certificates
that police people or security guards
need to have to carry arms also not
having any police records so these
requirements are not necessary to go to
university to follow the undergraduate
studies or the Diploma that I mentioned
before but these requirements are needed
to be qualified to be licensed as
private detective
therefore after fulfilling with these
requirements I will be I will be getting
my lessons anti card now our profession
is regulated but no 5 - 2014 from the
4th of April so this is a regulation for
private security we are waiting for a
new regulation - for better regulation
of our profession it will be pastors and
prohibition what are the things that we
cannot do with hunters investigates and
people of from service security world
who will work with us will not be
allowed to carry out the following
investigations either that is to say the
crimes that are being investigated by
the government if during our
investigations we become aware of a
crime it's mandatory for us to report it
to the police then we deliver all the
information and all the evidence that we
have gathered we give it to the police
and that's where our work stop finishes
and we cannot investigate intimacy of
people as they are staying in the
private homes or in reserved places and
we cannot use this type of information
or technical elements or materials that
encodes against the right of owner
intimacy of the actual person and of his
family
or also that have an impact or violate
the secrecy of communication and data
protection we will we are not allowed to
use means vehicles or badges that may be
similar to those that are worn by the
law enforcement agencies we are not
wearing any badges or any sirens in our
vehicles we try to pass the notice as
much as possible have produced a graph
to show you the evolution about the
different types of investigations so
this is a timeline from 1990 up until
so this is a very generic graph so
investigations of our labor issues
insurance
unfaithfulness or or IT techniques so
well if you think that the only thing
that we do are investigations of our
people who are cheating on each others
we don't do that we most of our activity
is devoted primarily to issues labor
issues and well nowadays let us say
recently only 10% of the investigations
carried housing some firms for personal
matters with regard to people cheating
on it and then but with regard to
investigations technical investigations
IT investigations or any investigation
which is somehow technical
here we're seeing a significant change
Park in 1990 there were less than 5%
whereas now that has been skyrocketed up
until nearly 50% I can tell you that our
profession so here we'll have people of
all ages a wider range of Ages so now we
are having new entrants in our companies
they're very much updated on new
technologies but I'd like to say that
other firms would require experts in
cybersecurity pentesters system
administrators do you name it we will be
very soon needing cyber security experts
number firms nearly 50% of the
investigations that we are asked to do
associated one way or another with IC
issues and surely you will not be
surprised when you hear the hundred
percent of the investigations in hundred
percent of our investigations we carry
out sometimes of IT investigations and
even if you say mean by IT investigation
finding out the name of the person
working in the company when as long as
we get that information from Google
through any browser social media so this
is basic and basic thing nowadays and
what to be investigating the on the
Internet well we investigated browsers
being Google social media Facebook
Twitter Linkedin we use a script Python
we abuse a PS we overuse IPAs this is
for us to get as close as possible to
the personal company that we will be
investigating
what fool well because we want to find
out about that person who is his family
who are his friends
what are his corporate responsibilities
why he meets with these people sometimes
and not other times so you will see
later on
well the usefulness of all - what else
do we check - we investigate later time
what do we do what we like what do we
like to travel this kind of thing and
also where do we work why do we work
there and not somewhere else my brother
for my job that we had the pharma
company we worked for so all that
information is available on the Internet
and we collected there what do we
analyze well we analyze information
provided in the browser information on
social media personal details address ID
card number photographs with the person
in them what place education training
even if you've given a ticket a speeding
ticket that information is available on
the Internet as well as family
relationships personal relationships
things that person like hobbies also
events we are planning to attend in some
of our reports we have provided
photographs that we collected found on
social media where the person was
carrying out an activity that was
counterproductive I don't know whether
it is dancing or was writing or you name
it and then also clients also request us
to investigate other matters and that is
the reason why I'm here today
so plans asked us to investigate all
fair competition issues that are very
much associated with the IT forensics
assistance management's also leaking of
confidential information detection of
intrusions later on which has a very
curious case of our intrusion detection
also industrial espionage companies have
very concerned about that this is not
only about corporate data going public
on the internet and then issues related
to data protection or data protection
regulation but it is about having
competitors spying on you stealing
industrial information and kind of well
overtaking you and then in terms of
insurance fraud many of the fruits that
are investigated in Spain are easily
solved through number of posts on
Facebook for Instagram this is a person
bragging about
I don't know having driven a racing car
door car or saying that he was I don't
know
Hill there and also information prior to
contracts imagine that a company wants
to engage in business with a Chinese
company while company may have some
information still to know what is behind
that actual company the company may look
very good especially beginning after the
first order but then perhaps the Spanish
company will never will get paid were
and then as I say before engaging into
business contracts we also covered
investigation about the company and as I
say many of the other cases that we
worked in associated with cyber security
whether it is IT service security
forensic analysis system testing etc why
do we need cyber security experts
working with us because of the not high
near an IT expert forensic as I may need
and as I say an expert I may have that
know-how
however sometimes I also want the party
to produce that report for me and then
one of the latest uses that had the
we needed to have the expert witness I
hire as an expert witness that I trust
and he produces and expert witness
reports and then I also produce reports
so that these IT experts also gives his
deposition and what do I need an ethical
hacker because sometimes I really need
to know the status in the system since I
have been compromised
I also need an intelligence analysts why
is that because we gather so much data
as a result of our investigations and
data not only connected and online but
also data that is gathered in the street
because we are following people
surveillance people then we bring
together all the data data that is later
clean that is used to produce a final
report well so we also need experts in
programming JavaScript PHP Perl these
are the paradigmatic programming
languages for mixing a ps4
[Music]
any type of misuses or abuses then
system administrators often in cases of
in nutrition the company may not be
interested in that is known that an
investigation is being carried out so
therefore we sent someone to go to the
company and to see what is happening in
the company also editor of IT systems we
need an expert to cover out analysis not
eating for us and then well many other
needs and requirements that we find on
as we play as we go on now I'm going to
share with use cases that are related to
cyber security as a result of solving
some of them I was awarded a prize and
some of these cases also helped prevent
significant harm to citizens that's the
reason I've been awarded that prize all
those prizes so this one is very
interesting case surely you will be
severe variation an insurance company
contacted us because one of the insured
people said
reported that some jewels had been
stolen at his home
so no first no well the jewels were
stood in specific place or kept in a
specific place and we were asked to
investigate the case because insurers
were claiming high significant
compensation so we just did a pure
investigation went over there gathered
evidence so with all that evidence we
moved on to analysis well analyze the
case then well some things were not
worthy suspicious we and as we were
seeing all - an idea came to mind and I
say because these jewels were Jews in
general watches and the like had been
stolen so we were investigating the case
but at the same time we had to estimate
the value of the jewels that had been
stolen so therefore we asked the share
person to send us photographs where we
could see the stolen jewel for instance
a watch for us to see the brand to feed
and to estimate the value of fish and
what we expected the person was to send
us photographs of either no big events a
wedding or first communion often that's
what you were you jewels but contrary to
what we expected but we got for the
insured person were just photographs of
the jewels and then all place on top of
table there were a series of well three
or four photographs but actually we just
did not expect to have him to have these
type of photographs both on the masseur
okay let us take a look at those
photographs let us analyze the
photographs that he shared
person-centered then I said well
analysis expect with this analysis
well metadata see what's behind which
are the data of those photographs we
could all do that anyone could do that
you don't really need to be an expert so
what did we find
okay the theft took place in May
photographs were made in July and we're
at his home
I took the jeweler's I put them on the
table I took a photograph s sent that
out to the insurance company well I
don't have information about the shirt
person so you don't really need to be an
expert to know that mobile phones well
consenting a lot of information attached
to a photograph what the case will be
second court and as I say I her as an
expert witness for him to carry out a
detailed comprehensive analysis of the
photograph I don't know how the case
will be eventually solved because it is
pending distribution what report so
second case stealing of information the
company is asking us to investigate some
anonymous documents that had been
received in the company about internal
processes in the company so these
documents were not expected to leave the
company so therefore we expected someone
in the company exfiltrating the company
and they will say well surely an
employee got a USB
recorded or saved as documented data and
exfiltrated them what happens when we go
to the place well we worked with an IT
system who worked there and then the IT
system expert found that some
photographs have been sent out from PC
and actually this photograph from
marketing catalog I never thought of
that but that's the particle operator
could see that those photographs had a
hashtag of the original photographs that
were sent out to come to client and I
said well there is a mismatch here
between these hashes
okay so analysis was made afterwards and
then we asked forensic analysts to do
that analysis for us so that is to say
again
cyber security experts and what did we
find
well this person was easily found
located we knew the IP address we do
everything we just didn't know how he
did it so we use a stenography and then
this person within those marketing
leaflets he introduced this information
which was crucial for the company and I
thought that that information was going
to be both specific but in one of the
documents the only thing Buffy was
sending out web has were new top
managers of the company to have an IP
access outside the company you may go
and say well not a big difference in
change of terms of the file but there
was a change in the hash okay so as I
said we located or found the mail the IP
address and then
the employer confessed that he had
expedited information and that was it a
more recent case we were contacted by a
client and they told me that the
daughter has disappeared from home they
didn't know where she is my first piece
of advice the one any detective
litigated was file a claim go to the
police see please do a very good job the
uniformity the wonderful team the
Spanish Civil Guard has a wonderful team
to tell any crime related to technology
they dealt with it immediately but in
this type of disappearance minors you
have to act very quickly there's a high
risk involved anything you do the more
people are that I involved the better so
it took the case and in collaboration
with police but it's something else they
gathered information from devices mobile
devices phone etc but they gave it back
give them back to the clients and what
did we do on our side we took those
devices it was a tablet the girl had at
home the mobile phone that she had left
which is amazing surprising for a minor
it is surprising him it's a little on a
minor and I computer they had at home in
the living room for everyone the family
service occurred as good technology
detectives what did we do we analyzed
those systems and we found two
interesting things first of all mobile
phones include routes locations where
this girl where that this girl was
usually visiting and over the past two
weeks the places were completely new and
we also found a discussion on her
Instagram at home some talk with other
minor a boy our hypothesis was that this
girl had eloped with this boy so
together with the police we worked and
this hypothesis of course the police
does not have enough resources to
investigate to put two place people in
every place that this girl was had been
or to follow this miner they have the
minimum resources there for any help we
can provide as a matter of fact private
detectives
we are collaborators of law enforcement
we have those resources and we use them
so we consider the possibility of an
elopement and we found the girl where
are her boyfriends parents place they
had told those people that she had
her life was a hell as cher was living
in the street and they had taken her in
after as if she was living on the
streets so this case was solved in
private investigation and in an online
investigation I said I can assure you
that if it wasn't for the capabilities
of external professionals many detective
offices would not be able to do this we
need to provide cyber security services
to Detective private executive offices a
fourth case intrusion I was taking the
picture to remember what I was talking
about a company the pharma company tells
us that there's been an intrusion in the
system they don't know what's for that
they may have been information leaked
they weren't very clear on that
they told us but they didn't want to
file a claim because they thought it
could be someone from within the company
what did we do an external collaborator
of ours a system an administrator so
with the link to us but he was an
external person he infiltrated the
company as an employee infiltrated sound
that well he was actually hired and he
starts to work there
we wanted him to have office hours
during the night to be by himself so
that he can gather information analyze
information and move around the first
thing is said and I remember this wasn't
a weekday and to some day the first
thing it said is it that it wasn't just
an intrusion the person our people
behind that intrusion so far we didn't
know who they were they've managed to
have persistence of the system this was
a very good pen tester has given lecture
here at this year's Cyber Command we
were surprised to see that there was
persistence and we decided to leave that
persistence there and investigate
investigate when the accesses plays
through she to know what was going on
and with person the terminal and how he
did it
we know who he was we didn't need high
involvement no investigation of the
streets but the company told us that
based on the profile of this person they
thought he was not alone there was
something weird so we so we subject the
employee to civilians and we saw that
four months had the ADF creating a
company for with products to be sir was
extra to be able to continue extracting
who is going to have a very important
advantage competitive advantage against
other companies in the sector we drafted
a report we had expertise is carried out
by others the chain of custody was
perfect to establish what this person
had done and this combined with the
investigation report the involvement of
his partners this report was taken to
the police because there's been a crime
disclosure of complication formation etc
this is how we did it other cases we
obtain evidence in cases of crimes that
can be persecuted at the request of the
claimant who do not investigate
ex-officio crimes that can be prosecuted
ex officio for example late harassment
at work sexual harassment discovery and
disclosure of secrets you need evidence
for all of this you need to keep the
chain of custody you see these and
lectures giving by professionals for all
of these we need professionals and very
often the things they come to us to our
offices and we need the technological
component crimes against honor
as usually slandered for example
imprudence company crime intellectual
and industrial rights
why because we do print investigation if
you find shoes on the floor to be sold
and they're similar to other shoes from
a specific brand this has to do all of
this has to do with cybersecurity
characteristics that the cyber security
professional needs to have in order to
work for a private detective office this
may sound very basic but I need to go
through them analytic and logical
thinking attention concentration and
memory of course an exercise if I've
entered this room I need to remember
that was never sit in there because
we're detail communicating skills body
language influence persuasion empathy
the work carried out by this
professional that was infiltrated in the
company it was very positive
due to his empathy he immediately
connected with other people and that
considering the family Hugh had had to
work in off in working hours where there
was almost no one around managing stress
and time very often we work under
pressure not just ourselves but those
people working with us
observation skills curiosity it's like
any IT person you need to be up-to-date
you need to check for a telegram
channels been meticulous and synthesis
skills we have a lot of information and
we summarize discretion that's basic
ethics very important to patients
persevere the ability to persevere if
you're patient you'll be rewarded that's
something I repeat all the time
sometimes we spent 20 hours looking at a
door and perhaps the person comes out at
our 19 well it's easier if you say well
you know one has gone out I leave if
you're patient you'll be rewarded
constant training and being interested
for new information this things changed
the past I could look for a phone in
Facebook now I cannot have today's
something else
using tricks we need to evolve and for
that you need training and being
interested
what can a cyber state a profession
expect from his or her job at private
detective office bad things timetable
Monday to Sunday this is like a
consulting company the problem here for
example the miner she disappeared on
Sunday they need something Sunday
afternoon you have to be there and
professional is working for us they
would need to analyze a devices and
Sunday afternoon 20.7 availability the
same idea I think it summarized here
because is it it's easy to see we don't
know when we will need the expertise
from this external professional it's
complicated making plans is complicated
I'm a plan my holidays on December next
week but you don't know if there will be
something coming up on Monday well
that's the life of detectives and people
working for detectives maximum demand a
mistake costs time and there are times
it's sometimes paramount for us time is
against us and we usually have one
opportunity very often
detectives only have one opportunity a
single opportunity to take a picture or
to record a video perhaps that person is
not going to come back through that door
so you have no other opportunities that
involves tension but it's interesting to
naturally international travels we move
a lot I've put in an under cons in pros
and cons - cons it could be a pro so
depends on the person some people like
moving around all this don't like today
I came from throg whathe here I'm
delighted to be here to give this talk
but I'm coming from photography pros
I'll be working what you like I think
it's a really cool profession and
working in cybersecurity analyzing
systems and pen testing something I
really like working for a private agency
well at school I know I'm not going to
be a detective
I can't I'm not licensed but I'm inside
I have a diploma have a degree without
three years three years I can study it
online I'll do my intership in the last
year but I could do it with an agency in
my city it's cool the next professional
private detective
for the required to have the two aspects
detective and professional there's no
routine one day it's always different
from other even though it's the same
investigation people do different things
over time they use some bicycle one day
and the motorcycle the next day one day
this happened last week it was raining
the person had a car and a motorcycle I
thought he wasn't going to take the
motorcycle but he did people do weird
things or it's funny seeing what they do
situations that entail constant
challenges that's great everything's new
everything's different you have to be
ahead of the bad guys our guys are not
really bad we're not the police but it's
cool it's passionated
national international travellers that
was under cons but for some people that
may be a pro is it it's a good thing
going out saying we have to take the
train we're going to this place
men men investigations ID are outside
Siddhartha because there's a
technological component because that's
what I do of the past three months I've
attended a training course at a company
called Zachary Sami receiving training
because we need to train personal
satisfaction the success in an
investigation you cannot imagine
people's faces or how thankful they are
you cannot compare it with anything it's
not like your bosses
oh the this audit was very well but it's
different it pretty
touches your heart and it's cool you say
I work for an objective agency well it's
cool it's cool I don't need to say
anything how can I contact Detective
Agency in order to offer my services as
a cyber security professional why do I
include this in my talk because in our
profession they're sort of professional
intrusion just need to take your phones
access any service platform once you
know and look detective private
detective out in our association the one
I'm deputy person now we investigate we
have specific Commission on professional
attrition and you see people that put an
address private detective plumber'
any other thing because people think
that anyone can be a protector the first
thing we do is calling them good morning
I would like to hire your services are
you detective yes do you have a license
do you know that this is a regulated
profession oh I didn't know
I cannot say I'm a lawyer if I'm not I
would never think of it but that's how
things have that's why I included this
in this talk where can I go I recommend
these two associations these two ways
private detective associations I
recommend you contact my station if the
majority groups together the majority of
offices and professionals from many many
provinces you just have to contact
Association them secretary and you offer
your services as pentester ethical
hacker the working systems foreign
signalizes whatever you do you send it
and we redirect us to with circulators
to our members so the many opportunities
to work because I insist we need
professionals from your sector in our
agencies another way detect private
detective professional association there
are three right now in Spain in
Catalonia in Valencia in Galicia
[Music]
they're going to create the association
in Madrid but it's going to take a while
so my recommendation would be first of
all contacted cotton ducting association
a PDP for example and each of the
professional associations since there's
a need
you'll receive immediate and and this is
the case because we have a lot of people
that don't have their own agencies
they're just detective working for
agencies they send their series so if an
agency requires means the detective the
area and the other province they access
the database they contact this person
they reach an agreement and that's it in
my opinion if you work if you can work
exclusively for one that so ok there's
some private detective agency that I've
created external company has devoted to
cybersecurity
exclusively cybersecurity but I think
that the rights approach which I'm sure
it will be drawn the future is that
private detective agencies will have
in-house stuff not for not to be private
detectives because they're not licensed
for that but it's collaborated it's
legal they're considering it and there
shouldn't be any problem instead of
using external collaborators sometimes
like rubber 8 it cannot work in a
different province or it's not that
person is not available for specific
topic having your own employee allows
you to
monitor his or her trainee you can train
that person as an agency you can send
that person to receive a specific
training course things that will give
the agency very good protection and for
the employee but this means an
opportunity work in a cool place cooler
at least than what you usually see in
the IT in cyber security work well now
let's open our Q&A to see what anyone
has any question doubt specific interest
of it delighted to answer your questions
hello what do you need to get your
license as a private detective I've said
it before but maybe you didn't see it
right now there are two ways to assess a
profession one
the University caused three years 180
credits and another university course
alls I'm not going to go through
everything in order to access the to
become a professional a professional
detective you need to go to university
for this curses you need to finish high
school I I'm not sure about the current
requirement but at least you need to
access University to be an IT expert
witness I understand the Ministry of
just didn't it license you as an expert
witness in the case of
detectives you have to the same thing
just something else in order to be an IT
expert witness you don't need license
you just need to preview knowledge on
the on that area in our industry
professor situation in which many people
say their IT expert and they've just
follow the three months cars in a little
school they're usually computing
engineers arty engineers they have
university degree and this knowledge
will be required by the judge in order
to submit a report to the court and
about the detectives there's a
difference between obtaining finishing
your degree but the license is giving
them by police force the Ministry of
Home Affairs with that degree you go to
the Ministry of Home Affairs you need to
fulfill a series of requirements that
have already been mentioned being in you
citizen no criminal record and with that
the degree you get your license then you
can be a private detective or a private
detective agency because there's a
difference between an agency that can
hire third parties or a private
detective the profit detective works for
private detective agencies it's a bit
complicated to explain aim at a private
detective as such cannot provide
services to citizens it can only offer
he or she cannot only offer his services
through an agency the agency has to
fulfill a series of
requirements and responsibilities
the chain is custody what does it start
for a notary you've said that you
protected a system entity of the work so
with the weekend or how does it begin
the chain of custody in this specific
case we obtained chain of custody since
we arrived that it was extracted and it
was analyzed we left staff there that
worked on the extracted material the
intrusion had already taken place I know
what do you mean we didn't manipulate it
because it's broken it's a very good
question
we collect when we arrived would put
that person there because we need that
person to be there and work that's one
this person sees that there was
persistent but intrusion was recorded
that's what we deliver any other
question
when I'm asked why care costs are
question castle ha in any case if you
have any other question I'll be around
visiting the exhibition and I'll be
delighted to answer your questions thank
you very much
[Applause]
[Music]