[Music]
hello good evening everyone so this
presentation is about Python darknets
and I'm going to share with you research
that I did I will show you proof of
concepts that I developed for other
systems and what I did in terms of
retrieving information automatically
about hidden services in torque I
introduce myself my name is Daniel also
known as ad astra I am a trainer and
consultant and every center of IT
security I've been managing and running
the block the hacker wider come for a
few years now
and I would like to I always say DS
because this is part of my lifestyle the
way I see Life I do IT security because
I love IT security is very much inside
me and I hope that those of you who are
here or those of you who are starting
also take into account that philosophy
or at least this is my hope I would like
you all to be very much willing to learn
and to see IT security beyond job that
will help you make a living and well
this is my email address you can contact
me for anything that you may need I will
answer will answer not immediately but
as soon as I can
will answer because I also have life
outside my job even though you may think
that this is not my case all right so my
presentation will be about Python how
many of you are aware of Python or
working Python
well nearly everyone in here okay on
this front bro
so lots of young people here I guess
you come from a university your students
and I guess does you study in Ruby
Python that you're so working with Java
do you also do scripting Java using it
okay
no from
I will also tell you how you can
disclose hidden services in the deep way
that may have malicious content that is
to say illegal content and how we can
extract information from these spaces
well we should not forget that there is
a wide range of information available in
tor or rip web and this information is
not a static but rather dynamic often we
have hidden services today services that
are exposing any type of content content
which goes against the law illicit
concept that it's available today and
tomorrow stops being available and not
because it has been censored but just
because of the content creator has
decided to shut down that content or
perhaps that content is only available a
specific times during the day or for
specific periods of time and then it is
removed from the Deep Web and what is
this about
first of all we will talk about
anonymous webs that are available in the
market then what are the anonymity
solutions that are available show me the
ones that you have heard after and
others well there are very many others
and free net descend riffle or tour
however these are the ones that are most
frequently used for all types of
activities not only for criminal
activities but also for other activities
for which these solutions have been
created initially as I say often tor is
associated with child pornography
selling of arms and forging of documents
passwords so this is what we most often
hear about this door and others but
these solutions store free medicines are
having thought or a thought so that some
of the content in it is not censored is
not forbidden especially in this country
where there is strong restrictions to
access the Internet
with this I'm referring to countries
such as China where there are
limitations in terms of accessing some
services expressing some opinions so in
these cases we have solutions such as
doors to allowing you to go out there to
go outside and to access that content
that otherwise you would not have access
in this type of environment so so this
is the type of solutions these solutions
have been created for that we should not
overlook we should not forget that or
Freenet dissent and others have been
created to preserve privacy and
anonymity of people they were not
originally
as a platform to commit criminal
activities despite the also being used
for criminal activities so we have
others such as riffle and so when rifle
is not fully implemented but it is there
and nowadays - Darnell includes more
illegal services than the other
solutions so as I said before tor is the
most widespread the most popular
solution and therefore the most used
[Music]
publicizing and publishing some illegal
content
well we also find one malicious content
in these solutions about tor and all
these web so this dark net has been
widely discussed I'm not going to tell
you what tour is about because I'm sure
you are all over of it and those of you
who are not aware of it I recommend you
listen to from a mono presentation there
are sitting here in this room they also
gave that present a presentation one or
two years ago at cyber camp and actually
they it's a presentation that you can
watch the infidel website as I say they
delivered in that position two years ago
and I recommend you watch it because
they explained very well all the Burnet
as well as others so this is a good way
this is a good introduction for those of
you who want to find out more about tor
other than tor well I'm going to talk
about Python so I hope that you have
some basic knowledge about Python
because I will be mentioning some tools
and libraries that are included in this
language as I say I expect you to have
some basic
information and knowledge about it and I
will try this presentation to reach
everyone in all the targets here in this
room
I was a center
what is that well the first thing that
we have to do is to find addresses to be
aware of the available services and the
question is how did you do that on the
Internet
if you want to find content what do you
do well you make a set even in Google or
you name it cheap flights here there do
Google that so do you use search engines
and those of you who are new to the know
start page
well take a look at it it is quite good
it is a search engine that redirect all
your searches to Google
therefore you no longer have to give all
your data to big Google then you go
through a start page which is kind of
like a proxy so the advantage is that
you will get the same results that you
will get in Google but this is a
different search engine yet exactly the
same results and you are not exposing
your privacy so
in solution such as doors we find
exactly the same thing lots of search
engines
lots of indexing pages with onion
addresses that help us to find addresses
to find content that may have a lineal
content illegal content in them we may
use fresh onion for that and do such as
Isis - forged passports so key items
that you could type in in any search
engine and then you will get onion
addresses as result sufferance s if you
want to hire a hacker or any illegal
content you can think of you can easily
search it through these type of
solutions and through the available set
sentence ok this is already starting
point will have a number of search
engines that we can use to automate our
searches and then we will get a number
of onion addresses that are indexed in
these societies
also as I said before a deep we're after
is dynamic you will not find the same
services all the time and as I said
before while you may see find a service
today and that service for whatever
reason may not be available tomorrow
because anyone can publish content in
TOR actually it is very very simple you
only need to add two lines to the config
file and that's it that is enough for
you to are okay
publish the service in the Deep Web
after with its associated onion address
so if you stop your tour instance that
will be enough for the service not to be
available anymore
references to take down the service but
it is Apache ordination or any other
service behind it okay as simple as that
so were to start so very many sites to
use darklings offers very many onion
addresses to find this type of services
with illegal contents also two links
deep link some of these are search
engines that we can use right away in
turn so this is fresh onions
amia is quite good by cool sacred search
engine
it's often quite updated
but fresh onions or amia is that
sentence like any other to type in your
side's Linux
so non-malicious
[Music]
and when we browse this type of a spaces
we'll have to get used to lower speed so
this is everything that we get as a
result these are onion addresses that
match our search
[Music]
so what we got as a result everything
that matches Linux but we could have
entered other search term for instance I
don't know passport or - or Isis are you
getting me
and now we will be having a number of
earning addresses so analyzed later on
we're doing that manually it doesn't
really make sense because we may get
hundreds of results sometimes thousands
of results so it doesn't really make
sense to do that manually you just don't
want to go one by one to check whether
they are available or not whether they
have the contents that you are looking
for do as I say you can automate that
through scripted as I will be showing
you this is a very practical
presentation I have some videos here
just in case I need them but because
these two connection is running very
well I will do everything life
so we have well we can use very many
search engines so what do we need to
interact with these sites in a
programmatic matter well we only need to
know the HTML structure of the websites
how do I do my search well they okay let
me show you such receive z-cube
parameter
well from Python script what do I have
to do I have to type in the on an
address
- and search and then the Q parameter
which is the search button whatever kids
whatever search them that I introduced I
could do that within program as a matter
with python script and it will only take
like three lines okay two lines plus the
proxy liner you can do any type of
search fresh onions
well fresh onions also shows you life
addresses so it doesn't show the
addresses that are not pointing at
anything or having taken down so it only
shows you active life addresses it shows
you when it has been published when it
was last visited and the last time when
it was published and then it gives you
the address as well as the entire
already name of the site and well you
can do any search or - or Isis Isis you
name it
cyberwar
[Music]
okay britain german in russian several
onion domains some of them are
supplicated but in anyway they match the
search term Isis shows content
containing Isis and then you see onion
addresses
this was published four weeks ago and
seen a day ago so very easy to search
for disciple free to make this type of
searches but then you can also get lots
of crap
okay what to do now
when you do this type of searches and
you come up to the services these
services are data sources think about
them as databases so lots of information
you can consult what type of language
are we using we are not using SQL but we
are using HTTP requests so here we are
talking about HTTP hidden services web
service but in the Deep Web of tools you
can get any type of service as long as
they support HTTP protocol we will be
focusing on HTTP which is the most
common web services therefore we want to
consult these databases and then to
check that the addresses that these
databases Britain published for instance
if I typing Isis for this specific
search then I get a number of onion
addresses then I have to check that
those onion addresses I have returning
anything to me that is to say that they
are life so if I check these addresses
or consultants addresses and then then
it tells me that it is down it is of no
use at all so I'm interested in those
services which are life and well those
that are down what could I use them for
well just for me to know that at a given
point in time the address was life and
that it is not life anymore so how do we
resolve the issue of solving the
plumbing in the pythonic way have you
ever heard about pythonic libraries or
pythonic toad
only three of you four or five okay so
we talked about solving a problem in the
pythonic way we mean that python has
been designed so that things are solved
easily only through a few lines of code
in the most straightforward manner
possible so when I develop something
when I create something I'd like to
focus on the problem but not on the
problems that I make it from the actual
language for instance if you're working
on Java a very cool language so you may
come up with very many problems problems
within libraries it is a quite complex
language however you don't find so many
problems in Python in Python we focus
more on the problem on solving the
problem and that is the objective that
is to say solving things in a
straightforward manner so going right
away to the problem and this is what
Python allows us to do how to solve the
problem like this so we consult
databases number of directories number
of search engines key terms any content
we may be interested in and then we make
our consultations through HTTP requests
second applying patterns to our queries
so search patterns for instance if we
look for child porn or Isis so fast
passports anything we may be interested
in then we filter those addresses so we
are only interested in those who
currently live that are responding to
our requests
so we are not interested in those
addresses that take us nowhere and you
just don't want to open it and to say
well not found so we filtered those out
then because queries against each of the
active addresses and analysis of the
response we will analyze the addresses
that we will find in a programmatic
manner and then we will analyze the
response and then what we mean by
propose getting the HTTP code that the
server returns to us and to analyze it
simple well very very simple we just get
the return the text of the response
which is just the ordinary HTTP code we
analyze it and furnaces we check the
labels and links pointing at other onion
addresses oh using Bitcoin addresses
user names email addresses telephone
numbers for since for Spain or with
Spanish country code or for instance
landline numbers or mobile telephone
numbers all that could be done in very
easy way then
story
the websites that we found as well as
any information information that you get
you may store it in the file in the
database that information can be stored
to analyze it later and offline we are
not going to be log onto the net where
okay all the time we can also do
spidering for each of the services found
do you know what a spidering is well
more people have pressed their hands
down
good
so when we find that pays side so we
want to do strapping we just want to see
all the links that it's pointing us to
discover more on you addresses related
to that service that will be the most
interesting thing to do
that is to say to get more other
addresses from that this is a simple
algorithm and then applying patterns -
expressions to detect illegal content
any Content that we are consulting any
HTTP address that we analyze we apply a
regular expression to it to extract
email addresses from that onion address
or as I said before well Bitcoin
addresses whatever you can think of
credit cards these are just patterns of
regular expressions that you find in
through Stack Overflow or through any
other case you can think of on the
internet and last we isolate the
services - match these patterns so we
have onion addresses which is
interesting cup content and feeding with
specific patterns so credit cards or any
type of numbers landlines mobile numbers
this is what we are looking for and now
each of these steps how do we do it well
we do that through in Python
taking database we need toward to be up
with the process in order to use it then
we require requests requests socks or
socks by the sir libraries in Python
it's requests humidity it doesn't even
work with - requests 99% of you is a
library in order to create HTTP clients
with a import request request dot
whatever the method you want to use and
the address you want to point after
release 2.10 of request we can implement
different things then our Python script
imports request to specify the proxy
songs that it's up in the local machine
and then we launch the script with
request and we say request that get add
red onion address proxies in the list of
proxies which would be one towards us
proxy and with this we can check the
data sources our search engines
themselves yes doing HTTP requests
through a library it's very simple it's
three lines then it gets more
complicated applying several patents to
queries
we have it certain genes some of them
received patterns the world won't search
for their URL others are a webform they
have a box and the request has to be
made afterwards
it's supposed to request with a specific
parameter depending on the structure of
its search engine we need to create the
routine decode routine that would be
second step and third filtering
addresses were interested in we use
requests we have an on your address in
the results we carry out HTTP requests
it's like clicking on the link and very
fine whether it's up or not Ricardo's s
doesn't ask admission fee ok this is a
very simple script for the first checks
we use requests we import the proxy Sox
specification for instance has to be up
in this case in my machine so I did it
in no time
well on Taurasi Alberto noventa thing
cuenta is therapy pools 9050 will be
open and proxy soaks all the requests
through this port will be routed through
tor they will go directly to tor
what do we have here we have a series of
proxies wonderful it's a dictionary in
Python and what do we do next the
simplest thing over them all we create a
function called search under dear
there's another search engine that would
check under there it's a different
search engine such as the ones I've
explained before but it's specific it's
malicious because it offers a lot of
services which are illegal per se
business
markets scroll communications core sites
hosting other languages that's a bit of
everything but it's certainly does not
filter addresses you could have
everything here so it's a good source
data for our goal what do we do with the
script we'd send the onion address and
when we carry out a search for example
passports in under there the HTTP
request is made and take a look at the
structure in this case search it would
passport there's one on this structure
this is the other one
when do do this without pagination it
would do the term which is included in
the search filter you want pages we were
not we don't want to keep just a result
in the first page 20 pages 30 pages
depending on how patient we are because
it's going to take time what do we do
now is a reserved word here that will
that we will replace later and would
create a cycle for
we created a loop for there were
repeated four four pages using these
criteria to search to rubbish
we're going to look for rubbish we I
trade each one of these criteria we
replace criteria wildcard this text
string with any of these criteria when
concatenated with a dress desert with
Korea requires this is very simple this
would be addressed to search this would
be equivalent to this
and lastly important we need to specify
we're going to go this HTTP request
it's very simple we're using Python it's
a simple proof of concept Python 3 park1
this is going to take a while
I'm but we can see here I'm taking this
and the only thing the script is doing
this first proof of concept is designing
the address I'm looking for and the code
of response page 1 page 1 and child-porn
CP drugs we're going through the loop
and when it says response 200 it means
the request has been made then the
answer is 200 HTTP 200 saying it's ok to
study status codes Nate DT be simple
what we've done with the problem is 30
those criteria and going through 4 pages
with a script in Python which removing
comments and things which I'll use less
it's just 20 lines but taking something
that would be 15 so that's a basic
search engine next proof of concept less
let's get deeper into the problem first
we keep what we had before and here
we'll start with her crawling process it
gets a bit complicated but not too much
so we continue with the same thing we're
using the same search and in which is
under there
and we say let's search for this
criteria violence - Isis we have to say
that this was designed for activities
developed by law enforcement
you don't usually do this I think but
you know it's not too complicated
what we see here we are requesting this
to this onion address we replace
criteria wildcard by whatever thing you
want to look for and then after the
before during a request we invoke this
function we create a queue and that Q
it's a an LIF o Q it's a toughness stuck
like a stack what the K said what's the
same way the trusses are getting in the
last ins the first out simple
it's a recursive process it's not yet
but it will be we have a process in
which we go through all the elements of
the keel not W this red edge from this
iterations
it's an HTTP request for each onion
address uncovered and what do we do with
this address we try to extract the links
we search with under day or any other
search engine you want we see search for
Isis it's going to show a series of
onion addresses which include Isis as a
criteria then we take in each one of
them using our program we carry out our
HTTP request against each one of these
links for each of the pages with said
and these gets four pages we obtain
responses what interest what what is it
of interest for us in these pages are
the links to other pages so spider and
processor crawling processes we invoke a
function called get links which has
nothing and open an empty list the next
proof of concept we use more things
in this particular case number two we do
the same thing we did before with crawl
we carry out the crawling process and
then with gatlings we use a wonderful
library code beautifulsoup
is it familiar to you but those who you
who put it behind you know that with
beautifulsoup
we can analyze the structure of website
whether it's a team xml or any other
here we have beautiful soup which does
wonderful thing going with a couple of
lines we can tell it to extract every
link in an HTML code and store it in a
list it's wonderful because we have HTML
code that we've previously checked and
that most likely will include malicious
content or legal content and out of this
page we're going to extract all the
links with the tags with the attribute 8
r EF links in this HTML structure what I
were interested what are we interested
in here the onion address create
database series of onion and trusses
which are directly or indirectly linked
to search patterns that we have included
we check that it is a valid address with
this function is it a valid address and
here we use the validators package that
python has is and I say please validated
it this add read is not taught to web or
dot onion because we want everything
before the point onion they taught onion
to check that it's valid address the
minimum length of 16 or 16 or 56 onion
addresses have this length
normal addresses used to have 16 new
generation which was launched last year
it can have up to 56 we want to validate
it to check that it's a valid address
not just any silly text that may be
included in HTML and we extract
plaintext onion so on in addressed we
return that the onion address and here
below we say we're only interested in
single addresses with greater said it's
a collection in faithlyn
that says that every element including
it does not admit it duplicate it's a
list in Python legalist every element
agree they are unique you can't have
duplicated addresses they're not going
to be duplicated this is what we return
we're going to have a lot of links
now and we will go through them here
here we get the links we go through them
that dynamically included in the queue
we're going to do the links we fight
we're going to create a queue with a lot
of addresses and later on we'll we'll
process them so let's execute this
process
mr. Botha dharamendra
this can take a while well this is just
a proof of concept as I said at the
beginning this type of tools this
breadth of concepts are just extraction
from other project in which I've worked
to some of my clients they're not
usually executed in this way they're
useless acute in servers with a more
solid server infrastructure it's not
enough by just launching the script you
need to put this into celery which is a
programmed task to be launched once in a
while and it will take the time it needs
it's a process that can take quite a lot
of time this is the process it's looking
for child porn page one and it's
starting to extract all these onion
addresses for someone here this one is
interesting when it shows this type of
failure it shows that the service was up
at some point but it's not up anymore
but the typical case in which the
service at some point was available that
onion interest was registered in under
day but it's not anymore
host in ritual the crawling process
continues and till we stop it we have
something to work with a lot of onion
addresses that will allow us to extract
information that may have illegal things
in them I launched it again
I prefer some other thing yes that amino
for normal so I don't like this term
either like this one but it is less
violent I guess let's see what I can
find with this first one it says nope
it's looking for more
you always have to check that it's up
here it has found this address let's
check nobilis podemos explorer Armando
we can't explode them manually later on
con mucha path NCO club okay so Thursday
was a tiempo it takes time so I'm going
to change this it has to connect okay
let's see some other
this is timed out
it hasn't answered it hasn't responded
in 15 seconds so that's timeout perhaps
the network is the connection is a bit
slow this one green draughts
let's see this one copy
let's see
one otra Asuna las direcciones commotion
contrada con esta pro se Minter's and
this is one of the addresses we've found
with the simple procedure and it shows
prices in case you want to deal
so with obtained part of the results
this was the first part of a job we have
a series of addresses with this topics
we need to analyze the addresses in
order to extract the information and
right now we have the fourth part what
do we do
before we stopped here just crawling
process and including every onion
dresnok cube now we're going to take a
step further and we're going to process
each URL it's linked how we just
received the link and we apply regular
expressions in this case we just have a
pattern a regular expression in order to
say what's incurred in this text it's an
email or a Bitcoin address and the same
we send an HTTP request against that
address matches with regular expression
given the content we're giving this
contains 8 t ml code of the website
we've just found
if they're sukhoi incidents we print it
on our screen much much and there are no
matches no matches this is the
interesting part of it once everything
is done we save to our database or
whatever you want they will it's usually
database persistent story now it's
looking for Isis page one the same
crawling process it's found an address
which is this one and I say ok let's see
what it is
actually I can only forget the NS so now
we should analyze the content of this
internally but it has found an Isis
button in this page so this should be
something here there's a threat so there
should be something related to it
this was timed out it analyzes
connections and if it finds matches it
says Matt or Nomad it finds patterns for
email address or Bitcoin addresses in
this specific case but we could use
regular expressions for credit cards you
have to be creative here
anything you want to extract
you have to bear in mind this is just a
proof of concept
these are extraction extracts from tools
I've created for clients what platform
do usually create so that this is
powerful use flask Django based on
services and micro services with the
server which is powerful enough so that
this type of process is execute in a
continuous way in order to get a lot of
information you need a table with lots
of onion addresses which will be the
entry points the search engines for
which we're going to carry out our
searches this is what we find in Python
before continuing
well the idea of this talk is it well
I've seen a lot of young people many of
your students perhaps and I would like
to show you how powerful Python is as a
language and all the things you can do
with this type of programming languages
the message is for you to create your
own things it's not just launch tools
that have already been created open your
mind be creative and create your own
tools it can be in this sense or
something else something that you're
passionate about it will be gratifying
and you're going to learn a lot this is
a piece of advice for those of you who
are still studying you're finishing your
studies in my opinion it's a very good
piece of advice and it will help you
from a professional point of view I will
suffice you to take part in projects to
create your things or add something to
projects which have which are already
available any questions
so either always crystal clear or you
haven't understood anything
perhaps it's the second one and details
in the presentation I'll answer as soon
as I can thank you
you