[Music]
okay then we wanna see asset dollars
good morning welcome back and after
preparing all the technical part of the
coming presentation we're ready to
welcome you to our new edition of cyber
camp 2018 you know that we are on
twitter at at in CB cyber camp 2018 and
also with our hashtag sorry 18 only not
2018 and let me introduce you now to our
census a co-founder of elephant hacking
he's here to tell us about a security in
a connected world I'm sure we will all
thoroughly enjoy this and I will welcome
him with a warm round of applause thank
you very much welcome good morning
everyone and apologies for the slight
technical hiccup let's start with a
little bit of imagination can you
imagine if we could get into our car
without even having a key can you
imagine if we could drive on the
motorway and we don't need to stop and
pay can you imagine if we could go home
and open the door without the need for a
key can you imagine if we could travel
and use public transport without having
to pay physically pay so let's stop
imagining now and let's see let's see
the demo of how this can all actually
work that's what we're going to be doing
this morning
although a word of warning we need to be
ever so careful because we're going to
be seeing different situations which are
demonstrations and is this reality well
later on you will tell me if it is just
a figment of my imagination of or if
it's reality as it is this is me growl
Sanchez you can see up on the screen and
how a co-founder of a start-up elephant
hacking we haven't been up and running
for a long time I love notes and ones
and hardware analysis reversing but
mostly I work with hardware we work at
very low level with assembler and a C
code well code writing on C then I also
we also help people with a higher level
activities but I mostly work with
hardware hacking this is the table of
contents that I would like to cover
during my workshop this morning let's
hope we have time to cover it all it's
not going to be very practical
activities will start with copying a car
key so we can use the car without the
need for a key we won't actually be
starting it physically but if you access
the internet you will see explanations
on how that would work we'll just be
using the key to open the door as it is
not to start the engine the second
activity will be going through the toll
booth without paying
for the barrier to lift and letters
through the toll booth area without
paying
then how to break into a house without
having to break in just opening the door
without the alarms going off because I
don't think alarms are that safe these
days which is why I've prepared this
presentation sometimes we're told alarm
systems are ever so safe while they're
not and you'll see how they're not the
next activity will have to do with
hotels how we could gain control to all
the technical devices and possibilities
at a hotel then we will see ISO seven
eight one six the cards how they work
and last but not least we'll see how an
NFC card for a public transport voucher
or card
it can be used a bus pass and don't
misunderstand me I'm telling you how
these cards these bus passes can be
copied a not for you to cheat but for
public transport operators to realize
that the system is not that safe well if
they want to listen to us who tell them
about this and finally we will have a
nice cup of coffee without having to pay
for it a getting coffee at a vending
machine because their their systems
again are not terribly safe so how did
this all start why do I want to do this
I want us to think this is like a
journey I left home a few days ago to
come to cyber camp
staying in Malaga for a number of days I
staying at a hotel and this is not
imaginary right it is all real for
instance when I tell you about the hotel
card it will be a real situation so I
left home I came by car here to Malaga I
didn't steal the car but I I needed a
key to open the car door so again is
that a safe system we'll see it's not
again to get here and I drove on the
motorway I had to pay for it but I will
show you how barriers can just let me
through
without having to pay and because I'm
very short of cash then I thought well
why not
get into a house instead of staying at a
hotel get in because nobody's in and
gaining access and without a very
well-known alarm brand
stopping me from doing it then at the
hotel there is something that's called a
must card or a master key that again
gives access to all their systems I will
see how security at a hotel is not as
foolproof as we might imagine and you
never know right if one of your guests
is going to be a clever hacker or some
other guest might come into my room do
whatever he or she feels like doing it
or things is fun to do again the bus
pass
it's a nice idea right having a little
tour around Malaga on the bus caching
different buses and using a bus pass
that is not real the machine lets you
through it clicks quite normally it's
quite amazing and then I just want to
tell you that at the company we
sometimes in audit companies and what I
tend to do is launching Nexus first and
because it takes a little while for it
all to work I go for a little walk
around the building around the premises
I go with my gadgets and I love anything
that has to do with industrial equipment
for instance lighting demotic lighting
control or heat heating and air
conditioning if that works through
domotics as well and also vending
machines I've always liked checking and
seeing how safe vending machines are or
how not safe sorry how secure their
system is I'm trying to get a cup of
coffee for free well I'll be telling you
how it can be done with the idea that
hopefully for instance the vending
machine manufacturers will listen to us
and improve their systems that's the
idea that's why I talk to companies and
give them advice although I must tell
you they rarely listen to the advice I
give them why not
I guess because there are not many
people who are sensitive to these issues
and all they think is not going to be
that harmful so this is the tour the
little journey I propose to you here
today for our workshop I hope you enjoy
the tour let's start with a car team
where's my car key I don't know what
I've done with it
well I've got the key believe me but I
can't see it now I've got a control a
remote control here as well so just as
well this is a very simple attack you
just get a quirky just see how simple it
is practically anybody can do it as long
as you have the correct equipment and
systems so how can you copy a car key we
first need to understand how the key
works all it does is with an internal
algorithm it sends a unique code to the
vehicle you press your opening button
and it sends this unique code to the car
and if it coincides with the individual
encoded algorithm if they coincide if
it's the same then the door will open
and if it doesn't it won't but controls
car controls are peculiar because every
time you press the button it generates a
code that's valid for that car that code
gets to the car and the door opens
that's the system force can we do in
this case we would be very very close to
the remote control quite close so we
then start to listen and sniff and when
somebody presses the button the door
will open
that's it sounds easy right well it is
but it's a little bit harder because the
code is valid the first time around
and then it's invalidated it changes
even if you send the same code again it
won't be valid the car won't accept it
it won't record
how can we copy the code you need to
have a device in the middle so that the
code when the opening button is pressed
it won't get to the car it will get to
us instead the car doesn't know that the
button has been pressed but now we've
got the code so the car owner presses
the button and they think oh that's
funny
it didn't open but it's a
man-in-the-middle attack the usual
simple man-in-the-middle attack all you
need to do is be close to the remote
control and get the code whoops the
screens not working the mic is working
right and another smaller screens
working is somebody hacking my
presentation or was I thought it was
going to be an interesting workshop I
don't know if the technical staff can
give me a hand with this the smaller
screens are not working either Wow
Elda me Selena
no no no bono come in Taba look I got
fed up on a sham with Erica we don't
cook so as I said a simple system you
stand close to the remote control you
get the valid code and the car doesn't
so the court doesn't know the code has
been sent the first time round it gets
it second time around so we then have to
wait for the car owner not to be nearby
must best isn't it and we would then
send the code to the car and the door
will open because the car will think
it's the proper key sending the code so
shall we see this for real I couldn't
get a car into the room unfortunately
first I've brought something that will
work in a similar way let me try and
find the battery I brought a doorbell
here's my doorbell for our clever
practical example a wireless doorbell
that you can buy at any old Poundland
shop
can you hear I press my remote control
and the doorbell sounds
so let me change to the through the
other screen now
if anybody here knows very much how
radio frequency spectrum works the RF
range
this is SDR it's a little bit more
powerful than the usual smaller versions
this is a TD T USB that has been
modified so that because T DT is UHF
mode it allows you to sniff a little bit
beyond the band the UHF UHF band in this
case I've brought one from two to six
megahertz from 2 to 6 2 from 2 megahertz
to 6 gigahertz originally I thought it
was 443 merc megahertz look at this I
pressed the control
I want the right band but nothing much
is happening why because I bought it at
a cheap shot like a Poundland and I
thought why is this not working I was a
little bit confused and funnily enough
these cheap bazaars tend to send cell
chinese-manufactured equipment which the
transmission in that case they use the
chinese frequency not the european one
which is three hundred and thirty let me
change that then see if that works
it needs to be at 330 330
there it is can you see it look at the
graph oh dear it's taking a little bit
longer than it should I hope the battery
it doesn't give up on me
right a 336 you see it's working when I
press the remote control he's not very
very stable I'm not going to say it
again well in fact this cheap shop where
I bought this remote control it was run
by a Chinese family and I have nothing
against China or the Chinese people but
they're not always very reliable why is
this working God knows I mean he might
just be sheer luck so we're lucky it's
working that's something so it's a 332
now what is quite fragile it's not very
stable mine is round about 332 then
we've got that now oh I forgot to
explain this little program to you how
it works what it does is sniffing a on
different a number of different pants
because the electromagnetic range has
different pants we can then change the
frequency thanks to this program the
modulation a number of different things
but in this particular example we don't
care about out about that we just need
to copy and reproduce this the signal
let's do that then
now the lead of the interpreter liberal
smoke I've got this utility from the
mohkum books project said transfer one
and it gives us all different options -
are allows to receive a data with - T we
it transmits or broadcast data then we
can add modulation and pain because
while pain will be important because the
battery is a bit low with - F for
frequency so - are for receiving that's
what we'll do to start off with I'm just
going to check
step is adding the frequency I forgot
what it was
446 was it 300 well thank you it was 336
sorry I've got a rubbish memory
all I want to show you is how it can
reproduce you can copy but this is not
the most interesting step not yet
333 was this point something
is that the one 333 point 3 5 because it
goes up and down it varies it's not very
stable let's hope it works first time
round
this is the command - or for receiving
data you see what it does the program
saves saves it on a route file if this
were music it would be like waa peace
saving notes and ones anything it gets
without a zipping is and then with we'll
have to do - tea but we're on - are now
we now add the frequency it's saving is
I now press the button I stop and if it
works
the Bell is here you see Bell 1 how much
that does that take it
it's got 90 makers yep
that's the size 90 makers in just three
seconds that's pretty good going so
without touching the control I'm now
going to try and broadcast the very same
signal we go to hack RF we look at the
parameters - D is for broadcasting so
that's the one we press - t we transfer
the file Bell and then we add the gain
on DB's what is that going to be 20 DBS
20 decibels and if the frequency was
correct when I press it will reproduce
they will play you will ring does it no
it doesn't why because their frequency
varies is not very stable but if I get
the exact right frequency let me just
try that again
here in right in the middle of the curve
so that I get the best average accurate
frequency three hundred and thirty six
point four five now you see is changed
because it was point three earlier on
again it's a very unstable frequency for
this particular doorbell so three
hundred and thirty six point four five
we said let me try that again
three three three right so I save the
bell and then I press play with 333.50
with a gain of 20 DBS there you go I
didn't even have to press the button I
didn't cheat and the control is here and
is ringing right that was a very simple
task yeah we're going to do that
something more complex next basically is
the same idea but in this case the
frequency is going to be for a car let's
hope it works this is a remote control
car a little toy car I'm gonna leave it
on the floor because otherwise it might
just my drop is I'm going to find the
frequency for the accelerator see the
composition of the frequency so that we
can then generate it from scratch
without reproducing it as we did earlier
but rather through modulation of the
signal coming out of the control
modulated a with the frequency
transmitter that's what we'll try and do
next
I don't know if you're familiar with the
Osmo comb project it's called pen source
jinwu jinwu radio G and you radio sorry
yeah tenemos right we're going I'm going
to do this so you can see it up on the
screen visually generating the signal
checking the modulation so that we can
then generate it again with all
necessary functions everything we need
air for the signal to be generated from
scratch as I said I'm going to turn the
car off first because otherwise it's
just going to go mad so what should we
do first
are you familiar with radio frequency
with all the details it's not that
complex it is a little bit at the
beginning until you understand
everything that has to do with
modulation you understand how signals
are made up through different very basic
functions some of them some of them
terribly complex all of that is done on
Python by the way so you could even
prepare your own modules there are
plugins so if you want to work with your
own module you can prepare it yourself
but it's not really required most
modulations you can guess as a plugin
unless you come across a particular
situation which doesn't comply with the
normal standards or where you want to
have it imagine your own unique
mission of broadcast that nobody would
be able to sniff in that situation then
you might want to make your own which is
not simple but it can be done for
instance in the military
there are modulations that are no more
for them but complete unknowns for
anybody else you could even crack those
with something like this and all is done
here on this so we get the remote
control we check the frequency for that
transmission the aerial is getting the
signal from the remote control we press
forward is not 336 or 400 megahertz
because 333 I forgot to mention that it
it's the American Standard which is the
one that they use in China as well not
in Europe so this would be a legal bail
for the US and China but not for Europe
but in this case there's another free
frequency 27 megahertz there's quite a
bit of noise there so 27 there it is so
we're already receiving something what
is it is noise so it's not going to be
very clean I don't know if it's going to
work very well I don't know if there
will be some something transmitting on
this frequency because you don't need a
license to broadcast or transmit on
these licenses is open and free look at
that huge peak there at 27 4.3 on that
band
27-point what not 3-5 look at it see
those frequencies there see how we have
that horizontal line not would equate to
zero that would be our zero and what
else we've got those tiny waves
oscillating stopping going up and down
those wavelets that's an AM type
modulation there's I know I do
wave stretches and then goes narrower
again
why because we first have zero without
any oscillation then one would mean a
tiny pulse of two tiny synovial wavelets
and then depending on the width of the
pulse and that would mean is 0 or 1 it
depends on the width I insist of the
pulse if it's a very small pulse and
that would equate to 1 oops sorry the
speaker corrects himself if it's tiny is
would be a zero if it's wider it would
equate to 1
so how can we generate those larger and
smaller forces so we said 27 not 35
don't let me forget that I'm just gonna
write it down or type it here because
otherwise I'll forget so we will now be
generating larger or smaller pulses for
notes or ones depending on the remote
control for instance it might be 1 1 0
you'll see what I mean in a minute on
the left not not one for instance on the
right whatever it says and what does
that do
well sending four different commands
through an analog means which is radio
frequency
so let's first check what poses this
remote control actually broadcasts or
transmits we need first need to find the
block osmocon source what does that
block to connect up to my radio
frequency reader
the driver is ready so that through the
USB port communication is possible then
with the radio frequency transmitter
tx/rx
what does that mean that smaller ones
that would cost you 10 euros I can't
transmit they would only receive in this
case a a can both transmit or broadcast
and receive but if we have an SDR USB
the typical one for TDT devices we could
do the first part of this exercise but
we wouldn't be able to transmit the code
sending the command to the car so that
the car would start as if by magic we
wouldn't be able to do that second part
so what do we do first we first need to
enter the number of poses divided what
poses per million that I get from that
signal an analog signal which is endless
as actually as many spots or points as
the accuracy of our device in order to
measure those pulses so an analog signal
would oxalate sorry a sine wave moves
from a zero and it gives up salayheen
all the way back to zero so zero one two
three four - well whenever we are tired
of measuring arrests how is our device
can measure and then back to zero and
that number of pulses that we have from
the first zero to the second zero that
number of pulses is what we can set here
we will say 20 million pulses per second
20 million times within a second I'll
measure that sine wave so from the first
zero to the second zero I'll measure the
wave 20 million times per second so I
will be suppling sampling at a rate of
20 million times per second that's what
I meant to say it's a sampling it seems
quite high but some are as high as a
hundred million or a very steep
resolution ours works great at twenty
million and is more than enough
especially for what we have here is more
than enough we don't need an higher
resolution all right so it's 2 times 2
to the 6th power I said 20 million
so we have a variable here we have this
central frequency that's our frequency
that's a variable
which we would name central frequency
that's the reference for our remote that
we will be recording or saving this is
270 356 98 I copy that so it's better
than learning it by heart so we better
copy-paste it so it's 27 megahertz so 27
million 1 2 3 1 2 3 so 27 million Oh 9 8
that's the central frequency that wood
will be reading not writing but reading
wood will be sent by these remote so
what we do next is try and find the
module here this is FFT tester and it
shows right away what is being read by
our reader RF reader it shows on the
screen a fizzes whereas Silla scope and
it shows as a graph that's been sampled
and that's what's important here and we
all need to understand that is 2 million
as I said before resolution is 2 million
pulses samples per second so in a minute
and we will see it moving fast but at
least we can see it we can even freeze
it to see how it is transmitted in and
we'll say that as well what we do here
with this module is a spectral analysis
so we look into the range or the
spectrum in the frequency we've stated
which is 27 megahertz to see our remote
alright as I said before we need a
reference frequency
which we've said is Center all right
so this is our base frequency our sample
frequency you already done it so that's
it so we take our input that is our F
and this is our spectral analyzer and
just like that
so if we press play always F did same as
before but now with our frequency which
is 27 megahertz so if I press it here oh
all right so you cannot see did it get
the right one yeah yeah so 2703 five six
nine eight all right guys like that
that's the frequency as it moves but
let's handle it now and let's change it
and we'll see a few more parameters
these was the Freak that central
frequency let's try and see how we can
add the pulse modulation
[Music]
using our own module here it is alright
this is our sampling frequency so what
we do is plug this into this or link
this T and we have some extra
information so we have both in parallel
so this is an output here and right here
we have the output underneath I know
whether it's the battery is our watch
but there's something right here
oops I guess it'll work now what that's
like that for the first half of it we
would get our reference frequency and
what we do next is save it on our word
drive with the new module that I'll add
which is this one here
so let's name it I don't know we mode
speed up
well this is not compatible because we
need to translate it into float all
right
okay so what we do here is when we turn
this signal that is a complex signal
into float as you probably know a
complex signal has a mixture of
frequencies that we rule out or discard
what's the imaginary side of it so we
only live the out but we forget about
everything else okay
manuela Corsa okay no bless him
our ice to see
when digital filter and they think
she'll ever posted oh yeah that's what
we had written right 27 35 27 old 35
well it does work
Oh again we forgot about that
maybe we were not getting the right gain
here
now it's not working as an emergency kit
I always get soaked when I recorded it
when I saved it
that was yesterday that I was checking
it out the frequency was twenty seven
three one four I don't know what the
difference might be let's try the one
that I saved yesterday and see if it
works
oh it does work twenty seven three one
four so let's use the one that I
recorded si because for whatever the
reason alright so here what we have is
well you can see it now Kenji
so here we have the wave coming in but
we'll see what kind of a wave it is
that's what we've seen before this is a
wave so what's here is interesting so
this is a wide pulse and other white
pals are smaller pals another one this
is small so if we think that the wide
pulse is a first one which is a sync by
the am modulation that we're seeing so
this is the white pass it is one two
three and this is the fourth one so we
have four as a synchronism and then a
smaller ones that are narrower ones one
two three four five six well not not all
of them but at least ten because I've
counted those before let's check it out
so we have one two three four white
pulses and we have ten the done narrow
so one two three four five six nine ten
and that meant for white pulses and ten
narrow commands that's the acceleration
one and let's use the break in command
so that you see it's different so I
press and stop so these are all narrowed
there's no white pulse
so we have ten narrow pulses are as many
as we want to send we can have one and a
loop or we want this one to be nerve
because breaking has no synchronism
frequency so let's check the left side
here some of there are some of them left
side we have 1 2 3 4 30 that are white
and I don't know how many that are
narrow so here you see how we send the
signal through an analog system and this
is digital so this can be have white
pulse and we as a reference taking one
and for a narrow pulse a zero just came
up with a code and here it would be 1 1
1 1 1 0 0 0 and that's the number of
narrow pulses that we have so what about
the right side and that way we see the
hole all of the commands there so right
side would be 1 2 3 4
and number of narrow pulses that's the
left one we try to focus on accelerate
because maybe on the right side it will
crack so accelerating so let's go
through it again and let's repeat the
test again
stop 1 2 3 4 that's for accelerating and
then 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 narrow pulses
so 4 & 3 so we closed it so what do we
do next now that we've seen how it is
sending so save it on the drive save it
on a WAP system and I'll explain how we
can edit it so let's name it let's save
it here for example
a little accelerate were speed up so
come here and let's press play and so I
saved it here stop close and we should
have a fine that is accelerate that wop
so we open it it with an editor so see
we are using here a music editor
audacity have you heard of it which is a
music editor where we can mix and cut
and process the music files why do we
use this that is actually a music
process in up well it works as a song so
what we have recording is just samples
songs as you know is was a WAP is 24 to
100 so we've saved a 2 million so it's
just the same same processing as with
the music file if we keep an increase in
it what do we find it looks like what
we've just seen right 1 2 3 4 of white
pulses and 1 2 3 up to 10 the narrow
pulses and this is repeated through time
so I got the what grown man well doesn't
matter so we have wave here waves that
are signed wives waves that are small
very small and here we are zooming and
and since they are so close together
this is the descriptors of one when it
is sent well nothing is sent is a zero
if lots and lots and lots of waste
another one so it is modulation which is
a and modulation and lock modulation in
with
and now what that we've saved it we can
record the signal we can save the signal
and remove this I will not do it from
scratch because it would take us a
little while and we would be short of
time but same as before this is the
output from our remote and same as
before from the input of our remote all
the way to the output which here is same
device so we are bridging from the input
to the output from our SDR there and so
next what we do not do is pluck the
output credibly but we process the
signal from the minute it goes into the
receiver until well so would we've
processed here is a oscilloscope so and
it goes there reaches there why do we
need it well we need to see
it's a stable frequency not no nice here
let's see alright
iced tea
but tenemos traffic when Thea esto le
fella y cuando el mundo so that is
stable I press something's going on
alright so what do we have here so we
have pulses ones and simmers what we get
here is our previous sequence sequence
with wit ones and zeros here would we've
done is as a reference we've taken time
from the transmission of a 1 sorry this
was a saber so from the beginning of the
sending and then the time once the
sending of the one starts and then it
ends so we are saving the time and we
have it here so we have time that it
takes to use and a 1 so that we have a
frequency or a square bunt this is a
square band same time as you take us to
have our reference frequency from the
radio remote let me expedite it because
otherwise we've run out of time so
what's next next we knit team do this
and we have the time price so we get it
with frequency
our code 1 1 1 1 so 4 ones and 10 zeros
so that's a goat weekend
so we add a victor lids magnifier so
that I can see it this is our effector
and so what we do next is so there's a
previous frequency so you can see right
so what we do here is 3 ones this is the
white pulse 10 is 0 we stopped
transmitting then 3 more ones another
white one and then 0 and then 4 times
over so we have 4 pulses that are
synchronism sent by the remote in
accelerating and then 10 small pulses 0
1 0 1 0 1 that's a vector we combine it
with a sine signal as a reference that
we've produced which is just a regular
sine wave as a reference and then we
combine it with a vector and we got it
here on screen so this is what's been
recorded or saved on the drive and we
see that we had our frequency and there
we had this Plus this this is the peak
where we are working on transmitting
this is the count that we produced next
and so we press them we click it on
transmit and here all right so what's
here so this is the signal produced by
ourselves without touching the remote
this has been produced by ourselves with
the vector that we added its ones and
zeros and so what do you have there
there is no noise right
why is there no nice because it's been
produced by our SDR and it's not going
on air it is just inside our word
generator it's not out in the air so we
are producing for wide and ten narrow
pulses so that goes on air first let's
save it on the disc on their Drive and
we'll test the signal
accelerate one that's what we've
prettiest press cat and Jane on the
drive this is what we heart and then we
have the bottom signal so we've got one
two three four wide pulses and 10 that
are narrow similar to what we had before
so if we start cutting I don't know how
many seconds so if we cut this somewhere
around here
and then we cut a chunk out of here then
you see that the source signal original
signal looks very much alike like what
we've just done we see that times are
much and with it there is no noise as I
said everything you can see here with
every pulses noise in the air which
cannot be avoided what do we have we
produced ourselves so it is clear so
what do we do next we have this with our
SDR up on the air all right same here
but we just get the signal and what we
doing is we're sending on air and I
think now yes yes it should start this
is the signal in transmission
so we see that and if we come closer
here
sure move and as it's happening why do
we need to come that close
people might think well slit will reach
right but that's right that's because
the game is a slow if we add a larger
game and we play and we click on play I
come closer come closer and the rich
should be increased and with game it
comes up these depends on the antenna
and everything 120 so I figured now
it'll go further
it's 27 megahertz there's noise I'm
being eyes and the batteries and
everything but that was it from 0 we can
peruse I think it's enough it's we're
past airplane age but from zero using
Gina's radio we've produced a signal
here you have it that was zeros and ones
that we caught from this remote and so
that's what I wanted you to understand
it understands the signal and since
zeros and ones as a specific command for
these important thing here is okay this
is where we were coming from so we got a
signal from an any given car and we've
transmitted it did and we've opened it
we copy pasted it
so we've copied it and reproduced it it
is a simple attack play attack and so
we've produced our own signal with our
own command what for in case we have
that sequencing sequence of the vehicle
we know how the codes are prettiest and
we can have a code generator and so
there's no need to come that close to
capture the signal from someone no need
to be there we have a signal generator
and we stay next to it and it's as
simple as that than what I wanted you to
understand how can this be avoided
that's what this is all about how no way
to circumvent it avoid it prevent it no
way whatsoever only thing is one we
press the remote and it's not opening we
need to move away because someone just
copied our signal if it's a shopping
center and we'll leave the car there
when we come back maybe we don't have
our stuff in there it cannot be avoided
it cannot be avoided it needs to come
from the manufacturer the manufacturer
needs to add an extra coding or
a different code but that will not allow
for a code to stay valid after some time
this is obviously the manufacturer so
let's skip on so the whole electronic
toll system how does it work I guess
we've all used the electronic throttle
system an electronic call they're all
the same I've never seen anyone that is
different standardized it's usually our
RF I'd eat hot this one is semi active
what does it mean I don't know if you
know about passive tax but it would be a
chip with an antenna no battery
whatsoever but the radio frequency
itself there is an antenna sending on
that radio frequency and there we the
electromagnetic waves it sends manages
to activate the chip and the chip in
turn with the radio frequency it
received can have a single identifier
sent to the antenna to the transmitter
that's a passive tag what does a same
active or semi passive tag do depends on
what we want to call it and how we want
to use it it doesn't wait so this a
battery and it's no need to since the
signal coming in is very weak it doesn't
need to use the right frequency from the
what was being received but itself it's
using the received radio frequency from
the antenna to say to the battery okay
turn on and feed me so that I can send
my signal and my I Dean what does this
semi and
if tagged do it doesn't use their energy
that receives to transmit but rather to
activate the battery and then transmit
the ID at a longer distance for instance
with 2.4 gigahertz we would be able to
transmit on a range of 300 meters that's
what we need
whereas in the longer tags the shorter
tags it would be 11 meters there are
different distances depending on the
frequency that we're using for
transmitting in this case for electronic
roto systems they're semi active and
they transmit at 2.4 so when we go
through the Tollbooth what do we see
there is an antenna an aerial
transmitting a signal to our tag in our
car and then our tag system
I am transmit the client ID but that
we've been allocated on what the server
gets in the roto system is an ID of who
is going through the booth so that we
can then be charged every month so what
needs to happen for the barrier to lift
without having to pay for it it's never
so peculiar and it's fun I find it fun I
just have fun with it what did I prepare
here well it's an antenna an area in a
choir here is the picture and this is a
real-life situation where the system is
ready and working in the car the
Arielle is simulating like it's the one
in the rotor system as if it were the
server so we're driving normally and
we're capturing all the IDS of all
vehicles that have the rotor system
electronic wrote tow system working
let's imagine that we capture 30 of them
the idea is that we can take it in turn
to use different IDs on different days
so that's different people will find
there's an extra charge at the end of
the month will they notice well we don't
know doing am I encourage you to do this
in real life or not
and how can this be avoided well how can
we stop this capture from happening
happening well by having a paradigm box
protecting us in this case yes as I said
it's only a Faraday box protecting the
system in our car to make sure that
nobody is nasty we're no nasty right but
there might be nasty people they're
cheeky people who it'll use the motorway
for free and we'll be paying for it we
don't do that because we're nice so
let's check what a tag system needs to
work and as I said this is not a
hypothetical situation this I did this
in real life
you will see in a minute this is what it
looks like all these numbers different
digits and it comes by default
this long list of digits for the tongue
so because the our company works with
software development one of the things
that we've prepared is a programmable
chip so that the code can go in any
position we like so as I said we would
go for a little ride in our car it
captured a number of IDs a few of them
and then change the ID in the right
position so that with a switch we would
just activate our transmitter for the
electronic road to system the antenna
would receive it and we would go through
as if we were somebody else some other
car when we go through the Tollbooth the
system would be activated and the area
with thing would think that as I said we
are driving some other car that's the
way to use the motorway for free
pretending where somebody else how can
you avoid us well by isolating is with
the Faraday box
cage sorry Faraday cage right I'm
running out of time so let's keep moving
let's now check how alarm systems work
at home I post an alarm from one of
these pound lands I wrote Chinese run
shop they tend to be not great but still
I bought a well-known brand I got the
code from the alarm system when you arm
and disarm the alarm this is a very
basic capture technique on FM because
it's a very simple system it has to be
something cheap what we saw for instance
in the remote-controlled toy toy car
that worth work that was more of a
simple system in the case of their
residential alarm is a little bit more
complex so let's see how we can crack
that code and we can cheat again well
it's very similar technique here we have
the client in this case the homeowner
who would activate the alarm when
leaving home the alarm is activated you
are meet you leave your home and you
think it's safe what would we do then
well we would be close by
we would then capture the code the
homeowner had to transmit to arm the
alarm and then it would also be nearby
when the homeowner comes back home to
capture the code to disarm or deactivate
the alarm again this was a well-known
brand for this alarm system and in fact
we found that the code is identical both
for arming and disarming can imagine how
terribly unsafe that's that is normally
a la car alarms are safer I found than
alarms for homes is a little bit
pathetic right pressing the using the
same code both for activating and
deactivating Villa that's a message for
my presentation never use a wireless
alarms is much better if they they're
wired because with the wireless system
is you have quite a high probability
than the code will be less secure so as
I said you would use the code and you
would be able to access gain access as
if you were the home owner let's see how
it works
we're not going to be working with GNU
radio in this case the radio GNU
here it is
I'll be using the same program we saw
earlier to capture the frequency let's
see what it is
all right
see I tell you what or not here it is
button a and button B what are we doing
now wanna see how it works I press
button a for arming this is button a for
arming now I'm going to press button B
whoops here we have it a button a button
B for arming and disarming I just wanted
you to see that so let's take a what
frequency is the right one for
transmission for this control if it were
a European frequency it would be 443
megahertz well as an approximation
let's press button a there we have it
let's double check what the exact
frequency is in this case is 434 997 I'm
going to copy paste it
4 3 2 9 9 7
there it is and now we're going to copy
you
first thing we need
to do is recording on the hunt harddrive
our button a how do we need to do that
in this case we need to be more accurate
more precise we're transmitting on a
different modulation so we're going to
be using the open source osmocon project
and which tends to work much better than
the one I showed you earlier here it is
minus F for a the frequency minus G for
the gain and minus R for recording good
[Music]
here it is
we need to do the sampler for a million
what do we need to enter now minus F
four three two point nine nine seven
right the frequency I got just now
right
good this is similar to what we had
earlier on I need to press the button
and here a 4-3-3 right so Wow I now need
to name the file but eh I press record
and I stop it it's exactly the same as
we saw earlier on in this case this
command has worked how we stood near the
home we pressed the record button we
waited for the homeowner to live and we
have captured that a as a button
I let's see what the file contains
why did I save that I think it was here
I hope you can see that can you see this
here the print is a little bit small
well I can see here some little marks
like stains some of them are wider some
of them are narrower what does that mean
well as we said earlier the narrower
ones equate to zero and the larger or
wider ones are a sine waves that would
equate to one so that would equate to
nodes and ones making up a code so that
the control can transmit that code right
if we can do this manually but this is
very helpful it's very visual
you see North node one one not one not
one and so on that is generating
sequence is what I need two copies by
the way is it not
not one well and so on I've copied it a
I don't want to waste time
so we generate that code with notes and
ones or what do we need to do next just
as I showed you earlier we need to then
analyze the width of a post
although in this case I'm using this
more visual system I find it a lot more
convenient to be honest you see there it
is I'm going to explain you how it works
but in fact the idea is a little bit
this is one I prepared earlier we've got
there 25 pulses you know and look how
it's synchronized perfectly well it this
is not like the remote control that I
showed you that I bought from the
Chinese shop and where it was it varied
quite a bit in this case is much better
secretly synchronized you see this the
post starts then it comes down another
one starts it comes down and from this
line through the next that would equate
to a full sine wave so from this line to
that one that means the sine wave goes
through zero because a sine wave always
starts at zero it goes up to 1 2 3
whatever then it comes down back to 0
before it goes back up again in this
case we see the posts very tiny pause
within the sine wave so it's not even a
whole sine wave this is more or less
half of 1 this is a narrow post coming
down to 0 then going back up again
another narrow post and look at that
third one it almost fills up completely
the sine wave so we have separated those
narrower pulses from the wider poses the
narrower poses tend to be round about
half of a longer post
which is very helpful because the server
for the alarm can tell whether it's a
North order one month and so can we
so you can read the information because
that's what we're doing right we are
just transmitting notes and ones in this
case not digitally but through an analog
Channel it's a frequency algorithm that
range so I don't want to copy it because
in fact we can do this manually you see
note note one note one right so I could
do that manually type it in first
I'm not going to do this this is a very
clever too
here it is so I said this is very clever
well I'm saying it's clever I have to
wait and see if it works I'm just going
to enlarge I want okay can you see that
letter size from the back well there we
have it
we have that number what does that say -
- - - all of those numbers minus nine
minus nine minus six minus six
what does that mean that's width - six -
well sorry a white one a white post and
narrow post that's what it's saying
meaning this is a nose or this is a one
that's the message well
the one I prepared earlier
so I said this is one I prepared earlier
so this is where I have the value for a
so I don't need to copy paste it so
again as we did earlier we've got it
ready now what what what can we do with
it we make sure the sequence has no gaps
in between the digits we copy that
sequence then of digits and then I get
my Arduino how much to this cost
well about 10 euros that's all I have a
radio frequency transmitter I bought
this one at a Chinese shop by the way
how much does this cost what about five
heroes that's all so it's a very simple
system right a very simple device
another one which is a little bit more
complex but still it's analog right so
just that very small investment plus a
little wire simulating an alarm system
that costs hundreds of euros to gain
access to a home that might cost
hundreds of thousands of euros as he who
works we connect the Arduino let's cross
our fingers so it works first time round
the reason I wanted to show you this is
that we have those two different ways to
record a signal the first exercise
recorded the doorbell signal saving it
recording it and then reproducing it
playing it again without having the
command then the radio control remote
control to a car we started there from
scratch generated the signal from
scratch with pulses with pulses with
modulation
whereas this time we used a more visual
tool like so getting then the code for
the alarm because we were standing
nearby with an modulated so we could see
the code or codes to arm and disarm the
alarm and then we broadcasted we
transmitted a thanks to the Arduino so
this is the code I copied we now paste
it for our magic Arduino to work let's
hope when I press it works so we program
the art you know with the disarm code I
don't know if you can hear it I can hang
on there is an error mode because there
is another one here I didn't get the
right one
the port was wrong
this is the right one so for those of
you at the back of the room you won't
hear it but it's transmitting I can hear
it let me show you the demo now
I now can
the Arduino now there is not working I
wonder what happened there it's getting
to where it needs to go I can hear it
alright because he's fifteen thousand
two hundred this is life what I wrecked
he was B was it zero here nine six
double oh well I'm just setting it
because earlier on it was used using the
wrong ports
I still use I might be old-fashioned but
I still use a serial port for my
communications so you will see it's USB
here but in fact the serial port is
still quite common because it can cope
with much larger speeds call me
nostalgia's but I communicate with our
my art unit Arduino at nine six Duvall
oh that's what I'm like let's hope it
works now oh there it doesn't
again apologies because only people who
are right at the front of the room will
be able to hear how this is working the
relays are being activated here is not
connecting up properly no idea why
apologies but the helic HELOCs
wave I actually made this system by
myself with a screwdriver you just
measure the links you need to measure
the wavelength at 400 megahertz I can't
remember how many centimeters that
equates to and for the width is the same
idea so just for 10 euros plus my
Arduino I could gain access to a home
with an alarm you just have to take my
word for it how can you how could you
avoid somebody doing something like this
well having an alarm which is not
wireless which is also not a very
well-known brand so that people can't
copy the code and what kind of alarm
would that be well definitely wired not
wireless system your sensors should be
wired not a wireless because I forgot to
tell you a story earlier on I had to buy
an alarm for me to learn how to do this
and the most popular brand in our
country that's the one I bought and I
found that the communication between the
sensors and the server their main
station in that communication is not
safe they say it is but is not so apart
from copying the remote control from the
alarm you can also actually
cheat the system for instance if I if it
didn't work with a remote control if it
worked with a keypad well even then we
could gain access by telling the alarm
system one particular sensor is not
detecting anything we would be standing
next to it and we will be able to cheat
the whole system at the company's
headquarters for detection not to work
so it's quite scary right how terribly
insecure this all is no security
whatsoever
so let me move on to the next exercise
remember this is a key to a hotel room a
keycard
right this is going to be a simulation
and I'm not encouraged encouraging you
to do anything like this but I'm just
going to show you how it could be done
how does a keycard work at a hotel in
the card has a chip have you seen many
hotels with her with a key like this I
haven't not many hotels have a key card
like this it's quite an unusual one but
in fact it's quite a safe system if they
use it right the standard in this case
the iso standard is seven eight one six
with a protocol that uses an apron
memory how does this work well it has a
memory bank protected by a password so
we can read the memory bank but we still
need a password and why is this key card
different or peculiar
well because we can read it we can see
the code we can see the ID for that key
card plus any other information that the
manufacturer or the hotel resection has
added with that six digit password what
happens is that when you enter your
password wrong three times the key card
self destroys imagine that what does
that mean that there are fuses physical
fuses so that when you enter the
password wrong three times there is a
hard voting a high voltage like a search
right five six votes something like that
and the cord is physically invalid
because it burns basically
so it's a very safe card right can you
imagine how hard it is for you to guess
a six digit and PIN number I mean you
you might get lucky one day I've broken
lots of cards like that I ended up
ruining them many many times because it
is very hard to guessing a code like
that what did we come up with so this is
the card the inside this is an apron
card as I said it has a memory bank that
is 20 1024 bytes is a small one some
others are 2048 and others are 4096
depending on the one we want to buy but
in order to store a hotel room number we
don't need much information so you see
the first 6 bytes in our bank memory
bank much a single ID usually that the
manufacturer those six bytes cannot be
modified we can not save anything on top
of them on paper every manufacturer
would have six digits are located same
as with computers there are some numbers
from X number T Z number and there's a
serial production of cards and can only
use those numbers allocated to them by
the authority in charge of regulating it
all and we are allowed to you right from
the sixth byte onwards so o 600 was the
beginning and from all seven own words
we can write as much as we want but in
all that you write we need a PIN number
we can read even the ID no problem there
that we've allocated to the card and we
can just write if we know what the pin
number is there's no other writing
method only by knowing the pin will be
able to write
this is a real card from the hotel no
names given here bad well any given
Hotel what was recorded in years
there was an ID naturally as with any
other card and three bytes only three
bytes here if you know how to translate
hexadecimal to decimal system is quite
simple and straightforward here it was
zero zero zero six eight five which
would be room 101 in the XML system it's
not too hard right not even them ever
control or anything of the kind no
encryption nothing so directly it was
101 why is that well they know why the
ones who did is they know that they
trusted the security and the protection
given by the pin number that is a
succeeded and also the self-destruction
of the god technology is good yes it's
old
yeah very old this is from the 90s and
I'll explain the story on how it all
started and how I actually started
looking into this protocol and this card
I'll explain the anecdote but please let
me finish
what's inside room 102 you just the same
hexadecimal to decimal there's a simple
conversion but not too difficult right
and in this hotel the master game
someone if someone would guess what the
code was
zero zero zero zero the empty cart is
filled with ones so here for the master
key zero zero zero zero and as I say
this is real live I got the cart don't
ask me how but I managed to read it and
I guessed the code for it not very
difficult it is just common sense right
do you see one two three cards you just
try it out and easily you find a
combination to open any given door all
right
so how does the sturb begin because I
before I move on I'd like to share the
story with you as I said I grow old and
in the 90s I was already thinking it
through and there's this friend who
comes and says you know there is a video
clef or a video store do you remember
what they were like you know what a
video store is but I see young people in
the audience but in the past we had a
video shop or a video store they would
have a sticker with the barcodes and
they would read your barcode that was
your ID as a client and they would
charge you whatever and you can you
could rent anything and then some 20
years ago 20 years ago it hung flies
right but they got him up to date and
started using a cart like this with a
chip in it same as I said before with
the hotel
and a friend comes and says there is
this chip card at a video store
well now it's different I went how can
you not okay you was neat to look into
it and sure I just screw the the regard
and just three atoms and it was ruined
it is worse than real no more read in
three attempts I looked into the
protocol and the standard and it is true
Phillips Phillips the one that came up
with this kind of card included
self-destruction options so asked for
another card got another one
said okay this one I need to give it
it's been to and I don't through time so
not a third time so what did they come
up with him back in the day to guess the
code it took him some time lots of time
loads of hours working hours but what
did I invent well what did I come up
with I decided to have a card this one
okay you cannot well what did I do a
physical card we don't have any it was
it's not a plastic card but a physical
card instead just one like that
I studied electronics for five years in
case you didn't know
apart from computer science I am
familiar with electronics and it built a
physical card for myself just like this
one the same size and the length was a
bit larger and I would get wires or
threads something like this what would I
do
I would pluck the connector the pin the
pins inside the machine I would get them
out to my cars that I had built myself
in order to weld some wires and see what
the machine was ridden physical card
that you had to enter or swipe through
the reader and back then when laptops
were nothing like today's I wired to the
car and won lots of inventions in
between but like that I got to you get
the physical pins of the machine inside
of a board that I produced myself and I
entered my original card into my machine
so what did I do
I put it right in between so this has
been done at a hotel because this was my
cyber country true but it all started
further ago when there were what they're
still we're video shops or stores so I
have that card
I wore it my card all the way to the
real card this one here I place my safe
in
between to see what was being sent what
did I manage to see well the pin on the
card and I had several cards but the
same thing over and over so funny isn't
it and I saw what was transmitted all
through the card see the machines all
the same pins always the same well so
does using breeders like this one this
is a bit more modern this is a parallel
port but this is very modern this we
didn't have before
then the serial port if you remember
back when we had the via digital and
other readers that are used for this
kind of readers but this is from before
that canal channel class I will I was
familiar with the cards but it comes
from earlier than that so what I did was
get the pin code out which was unique
and all cards have a pin code so I could
modify my card
we just had see what the card hot not
not this one this is the hotels car but
it had an ID the video store was using
as a client ID and had the balance in
the card in it so five euro I don't know
how many pesetas it would have been back
there about five year now and you would
be have it a year and you would describe
it and you would get a five euros worth
and I cut the pin and I managed to
modify
I didn't bring the owner to Irene as a
statement I'd lost at last I got to see
some films for free
this is good right how we can how can we
prevent it and we need to know how to
use the card we cannot live information
and encrypt it never ever ever card
quite safe because it's self-destructive
and old technology but very safe and
Pooley used as the usual
that's what a hacker does this is not
inventing is not just we've found that
technology is not properly used that is
not being done right they encrypt
information and instead of five years
you say oh five you kind of have five
year encrypted with a parrot or a public
key so that I didn't know I cannot know
that this sequence is says five year
that's a conclusion here you need to use
the technology right I think we have
time for one breeding I haven't said it
before this card came in later
I removed everywhere in everything as I
said same as with the car and it no it
had to be done at night so that was not
fun
and the the prison wasn't you buy so had
to be careful
so these God maybe the older people in
the room know about it but know what a
big is an EPROM is big is a programmable
microchip but is inside the card so you
can have this is not so trivial it isn't
an assembler it is a basic assembler
it's the NYX assembler 8-bit very basic
but you can program yourself code inside
the card see we have time oh no really
not so you can program your card and on
the assembler you can build things so
what did I do this is my card
the card I have and you put it into the
reader and it slave the byte sequence
sent by the the sender so you have the
original card the other card and it
saves the pin and we cannot try it
because we don't have time and you keep
it with a card like this you didn't know
warriors or anything of the kind
so a hotel what else can we do apart
from sleeping and come breaking into
other people's rooms with this kind of
cards one can have fun with industrial
control of our hotel our hotel is quite
complication there's boilers fancy
boilers actually also temperature
control or window opening and blind
control so what can we do with it we
have the bus protocol which is high
level but underneath there is an rs-485
communication control we were talking
about a different kind of our s and
before now thesis have been what's
interesting about 485 well it sense
London in the range is long-distance
here it sends through channel a that's
positive information and channel B same
information but negative so it sends I
have one positive on channel 8 and
negative 1 and channel B what is it good
for probably just so that you understand
the idea is to send information for long
distance is widely used in areas with
high noise wherever we have lots of
interference and we want to make sure
that information does not reach this
nation altered and here we have a short
demo of a module it to black to a fan
this one with two buttons and it's not
pass that who these people they language
they used to communicate and in between
everything we've done before is for
sniffing is not right frequency sniffing
here but MA bus protocol that we are
sniffing is a serial transmission
how does Mark buzz work from one module
to the next communication follows one
flow is not about two ways but it's only
two ways so it has no Rx and TX only TX
it only sends one way reading our our X
is transmitted when it comes from a
previous module so information travels
just one way not two ways but one way we
stay in between or in the middle and the
bad guy here gets all the information
sent by the button here the circum and
so this is it so recording reading this
is the map fast normal protocol this is
a button so activate the fan so I stay
in between us if you remember about the
power practice from a year some years
back here it is not buzz but back there
it was canvas Oh Baskin just the same
you are in the middle you listen
everything coming from button a you grab
the command you're interested in you
change it and send it through bus again
and you easily cheat where any module so
at the hotel you know that he what can
we use it for it see how much from my
hotel is if you change where
temperatures in the rooms was a lighting
turning oven on the lights people go
crazy and you have lots of fun lots of
fun for an evening for example and you
can change anything you want you can
trigger wrong lumps and hidden systems
and sensors that are not working
actually I was thinking of turning and a
ventilator and a fan on you can't eat
any device saying that they are
overheating even though it's not true
those are all things then the travel
path and I have finished and how does it
work a Travel Pass work same as before
this kind of cards that I have here
these are cards without a chip or
anything they are just RFID and if they
have an identifier same as here is a
single one but the difference is what's
the difference
these ones are protected or secured with
a self instruction but not these so it's
unlimited attempts as many comments as
you want probably you cannot say that
the memory database aims here this is 20
sorry 1024 this one as well which can
choose whatever you want but the memory
protection is not limited to any attempt
you can send as many attempts as you
want so what did we need to do with this
card in order to modify it well we need
to be patient mainly why do we need to
be patient because algorithm in it is
huge it would take us ten thousand years
to struct the mind the code out of the
card there are people who are very smart
in this world or with plenty of time or
well with lots of interest and they've
managed to x-ray the card some seen the
chip inside it's unprotected cuda
manufacturers would protect the chip
with kind of a booty so that you cannot
x-ray it and it's interesting and it is
unprotected and you could see it from
the inside
and they found a way to not to send so
many attempts and that way they would
get the number so that is the key the
record and key the right and key out of
8 so down from 10,000 years that it's 2
to the power of 14 10 to 1 hour and
within an hour we can change any given
card and
move around for free riding a buzzer the
metro or anything it's a pity because
again we would need an extra hour here
and we cannot show it vending machine
same as before same cord but instead of
NFC is RF ID while the vending machines
are not nicely damn manufactured it's
easy to see okay I'm not a fan of
vending machines how does it work same
as before but what do we do we use
everything I don't know what it is but
same readiness before and through brute
force what we brute force it and it
doesn't take that long and sorry we're
out of time but that's what I had to
share thank you very much I hope you
enjoyed it
[Applause]
other questions
no question so everything is clear then
thank you very much for your attendance
how can you get after the card if you
wanna come and touch it's all really can
come and touch that's way bring it if
something doesn't work is just a matter
of speaking live
[Music]