you
[Music]
good morning how are you
I'd like to welcome you all and said
there are not many people here it's
complicated this is Sunday there's an
election going on Andalusia people have
left I think we have an interesting talk
ahead of us 3540 minutes this is the
last part of cyber camp
we're here to talk about our experience
as the Spanish team the last edition of
the european survey cyber security
challenge with made an analogy with
video game are you familiar with
battlefield this year was a particular
fight there were many difficulties the
talent has increased the number of
countries two people in the steering
committee and i would like say hello to
my colleague our years ago there were
many last-minute decisions changes the
rules of the game conflicts of interest
among countries say we serve a battle
for all of us and before starting i
would like to ask a question to your
audience how many of you have heard
about European cyber security challenge
before hands up about 75% of our room
those of you have just come in did you
live did you hear me have you heard
about the events I will give you a
challenge well today's talk
is inspirational and motivational top
we're going to use one fellow and man
was an example to follow well
particularly for those who you the young
ones following us those of you who want
to be part of the Spanish team and we're
going to explain how you have to do it
you have the right place cyber camp
which is the classification stays in
order to become a member of the Spanish
team so without further ado we'll start
with a talk well I would like to
introduce Manuel Blanco aka rainy day
how did you started cybersecurity I was
quite young when I started like all of
us I was self-taught I was I thought I
was curious and little by little they
develop your skills you read whatever
you can you take part in Faro you
discuss with people in charge to
exchange opinions that was how I begun
and we also have Gonzalo earthy Leone
aka hands tapa and smooth he was third
he came up third last year in cyber camp
this year has been fighting and to the
last minute how do you start
in ETF I started last year at cyber camp
my first series CDF and in cybersecurity
was like one well I finished my studies
before finishing my studies I was
focusing in cybersecurity ethical
hacking and after that I was self-taught
I registered for a master's degree in IT
security but I wasn't convinced by it
usually when you finish your studies
they tell you that you need a master's
degree it's mandatory in order to become
someone to specialise I don't think so I
don't agree I think your personal work
in this space on my experience and the
experience of people around me the work
you do at home the interests you have
whatever your practice that's more
valuable than any degree well you've
raised an important point I would like
to ask you about the need to have a
technical degree in order to work in
this area the many self-taught people a
while ago there were no specific
training and people working in this were
self-taught but it's true that having a
technical degree gives you cross-cutting
knowledge and a basis after which you
can specialize your steering computing
in science and you know I've finished we
were speaking about this yesterday
I said that for me having my degree
provided me with the technical basis
which is very important that's what I
tell people all the time when they ask
me and what they tell me they want to be
hackers or cyborgs in cybersecurity I
always say the same thing it's a
cross-cutting knowledge it has to do
with every knowledge in IT what does it
mean if you're interested in web
security web hacking and wrapped him in
web apps or code analysis and web apps
first of all you need to be familiar
with our technology you cannot exploit a
vulnerability in PHP if you don't know
anything about PHP or you cannot do pen
testing and systems if you don't master
Linux or a Linux console from my point
of view I think it's not that important
perhaps it's a good way to have a good
theoretical foundations get Peters good
concepts it's one way to acquire this
knowledge
so if not yourself Tony cannot reach
those information sources here you you
have University it gives you your basis
but you can reach that knowledge
yourself total base is the most
important things that a person person
has passion and that the person learns
all the time so if you sort of answer
the next question we tend to go to in
theory conferences and they ask me how
can a specialist in cyber security today
the Internet provides you with the
necessary tools tutorials there are four
are many events in which you can get
into the community what would you
recommend to the youngest people that
are looking at us watching us today I
would recommend conferences when you're
starting
Cybercom rotate combi have all the talks
in the internet even though you don't
have the possibility to physically go
there 10 to the cumference there's
material in the internet and that's very
honest this is something really good
organizations are doing uploading all
this content for free and when we say
that we're self-taught we mean that we
use Google very well everything is there
just search in Google and when they
specialize well you filter the
information you want to obtain from
which field it's true and that came up
yesterday - let's imagine you know
nothing about cybersecurity I said I
tell you you need to self teach yourself
searching Google but what do a search
for hacking web you're going to see many
advertising material for many causes
that they want your money and then you
have lots of materials that are not
quality materials so that's why think
converses are important not just a
conference itself but also the people
you meet the people around you for me
that was one of the most valuable
sources of information so the community
you create yes so let's close this first
part of the conference which is
inspirational motivational we already
know your trajectories therefore our two
captains now let's speak about Spanish
team for those of you who are not
familiar this cyber camp allows in
theory to choose 10 people that go to
the European cyber security challenge
every year through cyber Olympics
individual CTF and hackathon
in serious role is choosing the Spanish
team that goes to the ECSC every year
and they're trained it in our facilities
this is two of our main tasks I'd like
to ask you something
so that you can explain this to young
people watching us that want to become
members of our team how can you remember
member of our team what do you do
interesting question the best way to
reach your goal is constant work for
example if you want to be good at CDF of
course you need to do that all the time
you need feedback there are platforms
such as city at time where there's a
list of the competitions that take place
where you can register and perhaps you
need to play with the team but you can
go through challenges move forward and
if you don't solve a test which is no
more the first thing to get to know
something is not knowing that after
fighting with it you can look at the
solution and you understand the mo in
order to reach your goals and then you
just have to play to be constant and
come to cyber camp yes that's very
important
I've said that in Phoebus in charge of
training the Spanish team in that try
knowledge provided our facilities as a
technical part but also soft skills in
other words the skills that make you do
more efficient at your work business via
communication the ability to work as a
team managing stress conflicts how do
you see the training would provide an in
theory
ours was quite fun with with Miguel we
did things which were yeah his nothing a
bit crazy so to speak but some
activities were quite exotic but we had
loves we get to know each other one of
the best way to get to know each other
was being forced to do silly things
laugh at ourselves and of course
yeah working as a team and cohesion that
something pivotal because we choose a
group of people there are specialists in
specific categories each one is good at
something and we create a high
performance team and the cemetery of
capabilities creates a team that can
have a good performance and a
competition but you have to manage trust
because these years were two days 16
hours have been interrupted competition
and management stress is very important
I would like to add something it's very
tiring being under pressure you want to
get a good achieve a good result it's
complicated to handle all that so it's
important to have social skills because
as you say this is a team you need a
technical profile when you need to be
able to communicate because it's a team
you need self-criticism if you can't
solve something you need to say it you
cannot use a colleagues ideas that's it
I think well this are some pictures of
this year's training we train 15 people
from cyber comms competition in the end
we had 10 members and five people for
reserve the first one was Jonathan who
came up second in city of competition
yesterday in cyber camp you already know
man Rockefeller would like you to get to
know the rest of the members of the team
you are not going to come up to stage
yet but we're going to watch a video of
this year's training
[Music]
[Applause]
when was this way LVL afirma so this is
the video of the training that we
receive that in civil and now let us go
into competition and then we will make a
technical demo of one of the challenges
that we did in London so those of you
who want to get closer to Europeans have
a security challenge it is started three
years ago as an initiative of venice'
with the origin track team and it is
kind of that the euro league of european
talents in this company did well the
design of CFT changes this year the
first possible attack on defense so the
parties here CTF with different
categories forensic map analysis and
also Santi ffs change every so often
manisa tries to give a different view a
different perspective every year so that
the competition continues to be healing
as well and actually the easier of the
other was
Ariella training where we could buy
shion-san is engaging comparation with
different countries at the end they
decided not to cover it will have worked
a lot on the aspects of negotiation well
we must say that we have kind of hurdle
with English English language okay so we
will improve our English hell though
this year we did a good job in when we
introduced ourselves and with now I'd
like to ask you what is the meaning of
this competition to you what do you mean
by the meaning so what does entail for
you taking participating there
representing Spain
how do you feel about it I'll give you
an example before participating for the
first time I didn't know anyone I didn't
know Borja nor Jose no one and I saw
articles in the news and saying that
Spanish team won the competition won the
challenge and to me I said well I want
to be there
that's my aspiration I would never be
one of them I would never win challenge
look one year later I was there in the
team and yes well you can see that he's
very humble actually he's very very good
he's the best
so participating in the European
challenge well this year we had the
participation of many countries the
level was very high so you don't feel
that you are participating in the
regional CTF it is a serious CTF is
higher level
yes actually I mentioned that some
colleagues in recent years the initial
purpose which was identifying and
promoting talent has kind of been lost
this is like being professionalized and
let us say you see some teens wearing
the icons and the
logos of companies and well because we
want to times we were kind of being I
don't known singles out so to speak and
these yeah well we had the participation
of 17 teams so 17 countries it is
expected Naseer to have the
participation of 20 countries so the
challenge is growing and growing the
first year there were only five
countries and what are the challenges
you are you face today so this year well
all the challenges as I said were
different multidisciplinary the
competition had a new party format
meaning that there were different
categories hacking web app hacking and
different challenges in each categories
and organized were classified by level
of difficulty the challenges were very
interesting and well this is a
photograph of our team there in London
and the facilities and now I'd like to
play video video for the first day of
the competition this is a setup that we
found in London
[Music]
[Applause]
whenever job is visto and Pocoyo are
they in the competition understand
geography that was a competition site
very nice atmosphere second day was very
very good because we could see some very
many countries big teams we had a
cameraman with us we have me well our
assistants very many people involved
right from the start to push the team to
get ahead of the others
Anisa tries to innovate every year just
to add novelties to the competition and
this year they have been stand challenge
that was kind of like a step room
challenge with some horror to it so I
like you to tell us about a bit more
about that challenge but before that
I'll play video
[Music]
when a contaminant consistent well tell
us a bit more about this challenge so
where do we fail
well that challenge was very interesting
it was not kind of usual it was escape
where we had to gain access fast trying
out a number of combinations to get the
pin number then we had to flag some
alarms and and well physically share any
annexes that says though that challenge
was held in the second day of the
competition of day one a diverse
competition we finished third we were
very close to finished first and we had
15,000 points but because of these
testings asserted to have gone wrong
from the start what happened well I'm
one of the responsible for things going
wrong so well when we started the
challenge has - okay we went like we
rushed into it there were a number of
challenges that we had to go through
first of all a door that you had to open
through a pin code so the night before
we had given we will have been given a
cryptogram and then then we had to find
the script to open the door
we failed that we failed that test I
think that all the teams failed that
very first test the second test was
going into the the room and then there
there was an alarm yes actually we could
hear the alarm in the video and so there
was an alarm and all of us ignored it we
didn't pay attention to it in
my case I thought it was kind of like
they come down but no it was an actual
alarm and there was a code covering a
button that we had to press to keep
going and then well now wait for the
best part is coming so one of the part
was kind of a bomb that had to be
deactivated so the first thing that we
had to do is just to bridge some
circuits and publish our experts in
Harper he was bridging that and then one
of the bridges fell into the actual box
into the actual bomb and I mentioned to
you organizer
look we just lost days in the box can we
get another one he said no no well part
of the test challenge was for you to be
careful not to drop anything uh not to
lose any of the components and that was
another failure and the very last
failure which I'm fully responsible for
that I don't know where there are
players well the halves like sound gap
in them okay
everyone knew that but myself so we had
to careful wire simultaneously we
already yes ready three two one and then
when I did it I could see that one of
the tables have gone into that gap okay
I could see that I hadn't cut the food
wire and then I tried to cut it right at
the end and then they eat immediately
very low noise a cryptic noise like kind
of meaning that it has exploded and it
was probably said okay let us run away
okay he has not been defused okay and
that was a turning point because we went
into the room back into the room we were
disappointed the rest of the teams I
started to gain lots of points and we
got like kind of this car
and actually that was a key a key
challenge a key test and then well this
curve was very tight those 15,000
schools would have allowed us to have
finished fourth of fifth and then we
would analyze why we could not repeat in
our win this year and then as we said
before this competition has like part of
it is about introducing ourselves okay
if in the past we were penalized in that
test but this year we got tapas course
thanks to Manuel and his presentation
can you tell us more about it
well actually we knew that that test was
very important was very relevant in
terms of scoring and because we had
difficulties in provision we decided to
devote time Swedish to Train very much
so it's and then we did a very good job
I have a good command of English I'm
fluent in English and then that's why we
did a good job and now it's time to
answer the following questions since I
came back to London that was in October
I think I had to answer this question
like some hundred times it's not 150
times the question is about why Spanish
team has won the secretary challenge in
Malacca we have also won the previous
year we were about to have our third win
and as you can see this year in this
table so we finished 11th in 11 position
and they won we were very high up in the
score table but the very factors that
penalized us and second day one of the
junior guys one of the most talented
guys got sick had to go back to the
hotel so we played only with nine people
the first day we also had problems with
connectivity to people couldn't work for
of hours or four good periods of time it
is true to say that the level of
participating countries is here was very
high higher than in previous year to
give you an example the Italian team had
six guys in them who had been in DEFCON
LasVegas professional players Polonia
had never been up in the ranking they
finished fools and then the trainer was
the captain of track dragon sector
Greece they were sponsored by heart box
some a number of regularities well they
kind of got some suspicious scoring and
actually the steering committee had very
hot debates and meetings and it was not
a read until the end when they disclosed
the final classification of final
results well I have analyzed this
several times before what about you how
do you feel but do you think what the
aspects that impacted as the most for
not to be higher up in the final results
well as we said before this competition
that's it for a couple of days well it
used to be 24 hours in the beginning
then it shifted increased from one day
to two days pressure was building up in
the secondaries we were very anxious we
were kind of worn out because virtually
speaking we were fast on day one and
then we had to keep that up and we just
couldn't do it as I say of drivel of
rivals okay the other teams were very
very high level and well that's that's
why when actually and they were kind of
going for us I didn't know since a
number one it is not that we felt
attacked but we received many claims or
the managing and team received many
claims about us so there were Restless
to beat us so once Allah would you like
to add anything there
well I share what Noel said well we
finished the 11th because there were a
number of things that we didn't do right
oh well that we were not as encouraged
and the rest of the teams also did a
very good job well to be a bit
self-critical perhaps the team was not
did not flow as much as in previous
years perhaps we didn't have enough
training perhaps in previous years we
had more training so there was a bit of
lack of consistency between the senior
and junior team so at the end of the day
16 hours of competition one day - we
were all kind of bit crazy and as I said
before softer skills have very important
to stress management teamwork becomes
all the more important on the more
relevant and a crucial element for this
type of challenges and also the
finishing 11th it is not something with
that we should be not proud of
not at all it is not a defeat so for us
this season wind this is a triumph well
someone will go and say what you
finished 11 no no no those who said that
they have not been there they haven't
gone through it
higher higher level in all the teams is
here no one has been defeated
so this who actually fails are those who
stay at home who do not take part in the
challenges or in any qualification
grounds and here we have the winner of
individual CTF Cybercom so we have
another person who won the city of
DEFCON man who also go where CTF was won
last year so technically speaking our
team was very solvent robust and
competent is here ok we would like to
well to be clear and to share all that
with you so that you are whatever it is
Spain has always been a clear reference
inside an ascetic competition some money
this is a question for you we are also
reference outside the competition oh yes
we are we should not forget that this
competition rather than being an actual
competition and while beating our rebel
rivals it's about also about networking
making friends and we are very good
interacting with other teams we are
highly sociable we make good friends and
we really had a good time would you
please tell us more about the photograph
right in the middle but what you doing
there so we have friends with from
Switzerland and we'll were just dancing
dancing together so we'll come through
well the experience that both captains
have had and now let us move on to the
technical side of the challenge Manuel
Gonzalo
will share with us some one of the
challenges that we had to solve ok all
yours
well the challenge was equal to it was
for exploding binaries in discussing
liners ok I'll go into technicalities
now it was an elf binary Linux 32-bit it
had a bit and ex asking the word first
act to be writable and it was linked
dynamically meaning that the system
libraries were not pre-loaded in the
actual binary but the libraries are set
for in the OS so these facilities the
reversing of the binary that is to say
to see instruction by instruction but
the binary it does
that's quite facilitated quite a lot
another thing which is facilitated is
that the binary was not stripped that is
to say that the function and the names
of the variables were
visible perfectly legible so these
facilitates reverse engineering of the
binary for you to know what each faction
does bug of this binary is known as
format string but you can see that
better it was an S print F function
where the input of the user went right
away as became the second parameter of
the function which is the parameter that
defend the writing of the variable this
allows us to embed in the faction
modifiers that of our choice sovereign
since check TP allows us to access the
pointers in the stack that would be the
bug and now I'll change over to mono
who will tell us how to exploit that
vulnerability to execute remote code in
the server where the binary is written
as I said before the back was a
formatted string within the V print F
family which was the function that we
were given my mo to expect the bug was
to take advantage of two primitives so
we have a writing primitive and reading
primitive in the server production DSA
all our was not live was not enabled so
when there were Sun leaks okay we could
exploit them for the rest of the
addresses and actually the exploit that
we developed will work even if the SI
and our would be enabled so therefore to
overcome the bypass ASL herb we used a
reading primitive we and then we
calculated the necessary these
placements to write the return address
of the handler which is a vulnerable
function and then we overwrite reading
we have a rosy descriptor of the socket
so therefore we had a loop
was really impassive data on an ongoing
basis the descriptor was overridden with
a different number a number that was not
open so we could break that and we could
end up in the return address and then we
also use J Lib libc Shakur so we entered
the clip BC address and then we took
advantage of any symbol that we found
and then with a writing primitive as I
said before we launched an attack of
written we wrote down the return address
in the stack of in the stack system to
overwrite that with the system address
and then we introduced the argument
which was in this case the reverse
function because we forget into the
return address we did return of the
socket so it was closed therefore the
address was no longer active we could
not remap the descriptors no nothing so
the only thing we could do there was
inverse of reverse shell so as we saw
before because it was in the loop it was
reading it all the time on an ongoing
basis we just overeat we overwrite the
socket descriptor and now this is
exploit you can see we are automating
the exploiting system and well it has
been programming Python and you can see
here some witnesses of the format of
direct access and we have the different
leaks from
I see and from stuck and then we move on
to above writing once we have the
addresses leaked then we calculated
sockets and then we do two other
writings so we fast overwrite this stack
frame and then we adjusted this duck and
then we ask the command to be run and we
did also need casts to use the addresses
of address and then well now let us move
on to demo well hopefully it will fail
well now
just okay well we did not solve the
challenge as a competition there was a
technical problem this was a challenge
scoring nine thousand points we just did
not solve it because we had a valid flow
and actually we solved it when we were
coming back home on the plane so this is
exploit this is the address of the
machine to be attacked in the virtual
machine and you can see the address now
okay we will be sending in a net cut can
you see it
but
okay now we move on to exploit as an
argument we use the address that reduced
to listen to net cut okay we also
transfer the port where we started and
then we should be receiving the reverse
shell so we already have a fully
functional shell and this was the
exploit unless we got a random code
execution then we had to read the black
file and we were given this virtual
machine for us to make testings to do
our testings so when you're making an
exploit the first thing that you do is
you test it locally when it works
locally you just launch it against the
server under production you are not
going to launch exploits if they are not
fully functional because if you do that
you may be living logs behind you that
may be later analyzed first you see
develop the exploit locally and then you
launch it to the server in production
we went to debug mode we see how the
elec was loaded we just didn't want the
address to be leaked to find the offset
so we found the formats logs we
calculated the address the displacements
and then we came up we came up to with
the MAC address then we did some
debugging so these are the 21 bytes
we sent in the payload and this is what
what we did to solve the challenge oh
this is the way you solve the challenge
and that's awesome
[Applause]
well actually we thought we'll be here
for half an hour we've been for almost
an hour
unfortunately we just don't have any
more time let us finish with the
official video maybe they're sharing the
experience of Spanish team in London so
probably some of you haven't finished
have you watched the video no many I
have not watched the video okay we play
the video to finish off with our session
[Music]
why No yeah what I mean I'm sorry okay
so we're saying it now we'd like to have
the other members of our team up here to
take a family picture I would like to
request the presence if a person who's
very important who's in charge of all
this event that the Deana she had made
this event reality
[Applause]
bueno M carry on justo cuarenta segundos
my America we just have 46 seconds left
I would have liked to interview and of
the guys but it wouldn't have enough
time perhaps a question from our
audience does anyone want to ask a
question yes I would like to know about
the renovation how many people knock on
your door how many people get in every
year well we were you serious about that
the competition has roads ten people per
team five have to be juniors between 16
and 21 years old and the others from 21
to 25 but in theory position rate is 40%
four people have to be new every day
five juniors and five seniors that has
to be kept
[Music]
you're competing these days in cyber
camp but do have the numbers 150 about
150 people must play wonders no more
questions
does anyone want to say something
they're very shy the captains do the
talking
thank you very much
[Applause]
[Music]