disable people in the country and
it see they seem to be largely ignoring
probably
no pun intended I guess there a silent
majority in in
being so but anyway on so
you may not occur to most people but to
we take talking on the phone
for granny big dick van with Allen we
talk and then
if you were unable to speak because %uh
the
you something on the vocal cords you
whenever I'm not an expert on medical
reasons why people can't hear or speak
but a
if you are unable to speak for some
reason or if you are unable to hear or
if you are
a deaf mute in could do neither on you
couldn't get how could you communicated
with the family would be a very
difficult task obviously
on people who are hearing impaired
online liberating
to on gather information from people
there talking to him but obviously on
the phone
until we have then really good picture
fans in a completely all the way in
about 30 years for that to happen
on in Negril deliberating over the over
the fence out and I don't expect that to
happen anytime
next couple years at least so that
brings us to TD's
yes he's getting old
done the done
yeah
the beans
you is yeppers dams
it doesn't get worse unions your YouTube
their legal
means yeppers new me lose my
dreams
around them be
do not done
me and we'll see the union
so this is it this is a I'll up the
camera this is it
this is a camera pointed at someone's
lips yen
or or did he shortly universal sign
language which which you speak in
him limited if the person is
you smiling yes okay the would
million is a woman who was living on the
other side
you due mid looms on the lips
loans well i pictured below the picture
with the phone against the plant
remains I need a whole facial expression
rain
less interesting I see there's new
developments in this field time in
India and the next witness fielded you a
little bit about it and since nobody
else is talking about tonight on a
I be take the opportunity to do it non
there's a gentleman is explained their
people working on the other technologies
with with the
eliminating the need for rent typing
which TD's use in actually visually
be you'll do lip reading everything but
obviously we were playing a significant
expense on on the the party the people
very soon worms
using mine you know
much greens which is most existing
vaccinated
much green Albert and gives information
on after that
after the end the target I I'd like to
have been anyway
getting on on the did mean subjected to
the most
commonly no common method used for
hearing and speech impaired people to
communicate with 10
where these DVD's telecommunication
devices for the deaf and they involve
basically typing information just like
Greece typing on a computer keyboard
and those your appeal familiar with no
10's on know that
now when you typed on your keyboard
these characters
each an individual code usually it's
called an ASCII code
in ASCII code you converted into d
what could be referred to as musical
tangale in San very musical they changed
very
variable pitches and audio tens gets
into the thin line in there
decoded at the other end in
reconstructed into the letters ABC
industry
G well learn telecommunication devices
for the deaf had been around a lot
longer
then PCs and in fact and me earlier
non telecommunication devices with F
we're simply
mechanical teletype machines which had
been around since the beginning
and the premiere in the twenty years or
so teletype machines keenan
non when the most popular in TD's back
in
thirty years and was called AT&T a model
make manufactured by a teletype
corporation Indian for those in
those in the audience who might be ham
radio operators you're probably familiar
with that particular machine because it
was in
on he was used by Western Union
frequently in in in
when the upgraded to be models like the
mild 33 kill time machine
all these things hit the surplus market
nearby and I'll 15 teletype machine for
next to nothing can use it as a computer
printer before a computer printers were
affordable when you had to build your
own PC for free by one in a storm
anyway on the most modern a
TD's now are much more compact in the
old mechanical
nineteen eighties it passed mom the ones
the username really don't have any
moving parts aside from
the keys which is in the keyboard is
opposed to the old mechanical tell
typewriters which
literally weighed in 50 to 100 pounds
and had
100 years in letters in you played
boiling in the word extremely noisy I
guess it would buy if you're against it
and new word new machines are quite
compact type happen to bring
my DVD with me manufactured by AT&T
this is the model 29-30 it still
currently manufactured the
but again for the past three years I
think a I paid about $250 dollars for
this at an AT&T prime next door
on you can see that it looks like a
standard computer keyboard although it's
not a
business culture keyboard like a lot of
us are used to typing on its
it said for those with you have been
dealing with computers long it remember
the in
get regional PC junior in the peanut non
they had a flat chick lit a keys it has
that kinda keyboard
and devoted ATT expressed a concern to
me that
nom some some users in this particular
device
founded found it difficult to type on I
don't at all but I guess in
some people who more didn't have a lot
of manual dexterity mike hasn't
difficulty typing this keyboard but
there is a tactile feedback and a
there's a two-line
liquid crystal display a 40 characters
prize you totally characters
units automatically switch roles to the
next line non
the way it hatches to your telephone is
edited is acoustically coupled which
means it it is there's no electrical
connection with the phone line
you need to plug in any cords or
anything and
the handset the telephone simply in
rests on the topic then
but the device for those who view member
from the early days a PC Sen
when millions were acoustically coupled
in you would stream along in
110 or maybe even three hundred died non
a you can remember hearing the the tens
and waiting for the carrier in hanging
the phone up in handset well
it's still down with the ladies because
if you're a if you leave your house or
something you have a portable TD
if you're going to pay for me for
instance in there's not a GD building in
the paper and there's no connection to
plug into
but Every Phone anybody uses has
handcent
the you can this is this a gold medal
regular phantom hands in any way you
could just
plotted on here in a good p.m.
determines the type on the keyboard
are the Dickey happen he were to convert
it determines
which bill into the microphone up the
defend your pollen from
and the change from the person on the
receiving end to the this
message not or heard by the earpiece and
your family
drink translated by the computer in the
device into text you see in the screen
you know what and getting back to work
did I mention about pavements
be not too long ago I remember the exact
number years but I think to three or
four years ago maybe no one was the ADA
funny but again 1990
okay on the American said war-making
Americans with Disabilities Act McHale
I'm gonna go over a couple things that
do
some mandates some federal laws that
were passed that required
that GTE be made available in public
places and
some the details on our not a quote in
here
not it's the law if an interior public
page 11
is provided in a stadium or arena in a
convention center
in a hotel with a convention center
warren et Concord mall
at least one interior public text
television
shall be provided in a facility in by
public text telephone referring to
TD telecommunications the nation again
in
in regards to when healthcare facilities
the lies States
give a public pay telephone is located
in or adjacent to a hospital emergency
room
possible recovery room were hospital
waiting room one public text telephone
more GTD shall be provided at each
location
and the churchyard issue here today July
26 1991
dispensed in finally the last eight if
an interior public payphone is provided
in a transit facility at the train
station a bus station
at least one interior public text
telephone shall be provided in the
station
anywhere four or more public payphones
serve a particular
entrance to rail station in at least one
is
in is an interior location at least one
public text till 10 shall be provided to
serve entrance
so the bottom line is done federal llame
requires on %uh shopping malls train
stations hospitals
to provide text telephones RTD's
and whether or not they have
hearing-impaired people that do work
there or visit there that just as the
Lady gonna be there
just like in we intend to be in building
seven for wheelchair access num
Meneghini wheelchair people but you can
have the Rams their hands it's a good
idea
bun one of the people many people here
have noticed that the public
GTE's but did if you notice said
what you'll notice often is a it is a
payphone or a sign near the payphone
that looks like a telephone handset
happy to sign with a few
white squares underneath which had a
copy love to hear this addition
international logo did
symbolizes TD's in a basically looks
like a telephone handset with
three rows and awake he's under its
urban a white on black logo
and that its to symbolize the Ltd is
available this facility
often I found in a hearing impairment
just find this interesting
up of a knife and did whoever manages
whenever facility is whether to
shopping mall owner hotel whatever they
don't have that he teased out they did
have a sign saying
if you need one of these come to this
flooring see someone and measure whether
they complied with all are not but it
seems to be the norm the
and they are really out in the open in
most cases one
yet had a question yeah I'm company I'm
gonna touch on it yet
on he'd mentioned as something I did you
bring up on
did in some facilities where it may not
be immediately obvious that there's a GD
available
on you might notice that sum up a tent
Heather
an extra on middle shelving to the
bottom it may be a foot deep
or maybe ten inches deep underneath in
is a red light and from it
and that near me not usually will have a
sign about it saying
TD telephoned you can use is a regular
pay them but what happens is
if you pick up the phone and I'll a
number it reaches a GD
the pain the pavement will be checked
that term rationally TDM underneath it
that Finn with detected in automatically
slide out on a motorized rumors and most
people don't even notice these DVD's
because they're hidden underneath the
pavement and
if you ever wanna c1e 3 yourself a good
way to do that is to
work at 12 these public text telephones
saying there's no one who's your
during a speech in here waiting to use
it on
and dial this number email me take this
number down it said
800 be 55
in 11 55
that is a national on AT&T
operator services number four hearing
and speech impaired people who are using
TD's
if you call that number you'll hear he a
term
mom the kinda sounds like a modem 10
although
bien you can very clearly here
a a ship between two different pitches
high and low pitch
send very very slow compared in the end
the militant entries to hear me
specially at fourteen at four which is
just like a
a buzz yeah you can say some things
yeah I'm gonna beat me touching on as
well yes the year that did
the National number for ATG operator
services
for GTD users is one eight hundred eat
1159 everyone in this room can try
discount
by going to %uh a facility where there's
a public pay telephone
up South Street Seaport Penn Station
understand very people have answering
plate is there they're wearing
on maybe this hotel I don't know but
name I would
I would think that may be required at
Headingley probably had an engine they
had to pull out a shelf or whatever they
do
but in any case %uh if you call that
number you hear it and then if you're in
a public pay telephone and it has a TD
catch to it
now in most cases it's it similar to
write or they will slide out and you'll
see something like this
facing usually the cleaning stainless
steel unit down which is
looks like it's a indestructible when
you're done making the call it XD tend
to stop any
slide back in but if you have a home
telefony you obviously don't have to
wait for anything that slide out because
you you had this device in here in
I'd mention it but this particular unit
balled up just like a n
that the size VHS videocassette you
recharges
I guess you can get about mmm two or
three hours of continuous use any
minutes
it's kinda battery 100 he's gonna try to
pitch frequently
bomb I wanted to touch on a
the fact that you can if you don't have
access to any
a regular GTE that you can you can
access some of the services now
with the regular computer modem I'm not
all services
they are provided tttt users are
accessible by
not by regular modem and the reason for
that is TD's traditionally have used a
need
not telecommunications who'd we're most
familiar with help me he's called
called kill me she told me she killed
her called ASCII an american Standard
Code for interment Information
Interchange
well this is the worst that was
developed I believe
in the late sixties and early seventies
prior to that done
there other co DEP said it but my dad
the main
telecommunications code for sending text
with something called Blondell
and it's a named after French researcher
the
a lot of people dispute that he is this
guy written will
called the Marie Curie the bottom line
is it's a
it a5 maker is opposed to ask you which
is a7 be candid
and %uh it only supports uppercase
your Jones
is actually here Jan
alleged that's true that'd it
it issued oh it's a shooter a to pseudo
on
upper and lower case characters that is
a a notice to correct it here
on it's a throwback from the days when
these were mechanical machines
on with the way they got around he not
having his upper case is
they would have won code it would tell
the machine
temple teletype machine to shift on
a budget this and you said you seen that
would rival or said
the character so if you got occurred to
say
go uppercase then everything from then
on the upper case we know they got
another code to be all lower-case
but generally speaking mostly users
didn't bother with the
with the upper lower cases you the
machine in supporter whenever but
the bottom line isn't and ASCII
is not compatible still with some TD's
because it's a seven because
good in the data rates are different on
nationally with then
and won't make a deal with bill 103 East
and you just 300 blind
virulent NY's bit managed to achieve
which is 12 ani: bodin
the although the whole slew the dow
whenever not protocols which were 2400
bodin
you were up to 14 foreign me at 34 now
they're all incompatible with
with some the older GATT's and on
you were finding more more services now
accept both
an ASCII now and and body okay this
particular
the machine supports both 300 by Danske
and my Dell in the butt and abide rate
by the way and I don't
is forty five and a half mile if that
sounds really slow
it is but it still ABI not much
slower than an average person can read
am it doesn't it's not cheap under a
semi somebody's typing is because they
can a 45-minute by
it doesn't seem like you're me tapping
fingers but
it's certainly not what we use to $49.4
million to the screen filling up almost
instantaneously me know what you mean
FN's anyway so it doesn't really think
people who were
using its just for casual conversation
in
there's another thing I wanna touch em
briefly nets a machine called tele
braille
which I just found out about recently
maybe even into me he didn't explain but
tell the realtor been
marines okay the most common for you to
tell me I just found out about it
this afternoon I was really is like
hotel a real something I never heard at
it's really not a TD but its it's for
blind
yet news word their mention
lesions
that
dead 1
year you're just just blindly noon
no any homes but bave
room
%uh yes God be
really ins uncanny to be something
similar to this but with with the Rays
diets they would move across the display
yes okay I guess I'm not sure how to do
that mechanically but
might take your word for it did una
so the seems
though none and you know that has really
interesting Logie
min me she actually can have a telephone
conversation by dissenting
something with your fingers and if you
got to do with that way then
its not so bad because it's anything yet
so on
I'll mention some other telephone
numbers you can try calling
on I did mention that the main director
service number for the
free 18g for different TD's which is 808
551 155 the
you can call the AT&T special needs
center
18 she has a special division at the
company dedicated
yes to people with the special needs
such as
a hearing and speech impaired people
were may be blind people as well
they had problems tell communicating in
in
I need special services are more
products
and a number free 18g special needs said
the police number is 800
233 12
to do and ATT number they've set up for
the ATT special needs center is 800
833 32 to reach you
and there's another service made
available
on by the various bell operating
companies I believe
called in really services you know you
may know someone who is hearing impaired
or speech impaired
but you don't own a GTD you want to run
it up a fan with you is one
he's gonna come from your home is still
a way you can communicate with them
and in a disused when these relay
services which are again required by
by federalized the bill at many
companies provide the services
and in my area in Pennsylvania and I
just call this number
here for my cycle tonight I carriers ice
in this bitch ballot in New York as well
the two the toll-free number 800 654
59 he'd for will connect you with the
relay services
yet
the
yeah if you look at the beginning your
own your telephone book where has all
information like
had I'll family stuff like that it has
that information in your usually
in if you're not sure on call Datt
special needs center no
they will point you in the right
direction and was sayin
means
min your moved
I G moon storms
he is decidedly the bloody be
31 sure yeah he doesn't do
this unit doesn't really know if it's
sending information to a phone or nine
you know to be heard something but in
had a disappointing injures now is
demonstrating summer
my radio surveillance equipment at my
table over here
and speech impaired person came up to me
and he saw that any new ones because
he'd each obviously he's gone before
he started writing a message to me as a
no no use this and
to be typed messages to me that he is
that he was a
his death and that he/she uses a TD and
immigration
so you can type messages on this town
it's kinda like a being on a computer
done a communication software in local
mode where
every type character you type is just a
good back on the screen on
thats that happened to this jury he take
type the letters the appear in the
screen in
for those of you who did not hear that
actually sounds like I will let you hear
watchin debido 10 sound like
you can have some more might gain in
this is what I T descends like
over the fam
do hate message I just
I just typed wasn't this is coming to
you from
the hoop conference on anybody hoopin
check that out by year-end I happen to
be ham radio operator images hidden
all forms of communications and then
I can tell by year mom whether it's by
do
um at forty-five in half by to ask you
to 110
he discounted other forms of
communications to go over shortwave
radio the
really tell it even support you can tell
from disrepair how it sounds like butts
beat it and so forth on
there are people surprisingly who can
you can is a more stamina
him real african pin and understand
Morse who don't you like forty some
words a minute
unit that is always needs me I'm lucky
if I can do
1819 and that's another met the people
can
you can use it communicate if they don't
know if they can speak
admits getting off the subject
the models at AT&T cell ATT seems to be
the biggest
provider these although any be we stand
corrected and then
here Linda bien and I know that a lot of
companies that make his bed
motion we p.m. yet
wanna will be a good source for finding
out about
other other right beside con ATT special
needs in addition Agnes and elsewhere
where can one find out about other other
devices from other companies
the your center yes
my in delaware yeah
di dati in delaware yeah
on the phone yeah and you look
billion Wii the pages added telephone
directory
your jeans you know
me this is usually state agencies yes
okay the ginger CNN you
%eh for you know these exist in in most
states uncanny
you had it Cummins
9 sign language school me
yeah I'm
done
great yes
peach he kinda have to if you're not
already
involved with the whole culture mom
then you have to seek this stuff down
yen I can decide to download acres and
is interested maybe
possible for communications but dead as
says
the people in the audience and you if
you if you hung around make some phone
calls in
and be contacted in a school for the
hearing impaired her speech impaired and
blind to
and whenever you might really get some
leads us to where you can find in a
reason price device
may be there the item I sure but there
may be a market for these
for use devices as well I don't know
people with I would assume that one
upgrade
nom from one mild another just like
people upgrade computers only
but there have to do is really is that
we in the computer area have to
on I did mention that somebody services
can be accessed by and by
a normal computer an open to give you
the technical details
and how to do that you gonna need a
standard PC communications package
with a modem that communicates and at
least and
300 behind I Donnelly the money and I
know
hmmm I did mostly services communicate
when they commit when they are
compatible with Angie communicated
either
300 1200 2400 with I make fallback if
you need a 300 baud modem
on the in I
the settings you want is a communication
software or aid
data bits no parity
and one stunt bij a check engine the
in me the submenu communication software
to enable the flow control
and you also want to choose enable
the exponents of protocol all those
things are important
if you don't have and aidid its new stop
it
carried it emits no parity 1 stop it on
oh and it has to be having duplex in for
God and that
it's very important must be half duplex
you have to use flow control
you have to have your exon exon enabled
then if you call for instance that 808
551 155 number
with your computer his type if he hadn't
he's compatible million needed from them
from the N in the black medications be
my guess you could just take then
a TD and TE if you have a 10
no damn I GTG 185 I woman 55
and then after the modem dials you'll
you hear carrier tune in and you'll be
connected
and the way that works it's kinda
interesting on
you'll be connected with an operator who
has won the CD is generally there
on I've just from communicating with
them doing well social engineering I
found
motor them are not disabled it just down
making hearing in you can speak the dish
is just the job with AT&T year the
library company have been work in
on what I find is really strange is
dad the the operators you handle
directory assistance
services like looking a telephone
numbers for you batt
um aren't lead in any kinda computer
system
they have and I finest is sometimes you
to call you get
you get it I love it outside a
Philadelphian is a big central office
near a live in Wayne Pennsylvania
and but there's a need a TD office near
where the band
directory assistance services for the
hearing impaired I have taught you TT
operators in washington
in North Carolina in other areas he just
it's just
be look at the dryer when you call that
number depending in
the traffic patterns at the
telecommunication system you get ready
to wherever the
they have people available but there
when I find earnings earnings a with
time running his
on AT&T bills itself as you know then
the company in the future and you will
experience this in and whenever in the
future
yet they're still using and and
manual telephone directories at the
siege
at these offices Emanuel phone books for
the Rangers them on a shelf
and another telephone which
if they can find in the phone book what
they'll do is they'll say please hold on
tight they won't say it is the type in
please hold while we look at your number
and you hold when they pick up another
phone
incall a regular voice Directory
Assistance Operator
and alas that information over them
and then type that in in the whole
process takes a good minute
which is I find it almost excruciatingly
slow
on is now I can you call regulations
just get rescissions operating his type
he struck he started the back nine
usually in
and any to connect with an automated way
to tell you the number well
PD users unfortunately had to suffer
through this awkward painfully
slow in technologically non
and anachronistic the method where
they don't have on-line computers
international the operators
why don't you have some sort of online
system work you know you had the ttttt
integrated with a directory assistance
terminal like to regulatory agencies
Japanese it
now we don't know the justices our job
in whenever I found
furman from a hacker stamp on a hacker
that the TD operator
are often much more on %uh
6f to build a social engineering then a
regular operating because
they have really boring jobs evidently
they don't get a lot in they don't get a
lot of calls
so what you can have some pretty
interesting conversations with the
city's average despite having a TD
and what are the other advantages I
found two weren't using ATT
is that said it's a toll free number
when you call
on directory assistance view this as
opposed to
Delhi won the area code and number um
we have to pay 75 cents now yes recently
than last year
on they said over in protest after this
week these people shouldn't be getting
free
ATT decide if they should be getting
free n jettison services
sell at they put in a handy and any an
iron
NEC type system whereby they knew who
was calling
any wrote something down whenever the
like two months later you get this bill
in the mail attended this addendums your
phone bill like the back and a half
now from all the lies that I read
they're not legally allowed to charge
you
more than the going rate for graduation
services yet
the times I've done it be tried in like
a dollar in hand I'm always call them
and then
complained in something I'm times have
been had asked her she providers are
going to take it off my bill ni had
so I found a way around that n only
reason I'm saying is it because they're
B&D been jerks about this so what I've
done is
you can eliminate having to deal with
the automatic
identification %uh giving your phone
number up in every holly hunter number
for Jimmy don't know whenever you call a
toll-free number
pretty appalling will know your phone
number you know they'll know immediately
if they have the right equipment
will know within a month when they get
there there what's bill so
be aware that the privacy standpoint
budget one way around on
one way around the this exorbitant fee
that AT&T is trading is he just dial
zero until the operating
operator have been trying to Dallas toll
free number and I can't seem to get it
get any answer
on can eat right for me to see what's
number and its 800 even if I 1155
and I'll try and into your range say
Thank You operator and you hang your
phone up in here in
in they need you prices your call the
operator will that point
ask you for on you
if we want to work contact every the
number the persons name the person whose
number you want
YouTube channel name city in name and
city in central SQ regular season
but then if you call to the operand
found they will let ask you
what number you calling from so when I
have frequently don't just give them the
number my local
on AT&T office YouTube who evidently
gets the bill
so that suggest desserts as far as I'm
concerned you're gonna add something
your own
the last week twice one
on
damn it I may be in your party any be
nynex policy I'm I'm from
null ankle and so met you may be right
about that for this area
your
be yeah
yea
that's pretty lame at nine exactly as
you can see I had the a the t-shirt x9x
and a former nynex employees
done
yeah
your own
on go figure well if if they re either
way I look at it as if they're gonna
charge exorbitant fee then
I'm gonna find a way around it and if
they charge a fair fee I would mind
me you have a family to your home you
want to go at a payphone define ATT
dances as to if you've got a long
distance directors as a group a found
a normal value that way Sam with three
questions anybody had about 20
one question I want to ask the audience
I know there are special number set up
for
emergency services like the you hearing
people
gene people can call 911 for that system
I know New York area there's another
number you can call
I think the three digit number gonna 311
okay if you call 311
from a cellular phone an order from a
Senate run from it
for many found you'll get a TD operator
on
the TD emergency operating sure they've
set up the system's and
wright also found 9
to Emanuel's he called me with this an
interesting tape recordings are some
time
fan messages in me what I said they send
ittt messages he played them over the
phone to me
night despite held the phone up to
tonight he dnt
and we were able to decode messages
pretty interesting one last thing I want
to say is
did with the way did that one advance to
the lower speed
by Bill forty-five it had not being as
it does require carrier like
were used to using a I'm no dams you can
you can record
and these TD messages on in answering
machine
and so many can play them back in
decoding visit audio tones voicemail
systems you could leave the
messages for for people on a voicemail
system Batt's I've done in actually
found it is sorta
accrued but sir to the effective
security method
up leaving leaving messages an average
person
like leases know exactly what it is an
admitted he did he and wouldn't you know
I wouldn't
say there's some real and away they
couldn't figure it out but on
you can leave the message on voicemail
Ranger machine with ATT
and the person who retrieved them can
get hold it GTE
and up to the speaker each machine it
will decode and display on the unit so
on that has ended and he couldn't do
that with it with computer type:
on message has militancy night in if
they don't take a carrier to hang up
really
Sam any questions about ATT's it might
be able to answer
yung's
oh yeah it's something now they kinda
full back on a little bit but to
ya the folks might have earned the worst
damage in addition
okay on idiot for those are your 26
return to sender readers many you
probably are you would be here
on and you've probably seen these AT&T
or read about the AT&T 2000 founded the
public you pay found
the day looks very futuristic there's a
there's a color video display on in a
keyboard in all this
well those things some are combination
regular ASCII computer terminals and
TD's am
evidently there are some ruling a few
months ago
that form forbade I ATT from
from having the the ass keep are there
to work anymore
as a regular telephone limit in didn't
go with certain tariffs or something
but you can still use these is a std's
however I found
the nail you on a charge every time you
can even you cannot call
the you cannot call the toll-free
director his number
on 808 551 552 on
from Wendy's it won't work my baby email
you the operator comes on and says
or that did then ten types you know
please deposit the money or whatever
sanam
I'm sorry so that I guess the answer I'm
sure the ass for credit card number
rate she can even use a red box a happy
admin
yet to give the card number hmm out yet
yes
the usual
I'm dats I that's something I have I
have
stated AT&T on me to call an 800 number
you should not be a charge get it it
said
toll free number i mean that's the whole
definition any numbers call the
toll-free number yet
if you call 808 551 552 operator
who types images back to you when you we
answered actresses information
at no point anywhere says it is any
charge involved calling us 8
this toll-free number and by too much
let you get this delayed
but gonna have charge and every time a
disputed that's the rational I beauty
and
you that I call the toll-free 800 number
and water discharge was never informed
there is a charge
now you'd heard there are some some lar
something you could not charge for
calling her number
yett doing this to us in the
we'll mother be hii
were moon Miley lawn
your mood that day UK he didn't like
going home with the dog barking midnight
tude the be though
we can you to clipper ship they don't
mine at you think the regionally
yeah he is by the way we demonstrate
leadership tomorrow
he even possibly yours is Justin's
go home health care yeah I think we
probably all agree that no but no human
being can go do it single day without
that making some losses hung in her
written consent it's just a legislator
year and something else yeah but you
have to rate only got it you
you got it you have to go through one or
two levels up I would enjoy it because
yeah I don't give up and they had they
can hang up on you
so I got him you know they're is our
talk with him for an hour to get it off
but they're not allowed to hang up on
you and if they do I
before I before Ian as I initialize the
conversation I get their name
so whenever you get somebody's new
special operators name first
they will never be rude to your hand is
a No
you can call the supervising get them
fired or leasing a lot of trouble
sold you read something years
there
didn't no unfortunately on
there would be a good idea I wish
someone would come up with in sort of an
all all in one solution known he'd asked
whether you can use one of these things
to send
text message issued his new alphanumeric
pagers which I'm not unlike not lucky
enough to have been
by the display page just regular digital
sleep later know there is a device a
company called
at page entry PA GE a PA GE
NGR why I believe a toll-free number to
call them they make a little calculator
size device
that can be used to send text messages
and faxes surprisingly can take message
in all come at a fax machine
or send messages to a I a text pager
with now with the advent of digital
signal processing technology coming
becoming mainstream somebody could
easily are now without too much
difficulty something like ATT could
easily design
a device that could send messages to
text pagers which would be valuable to
hearing-impaired people who think
and send by Delon & scheme education
but they haven't come out much this is
really a I'll
hugely profitable market since ron is
you would think
you think big mouth establish twenty-two
million people but damn I need these
things that
they just don't come seem to come out
with the with things that people want
generally yeah be
I'm sorry 1
bottom motto modems him
by I'm I'm sorry and i cant usually seen
were zone there were some bottom modems
listen about a million Leanne
oh yeah oh yeah before you know it's
true mom before Ashley caught on yet
yeah do it also did bottom yeah
that was one of the best modems didn't
ever made I still think that
thank John Draper for that done
a bad bono's just it is a way of saying
ASCII but it's referring to a different
telecommunications code
botella body was in a moment french guy
who
still who came up with this code again
Schneider now but it's use a bodily
referring to
if I did telecommunications co di unlike
ask you which is 70 telecommunications
hey
but if that does make sense you go to
library looking at his
they can explain it better than i can.
the book yeah
he asked if you call from a payphone in
any give that number
they say did they say they can build up
a pen I don't know I've never tried to
get in the paper member I usually in the
number my local AT&T of its
you're not a call to an opportunity 9
demand yes
yeah that's a good question I have not
done that if you dial
a dish from a regular pay found with one
of these things that eight
hundred-number
on ostensibly on I don't know whether
they would ask you the number
bombard your home or whether they were
just as early as bill that
that PIF mm I don't know that's a good
question never tried it
yeah well answer phone down
yes mines
young he tried a number union
hun homes
d
down
when I'm done
brain larvae but
me
oh yeah I'm glad you touch on it yeah
there's there's there's were called
human TTT protocols a little
abbreviations which on
which make it easier for people say
message without having a whole word
there he said he saw things I said GA on
the screen when he tried it
GA meet is an abbreviation for go ahead
it means like I'm done taking his line
now you reply on heey becomes normal
only talk even hell intimated in a sense
the waiver by the beach typing something
you type go ahead
another there may be other little
niceties like that but one other I
discovered he said
at the end of the communication on heey
you type SK SK SK was any
stocky okay snogging okay I T I thought
it would
I didn't know what it meant but it but I
you that I just it is that
invention why the rather %uh little
conventions used for typing that
and money
a learn
okay sometimes you can't add it seemed
people will take a hit into the line 78
a go-ahead
yeah
irate some CDs do not provide a quick
question mark character
so wet me take you kill and I notice
some other directors just operators use
the QC said a question marks and that's
it that's probably good
great I guess they they use it
lowest-common-denominator
that make sense I'm gonna had to leave
your game over I'm expanding our past my
time but
I'll take one more two more questions
that appeared
my
DES him
in
yeah
on
it's a ham radio program call him
competent 8 a.m.
see %um p is a public demeanor is it
see him calm is it's ever sailors
appellate to me
yeah
that's great I've been looking for
something like that and I will
communicate
on it like 45 in half by Badeaux
a bet you still have to build some kind
of a part where to place them
years the just said like an XR 2211
shaper something I would
I am bomb is there a particular magazine
article that detail how to do that the
year
aware really that's that's great you can
build your own
wannabes with the public domain software
package and the text instructions in
their
had using an other lobbying to to make
your and so and I do that myself just
for the challenge
ham Commons
a contact your local Ham Radio Club if
you know where to get than 0.3
right direction yeah even
the great idea eat so many program HP 48
calculated utte work that's fantastic I
can have to go yet one more question
yummy he on
that
bombings yes
yes you can do that unless it's a pay
phone the doesn't accept incoming calls
on and some love the some other pay
phones that have a huge question was can
you can you call
a pay phone has a TD from another TD
and will it answer on Cocotte says we're
promising this year where
you can't accept calls echo cuts because
you can there's there's
readers ten reasons for that but on
I'm sorry Union when when when
your dad I usually have a have a light
world
room
yellow on a paper and yet there that
soon as there's a red light
is a red light on the front of the
keyboard on a on the front the keyword
or any public
paid TD fans and when it's when it's
raining if it's a bell
you know bill operating are in our box
fan on
you see this light flashing along with
along with the reigning
she can actually see it raining but if
the coke I
is not gonna take incoming calls
regardless whether GATT finite is a coke
I
so be whenever I gotta go thanks for
your time and
like good