this is the uh... smaller
satire
already has
absent
prestige in jeopardy right
arthritis missing as well
well you know nothing about it
yes
sir
sketching everything
training really hard as a
glossary of irregular
but nevertheless they
voice to those boys
off
bernard's esquire
travail
mia
is the writer
lady rendell
sitting down university this summer
hostile acts
yes it is that
studied
biscuits
license
mental hygiene
he's here sar
and see if i have a little earlier
announced he is a hollywood directors
is always the threat right
roosevelt back east
designator
talking about
eastern is great actors
businesses have reasonable
barbara vital signs touched on something
very soon
basically
well even the challenges
lantos already ease policy
participants the words
our at issue here
solace
starts here
star anise they have a sense
his life
soon
that anyway
yes uh...
it's at
anyway
total
one issue
better there
taxes not so much technological stuff
what's interesting about hackers fifties
itself
packing freaking as a subculture that's
where i came from a story about writing
um...
about
i started reading music criticism
ide became
increasingly disinterested with that
convinced it was really exciting
in terms of subculture of activity in my
generation
was uh... cultures a worker incoherent
talking specifically
and up
but once i got to know the cultural
better
eve the realtor problematic
i dealt with writing about
this is walking
between
making a case for the breakthrough
too difficult for the right of the
subculture to exist
the subculture that civilians
you know i would like to
you know you all know that
hackers are
all twelve of their mothers are
wonderful people
of
but uh...
established a summing hackers are human
beings like everybody else but the
problem is writing about them takes
place
we have a general atmosphere of total
misunderstanding and fear and terror
and
too right
the subculture does it really is
is problematic because he'll just be
skiing into these prejudices against
them and you won't really
make the case for the support of it says
no i believe that the suppose
resurrected system needs to exist
because i'm interested
for one thing some of the political
implications of subculture
he decided to break through corporate
barriers
information hierarchy sam
of listen up
controls information
dedication
planted in this increasingly information
based citing army
actress
are generally is interested in these
political questions as some of us
journalists are
side some of you are here
tonight up
nonetheless for those reasons i think
it's important for the same
exist
well i think it was
advocacy journalism
i support for the hacker subculture
i try to present it
as accurately as possible
but when it comes down to a i'm making a
choice to be
hackers sympathetic
this early proactive
at least sent them
in the best like that i can
amicus or just because i hear a lot you
know it but it is a lot of suspicion
patrick community and
rightfully so
but there's a kind of attitude alike
you know one of the justice system where
we are going on
also
and it's not
you know it's difficult lately
present he works at all
and just illustrate presentation people
are gonna hitler out there will always
prejudice against acting retain their
discovery into that
whether prejudices are already so we
have to make a case for the n_
and that also pittsburgh pa one do you
all
to also make a case for some time to sit
there and pictures
just few out information
to outline and spew out information any
immediately at that comes along
or on the other hand totally not talk to
anybody about the council on his cut
that copy
uh... there's talk about this now
on the one hand it's real dogmatic
meteorologists thanks
until the other hand he noticed a case
uh...
hackers who will just
religious
spewed out all kinds incriminating
information
yet reporters have never talked to david
never seen before anything that's
certainly know that there really report
is not just here for hours in a lot of
business and that
you have to develop more sad attitude
towards towards dealing with the press
not just
on the one hand
yet they're all
uh... creates a transaction hahaha
and or on the other hand that you know
you can just present the information
once the information gets out there and
everybody will know it wonderful thing
hacking freaking is and how wonderful
you people are and
you know you're right to exist will be
guaranteed for life
you guys develop kind of setting i
developed the kind of political attitude
about making
making changes for yourselves
i don't want to honor
or past my
dot blot questions afterwards
do you ask him
i am
despite his denials helpful questions
i'm not sure exactly
uh... what kind of questions you guys
want me to answered so
let's let's leave it up
what my expenses for
off a bit
actors and and
more planted asking questions of the
country
uh... i first
what what is difference between the
infants mother
tells us that apparently done much in
the last
three four years
partly that's because i'm
none of the computer report
sorta like giulio myself
lam reporter much more as a reporter on
cultures and groups
when i first became interested in them
attackers was
in nineteen eighty nine twenty two
about sent a pic of major point six
hundred and
sign up for the world
concern exploring both of those worlds
the first thing that it was around an
editor of harper's magazine immediately
form
in february nineteen ninety
which we got a lot of
with largely with meals help to get a
lot of
people on the well
together to discuss
when we get it was his computer hacking
chronic and attend a four
online
in which another
discussion try to ask questions and see
if there was such a thing to happen
spreads the word of the people drew the
line
this uh...
this belongs mostly pins permanently in
nc
to people who would go on to the
even bigger figures need capital
fiber-optic and john perry barlow
who uh... sort of had a generational
uh... war going on
it led to
claim the topic with basically no
different from here
escape order
immediately after that optic
grabbed his credit rating t_r_w_
download it can be informed
that there was a bit of difference
between the skateboard
so an indian
but not to mention answered
that i was very different way too
present packers
i think works just because we let
talk in the worst read
interfered very
behavior as little as possible
opposition of most of the words that
ended up in that article
so that we hope it was
you guys into words because we just
use your own words
the fundamental of
teenage computer hackers
started hanging out with them
try to figure out more about what lead
someone
at a young age to watch
started reading this article
from amman jacket
and
basically what we did was sort of
apprentice ourselves to these two guests
and got them to teach us
everything that
possibly understand what happened
remain very there was that
uh... work
miles ahead of us and most the time we
just
we're trying to get them to slow down if
we could
we can keep track of it
we hung out with him for a long time
coming up from july three months
thomas the time we were having dinner
with them
figured system security specialist
informs us tonight
uh... and it was a explained was what
they were doing why they were doing
comment over the course of that
we sort of learned
we we can to some conclusions but why
why they were doing some conclusions
that they should have had come to
themselves
and we will make it to psychoanalyze
a bit was that
that's what it means for me
packers this money to uh... to
contributions to the day
really the only thing that valentine's
day fifty two
to stay with you and said that
thing and while i'm here with the
national public radio reporter here
talking to a few people
yesterday
something
missile strikes me watching people
there were a couple talker ferguson
photographers study lined up for some
people in bethlehem
and uh... and indian people taking
pictures
they really seem to be a
despite despite the fact that you and
said that that there's this
content and you better
it was a real feeling of black when the
partnership for peace
smiled
but that they're going to get stressed
by the media
and and i think is a real
there's a real distinction between
different types of
reporters uh... for people that are
going to really listen to
what do you have to say that i
understand the technology trends and
sociology
um... and i think
are gonna write articles that that
health and on her
again
a sixteen-year-old girl here yesterday
told me that he
read my article and got him
more interesting happening
dance high school library and that's
that's the best in the months of
uncertainty but
oracle was absurd
well i was hoping would happen
simply things can come from from
talking terms but
when you get the brawling show
showing up
and uh...
asking if you could break into
defense department computers and
launch i_c_b_m_'s things like that
did you get a bigger pretty early
there's no way
anything good can help
you've gotta keep
you've got a lot of things we don't have
to say nothing signal
companies could really seems like that's
something that
a lot of hackers
knuckles
them to participate in anything
as some people in that can be
gergen
bogelindah
esteemed colleagues on the left
both left your word for it
exert myself to be journalist who say
consider myself to be a brighter
commentator
editorial big mouth
hopefully somewhat entertaining for like
you to meet
crossovers and areas of their dreams as
soon as being
phone companies being the pentagon
whoever socials
uphold retirement system tried to
made some sort of transitions or provide
some material for people to build a
understand what's going on the other
side is an awful lot of
misunderstandings or something going on
and i think also this field but also see
is a great deal of
boring boring writing going on
and entertaining eats and fun
and here's the bottom of a lot of potter
for that as far as i'm concerned
uh... febrile a speech they do in cyber
christ
we'll have some idea of what we're doing
an enormous
that review of this conference will
sacrifice gets nailed to the cross
so hopefully will be the experience of
some of the others have been
but you guys are not the bad guys the
media sometime this week with it that's
our report for america doesn't want to
go for the future and paid usd
acknowledgements contributes to the
personal feelings in the event
immediately rhetoric that
we hear going on
all of the closing sadler sort of some
of the packers mark understand exactly
what to do occurred with fiber optic
couple days africa bust on the latest
round
and i want to talk to him so i
home of the bomb
and because of the same sort of a chat
with you
how to get my phone
the system information
usable stunned of that so we chatted for
a couple minutes and uh...
he said you know when lawyers as i can
talk to you
personal and stand with the case going
down on thirteen of you are supposed to
be
because of many more trouble because you
have an answer
but before we go with the stars one
question
warranted it
four hours on the record conversation
thoroughly enjoyed it
he did not understand
and a lot of
whose fault it does not understand
when people go on a regular army they
don't understand what off the record is
that we don't understand offered what
background is
houston's anonymously let me read to
your onesies and
according to sources will be identified
the blues dot the white house
the same kind of thing you have the same
privileges and rules and quality
journalist quality writers will appear
to those
types of rules regardless of what side
of things you may or may not be wrong
and all of the better writers will
keep confidential your secrets
anarchy confidential the secret of the
pentagon and all the other server level
of people as well
so we will do the same through everybody
but you don't wherewithal ruled really
or
with the issue about
hacking
somehow
business impression of the tracking his
movement
that is so uh... something that's run
last four years or ten years when i do
but i did
i'm craig wintom technologies been
around for a long time
and people have always tried to stretch
technology
and push the edge of it
the difference that we have today versus
the other types
happened prior technological society
connectivity there's a real difference
and when you have the kind of work to do
we have to break the presents the
awareness
is the main different
people always push the edge and we're
pushing the edge of john wooden for
social good
and this is not
something that the media in my opinion
has really gotten right
there's a majority of the new york i
read the stories on the rise of various
factions of the security industry
they didn't want to removes do not have
a technological basis
general no fans with some of my wife to
determine time of the technological
basis to understand
when somebody's beloved children were
not as a possible is it not possible
and i'll give you the most part of
example than our past michael
on january tenth nineteen ninety two
ted koppel
was post tonight
when i was sitting there with my wife
level lathem kids of all that we were
sitting at home at eleven thirty
and he came on to announce
that the united states had won the war
abused and raw
using a computer virus
by both of my life isn't there something
wrong with this picture
and they proceeded to describe how it
works
and what it was
the national security agency in his
infinite wisdom
design a computer virus to go inside but
shipped
which they've engaged in the c_r_a_
socioeconomic salute your trip
designed to take them off
they fly over to france and they find a
french better cos all this fits into
that and they put this ship
with the words into a freshman
the fresh powder
is apparently down three brought one way
or another
and residents but went on this story
with u_s_ news world report
providing will be accurate information
they got the printer to amman jordan
and since it was an embargo that we
won't let the printers with the virus is
through
and they don't know about this printer
into iraqi air defense installation down
near kuwait
so i'll call amanda's before we decide
to send in the cruise missiles to make
right turns of yours you no doubt
we decided
it's time to launch the virus
political forums that go
the fireworks
this is not likely
jobs
uh... of the printer
into
the air defense radar systems protrude
which are running windows three point
lead over
and
and subsequently made welcome
alderson scapegoats
i was bothered by this story
specify what it means that i had some
homework to do and i have a personal
files religious draw out the back my
mind
and suddenly i wouldn't normally
all the iraqi virus hoax
this story word for word point for point
issued particulars fourteen unfolded
documented on whether or not
was written originally by job gains
in the world columnist under people
versus unseemly
it was an april fool's joke
one who becomes the question so i pulled
out the following monday morning after
talking to problems people who disavowed
any knowledge of it
perhaps whatever reporting it
thoughts of the author brian duffy of
u_s_ news world report was that brian
the stands approx what happened
and apparently i sent him something of a
panic holding back two days later he
says we're standing by our story
extractors
presented
where it is your source he goes
tumhala old temple
whatsoever knowledgeable general
somewhat remote will meet up point is
because what we're talking to him on the
left to right be aware of the rule be
aware of your rights that good
journalists will be a good
and ready to start ordering some stories
of your viewpoints burke was right
about changes what should happen is
relatively late
off that
under the head
it's the release of backbeat
last year i was looking at numbers
scripts i didn't think i was in a coma
uh... i had
small pet projects in life
filter all that i was uh... i think that
it off the ground
but the thing that appeals to me about
the script
standout reasonable all the others i was
being offered
uh... screwdriver
of was
inside it
had a sense of humor
that was based on
kindest delinquency
uh...
it had a similar things too
to the movie back beat a dismayed
thing that really appealed to me was
that he was a tough he was a subculture
thirsting for it
pads
really threatening the scottish culture
in a way that
the star has got to move slowly up the
good and evil and was deficits unit but
also the influenced by it
uh... i think that preached generation
what uh...
what is discovering things and you what
is working out
re-routed
uh... working out the rules that you
want to get by
disastrous receives actually concerned
whether it's
drug experimentation or riding
motorbikes in the nineteen fifties or
whatever
it was really from abroad cultural
hooted script but i also
just like the sense that
of polum anand
disrespect the
i think it's very healthy independent
the more i i don't know about
packing helps more i realize that
that sort of
absurdity of the world
right isn't it ridiculous
that antibody costs of this stuff
everybody
shots of the computers either
allowed to leave their life
lullaby and
the money that you say you have your
parents money have you come when
somebody says you have this committed
this crime we haven't had that problem
today
we've got his grade school
request
uh... i think uh...
the mayor of that
acting is hella society is not in using
but as uh...
philip bruce ears but with us
as well
i think
rebuilt
uh...
put on the subject
at the point of view of making a movie
the question that arises as to how picky
treat
a real-life situations
uh... scripts
oversee borrows a lot of relations
and real people
in order the tickets
it's enjoyable and painstaking maybe the
people i can see
um...
but also
that is going to be treated some waiters
subject matter
that's the
the big question that that approaches
thanks people like like me who
wanna make movies based on somewhere
real
uh... i had expressed in that there
isn't really any right old city
granddaughters making backbeat
uh... i love people one of us
runs try to get the thoughts around
accused of a story of fifty stuart
sutcliffe
uh... these meshes with with john lennon
it's very sacred stories
in the sense
very well documents upon real people
work
of the people were alive
a lot of the
uh... the story and document it
but i had to take meetings with with the
facts
one of the things that i
was approaching festival
uh... what i
continual
started to think about researching this
this may be written
draft was
reach do what i do know baki versus
absorb myself as much as i could
the residuals
knowing about title head
he did two years
um...
i may try to use that
knowledge to use
to get the spirit of the baby bells
bearing in mind that sounds good to have
to do
dot thanks for that
so it's really too
two ways that i thought approach
material going to find out what's what's
really out there and then find another
way bridge
it could be presented
for the screen
that is true to that
essence at the same time
takes a lot
ghmo
as a major success how hackers ripped
off the ground originally it started out
with a state of one of the things that
this would be a very much newspapers
that was not
originally developed at studio it wasn't
somebody saying capital port-au-prince
rollerblade movie kids are really into
that
surfing etiquette that came back as a
result really the pictures that all the
way that israel origins were working for
anything when gratify my high school who
was studying mathematics her first year
college trophy
into room in a lot of computers and it
was about
ten o'clock in the evening and every
computer will still and workbooks
and my first reaction was like one of
these people of the nation
and i said to me too
who supported him again and
insupportable role
practice operates competitive games in
everything because it
management everybody and was a big sign
on the walls of no cracking
coddled consequences pretty high
that every monitors doing this work
isn't there some sort of monitors some
things like that he's over there come a
crack in turkey
and that was really sort of the
department uh... and seriously looking
at
everybody
ended at this level of concentration i
think it's a little concentration
great athletes get into the next level
concentration ethnic
dancing to some really great musical or
having great sex or having to do is just
the flow state in that
that is what is starting to realize at
the time to place on that
that's when the germans
we're going to write about
because i i think that the pentagon's
recruiters from character remnant
ultimate movie about a little bit
as time went on in the mornings came out
and i moved to new york and was
always tracking stories about actors
an influential articles point forensic
wasn't even sure that they were very
partial to me in terms of looking at it
as it does it as a subculture
and then wrote the script and and this
request what's called spec scripts
peaking too right
took two months off mike
ships as a bartender in
and hung out with fiber optic and nasa
weakened
and and
for workers and very generous
rivera ideas and the things that they've
been through
and during that time
the start of your growing sense of
responsibility towards the ideas look
like he doesn't think that they think
i do think that uh... his
present you guys that are kind of
advocacy journalism that's good
there was a very management advocacy
screenwriting in the sense because i was
just someone over part of a sense of
humor and
and politics and and and things that
they were trying to say and do
very much agree
the idea that the uh...
but there's a responsibility on u_s_
happens to be present
when questions are asked to you by
journalist removal long period of time i
was with the people i was working with a
solvent sample
confession in the meantime as we hear
from forbes i saw that happen
and and send them
over all this stuff and just everything
and
you know you have to understand that
these people come here or
which try to make a buck
and they're gonna try to come up with
the most dramatic
significant monthly
actor takes over satellite
and stuff like that because that's
then going back to the returns and all i
have been hearing on this story
injury when when your life
isn't very nice
so where there is a two-way street bears
a responsibility at this point and said
i mean talking
one thing i would say have a car about
this particular script
which using very
with michael
as well was it when we finally started
to get their first office
eastman first when i was several years
ago and hackensack exactly
cutting edges like
that it is now unmask persistent and
work experience that most reactions we
got people without
the interesting thing was that
volume strong great visible
interactive studios now making the film
under a previous regime
had the peace covered by what's called
the story
through reader
when it was working with us manage the
social engineer copy of that coverage
wistful officers and his opinions
this type of thing
young republicans it's not really pissed
because uh... does not like the whole
idea of
having actresses protagonists and
sort of introducing their view of the
world and how it works in life
in a sense of we don't all become
hackers
shirking our responsibility is
individuals incessant
sometime later michael
gave a script for particular studio head
responded with the quote
i'm uncomfortable with it
anti-establishment attitude
and even though we are being turned down
by a studio might my reactions like
it works
and and and i'm an actor
any questions that anybody would say i i
think that you wanted
one last thing
grateful to you live in it and i don't
quite know who
relief but it's in terms of
onto when you're talking about their
responsibilities as happens in talking
to the media
if you're not very careful
what was you'll be paved over by the
information superhighway
and i think that's quite true that uh...
as people finding a way to make money
out of the internet
and and people trying to bring you the
whole home shopping in everything
there is a
with they perceive as in cancer
and packers are that cancer
unless you find a way
to present yourselves intake down as far
as your responsibility to people that
so you really should be political but
you should be aware
when your problems
because let's face it this circus that
corporate america is not pregnant
i don't have much
mechanics of that
when i need
became aware of this world was
twenty-some years ago
grip of the global network projects
you know the answer yes
sixty
edskitty
information corporations were structured
basically before monopoly
capitalization
and
mammal religion
which for about a subversive as i could
be in that period
um...
no
for unique about this
activity any information world and
facility that
against the group that calls
is called hackers has
but frankly the whole younger generation
which is about to leave computer
technology we you know
any of their
their seniors
if their teachers or their parents
is that
the
context of society has become
information based approach to
boiling
gold whatever also
finally
you vote for the potential for
a new frontier
which in the american spirit of
storytelling and the great american ms
has always been
com about
some guy going out there on the front
here
and what's happening here when i've been
watching the last day or so it is
kissing them spirit of the missing
somewhat culturally celeste
twenty years until things got quality
cells
to get this you know
i remember also seen two months ago and
at u_c_l_a_ at the
highway conference
where i'm sitting
edison wandered inside
and watched uh...
heads of the major companies flap about
what a great thing this was a sin
a little bit all be connected
subverted
and they didn't have a clue
uh... and what's fun to see here's the
people who do i completely understand
that you use it
the same has been raised which is about
to listen to which is our responsibility
that's responsibility for buddy
posted relist makes films www
create any kind of cultural activity is
to have some sensible
um... their own responsibility everybody
there is a wrong way to people
the problem is that some people want to
carry more of their own way
their people just are
irresponsible
we're trying to be
hairpin where or what
what's going down rolls on
chronic movie that's uh... reveal upon
those
we think we could do it
both
higher
student
clinic
exploration
house
and
tell us
paras four
rehearsals
newsletter corporations
you'll find
the occasional
words resume does new building
i gotta go back to the point of view
earlier
you guys are the problem
and at least
alone here
i don't believe you are the problem i
think you're part of this
you've offered an awareness offer
what the capabilities all our why
revealed
you guys are about technology abuse
used extension
how do i use it and five
large activities
super malicious
you don't by and large have these
grandiose political financial economic
or ka environmental agenda leader to be
like the technology works we can want to
have some fun with it and occasionally
something you get it cracking at the
okay
may not be right but that is not the
fundamental problem before for america
faces and
they find it very easy and convenient to
blame something that is very little
fibroblast
next you guys
so up
the serb people there but
the awareness is increasing
and i think that we're gonna see the
change occurred
through the legal system pond
fortunately because the lawyers in the
corporations are beginning to realize
in an information asset intensive world
they have to get on the ship because
there's going to be some major fiduciary
responsibilities
whether it's you guys breaking into the
bad guys steal the money for the federal
reserve or whatever happens to be
privacy issues corporate espionage real
issues are going on out there that
you're so
molded demonstrating
the lawyers are going well for starters
starts losses the lawyers are part of
the lawyers upon in order to be a good
thing or not
underwhelmed
i was given the lawyers that i don't
know what i think it's going to be
happening anyway
but it was a rift used is that something
to a very briefly i mean i think that
it's so hard
quite precariously poised to the women i
think that
certainly uh... law enforcement agencies
and
corporate america report
you back over europe
basically saying that packed music row
and they're frightened of it
and they seem to return to property
and so they use the the forces of law
and order
to protect property which they
was done
i think the issues of
access and transfers
freedom that was certainly very
important
uh... that my country and and dot the
nineteenth century
is going to be a she said she was there
the industrial conglomerate so she took
all of the land that was probably a
uh... man at and all the laws of the
u_k_ basically of uh... reporters to
protect those interests i think that
is the paris time i think that's why
it's important for
uh... journalism
people like ourselves too
blowing your culture
it is presented
in a positive way
because i think that is not the culture
this criminal all legal
straight with us
uh... i think that it's just the first
discovered by people
it would have prevented
i believe uh... by large everybody
with some degree of intelligence look
like use of the above
rockers and
are basically hackers and i want to try
to prove this
noted
a lot of seminars and conferences for
corporations with him
oracle
and at one point
i sat down computers but we're pretty
and we'll have a coffee break or
something
and i sat down with the could not see
the computer screen
restore ladies and with dr
holy shit just broke into the white
house computers
breezy delivers unrivaled wasn't
inclined
the all
want to know it was the first time in
their mind
but they realize
that they have certain attacker essence
with them
i couldn't help educate
uh... yes fine
add to that dot anne
that is one thing that you can do and he
did his it is simple but it but it is
one thing you can do so political
analyst is to give
the site's taste
because uh...
anybody who's
you know anybody
to recognize the people of this once
they are
put face-to-face with that sort of
changes the whole perspective
again you have to be very careful about
the context in which you do that did not
like
you know have
uh... current affair shooting you know
shoulder
but you know if you can
if you are you know in in the face of
the situation with somebody from the
media if you can get
you know it somehow
you know it's a matter of just some
surreptitiously getting m
you know a password to access to my
something under so that they can you
know see what it's like i'd understand
with the buzz is about
you know i can be achieved by this
but let's just for that to get a sense
of
but it's all about
even if he does i think
up in the corporate
six
haha
different scene
meetings dot kind of momentum
using laser copies of this
doing later copies
burger youngbleaux countertop
hardware ran back and didn't get
they came back and
meaning principle
you happens again
and his friends and we think that you
were not
vivero packing but did not plugged into
the behavior here right now
i'm pretty good good
technology consultants
if you look at steve might be one of the
things he talked on the book is alan
greenspan elitist
you know monks
running on the tablet and a big party
also leading to the string on
vastly different and i could see
generationally in terms of how young
hackers are now out there were a lot of
people out there
consider themselves actors were not
any political movement were
from the convention three repentance but
they're doing
i wanted to make it simple answer user
and spring up more and more
passengers to preside
i'm too old to speak about being young
in the eighties
record step back to me twenty five years
and make a very simple statement
that my generation
in those twenty years in the late
sixties early seventies
at the technology that you guys had
never would have break in the eighties
online
one of the things that was a big
difference in we hear this next
generation stuff i want to get into all
that
began democratization process for a
differences are i think carries a little
bit further than that and
we're going to start now called cyber
civil disobedience
and right
believes that this current generation it
may be so apolitical that they really
don't know that the manpower that they
have
that to make political statements twenty
five years ago we had to amass five
hundred thousand people on the streets
of washington and get gassed in order to
make the headlines
and the required massive amounts of
organization transportation and oh
police members and everybody else to be
able to make a political statement
that is no longer true today the
technology exists to be able to
massive massive systemic shutdowns
renewal
gift on one by one of them on my last of
the lawyers may say no it's conspiracy
or something else
but the ability to have a large part
demonstrations in cyberspace that
effectively or some other civil
disobedience
is a political force that has not yet
taken hold and i don't know what the
future government
personal question of op arctic cracker
in terms of uh... uh... what's changed
you know it's lost
twenty years ago
the weight of the technology has changed
maybe we need to a real way
real change in the way
people insisted impact
twenty years ago because computers
tended not to be linked together
the people that got interested in
computers for the people who are
interested in getting inside machine
people who are basically
you know centers people who would
tech park artwork
radio with the people who just want to
get inside she messed around
now i think that the way people are
involves computers and people get
involved computers tends to be more
through communication
uh... outside power system without
doorstep yesterday actually which i
explain my fears but not quite sure
actually but uh... america line it's
actually the most important
thing out there in terms of in terms of
the next five years of of hacker
that i am
you've got a situation where there are
cast and one that policy just because
because it gives it goes against a lot
of what this process about which is that
you guys are qua smart and develop most
people in america
and
you like that
elastomeric online is giving access to
the concept of computers in the concept
of communicating
with computers
to people who
one year ago five years ago twenty years
ago
had absolutely nothing to do with it
and that is
a kind of democratization
hacking has has always
i think that i think that there's always
been
uh... in some ways
connect more people who are willing to
pay the bill we're going to pay because
a lot of people that
you know in the denise computers acog
or people who could
before computers
i think that as confused as you grow as
online connections get cheaper
you're going to have people who are
involved in this crew who would have
been other whites and you're going to
have
people who are different than the rest
of your article unit
disarm
the looking around at the heart of
america online if you're going to have
more
withdrawals there
you know
uh... it seems that this is the best
community that that's much more
comfortable on america online
their conference like this
like i say it's just a theory but can i
do believe that that that uh... people
are going to people's first
connection with computers now is not
about getting inside she needs the
connecting to other people that's one of
the first instinctive i think that
that's gonna change
that's going to attack in the next
witness
image and uh... steve levi's booked me
it's a wonderful book but there's also a
kind of uh... paradise lost in areas to
it you know which i think you probably
picked up the package that he was
talking to and and this is just
something you have to take into account
anytime anyone who's telling you
you know well enough to use your help
used to be in the light line with the
peace to the village voice
there were people
you know saying well you know after
operation sun devil you know we're not
gonna get fresh crop actress in a
biscuit status when i play with their
new ninja turtles and
actually intended audience
well you know uh... four years later
we need to charles to be on hand
restaurant still here
fresh crop circle
hase
sinuses
pet
as long as it's just you
uh... instead
funny huh
issue here
possible
finalists
pauline both houses
if the f_b_i_
stars
loss
here
there
stand how hard
dress intervention
uh... mark
sparkles suspicious
it's
mariusa
pain intercoms
calls
any surprises pocahontas
piece
now on
senator gore
introduced
tracy
theatre had
i think
with seizures
man
tourism board got problems
your compound the problems on
hundred-thousand were beautiful weather
superhighway that we're reading for
worry a lot of protection
and whatever the group of privacy is
important to us from our standpoint
and we're not going totally blew me off
including question off his gates on x
businessman hell is this
because the question that i was
addressing was politically derailing to
his efforts to try to get something done
he had a piece of the puzzle
but he didn't have the whole thing over
the next three three-and-a-half years or
so as we tried to work with gore prior
to becoming vice president
and uh... it
we were blowing up totally his office
did not want to know about it and about
what was the same as part of a problem
with were facing
often up in government
the issues that we all care about are
very very fundamental they're very very
high global issues
and unless
they are built in to some sort of
solution base for us as a country as a
whole
i think they're gonna be really missing
the bar
right anyway
forces me too
briana
peoplesoft
but a lot of activity
rodeo
always always been
what i hear you
or
keen haha
fourteen
when it will take place
anyhow
anyways
is on
heating up
will always
needed
hostility
in blue
union
you
people
you are u
certainly
wooden or out
seen below
and okay
today fault
nikki giovanni
anywhere
bible
and pittsburgh
leaking out
information
an extra day
measured
less likely than expected
the new color
came home from work sister
beauty
one-third
and
anywhere
already
a lot
applique
behavior i didn't you
home
didn't u
came here
yahan
editor
all right
you
pc
do you
scheduled etc
i_v_f_ all about
caterina
personally
with that
i don't get it out
it was
value-added
gateway
boyish audience
equilibrated
strategy
well
television
cbd
about that
well these days
they are
rhode island
well full-scale
well
illegal action
early on
it all
newsletter
i don't know if you
what it was
already
equally
let alone
please come online
homeland
would be
there are or
so bad
kissed
no
it was
dot
okay
xxoo
does
dot
k he applied
you
the what
said he he
dot
k