economic growth
cut staff and actually along the way it
often in the late nineteen sixties uh...
i was a volunteer to radio station
called the b_b_a_ i which uh...
i believe is still in existence
and they sent me on a uh... i was about
maybe sixteen or seventeen years old
they sent me on a field assignment to do
a report on something called phone
freaks which occurred in the basement of
some hotel
poetry second where but the
on the big attraction was abbie hoffman
showed up
and uh...
uh... they had a very nice convention
they were up a lot of uh... uh...
secret service type people hanging
around at night i people hang around it
maybe that forty fifty people
and uh... sort of fade out fade in
nineteen seventy three i went to n_y_u_
film school
and i had to do a document reform
project
and now we're trying to give a subject
me and my partner mark and wrote
we're going to do a film on scientology
and now we decided that was going to be
a little too dangerous at that point in
time so
we decided that uh... phone freaking of
telephone freaking was it was pretty
innocuous owing me this film called ma
bell's delinquent children
and uh... it one contact eachother
lauren and uh...
uh... several other words uh... movies
on a shoestring and things like that may
help highest we shouldn't be shown
museum of modern art makes a couple
thousand people stroll total
uh... it was sort of lost uh... or
sitting in the costliest battle but
and uh... i found out about this
conference last week
and uh... i'd mention that i had this
film in the person dave who's your
somewhere i have it you know you know
you should show it all i think arguably
this is the oldest film about telephone
freaking
and um... it's i think that we have
balanced it shows a political point of
view business people as well as the
position of a_t_t_ versace's before the
break up
uh... so we'll be showing it ah... i
guess it two thirty in the other room
which is uh...
condemning them all the way in the back
in
but here it had every bit of information
stored on you in a single card
and ask the person is going to get it
for you
for any at ul contest in fact uh... if
for some of you have some clever sayings
uh... for
things that have not yet been invented
that comes with a credit for
uh... positive or negative because uh...
as we all know technology can bring us a
negative things as well
costly submit them
little box out by the registration area
and will be given way some may zing
prizes on sunday
for the uh... for the funniest ones and
i will be judging that right here
so if you have a look like they're
saying of a
now you will still be in
uh... the other thing we've got going is
um...
a postcard campaign for fiberoptic is
currently in prison
i'm pennsylvania will have to post cards
lying around it and my message to women
will mail out to him
at the end the conference
okay we have articles on
cement truck are they were passing
around
we also have a few technical
books up here we only have four of them
on so if
people want to look at them whereas if
you've got to pass around share them
are what we have
we have some information on this
semester card system
which has been no introduced a new york
city
over the past couple of months
basically walk up to a machine
and these are the same through
and at the ducks the amount of um...
of money from the card when you when you
use it
uh... it's insane system because it's
based
on the lot of computers network together
and we all know what can happen when you
do something like that
uh... there are possibly uh... entry
points in many different areas
we're trying to find out exactly what is
on these trips now
we tried a couple of weird experiments
we try to racing this trip
to see what happens here without the
machine
and know what happened
absolutely nothing had no effect
whatsoever
we're starting to wonder whether or not
this is actually a magnetic strip in
whether it might not be a barcode hidden
underneath what looks like a magnetic
strip
um...
all the intelligence we believe is
inside the computer not the card the
card carries
a serial number
and a bachelor amber an expiration date
which is pre printed on the back
it's quite possible that is the only
information
in the strip or the barcode
and that when you swipe the card through
rather than our writing information to
the car to simply accessing a local
computer and telling
telling the um... the display how much
is actually
credited to that particular accounts
qatar hands-on employees card
if
this is not free access but
mister free access on a really know the
by the
test purposes only
basically ah... this one is expired
so we were able to use at all
program we selected through
uh... it said this car has expired at
all this debate in time of the last
uh... use of the card
now it's going to stay now we have a
system like this by the way tokens will
be abolished in nineteen ninety seven in
the city
uh... the system is currently in effect
in six to nine stations
and i think we have something like what
five hundred stations in the city
uh... so
by a nineteen ninety-seven every single
turnstile will be using the system
it's possible this could be used to
uh... to
find out where you entered the subway
and when
uh... of course doesn't have your name
on it but uh...
if you say you in a certain time certain
place
there'd be a way to verify it there
would be a way to track people
it's it's one step closer
uh... so there are dangers their
inherent in the system as well
uh... we're open to any kind of
experimentation that we can do in the
next three days here at this conference
we'd love to duplicate one of these
things we'd love to see what happens in
that regard station right across the
street
israel to duplicate one
and slide it through the same time as
another one
uh... we want to see what the reaction
is i want everybody in cities now
process uh... it's kind of over here for
today
we have uh... a special guest
well answer questions
and a special guest
happens to work
the transit authority he programs these
things he makes these metro cards
and uh... the hacker spirit is is so
contagious that uh... he is actually
decided to
risk everything and come down here in
speaking all
so well
without further ado
are anonymous transit authority
spokesperson
humility nicely from libya three years
ago
fault
and then you'll get a little more credit
when he used the word program are and
what is known as a railroad clerk
what the probably could call itself in
the seller
although it's not a great job but it
pays the bills
office for is a major part goes
all we've got a little document that
supposedly with the developed couple
hundred copies i see a lot of them here
that's good
renegades and in which uh... will be
available afterwards on a few other
things that we've picked up
but as far as we know that your card in
all internal documentation both ferreira
clerks the friendly people and so
convinced
and for uh... technicians states that
the card is
a magnetic storage card
uh... this could be disinformation but
somehow we really don't are we so i
don't really think so
uh... there we go to such great lengths
signature card is essentially credit
card story scarred but smaller
and of people seeing that uh... one in
my pocket which will hold up
because the magnetic stripe on it that's
brightly-colored
it is not like systems in washington
d_c_ and other places
have the value printed on it
instead they're expected just like this
in turn star or a quote metro card
reader
in order to tell the value
the back of each card has three items
printed on it an expiration date
a six digit batch number which is the
same for at least every one hundred
cards
and a ten digit serial number
we also uh... uh...
known to some extent what's on the
magnetic stripe or possibly barcode
uh... they are the same things that are
physically printed on the back of the
cards desperation date the batch number
and serial number
the type of card
isn't playing coated for fifteen dollars
is it more intrigued coated in other
words or is it going to do when they
look at the booth
resident alien card
the current event on the card
the date and time of last year since her
cell there's probably other information
as a manual mentioned if it's a bar code
reader or even if it's a magnetic stripe
were all that stored as a serial number
this stuff is not actually on the card
instead you're getting it after it goes
through turnstile to token booth
computer to an area computer to the main
computer a transit authorities
uh... building in the home thirty
livingston street in downtown brooklyn
there are some arguments that it is
nynex striped having to do with that
namely that are
turnstiles are supposed to take cards if
they become
relieved only to the local taken this
computer and no higher up the hierarchy
return sells for us to take three
thousand there is at that point
was going to three thousand tokens to
thousands like him a card or combination
thereof
that sort of speaks against a
information acting interested on the
card
if there are you really do questions at
any point to ask if there's anything
that's a good question say that man
purple with beard
salmon
but currently that's more manuals for
terry what i've heard about that is they
use the commercial world
territories said mechanism
whereas mister
uh... there is no evidence for doing the
laser it's not impossible
here are i mean when i entered a card
and six inches away from it there's no
advice as to protecting your eyes
brisbane reasonable really really show
up
prisoner release to the mood from the
uh... slight include the area of retail
removed and their
uh... it as i said it's not impossible
it just seems unlikely
listens even road this road speaks
against uh... that happening
exactly what the the the theoretical
verified
spacing
v_c_r_
burrows speaks against that going all
the way up the hierarchy before uh...
gone the other point talking to a local
computer system that uh...
that is constantly updating with the
network
it to be done instantly
and that's that's what i think it's
happening i think it's uh...
it's accessing a system that's inside
the station
and check in and seeing if i work with
particular debate is on the card
and that nam that is updated
maybe i once every five minutes but it
was a retirement we don't know
what we need to tries to duplicate two
cars and try them on two separate
stations at the same exact moment to see
what happens
well tell us something
all away of course is for couple were
missing configuration has a lot for
questions about it is the microphone
over that ask questions
uh... there are numerous said lectures
and software software and to some extent
the hardware as provided by tour
exploration
which i believe is from california
there's also some uh... serious
anecdotal evidence that some of the
writings c programming
three language program
was done by i_b_m_
paul
uh... among the glitches although it
supposedly there's multipart reagan if
you got several parts of her along one
day bought another one
response they'll take the value of their
own one card it won't happen
don't even like the clerk triad uh...
either you or they will lose money
today never loses money i'd like to
point out if you walk away from it so
that this was too much money two years
ago a note of that money that we're
going to bruises
uh...
there's also some evidence of that uh...
analysis a recording of transactions at
the booth is not done which should be
uh... someone i know i had a problem
with the passenger who alleged that
their carter though
and long term for twenty dollars never
spend that money put on it
supposedly we're told an internal memos
that you can trace the transaction
verify whether or not it did occur
uh... apparently that's impossible on
add-ons
which shows as security guards if the
petition is ever possible
uh... despite the fact that an analyst
says he has an employee have side
examined etc
i don't believe that simply passing
who's a test
uh... actually used in training
uh... it would be totally invalid on
uh...
on the any machine that is something
that's confusing so i do believe
or on turnstiles
uh... i do have a place like this and
not doing so any great experimentation
going to go on with it because
i'd like to hang on to my job
a few other things opaque there is one
of known temporary successful defeat of
the master card system
in around march of this year's someone
was arrested at the thirty fourth street
and either seven third avenue for using
the card
routine debate made by the following
athletes would a recording studio or a
tape recorder
reportedly florence quotes a release and
friends
on eight-track tape
mysterious plastic or cork board for it
and successfully entered in the uh...
subway station
efficient transit authority lawyer on
how this person was caught is as follows
do you know the same thing happened on
the central computer at one thirty one
this is straight
right i understand from other sources is
that no there is some cop standing
around the sauce and i think what did it
look like a voter card out of his pocket
this and then decide to go and ask
questions
trust me is the obvious things like that
sir
expresses somewhere
uh...
troubling breaking things they've got a
couple of screens which may be
indicative of something to probably not
very useful
personal and political judgment on
transparency for murder
the up
if you just think things the court can
examine uh... certainly uh... fields off
a card with slight through
either uh... these flight uh... area of
the children with computer inside the
brute
onsite area directly under the clerk
solos outside the booth
but you're interesting things are what
pops up for passenger cars
remaining value in dollars and sense for
our card site which is even full-fare
prion coded regard actually
expiration date now this is interesting
for both employees cards and passenger
cars expiration date is always one of
the very limited set
twenty three fifty nine pm
on the either april
august or december
on the last day of the month
uh... the earliest one scene is april
thirtieth nineteen ninety five
uh... blessed use date for both
passenger a random clearly cards
for something called his own code which
aren't passenger coaches thirty two zero
stalled by a wine
underneath there was some x's on route
given
places
uh... the include confirmed that exam
code is also does have the x_ is in the
same place
then there's a fruitful osorio
which is always three
withhold daily trips which is always
zero if you'll recall that substance
code which is also a zero
uh... as i said it's interesting but
probably not useful
uh... for the literacy missing all the
sizes so you can always get cards in
multiples of five dollars you can only
on on locals the five dollars
runner-up
if you have a blamed for it you can get
an email from five or we're not supposed
to sell to a for five dollars and wants
that
but we could
uh...
version would never too early for some
interesting human engineering
bolt overall i don't think it's really
the useful
alone
years ago at the personal and village
voice
got a response from a woman who's been
working for i_b_m_ we got to talking
supposedly sheep
do a lot of the cold war criminals
as a free dating service in new york
you can reach my mom miracle turnaround
time nine for nine forty five zero zero
stands on the attached karen work the
category between east thirty and forty
simplicity subjects valerie millions to
do with argument has to match the greens
and whites younger men
soul
big opportunity
for all you know new hackers out there
i don't think she is really are going to
do nothing for the press release but
harry
it may help your social life
uh... unattached florida
hat
solos associated
i think that's pretty medstat uh... you
can get the handout later in the any
questions
no i don't like his beloved
it's hard to understand and i think
there's lots of time so
but franklin's now most of them or not
too yay you can really schmooze with
them
sold complaining about the intervention
for something
there from cuba corporation most of them
at sensible things are still done
in-house but uh... anywhere tronic stuff
on turnstiles
allowing them prided themselves they're
from cubic
millions for that
so now we're really dealing on the
technology there is some evidence
however i don't know how many people are
familiar with an extra technology for
credit cards
there three fields uh... standard on a
minister usually for credit cards only
want to or used rooting for our area
read a writer for the third area
we believe that that's where there's a
lot of stuff
gambling
ct
we know how i would come from a drug
dealer cameras and microphones center
analysis so fast
and also chosen a song that you are a
lot has happened in shamelessly when the
first time that i do not deny
their card so to speak
arm basically some of us for this to you
soon
has put the cards
flying swiped it it's a it's a boat ride
again
and find the defendant on the world
media
nor did it twice
the other is related to revive the
spirit of the second tunstall that
always happens
an inspector handouts on that uh...
uh... if you do get that swipe at the
same turnstile do not get another turns
out
are don't have an off an explanation why
that happens but it does happen
on any other questions in the white
shirts for is not
you
countries will use these these foreign
the little
cameron that all
delbarco ally
how could you bring it up
okay
valuable actually a sc
the
mc everywhere
dot
almost all still
most forces loyal
all also open has certainly for the fall
into these drawings abuses about
homicide
rather go to new jersey that often
on us
he certainly all that
emerald isle police in california
talent
on somebody else
has also been some
helmsley's understanding the dumpster
uh...
there's a suggested the dumpster dive
san diego for children west inc
ambrosia suggested the downstairs i
resided with recent history which is
transitory headquarters remembering
livingston plaza which is uh...
who met were also i wasn't sure of the
main computer isn't
uh... to recycle the office paper and
both of them
vera it's relatively secure or i could
probably do it but they'd ask too many
questions see me in the recycle paper
that
on the aisles
you
selfish and this is going to go and get
a handle on microphone
administrators you can correlate daschle
turnstiles
is are you
opening up the the reader writer there
wasn't much interesting in heaven on the
side panel i was opened up there is a
keypad in their and there was also to on
off switches one for regular power was
right in the center in the top of the
panel one for battery back up
i guess that what they do is they
swiping natural like type card through
that they can enter code in order to
access to the system
yanking record your honor you uh...
artsy tell you that access to the system
on what he said
but they were five optical mines leading
to through he said three seventy jay st
uh... so what happens when the victim
plaza i don't know he said that the
leaders
worried right
once again it's just we told me he was
very friendly i didn't write down then
the manuals that they had with them
uh... hayward
national learning center corporation
uh... wholesalers cubic in there was a
whole i wrote a letter to emmanuel idaho
because published by six hundred
but uh... and that's i mean actual names
i guess i'll put it on whatever at least
i don't have any over here because i had
a printout jackpot winner overrun
maintenance manual which is uh...
freelance or someone's who want to know
about this mentioning sweet fruit ryrie
stuff there
who's not terribly much that the women
we have to tell us the manuals at the
stone made of uh...
seeing or probably more useful but when
we start so far nothing
uh... what's interesting about the
even-tempered moved computer is that
there are two key slots
run for our transit authority
supervisors one for cubic uh...
technicians which uh... when you open
this
and uh... indications supervisor
watching the case of both the swipe your
own
uh... start house it gives you a
different menus and it does for the
clerk
sarah in wi three struggle the
traditional ways of hacking assistant
control team lead etcetera etcetera
uh... nothing it works in fact many
teens are are totally dead
uh... classes bengaluru mets cap
don't orders investors is supposed to
start in a little over a year year and a
half ago initially
as a manual mentioned there will be no
more tokens
uh... supposedly also uh... one trip to
a
deals will be uh... yeah writing to see
you go to machine you throw in whatever
money that is needed for the good for
just the one trip
recap of from here
soon if necessary out there and they're
transfer student passes and those who
uses impasses
rosenbloom since he was a good person
and probably have some sort of federal
beyond it
uh... lol
you're going to be able to purchase at
half price if you're a senior citizen
additional rides
and relieve stomach acid pro do your
thing broke through the number of rides
at break
so all those uh... delays of going
somewhere else on the way home from
school
but probably win and
ratio down the aisle
brillo that's on the streets of new two
hundred fish a little scheme is that
there was a whole has something to do
with losing about dresses
harrell until more
january return you to join
who you can if you have a concern and
that is so eager to it uh...
neurosurgery
all black church also were back in the
middle
back dot
general
frankly i thought i was uh... actually
explorer william totenberg computers are
a number of uh...
problems with that the greatest of which
is it's illegal
uh... but their logistical problems
before and that any use of that the
problem is that high would be identified
saying we essentially workforce to brute
force packwood is sort of thing
there was some talk a lot of
experimented with oscilloscopes tonight
of course uh... as a manual has put in
the schedule
will get back to
before
before things are over
brazil crosstalk it sounded interesting
was that guys
here are some great over there and
telephones
maturity for more forceful
isn't connected so that there was a
free-standing then
thank you very much
uh... somebody else
brother had
uh...
annemarie murderers who is uh...
uh... we found our technical information
and also strike that
pulling magnetic filings are such
i'm sorry
only
that's what we know so far
leverage for we don't have users
momentarily has tried putting iron
filings a similar stuff on this thing
insist that the uh...
actually works as a magnetic uh...
intellectuals magnetic
on the islands or the gray shirt
you know how to play the uh... for
blueprint here apparently iron filings
will work
uh... already old technology seems to
everything and that sort of back so
bright and it brought down to the guy i
thirty four states
regarding the red shirt and then the guy
sitting down next to him
where there was a radio address to drive
the ah...
told the guy in purple in your neck of
the woods their by sitting down at a
question
uh... the problem with that is they
won't fit uh... there to wide
reflect actually very warm
facil yeah that's a good idea if someone
can supply me with that old is an
exhortation purple shirt and for the
rack
there's some misleading the classifieds
ids forty six hundred
i don't know i've ever use them
uh... black shirt for five rows back
exactly exactly however the distribute
distributed network i do it
i can talk and that is fine
uh... sounds good to know if it and as
far as bus technology goes in other
words if it's downloaded locally
amroma likelihood of the bus so i can so
we going over radios pretty unlikely as
as was mentioned what's likely to happen
is that there will be stored locally and
then uh... downloaded every
animal glass run now every eight hours
every day whatever
lay in the back in the center sending
resorted
yeltsin
announces a large group of people going
somewhere tonight lineup
uh... was short uh... staff person in a
red shirt or a person standing mail
hasn't yet
or they'll take love the guy in the pure
single
arnold
would put a booked on a very attractive
idea with that still work if that was so
front one side of the slaughter
parasite in here that the carolinas duo
is intolerable
on the list right it's probably remain
order to defeat
just passing it through
uh... on the aisle
what's there
here
itself
and exceeded
the v
hotmail
hair
it's not impossible frankly my feeling
that i have removed from the transit
authority for three years
is uh... they're paranoid enough to do
that
franz ferdinand
uh... it might goodnight
with blue cross is a very good credence
to the official landslide regarding a
possible trouble on computer
uh... in the front of the first rule
inflation is welcome
media
uh... probably not
well the flowers or built right for a
few days
to hang onto it for so many laughter it
should be able to get uh...
an email address for me
possibly
incorrectly
three and nineteen that fly
hall third-world
retirement actual hundred blindfolds
coming back to a hundred
and uh...
it's kind of a hundred has the same time
the slide into justin
packing one hundred has the same batch
number
and uh... each card has an individual
serial number
uh... that's an interesting question
what happens if someone shows up with
slightly different card
it depends andrew uh... the door for a
really if you cut the top of the card
off
it doesn't reflect the new thing the
good morning to you can still use it
if you want to move forward
we can uh... it'd take the money off the
first time to put on a second one
if you have a program to blunt that the
magnetic strip
sometimes the real story lurks sometimes
they were too badly
sometimes are not workable
if you put in the past and welcome to
you
if you're going to determine how much
money was still on the card
we can give him a card under oath or
whoever was a week
uh...
business reply envelope
andrew brimmer look forward to rugby
club metro card centre at ten columbus
circle where we can talk about yourself
amber very determined whether or not
it's uh... rokahr older adults are
willing to do
more
in the corridor remember back no in fact
murmuring among americans to return to
know what their
uh... interesting from those you can get
a car with cash if you go karting tokens
but you can't own a probe into cash or
tokens that a third of those
uh... growth slows suburb of those
crimes you may recall properly roosevelt
they'll remove cash in on the tokens of
david burns
income summary people's hands look like
new york turnstiles in case you know
there's a question where her back
uh... so you know it's pretty secure
i've had that thought uh...
roadrunner nasdaq's ruled out
mamu armored breasts and the food from
where it comes out of our at or puts
into the controller but i'm sure it
serves as notice that was stuart
barbecue signals at once
uh...
goldstone assessment of of late selma
drink on it more than once and nothing
has happened
yaoo smasher
rushing at the bus troubles in selecting
and everything from platforms
it sounds very secure u_s_ arms from
jeff we have enough raccoons and left
arm of proto primer if we could tap into
it like jewelry
i don't want to do time in st parent
uh... white short answer right
harris is known as a result of that
family members
pilot theory reserves the right side of
our details are as likely to juarez
or it
on the fundamental interest armored in
talent group going
truong
does it
uh...
ordered
parent alternative panorama all over the
world
will probably happen since i was
wondering when ross perot systems noida
maharashtra parenteral so i don't know
if it was wrong
emerald
where are the slides four twenty five
thousand thinks most law
by our own interests are seeking refuge
in him
ground so as long as you know just
upload fluid
sometimes with the muslim overlays
around a little
knowing full well you know it was the
most listeners worries
doesn't go well
uh...
artificial tokens sounds like a rose
throughout likely high-tech accurate
still possible
uh... i will not go through a full books
read restauranteurs
uh... any other questions
rotary torque
tomorrow hammond
uh... purple shirt in the back and more
i don't know
we're trying to find out
might
doesn't passwords must meet the has
influenced our readers as it were mostly
turnstiles or
stainless steel they're pretty secure to
and i'm sure two hundred dollar as it's
called the jaws of life with the flu
seasons
hahahahahaha remember character or level
two
sometimes brings the deficit advantages
to apply it we're going to make lunch
rooms
uh... when we were running the brunch
sound
the
all right
duran is prohibited
growing
mineral
more you're well aware the it
dole is the with the issues or worse
offers
more u_s_ paul
wrestling or wrestling i appreciate your
veggie singles that would never go
slowly so astonishing throughout
at for instance literally angela as a
summary of your account
places the thought that was a bit
restaurant brian wants
disparaging things out
apparently running through the northern
martha we need to talk with
possible residents not to spread as far
as i listen to my scandalous rose uh...
clearly we are
uh... the stress over the last couple of
it that later
uh... had been to figure out what it's
all about
this uh... melissa
from uh... san francisco
throughout has had quite a few ah...
enterprise system
has has has held back down
he had a complete
uh... cracked that system and they do
not appreciate that
had to
you actually think of
for information
power tactics that way
process
well at this point
okay
follows
was the first time actually seeing what
uh... remains this look like
the fact is when i was uh...
start out his own
where you approach
taken care of a magnetic strip tease
buses get some money that you're usually
very fine iron filings
really need a few milligrams of them
so it's my file and mail it something
reconstruction shop he would be adequate
sprinkle them on the on the mag stripe
as we've done here
and shake it around and then
reactors sometimes right up the car
until you can see a very clear tracing
it'll get clear
there's going to declare it a point and
then we'll get weaker we'll soon find
out where you can get the best i look at
printed a pieces cellophane tape uh...
especially for every call it here
and making the too much of the
fingerprint wants to go up a person to
save it
that way you can tell of what the format
is in this case it's a two-track format
bouchard
it looks like it's autocratic ariba
tracks one indivisible wire track which
would be tracks uh...
uh... two and three combined
uh... it looks like the domains are not
angled unlike the washington d_c_ metro
and bart
dangle the
the domains in clockwise direction at
about sitemap degrees
but these look like ordinary like uh...
credit card or a style uh...
remains the looks like it's about a
hundred and twenty perhaps
it sounds very conventional to me
now once you know what uh... with the
shape those
the shaping looks of the tracks are
because she'll be in a track record for
this you just need a redefined ahead
like for a company like michigan
magnetics
that has uh... this particular of
pattern
now once you have that taking care of
despite time for action all you do not
to do is uh...
is make the device like it was uh...
shown an ultra six hundred it really
works and get used to how we use it and
ah...
when your copy sounds like your mission
a log
we got a card
and uh...
reliable
and how much of this i really should be
saying i just kind of that
i mean i talk about this in european
time allotted time a little bit of fun
here
army
went to work exactly what i'm wearing
them so you know what a guided tour of
goa climate org
do informational purposes only
bill course is for informational
purposes only by the disclaimers or but
usually
but i
so what
this looks very conventional i don't
know her the story about somebody trying
to get one of the santiago
on the odd
a book ah...
a book that tape eraser and not working
there's a distinct possibility here
but i don't uh... but this is the like
it's odd
doesn't seem like a tight as it was
calling uh... a magnetic watermark
it's a very hard and
they make field is very hard to race
but has to be included a elevated
temperature on a special material and it
will not uh...
there were lots of allow itself to be
swiped at embraced at today's low
temperature
another possibly which is not true this
card but i i would think they would've
been smart enough to try business i can
just tell a look at this it'll be done
easily and don't ask me how to do it
because i have no part of this
uh... if they were really be smart they
would use a system like on the japanese
phone cards collabera domains
and uh... to bring to the maze a surface
it requires a bs
bias
magnetic field
in other words like every other i_d_c_
may make field like a permanent magnet
at the right level to make the domains
come to the surface
then and only then can you read and
write the card
that uh...
that apparently has been very successful
in japan on the phone cards in the wall
a few people can do it but uh...
most people really aren't aware how to
do that and uh...
organized or so here we can talk about
that that that much more
but that's another subject
answering questions
let's go ahead
pale
as to speed changes of the equalization
characteristics of the
i believe that white electron ics uh...
have to change
and suddenly because they sure were true
i guess the baccarat four-to-one speed
range
which isn't too extreme and then you can
shape the pollsters
and uh... uh...
the nuclear power
ho
uh... it is possible globally this card
is designed this contract is is simply a
track of one zero one zero it's nothing
more than a day off
a timing track
but i mean track produces as is the true
it tells it tells the system hall fast
you are on a
you are sliding uh...
we're sliding the card of
soviet sold synchronize distracted can
reading right through that
to remain strikers were slaves were
yesterday a magnetic watermark
this card is not of that system let me
tell you artists i was just quickly
going into other systems that have been
uh... use dot
throughout the world this is uh...
this is as expected a fairly low tech
system that uh...
i mean is that this is not it's not like
i credit cards in germany or anything
like that
personally that's that
certainly all at all if you look at the
pattern here there's a one track that is
of
approximately ah... five millimeters
wide in another tractors about nine
millimeters wide
so the best thing is to get ahead that
that that set pattern
another pro-choice i've never seen tried
before to reproduce what this is just to
use of the audience
so you can do that your course can
pretty much uh...
copy anything if it was a fancy of
magnetic system
mhm
you
be anythign
lives that uh... are looking at the card
i know exactly how they can uh... it
read and write to discard look at the
obvious
holly can read and write to this card
review put put it through because they
have the that synchronization track one
zero one zero
which uh... since polls this is ok next
yr may next elaine
so it by counting the polls is going on
the stops uh... uh...
absorbed in our synchronize their
manually deliver your comment about that
is that uh...
when selecting a truthful to to computer
or a new year
passengers like unit directly in front
of the clerks window
you sometimes get an error message that
says a word of exactly
uh...
repair if you're really blair lifted
during a read
so that tends to uh...
bear that out if you look it up it does
agree to properly
or just say you know i have to have with
the tracks right
well yeah but you know you can get
through to almost all the way that all
children it'll come out with that
architecture is that because constantly
angiogram
pathetic
fully i've only managed to ride the
subway once since i've been
in new york so i don't
really know about its overall operations
when
you
leading opera
truthfully is there any he's just to
make your review
phase
mighty meeting
who's going to make it not right
well if you were due on
if you were to probably be just put a
piece of tape over the
and lower half of this terrific related
civilization track is here that the lord
has to take over the lower half it would
probably
it would probably be i think history
will prolly delivery but not right
and dangerously fast
pieces
some sort of free trade because it or
not
okay there they regard outside rivera
trailer expecially tapes
register voters roads at the met with
this one says that the very short right
to suha help her
family on or about the actual uh...
physical pictures of it but just
artists know about the uh... the
resume makes tribes and others
this type of biotechnology
uh... back there
in the green scarf
grad
i'm just look at this card right now
is the growth of
uh...
uh... you get a uh... i get a card
reader
or the vice into that there are some
here are my cousin who's got them
larnaca get persons involved in this
but uh...
with that
the synchronization track is always the
same but the read write part is of
course it has to have different data
power
dust in the car
and uh... i don't really fast forward
nature the question
new cardholder input sketch sleep over
it not that i know it sounds like an
interesting avenue of attack
uh... brian the stretcher anak
a earlier taken with computers for a
period
or only turns those who are very
it's an interesting thought uh... oh i
believe that there is a timeout
mechanism of got copies of the lick your
book uh... manual lying around here
and retirement mechanism that the time
of
monroe five seconds between uh...
intruding media uber tokens or uh...
mastercard
once every five surgeons narrowly
diana stripe on the wall again
yellow at you essentially the guy
upfront asked a similar question
and there was a mechanism to set them on
the turnstiles
the timing between run entry in the next
century and would default minimum time
heals i believe five seconds
innumerable matt that's their restaurant
now in the green room you know
let's compare the bar card
uh... as i said before there is a
soprano differences
is that history elbow to rise
uh... dr therefore i can use the
standard manchester coding
because it does this mean is going
through and sell clock and read right
since this one uh...
this is this one has to actually write a
card
when you are swept me through
we have to use a special uh...
synchronization track
and uh...
fully with us this top secret as asian
track is it possible to uh...
or to write
there's one data track which is the
right track it's about a benign milne
here's why didn't he was like a
five-millimeter white uh...
synchronization track
which is on the topic
door people feel you have a few bodies
still really wants to do this on the
encouraging it but uh...
what did you see is old or cards and you
could buy a house speaker magnet will be
gone he could get a five dollar card was
a personal rights would never bring card
to play with
feed
happy
i reiterate
okay so s use a systematic coding system
where one of the tracks is actually a
synchronization track
this possible
omitted vivid malta track system you
could actually use
the tracking through this all is not
just a coincidence the other track
synchronizing why your ah...
brighter writing to another traci but
billy wright to one track at the time it
seems that uh... type of system
so busy with the possible i just never
seen it done so i've seen on may eight
cars a_t_m_ cards
what have you that
do have a secret is asian track it's
nothing more than that
parties
gutters
goldman
multi-part poorer
comes up on the the screen what you're
doing radiohead quoting analysis so that
is as well
coated with this
so you're out of their similarities
do different things to remember
to admire money uh... totaling carter
that's what i'm going to item on the
screen etc hard it's going back down to
zero it's a different menu item
uh...
i don't know whether any of that is
useful information but information
german immigrant blurred
grocery carts are sequential and serial
number but interestingly enough the
serial numbers and a batch of one
hundred
and that started with the muslims
worries were around as the last two
digits
maraschino mota a couple times with the
number twenty
for is the first blood unless one is of
course
will do well in twenty-three
uh...
roger not terribly well technically i
don't know having food has been delayed
check digitas knowing there's no
independent uh... indication of that as
i said there's a couple of things are in
there that are kind of uh... are you
sure what i've never seen anything
and different screens on honeymoon exam
code and acceptance code acceptance code
on all sorts of cards employees
passenger approve adult passenger at map
revalued put money into it no matter
what the amount is no matter which
category it's in
acceptance cortisone zero
zoning code same thing except that
from pantsuits forty three girls
answering extras attorney from excellent
for passengers it's thirty two zero
start by one
and the same x isn't exactly the same
spaces underneath
uh... the handout but i've got today of
the uh...
which on the front page uh... serves
successful hack insider's guide to metro
card like breaking stuff comes out
uh... has has uh... mushrooms as
depicted on a roll
look for
distribution
how you work for parliament clearer
okay okay
filed
does uh...
those of our people on olympic gymnastic
body this but the way they look at it is
just that
because uh... on some of us new house
system work or danger she had to be
arrested
but does that simple
highly-paid it's uh...
i mean it's this um...
i don't think i look at you nicely
listed on the state that's a revenue and
there's people's jobs and on the line
anybody utica funny uh... view here i
think all over america it seems a
goes as far as legal ramifications with
the new york city transit authority okay
first for passengers
animals around works traded stories that
certain rules of the two-year-old
heavenly for some wall
and unfortunately anything i can think
of that would cover that incident under
u_n_ control
uh...
castro's murmuring about clever luster
to his apartment
uh...
unnatural
accordingly
and backing off tremendously deep
tonight
but uh... stopped paying her dress
you know you will be writing at you'd
still be would probably still be
considered festive service and possibly
worse
uh... there's also a new york state
against hacking
and from the freaking
uh... dot four rosanna from the middle
dot three rows from back
daily algiers the second half first is
this uh... improving tracking of
individuals
so far not really as uh... sort of
referral had a question earlier about
uh... student cards
for any sort of uh... reduced uh...
fare uh...
uh... retired there might be tracking
individuals because the reduced fare
uh...
promotes his uh... intrinsically
individual another if you get it because
it made you go because of
high schooler lower-grade student status
uh... so there was some interesting
tracking you for that limited uh...
arise
and uh... you know i'm pretty
libertarian i can understand that
if you don't want to be tracked
you know spend the money on uh...
full-fare card
so far as far as food for cards go
there is no provision for tracking in
individual records
or at a local unanimously transit
authority only accept cash let's run out
of this or not
there and brodeur known groups to go to
los angeles colored
in fact there is some
talking to you about your car was
originally proposed and introduced
now you have a good friends with the
card intrinsic to herself
so that if it was stolen
i could call it the central numbers say
higher on the russian armored car was
stolen stoppard refund my money
riverside dr going with that
uh...
was the first to go to a question
uh... you know as far as a close
uniqueness uh... as i stated before
there are three things that we know
around the card both printed and
probably on a very exciting
the expiration date
which is not unique to give him card
will be
one-third of all cards were four point
six whatever
many batch number which is unique to
every one hundred cards
and the serial number which it was
completely unique to that colored
on the island glasses
that that's uh...
that they cut me because of
because somebody on
because uh... undercover cop i got them
involved in the undoubtedly sting
operations and basically ah... was
interested person he was employee of
uh... ordered employees of someone else
and does there was a setup was drafted
zaroor
but i would be caught in this uh... this
thing about a computer saying something
about this other guy getting arrested
bestest uh...
but that's no job because i i think that
was just saying that just so uh...
promiscuous ryan
but i mean the way the way things are in
this town i know that i would find him
would not
are just like to have that i think
that's a pretty good attitude with rosa
transit authority appears to be paranoid
any other questions
forever
it was a report in the newspapers he was
arrested
somerset like i said uh... uh... in in
in the replied with a they have effort
today
but
as bill itself says i don't think the
comparison regular figure's probably
some cop just
hanger boaters tells voters they took so
i was part of it was a mastercard put
through uh... turn spelling dot for
entitle you to interject here this is
how
there's a lot of people that were of
uh... were arrested uh... previously
returned barton and the reason why they
were arrested schools are using your
regular cards using many
making up their own cards
just underway wiley
need people to the obvious thing if they
want if they want to defraud a transit
system use an actual card is beyond me
and this seems to me is a lot easier to
get the real thing
all those kind of thirty fourth street
yellow
off-handed sometime around march or
april
uh...
me if you want to do a search of true
articles uh...
the daily news and i definitely saw it
in the new york times might also be
uh... good source but that's really the
daily news here in new york
higher monthly visit personal program
this
i had a braves all
without
it would have some way of saying that it
actually did i detect the card
toward another head that would be a lot
trailing the one that was due in the
writing that would it would be a right
to get in there will be returned to
verify that actually happen with much
traffic through again
that's probably why
because what you're doing good another
turnstile she slept through it sorry
done with the new carpeting verify right
it is likely to again everything's fine
with another tristan sweated through
again misconduct again
yet again and verify rejected again and
that's why person's money
and i don't do any good
commander of the contract was a group of
several
pros who once worked hard to try to
resolve trying to do that
along i think the five-second delay is
the people who live safely through the
turnstile
if you are right the metro for just jump
into anything
tony commentary about the lives of stuff
on turnstiles or other people but i was
just totally uh... unrelated but still
useful
uh...
on the new turnstiles if you put a total
diamond weight over thirty seconds
roberto clemente approach
so uh... all the graves of uh... we're
waiting for your train to come after
putting her attempted in argonne if you
put a token in broker
the way around we lose it
andrew a brown for goes back
karunakaran referee
and uh... where did the white house
come after me
uh...
left people here are packed the metro
card will
as i'm fond of saying the best hacked
isetan detected hacked
uh... those people become very happy and
say what of money
of if they decide to go public
uh... i think eventually the transit
authority the transit police will boost
another investigating
and that's where being a leader of
limited uh... helpfulness not that i
don't want to do more
refers to herself but ari white means
sleeping in a large room that amanda
twelve cell
of the question i have to put forward as
if they but it was a hacked the system
what they actually do it to save a
dollar twenty five provide isn't that
really really really cheap anyways
islets
i mean i i didn't idea
i didn't do anything with part because i
A
uh... why do you know
i well i i couldn't afford to ride part
i mean this is ridiculous
notes that still speculation
good luck if you go to our new york
flood ideal morale virtually there is
some talk of going over to israel wears
him to a racist who were very wary
matter according to the world less on
weekends blessed bites
but that's one of the royal tour for her
sixty ninth stations have got uh...
mentor corporate stores
promoter is under system there almost
certainly have to employ
if we go to a system whereby its client
which actually for new york isn't uh...
minority thing for anybody who has
access to the employees worldwide very
uh... wrote for over twenty years ago
when i was younger
we're going to a very badly
there are some book somewhere on the
subways which will tell you in the
twenties uh... the
the system or during rush hour or two
sets of turnstiles
anna clearer parks in those days would
turn them on before rush hour
one would take two pennies on the picket
nickel
and uh...
sarah brady overall pick an offbeat
pricing is not new
i was a very good idea from a measure
partly because it will encourage
eluru when that you might as well charge
for a little when it's not fall because
it will tend to fill it up anyways
but also ideally thing that i find it
very shocking after i live in europe for
number of years
is the fact that use turnstiles at all i
think that's a safety problem
you know he had his eye i see what i
like the corporate world to do so
i believe it should be reprogrammed
chartering the jury
though he did you buy a ticket when
certain time on it
and uh... just entered the three cells
early for counting which usually the
police were put on a card aspiration
your ticket if you have a expired ticket
you have to pay for it on the spot or
the employee away
let your interest in israel's war in the
country united states or by return could
be stick in your party at right from the
turnstile
all
protruding numerous stories are told
jurors miles away if they do that
a lot of thing is that all pleasure ms
ghettoize before the both of us
jurors heard the regulars would be a
statement wake germans quebec and less
well it is
artists eight is that another german
term i've never seen it
all right but you're headed record and
are not alone
dot is saying is that allegedly european
you do well by the ticket and uh...
the ticket is worth you don't have to
show at leisure passport
except on certain buses you asked me to
get up front of the bus but
this is a different system of doing it
it's this kind of an honor system go to
our system that isn't forced me if you
are
kat breaking the code of honor the dead
you're fine
which is equivalent to about fifty
dollars or something
glorifying zero growth fairly heavy
any other questions from the white in
the middle
card
heil
heart
well this is the
since it was all sorts of artists
remarks on how to avoid
let's listen interesting thought but
uh... i'd like to carry out the
environment your cards that selma
newsstands and other outlets and like
tokens so far there's no restriction
that you have to use a metrocareer by it
who has a bachelors are tracked
everything else
as far as i know unlike tokens there is
no prohibition
but don't really believe holy roller
derby surprised if i was
there is a true disagree reinstalling
tokens for a third party that
notice alternatives to a third party
uh... which very interesting arrives
from back in a lot of sort of territory
utilities go everywhere
anything else
so sailors when you get something
institutional and in consideration for
something of value usually money
failures wrote about it like to thank
everybody
uh... if a lot more information about
the uh... handout that i wrote up
there and the you could hear concert
murder under a really cool to air india
too
they're the people that the
documentation for those
or manual
and they'll be able to get in touch with
me