so welcome that you're actually watching
my talk exploring macros in libreoffice
and white could be actually interesting
for you yes i'm stuff about me my name
is alex i'm called in said script on
twitter i also have a really awesome
blog no but actually every finding i
have and i'm allowed to publish is on my
blog so in case anything is unclear or
i'm talking too fast you will most
likely find a blog post about it
i'm working in a Paris as a penetration
tester for cue 53 like this gentleman
here I'm mostly a browser and web guy
but I started six years ago
to learn about PDF and how it works and
yeah I've actually spent all the six
years on PDF so yeah it's a nice read
and so I decided last year to move on to
another file format besides that I
flavor
I don't know counter-strike and I watch
CDP shark movies this is kind of this is
kind of important so what will be
discussed today a really simple overview
how I start learning a new file format I
will talk about my latest it's kind of a
simple finding in PDF but it showcased
how understanding the file from what
really helps you to find bugs when you
need them basically then we will move on
to Libre Office and some client-side
attack I found and how this would work
on the server side and we will talk
about sharks
so maybe you don't care about file
formats at all yeah you're kind of right
but also wrong nowadays more and more
stuff gets converted on the file on the
server side I don't know like just think
of JPEG to PNG or I don't know sometimes
you can upload some file document format
which skirts convert it to PDF for a PV
preview feature nobody really wants to
read the whole documentation and you
will see later why there's also image
magic which helped me a lot to actually
get into all this and the last part is
it's really fun and it's always nice to
have other people I can talk to who
suffer the same way I do
basically oh yeah the first awesome
movie I have to talk about and yeah
that's a real movie it's six at a target
six headed shark attack there is two
three four but not five they skipped
that one and this one is really terrible
for some reason he can walk on land with
his head okay um so how I approached
stuff with LibreOffice and it sounds
super simple but believe me it's easy to
make a mistake here
you really should install the latest I
don't know developer version Enterprise
version professional version whatever
the name is the reason is quite simple
because most of the time you can use the
application to use certain features and
the standard fuel which everybody's
using actually supports the feature as
well so it really helps you to get
proper coverage of the file format
another important point get the
documentation never expect that the
documentation is awesome and explains
everything and contains
everything because most of the time it's
old incomplete and really huge
yeah and then you complain about how it
makes no sense then you read it again
then yeah you start to look for keywords
the keywords can change for each
documentation because to just name it
differently all the time you click like
a maniac on every available feature in
the program for some reason it's always
the case that we just do not work when
you actually click on them yeah then you
start to Google you go to google search
for them the key word you should always
include is not working because then you
find forums where people complain the
feature is not working and you can see
some explanations how it should work and
stuff like that yeah
also you really have to read how the
actual file looks like when the program
created the file like with PDF it looks
completely different at first what you
expect when you read the documentation
and it's basically always true yeah you
have to get used to your roost
use standard text editors or sometimes
you read to need to read heck stuff or
just write some scripts so you can
actually understand what's going on and
then you can start mapping the
documentation and the features to the
actual actually created files and then
you repeat this steps for five years one
nice thing this is especially true for
windows check the file extensions as a
nice and example for Kiev or when you
install a double reader there is one
file extension called PDF XML which
doesn't really work anymore there's
actually a link trigger that you don't
have to download a module and when you
open it it's a 404 page and
if you want to be cool instead of using
dot PDF you can use dot Acrobat security
settings and it's the same identical
stuff oh yeah this movie maybe you can
already guess what this char can do
instead of water he lives on the beach
and for some reason that people decide
hey we will still want to be on the
beach so they have to fight him
don't worry sharknado is not even once
in this presentation yeah as promised
one my last example for file format
stuff we can do when you know the file
format really well as PDF over the years
I learned that PDF can send HTTP
requests we had two different languages
actually there is one executable just
handling comments and there is stuff
like XML support and the XML support is
actually important because last year
there was a github repo called bad PDF
and it's when when it was opened on
Windows with Adobe Reader it would send
a request on an to an SMB share of an
attacker and suddenly Adobe patched it
and I was kind of surprised so I decided
I can do that
it's not difficult so I think it took me
one day maybe maybe less and basically
what I used is the fact that XML is
supported so I used the XSL stylesheet
inside the XML structure which was
loaded from a remote SMB share and this
allows once again to leak the anti-male
hash and I didn't report it and it was
fixed nevertheless so I decided to do
another purpose because I had some time
and the pitch was basically they only
allow internal IPS or domains without
the dot so they don't break stuff for
companies I assume maybe you think about
using I don't know like ipv6 or yeah you
can represent IPs without a dot that's
also possible but actually on Windows
you don't even have to do that because
there is an awesome blog post from James
Porter from Google project zero where he
explains how Windows handles a lot of
the path stuff and he also mentions it's
a B shares or UNC paths as they are
called and basically in Windows what you
can do there are two devices called
Landman redirector and veptr free
director and all they do is tell Windows
if you want to use SB as the protocol or
that daf which is basically HTTP and you
specified as you can see it on the slide
and this works fine on Windows and it
contains no dot so this was another
bypass it was actually fixed and then I
stopped I got kind of bored but it shows
you that Windows is kind of awesome when
it comes to this kind of stuff oh yeah I
could talk a lot about this one because
Sharktopus is actually free movies yeah
and this one he fights whale wolf which
was created by an evil female German
scientists for some reason but don't
worry
octopus wins of course yes sorry
oh no I already told you it's a trilogy
so let's come to the LibreOffice I
started I think last year if I remember
correctly and the reason was image magic
is used a lot on the pagan to convert
any kind of stuff I was aware of image
tragic and Google project zero found a
lot of stuff in a ghost script which
allowed remote code execution and go
script is also supported by image magic
and I decided I tried it as well why not
and there's a file called delegates that
XML which contains a lot of file
extensions supported and I decided oh
okay it supports s Office which is
either OpenOffice or Libre Office and
that's basically the reason how I got
started with this I basically used
LibreOffice write a writer the whole
time during this time and there are some
differences between the different
applications but most of the time they
are quite similar actually what also is
quite nice is that the ODT file format
is sip-based file format so you can
easily modify it and there is an even
better file extension called F DT which
is one huge XML file which is basically
the same as ODT and you can easily
modify it and just play around and then
I grab the documentation so my Google
documentation there's like the open
document version 1.2 I just assumed
that's the latest one it has free parts
and then some additional specifications
and yeah when you combine them it's like
1200 pages to read I just decided I go
with the part one makes kind of sense to
start at the beginning
compared PDF it's not that much I did
wants to come the math and when you
combine on PDF all the important
documents you know over 4,000 pages I
think it's I compare it to Harry Potter
or stuff like that and it's kinda in
this area so maybe you know know now why
nobody wants to read the whole
documentation yeah after that I just
started to look for interesting keywords
and there are were actually quite a lot
laughs like script script sauce macro
script eventlistener that sound or
everything sounds like perfect but it
didn't contain any structure examples
which was kind of a pain and at first I
couldn't really find where I can use
macros I found like the settings and
stuff like that but I wanted to create
an example document and last year was a
brew con and I was maybe a little bit
tired from the day before and I didn't
want to go to the talk so i decided i
sit down and just google for one hour
and i will find this and and i actually
did I found the scripting framework your
eyes specification and it contains not
only how the script URI has to look it
also specifies which languages are
supported and it supports Python
JavaScript bean shell - yeah and basic
for some reason and I was wondering how
they actually support Tizen
and LibreOffice and OpenOffice actually
ship their own Python interpreter when
you install them
it's basically bundled in there so so
where was it actually hidden this nice
feature there are different places but
the first one I found is when you create
an hyperlink there is this really small
icon and it handles the macros for
hyperlinks and it also shows you which
events you can use I choose the mouse
over what it's called mouse over object
in this case so when the mouse is over
the hyperlink it the macro gets executed
and then I just used one of the
pre-installed macros from peyten because
I like peyten basically that was the
sole reason and then I checked the file
because finally I could have a look how
its created and that's the element
handling that and I think it's quite
obvious when you look at it that it
specifies a file which is on a file
system in this case it's table sample
type I then there is a dollar sign and
create table so I decided okay I will
find this file I found it and I looked
into it and of course it has a really
simple function called create table so
what would you try when you see that
maybe I can traverse anywhere so I
decided I try traverse down to the root
folder and just place testify and see
and create a function called test and
see if gets executed so I save that file
open that in deeper office move my mouse
over hyperlink and my script got
executed without any dialogue or warning
or whatsoever so this was the point
where about where
I was really convinced this is not
intended but I prefer to have proof of
concept which works without any
requirements basically so my first idea
was to use a different location you can
define like location user which is on
Windows the app data folder
Linux it's in the user folder as a user
home directory and I assume from Mac
it's the same and my idea was that I
triggered a download of my militia
malicious Libre Office file on Windows
specify a script inside the AppData
folder traverse down then traverse up
into the Downloads folder and specify
the same office file as a Python script
file so basically I would need to create
an LibreOffice file which is also valid
Python script and sadly that didn't work
would have been cool but LibreOffice is
actually really strict about data before
the zip header it allows for some reason
to merge two zip files and then it just
reads the later one but you can't add
anything else and so I kind of gave up
and decided I need another solution
so I actually read the code because it
was also written in Python and I
discovered that parameters are supported
so you not only can you load any Python
script and any Python function but you
can also pass parameters so of course
when you install Python there are a lot
of Python files so I had a look into all
the files which all Python files which
are shipped with LibreOffice by default
and there was one really interesting one
it's called pied octopi and it has a
function called temp file pager and one
parameter is called CMD it's quite short
and maybe you can already see what it
does when you understand Titan so
basically you can ignore the first line
lines it just creates a temp file and
then the CMD parameter gets passed to OS
dot system which is the windows shell in
this case and you can basically execute
any program download I don't know
whatever you want and the payload
actually looked quite simple in the end
all you need to do is Traverse three
folders down into the Python core
library a Python code file a folder of
LibreOffice and execute this nice
function and I did an awesome recording
of that of course if it works yeah so
it's really short so basically I created
this malicious structure such as shown
and yeah
[Applause]
of course because I've used peyten which
is shipped by default it works on
Windows Linux and Mac so that's quite
nice then I started to finally report
this issue and I made a little mistake
and reported it to the Box allure system
which is not intended for security bugs
in libreoffice so it got closed and I
responded with are you sure maybe have
another look here is an proof of concept
for Windows or maybe try that one and
then they were like oh that's a security
issue and moved it to the right location
which is actually a specific email
address you should write to and then
things got moved quite fast
Libre Office I can't remember how many
days but if they fix it really fast but
then they told me I have to wait because
OpenOffice is sharing some code with
openoffice and libreoffice are sharing
some code and they are vulnerable to the
traversal as well so they told me to
wait three months they didn't fix it and
then they decided I'm allowed to publish
the the details in OpenOffice the issue
is not as pay because they don't know
but they didn't actually implement the
parameter support but one problem is
OpenOffice is still vulnerable it's
still there still no patch available so
not sure if there ever will be a patch
for that actually but LibreOffice is
safe I can tell you that so as I already
mentioned there are other like macro
languages you can use the base one which
is we shall basic in the LibreOffice
world as actually quite interesting
because they ship a lot of
pre-installed bass macros and some of
them are really powerful so I try to
abuse them but they do not work I don't
know why you always get the same error
message wrong amount of parameters or no
parameters passed and I tried to use my
own bass function which I managed to do
with some googling skills and no matter
no matter the amount of parameters I
accept it always decided it's the wrong
amount of parameters so maybe I get it
working this year let's see they also
support JavaScript which is not really
JavaScript it's more like Java not true
always actually exists but it's a thing
yeah they also have support for Java
itself and bean shell but you actually
have to install the Java Runtime
environment and it must be available in
the path at least on Windows and Linux
and one problem to actually abuse them
is the way how they how the the path is
created because they don't use slashes
like for Python they just use dots and
no matter what I tried I wasn't able to
cause any kind of path reversals so I
couldn't abuse them sadly so let's talk
about the back end a little bit but
first we need more shocks by the way I
like this title so much much Evelyn
sharks the snow will run red with blood
I watched it it doesn't in case you want
to watch this movie it's not the same
movie as snow shark that's a different
one
but but but snow shock is actually
really awesome this one is also kind of
fun and no I don't know why it exists
both movies they act the same wait the
Sharks okay
so the first problem with macros on the
back end
I take image magic as an example because
at least in my opinion it's the most
used library to convert files and it
uses the headless mode of course of
LibreOffice
so all these mouse-over stuff doesn't
work it just doesn't execute any Mac
macros but there is thankfully more
events available which I've found weeks
later when you click on the right menu
option these are all the events which
are available for a document to react on
and not all of them get executed in in a
headless mode when the file could
actually converted but as an example to
highlight that bone called few created
gets executed so when you when you use
them they actually look really similar
to my clients ient exploit so I was like
oh yeah I can use my proof-of-concept to
attack backends as well yes sadly it's
not mentioned at the documentation but I
learned that when you use any kind of
event which is related to the whole
document itself it just decided to add
additional parameters sometimes it's
born sometimes there are two additional
parameters sometimes they're even four
so I couldn't use my proof of concept
because I needed to control the last
parameter and it was not an option
anymore
I tried to find another nice function to
abuse but sadly I couldn't
maybe I wasn't looking good enough but
what can you do
so I decided to give polyglot files
another go
so to include Python script inside my
malicious of office file on the back end
and in this case i can assume and i'm on
linux i tried to abuse the proc self
file descriptor folder which basically
contains all the open file descriptors
of the current application so i wanted
to see if i can specify the file
descriptor to the office file itself to
execute my pipe my own python script
basically that was my idea in theory it
actually would work because Python
supports super compressed files in
Python two and three actually and sadly
it didn't work because they use the
compile function and the compile
function accepts either a string a byte
string or an EPS
abstract syntax tree and in this case
it's always a string so we have the same
problem on the back end as on the client
side when I just include my Python
script at the beginning of the
LibreOffice file really Libre Office
won't posit but if I include any other
crap which Libre Office except at the
beginning Python will fail so once again
I was stucked and to this day I have no
solution for that so you would require
to have an additional file your full
control
on the backend and then you can actually
exploit it but thankfully dia other
features I discovered while playing
around with LibreOffice you can link to
external files you can load remote
images there is something called special
fields and at first I was hoping to
abuse all the objects in LibreOffice but
for some reason they do not work at all
in the headless mode
either there are like a blank object or
some stupid standard chip back arrow
will show up after conversion so I
basically gave up using them but one
feature which is kind of nice is the
linking to external files basically all
of the LibreOffice application allowed
to link to external files on the file
system and you can hard code basically
what you want to reference of course
most of time when you attack a back-end
based on Linux you try to read et Cie
passivity or stuff like that or et Cie
hosts or this kind of standard files but
there is a protection in place which
requires some kind of user interaction
to yeah I want to update the link I have
a bypass for this feature but it's
certainly not fixed so you have to wait
until it's fixed and I can publish it
how about blog post yeah external images
they mean they're quite simple you can
use file the file protocol you can use
HTTP HTTP this allows to test the
firewall of the server which is
converting your office file most of the
time when HTTP or HTTPS is allowed and
basically all ports are are allowed
that's kind of my experience so far
it's also nice to check if you can maybe
use DNS for some DNS channels to steal
data and the developer version supports
now PDF JPEG files so in case you want
to read local PDFs of the backend and
you know the location you can actually
include them in your office files and
after they are converted to I don't know
cheaper or whatever they will contain
the content of the PDF yeah special
fields which I actually just called
fields but I call them special fields
they always get updated also even in
headless mode so it doesn't matter in
which context in the on the right which
means like ODT files you can use
features like full file path which is
basically always the first thing I use
because it shows you the file structure
on the back end it shows you if your own
file name is used so that's sometimes
helpful not all the time sometimes you
can use the offer to get the current
user but only sometimes for some reason
I try to abuse the DD II which is quite
famous in in the Microsoft Office world
because it was abused a lot to execute
external programs sadly it doesn't work
the same way in LibreOffice so they
didn't port that feature and
additionally they have once again the
requirement when it's linking to an
external program and data you have the
kind of user interaction so it can't be
really abused to attack the back end
yeah the colic which is basically the
Excel version in libreoffice has no
special fields but it has of course
functions like Excel has and two years
ago I think if I recall correctly there
was a function you could abuse called
web service which allowed to read at a
local files or any HTTP or HTTPS
endpoint and the content is actually
stored inside the document without user
interaction actually they decided it's a
buck and fix that sadly so maybe when
you encounter really old LibreOffice
version you can use that
another cool feature I always abuse is
the info call because it allows you to
check if you're on the Linux or Windows
you can check the exact version of the
Libre Office application which is used
and yes set is the OS version is
hard-coded to Windows NT 5 actually
Microsoft Office supports this called
properly but Libre Office just used NT 5
so yeah you can see I still have some to
use I want to explore more about CDE in
general actually I want you to continue
with getting a working - injection on
the backend and check how the base macro
support actually works
there must be a way to get it working I
mean it's in there and somebody must
have used it properly yeah all the
objects seem interesting and just so
many features you can use and some of
them work done in the backend in
combination with imagemagick so maybe
some of you want to
me in this awesome journey we can watch
some be shark movies together so some
general security considerations yeah as
you this was this was just a short
overview of what you can do in such
complex file format what you have to
consider is when you use applications
like image magic you maybe don't even
realize you were supporting this file
format because when you upload like a
ghost script file or a LibreOffice file
with a dot jpg extensions extension or
some configurations of image magic or
maybe all of them I'm not sure now try
to sniff the actual type of the
application of the file so it it try it
looks into the file sees it's not a JPEG
file and then actually decides oh this
is an office file or this is a ghost
script file and suddenly you support the
file types and you never wanted to so
you have to implement some kind of logic
on your back ends so that you verify you
only support the file formats you want
to check or convert and this is actually
really important because we abuse this a
lot in the past when you want to disable
macro support in Libre Office good luck
I assumed there is like in just an easy
option
I don't want macros I couldn't find one
like maybe I didn't look hard enough for
pipe you can just delete Python script
at PI then the feature is completely
broken when you don't have to travel
travel runtime environment installed
you're fine in case you have it
installed and it
in your path you have to disable it in
libreoffice because it tries to actually
find it and then use it for macros of
course you can use containers if
possible because then you're just really
limiting the files and you can disable
network connections and stuff like that
and it's actually possible to run file a
filesystem jail for LibreOffice and it's
used in libreoffice online and yes
that's the thing there you can get the
commands and and the necessary files to
run Libre Office in filesystem jail oh
yeah
ghosts Chuck this movie is so ridiculous
so this is about a shark who died but
for some reason he's a ghost and as you
know ghosts can appear everywhere and
this shark can appear everywhere whereas
water everywhere in your bathtub in your
pool and you can kill him because he's
dead yeah he can he can he can eat
everybody he can even fly up into the
sky for some reason so this is my main
part actually of still five minutes left
I can show you some additional content
in case you want no who's that No
this is not really file format related
but it's windows maybe if I heard about
dot URL files on Windows
they are super old and still work in
Windows 10 and I found this issue
because of an ascetic necessity we often
had one abilities where we can execute a
program on Windows but we weren't able
to pass any parameters and just opening
calculator and CMD all the time is kind
of boring I wanted to prove that we can
actually execute our own code so when
you execute you can of course point to
an SMB share or ripped-off share and
execute an executable from there but
then it's blocked there is like this
nice warning box do you really want to
execute it so I have had to find a way
around that and there was a nice thing
called DLL hijacking which still still
is a thing and I decided to use the docs
URL file format because you can execute
it from a remote SMB share without a
warning you can define the application
which should get executed and you can
define the working directory and you can
point the working directory to your
remote as a be sure which is awesome so
what will happen when you execute a lot
of executables stored in Windows and
point the working directory to your SMB
sure that's basically what I did and I
found that veined of CPL at least on two
systems and one VM it worked
and on one VM on my cubes it doesn't
work for some reason it still tries to
load it the remote DLL but then
something fails I'm not sure yeah it's
cute
must be cute to secure
yeah but basically how it works you can
execute main dot Cpl which will is the
settings for your mouse and then it will
try to load master DLL from the remote
SMB share and when it's there it gets
executed and that's basically how I did
it and have beautiful videos somewhere
yeah in this case I just used my local
seed dollar share but I verified it with
remote SMB shares it's not worried so as
you can see there is the mouse DLL this
is the test dot your arrow file yeah you
don't see the extension in case you're
wondering yes you can change the icon
because there is parameter for icon you
want to use less you and yet this dot
URL file basically contains this payload
here and now you will see what happens
and now it's open that's basically the
normal window in case yeah I reported
that to Microsoft there is a registry
key you can set which nobody does Libre
Office actually had a bypass which
allowed me to abuse that but somebody
reported it before me and now they have
a similar behavior to Microsoft Office
and what they do they actually pass the
dot UL file and check the executable it
points to so when you try to use the
remote SMB dot URL file as a link in
Microsoft Office you will see an
dialogue with do you really want to
execute main dot CPL and then you have
to click like two times yes yes so it's
not really nice so at least Microsoft is
aware of that so yeah that's that thank
you thank you Alex I think we have time
for a few questions anyone getting tired
here we have one let's see if I can make
this work yep I can I think it's already
up hello interesting talk thank you I
don't know if you already said this but
the when imagemagick
uses libre office for file conversion
does it also support Microsoft Office
document formats oh yeah it does so you
can you can use you can use certain
features of Microsoft Office in Libre
Office because it's supported you can
also use the file extensions dot like
you can literally use a created file
from Microsoft Office sometimes you have
to change the file extension in case
there are some file extensions
restrictions but in general yeah it
works so did you look anything into the
conversion or import feature so yeah I
tested some of them but so far nothing
came up but I just just got started
awesome thank you
so anyone else yeah I also can talk
about Bishop movies I've 20 more I can
talk about hi thanks it was great awk
have you tried so I I don't know
Microsoft Office supports the oddity
format and if yes can you every was dead
in Microsoft Office yeah I tried that
but microsoft office supports libre
office file format because I actually
dis lights were first created and first
in the LibreOffice impress what it's
called
then in PowerPoint and then back to the
profits so yeah you can switch between
them but many features do not work like
the micro support is not at all there
sadly and yeah most stuff basically just
gets ignored by Microsoft Office sadly
anyone else here yes sir
what be short movie is most be and
therefore most awesome most awesome
would say two-headed shark attack is
really funny because to talk so much
all the time the worst one all
the mega sharks are pretty terrible
I think mega shark versus mechatronic
shock
and yeah it's a real movie by the way
the free movies meet with Mega Shark
thank you Alex for this amazing talk
[Applause]