kind of attacks can happen as a result
of that and we'll also be covering the
mitigations for them a brief
introduction about myself my name is
summit I work for the product security
team at Citrix I'm a web and mobile
application security enthusiast I've
spoken at a bunch of conferences awfully
it including Def Con China lack at Asia
app sec USA good blue and some more in
the past so for those who do not know
what what is basically it's an open
standard for token based authorization
and basically as an end user you can
authorize a third-party application to
access the resources resources on your
behalf we'll be covering why what came
into being we'll also cover the flow in
a nutshell and various terms that I'll
be using across the presentation and
obviously the grants that what provides
there are four different grants we'll be
covering two of them because those are
more relevant for the current discourse
and open ID Connect which is basically a
by-product of worth and it is used for
authentication
whereas what is used for authorizing
clients will be covering or these
attacks and the mitigations for them and
finally you have a short Q&A session
some disclaimers ideas presented or
personal are not speaking on behalf of
my employer some content has been
borrowed from Rand David Campbell slides
on or 2.0 and mobile devices or zero and
RFC documents on what humor is mine if
you like it drop me a mail if you don't
you can blame security first first all
right I also have references to Avengers
infinity war but no spoilers or for
Avengers in game so if you haven't
watched the end game you are still good
but if you haven't watched the infinity
war then you deserve the spoilers okay
so why what
so consider this scenario where Linden
wants to access your contacts from Gmail
and in order to do so it prompts you for
your password on LinkedIn website now
this clearly raises eyebrows and it's
suspicious because LinkedIn you can't
really give your credentials to a third
party application so the problem here is
that LinkedIn with your credentials can
do far more than just access the
contacts from Gmail there are other
drawbacks as well LinkedIn would be
required to store your credentials which
is again a no-go Google will be required
to save your credenza port
password-based authentication and access
cannot be revoked from one single
third-party application without revoking
it from all the third-party applications
because the access is based on your
password and if you change your password
it gets teens for every third party so
this is where what came in and it
devises a mechanism for providing
LinkedIn in our case to just access the
contacts on behalf of the user
from Gmail and nothing else so it's a
protocol for delegating authorization
supported by web mobile and native
applications an access grant to a
specific third-party application can be
revoked and the scope of access or the
permissions can be constrained it also
avoids sharing of your credentials with
the third party application and as I
mentioned it is also it also sets a base
for an authentication protocol called
Open ID Connect so before we move on to
the flow I would want to introduce the
various entities that are typically
involved in a lowered setup firstly the
resource owner this is the guy who's
going to grant access to the third party
application to access the resources on
its behalf this is generally the end
user and finally this one is the
application or the relying party or
the client all these three terms are
synonymous and this will be the
application that is requesting access to
the protected resources on behalf of the
user then the resource server this is
the server hosting the users resources
which is Gmail in our case and the
authorization server this is the server
that authenticates the user and
generates an access token when the user
approves of the authorization this was
Google in our case and finally the
browser so all of these entities will be
used on the next slide not not this one
just on the next slide
so this one is a mandatory step that is
required for the authorization server to
know who all are the clients that are
going to request authorization so client
registration needs to happen has a step
before the earth exchange happens so in
order to register your client
application you provide your application
name website logo and a redirect URI the
redirect URI is used by the
authorization server to redirect the
auth code and the access token and after
you register of all your eyes of the
client you get a client ID and a client
secret the client ID is not sensitive
information it can be made public
whereas the client secret has to be kept
confidential and in case an application
cannot keep the client secret
confidential it should avoid using the
client secret completely and this
happens in case of single page
applications or native applications
because the applications can be reverse
engineered and the client secret can be
extracted from them okay so the resource
server or is there and the relying party
or the client is stack exchange in this
case and we also have Google as our
authorization server so when the client
needs to request authorization or the
relying party needs to request
authorization it will show it shows a
prompt saying sign in with Google or
sign in with Facebook let's say you
chose Google the client will generate an
authorization
request and the browser will use reader
get redirected to Google's authorization
page which is where the user will enter
his credentials approved of the
authorization and that is when the auth
code gets generated and sent back to the
redirect URI and the redirect URI is
obviously Stack Exchange is redirect URI
on on fetching the auth code the relying
party exchanges this auth code for an
access token by hitting the
authorization servers token endpoint and
once it receives the access token it can
fetch the resources on behalf of the
user so that covers like the OAuth flow
in a nutshell we'll be talking about in
more detail as we move it so the only
difference between what an open ID
Connect is that what is for authorizing
or sharing resources and open ID Connect
is meant for authenticating the user so
the access tokens are consumed by the
resource server because they prove
authorization to the resources and the
identity token is consumed by the client
in order to populate the UI stating that
this is the user who's authenticated so
the flow entirely remains the same the
only difference comes in to the last
step where you get an access token and
in addition to an access token you also
get the identity token now this identity
token is consumed by the relying party
and it is not sent to the resource
server access tokens are generally
opaque and they are also called bearer
tokens so when I say opaque it means
that they don't have a structure to them
if you try and decode them it will not
make any sense
it just informs the API that you're
hitting that the bearer of this token
has been granted access to this API
whereas identity tokens are jour tokens
and they have a structure to them if you
decode them they will comprise of claims
so you the claims are nothing but
statements
stating the identity of the user and as
I mentioned before or the jaw tokens or
the identity tokens will be consumed by
the client application dots are
self-contained there's some more
information in jorts on this slide so
jorts are self-contained which means
that you can verify the authenticity and
integrity of the job that is coming to
you without ref referring to another
third-party the reason for that is that
jorts are signed so you can actually
verify the signature and validate
whether their integrity is intact the
comprised of three components one of
them is the header then the payload and
the signature the header portion
comprises of mainly the algorithm used
for hashing the payload the payload and
what kind of token it is the payload
contains these claims which we saw in
the previous slide and the signature
path just mentions the hash of the
payload and header all right
so in the authorization request that the
client makes to the authorization server
the client embeds some scopes which is
basically permission that it is
requesting this may be like it might
request the email of the user or the
profile of the user so some data
regarding the user and once the user
approves of these scopes in the identity
token that is generated these claims are
embedded by the authorization server
these claims are also available at the
user info endpoint on the authorization
server so the client can actually
request for them and scopes allow
applications to request delegated access
so basically if you have a scope saying
mail dot read the application is
requesting read access to your mails and
the authorization decision basically is
made by combining three entities which
is the male the permission that you're
granting who's the user for which the
male belongs and the entity that is
requested which is the male in our case
so if you have mailed or treat'
permission the only the males of user
who is the red one will be access and if
there is some other users mail they will
not be accessible to this particular
client coming on to the various ground
types there are four of them one is the
authorization code grant an otherwise
the implicit grant resource on a
password credential grant and Klan
credential grant all of these are used
in different situations or scenarios I
will be covering the first two but
before we start with them I'm
introducing the real actors small
analogy a resource server will be the
soulstone and obviously a Red Skull
right now possesses that sole store so
he is the resource owner and Thanos
wants it and this is the application
relying party or the clan and Gomorrha
will be at authorizing authorization
server so tano's tries to access the
source indirectly and he gets an
unauthorized response and it asked the
resource owner for giving him approval
by redirecting it to authorization
server so you get redirected to the
authorized endpoint on the authorization
server and the user then approves of the
authorization and that is when you get
the auth code back redirected to the
application so Tanis has been authorized
to access the resource server now but
there's one additional step in the auth
code ground flow which requires you to
exchange the auth code grant auth code
for an access token and for this the
client needs to authenticate to the
authorization server by using the cly
secret and the client ID so that's where
the client ID and client secret come in
handy and once you hit the token
endpoint with the client secrets the
client this token is generated by the
auth server and returned to the client
the client can then access the resources
with the help of the token embedded in
the header so tano's finally gets the
soulstone he's happy so what are the
benefits of the auth code step you could
have directly returned an access token
from the author but the auth code
actually helps you to provide the
ability to authenticate the client so
even if the auth code gets leaked it
cannot be exchanged for an access token
by an attacker the attacker needs to
know client secret and that is when can
exchange the auth code for an access
token additionally auth code gets
exposed to the browser in the URL when
the redirection happens but access token
is returned in the response body by a
server to server call from the odd
server to the client so therefore it
avoids the leak of access token via the
browser Earth quadrants are frequently
used for web applications so that's
their use case and if you see the
traffic it would look something like
this yeah this is the authorization
request and it comprises of the
authorizes servers fqdn
followed by the authorized endpoint and
then the restore response type which is
set as code for a cg which is
authorization code grant and then the
client ID and the redirect URI where the
authorization server will redirect the
auth code and in the response the auth
code is being redirected to the client
with a state parameter which is used to
avoid CSRF attacks we'll come to that
and when you hit the token endpoint with
this auth code you're also supposed to
specify the client secret so this is the
client making the request it can send
its client secret
the auth code and that's when the access
token is returned and has returned to
the redirect URI again all right the
second of them implicit grant pretty
much alike
orthe quadrant but with the difference
that the auth code is not generated that
is not sent back to the client but
instead our token is directly generated
and sent back to the client
tarah still gets the resource so he's
happy so if you see the traffic it would
look something like this
there you have the authorized endpoint
being hit again with the same parameters
and then you get back an access token
directly so implicit grant was earlier
used for single page applications and
mobile applications or native
applications but off late everybody is
recommended to use earth quadrant
without the client secret for native
applications so this slide summarizes
which grant to use in what scenarios so
as I mentioned implicit grant was used
for single space applications earlier
even for native applications but
nowadays we are using a CG with an
additional layer of defense in depth
called pixie which is proof key for code
exchange and we come to that will cover
pixie as well in the slides the rest of
the to grant types are used in these
cases which will not cover right now
because we have shortage of time so next
up is why DC open I reconnect in context
of native applications over all the
steps remain the same the only nuance
that comes into play is when the auth
code needs to be redirected to the
native application and since the native
application is running on the mobile
device there is another attack surface
that gets exposed because it's not a
server to so call it's like more of
untrusted device where the auth code has
more chances of getting leaked so first
step users need to access some protected
resource or the client opens the browser
redirects the user to the authorized
endpoint and once the user signs in the
user is asked to approve off the
requests made by the client and once the
user approves the authorization endpoint
generates an auth code it needs to send
it back do the native application and
for that the browser has to do an HTTP
redirection to invoke the native
application with the auth code and
that's where you have to register
callbacks and if you see here the
application has registered a custom URL
scheme
XCOM dot microbe dot my app and when the
browser receives the auth code on this
scheme it knows which I have to invoke
because the application has registered
for this custom URL scheme and that's
done this way so if for Android in the
manifest file you can define the URI
scheme and whenever the browser receives
this custom URL scheme it will redirect
it to the native application which has
registered for this scheme once the
application receives the auth code it
can exchange it with the token endpoint
and it will get back the bearer token
with the Refresh token as well and then
the application can use this bearer
token to access the resource which is
the API here by embedding this is done
by by emailing the bearer token as an
authorization header so if you see here
this is the authorization header with
the bearer token embedded so that brings
us to a first attack scenario called
authorization code intercept attack
and the preconditions for this attack is
that the authorization code grant is
used and in native applications the
client secret is not used because native
applications can be reversed and you can
get the client secret and the attacker
manages to register a custom URL scheme
by using a malicious application on the
same device so this custom URL scheme it
was supposed to be used by the
legitimate application and the attacker
has registered for that callback with
his malicious application so you can see
where this is going because once the
authorization code is returned in step
number three the browser will because of
the HTTP redirection will try to invoke
the legitimate application with that
auth code but since the malicious
application has also registered for that
custom URI scheme the attacker gets the
auth code using his malicious
application and once this auth code
reaches the malicious application the
attacker can redeem this auth code for
an access token by hitting the
authorization service token endpoint and
obviously it becomes that most important
to handle these redirections carefully
instead of using custom URL schemes
which is this there is no naming
Authority for them so basically anybody
any malicious application can register
for the same custom URL scheme as the
legitimate application so instead one
should use claimed HTTP scheme URI
direction so the scheme remains HTTPS
followed by the fqdn
under the control of the application and
this is where the identity of the
destination application is guaranteed to
the authorization server by the
operating system no other application
can register for the same fqdn
because it is owned by one particular
client
which brings us to peak peak AC which is
pronounced as pixie and it's called
proof key for code exchange so pixie
adds some elements to the regular earth
Code round flow to ensure that even if
your authorization code gets leaked an
attacker cannot exchange it for an
access token so in addition to the in
the authorization request what the
client does is that it generates a code
verifier which is nothing but an
alphanumeric string kept confidential
with that particular application which
is generating it and it generally takes
the hash of it which is called the code
challenge which is symbolized by T
followed by whatever code verify it is
applied on so that's the hash value of
code verified and then you're supposed
to send the code challenge method which
is the hash function you've used over
the code verifier so basically you're
sending the hash value here the
authorization endpoint stores that
hashed value with it and then it even
redirects the browser to the client with
the auth code and this can be
intercepted by the malicious client so
the malicious client is having the auth
code now so in request number C where
you have to exchange the code for the
token the legitimate client needs to
send the code verifier which is the
unhoused value the message that is has
digest or just which is hashed so the
code verifier is not known to the
malicious application and that's what
provides the security here basically the
token endpoint will receive this code
verifier hash it again using the same
code challenge method and then verify
whether the value matches the code
challenge which was received earlier in
request B and if it does only then the
access token is sent back otherwise it's
not so this is a small and sweet demo or
faulty pixie implementation on Microsoft
IDP and it goes so if you notice here I
have these last three requests one of
them is going to the authorized end
point the other one is going to the
login end point and the third one is
going to the token end point so the
request that goes to the authorized end
point has the redirect URI
yep so if you notice here or there's the
redirect URI of the native application
and then the code challenge which is the
highest value of the code verified and
then followed by the code challenge
method then I'm redirected back to the
login page and I send my credentials and
then the server when it receives that
login request it generates an auth code
for me and redirects the auth code to
the native application which is
happening here so you're getting
redirected back to the native
application with the auth code and
finally the native application when it
receives the auth code it hits the token
endpoint with the code verifier and the
redirect URI and the auth code
so just sending it to the repeater
trying it out and since it has the auth
code and the code very fair value I get
back the identity token access token and
refresh tokens in the response but the
problem with Microsoft's IDP was that it
wasn't validating the code verifier here
so even if you remove the code verifier
completely you still get back the valid
access token identity tokens and refresh
tokens and since there is no client
secret involved if your auth code gets
leaked through the same attack that we
saw earlier this can result in a
malicious application redeeming your
auth code for access tokens so the RFC
unpick C actually mandates that all
native applications must implement pixie
and all the authorization servers must
support pixie in order for the
applications to use it but Microsoft
clearly wasn't validating the code
verifier which resulted in a in many
native applications are being
compromised which were using the same
endpoints login dot Microsoft online
comm and then we have the cross-site
request forgery on the client redirect
URI so let me explain this with the help
of a flow diagram so we have the
attacker here who is publishing a
malicious web site and the clutter and
the user or the resource owner happens
to visit this malicious web site the
malicious web site then generates a
forged response with the attackers or
code in it and what happens next is that
the client will extract exchange this
auth code for an access token with the
auth server and it gets back the
attackers access token instead of the
legitimate users so basically if he
accesses the resource
he led back the attackers
instead of the users resources so this
is like a login CSRF which happens with
what flows so there are two mitigation
strategies for this one is to embed a
state parameter in the authorization
request since there is no authorization
request the attacker has no way of
knowing the state parameter it has no
way of adding the state parameter in the
response to the auth request which is
this one and the clan needs to validate
whether the state parameter is present
and if it matches the one that was sent
in the auth request and that's how the
attack will get detected the second way
to do is and do it is using a region
header check because the malicious we
have said generates this authorization
response the client can check what kind
of origin this respond response is
coming from and then take a decision
whether to proceed to exchange the auth
code for an access token or not and the
most commonly found one is open
redirects on the client there are few
assumptions are here so we're using the
implicit grant just for convenience it
could be both Quadrant as well but just
to show the flow in a simpler way I've
considered using the implicit grant and
the client registered registers a
redirect URL with the pattern client
some site dot example /cb question mark
star so clearly there's a wild card at
the end and the attacker can actually
add anything to it additionally the
client is exposing open redirects using
the redirect to parameter so all that
the attacker needs to do is trick the
victim into opening this malicious web
site evil dot example and from evil dot
example the attacker can initiate an
authorization request with the redirect
URI specified as client Sam site dot
example which is exactly matching this
/cb with a question mark redirect to
client or evil example /cb
so since the client is exposing this
open redirector what will happen is that
whence this request reaches the auth
server the pattern matches because there
was a wild card at the end we've just
added a redirect to parameter at the end
so matches and the auth server is going
to redirect you back to the client with
an access token which is here present as
a URI fragment and once this response
reaches the client the client since it
is exposing an open redirect it'll
redirect you to the client evil dot
example and the waiver our browsers
behaved is that if this redirect does
not contain any you are a fragment the
browser's will attach the reader the URL
fragment from the previous response and
had it appended to client evil example
so that's that's how browsers behave
they try to add tag-along more
information to whatever you are
accessing so they will naturally uh or
inherently act the access token URI
fragment to this particular domain which
is the evil domain and that's how your
access token could get leaked so if
you're using auth quadrant and the same
situation is there with the same
assumptions you could end up leave
leaking your auth code instead of the
access token so let's say that the
client com was exposing this read I was
exposing a reopen redirect with the
parameter redirect URL and it had an
integration with Google Drive so when
you hit this particular endpoint you are
redirected to Google Drive to authorize
the client to access your drive
resources and once you're thrice the
client redirects you back so sorry the
auth server redirects you back to the
client and since the client is exposing
the open redirect it will redirect you
to attacker.com with the auth code
appended to it
so as a mitigation clients must not
expose open rewrites that's the best
case clients must memorize which ad
server this enter North request to and
ensure that any subsequent requests go
to the same authorization server Klan
should use a CG which is the auth code
grant flow so that even if the odd code
gets leaked there is still a need of the
client secret to be present in the next
request so the attacker who gets it
needs to know the client secret to
exchange that code for an access token
so small joke on Thanos again Thanos is
a client who is exposed the open
redirects and this is the dialogue
between Gamora when Thanos snaps his
finger and returns all right so fishing
or using you stressin auth servers so
this is a simple example
pretty straightforward or where you are
misusing the trust that the user has in
authorization server so what you're
going to do is you can register or an
attacker can register with the
authorization server with this
particular redirect URI so basically his
registered or malicious client on the
aughts over and then it can send a
forged uri to the user since the you URI
has authorization server's fqdn the user
will trust it I will he may click on it
and if he does what will happen is that
the scope here is an invalid scope so
the authorization server will basically
generate an error I'll redirect you back
to the attackers domain because that is
where the request is coming in from and
that has been mentioned here in the
redirect URI and since this redirect URI
is already registered on the auth server
the server will think okay I can
redirect you back to the client but
still I'm not going to give you anything
else I'm not going to give you or code
but I can still redirect you so you're
eventually gonna get redirected to
attacker.com
without the auth code but then you can
do a lot of phishing attack because the
user thinks he's visiting also and he
eventually ends up on attacker.com so s
authorization server needs to take a
call whether to redirect or not and he
may choose to inform the user about the
redirect and that's the only way the
user can save himself okay then the mix
of attack this attack happens in
scenarios where the client interacts
with multiple authorization servers and
one of them made Guru or turn malicious
and the goal is to obtain the auth code
or access token by tricking the client
or the application to sending it to the
attacker control auth server -
preconditions I'm gonna use a CG here
which is the auth quadrant but it
applies to implicit grant as well it is
and the client is using multiple odd
server that's the only precondition and
the other one is about that the client
is using the same redirect URI for all
the authorization servers so the
redirect URI is not authorization server
specific so I'm gonna take the example
of two AAS or motivation servers one is
Google one is Facebook and let's just
assume that Facebook goes malicious no
offense to Mark Zuckerberg of Facebook
it's just that Facebook has been in news
of late and let's see the flow using
this diagram so what happens is that
lets say LinkedIn shows you that you can
log in through Facebook or Google and
the user chooses Facebook so the
authorization request is generated
Facebook's auth server and Facebook
since it's malicious it will redirect
you to Google's odds over so you get
shown now you are shown the Google's
also a page instead of Facebook that's
the only place where the user can get to
know that there's something going on
but if the user doesn't pay attention
then he may authorize the request and an
auth code gets generated and is
redirected back to the redirect URI of
the client and the client still thinks
that the earth was J authorization
request was initiated with Facebook so
it will try to hit facebook's
authorization server to redeem this auth
code but once Facebook gets the auth
code it will try to redeem it at
Google's auth token endpoint and get
back a token for the user so Facebook
can now use that token to access victims
Google's resources so the idea here is
to you know this odd server could
actually return an issuer parameter so
that the client knows that the auth code
that it is receiving is from not is not
from the intended also so in our case
the issuer would have been Google
because that's the entity that was
generating the auth code but the client
thought that it is initiating an author
request to Facebook so that's where the
attack would have got detected
alternatively the clients could use
authorization so a specific redirect URI
as like so clan comm glueten Google
redirect URI client comm FB redirect URL
and the client when it in its initiates
thoughts request it knows that it's
Facebook that it it's redirecting to so
the redirect so the auth code should
come back to Facebook's redirect URI but
if it comes to Google's redirect URI
then obviously there's something fishy
going on so the client will probably
detect it and then finally I thought
I'll give you some defense-in-depth tips
so that you can reduce the damage even
if your access tokens or auth code get
is getting lead
so what if your access token gets leaked
what can you do best
can you still reduce the damage so there
are ways of tying the access token to
the audience which is the resource
server so you can have access tokens map
to be used only to certain resource
servers and that's called audience
restricted access tokens there are
multiple ways of doing it and I can't
really cover them here because of the
shortage of time but you can read about
it on the RFC's that i have in the
references the other thing that you can
do to avoid the misuse of an access
token by an attacker is that you can map
it to the sender so basically these are
called sender constrained access tokens
so when you're generating an access
token when your OAuth server is
generating an access token it binds this
access token to a specific client or the
application so even if that access token
gets leaked to a malicious entity it
cannot access your resources so again
there are multiple ways of doing it but
you know you can always read about it I
am NOT going to cover this right now
what if your auth code gets leaked so
maybe you can have the server what
server implement the one-time use it's
restriction for your auth code so if
let's say your auth code gets lead the
legitimate application uses that OAuth
code and the malicious application also
uses that auth code so what the server
can detect this obviously because it is
receiving two different requests with
the same oath code and once the server
receives two different requests what it
can do is that it can invalidate all the
access tokens that were generated with
the previous auth code the other thing
that the what server could do is that it
can bind the authorization code to the
redirect URI so once you hit the
authorize endpoint of the es the auth
server Maps the auth code it generates
to the redirect URI
and once the attacker tries to redeem
the auth code the server needs to check
whether the access token that it is
sending to the reader QRA the redirect
URI needs to match the auth codes
redirect the auth code mapping before it
did so basically you have a mapping of
the auth code and the redirect URI and
the server needs to validate whether the
requests coming in is actually in the
request that is coming in the redirect
URI is matching or not so you can have
the auth code bound to the redirect URI
if you happen to use implicit grant and
your access token is getting leaked in
the browser's history
avoid using redirect based access token
returning the access token you can
actually use form post response methods
so that your access token is not exposed
in the URI also you should avoid using 3
node 7 times redirects that's a no-go
for sure because your credentials may
leak to the client and more on it at
this particular RFC you can have a look
at it alright these are some very
important references that you should go
through and if you want to implement the
perfect or what solution I know it's a
huge list but that's what things we do
for security all right so all right so
that brings me to the end of my talk and
has some contact information just in
case you'd like to drop me a message so
thank you for your attention and that's
all I'm up to take questions
all right
see thank you that was a great talk
let's see if we have any questions in
the crowd the Hansa I know you're
getting a little bit tired but come on
guys
it must be one question it's probably
candy in it for you really you covered
everything man this is amazing you
should hire you to do this guy's stuff
so no hands up well I'm sure you can get
in touch with you on Twitter or email if
they have any questions afterwards or
during the party of course which will
hop in after the next talk so thanks
again summit that was great thank you so
much fun
[Applause]