okay so we have agreat talk until now
by nick of soul some of those uh... can
cope
and uh... capital
thanks
so long
recommend her body to this awesome
called friends and to my talk that is
about as the title states
uncovering as there are days and advance
housing techniques
uh... you had seen several methods and
this talk about how to get the two
routes to successfully unlocked
unix
and windows solaris
and more
uh... in case you have questions or
comments please ask a comment right
after the presentation
because of the presentation is displayed
on the council i'd on the screen
uh... we will start with the short
introduction about who i am
then i will introduce you to the topic
of the car and
presentation off the what's we are going
to discuss the main topic which i
entitled
ortiz and the rush for public with her
abilities
must advance causing techniques
the reason why i put
rush for a public banner abilities until
the title is that
as some of you might know
i did put much work into exploring
whether abilities
that had been already publicly announced
yeah as a side note
the discussion of the speech can be
applied to any operating system
including the window series of operating
systems
most off the detail yet directly apply
to unix systems like lineups
b_s_t_ or solaris
the upcoming slide contains information
about myself
so who am i
realize actually come on in both windows
and linux it's and will display the
county logged in user
just mention that
uh... mine a mystical also bylaws added
some of you well no
the nickname ideas through all of my
time of the hacker this thing called
i let them grow up to germany
and uh... billet shibuya frank vogel
all my family is greek so off both of
our parents
as some of you
might have noticed by reading my public
runner ability advisories
i feel connected to mike recruits
i have a strong personal i'd like a king
self-rule
rediscovering wilder abilities writing
exploits upright all to finding out how
the self brown facing us running
i started being active with packing
before the date displayed on the screen
i can do you remember bill
better brought my plus reworking exploit
back in two thousand three
and the past life been working as a
penetration tester richard
with the company base in germany nearby
mileage
yen
cowardly i do want their ability
research
so i would just proceed with
introduction of the public today
from weekend defined brodeur abilities
since ever colossus
that have been developed over the course
of time
every colossal blunder abilities has its
advantages and disadvantages
remote exploits
can be tried as exploits that when run
by the attacker
gain access to the system silently and
without user intervention
scanf s can be additionally programmed
to support
a remote exploits it means of
discovering vulnerable so gross
sometimes remote exploits do not used to
the desired privileges on the remote
system
so the class of local road exploits
can be used to gain elevated privileges
will corrode exploits can be used
uniquely to at the scene a real revered
sect are already has access to the
system
aroudn the informal when their abilities
out the client side with her abilities
that when
exploitative attack
entities and organizations companies
individual users
the clients at the texts nominee require
user intervention of the victim
and this particular talk
i would especially illustrate
how remote softer false
remotely their abilities i discovered an
exploitive
most parts of his discussion can be
applied to local and client
when their abilities
that's for sure discovering doing our
abilities since kisi
uh... program program as around the
world constantly do mistakes
and introduce
flawless especially
when you reach us all persons are
implemented
an interested the tech up there for can
be like in discovering grow their
abilities but looking into
about c_b_s_ bills
well for example reversing updates
every new technology brings new
possibilities for the attack not
the reason for this
is that new technologies
are in nature and only get secure after
several use of patching in crafting
discovering flaws can be fun when you
have to be appropriate to set up
like you would see in the upcoming slide
about the environment that needs to be
set out to be successful
there is no secret everyone cooks with
water just needs passion time experience
and good music
now to the environment
that needs to be build-up before
auditing for werner abilities can begin
good will definitely
needs virtual machines
the reason this
ritual machines can be easily installed
and use nowadays
the amsa perfect or proposals
many operating systems let's say targets
can be installed
the running of the ems can be used to
for adding offset some values for a
different exploit targets to
i remember the time i was not aware of
virtual machines
i wanted to exploit a window flow and
had bird like
tamil more cds
every cd containing its own windows
version of windows language
so i took the city's one-by-one and
started on real aqua
wada time over half
if you can't have it so simple with
little machines
digest installed software said they'd be
m
and if the gossip rating plates you
won't loose dot dot
except the roof that's inside the bme
but that's a different story
what example setup this as you will also
see in the next slide
their windows seven aust
with several guests installed like
window a split up some previous these
embarrass eighty six and so on
as a side note
you can easily do cal debugging
they're using pipes
without using the real seria live on the
real hard work
so this is an ob it wanted shoe as
neutral machines
there is a lot of stuff that you can use
to do it for this propose
the embargo workstation oracle
virtualbox julia malone
and so on
diablo sleepy noviembre book station
over the years
that's the screened on behalf of the two
machine
running for freebsd inside avital seven
host insulation
it illustrates
illustrates quite pretty why g_m_'s have
many advantages
at the left name
you can see the operating systems but
never installed and already bill away
lable for booting
by the way
previously previous iran's
very stable unsaid bbm and installation
is quick another upset is that the hot
the stuff that the m gross according to
the use it should
so you don't need like twenty ppm
first place
the next slide
will be about important to us that a
person he prefer i'd recommend when
doing out its
the tools
a bigot launchers is the ability to
program right coat
so a bit too i included is the kind of
programming language the one you like
most
interpreted languages like peril
or pipes on
can be used to easily for pos software
developed
and bright exploit itself
and other proposals the high-level
programming language s
have this writing all tools
take the example you want to observe
processes how they're on the set raw
some positives require native codes and
need to be programmed to to compile
language like c
especially local exploits tend to be
written in c
another example our pc exploits
and of course it looks
much more lead to code in c
especially when you when they had a
common so a lot of them back to exploit
the startling unix tools are present
most of you will have grew up with them
already
are important investigate box
and my experience shows me that
especially traces like esterase pull it
looks
trust kate race and kate donvan bsd
ansel artists
advised to use because one can see
what's happening
for sample we should packets to a
service
with easter recess mechanics ecstasy
what's happening but the packets arrive
by attaching to the running service
process
house races a system called plaza
lecture us
the key ok trace three dom combination
has nearly the same function they'll
they use information coming directly
from the colonel
there for the cake
ankit racing to dump
x_-rays
disguised as a massive too busy to a
traces library cards in contrast to the
either hit cities that place system
colts
directly related to its for windows like
the post this morning to all of the
distributed by microsoft
process money till it can be used to
review box
by looking at my system access of a
process
this is a two i discovered the internet
infromation so rogue wrapped up
authentication bypass
without looking closely
at the five system
when requesting resp special unical
correct us
of course
de beca sab every important when doing
an artist
g_b_ is fine
and powerful unix
wendy mae g can debug both in bindles
use eleven tells space
ali bbg is the debug operating inside
windows and use a space only
the next three dob shows it to a sample
used during an artist
uh... namely the sister awesome writing
on freebsd
ministration
appears to rediscover the freebsd f_t_
p_d_ remote route to exploit
but using proce
this particular f_t_ p so they exploit
takes a rogers other library load inside
and see a true
the trustful
as shown in the real sation
was attaching to the process i'm at the
the process that is responsible for the
caulking
the f_t_c_ server
the pet of the processes
one one
three eight
and the screen dob
you see two important parts and close in
red lines
just popped shows the stopped an open
call
to slash us epa ross mash m_s_ switch
com
at the spot exists and set the seat
route
b_s_t_ piece of us
will attempt
to open various library files
you see this in the second popping
close-in rat
so if one of the celebrity flights like
slash lip
smash at assessed underscore compile
castle
texas on the prize system
the s_d_p_ several
will gracefully load them into the
running process
uh... that pop but the spectacle of
commodity execution route olympia t_p_
sell-offs that was discovered using a
tracer
well the upcoming slides
will come out to discover whether
abilities ferreting source code
and by doing binary roasting
to audit by looking at cells called
of course that this required but the
reason we don't know what's the
programming language quite well
i personally prefer reading signal
because most of the unix rose buildup on
c
some box can be discovered
unexploited without reading one line of
code
one good example for this is the apache
range spice
denial of service that
if you heard about it will make a remote
apache installation non-responsive what
effect of the so-called apache killa
the apache killer was discovered by the
causing only mils soul scott was through
a study by beth use just plain causing
this topic will be covered in the next
lives
in contrast to the apache bach
most of the time forced me to be
research
everyting soft coral
to understand the weaknesses spent to
build a stable exploit but taking it
want to show those
one example is a prolific acadia remote
exploits
i have been looking on in the past
and is heavily relied on understanding
the sales growth
at the bottom off the slides
trying to determine the situation
one of the critical code lines that made
this publicly announced vulnerability
possible
and the top while the buffer length this
verified
wild offline
to be now this can result in a sec days
copper we're on
but the baf land changes to the negative
value
and that is indeed possible
sometimes the sales quotas not available
proud that technology sabha find other
ways to understand the software
one way to understand binary code has to
do
binary reversing
binary reversing requires quick
knowledge i'll pass on block
but it's a very good
to understand eighty successively
because this is the most deployed to
process are
at least
and the desktop and server wrote
although some bless including tom
embedded systems
icebox especially hardware
running some lower risk can be done to
understand disassembled all quote
the interactive disassemble
there's a good tool probe in every
bruising
top rosalie
tend to look at suspicious car passed
and parody test the skull pols using
scripts
weeding cells called or binary roseanne
is very effective
when doing parallel testing in recent
now rials
and other factors that binary rules they
can be used to develop they exploit
itself
for example the priority p_d_ exploit
heavily relied on disassembly codes
defied all seth a specific awsome
instructions
the screen dump at the bottom shows
an example of a disassembly
it is the right b_r_t_ entry points
they exploit relied on
in order to be able to leak process
memories for further processing
s describe before borrowed testing means
testing output to coco pops andrea test
cases
this includes housing around
the critical cole pulse
to on come up with her abilities
and that takes us for the next topic i
want to present today
cmi ultimata causing with propriety
but i polis xenia automatic causing
because nothing is done probably by the
programming language like world
and more important
done by the knowledge of the program a
this housing technique can be especially
effective
propane tanks protocols because human
being simply on the stamp latex
particles c_v_r_
and therefore penthouse more confortable
role by the republican party
can be done this way
smitha dumps retrieved prompt for
example the white sharks in the fall
are required
one downside is that
usually only in the initial packets of
the binary protocol can be covered
the reason for business that battery
protocols tend to be more complex
and a lot of packets i exchanged
but they are only visible in binary form
for the program a
thousands
i want to mention that library somewhat
yourself the programming language can be
bows
high-level
that want it's just that neelima if not
all of the binary protocol discovered
during the housing session
since
the library of module as the cold
already in place and we have the ability
to speak to the seller side in the
convenient manner
to make you understand why
the knowledge of the program a about the
protocol is so important
i would continue with the causing
templates
are you still up in the past amber
destructive the several parts of it
this very basic template you see on the
screen
written employer this very effective
when used properly
the script when ron
corrupt connects to the remote service
and this case fees of our steam comport
eighty-eight she deeply
as you see in the comments
says the payload and greets
the response
the crucial potter's railroad
looked causing ideas here
so the program a
texas knowledge about the protocol to
attack
and coast possible packets that might
make the service failed
the packets can include overly large
swings
pemain string specify as
apec it's adjusted his to test the
specific too suspicious code profit
reviewed by using binary roasting or
called auditing
this template can be extended sc
to sent several pecos by repeating it
it can be extended in the way
the packets are rep after the response
and hurling packets are sent and so on
bd
the template and the previous life tend
to use a binary protocols by just
replacing the payload
with binary dot south
each modification of the packet
to send us run as a test case
against the syllabus
each test case
might have resulted in the fall
so that were requested such self on the
remote site using pesos like the one
described in the previous lights
astray straws
another tool to mention stopped
which can be used to inspect memory ncp
you use a check
for example
a spike in memory hughes which out the
request the sent
can indicate the memory consumption
or denial silva sole
this during the talking session
we successfully fought a box
and it sure about that
the motor abilities research and explode
written
extending the basic template
the following example shows how the
basic template
was extended to real exploit
after barry fighting a border ability
will sit on
in this case
we will rediscover
the apache remote denial of service and
write parts of the apache killa
the slide show us the very basic
housing template at the top
islt you can see that everybody
during two thousand session i decided to
plaza specific h_t_t_p_ head out that is
supported by default by the apache web
so well its name is strange buys
we enter the race parades bites that
uh... been assembled warm into the
template
and looked at we can break at that she
will do it
the rains set up in a simple form
does not make the rep so will prevail
so we had a overly long had out with
overlapping ranges
to the cost them blade ansi
but their pets you behaves unexpected
anne beat
but talk to our shows a spike in memory
users
so we assume
this might be a flawed to handling of
the range by setup
the memory leak israel we have our fifty
requests are related to the apache web
server using the perma dual
parallels ball manager
the result is
that they'd see h_t_t_p_ did become some
responses
and because of running auto subspace
many processes that killed and the
operating system
the system hangs
a different way of causing software that
especially invoice engulfs
battery protocols will be discussed now
nowadays
many are critical open-source programs
in the unix wrote
i've written in c and c plus plus
shelled from experience
housing by modifying c sauce on the
flight can be very effective
housing housing by using c sauce gamba
confortable and easy to do
even with complex protocols
how can you tell us using this technique
so simple
the targets of those shows are
and compiled
let's take the example of some bob
only nuts
bsn bt services compiled and executed
and said the testing and why rent
so it can be audited though
now the plants also is like for example
s and b clients
are compiled an off of the compilation
of both parts the audit can begin
the clients losses a modified during the
pausing session step-by-step
and after each modification east
testcase
eskom pirate and run against the soviets
using this technique we can discover not
only buffalo barons and the like
that also logic box
if you want to discover logic box we
need a strong understanding of the
cultural and the product software b
apparently auditing
the suspiciously
client code clients
i've changed in a way to parole logic
box upon this oversight
by being the commonly known brunner
ability is like
buff overruns
memory corruptions
tomas ring box and so on
denby were don rather blindly
to accomplish those who do the following
we look for the critical code and see
sauce
like electrical airport come on time the
court all parcels
and as a side note which we can all get
results when doing housing tests
easier pots of the sauce
it is important to dig deeper into the
coach
went to the more complex leah sofa
software as these mails
tend to be more were durable
now which means the buffer called and
said let's one-by-one
each modification of baffles
than the client code
is comprised untested against the
service
the next live contains a spring dob
illustrating coaching deals and the s_
and the client to potentially provoke a
buffer overrun
there's a lot of places we can modify
coatings ambala
the screen dump shows a very simple
location of the client
but it's a very shortly office of the
client
the cmd log-on function
the dust parts of the s of these
sessions setup
changed and the man out but the partial
birth center long passport p_b_s_ and be
service
i put about but with the size
eight thousand ninety-six filled with a
sense of the source code
that i've typically typically session
sent out the mods
i've come on comments about the copies
when they could use which
and the other copy unchanged alliance
where the bop bop
and stopped the length is written
now the court can be compiled
along crosswalk will be sent to this and
be service
i have to know that sometimes deal but
he long buffer lengths out truncate his
and set the client itself
because they are all so long
so sometimes these size checks and set
the client sauce
me to be changed to insert the packet
was sent with the correct overly long
about the size
sometimes we need to adjust several
buffer sizes
because the babble sword
the dot doc
that got overflow
and the client envy
might get sick mentation by eleven
violations in the clients have prior to
sending out the packet
another notice that popo grounds
sometimes need to be and the specific
range
it's not enough to make the bottles as
large as possible
sometimes small about the size of
richard m_ overrun duress lovable for
says this will mob
then we have successfully discovered the
runner ability
we're going to exploiters and the
several stages to do this i described in
the next section
logic box i'm nice to have
sensex plus the logic docs can be more
stable effect if any easier to develop
buffalo overruns and memory corruptions
can be a stable and effective as logic
box
exploiting them as children might
president experience more time kam
consuming
the goal is to retrieve a remote shot
accommoda line so the attack at getting
children to the system and late into the
network
a straightforward way to do this is
in the case of pop over on some memory
corruption instill
that's memory to hit the good place to
controlled the instruction pointer
it's eighty six it is caught the eye p
after watts
bypass protections like bsl r
bedrest space layout random ization and
that makes
the nam execute a little bit bit on mon
executed bill mappings
what a m d sixty four
thereafter all paid off can be executed
to successfully execute the shell
i personally prefer retrievers shouts
and likes bright codes
because this makes a profit possible to
leave eight iowa protections
most of the work of both
to start using it debug elect jim
at the time
graphics pipelining
quite stable burst through this time to
at targets
the next stage is to say and it just
exploit in the white in real world
a crucial station exploit writing
nowadays esta bypassed protections like
a s_ o_ r_
so we will have a look at that
and how it's done lit up some x_-eighty
six bed from a bit closer
required for bypassing address space
layout randomization arlette ups
december control or what the instruction
pointer
for example
tape respecto heaps smashing
overwriting a bunch of point up
so as soon as we have to control over
the instruction pointer
the address basis randomized so will be
jump to
seca dresses addresses of libraries
heats up libraries already the mice
the image referred to as the tech
segment
consider them for the code segments
is not randomized
that's a lobbyist lobbyist of our
implementation of limits
as high-powered us that good a colleague
of say yes so there are
implementation
this week by design
they are all the methods which a more
complete to protect systems like packs
execute headsets
position independent execute the bones
since they don't see this is week ansel
our implementation betty ford i refer to
it to you
what we do is to be jump back into the
text segment because it's at the space
has a six address and as predictable
at the time of the sliding up those new
verified that the straw was not matched
but he's not in the recent goal
from two thousand twelve
has the following it image illustrates
the example shows the memory of apple
priority p_d_ running on the notes
the bill registro stop a rating system
version
and tell bill date
letters from january of this year
yellow regine
shows the virtual memory space that is
not randomized
and the rep regine shows the ritual
mammy space
that is randomized
you can obviously see but look at the
very top left author yela regine
that the base address up the process
tech segment
stayed the same
after proactive p_d_ has been was
startled
as to the tech segment was always mock
tests being readable and execute a bull
we can't jump to it an execute code and
set the segment
the previously described law is very
important for bypassing i_s_l_ are on
the notes
bypassing i a sellout bill involves much
more than the fact that the address
basis only partly randomized
the broadest it began to execute code to
get the shot running
might be true
the steps involved traditional album
balding we look out beyond that point
and that the sixty-four beauty entry
using i dot
this depends on what and that was
available in the process called cold
that at all
from the p_n_c_ entry weekend indirectly
jump to the randomized elaborate
function
we look up the mam copy purity entry
using i dot
as the next step
who use
i'm up to met with spree memory ration
with required an execute permission seen
a build so we can copy code into this
memory regine
next to use them copied to copy bites
from the text segments
to the newly-created memory agin
the proposal despised being copied
is a copy of the shall quote
who worked with the new memory regine
we jump to the copy were team that will
copy the shuttle
yeah and the payload that working soon
we will show this executed
texas to actually called the m_f_n_ them
copied functions
we need to use returned oriented
programming
i'm going to show you know much about
area salah bypass technique
and will explain it using the
illustration art
the image of the first
consulates complex
so i will explain how to successfully
run the show cold
at the left side
we have the attack on
at the right wing of the proactive p_t_
process memory space
the great prod off the memory space
is there not randomized memory
and the rat pappas the randomized memory
we can only execute
code inside the great part
executing code and the rep pappas horny
possible indirectly as we will see
so their tech at number one
connects to the remote f_t_ piece of art
no login credentials on you to execute
gold
we expect that uses frog
the baby a should feel returned oriented
programming
to execute it
several functions inset next segment one
by one
the first one chin
we jump to his cm at
g_o_t_ entry
peyote entries allow us to jump to the
randomized memory blocked
now finally execute the lab rian system
called
at number two
am at escort to create the required an
execute a board member mapping at a
fixed address
the newly-created memory mapping is
shown
and this image of the bottom as doc
yellow
we need to have this memory because we
need to fix i'm randomized plays we can
write the shout go to
and we needed a place that is executed
rule
to execute the shuttle
wants we have created mapping we use rop
again at number three
to be exicted to be able to execute a
new function
this much of this man copy
but not before
make use of the beauty entry to rescind
randomized library function and the rat
regine
for the man copied to permit is a need
it
while the cement copy itself
and dot the one suburb edible mnemonic
ps
like assembly instructions
inside the tech segment we copy
now use imap copy and rocked special
bites one-by-one
from the text segment to the
newly-created memory mapping
at the bottom
these special diets isobel as fractions
which once collected ir you straight up
or
copying the shackleton executing it
once we have forty copy of the buys from
texas ecm into the new mapping we'd me
just jump to the bites at number five
which i thought copier gets executed
ebu copied the shout quote from the
start
feathered dawn
of the required to execute mapping
timely we jump to the shuttle find out
itself that number six
finally we jump two percent board itself
that number six old the shuttle to get
executed
adsense pectoris fished out to be taken
at seven
this plight that uses exactly this
technique to bypass a hassle hours
publicly available under the name pro
active duty
i agree more toward exploit
this exploit uses stack baseball forum
to execute code
and the rotor ability for it was
publicly announced ban anonymous
individual and uh... advisory
working with is that the i
busy work day initiative
because logic box can be fun too
and i'm going to be effective we will
discuss them now
though
sensex plotting logic most strongly
depends on the nature of the back
and can be called complex i give the
previous t if t p t remote exploit
which once was a no day as an example
the scenarios
there's not really was that weekend
though it's an opportunity nomic county
linked library into the process of fifty
p selva
we can't do that because the locked in
to use those inside the c_h_ word
environment
and weakened by five so that this using
death to be protocol
how do we exploit the flow
we need a way to break the c_h_ short an
execute code
the easiest way in my opinion this tour
program economical i've read that
breaks the c_h_ route
but using the picture a system called
betrays is a system called
but allow us to debug processes
so we attach to an ic system picked
existing freebsd process but once this
route
using p trace
then we copy the shout quote into the
ruled on process again by using p trace
the lost that person that the process
continue
at the shuttle position so the shuttle
gets executed
the an expert on n_b_c_'s sixty four ten
and this particular case
bypassed easily because on freebsd bessa
replied execute memory mac mapping
india sticky process
i guess guests that this is
the case and all the previous e
processes
so rewrite the check wrote into this
region
now that pete rose from the court and
said
the mapping
i will show you the procedure depiction
of
and this picture a
uh... press the attack at the left and
the seller running this fifty p service
at the right
detector connects to the f_ t_ pizza but
i'm not saying using
the credentials
the s_d_p_ service once inside a c_h_
food environment
soviet tech outlets economic library
onto the prior system
and the library breaks out
of the seat ruled attaching to the root
on pro says using p trays
the process and priscilla stopped
state now
process katee dates to attach to either
dean krohn
so sloppy sendmail
or any other known
that name
road don't process
the shock vote is injected into the
running process
we got the process continue at the
shuttle position
and as shown in the six sample
utica gets
mecca reverse roe chelle
we have our desired which are
banal need to make the exploit a stable
of pulp fullest possible
i would describe ideas about how to make
this in the next section
her way to make the exploit more
powerful
his batting targets through it
the reason is simple
we want to support as many as possible
warner role installations
that are out there in the internet
targets can be divided two pilots
who supported operating system
the support of software version on the
operating system
we create the environment by selling as
many possible virtual machines
with the literal below operating systems
and self diversions
we need to get the offsets and possibly
other bloodiest need to be examined
as the first step
we had hoped would exploit
uh... before the start of integration
part of selection
bordering three examples
of three different exploits
we show
what has to be added to the exploit to
support role where since
the priority p_d_ exploit was designed
to make it easy to at targets
the fairly well yes i need it
the write-offs that can be followed
using i dot
ladder patting values ophthalmology
using a postscript that was written for
this proposed
by observing the behavior of the pros to
be peace of this
paul the second exploit
that that they can extremist gifted
beauty
already the did nomic libraries the to
become part of each operating system
version
kartik sample arnaud crude exploits
previously
but has been adjusted for running a bill
from x eighty six
an m_d_ sixty-four architectures
to shout outs i had it to the exploit
and publicize adjusted for each track
architecture appropriately
now that we have your the end of my
presentation
we show you
the last apt with can be made to make
this but even more effective
we are testing shaping it just looks
like in the wise
exploits can run perfect in the testing
environment now
material without they might not succeeds
in getting a shot
that personal experience shows
that's not always the case sometimes
exploits can sexy
uh... even own when only tested in a
testing environment
so based what needs to be made stable
but testing it and real networks
actually i don't recall my we recommend
that slides very much because
you have to break at the systems too
past this
exploit and the wife
arts accomplish that like
sacha agents getting nicer to finding
running sellers and the wide to test
exploited against
scandals can be developed
to sequence irreparably durable sobils
once we have also i was discovered
majestic splat against them
if they exploit dates
look what's possible uh... uh... today
real collars
all it is possible to get the
information
from the world are open so i'll go to me
make it
uh... instead of intended it to machine
they exploit their
what we do it the neck at the last
episode just exploit by addressing the
status in the extra code
and i want to thank everybody
who supported me overtimes
you know who you off
now hope you like me like uh... i hope
you like the uh... the talk even the
vote
but ripping
and from the
from the pay periods so if you'll
have any questions comments or
suggestions please ask you know
anyone yeah mckenna
layout peach vases then
teach causa is quite buys if you do
uh...
if you do binary fucking because you can
use the framework you don't have to
write everything by yourself
that what i think is that
customized systems spent two billion
more
more restrictive because you can't do
what do you really want me to know what
you have in mind at this in my opinion
back constraints in the third some three
trials are
another question
tillotson magic are not
uh... and i think that follow dramatic
uh...
housing all discovering rotor bidders
is made possible but not really humbled
on the renew kore
uh... software because saw
you need to put some some brain
situational
any question yeah
can you speed the plow type of you know
now basically does is that
start using rob
uh... if you go she looked at uh...
spend return oriented programming or
like the only to return to live c_e_o_
extrication
you jump to a function
jump back to a function where you can
jump to the memory
so you know if you can't do everything
ok in the pro active duty extra case
yet to request one their reading of the
memory
that's what's so that was values
buchanan to use uh... dot with a riot
it's at the s_d_p_ process memory
is that you don't need the bright
you can't do everything we watch out
anyone else
to a balanced
politically still have pastor
you could work for moving the world
united parkinson
yeah how i do that so basically that
does not recommended to do that because
that's candy
uh... dangerous
you can
suggest a key exploit hines canvas of us
uh... and later on
you find wardrobe lots of us
and then you just look what services are
running what is still not what's exploit
fading with
and if you find out what right-handed
oil even if you doesn't find white
failed
just installed the low the operating
system which runs remotely
on the internet you mean the cats
individual machine
and then
you look okay what good to have failed
nobody you find uh... uh...
the thing that they are
and then you can fix that that uh...
just sit down
yeah relics but more properly
another question or comment
i don't see anybody
is that correct
we'll banality