dream
hello everyone
so i've expected stating that way
populist local client platforms
soprano
uh... my name is affects and i want to
talk to you about another climbed by
firms and their respective clad context
we're gonna look and had to come
to fairly different approaches and
inclined platforms
in detail one being the apple itouch
uh... in the first generation and the
second being a group of crumbled
when
uh... both of those devices or
uh... pretty much clout dependent so
we're going to look at their respective
cloud implementations and how did
essentially different and i want to
close with him
thermo body by security comparison uh...
over to fort bridger platforms
uh... what
the if you take away one thing from this
talk is three companies do not make
security because they want to
but because they want to protect our
business model
so far apple or uh... most of you
probably here dot apple sold more
pipettes and last year dan h_p_'s hold
pc platforms
of any kind of form
so um... every idiot in the world price
pipettes
i'd like to make some money in from the
hardware sales primarily
uh... in two thousand ten voluntary made
thirty two billion become
units sold spend twenty billion
uh... in u_s_ dollars
did take thirty percent of all dumb
money that uh... people making the ap
story
uh... which is another six billion
pin-ups more money
and then they take thirty percent off
everything are the mobile provider
charges you phone calls uh... as a mess
but that's another too dot eight billion
tell u_s_ dollars
and um... this goes to
bom apple they health
thirty and sort of thirty thousand
shareholders but they're not
uh... paying dividends so tall stays in
the company
and this is what they've built their
security model
so what apple once it is uh... besides
the consistently and uh... simple user
interface that award loves what they
want is a integrity protection of their
operating system
and one anyone else on their operating
system uh... date
restrict third-party software
bum from the source you can only get it
from the ups store
uh... from the capabilities slate if
you're building some software dept
well let's say it makes a less sucking
ymail point it will never make it into
the ap story because apple housing in a
client
gay restricted content and they restrict
the payment models
protecting the uses data is not part of
two security design because it's not
part of the stuff that they make money
with
um...
accordingly the apple apts story is
really restrictive thanks uh...
if you ever try to sign up with them as
apple apts to rent on publisher
comes you will receive a piece of
conflict that makes every lawyer tried
when there is lots of interesting
regulations india
well you can get rejected for a pretty
much any reason number not even given
your resume
and
is essentially all rights go to apple
but every possible damage blatantly
phoned damages you can get sued for are
limited on applet cite two fifty dollars
but you already paid ninety nine dollars
to get signed up to the ap story
so essentially itself out of jail free
card for apple
and although the thumb all tourists goes
to you
also they have a very opaque
review process
so you're submitting a binary tree ap
store
magic happens fall we know it they could
have a bunch of monkeys stepping around
tonight pabst
and of the monkey uh...
parts and and you're a cop is accepted
uh... we really don't know
uh... however we do know that they have
the content is armed not to do it liking
but let's say it's pornographic or
political warrior apple bashing
uh... warrior good security software
because apple has no security issues
uh... then it will be rejected
thumb
interact store guides their social work
themselves that in their arab store
gusty explicitly say
if you want to present russia's it never
helps
so if they don't even fear publicity
anymore
now on the other hand why does google
make the chrome book
onto gold for google is data collection
budget generating ninety six percent off
all their income come from selling user
profiles
uh...
you're not just a little
thirty billion plus dollars formats per
year
you get situation is also very different
because some sixty seven percent off to
stalk
uh... class b_ stock so if the decision
making and money-making stock is in the
hands of three people
so the three people
uh... make all the money and everyone
else in the company can claim that
they're working for a technical company
uh... for doubt business model to work
google most dot t_ ensured at the use of
field safe to enter his data into the
chrome books so it can go into to google
clout
and can be used
uh... in publishing products so they
have a completely different business
reasons
to build the security model
axia umd you already see in the design
so what they want is they want a device
that excuses reruns one single program
which is the browser not surprisingly
dot as google chrome
but they won
to prevent third-party software when the
device of theirs
absolutely no legal way to put
binary code on the device that is not
coming from google
patriarch you want to protect the user
data
because of the devices stolen they want
to use it to get a new device which is
back to you pretty cheap
uh... sign up with his google i_d_ and
everything
in is nice again
they also want
to have a fast that uptime
and what is really important google
realized very very soon
but they have to win over the hearts of
the merits first because that merits are
the ones that multiplied our technology
around but the
other it gets on the planet
uh... so for example when when google
started to breed how have their own
public d_n_ a service
and even at the privacy lobbying german
hackers
but would not say wait a minute now if i
use the group will be announced in
google knows every single thing i look
appendix and profile even better
what they said with look at decide p
address at state dot a dot k dot k how
cool is that
so they are nice that this pretty soon
some
and uh... you can
this goes on with their own webstore
servlets webstore
but you can uh... you can put extensions
uh... to to google chrome and air
to sign a pro cesses troop leal
cost you five box
very little contractual hassle
directly submission of two contenders in
the review process whatsoever
everything as html and javascript anyway
and yup
there's there's not much to it
so let's go into the details
uh... the ipod security architecture so
sensual what we're looking at is a
stomach the standard xa newtown pa cosby
is the operating system architecture
done everything runs either ask allah
root word a single user called mobarak
uh... they have a few krunal additions
um
one is called seatbelts
uh... that limits
somethings like p trace debug
capabilities
but they have binary code signatures
sold at binary code of silence
somewhat we're getting to that
them
there's a system-wide storage of
credentialed so detective has a really
easy time a state to steal your teaching
uh... but there's no on disk encryption
for example
like your datasets on this
as it has
and a half days of our deep even
tellme all the modern ship
they have a integrity protection
mechanism desist prominent condos climb
platforms this is also coming from all
the funds that the other integrity
protection
uh... meaning that on power on
there is some initial trust anchor and
from this initial trial sankar
but the next stage is validated and then
the next stage of start up and then
the next stage validates the third stage
and so on and so on
they're doing this as well they have in
rome come
some apple our state keys
uh... and they are used for the
verification of the next step in the
next step
uh... loading
fell melody loading i mood of course it
had an eye on it
i brewed loading colonel karnal uh...
checking water for their signatures
rome this is integrity protection is
nice if you could write
some of this being applet they didn't
so essentially uh...
the device can also brute
uh... into something that a steep but
the issue most though device hockey no
amanda
lead firmware upload won't write it
and uh... yet saying it's unfortunate if
you have a buffer overflow in that which
date yet
uh... because it involved so to update
uh... to buffer overflow to fix buffer
overflow you throw away the device
some so
yeah but this is this is how we actually
get into any i passed
uh... first-generation
them and this is how all the table
export
and then we looked at this dispute
loader and and how does it in detail and
found out that they are using x five a
nine certificates and and the
certificate chain
uh... from a accurate c_a_a_ over some
problem immediate c_h_a_ and entities
uh... and we looked at to coach
and found out there
it doesn't verify basic constraints
now i a short elder border basically
strengths some
become use case of the next five a nine
certificated
uh... is to build a trusting obviously
uh... but obviously the c_d_a_ ed one
point once to give you a certificate for
which you have a private key
but that doesn't make you see a right
so essentially to see a asserts that a
little bit that says uh... this
certificate on signing
is for c_ a_ words not
now if it's really bad if you're not
taking this little bit
some
because that means that we have a valid
and if you certificate
we can essentially sign ships uh...
which um...
eventually is obscene and signed by
apple
we talked to matt interestingly enough
there actually shipping um a private key
and the public she ended signed
certificate on every single device which
is used for their push services
however we found out that the bootloader
restricts this is the whole process two
three steps
and since they have to some intermediate
sia is already
uh... we couldn't use that one of the to
boot loader
however if we looked around and use a
lens and found out that they did the
same thing there
because essentially what they did was
invaded downloaded a open-source library
call time correct
and use that for all their crypto
without understanding the library
so we take this pursuit of the kid
uh... push notification certificate and
we signed shift
for example
h_t_t_p_ s certificates four star
like the entire internet
wherefore anything that you do
itasca i'm at has scored pop three has
slowed bpm connections or what not
and this then cause they've very hurried
updates
by apple
uh... interestingly here
is so they opted at i_r_s_ afford
and that means uh... they updated iphone
four and i've thrown in at three g s
nobody else so if you have a nice phone
before three g asbestos alll is broken
and apple doesn't care
uh... which i find interesting because
compare that to microsoft who still
shipping security updates for it they
dumm operating system which is ten years
old interfilm actually out of service
called exp
which actually doubts as as are correct
so if you have an older device who want
to go to that website and if you find a
nice little oc though on top of that
then you're screwed
benja short throw away your iphone and
buy something decent
then coming back to apple and crypto
that they need to uh... signature
mechanisms to check the refineries
radars that they didn't help slide
wineries
so the karma verifies the integrity of
applications at libraries
but if you do a signature mechanism
don't do it like al pulled us because
what they do that was the they
essentially only sign specific sections
in the file they say well what's
important to code section
to read only data section
and doesn't that done
andheri essentially of the balloon uh...
made-up toda and and i don't think so
though what happens is there is
obviously they ship load
ways to get around this
for example they don't signed header of
the file
while the head are off the filed
contained study information brady entry
point is so all you need to do this you
take a signed binary
can slap some unsigned binary code at
the end
uh... you changed the entry point to the
end to binary is loaded film everything
is happy
and um...
get out the execute code
uh... part of three hundred regmi j
breaks that you find for you i thought
uh... the system updates for forty i pet
are essentially um...
scoop them covered by the integrity
protection and ites youths
so yeah did you get application updates
in the ap store
however
uh...
application updates are also covered by
the by the monthly review process
so if the map developer finds that they
have a critic of on the bill to you in
their coats and a shipping opted in the
next hour it can still take up to two
weeks
uh... morgan randomly be rejected
uh... by alcohol so uh...
there is no shortcut for security
updates
also one thing that well in some people
wanna play with potentially is uh...
carey updates of the mobile phone
carrier
firm kenwood some magic
uh... updates of little things in your
iphone or ipod for example the proxy
server you're using
uh... which is then an interesting thing
if the proxy server
live is not located at the carrier for
example
so um... the apple apts toward
uh...
essentially the apple out the story etc
appliances into itunes into our clients
are
wrecked yet
it's a web browser
than it has a if everything javascript
referendum object to see a p_r_i_
uh... containing baram july kit classes
it is white listed to certain list of
the main so you can draw these state my
ap story now is ed google dot com
threatened to white list this pretty
permissive and at how some signed p list
xom l
bullshit
the problem with that whole thing is if
you're building a web browser
uh... usual dot you build a web browser
so in order and four do u security has
some chins of web browsers to work
for example the use a house to see
but the address bar
now the ups store coined doesn't have an
address bar because it always talks to
apple right
but that means the user has no way to
see you
you know it
took a left turn and now rand on google
uh...
you have no indicator of whether you're
using h_t_t_p_ ass or h_t_t_p_
and uh... jeff
so the standard web security things
simply don't cut it anymore because the
user company could you could decisions
that for example means that
seaview
injects some javascript skin random
apple websites
let's say an open waistline like here
uh... but you cannot cheap call some of
those javascripts uh... thinks
bills javascript functions contain
interesting functions like itunes dot
billy at chin
as you will to see them talk just your
credit card and by suit in the upstart
uh...
they have csr after bill clinton some
dead barton are meant to prevent such
attacks that are c_s_i_s_ paste
however
persons the libraries are elected
libraries they would happily fill in the
tokens for you so the attacker doesn't
have to care about them
uh... n this all is pretty hard to fix
so
but i'll give you an example
here is they dumped your during the ap
store as you see
to get a pop up that asks you for your
apple id to you
uh... which is somewhat expected some
because you know
during the ap store right
uh... however just pop up was actually
cost
though by a little
piece of javascript it you inject in pa
bitterly websites tandon
you know club
if you can guess what a password goes to
uh... like once you enter data
certainly not to apple
uh...
even the vanilla web security things
um... part not right away or it is that
the disease after prince arthur not very
good so from even if you're going to be
injecting
the uh... you get like one out of
hundred shots
uh... were totally works from
the thing is
dwight list also means the domain
whitelist also means that if we have a
cross-eyed scripting somewhere
on a domain that is in the white list
we can essentially be do you have to
score for your device
so all we need it
employers
across at scripting somewhere on and
apple dot com website because the white
listed entire epa dot com
and to let and we found it on the front
page in the search field
didn't have to look forward to tweak
because at scripting in research field
what psa uh... essentially
there is uh... the what kid has an ex is
as alberto rates access as kansai
prevention pool
dumb
and that's all there to prevent us from
hacking around however since this is not
a real browser
uh... it will support the data you al
or data you are scheme
film as a source of content
which were pissing browse it would never
do
thumb so there is split javascript code
that we execute in the context of the
data origin bone which
you know it's considered harmless right
by the browser
and so
we kept his we can inject javascript
that essentially
dry folly
marches download instill run
applications on here at the devices
uh... this is how you do it
so essentially it comes to talk to her
is your concert scripting
uh... thingy and you put them
they tell you uh... allendale would pay
sixty four in code above the bindle
tend to be low essentially
why is it a stupid piece of shit from
the upstart
the interesting thing here is
that were not sure whether we can
disclose how to do that because that's a
good to certain known certainly have the
fraud injection
uh... issue
uh... and stand so we talked to alcohol
they fix it then
they fix it by fixing the cross
expecting in research field
so if you find another car side
scripting feel free to have fun
now so how does your data end up in
apple to climate
uh... obviously early you will have to
switch on and use the italics which
uh... very expensive t_v_ advertisements
will
continuously tell you to do
and also if you're updated over high
flow over g_i_ june's uh... interphase
injured in an operating system update
you will find to be our child has
suddenly turned on
lately
so what it does is it takes
any documents though that has a certain
datatype an issue at all
uh... iniki well you file
were any
document that in unit out subdirectory
named documents
were library private documents
anything and air automatically goes into
the clout
the only thing you can prevent that is
as the at authority
toucan flack documents as
not to be exported into the ipod
which means you as a user help
absolutely zero control over it
um... it looks like the whole
transmission poses is h_t_t_p_ s some
new we talked about a couple just talent
for cryptographic solutions
but let's just assume that element over
your po he wrote that as uh... secure
obviously at the storage is pretty much
guaranteed to be on a trip to it
because otherwise apple wouldn't be able
to access your documents and
now moving to a different if i a sort of
a to law enforcement or have to sell it
to someone else
uh... which uh... if you if you read to
use that to terms accused
they're totally free to do
very good
to coach define essays here's the answer
i don't care what the question was
chroma security architecture so
essentially
at the the chrome wants to crumble is
for people them off my extraordinaire
that grew up quickly
beating other people for touching their
screen
we prefer to actually have to vices
would keyboards
but
this device is different uh... too so it
has a keyboard with it
and uh... it requires a google account
work as the council
tumne peers individuals separation
between two users so multiple users can
use the same device which is by design
because google envisions that at some
point universities will have so crumbles
and uh... the student just grabs a
chrome book and uses it with his google
account and everything goes to grow and
cannot keep that in mind
it's a standard lennox operating system
they have a few announcements
they also help warned sing-along routier
zaidi did a run
everything under
they have a very strong focus on
preventing native code execution
there is no fight a bull flies system
that has mounted execute a bull
so they essentially
essentially have to decode and twelfth
dvp
on the file system implemented
uh... they have a personal firewall
uh...
which i've had dozens
after we told them that i_t_t_ six is
also a protocol that we use nowadays
gumtree
take out a type b_ visits to the
personal firewall
and uh... what is very interesting they
have automatics highland updates
without using intervention
so you contact you stop the device from
updating itself
the only thing though that you can
access as a user is the chrome browser
nikon comes which although lady
famous features security features of the
chrome browser
as your ideas and boxing um...
disabled and j_p_ i so your conduct you
have primary uh... poppins
with heights the full file system so if
you save file save
during lease your home directory
interestingly enough uh...
also the chrome browser ships with uh...
goldstone compiled version of adobe
flash
they apparently forgot to tell that
there will be about to file system
hiding
so if you have a fire safety dialogue in
a flash application you see the entire
filesystem
what was funny it is
the who remembers in two thousand a damn
alexander sought to ralph and and of
policy creating
mt five um... collision certificates for
as a cell
most plaza vendors fix that by taking
the certificates
down putting it into the browser and
flagging it as evil so it would never
ever be accepted
google at the same thing but forgot the
flagging
if you were alex hardy raw footage that
you can control
the clock overwhelm broke
but if you have this is all men in the
middle for everything
uh... however do you need to keep it
only sakharov apparently hats
them to be biased
also has a development notes so um...
this is the peeling tutored name
num
to keep so it was about to say to the
greeks
did as a small switch on the back of the
device when you don't need to devise a
chose his gary big-screen roger and
develop a remote scare for blah blah
uh...
soap
but they also have an integrity
protection chain it is a lot more solid
then uh... the one that bone
that apple develops
uh... this year's oxy from the
documentation
uh... what do you see here
firmwares and come out so the way they
built this system is
uh... action ought to stick but they
have
iran's sections and they have the
firmware
the napa carmel and then they have the
fire system
and of all of them they have to
so if they are updating one side and if
i could optic instilled switch over to
the other one
so everything's redundant
from
came into real stuff from
this fall works essentially
noticeboard as funny as they are to use
the tpm
some on the platforms
uh... two-track uh... that you don't use
an old accused so you can't do rollback
but i can't give you did manage to crack
and older appa told a group team
so you can't really use that because
they'd have seen any repeat
what it also factors in
is the kind of worsens
if anyone here can convince leanest for
whites to adopt a versioning strategy or
firefox so um... every two weeks will
get a new major worsen of two minutes
condo
because if the end and this is a sixteen
bit field so if we manage to get to the
knox condom major worsened to sixty five
five thirty five
all crumbled stopped working for effort
so if you know let me know what you know
stalwarts film that might be worth to
give them a drink or two
and convince them to do that
uh... they built the extremely smart and
fast of filesystem integrity spell
checking
because
what they do like if you build embedded
systems this is how you do it
but they don't integrity check the file
system data integrity checking some
detox or come
the actual hardware layer quickly
dacha hard right
the whole partition this poem
checked every single block white house
and endurance is super house on top of
that
so essentially every time you read
uh... the block from the partition
it will help has verified list of hashes
you know what check to house office
block and if it matches fine if not
uh... but you get a little sign that
says please connect me to the internet
in you know
i want to reinstall myself
and this is actually extremely smart
because cashing cakes in when the layer
above that's so you're not verifying a
block twice in most cases
firm and displaying to put up time for
example down to from less than ten
seconds
and uh... makes it really really
portable
uh... however even that integrity
protection some has imperfections
the
for example partitioned tables not
integrity protected so if you can make a
film do the caramel
will work on the driver's side into the
partition table helms did will fucked up
uh... parts of the device
is also partitions for or we have in
south florida unifying
poem modules that are not integrity
protected so
president de assumption is would later
promotes that if you can drive in to
dignify section
uh... you can load here for a more drugs
before he even did announce couldn't
start spin
nobec toward tabloid
enters a theoretical breach of integrity
here
because at the point where there is
starting to colonel
uh...
this is what they have shows the uh...
as the integrity put their has to start
parameters for the connell
then what you see here
in reg is three percent u
plus one
but this is what it later fill-in
uh... did u i_d_'s of two discs that
they're actually one boot
but the thing of course it is
diablo warned is what they signs
into lower one it's what they execute
so um...
this is club gives me a theoretical
breached
i've seen a talk submission to a
conference in asia where some academics
claim
but that it could actually turned us
into an actual attack
i would love to see that some i was
simply too dumb to do that
when you keep in mind that
what do you think that the books are at
mend to be shared slick and universities
it is also worth noticing that
his veto only section in the beginning
with a health care routine
uh... which then loads the firmware
is obviously somewhere on a trip
and one of my colleagues of mine
find out that
that you essentially connected to the
pins when the device and that makes
you retire on the let's read only
uh... essentially you can run software
and say please become read right
and i will say yes
and then you update deferral ordered and
those so we do have a chrome book now
homes that says richard relapse though
when you put it
which obviously means that you can then
essentially do whatever you want to pick
brought to come up
whatever
do you call must use a data encryption
to home directory encryption is a pretty
well designed cripple system from my
point of view
uh... everything but a trip to expert
when it's what is interesting here for
you to know what is
that uh... it essentially depends on you
use a password
so this is fairly decent data separation
because when user cannot access the home
directory of the other use of the
tuesday
essentially had she doesn't have to keep
the key is generated based on your user
password that you entered
soem
but this is important outcome
to keep in mind
to update story with the chrome books is
a bit strange some as a set date
does not allow user intervention
some every forty five minutes
it talks to google him using google ts
well maja protocol
and then it starts taking the active
system partition
ended runs the updates pondy inactive
system partitions
but the updates are incremental
modifications
of two from where andrew partition so
centrally go house-to-house eight
consecutive
uh...
history off every single image d_f_a_
shipped if they ever lose one doctor
does not work
uh... because they are also updating the
house just above four and forty eight
for the prop tables
gap take us transported over as a cell
and is by itself integrity protected
what is again interesting hearing is
eight thirty
approach
parity integrity protectionist checks
after the update is applied
so they're not downloading the whole
update checked integrity and then apply
the update
nordic download to update step by step
in applying it to did mixed into the
other partition and at the end
they do the house and go like quips
something was wrong cory yes that was
built
do everything they did a signaling
something was wrong or govt
is whether dissected bootable fleck
forty other petition back were not
if you know keep in mind
that the partition table is not
integrity protected
here is the again a theoretical wade
to get in there
but we couldn't make a practical tasha
called some lost guys
uh... they've made a theoretical
practical
nineteen eighty seven or something right
to google web store in as a said is
there a good portion of the arab store
uh... distributes browser extensions
um...
it's all javascript stuff from
did the user
krenz permissions on installation and we
all know that
hidden what is interesting here
um...
do you do a p_r_ itself might work
politically
chrome extension can do
is essentially it looks like it was
built for russian banking trojans
uh... because one way and one thing you
can do is a so-called content script
uh... where you say for the following
domains
i would like to get control after your
energy entire dom
and i would like to change some things
in the dog
uh... which is exactly what very um...
expensively made thinking trojans and
windows usually do
uh... so that they can get your payment
your talents and happened what not and
send it to you
servers uh... outside shipping sterling
so it's really really powerful dumb
we already see submissions for black in
vegas that
nick an entire talk about it
they also have um... paid extensions so
that people can make money off their
browser extensions
but they're not really well protected so
if you have the extension hygiene which
you see when you browse the catalogue
you can essentially creates
certain request here
uh... and endure download the extension
for free
uh... you can also use uh... degree
wilson configuration for your browser
and than just alkali due to the
configuration in next time you send your
browser it will download d extension for
you
without you paying obviously
what we found interesting and what comes
back to my initial points keep in mind
what they make the money was
uh...
when we reported this to google in in an
actual onsite meeting
basic
steps that we should update the
documentation
so they have no no interest in
protecting
support people that make money off a few
extension that they sell on under google
checkout
uh... because that's not what they make
money with from dayton driver documented
fact that this protection simply doesn't
work
certainly cheaper
how can you install malicious extensions
and browsers as well
uh...
if you get obviously if you get control
over to google account you can use
google adsense
and just how diminishes extension to it
uh... will also
some exposes in chrome special i p i
still webstore
uh...
day held earlier this year
what we found dead uh...
gatehouse
h_t_t_p_ domains with him to write list
so you could inject uh... h_t_t_p_
done very similar to apple
and help them download and install
extensions
uh...
d configuration d confirmation dialog
that says yes taiwan install that um...
was implemented by a javascript so d
extension cord click itself
on the dialogues and suggestions for me
uh...
there and as i mentioned to um... do you
have to militias extensions are fairly
powerful you essentially controlled the
browser in an extended to cannot imagine
in firefox work
lets move into the group of clouds
poem
so an example here being total collapse
so for the google helps game you have to
realize that if your account has
compromised everything was lost
uh... review session cookie is
compromised your account is compromised
so
that a password or to factor
authentication doesn't help you that
much because he half to lose this
fucking cookie wants
and that's it
uh...
it's gold it doesn't love you anymore
uh... needed let's say because your name
doesn't sound correct on google plus
but you're fucked
we were if someone else can make a
little not loving you anymore
law enforcement government so long
you're fucked
if you keep that in mind fine you can
use collapsed
uh... so essentially your protection
must cover the authentication
authorization lofty user in third-party
applications
uh... there many google helps so that
you some third-party coach
uh... and synthesis in octial nightmare
because cougar keeps buying companies
pregnant
i think this is
and uh... integrate their products in
hindered offerings
and often this code is really not
compatible with the way google dust off
so that handover cookies second fourth
at some point you can see people
burns the alps attending like thirty
copies from one side to the other
because the gluten couldn't
makeup which group used important one
uh...
param soldiers you certainly have volume
bentsen's nowadays they're paying uh...
lots of money if you find critical box
legislation a block
uh... an example of interesting things
in the clouds
google docs allows to write naturals
uh... for at their spreadsheet
applications those macros are actually
executed on google servers
firms you can import macros from other
people which uh... you know by ones
you look at the coat and then you say
this macro school and you save okay
if the other guy updates the macro later
uh... it uh... it might change behavior
them what we found will be interesting
owned one of two leading macros homes
used by the most people on on google
docs is a credit card number validation
checker
by russian
and it's action that you couldn't do it
let's actually not stealing stuff
so it's the one russian but that's a
shitload of credit card numbers and not
miss uses them
produce good
but as i said lake uh... if you have
heard turned sites then everyone is
fucked
what is also interesting is the macros
can do it needs to be requests
now keep in mind does h_t_t_p_ requests
come from within google
uh...
as you can get up to plate
end fifty geeks per second data
transmission with into google data
center
socal only good connected law school
group
uh... and that's that's a pretty decent
way to do it
we found one way and of where p
deduction account switching uh...
functionality on the google main site
buchwald actually allow you to steal
someone else's accounts
come i'm not walking you through the
entire
uh... cosas players and julia um
intercept
uh... a lock in requested you presented
accounts which request where you are
already locked in
and then uh...
theater laughin becomes accounts which
is for it
uh... forty user in it looks similar if
not hundred-percent equal to regalado
will walk in but very similar
and you end up having to cocaine
uh... which dennis obviously came over
financial black should be fixed by now
well even google belongs to the
companies that still think that all of
us top ten has something to achieve
from i think some some managers
obviously haven't doing poem
yearly review bulb to open spokesmen
processed a contract my
so also google site to help us that
scripting
uh...
to google sites apartment is actually
uh... and very interesting playground if
you want to get paid by google for one
abilities cool websites is a good
starting point
because you're living off the google dot
com domain
which uh...
breaks a margin pretty nicely
and you have a lot of power
over what you can do
other services
uh... of lots of
nineties style cross at scripting issues
so
for example the administrator paramore
the and post he needed to secure it and
it drifted schoolgirl email service that
is also used but many government
agencies in the states
uh...
but you have a concert scripting rodent
bucket didn't move when viewing messages
from users so if you have across that
scripting in the subject of an email the
user
to call the apple and say look and
baptist account please and pop happened
at storms
and this this well authorization and
exchange of data things um...
really doesn't work too well even when
googled slide
uh... an example being
give one side wednesday access your data
in google alps
uh... you get a little website from
google that says
well do you wanna allowed each dot com
to go
financial you know if studio daytime
would you can obviously do as you use a
who wasn't the right thing to redirect
films where you
automatically essentially click on the
though i feel lucky button
which then cause us
who go to ask you something like this
who wants to access your google account
do you wanna allowed us
but the obvious answer is while you
already talking on my day now so go
ahead
uh... which then
redirects through do search engine and i
feel lucky
uh... onto our web server
uh... cairns happy new leaks your
article authorization token
uh... into your web blocks
so at what you see here isn't it the
google summary is essentially
who goes succeeded in hardening the
client platform
inorder come to make the use of field
from
this is really safe and i can enter my
day take care
what in fact happens is removing the
risk into the clouds
bum
where
to security challenges scholar
still a lot harder and even almighty
google uh...
makes mistakes aaron into foreign dead
like we've learned how to do should
write
many years ago but in cloud computing we
throw away this knowledge
again and you
as they have
nothing happens
uh... also culture pretty opaque so them
they collected like like he's the
following together services room or is
uh... but i talked a couple of people in
the payment to me and found out
the following interesting thing
uh... apple
runs the i quote not themselves but they
run it on google and microsoft
now google achchi runs his clout now in
ibm data centers
uh... largely for the non-essential
services
ibm
that i know for a fact and she wants to
data centers not themselves anymore and
but outsource them to third parties tend
to have them operated by people in china
suppose that its rewards
decor of the problem being
you'd never know where your data and sop
at and whose action responsible so if
you have a data breach in this scenario
was that like reduces
i wanna close with that what i find an
amusing film matrix
the off to four major nobody platforms
nowadays
if the four major platforms uh...
you will see that
thirteenth of june
widely used platforms dot t_ ron mate of
codes
while home
the blackberry and secluded
who almost not jus windows fill in
action only allowed managed coached
the permission model forty ops is pretty
much the same when all of them so
when you install inhabited gives you a
menu of stuff it wants to do which it
data
and either your fine with that or you
don't get ya
that's the same for everyone
thumb
device management of his
very um...
uh... yeah different across the board so
the apple bios how some device
management which put
is unfortunately undefinable
well on android you have nothing that
comes
from from itself
uh... there's a lot of third-party
products but knobs by him
by itself
a blackberry and windows fun actually
house device management
they all have somewhat of a clout
ukelele considered a blackberry
enterprise service as a private college
but now
the interesting hardest
uh... divine abilities on autos an
android we have plenty thought like
barry introduced webkit
so uh... it made a tactical from
remarkable
on windows phone seven so far d only
thing that broken
uh... where william extensions
into most amusing
remember in the nineties
uh... we'll inox users were making fun
of the windows users for having all the
malware
on a mobile phones now the windows phone
users make fun of the limits android
users for having all the beltway
uh... and without
i think i want to close
and thank you for your extension
and of course
questions
make homicides
well i was
i was just
pointing out possibilities but also
um...
the media is not a very good measure for
doubts uh...
before dads are you don't have to take
my word
uh...
to go and look at upto deep the story is
also a reporters that critical e covered
apple
bumping the medium
and what happens to their careers
uh...
and so far at the media is not a very
good measure on what actually happens
you think that uh... uh... will the ipod
idea ever bc maybe implementation
i think the so far does not business
incentives and doing it correctly that
the whole point of running a cloud is to
have access to use a state of
uh...
pretty sure that
uh... you called archie may he could but
how for a decent
crowd that
house opaque storage were even even
calculation there's some advance
cryptographic concepts that i'm
not really understanding but apparently
it is possible to used to actually
uh... run calculations in operations on
encrypt the data without having to keep
the problem is there's no business
incentive for us to insult
when you mention on the
by guest taking about the i'd are equal
right but realist
was mentioning that basically the same
which imposes no perspective
but they using webkit but it will drive
missiles they should be expected night
alone didn't you elaborate on that
do you never third term
the question and it was in the context
of the arts the ap store application and
directions application papa but even if
you reviews webkit that's one thing
uh... that you actually have to
implemented books that made this is a
margin
uh... policy
checks
and you have to act you turn them on
and in indian
in the arab store alp
for example did simply turned off
because they assume
de eat
what whoever they talk to is always
apple
npr jin doesn't play a role
so you can turn it off
and that's what they did
okay thank you very much time