we work for Microsoft in the area of
cloud security today we are here to talk
about how to improve an organization's
cloud security posture so they quickly
take you through the agenda for today so
we will start with introduction to
computing we will talk about what some
computing is what are the services that
it offers and be able to compare how
security is different in cloud of from
the on-premise environment and we are
specifically going to talk about certain
areas like identity access control data
security monitoring within cloud and for
each of these areas we are going to see
some of the practical scenarios their
customers faced in the journey to the
club and we will follow it up with
potential solutions to address each of
these challenges and we are going to
talk about what is the best mist
solution for the customers to quickly
you know to these new and emerging
challenges in the cloud and we have a
dedicated time for Q&A towards the end
but in case you guys have any questions
where you want to stop us before we move
to the next slide simply raise your hand
and we'll be there Oh what do you
so just to do a quick survey how many of
you walk on cloud technologies on a day
to day to day basis by show of hands
please okay a couple of you I expand the
audience a little bit more how many of
you are familiar with cloud technology
you've not worked with it directly but
you're familiar with what that 90 so
okay that's great so let me give you an
example say me and a couple of my
friends we got together and started an
e-commerce startup and as part of that
they're setting up was an application
server and right now it's working out of
my garage just as a desktop now I start
getting a lot of custom
and I need to scale the size of my
application with the server and so what
do I do
I can scale it up to say maybe adding a
couple more servers still managing my
own infrastructure but as I as I go
forward my company takes off and that
means I need to scale up there were
multiple there are couple of options
here one option would be I go ahead and
buy more infrastructure manage it on my
own and take care of all the costs the
lugger could be I just rented from a
third-party provider
he takes owners of everything from the
maintenance costs making sure it's up
and running and things like that so
simply speaking cloud computing is my
third party will deliver on-demand
resources on a pay as you use basis why
do customers moves to the cloud as I
mentioned its on-demand
and then is the matter of a self-service
portal so the cloud solution provider
will give you a sense of a portal and
you can just go and just a few button
ticks provision and configure all these
resources the second would be cost so
I'm reducing the amount of money I spend
on electricity making sure the servers
are cool making sure that are up and
running the IT admin cost etc I'm
loosing all those costs the third one
would be depending on my needs so let's
say my e-commerce site is seeing of
massive boom because it's new yours and
people are buying a lot of gifts to send
to each other and now add this for the
steady short period of time I can just
increase the number of instead
to scale up or improve increase the
amount of compute that my system has
which is a scaled up just for that
period of time and I will pay some extra
money just for like those two three
weeks around New Year's and then I can
scale back down the top the fourth one
would be performance when we say
performance that's actually referring to
the cloud solution providers ensuring
that you have the latest in the greatest
hardware running on the cloud
infrastructure so you don't have to
worry about upgrading and updating those
the last one is reliability
what is reliability me so reliability
refers to the SLA based availability
which means the cloud solution provider
is actually guaranteeing a certain
amount of uptime and they will back this
guarantee and in some cases it's
financially back and you can claim that
this is well before we start some of you
might be familiar with some of these
terms but let's just go over these one
time so that we're all on the same page
because we will be repeating these terms
over and over during the course of our
session what do I mean by optimize
anything that means my friends was in my
garage or maybe in another room or
another building but that's owned and
taking care of by us that are the
structure what is a cloud solution
provider or cloud vendors we will use
these terms interchangeably so that's
any third party that could be Google
could be AWS could be IBM could be
Microsoft and they are going to own the
cloud infrastructure that we're talking
about the third one is public cloud in
the key thing that you need to remember
about the concept of public cloud is
that you can connect to the cloud over
the Internet the fourth one is cloud
customers so cloud customers would be
companies like the example I give my
e-commerce site or could be any of your
companies that will adopt the cloud this
last one is resources so resources
Sothis any web applications and in
observer database that you configure in
provision on the cloud that's a resource
in terms of subscription so subscription
I always familiar with Bigwater cloud
subscription means show of hands okay so
I just quickly run through all that when
I go to a cloud solution provider asking
him for their cloud services they will
provide me a subscription which can be
accessed through an online portal cloud
management portal you can call it and
that subscription gets mapped to a
certain login ID and password so those
credentials are what I will use to log
into the cloud management portal and
access my subscription my subscription
is the boundary within which I will have
to configure all these resources any
when I said he saw says all the cloud
services that you provision will be
within that subscription some cloud
providers also give you the capability
to segregate the resources that you set
up for production environment as well as
Devon text because let's say I would
have a different kind of access control
and management before the production
environment for them and test I will
just let everybody do whatever they want
for the session they will consider a
fictional insurance company called
iseman insurance and let's take a look
at what their cloud adoption journeys
with that like and some of the choice
[Applause]
so let's talk about scenario number one
now iseman insurance is a company with
about 50,000 employees and currently
they are looking at migrating their
payroll application to the cloud now all
of these employees has to access that
payroll application right so the app
development theme for the payroll
application comes back and asks how
should I be authenticating these all
these 50,000 users on the club because
as it stands today I am using something
called something called a compromised
directory service say for example Active
Directory to use the copper credentials
for my 50,000 employees to log into this
application now when I move this entire
infrastructure to the cloud how should i
authenticate so let's take a look at
that this is one of the very initial
problems that most of the customers face
when they decide to move the
infrastructure to the cloud right let's
say you start a company that does not
have any infrastructure in compromisable
because you have just started the
company for them it's easy to start
their journey directly the clock create
your identities in the club so when I
say identities I mean your employees
user IDs and passwords and all the
details about your employees which you
can later on use permit litigation as
well like so if everything stays in the
cloud so identities as well as the
applications you can simply leverage the
identity solution which is in the cloud
and you know let your users log into the
applications in a secure way but if you
are a traditional company or if you are
an established enterprise who has
already invested a lot of amount in the
on-premise infrastructure and in your
own private data centers for you to move
the cloud you will have to first figure
out the problem of identity how do you
manage the identities because all of
your infrastructure or the identity
matrix the identity solutions are in the
unpromising etwork and now we move one
of the eigen applications and hosted in
the cloud how do you log into that
application because my authentication
server and the deed
are in the entremets work so this is the
problem the most of the companies
initially phase so let's take a step
back and talk about how on provides
authentication works and then we can you
know figure out how we can have an
equivalent solution in the club so we
all access applications within our
office network or the private network
and we are able to log into this
application seamlessly so have you ever
thought about how this authentication
works and even how does somebody log
into applications or for that matter
let's say how does someone or an
employee log into his workstation when
he is in office what is the
authentication that happens in the
bathroom anyone you can take a guess
it's okay okay so what happens in most
of the unpromising network scenarios is
that you have a directory service which
is most often an active directory which
will hold all the information about your
employees starting from the user IDs to
their passwords to their designations to
their email ids to their phone numbers
everything is maintained in one single
server which is called as a directory
service and when you whenever you try to
log into your machines or access
applications you try to enter the
corporate credentials and these
credentials are validated against the
identity server which is in the same
network the crucial point here is that
because it's in the same network I can
manage this authentication process
seamlessly and through leveraging this
sort of an identity model from several
years we were able to provide secure
reliable robust solutions within the
on-premise network but the apprehension
is that if I go to cloud which I get
included security in the club with maybe
any security challenges for me or get my
employees do my employees now need to
enter new credentials in order
as the cloud applications that's the
primary concern so we have a couple of
solutions to address this problem
let's talk about the first one which is
going to manage the identity solution so
what happens in this is that you create
another directory service in the ground
and you synchronize all of your details
which are present in the content
directory or the active directory into
the clock so once this happens you know
all the details including the password
hashes of the employees will move into
the club and once directory service in
the cloud is aware of all the details
you can directly leverage the directory
service in the club in order to
authenticate your employees you don't
have to talk to the pontiff Active
Directory as such because both the
applications and identities are in the
same space whereas the other solution
which is called the federated identity
model for some reason let's say you
don't want to move your employee
password hashes out set up your network
what is the solution that we have it's
the federated model so the federated
model what happens is you have to
initially set up a Federation service
within your on-premise network so this
will be an internet facing server which
means anyone come into it can come and
talk to it and at the same time you will
create a directory service within the
club experience as you can see even here
we are going to create a directory
service but this directory service will
not have any information about your
employees password hashes it will just
know the user details meaning it will
have information on the list of users
but it doesn't have password hashes but
what we are going to do is we will
establish a Federation trust between
both the entré minds as well as the
cloud directory services and now let's
think of a situation where the employee
is trying to login to that he endorses
corporate credentials initially the
application redirects back to the
Federation server because the Federation
server can talk to the Active Directory
can validate the credentials if those
credentials are money it will issue a
okay and the pokin will be carried back
to the application and then it will be
given to the directory service in the
cloud but how does my directory service
in the cloud know whether it is a valid
token or not because this token has been
issued by a different directory sitting
somewhere in the on-premise network in
knows that it's a valid token or not
because there is a Federation trust the
DS established between them which means
if I sign a particular token and they
show it the other server can determine
whether it is signed by me and whether
it is valid or not so this way without
moving and going password hashes of the
view Network you can still achieve
equivalent authentication if you want to
log your users into the applications and
if you combine both of these solutions
it's up to the enterprises to determine
which one works best for them
but the first one the managed identity
solution has less maintenance because
once you sync your details into the
cloud you don't have to maintain any
extra infrastructure in your own one
device so it's sort of imple and also
simple is easy to maintain whereas the
federated model because you are hosting
your own Federation server in your
network you will have to ensure that it
has high availability at all points of
time because remember that if your
Federation server is down for some
reason it means that your employees will
not be able to sign into these
applications whereas in the cloud
scenario your cloud provider will give
you assurance that it will be available
for ninety nine or ten point nine
percent of the time in the last point of
compulsion is the password so if you
have any such security compliance
reasons because of which you will not be
able to move this information out of
your network in that case Federation
server will be the best solution with
that let's move different problem that
iseman is now faced so now we understand
how can I smell manage the identities so
with after this the there are multiple
teams within iseman insurance that
decide to go ahead and migrate to the
cloud so as you can see there's multiple
applications and all these application
are going ahead and provisioning the
resources in that cloud subscription
what happens now so at some point in
time you will start having a lot of
databases you have a products in API
servers you'll have a lot of web servers
and all that might just become a lot of
confusion now the idea even for iseman
insurance has a challenge and they want
to figure out who's who can identify who
is the person that's creating these
resources who has access to these
resources and who's doing what with
these resources so let's talk about how
they're going to solve this problem
so this translates to the problem of
access control in the cloud with cloud
granting access to someone to control
the resource is pretty simple we just
log in to the portal click few buttons
you will have the permission at all you
will be able to give the permission so
it's not only about giving the
permission it is also about
understanding what are different levels
of access controls that somebody can
have in a closed for instance I can have
access and a resource limit meaning
maybe to control the database or maybe
to deploy an application or maybe to
read data within my database and you can
also have access and this source
replevin
what is the resource group in club it's
pretty simple to understand you group
bunch of resources into one group that
becomes a resource group so Iceman's
payroll team for instance can group all
of their resources and they can have
solid payroll resource groups all my
infrastructure will be in one logical do
so somebody can have access and the
resource group level which makes you
will be able to control all the
resources under it the last one is the
subscription level as separately
mentioned in the initial slides
subscription is the boundary in the club
so everything is within the subscription
including the resources and the resource
news so if somebody has accessed a
subscription level is going to control
everything starting from a resource to
all the resource groups so those are
different levels
is that somebody can have so Before we
jump into the solution we need to
understand a concept called our buck
because cloud providers extensively
leverage the are back model in order to
solve the problem of access control what
is our back our back is a loan based
access control model which is used to
perform certain authorization mechanism
our back is not new to you know computer
security it has been there for quite
some time
we are only leveraging the concept in
cloud so all that is all about giving
authorization or giving the access at a
very fine-grained level so what does
fine-grained exactly mean it means that
you are going to give the permission to
a particular employee the minimum level
of permission that he needs to
accomplish a task for instance let's say
I am in an administrator team and my job
is to access the logs and you know move
them to a different location so my
permission should only be at the logs
level to read the logs it should not be
at the entire data base level where they
can connect to the database read the
data or you know I had some details to
the difference there are three things
important concept within our back that
we need to understand the first thing is
the concept of a role so any action that
you perform on a resource he's sort of a
privilege that you have let's say you
connect to database to read so we have a
read access you connect to database to
write data to it remember write access
so whole is basically you know a set of
privileges that somebody has on a
particular resource the second thing is
the scope as we discussed in point
number two about the boundaries we need
to have a scope for the access you can
be a reader but can you read all the
databases in your resource close can you
read all the databases in your
subscription no so scope is all about
defining what is the access control
boundary field and the third thing is
the role assignment remember all our
identities are now in the club and you
cloud knows the list of users
that are going to login to the
applications are going to access the
resources so once we have identities and
roles set up in the club access control
in cloud simply reduces to the activity
of assigning roles to these identities I
don't have to go and give special
privileges to everyone I can just map
these rules in if I want to revoke and
access I can just simply remove the
rules
it's lit so let's look at our back works
in real time let us say a particular
user has issued a request couple of
requests one to a particular database to
read the data and due to a different
database to delete the data what are the
list of things that cloud and we're not
with us before executing this the first
thing it verifies what is this guy's
role thus he's trying to read a
particular column from the data so does
he have the reader room second thing it
tries to determine what is the role what
is the scope of this particular person
he might have read access but he but
does he have access to read this
particular resource it determines the
scope once these two undetermined it's a
matter of faith alone access or denying
glasses in the first case let's say the
user has legitimate access to that
database it will be processed if it is
in the second case made he's trying to
give it someone else's database the
access will not be provide it will be
simply denied so let's quickly talk
about key things to remember in terms of
access control so understand what kind
of access control features your provider
offers because not every cloud provider
is going to offer the same level of
access control mechanisms second things
are back is only an offering by the
cloud provider it will not be of any use
until the customer actually spend some
time to figure out what is the level of
access that I need to give what is the
minimum level of access that my
employees need and accordingly going
back through so the bonus is also on
customer to do that effort and
accordingly about these rules and the
third thing is the case of privileged
account so privileged accounts on those
accounts which have you know access to
highly sensitive environment or any risk
and
where you are gathering lots of
sensitive data for these sort of
administrative access make sure that you
track this separately to see what is the
kind of access these people have and do
they really require it and on a periodic
basis you need to revise and see if
their access is justified and the last
interesting thing is about the
just-in-time access you can think of
this concept as similar to the web
application you know cooking validity
sort of thing where once you log into an
application you will be given a cookie
which means I need only for a certain
period of time the same concept is being
applied in terms of administrative
actions let's say I need to connect to a
remote server to do some administrative
function I will have the privilege to
know this only for let's say fires or
radars and after the expiration of that
time my axis will be automatically
revoked so with this we are going to
limit the exposure of privilege so even
if an attacker gets access to my
credentials out of this privilege time
he will still not be able to connect to
my resource to do any of the harmful
things so just before we move on to the
third one I'm guys following many
questions still awake
okay so now we've looked at what are the
identity problems that and how they
overcame them we looked at how they can
manage the access control problem now
iseman has to look at a different
problem they are worried about the data
security
so as I'm passing mention rat in the
beginning there an insurance company
right what is it what insurance
companies do you find claims with them
and so as part of those claims their
customers will disclose different kinds
of sensitive data things like medical
history things like family is medical
things like payment information could be
Social Security numbers and now they
want to make sure that they can secure
this data so their privacy analyst comes
up with the question that we have all of
these sensitive information stored in
our databases how can we make sure that
the cloud solution provider cannot read
things how can we make sure that if
there is an investigative agency that
comes to the cloud solution provider
even then they can't read the data that
we have all for instance for some reason
if there is a data breach with the cloud
provider that I am storing my data with
even then I don't want the hackers to
get my get to my data so what do I do
let's take a look perhaps this is one of
the most controversial and most debated
topics when it comes to the cloud like
what happens to my data and is my data
secure in cloud so we all know that the
problem to data security the solution to
the data security problem is to store
the information in an encrypted fashion
right and new cloud vendors encrypt the
data and they store it in the cloud of
course all of them do then what do you
think is the problem when the data is
already being encrypted and stored in
the club what is the problem
so with any encryption it finally was
down to the question of who is holding
the key because whoever holds the key
will be able to make it the information
if he has the encrypted text in his
control so most of the offerings that
cloud windows by default have those
where they encrypt the data and the key
also stays with the cloud provider so we
need smelly secure mechanisms to solve
this problem of key storage and key
access and how does this whole thing
work so we are going to talk about
something called hardware security
modules or HSMs as we call so
HSR crypto processors which can store
keys
and the main important point when it
comes to HSM is that once you place a
key in a hitch isms you will not be able
to extract the key outside of the hedges
not even the owner will be able to
extract the key outside the edges but
then what will hedges him do it it can
perform cryptographic operations meaning
you can send data to HSN it can use the
key which is present inside the HSM and
give you the encrypted textbook or you
can send the encrypted text to the HSM
it can decrypt it for you and give you
the plaintext back but the key never
leaves the system the key is always
inside so that's one thing to understand
and the second important thing or the
concept to understand here is something
going to bring your own key I think most
of you might have heard about this so
bring your own key is an offering where
you can bring your own keys into the
club and you can encrypt or you can use
those keys to encrypt the data that we
stole in the club so together with these
two concepts we will be able to solve
the problem of data security and let's
see how let's go back to the same
scenario to the estimate iseman
customers enduring sensitive information
like medical information for instance so
once they enter the medical information
it will reach the insurance application
and insurance application then needs to
figure out what are these sensitive
fields that need to encrypt and those
fields directly flow into the hardware
security module and the HSM will then
encrypted and sent back the encrypted
text remember that the key is still in
HSN nobody has access to it we send the
plain text when we got the encrypted
text which can now go into directly in
the clock so everything that's in the
cloud is encrypted with the key which is
in my control so the westin the best
part of this whole thing is that you can
save or you can create these each
essence within your on-premise network
or you can create them within the club
so if you are already having a chasm
which you are using in an optimized
Network you can simply extend it into
the club or use any of the keys are
wasted any of the cloud provider offers
so don't be confused because even if the
cloud provider in
is offering it in Chisholm because of
the very nature of the concept of the
concept of HSN he will not be able to
gain access to the case let us quickly
go through the things important things
to remember first one is that although
your data is stored in club you can
still retain your control using your own
key and using the concept of hardware
security modules and not just encryption
keys you can identify all of the secrets
that your application uses for instance
like database connection strings or API
keys or even the certificates that you
use for authentication purposes all of
these can be moved to one single case
stone or a key store which is backed by
HSN the third thing is the system should
not be accessed directly by any of the
employees or any of the users because
there is no reason to do so unless you
have some complex business case so there
should only be programmatic access to
access to read or to use these
intercepts and remember case cannot be
extracted out of HSMs but that doesn't
mean they cannot be deleted so if I can
delete a key which is placed in HSM then
all of your data which is encrypted in
the cloud becomes junk because without
the key I won't be able to decrypt it
like so make sure that you have very
tight policies around who can control
these key stores and who can update or
delete the keys within these key stores
and the last thing is once you you start
using these clouds hosted key services
you also get other benefits like now
that you have all of your keys at one
single place you can define key rotation
policies on top of it you can have
proper versioning system for it you can
read the access logs of respect to each
of these key stores so make sure that
you leverage all of these features when
you are using any of the key source so
that it's more different on top so
that's great now they have decided that
they want to move all their applications
to the cloud but because of the nature
of the size of data they have a sales
and marketing application
and there is a really large amount of
data in the sales database so at one
point they have migrated all other
infrastructure except for the sales
database from on-premise and the network
admin wants to make sure that the
on-premise data organized resources or
the database should be able to securely
connect with the database as well as the
API servers the live application that's
hosted in the cloud and so we want to
find out how can we securely make that
connection
let's take a look at that and yeah thank
you so my grating IT systems is not an
easy task it's going to be very complex
and with the more infrastructure the
problem becomes even more complex so
companies do not move their
infrastructure overnight to cloud
they're going to do it in phases so that
they can test the waters and they can
decide for themselves whether you know
the cloud is working for them and if
they should move the rest of the
infrastructure so there will be cases or
multiple cases where some of the
infrastructure still lies in the
compromise and some of the
infrastructure is not 2 o'clock and now
both of these resources need to interact
with each other so how do they do this
this is the problem that you know
network teams face for instance in terms
of implementing these Corrections and
the need to access these resources as if
they are in the same infinite array
that's because that is how we have built
all of our infrastructure over the years
so in the pursuit of achieving these
connectivity there are a lot of things
that can go wrong but it still is in the
same Iceman's case I assume that the
network admin takes the optimized data
base and exposes it to internet so that
the traffic and it's come directly to
the database and you know somebody in
cloud can talk to the database what
databases are never to be exposed
you know openly to the Internet or to
the
many of the outside world so that can
lead to who attack such as brute force
attacks a lot of other attacks so
insecure hybrid deployments can often
lead to political security gaps so he
need to have a proper strategy in case
you want to connect your on-prem
resources to the club resources and
before we jump into the solution and
just spend 30 seconds to talk about what
are the virtual networks within cloud so
think of them as a network boundaries we
played a net for boundary and you add
resources to that red firm boundaries
now all of these resources can talk
internally among themselves they can
talk privately so if one resource need
to talk to another resource it doesn't
have to come over internet it can just
in each other using the local or you
know private addresses so you can create
virtual networks as many virtual
networks as you want in the cloud now
let's go to the solution part and see
what are the couple of solutions that we
have the first thing is the virtual
private network gateway connectivity so
what happens as part of the solution is
you need to install you need to set up a
VPN server or VPN gateway within the
compromised environment and the cloud
provider himself will have another
gateway on his side and you connect both
of these gateways using a site-to-site
VPN so I guess some of you might be
using VPN to access your network from
you laptop that's a point to say VP in
this case since we are connecting a
virtual networking cloud to the
on-premise network this becomes a site
to set repeal and once this connectivity
is established by your networking all
these resources can talk to each other
privately as if they're in the same
network just like you know interact
there is the other solution involves
establishing a dedicated connection
between the cloud network in the
optimized network so they take advantage
of Internet service providers who will
actually come and physically connect
both of these using dedicated networks
which means the communication that is
happening between these two is not over
internet it's a completely private
network
nobody has
to the network so if we come quickly
compared both of these scenarios so the
first thing is about the traffic right
so in first case the traffic still goes
over internet or IPSec protocol of
course it is an encrypted connection but
it still goes on within the Internet and
the second whereas in the other case it
goes it does not go Internet it's a very
dedicated out and because this is a
dedicated lock it has it supports higher
bandwidths so in case you will
production workloads are mission
critical for instance think of a stock
exchange website where you have no scope
for failure and it will make sense to go
with this certificate which guarantees
more availability more bandwidth the
connectivity so that's great so now
these factoids four of these challenges
and now I smell insurance is decided to
move all of their instruction
infrastructure to the cloud now their
security team comes back and has
questions around my security monitoring
and alerting systems are right now on
permits and all of these systems will
not do not connect or obtain the
monitoring and security alerts from the
cloud infrastructure so now how can I
fix this problem how do I solve this
challenge let's take a look
so lot of established companies already
have dedicated security teams that
monitor the network and the host layer
to identify attacks such as brute force
attacks or malware which predict which
is spreading across the network or some
sort of anomalies in the traffic it'll
maybe there is huge amount of traffic
traffic which is being moved from the
compromised to the outside world so that
then triggers another so they do monitor
for these kind of attacks and scenarios
within the entremets world and they
often use tools such as SIEM which
stands for security incident and demon
management to collate or to gather all
of these alerts which are coming from
different systems across the network at
one single place and on top of that I
can write my own rules which will
trigger the alerts whereas in the cloud
you do not even have access to any of
the network to scan the network to start
with because most of the underlying
infrastructure is owned by the cloud
service provider so the question of how
do I monitor for security incidents and
evils in cloud is a very valid question
and remember these tools that we use
within the mantra my spell book they
don't have any out of walk solutions to
say I can monitor cloud it will give you
the alerts right so we able to see how
this will be addressed and another
important point to remember here is that
the threat landscape in cloud is very
different from the mantra minds Network
for instance let's say one of the
credentials of your on-premise
workstation are compromised now can
somebody directly connect your machine
no he needs to be in the network
initially and then he can exploit it
whereas in the cloud if there is a
virtual machine that is public facing
get such credentials compromised I
considered my own connect to the virtual
machine and you know control it so we
need to understand that the threats are
emerging within the cloud and they're
very much different from the traditional
attacks in the traditional incidents
that we used to witness in the optimized
world and security monitoring teams also
need to evolve their strategy in terms
of covering this
his new attacks with respect to the club
so the solution for these kind of
scenarios is identify cloud providers
who provide out of box security alerts
as part of the offering so not everyone
does this
so before you switch to a solution just
find out how are the security alerts
shown within the clock for instance the
screenshot here shows various different
attacks or in events that are generated
within the club so you can see for
confused for networking but storage and
data in for applications so in the cloud
provider most importantly is is able to
show this information to you because he
has access to the underlying core
infrastructure so he can do a lot of
things that you cannot and he generates
this for you and gives it to you and you
can also sort it by civilian use or
critical issues across on the
applications and so how do you monitor
them you know once they show the alerts
couple of things you can do one needs to
monitor these completely from the 12th
so you can just know into their security
centers and you can see all of these
monitor directly from there or you can
bring all of these alerts back to the
monitoring systems that you have within
the optimized network so there are
options to integrate the solutions for
instance you can bring those alerts into
your own siem solution so once you do
this you will have one single view where
you can see all the alerts which are
related contrivance as well as which are
related to the cloud and make sure that
you leverage the custom rules feature as
well custom rules feature is where you
define certain alerts which you think
are specific to your application so
specific to a business case that I use
and you can define these alerts and you
can integrate them but to your
monitoring solutions as well so let's do
a quick recap we talked about identity
so you as a company needs to make sure
that you are in defi what's the right
the management solution for you and what
is the way you want to configure it the
second one that we talked about was
access control and that means you ensure
you implement role-based access properly
in the cloud leverage the capabilities
that are provided by the cloud in the
solution provider the third one is the
data security
so we leverage the concept of bring your
own keys along with the cloud through
HSN so when I say HSN's there were two
options simply remember what the two
options were so one was that the HSM
could be your own demise at yourself and
the other could be the cloud solution
providers Edison and you can pick either
of these choices and see what suits you
best
the third one was hybrid connectivity so
how do you how do you ensure that all
your resources which are on-premise
connector securely to the cloud
infrastructure that you have in place
there are multiple ways as we discussed
pop quiz yes
side to side was but what was the other
one that was there thank you so much you
guys paying attention the first one was
tap tap into security alert so you have
the monitoring systems organized already
in place you can either use the
monitoring system that the cloud
solution provider gives and there's a
dashpot that they'll provide you can
take a look at a dashboard or you can
feed all the information from the
dashboard into your own provides
security systems security monitoring
systems and identifying they care of
those security alerts questions yes
and I would provide us the source and to
their customers right so let me take
that question so the question is how do
csps deal with land somewhere attacks if
they will ransomware attacks which are
spreading within the virtual machine at
work in the cloud you know how do they
operate so there are two ways of solving
this problem one is that remember the
connectivity when we connect them the
resources which are running in the cloud
to the optimizer so if you have your
systems interconnected where you have
virtual machines running in cloud which
are joined to your domains within the
optimized network and within your
occupies if you are having the policy to
verify for such kind of ransomware
attacks you will be covered it's the
more but let's say you are not covered
you don't have any connectivity and your
virtual machines are running in
isolation within the cloud then what
next so cloud providers do have this
technology at least when it came to
wanna try ransomware you know situation
cloud providers receive updates with
respect to which machines are rented
because a lot of these machines so they
do have
even without the cloud is the only
public cloud is what you
your feet might be - think I got that he
didn't it is required for powder okay so
when we say cloak will generally talking
about
in statistical reports of the Fox to the
customer what they can show you is I
should they can assure you for instance
that your application will not be denied
service attacks because they have other
software and other analytics like now is
very big right so they have no order
analytics and intelligence to figure out
whether a particular server is being
attacked on multiple places none of that
so the issue of you from distributed
denial of service attacks anyone but
they don't offer you what they also we
talked what the carabiner name one big
line that's their application
around
[Applause]