all right good afternoon everybody
welcome to securing the worst what about
the data it'll be presented by Jeff Jack
Pavlik here a man of many talents and
I'm not exaggerating
he won't switch himself on it staring
contest
actually not cool Network stuff we're
going to be talking about data networks
is actually why we're here let's talk
about this whole idea of networks
the whole idea of the network centric
way in which we secure our environments
and our data usually people think about
IP s's firewalls maybe laughs if the
budget will permit beyond that a lot of
people don't think outside of that they
think firewalls going to take care of it
maybe I'm patching some of myself maybe
I'm doing some voluntary bility
management but after that that's that's
what we're doing getting people outside
of that is what we're trying to do today
we're going to talk about focusing on
the data but first of all Who am I maybe
I get the miserable reference okay no
all right my name is Jack Alec and I am
also odd-job on Twitter 0dd ej0 BB if
you want to follow me I'm a blue Timur
with offensive tendencies so I like to
say my experience is not leet but I'm
not a noob either so keep that in mind
there's a lot of things that I still
don't know things that I'm still
learning there's probably people in here
in this room who are going to say yeah I
already know some of this stuff maybe a
couple things make it go nice but I'm
sure there's many things we can all
share with each other in conversation
and of course huh do squat over there
all right well perk up your ears you
might learn a few things then I hope
hope it'll be valuable to you and also I
am super beliefs x''b 'l i cannot
believe they actually
that in the program that was awesome I
did that when I did the CFP and it ended
up on the program fantastic that they
did that so I like to post an agenda
before I just start talking on things
that keeps me on queue it also keeps you
in mind of you should be giving me these
things so we're going to discuss the
goal of both information security and
also the threat actors we're also going
to be discussing data in general also
we're going to discuss non-technical
considerations to secure with data known
as business operations and also suggest
features to look for when you actually
look at technologies to secure your data
so who's ever seen this headline no no
you haven't exactly didn't see a single
hand go up because no one ever saw a
headline on the front of the New York
Times in the USA Today or Gizmodo or
anything like that you never saw a
company firewall bypassed in hack maybe
you know somewhere out there where
they're actually describing the hack or
the exploit or the thing that was going
on maybe they say firewall is bypassed
or this control is bypass but generally
nobody the CIOs the CEO the CEO oh they
don't care about that that's not the
thing they saw in the newspaper that is
the thing they saw in the newspaper and
very recently this is something we saw
in the newspapers we woke up a couple
days ago to this so I just had like I
just created my slides this morning so I
was able to put this in here ransomware
hits hospital and closes temporarily I
believe I even saw an entire Hospital
actually had to close that's amazing
that ransomware was able to do that but
again ransomware is not a network attack
ransomware I mean it surfs the network
sometimes to get to another device but
ransomware is a data attack it attacks
the data it's wanting to get at that
data so what's the goal the goal was
with the firewall because the firewall
isn't worth anything
the data was worth something you're
going to see a lot of Star Trek pictures
so we see the data is actually wear
something firewalls aren't when you get
a firewall it is immediately entered
into accounting as a cost it's an asset
for a little bit as a cap acts right and
then it advertises out but it was a cost
that data is going to exist there for a
long time and it's going to have value
why because you keep using it when's the
last time you you thought me wife's
Facebook three Facebook's not free you
are the value of Facebook the more
you're on Facebook the more you're on
Twitter the more data they're collecting
the more data they're collecting they're
correlating that they're doing various
things to see in various market segments
they sell those types of correlations
and things to their partners also known
as advertisers for the money your data
is worth something to somebody
Facebook's data is worth something to
somebody Joanne's the the arts and
crafts store the sewing store that's
their data is worth something to
somebody their data if you if they took
their data away as in ransom where their
operations stopped revenue stops that's
value so the data were something the
firewalls are not resources can also be
worth something right we can have an
entire data center with plenty of
servers in there with ridiculous
processors that can do amazing things so
that could be worth something to
somebody somebody could want to liberate
those resources for their own malicious
or other or other purposes so that's
worth something but we're going to be
talking about data for this but data
it's very important to understand it's
not as far as IT I'm going to assume
we're all IT or security and we're on
the technical side of things here it's
not our asset as far as IT goes it's not
a server log you know that's our asset
it's an institutional asset
we have to talk about data as an asset
not an IT asset companies don't
generally deal with your firewall when
does a company actually deal with your
firewall actually they don't even know
they're dealing with your firewall all
they know is I can't get to X because my
network that my network past there is
being blocked by that and they're
calling you up they're putting a ticket
in and saying hey I can't get in I think
your firewall bla bla bla because of
course their IT right the accountants IT
that's the only time anybody ever
notices the firewall when it's not
working well what are they trying to get
to they don't care about your fire well
they want to get to the data they want
to get to their job they want to do
their work your firewall is not their
work however we know that all levels of
the company come into contact with data
on a daily basis whether it's gathering
storing it's editing its processing its
transmitting its accessing and yes even
destroying data sometimes you need to
destroy data and you need to do that
properly and many of those may not even
involve technology have you ever seen
especially at colleges I used to work in
higher ed ever ever noticed in some
colleges or in some other institutions
where some want to write down a customer
or someone else's username password
social security number or some other PII
and pass that via sticky note to someone
else track that vit what kind of process
do you have in place for that right so
this is data but that is data that's
information you can't track it right now
because it's on paper that was data they
gathered it that way so some of those
processes aren't even technology they're
paper the word of mouth some data is
irreplaceable like intellectual property
trade secrets you know god forbid if
Colonel Sanders recipe ever gets out
right I mean it'd be good for me because
I can cook me some KFC whenever I want
the Colonel Sanders ain't going to be
able to get as KFC in the good enough
profit margin anymore because everyone's
going to have and everyone's going to
know it
I don't know if KFC's recipe is well
known or not but if you've got a trade
secret Cummins has a trade secret for
the new engine
they've got research and design hours
and assets in expenditures pulled into
this brand-new engine that we're gonna
build and release next month and sure
enough the next week they see a big old
advertisement for an engine that does
the exact same thing it's the exact same
design and you go how'd that happen you
can't get that back you cannot get that
back and you cannot replace the cost
that you already spent in getting that
data and creating that data so that's
data so that data is obviously valuable
because it's unique to the organization
if others had you're no longer having
the competitive advantage of
differentiation so I'm like some date a
lot of the data that we think about is
not even about your organization
Facebook's data a lot of it's not even
about them it's about you it's about
their customers it's about their
partners it's about their patients it's
about their employees that's the type of
data we're also trying to we're also
trying to protect isn't it so once this
information is taken it cannot be
untaken you know OPM when that got hit
that data cannot be untaken your
fingerprints if you were in the OPM
database breach your fingerprints cannot
be untaken from that you can't go back
and not get your fingerprints they have
it that's scary and that scares a lot of
people who know who are in that and they
understand what's going on that's a very
scary thing someone has your
fingerprints and you don't know who it
is
vehicles equipment furniture or all
assets we can replace maybe not that
exact piece of furniture but I didn't
care that I had that exact piece of
furniture just as long as it wasn't aunt
Ethel because no one can replace aunt
Ethel couch but we can find a couch
exactly like it and put it back in it
may not have the love and the shape of
our aunt Ethel in it anymore but it
certainly is the same couch
organizations tend to only value their
data after a breach now we understand
that very much people only start
worrying about security when when they
get breached oh wow how much are we
spending on security well we need to
lower that all of a sudden the breach
happens hey how much does money to
security need how much money do you need
can I give you a million dollars right
now and you do something with it that
you know takes care of some headlines PR
wants to know you know that's the type
of thing we see after a breach but data
has a value and if you can get your
organization to understand that their
data has a value on it and that once
it's lost it now represents a cost to
the organization I think you can go far
and taking care of some of these things
that we've been wanting to take care of
because when they finally pay for the
data it becomes a cost rather than a
value and this was generally what risk
managers care about but rarely does
someone actually consider consider the
value of that data so if you truly
protect the data so if you truly value
the data you want to protect the data
you don't want to protect just the
network if you knew your bank for
instance was an opera as an operation
required the bank tellers to take cash
to their homes and count it and bring it
back and hope that everything's going to
be ok that's not going to be
counterfeited that couple a couple
Hondo's aren't going to be lifted or
rolled up and used for illegal purposes
I'll let you decide what those are why
then do we not view unencrypted laptops
USB drives and shadow cloud as the exact
same thing someone is taking my cash
from the bank that I'm supposed to be
securing taking it home and Counting it
doing whatever work they're supposed to
be doing bringing it back the next day
and man we hope to god it comes back ok
we hope it comes back ok
I mean how many times
you seen that in a headliner it's part
of a story oh yeah it was unencrypted
laptop stolen had date on it there's a
nice little Twitter feed actually that
deals with tabletop exercises like I
think it's called bad things daily yeah
love it and one of those is unencrypted
laptop look like a whole database of
stuff was stolen what do you do that's a
great thing to go through and a lot of
that has to do with data that just walks
away from your organization so where is
the data
well here's your trusty old network
right that looks that looks like we can
control a lot of things in there but
then we start getting these guys in
place and now data starts kind of
walking off Prem we get this guy and
that's definitely off Prem oh we get IOT
or some of these other things that are
happening at people's homes we don't
know what's going on but people bring
those things home and IOT may be
involved in some things and we also you
know Samsung Smart Smart TVs might start
listening to your sensitive data who
knows what's going on there there's a
threat model and then we also see a BYOD
that's the classic so where's your data
the network's no longer a place where
the data solely resides and that hasn't
been the case for quite a long time but
we still have to remind ourselves to
this laptops ability tablets USB cloud
can anybody another place off the top of
your head can anybody think of another
place I haven't mentioned there it
covers a lot of ok
many of the new places I say new and
parenthesis they're not controlled by a
firewall they won't be seen by a
firewall they never traverse a firewall
so you have a wonderful policy crafted
in place but it's not doing anything and
even if it does control network access
to a resource for a thing
it doesn't necessarily control who as an
identity has access to that resource or
has access to that data or what kinds of
data once they're in that resource that
they're allowed to grab at even when the
so when the data's on créme they're
hardly is the best defense against the
tax and breaches malware gets through
firewall standpoints because why the
users still need a browse check email
download files and yeah a lot of times
they need to stick USB drives in their
computers
they found in the parking lot that
wasn't distributed by me at all no I
wouldn't do that
all of these bypassed your IPS and
firewalls data that is in the cloud can
be accessed seemingly from anywhere yes
their security groups you can put in
place but they're designed to be
accessed from anywhere and be used
anywhere so you're not going to be able
to stop the those types of attacks with
firewalls and sims where your data where
your data is is also not an IT question
it's an institutional question so the
business needs to gather store and
handle data that's not the IT department
the IT department cannot query what is
in a filing cabinet if you still have
those a lot of places probably do you
can't say oh let me let me just run a
grep on a filing cabinet over here can
do that so what do we need to do we need
to be intimate with our organizations we
have to get inter intimate with our
business operation heads and figure out
the who what where when why and how the
data for the organization and a lot of
times we call the state of discovering
classification have lunch with people go
over to your VP of Operations your CLO
go down to the functional users say hey
I'm going to shadow you for a day or a
half day and at lunch I want to go to
lunch with you and ask hey I saw you
opening that program what was that
program I have never seen that before
how does it work take these notes you
saw them write something down on a
sticky note that looked like it was data
that shouldn't be just written down
what's the problem with that process
let's figure out a different process for
that let's change the way work looks for
them so who needs access to this data I
want access to that data
that's an awesome data so we should
access have access to this data the
firewalls are not going to be able to
tell you so stop looking through your
firewall logs to figure out who needs
access to data they might be able to
tell you who is attempting to access the
network for that data but it's not going
to tell you who needs access to what
particular directories files schemas
tables columns fields
and it's not the end all be well as the
firewalls aren't always in a position
again to determine who is accessing data
you still haven't managed to get access
to the data just the resources we are
going to have to ask the organization
also again consider that micro
segmentation on the network basis micro
segmentation is even on the network
radar for a lot of people is anybody
doing micro segmentation in their
network no it's not on the radar for a
lot of people to make sure that this
device can't talk to even devices within
its broadcast domain and be able to
detect what type of conversations are
going on so that's even a thing and
that's how lateral movements easy to get
around is let me just take a round on a
broadcast domain so be careful what you
put next to each other in the same
neighborhood right so we have to ask the
business operations they're the ones
creating it they're the ones using it
they're the ones handling the data they
know about how those data that data
actually works from there now that we
understand how the business operations
are working we can either change some of
those business operations or we can even
start identifying role-based access
requirements we can say okay so what's
the needs access to this this this we
need to reorganize our data this way so
that the role based access can actually
work you may have to organize your data
a little differently and here's a little
pro tip or at least a little pro opinion
shift your DLP priorities from network
DLP to endpoint of course that depends
on which applies more to you but and
this 80% number is more of a number
based on my experience and understanding
and looking at various networks and
customers I've been in 80% of your DLP
concerns are going to be happening on
the endpoint and even if not do you have
SSL access do you have SSL visibility
into those network streams going out in
your network how many people are doing
an SSL Men in the middle one one person
congratulations CEO said another person
yes expensive stuff yes very expensive
and so a lot of times what I'll
recommend with people is say hey start
on your endpoints first because that's
where you're going to be able to take
care of most of your data handling
that's where you're going to be able to
take care
of being able to see who's sending what
types of data out beyond just that so
just something to keep in mind so the
first thing we want to do before we
start saying well let's get these
technologies let's get DLP odd-job said
and endpoint DLP is where we need to go
know let's first look at the business
operations is there something we can
improve there there's something we can
do better so let's take care of our
business ops before tech always look at
ways you can simplify consolidate the
amount of methods data is actually
handled if you have 20 different methods
to gather the same data consolidate that
down to a couple maybe maybe you have a
main one but then in case it's not
convenient for the customer let's get
the edge case out there as well and say
okay we also accept it this way change
the way work looks wolfs right here in
the middle of this in the middle of the
speaking hall here and one thing I've
always been impressed by what he says is
you know when you make security changes
in the organization about culture that's
not going to get your work done when you
change what the business does as far as
how they gather these business
requirements as they gather this data
when you change the way work looks when
you change workflows and say this is how
your work looks it's security is built
into that not as some weird snake way of
doing something work is going to get
done when security is just culture old
don't click on that thing that's a
culture don't click it but I have to
click it because it said invoice dot PDF
and I'm an account accounts receivable
or accounts payable whichever that is so
I have to take it but if my work no
longer looks like that I go funny that's
not how I do my job and then you know
you start looking through and verifying
is that even who that is because it
throws you off so change the way work
looks before you start changing
everyone's technology in business on
that front so change try to change the
way work looks like make quality
business they get a point of quality I
saw a nice presentation by someone from
anthem and the application security
department
and he actually presents application
security as do quality applications
expose data no but that's a security
concern yeah but that's a quality
concern so let's make sure our business
applications as well as your
technologies have quality built into
them and present it that way
once operation changes are agreed upon
let's look at technologically supporting
those goals
let's technologically audit a lot of
those things because a lot of the things
that we're going to be changing in
business operations are going to need to
be audited and it's hard to do that in
person so we might have to have
technologies to do just that and once
your policy is designed for that you
need to start first when you start
looking at technology start looking
where the data is and securing that
instead of saying well we're going to
start on the network and now that's way
out
that's way out from the debt from the
data start from where the data is and
say how am I going to secure access
within this database how am I going to
secure access within these file servers
how am I going to secure access within
the ERP how am I going to start then
securing access on the systems those are
on how am I going to secure access on
the endpoints that are being used to
access those services or the terminal
servers or that are accessing those
services then you can start saying ok
firewall and get your basic rules in
place but what else might we be able to
do there we go so what is the control
before we move on to technology what is
a control a control has to follow these
three rules as we manage operationalized
and audited I like to think of being
managed as why don't you ever look at me
operationalizes why don't you do
anything about me audited is do you even
care what happens to me or if I'm even
doing my job so manage if you can't tell
me if your entire organization is
covered on the rent point you're on
you're not managing your endpoint on
opera's a operationalization if it's not
kicking tickets out to you or kicking
out emails to you that match workflows
for you to remediate or look into
something for investigation you don't
have a security control you have a
security uncontrol if it's audited are
you sure it's even
right have you tested those use cases
you've put in there that this should be
protecting is it ethical or efficacious
I think of it in there
does it work who's been accessing it
who's been making changes to this thing
can I audit that a lot of compliance
cares about that but that's just one
third of it so let's be taking a look at
those things as we as we these
non-network second we're going to take a
look at and do as much as you can with
what you have already that's very
important if you have something already
in place if you have things in place
already that you can use there's no
sense in going out buying hundreds of
thousands of dollars of equipment or
tools when you have the things already
in place even if it requires a little
scripting a little bit of a little
finesse to get some of these logs
working right if you can get those
things working right then let's go ahead
and use those data classification
solution so I'm not going to read every
every small little thing on here but
sometimes you're going to see that as
part of DLP solutions and there's
certain things that should be allowed on
here that should be able to do it should
be you should be able to create
classification without having to just do
reg X's as reg X's introduce another
problem into the whole equation but you
should be able to actually put in
metadata into a file to say hey this is
this type of data or I see that this is
this type of data going to this database
connections on the endpoint DLP side of
things we should we should be able to
recognize what a cloud app is we should
be able to see oh that's a Dropbox
communication oh they have Dropbox
installed on their machine oh this is a
web browsing connection to Google Drive
or whatever what's going on there I
should be able to recognize those types
of transfers I should also be able if I
have terminal servers or Citrix how many
people have Citrix in here okay no it's
not always in there but a lot of people
have Citrix in their environment and so
you need to be able to have and point
DLP controls on all that that will work
with that
what about database there's a lot of
database controls out there that will
actually look for account behavior so if
someone's doing things that they've
never done before on an account kick out
an alert to somebody hey so-and-so that
account is going crazy across all the
tables there's a lot of account there's
a lot of access failures
that's weird what's going on maybe an
account compromise we can lock down
access by users on tables or even fields
that way too
maybe the system doesn't come pre-built
with that granularity there's a lot of
security tools on databases that can
actually provide that kind of stuff
mobile management is not to be confused
with mobile threat prevention so there's
some overlap there but when you get
mobile management you should be able to
have containerized data controls whereas
if you have a container that has all of
your corporate data that has a VPN and I
can access my files and edit them and
everything like that but I can't copy
and paste out of there the clipboard is
not allowed I try to take it over to my
Dropbox account ah you can't paste it's
not going to happen the data do not go
that way because that container did not
allow that action the email it stays
there you can't forward it to somebody
else you can't just for it off to
yourself you can't copy that email move
it you can't do that it stays within the
container when you leave we're going to
blow up that container right so we got
to take a look at those things and you
should also have app control we should
look at we should look at a limiting
email on the corporate data transfers
inside that container as well so these
are all things look at but don't forget
device file and drive encryption talked
about that before with the bank and
don't forget the Oxford comma that's
thank you don't forget the art because
let me tell you what device file and
Driver encryption or different device
file and drive encryption security as a
service Kaz be anybody heard of Kaz be
cloud access security brokerage of
course will pass so just a very quick
I'm going to make these slides available
but a very quick the cloud-based
solutions they're cloud based solutions
they're designed to look at threats and
control how data is transmitted some
clouds sometimes Kaz B or even security
as a service providers will let you on
on prem giri tunnel all of your traffic
to them so that as you're going up to
other various cloud places they're going
to go ahead and inspect that traffic and
see what's going on they're going to see
who it's so and so allowed to do this
they're also going to be taking in your
Active Directory or LDAP and seeing who
these might be tied to some of the cloud
access security brokerages we'll have
four forward and reverse proxies that
you can put on the end inside of your
network along with endpoint devices you
can put on mobile and also your laptops
that are running around out there so
that if anything is going to go to these
certain places they make a pit stop to
your proxy and that then controls what
access they're allowed to put up there
oh this person's trying to go to Dropbox
hmm we don't have a Dropbox but we do
have a box account on the corporate side
so we're going to just shift them over
to that Oh their leaves in their
personal box account we're just going to
shift them over to their enterprise box
account make sure that that's being used
because that type of data that they're
using is corporate data you know make
sure that they've taken care of or maybe
more want to go ahead and let them do
that but you know what we're going to
encrypt it and make sure that if that
ever gets hit its encrypted again not
just with Dropbox or box it's going to
be Phi 11 level encrypted so look for
those types of things when you look at
security as a service Caspi that's
fairly new technology to this is within
the past maybe four years five years
maybe some of the stuff and it's
enriched with every single year there's
always changes so be looking for those
types of things I'm not giving you
vendors by the way even though I do work
for a security bar I haven't even
mentioned that if you do want to know
about stuff like that
you can still talk to me we can talk to
vendors but I'm not here to talk about
vendors I'm just talking about here are
some controls you can put in place some
places you've maybe never thought of
going before so let's wrap up try not to
make this too long
data mr. data is not an institutional
app or as an institutional asset it's
not an IT asset so we have to go to the
institution to figure out what they're
doing with their own data network
technology is usually not in a position
and usually doesn't have the features to
secure data certain next-gen firewalls
will say oh we have DLP know you have
some DLP features I can turn on on the
firewall that's all fine and dandy but
your firewall isn't at my endpoint oh we
have an endpoint module okay now you may
be talking well
I tell you what once your single
platform goes down if we want to start
going collapsing everything down to a
single platform what happens when that
one platform goes up goes down yeah sure
we have several different solutions but
we don't have layers we have columns and
once I knock down those columns the
whole thing comes down I knock down the
thing that's holding up the columns the
whole thing comes down so we got to
watch out we got to make sure we're
layering that technology we're not just
putting it in place and in parallel or
series I forget however that might work
series of probably the best way to say
since data is institutional security
must be built into the business
operations first we have to think what's
the business wanting to accomplish what
is the business wanting to do if you're
in martial arts and you do sword martial
arts you always hear you might hear the
phrase laid before face blade before
body move the sword before you move your
body not only is that safety but safety
for yourself to make sure that you're
not going to cut but also safety for
yourself or that your opponent's not
going to cut you while you're trying to
move back because if you move move your
sword up and try to move back someone
you have an opening but if you move back
first and then move up that's different
you're protecting yourself so keep that
in mind beyond basic perimeter security
attention has to be mediately given to
data security rather than network
security so yeah we've got our lovely
perimeter end we've got all these very
basic foundational level security tools
in place fantastic that's great we're
not wanting to get rid of those let's
immediately start going to the data many
technologies exist to affect not affect
affect data security measures and
controls and I think I even said that
wrong whatever
so the rapa and I and not this isn't our
last isn't our last data isn't our last
data picture either you still need that
security and this talk is merely just to
explore security beyond the perimeter
any questions
any comments any discussion items
because we still have about I think five
minutes left
has anybody seen some of this in their
environment I see someone in the back
what have you seen in your environment
you'll have to tell us who your
environment is yeah the LP it sucks it
does it's not it's something someone
wants right now isn't it it's an
investment it's money I just have to
give you money and you give me DLP yes
it's also very hard to find yeah yes yes
and not only that they don't others
always understand your business
operations and how those work right
that's a big part of it too so you know
again this isn't going to be you know
DLP is not something you're going to buy
probably from one vendor it's a it's a
program it is a it is an ecosystem of
controls and that's not necessarily just
so I have this technology it's how do I
at various places put in place these
controls and how many people document
stuff after they've done it one person
to person three person four person wow
that's quite a bit and that's that's
amazing document your stuff after you've
done it and as you're going along all of
these steps that we've discussed here
document everything because you're going
to help yourself out in the future
you're going to help everyone else out
in the future so document those things
as well has anybody else seen some of
the stuff we've talked about today well
hi yeah
yep gasps Katie got you there you go
right and again now you're not only
getting technology to not be so much of
a cost but now it's providing a value to
the business because the better you can
streamline your processes and be better
and have better quality in those things
it's probably going to be more
manageable it's going to be more secure
hopefully because that should be a part
of quality and like you said it's not
gonna be broken you can actually use the
things yes yes IT does not own the risk
on anything unless of course something
they put in place cause that the
business owns the risk we're there to
advise on how to remediate manage that
risk so keep that in mind - all right I
think that's probably about all the time
I have unless does anybody is anybody
keeping track of my time I what time is
it
336 okay yeah a couple more questions
comments on anything they're seeing in
their environments now the endpoint DLP
piece like you said there's a lot of
crap out there and there's a lot of
things out there that people say oh it
does this ad does it does this and it
doesn't work so well
and as I always say even if even if
sometimes you can't get the best
protection get to get the best
visibility at the fairly very least get
the best visibility so you can
understand what's actually going on in
your
you know treat your sim again as you're
looking at logs and things treat your
sim not just as a log dump or you just
dump all your logs actually make it
worth something I actually put workflows
in that I actually put something that's
operational make all of these products
also orchestrate themselves to where if
if you know one thing catch if an end
point thing catches something it kicks
off something to the firewall or it
kicks off something else it kicks off a
ticket it kicks off other things other
actions do other controls you have in
place so that it can remediate it can
react to something that it saw or inform
somebody hey you need to further
investigate this so I hope this was
valuable to everybody and I think I was
told once I don't think you're going to
be able to fit all that in in 50 minutes
but I think I did it and I hope I didn't
go too quick for everybody I'm going to
make these slides available for
everybody and I'll definitely tweet it
out
so keep keep an eye on 0 DD J 0 BB if
you want the rest of these slides it
will include the notes as well and as
the second picture indicates let's drink
about it let's talk about it and let's
keep these conversations going you're
going to know more things than I do
because you've seen other things and I
may know some things you've never seen
before so that's why we have to keep
these conversations going so let's not
stop here let's keep going on this hey
guys
[Applause]