hey everybody welcome back
uh the good news is today's talk uh is
talk the talk communicating business
risk during cyber incidents uh all
incidents are incidents including the
fire drill that we just had uh i pulled
that as part of this mostly because i
wanted to have the least number of
people in here to hear what i'm talking
about so welcome back
uh my name is alex nettie i am the ceo
and co-founder of a cyber security
services firm based out of richmond here
uh and ultimately from my side a little
bit on my background
i worked across a number of different
spaces both in the public and private
sectors i've also worked through a lot
of different disciplines within cyber
security i started out originally
information insurance got way down in
the nitty gritty and vulnerability
management and apsec and came back up
eventually to overall strategy uh it
took me through a series of incident
response roles both building programs uh
and participating in those instant
response functions across multiple
fortune 500 companies
a big part of today's talk though is
talking about incident response so
picture this uh it's a quiet friday
afternoon or in this case maybe a
thursday afternoon you've just gotten
back from a fire drill you have all of
the food that you need
and
oh no hackers in the mainframe uh
everything falls apart you've just been
kicking it with your friends you've been
talking about the latest controls you
want to implement or talk about ssdlc
trying to figure out how to make your
program better and everything gets
turned on its head and it kind of ruins
your day
the biggest thing though of course is
you say cool no problem we have an
instant response plan let's roll this
out how many of you guys participate
currently in the incident response
function at your company
trick question you all should have
raised your hand right everybody has a
role but there are some of you who are
experts in this so i'm not going to dive
into cybersecurity and the response at a
high level though it basically looks
like this preparation getting ready for
an incident and this comes from nist
incident response framework
you eventually want to move into
detection analysis you have to be able
to detect an incident in order to
respond to it can't detect it can't
respond
that moves to containment eradication
and recovery how are you actually going
to handle getting rid of that problem
and recovering from it that middle part
though is cyclical as you find out new
information you have to move to contain
it and it's over and over until
eventually you get some level of
confidence that you're done with the
incident
finally post instant activity how do we
prevent this from happening again which
of course takes you all the way back to
the beginning
so uh here from the budget version of
inception called tenant uh we all
believe we'd run into a burning building
but until we feel the heat we can never
know you do uh how many of you felt a
little bit confused when jake came up
here and said there's a fire
i honestly thought he was kidding uh
right he's coming up here saying there's
a fire you need to get out of the
building there's a little bit of
confusion where do we go who do we talk
to where is the fire am i smelling smoke
right you're having all these reactions
and you're panicking this is the biggest
thing to talk about with incident
response is that panic is such a hard
thing to overcome and we'll talk a lot
about repetition here with understanding
and getting comfortable in that space
that's the first thing you have to be in
as an incident responder or really just
in a company or in a company and
functioning in that function of instant
response living in the uncomfortable not
knowing all of the information uh think
about when you see some shocking news on
tv you want more information you want to
make sense of it you turn to conspiracy
theories or whatever other dark web
areas you're going to spin into or deep
depths of twitter to try to find out
answers that's what we do as humans you
have to be okay with not jumping to
conclusions
ultimately you have to have the right
people the processes and technology to
be able to get those answers we talked
about that detection and finding all the
information you need to be able to
respond to an incident
uh eventually though if it was just you
and your cybersecurity colleagues you
could probably take all day right you
could spin through the logs and pull all
the information and get everything back
up and recover from backups the problem
is it's not just you there's a whole
company outside of you you are just part
of it and that's a hard pill to swallow
let's talk business
uh when we think about the relationship
between business and i.t on a level set
on this real quick
here's a good example in the olden days
we had hospital beds and we had paper on
the end of the bed right that's the
chart for the patient it tracks
medication vitals other prescriptions
recommendations from the doctor but
eventually we realized if we put on a
computer you could access multiple
patients from one place made it faster
to pull up and store that information
eventually move to much bigger computers
the cloud to be able to manage that
across the world and pull out much
bigger health outcomes ai and everything
else feeding that
that's what it is
there's a perception problem though when
we think about i.t
we think about companies use or used to
be doing business by paper we think
about taking it to electronic methods
for convenience speed and efficiency and
we think about cyber security how can we
secure that electronic information the
exact same way we used to secure paper
that's awesome the problem is your
organization is thinking about it very
different we do i t because everyone
else is doing it they said i need a dark
web powered blockchain ai
whatever to make all this work cyber
security is not a value added
organization how many of you heard that
one
and there's a bunch of jargon and other
stuff that organizations talk about
that's a huge divide and this is what
we're talking about today is how to
bridge that gap
you need to step into someone else's
shoes haha business look at this guy
he's having a great time
is that what you think of when you think
of your business leaders hopefully
because that's probably about a good
good summation of who they are
the problem with business leaders is
that they're wearing a lot of hats and
here's my boy from caps for sale an old
children's book if you know it but look
at all these roles that we have that are
coming out here
there's all kinds of stuff that business
leaders have to worry about and it's not
always just independent if you work at a
smaller company there's probably some of
your leadership that are wearing
multiple hats right now there's not
always a direct hiring manager or
marketing trends manager or payroll or
i.t or insurances there might be
somebody wearing multiple pieces of this
puzzle and you have to know that as a
cyber security person
a lot of these people have skills that
you don't have and that's okay that's
why we're dividing and conquering and
we're building part of a business the
larger company the more people might fit
in in these individual buckets and again
there might be people that are wearing
multiple hats
what does it boil down to
cia triad boring not going to talk about
it
but business leaders don't care and
boring the only thing they care about is
reputation of the company how do we make
sales how do we keep this going how do
we make this company work because if the
company doesn't work we as cyber
security professionals are out of jobs
reputation the umami of cyber security
so back to friday afternoon
there you are robot hanging out
you're getting inquiries
co-workers hey is something going on
with our product what's up
little g chat
help desk we're getting reports that
users can't access the product
coming from business leaders why am i
hearing the product is down are we in
violation of our slas or our customers
going to sue us do i need to fire up our
lawyers
and vendors hey all our integrations
aren't working what's going on
all of those things boil down to a big
core idea here
and ultimately you come back and you
probably say something like we're
investigating
the core ask here and the root of the
question that's coming in from all these
people is what's going on and how do we
fix it they want the same thing they
want to protect the reputation of the
company so all of these things and these
answers their questions that's the route
that they're trying to get to if you say
we're investigating you've said the
wrong answer
customers we got a weird email is
something going on
news outlet we received a tip you're
being ransomed sure why not
or regulatory body we saw tweet that
you've had a data breach true
we're investigating wrong
what's the core ask here we need
information answers now that's what
we're looking for we need to know how to
handle this and manage this ourselves
externally though
there's you again industry peers are you
hacked tell us what happened so we can
stop it too we care about us but like
you got any uh any iocs anything you can
share with us
cyber companies we're hearing bad things
and we're at your service for a fee
and the government
hi we're hearing something's going on
how can we help how many of you have had
a conversation with somebody from the
fbi dhs or cisa
they have a lot of great tools and stuff
but they want to help the question is
you may have sat down and said i
legitimately don't know how you could
help us you don't know our environment
what do you have that can help me
but they're coming in saying we want to
help
that's the key function here you
probably answered we're investigating
but they're saying how can we help you
with this issue
the question is do you need help maybe
you don't know that's okay
in reality there's you in the middle and
here's all these people
but the problem is i showed all those
arrows always coming in to you every
time and it doesn't look like that in
reality it is insane there's errors
going every which way someone contacts a
news media outlet who contacts you who
talks to a regulatory body who talks to
an executive who talks to his buddy that
he golfs with who works at a news media
outlet and it ends up being the spider
web of nonsense going all around and so
the problem is you're no longer the
focal point you're just on the bottom of
this stack of a lot of people with a lot
of different interests trying to find
out how to fix this problem
and what do you probably hit them with
we're investigating oh man wrong answer
does that look familiar same thing rat's
nest for any of you who've ever worked
in a dc that's exactly what that
actually looks like an incident it is
bonkers i don't know how to put this
politely the problem is is that you
can't plan for everything that's ever
going to happen in a cyber incident
there are so many plays if you will that
happen you could never anticipate them
a hilarious story and i'll leave this uh
company redacted there is a shredit
truck that had come up to shred a bunch
of pii evidence for this company it was
all kinds of banking information
financial information
and the truck jammed up and they said
cool our shredders busted we're gonna
bring in a new shredder truck and they
drove off down the road the problem was
there were still checks and account
balances and financial information
sitting in the hopper and as they drove
down the road the exhaust pipe on the
top took those pieces of paper up and
just literally distributed them down the
road and a good samaritan called us up
and said hey i am finding a lot of your
financial information lying on the side
of this road it's just a long line of
documents blowing around out here
what the hell do you do
did you plan for that no that is the
most ridiculous thing you've ever heard
of it's bridging physical and cyber
security sure definitely information
protection but you can't plan for that
and you have to respond accordingly
so we've got to think about what are the
priorities then for the business
for you
it's an instant response life cycle
tried and trued by nist it's got
everything you need you've got thoughts
and plans and everything else that goes
with it
however your business leader priorities
again it's that reputation cloud
ultimately it's them saying what's going
on and how do we fix it they're trying
to protect the reputation of the company
that makes sense that's the whole point
of being a business
but external entities also have other
priorities things like we need
information answers now and how can we
help you with this issue all those core
things that we talked about so now we
have all of these different things
happening as a result of what's going on
so how do we go from this
racing point in a few years ago just
absolutely botching this pit stop
to world record pit stop instead
that's the efficiency that's unraveling
that rats nest how do we reduce that and
change ultimately how we approach
incident response
the key here is communicating during a
cyber incident
we talked a little bit about this where
everyone is at a disadvantage right from
the start of an incident the first
things first there's different
priorities everybody has a different
view about what they need to do as a
result of their job
you have a different priority than those
business leaders than external entities
and even your co-workers and that puts
you in an interesting position to have
to figure out how to bridge that gap
the second thing there's different
expertise you're a cyber security
practitioner or rit and you're working
in the space and so you know what you
need to do to maybe bring something back
online restore from backups closed ports
whatever it might be
but your cfo has a different expertise
and accounting has a different expertise
and hr has a different expertise and
corporate communications can write way
better than you could ever write
so how do we manage all of those pieces
third there's different ways of working
some people are working agile some
people are working waterfalls some
people are working ad hoc some people
whatever other cmmi jargon you want to
throw out there but everybody works
different some people are in slack some
people are still sending emails and
somebody in your office is still
printing emails and hand delivering them
you know it
but there's different ways of
communicating there's different ways
that we talk as humans this is a big
piece the puzzle when we think about who
we are as humans we have different ways
of talking about the same thing if we
gave a brief to all of you right now and
ask you to come up and present on it
every single one of you would have a
different take a different way of
presenting it and a different way of
communicating that issue
that is the biggest burden when it comes
to cyber security incidents it's not
actually solving the problem
it's figuring out how to speak the same
language everybody is different jargon
cfo's up there talking about ebitda or
stocks or whatever else you're down here
talking about vulnerabilities
none of that makes sense to the other
person so where do we go do we go closer
to business leaders to be able to meet
them in running the business do they
need to come to us
i think it's somewhere in the middle
when we think about something like data
breaches and let's talk about this a
little bit uh this was a study that we
did late last year uh and what we did
was we took a little bit of what the
industry is reporting so in this case
taking the verizon dbir and looked at
what breaches are actually happening and
so you can see it's things like social
engineering basic web application
attacks system intrusion miscellaneous
errors privilege misuse lost and stolen
assets what does that mean to a ceo
nothing what's a social engineering
what's a misuse what's a back door i
have five on my lambo or whatever
they're driving these days it makes no
sense to them
the thing though with the dbir is that
you can see it's pretty well spread out
between things like social engineering
basic web application attacks and system
intrusion that makes sense right that
jives roughly with what we know about
attack vectors today and i know there's
a new dbir out i'll update this data
eventually here
what gets tricky then is what are people
talking about in academia so we go to
something like site.ai and we start to
search on some different fields things
like social engineering and basic web
application attacks and no surprise
we're talking more from an academic
standpoint about system intrusion the
cool stuff of cyber security nobody
wants to write about social engineering
and academia
but here's a problem what is your ceo
seeing every morning when he turns on
the news the new york times or opens up
the sweet light pink pages of the
financial times he's seeing the cool
stuff because it's cool he's not hearing
about the number one attack vector
social engineering that's barely down
there in the new york times in the
guardian some of those other categories
aren't even up there no one's talking
about denial of service in the news
which is bonkers so from that standpoint
already you're behind you're not talking
about the same level of interest in
these individual categories
even worse someone then goes to google
and it turns out they're only looking up
the cool stuff they're not looking up
the stuff that's actually impacting the
business do you even see basic web
application attacks on there and we just
talked about that being the number one
problem
so that is a huge problem right from the
start if you have never talked to your
ceo cfo or any of your other leadership
you're already behind that's a huge
problem so again how do we bridge that
gap we got to communicate for success
first things first what is impacted
we're having this cyber incident and
what is the problem is it email is it a
product is it an app is it something
else wireless whatever it might be
tell them what is impacted the key
though in telling them
is you're probably thinking about i.t
impacts about the specific system app
database server they don't care
what they care about is that business
process we talked about that earlier how
business process is tied directly to it
you buy it to support business processes
shout this from the rafters to everybody
who's in your leadership
if you don't know all of the business
processes that a system and app supports
if you guys have salesforce and you
don't know how you're using salesforce
you better find out because now if
salesforce goes down you can't
communicate what's broken is it just
your sales cycle or is it the website or
all of your inbound marketing or this
conference that you're having right now
you have to be able to understand how
that maps out if you don't the best day
to start is today
the second thing how long is this going
to last this is a tough one i don't know
right maybe i could pull together some
information it's a cloud backup it
depends on how many people are on the
vpn and the concentrator went down last
week from a patch and like i don't know
it could be a day it could be 50 days
that's fine but i don't know is it an
acceptable answer to an executive we
talked about all the hats that they're
wearing earlier those business leaders
have things they need to do people they
need to communicate their jobs that they
need to do
so if you're unsure give a range it is
okay but you're the expert you're
probably the person who can best
approximate what that time range looks
like you could say it could be anywhere
from an hour to seven days that's a big
difference but at least from an
executive standpoint now they have
something to work on if there's a sales
cycle or a shareholder meeting coming up
or something else they can plan and do
their job appropriately
the biggest thing at the end of the day
is that reasonable estimate is a huge
help to them again you're probably the
best person in the company to give that
estimate so you as an expert need to be
prepared to do so
where do you need help do you need money
time people uh one of the big things
that ultimately is for you to be able to
communicate from that help standpoint
and say hey
what do we need help with and more
importantly what might be something that
has a broader impact on the business for
example your email server gets locked up
and you say if we could just shut down
all email because it's literally just
crawling right now it's not really
working it's it's in and out and
intermittent if we could shut it down
for the whole company for 30 minutes we
can restore from backup
that's a conversation that a business
leader can understand and say yeah i'm
on board for that shut that down
communicate for success are your answers
actionable
don't give somebody wishy-washy answers
give them something that you know
concretely don't overstate it but find a
way to give something uh that they can
work with you need to keep the business
moving again i think one of the most
interesting aspects of being in cyber
security is that you probably know more
about some people at your company's jobs
than they do
i constantly am coming in after hr and
going why don't you have an individual
employee number an individual department
number so i can track this and pivot on
it and put it in my sim it kills me and
i'm over there trying to tell them how
to do their job right but they do so
much more than that and sometimes we
come after them thinking we could do
their jobs but you probably
are not the right person to be sitting
down and having a tough conversation
with somebody
you need to respect that and ultimately
that means that you need to give
directions to people so they can keep
doing their jobs is email down as sales
force down what is our backup plan to
keep things moving your number one goal
is reducing impact to business that is
cyber security
not logs not app security not
vulnerabilities that is what you're
doing that's the main top level thing
and you've got to be able to communicate
that to business leaders about what that
means
are you managing expectations there are
a lot of decisions and actions that can
be taken by others as a result so going
back to what i just said you need to be
able to give them the best information
so they can be the best at their jobs
it's okay if that information changes
you ultimately want to make sure that
you keep giving them that information in
real time and keep them up to date
another thing to think about who's
remote working or out sick we used to
joke about this during contingency
planning exercises about like large flu
plagues and lots of people being out at
once and everyone's like oh they're like
sure that would definitely happen and
then covet hit suddenly that became very
real and so that's something we have to
think about is if i normally talk to
this person or this executive who i like
and they're not here today because
they're working remote or we're totally
remote company or they're out sick or
their kids are sick or something else is
happening who else can i talk to you
need to have a list it's not just one
person or a small group of people it's a
bunch of people
constantly communicate this is the
biggest one whatever is going on and you
know as a cyber security incident
happens it continues to grow and change
and evolve and you learn more
information that cycle in the middle
that we were talking about it goes
around and around around you have to
stay in constant contact
if that one hour to seven days estimate
turns into six hours to seven days
you've got to tell somebody if it turns
into six hours to 24 hours tell somebody
let them know what's going on those
regular touch points will make a huge
difference
so after all of that you made it out of
live uh you guys had kind of an ad hoc
process and you've made it through which
is stupendous so what do you do flex
seal boom we're done here right move on
let's get back to business we got things
going on
yeah you've been there you've been part
of this something went wrong uh let's
just throw some money at it let's bring
in a vendor to talk about it we're gonna
implement some das tool and call it a
day and it's never going to happen again
instead let's think back to that life
cycle preparation let's prepare for the
uh not unexpected it's expected right
it's not when an incident will happen
but if or not if an incident will happen
but when it will happen
let's talk about contingency planning
when we think about contingency planning
or the cp family nist or whatever you're
thinking about cyber security but it's
so much bigger than just you
it's about focusing on business
processes how do we keep the company
moving that's what we were talking about
earlier so it's not just about it
systems and apps it's about even other
things like alternate work sites backup
laptops
how many of you know that your company
has a whole storage bin full of laptops
in a warehouse somewhere that they could
go pull from
and how many of you have to go dig those
suckers out and apply patches on a
monthly basis because they're not online
that's contingency planning and that
could make a difference for your company
so that's an i.t piece but for everyone
who needs that laptop the hr person the
finance person the facilities person
that's invaluable
the second thing disaster recovery
exercises it's not just the after
incident exercise that's the key
no more table top exercises everybody is
talking about this we're done with
tabletop disaster recovery exercises you
need to actually fail over you need to
move to a different availability zone
you need to fail over to a different
region in the cloud you can't just say
it works or say the backup works until
you've actually done it and you'd be
surprised when you do it it suddenly
doesn't work and you go man i'm glad we
did this because if things have gone
wrong that would have been a huge
problem you need to actually run those
real tests to make sure that what you're
thinking will happen will actually
happen
your incident response drills this is a
key piece of this puzzle you've got to
be able to find a way to respond and
when we talked about that initial flow
through from the nist side that's great
that's a lot of individual steps
going through the motions helps you when
we talk about that panic response you've
got to be able to suppress that panic
response especially as an incident
responder or someone who's in a role
doing incident response if you're part
of the equation even as just a database
administrator but you're going to be
helping with this incident response
you've got to stay cool calm and
collected that's a huge piece of the
puzzle the biggest thing about incident
response drills is while one talking
through some of these ridiculous
scenarios like those checks being
distributed down the road they're
helpful they're great thought exercises
and it could help you in the long run
it's not about how to respond you could
never ever ever play book for that
shredding check instant you might you
might take it back and say hey i heard
alex talk about this ridiculous thing at
this presentation how would we handle
that that's a good one i used to love to
pull from movies right ridiculous
scenarios but at the root there's always
something that you can say all right if
godzilla shows up what is the root of
the problem well it's going to be that
our office is destroyed so the route is
how do we move to a new office and get
set up and running again all of that is
helpful but the biggest thing it is
about building relationships we talked
about building that bridge back to
business leaders it is about you meeting
people is about finding a common way to
talk about the problem and it's about
becoming friends with those people you
are part of this equation and part of
the larger business if you're now saying
i would love more money
now you have a face and more importantly
there's a reason behind that
that's that post-incident activity
we're telling business leaders why we
need more resources and now they've seen
it right that's a huge piece of the
puzzle they've experienced it firsthand
i'm not telling you to catch them while
they're off guard but i'm telling you to
catch them while they're off guard while
it's fresh in their minds take advantage
of that right come up and document all
the information that you talked about
during that incident and that post
incident
most importantly this is the key phrase
that will resonate with every single
executive that you talk to to reduce the
risk of this happening again
dot dot dot say whatever it is you want
to say
that is worth a lot of money right money
time resources people that is what keeps
a business ticking and so to say to
reduce the risk of this happening again
can make a huge difference
cyber incidents ultimately have a
demonstrable impact on the business so
you want to make your case right how can
you prevent it from happening again what
are some things we could do what are
some things we could do better but also
telling the business if there is nothing
you could have done that is an
acceptable answer to say we could not
have stopped
shredit one of our third-party companies
from distributing uh you know checks all
down the road what are we supposed to do
about that
nothing but having a plan in place to
respond to it when it does happen again
that reduces the risk having a team
mobilized or understanding that hey
let's just have maybe some garbage bags
down at the security desk so everybody
can run out and start grabbing those
things off the road that can make a huge
difference that becomes part of a drill
a contingency plan all that feeds back
into that cycle
document all that in a lessons learned
after action report executives love
things that are written down i don't
know why maybe they like to read maybe
they're just taking it while they're
jawing around to the caribbean on their
private jets i don't know what they're
doing but most importantly you want to
write it down and say hey this is what
happened that's great because now they
have something that's actionable they
can take it to the board they can take
it to their other business leaders but
it is a cya for your ass to put it down
on paper now you've at least warned them
and said here is the risk and hopefully
that turns into money becomes an
artifact that ends up in the budget next
year to get a new tool to get more head
count to get more whatever but
ultimately if it doesn't turn anything
at least you wrote it down you said hey
this was the problem and we tried to fix
it
at the end of the day we're all the same
hello i like money
executives we want money for our budgets
executives want it for their stuff
that's fine
but that brings us a lot closer together
than maybe you're giving all of us
credit for
so how can we get more resources
well let's look at cyber security risk
ratings when we talked about reducing
the risk earlier
when we think about risk we do
likelihood
and impact and it feeds down into
probability and impact and we multiply
it out and its probability impact equals
risk
and this heat map from hell and that's
how we talk about it
all that comes together and we say cool
great yeah we've got some impact i got a
high risk what does that mean to an
executive
nothing
what does that mean to mr krabs
hello i like money
that's what resonates we're talking
about running a business the business's
job is to provide a service which
generally charges money for that service
if you're talking about this
that doesn't resonate with executives so
you got to find a common ground that
works for them
i'm not talking about your dad's
cybersecurity risk assessments anymore
cfos and finances have been focused on
managing money to include earning and
not losing it for decades cybersecurity
is a new profession shocker cfos and
accountants have been around for a long
long time they may be frustrating and
annoying for you but they are very good
at what they do
risk management is a newer role in most
companies but it's broad right when we
think about looking at 10k reports for
publicly traded companies there's
usually risks documented in there
business risk competitor risk coven 19
risk and in some cases cyber security
risk management those a broader function
than just cyber security risk management
you need to remember that that risk
management function is probably who's
running those disaster recovery and
contingency planning exercises it's part
of the broader scope of reducing risk
for the company so they're using things
like probabilities so it's not just it
finally we have contingency planners
like we talked about focus on reducing
downtime and business interruptions
again it's not just about i.t if our
office gets struck by godzilla how do we
get the office back up and running again
or where do we go to work
ultimately you've got to speak to your
business leader's language and that's
where there's this new concept called
quantitative risk that's coming out
this is a big help uh ultimately we
think about things like loss magnitude
how bad could this be how much money
could we lose as a result of somebody
getting into this database how much
money is that worth that is quantifiable
right there's enough data in there if
you're looking for metrics go pull up
the fines for gdpr ccpa they will tell
you how screwed you will be
if that database goes public that's a
number you can tell somebody about that
and if that database isn't protected you
can say hey
right now i'm guessing it's probably
somewhere between five thousand and five
million but probably about a hundred
thousand dollars we would get popped
with if things went wrong and uh we
don't have any encryption on it now you
can probably get a tool to get that
encrypted
one of the big things you can say is how
frequently could that happen again you
guys are experts you have the best
guests one in every five years once
every 10 years once every 100 years
there's data out there about how often
breaches are happening the verizon dbr
is a good report but there's lots of
other data that's starting to be
collected from the industry at large
that starts to fit into this equation as
well
we can then look at things like how to
control it and so we say how much would
we need to invest to fix this problem
looking at things again like the lost
magnitude and loss event frequency from
both of those
and we can pull together and say hey
we've got all the information we need
about how much this control would most
likely cost us the hard part is if
there's a whole process to move through
if we don't know how many people we need
or how long it's going to take us it
could be a range but if somebody shows
up and says i'm a cyber security vendor
and it's going to cost you 5 million
dollars a year you're lower bound you're
most likely in your upper bound or all
five million because you know the cost
so that makes it easier the question
then becomes for that second part like i
was talking about how much does that
actually reduce our risk does it solve
the problem does it change the math from
earlier about how frequent it might
happen and more importantly how much it
might cost us
you put all that together and you end up
with these graphs
these if any of you are financial savvy
look exactly like stock market ticker
symbols or financial distribution curves
your cfo would recognize this
immediately
that's a huge advantage for you as a
cyber security practitioner you're now
taking your gut instinct which is good
and you're actually putting numbers to
that data again you're the expert you
have the best amount of data to pull
this together but if you come in and you
say if we have no security controls
here's our risk range and if we're able
to implement some controls or more
controls and reduce the risk by that
amount they go cool i need to invest
zero dollars for the top one and i'm
totally pwned i can invest five million
dollars for the second one or i can
invest 500 million dollars and get the
third one
i can now make an educated decision as a
business leader about my risk tolerance
do i have zero risk tolerance and i need
to invest that 50 million dollars what
can i call it a day at 5 million go you
know what firewall and mfa and a good
patching program is all i need because
that gets me pretty close to that third
one
that is a different conversation now
you're talking about dollars and figures
and quantitative amounts not just heat
maps
in case you didn't know as we were
talking along there there was different
quotes through the bottom of there if
you were trying to keep track of where
they came from there is all your answers
as well
uh again i'm alex neddy from hive
systems it's been a pleasure to talk to
you guys sorry about the delay with the
fire drill thank you very much
[Applause]
uh any questions before i go about any
of that
easy thank you
[Applause]
you