all right we got a good group of people
here
we are here today to talk about anomaly
detection so thank you for
making it in here
you could be anywhere you could be at
the bar it's a bit early for the bar i'm
the last thing between you and lunch
so um anomaly detection you know this is
an intro talk i'm not going to get super
deep into
machine learning it doesn't really
expect any previous knowledge
it's meant to really introduce the
concept of anomaly detection because
after all you see it everywhere right i
was talking to some folks in the vendor
hall so many products that have anomaly
detection as one of the key parts of the
product or the technology of the
innovation
um and so yeah so thank you for being
here i'm i'm andre i've
been sort of in the devops devsecop
space for my whole career 10 plus years
was a red hat for many years as a
consultant
traveling all over the place now i'm
working for a startup talking to
teams of all sizes that are doing cloud
native stuff whether they built their
companies on cloud native stacks
migrating critical workloads there and
seeing what's working and what's not
working and
i've really become interested i've been
doing server hardening and sort of like
cis standard and diesel sig
automating security automating hardening
automating vulnerability patching and
stuff like that
uh but you know it never quite got to um
that ideal place right actually you can
never get to an ideal place but it never
it was always like a sisifian task where
you're constantly patching going back
trying to shift left and all of that to
achieve security but a lot of people
that i've been talking to are still kind
of struggling to to make sense of that
so the point of this talk is that i've
really started to research a lot about
anomaly detection
and i decided to share a little bit of
what i learned i've been reading some of
the research papers
talking to people that have anomaly
detection as part of their products and
um you know learning a little bit and i
want to share with you all
so a couple of things that i want to
cover today is why anomaly detection
specifically for cloud security right
analytic detection has been around for a
couple of decades you've seen it in the
network space fraud detection a lot of
different areas
but how does it fit within the world of
cloud security and cloud native
applications
so for that we're going to step back
really quickly and look at the history
of anomaly detection for intrusion
detection
sort of why was this created do the
reasons for which it was created still
makes sense in this cloud native
paradigm right
quickly look at a typical model right a
typical anomaly detection for intrusion
detection model
and sort of look at the benefits right
what does it promise to bring to the
cloud security sort of arena right
um and you know no technology no
innovation is without its flaws and
without its challenges right it's not
about trying to find some sort of
panacea or anything like that we're
gonna take a look at the practical
challenges right um you know if i look
at the promise and all the benefits that
it can bring for your company for your
organization or for your to your
practice as an individual practitioner
um you know why isn't it more widespread
today why why hasn't it solved the
problem already so we're going to take a
look at that
there's been some challenges to the
anomaly detection model as well to the
sort of anomaly detection paradigm we're
going to quickly take a look at that and
take a look at the evolution of anomaly
detection there's been a lot of advance
over the past couple of years past few
years taking some of the look at some of
the things that are making it more real
than ever
and
you know
really have a real world impact
so why anomaly detection for cloud
security and why now right so why does
it matter right why should i care about
this right
um you know cloud security is way more
complicated than the sort of paradigm
that we inherited from on-prem right if
you look at the trip you know when i
started as a sys admin as a devops
practitioner
it was you know put the server here
right apache lamp servers whatever the
server may be right and you leave it
there in a rack for a year right patch
it maybe
you do patch it right but it's gonna be
there that static ip is gonna be there
right you can protect it because you
understand it really well you can harden
it and it's your baby right hand crafted
cloud security is way different right
especially cloud native applications
that are being developed nowadays the
typical application
is going to be deployed as a
microservice you know frequently a bunch
of small little services that are
running in kubernetes
running as functions as a service
it has all kinds of funky auto scaling
happening all the time that's
one of the reasons why a lot of people
are migrating
to um kubernetes frameworks and if you
look at you know just microservices
architecture itself there's a lot more
interconnection right there's a lot more
network traffic you know as you look at
these auto scaling situations there's a
more a lot more dynamic ips
so in other words the
it's a lot more complex to even
understand what you're trying to secure
right things are more ephemeral and
there's a larger risk surface
and you know this is actually
not a solved problem in our industry
right cloud security by any means right
so you know everybody here has job
security assured for many many years
because
you know like one research group of
researchers did a scan over the like
this year at the turn of the year
uh 72
of the cloud configurations that they uh
scanned
75 of the organizations
had
uh 72 percent had flaws right had
misconfigurations like open s3 buckets
right
um security groups that quad zero
you know world world re road readable
world writable stuff right
real problem and this is being exploited
a lot right cloud environments are a
massive target right now
and um you know there's more and more
zero-day vulnerabilities right all the
time i mean maybe we're discovering them
we're doing a better job of discovering
them uh but you know uh google's project
zero was reporting you know 2021 was a
record-breaking year i'm sure i'm not
going to say i'm sure but
it is likely that this could be the case
in 2022 as well right so it is critical
right it is a critic what we're doing as
professionals is incredibly important
right i think you know most people could
say that their organization
are all in on cloud
strongly migrating to cloud right and
it's not a solved problem so solutions
are needed
but you may say oh we had solutions
right we had signature based tools
that can protect our environment that we
know and love right
yes we can right but it's not always
hitting the target right this is where
i've been talking to a lot of teams as a
consultant and as a solution architect
and they tell me you know it's very hard
right as an analyst just putting my
analyst hat on right because
you know say i want to protect my
kubernetes clusters right and then i'll
have product x y and z and they'll say
we have 400 rules we have 500 rules i
have 2 000 rules i win you know
and it's great you know it's great but
the problem is you get all of those
rules right you download the rule set
you apply against your cluster against
your environment and this even applies
to cis standard and some other things
right then the app doesn't run right the
server the service doesn't run right and
then what do i do i have to go through
the process of i'm gonna suppress this
rule right i'm gonna make sure that this
rule is applied
it's a lot of work right and it ends up
being a human being
that has to decide what to suppress what
to allow
and as a security analyst i don't
necessarily fully understand the
application stack or that cluster how it
was built right so you know if you
tighten it too much
you you know you start getting a ton of
false alerts right false positives
very common how many false alerts you
get in a day a hundred right and then
people start even checking right stop
checking the siem of course you don't
want to do that but it does become a
problem right
so you know
that is
you know hasn't really solved the
problem right cves are out there we
patch the cvs that's great you know but
do we always why are we are we ever able
to achieve 100
you know coverage within that month
before the flood starts all over again
right
so that's the thing you know and
signature based um security right is
where i have like you know a signature
for a malware a cv number assigned to
that package right to a vulnerability
that's found in a package
um that's all great right but a lot of
exploits that happen in the real world
especially more complex ones that really
threaten the health of the business
end up um being zero day attacks right
where a signature doesn't even exist yet
that's something that happens a lot
right and you know just signature alone
is not solving the cloud security
problem
so let's take a look at what anomaly
detection is and again this is an
introductory you know talk so if you
never heard about anomaly detect i mean
you probably heard of it but you never
really studied it you're what you're in
the right place that's where you're
gonna start if you know a lot about it
let's talk about it and and we can all
learn together
so anomalies right so first of all let's
the lingo and the jargon right what's
anomaly detection well what's an anomaly
right so an anomaly just comes from data
science right and i found this really
decent um description which is basically
a data point that's different
from others in terms of its features
or they're rare in a data set right
they're odd things that happen every
once in a while there are things that
behaviors and things that look different
than the norm
so you know looking at anomalies
where did you know where do we start we
as an industry cyber security where did
you know we started using these models
to protect our environments right this
is basically a lot of the credit goes to
dorothy denning
in the late 80s created the first sort
of statistics you know statistical model
a complete model
to create intrusion detection an
intrusion detection system based on
anomaly detection
anomaly yes exactly
so the idea that she had was that in the
hypothesis behind the whole
research right and the whole commercial
application of anomaly detection comes
from the idea that the exploitation of a
system vulnerability involves abnormal
usage
right
there's a lot of logic to that right so
think about it this way
if everybody is using that system the
way it was architected and it was
supposed to be used we wouldn't have a
problem right developers will log in
develop code commit to the repo
create an image right push the image
requests will come from the outside
front end would talk to the database and
everything would be copacetic right
when things are misused
you know and when things are malicious
you know when nobody's programming or
architecting for malicious activity
right so if we can detect something that
is
outside of what that pattern should be
then there's a good chance that that
could be malicious activity and that was
the basis of the model right there were
some i there were some um usage of uh
statistical anomaly detection
in sort of factories and in the
industrial sector before right you know
you're looking at uh you know airplanes
or the you know uh production line and
seeing things that are outside of that
statistical model like that curve right
but uh dorothy then was the first one
that created a full model that kind of
put that all together
in what could actually ended up being
created um intrusion detection systems
that protected very critical national
systems for many many many years and is
the basis of everything else that's come
after that
the cool thing about this model that she
created was that it doesn't
necessarily apply to any specific system
or application
right it's a conceptual model and it's a
way that you can reuse into a lot of
things right and and that's actually
something that's really powerful to
where we are today we're going to get
that in a second right
how um
flexible this model is right that's
something that can really benefit our
industry as we go
and one of the things that has been
there from the beginning as you're
thinking about anomaly detection is that
it's an extra layer of protection right
i'm not here saying like let's stop
doing signature based detection
absolutely not right that's a must-have
right we still need to um pursue those
vulnerabilities we still need to harden
our systems we still need to adopt all
of those best practices
but
this would be an additional layer that
is very very important
why why is it very very important we
talked a little bit about it right but
one of the things that i wanted to bring
to this talk today was the idea that she
had some original motivations to create
anomaly detection
anomaly detection for intrusion
detection
and i wanted to take a look at do these
still apply to cloud security to cloud
native security right like maybe this
model is outdated right it doesn't
really make sense for our industry
anymore i think that it does right
so if we look at it the motivation
around it was that
in the beginning it was almost
impossible you know she believed that it
was very difficult right to find and fix
all of these deficiencies for technical
and economic reasons is that still true
today
absolutely right if you go to the
commercial sector and you talk to
customers they are constantly
in the hamster wheel of addressing
vulnerabilities you know it's almost you
know then people like i need
vulnerability automation right you know
and yes that's great we can do ansible
we can do all of those things but the
thing is that that's costly
right i'm actually spending all that
time working on that stuff fixing those
flaws and not working on other activity
and guess what i create a secure image
now my developers say yeah you know like
we can't really we got a sprint that
we're working on we can't really make
changes to the system right now right or
wrong
right you know so this is absolutely a
true statement that hasn't changed in 40
years
right very prescient i think the work
that she did
so the other thing this is very much
along the lines of what i was talking
about right even when we know and we
found the flaws
in the system
it's not easy to replace it
you know how many times do is it i know
i know i know about that system is just
don't touch it please you know leave it
there
right very very common why
the developer left we don't have the
source code right i don't have the time
you know it you know
and for economic reasons i like how she
called out economic reasons right we're
running a business right we're running
an organization we have only so many
people working right so many hours in a
day right it becomes very very difficult
to replace systems even if i know
they're flawed
and well okay great so let's do
greenfield let's develop new things and
we'll develop
develop and perfectly secure
right i see
so
don't laugh you know what i mean that is
a belief but but you know it's not
really possible right is it impossible
i don't know that it's impossible right
it's possible like in a sense that
people are doing shift left right
they're embedding security into the
pipeline right they're then doing static
code analysis
they're doing iac scanning right
infrastructure is code scanning they're
doing vulnerability scanning you know
during the build phase so you don't push
that stuff out to production right you
don't deploy that to your clusters and
then when i do deploy it i you know
constantly scan it in the runtime so it
is but it's extremely difficult right
and again you know the economics play
into that right i'm all about
you know sending out new features that
are going to map up to my marketing
roadmap and that are ultimately going to
generate income so i can keep everyone
employed right
so these you can see
40 something years ago and those
assumptions are very much still part of
our
uh context
and this is a good one too by 40
something years ago even the most secure
systems are vulnerable to abused by
insiders who misuse their privileges
right zero trust anyone right 40
something years ago it's still true
right still very much true the system is
perfectly you know the the doors are
locked the windows are locked right but
um you know the people that are inside
the house you know
very common it can exfiltrate data you
know you know the deal
so these
assumptions that dorothy did you know
underpin the research and the model i
think are still very much valid for the
cloud native paradigm
so quickly looking at a model and you
know
um this is a generic model she created
this using just statistics right and
these are some of the components that go
into essentially every mod every um tool
to this day right and we're going to map
this out also to cloud native and cloud
infrastructure
to see how these appear in that context
right so the six components are subjects
right
service accounts
human accounts api keys right these are
the things that are these are the actors
if you will right in that cloud
environment right
very much still a thing right iam active
directory you know these are things that
are um
very difficult to protect
right there's there's a lot of you know
there's whole tools and marketplace for
credential
sort of like least privilege right
making sure that people are not allowed
to overly protect
they want to give root pseudo to
everybody right but sometimes we do
right
so objects objects with the resources
right so in the cloud context these
would be ec2s elbs right elastic globe
you know load balancers right subnets
these will be uh you know inside of
kubernetes it would be the cluster the
you know the pod the container right we
have to be able to kind of identify
those and classify those as objects in
the model right
audit records essentially these are
going to be um you know what we're
consuming to create that model
right so like how can i know you know
what is you know the standard behavior
and what's anomalous
more often than not i'm reading logs
right i'm reading cloud trail you know
logs from aws i'm reading gcp audit logs
i'm reading you know kubernetes audit
logs i'm tapping into audit d inside a
linux system right i'm tapping into
these different resources to build this
model and the model essentially is the
profiles right so the profiles will be
who's talking to who right what's
happening in a given time frame so if
you look at um these resources as nodes
in the graph
right and in the connections between
these nodes as
essentially you know edges right in this
graph you know that's basically as i i
can start building a visual essentially
a logical model of behaviors by looking
at what resources are communicating to
which resources
uh and that creates a profile you know
in originally she did that based on a
template but now there's more modern
ways to create this profi profile and
update the profile right because things
change you know i mentioned in the
beginning that cloud native
you know velocity and the speed of
change is so critical right we want to
you know now people are shipping code
on a daily basis on a weekly basis
bug fixes and features
uh records right okay so i found an
anomaly right that's going to trigger an
event or an alert
right and it's going to go to different
channels depending on where that's going
and activity rules is the idea of you
can use it for a variety of things one
of the things that's commonly used
is to produce a report right to um
trigger some auto remediation
right i can call you know a web hook to
address something right i know i noticed
something
very unusual and potentially malicious i
made sense of that in my model i may
want to try to communicate to the aws
api and change the security rule to you
know close a port right that may be one
thing i want to do
so that's the model and incredibly i've
i've worked to you know i've
been pretty intimate with
one of the cutting edge models right now
um with a company called lacework and
you know
a lot of the stuff is still that way you
know i looked at other vendors as well
did a bunch of research and a lot of
this stuff is still very much done this
way you know so again this research has
really been influential and and um you
know a huge leap forward
so to give an example a more real world
example you know i said this talk was
going to be introductory right all
levels so the idea is think of securing
a house right let's compare signature
based protection and anomaly based
detection
looking at a house right so i want to
protect my house right i work with adt
or some other company i put um you know
locks on the doors i have keychain
touchpad maybe for my garage or for my
door sometimes
you know each person in my house my son
has one my my wife has one right i make
sure that all the windows have alert you
have alarms right that's essentially the
the you know the the signature based
stuff right that's my cis standard right
that's my my my stig right where i'm
saying make sure that root is not
allowed to log in you know you you know
using a password right these are all
those checkpoints that every house
should have quote unquote right
cool right but the thing is that what if
someone you know my son coming back from
school drops the keys on the floor right
and then someone comes into the house
using that right then i will be able to
there's no rules against that my son is
allowed to
to
come into the house at any time right
there's not a window maybe my gardener
can you know use the key to open the
gate to the backyard
you know monday through friday you know
9 a.m to 10 10 a.m right my son can do
it at any time but i can know my son's
behavior right he comes home from school
he goes to do his homework then he goes
to play video games normally he spends
time in the you know living room etc but
then i see that the person that used my
son's key came in went to the master
bedroom
and started poking in the drawers in a
closet
right
that's unusual that's an anomaly right
that's potentially malicious that's why
i'm going to bring this up so one of the
things that we need to start seeing here
is that this needs to be individualized
right
cis standard
disa sig boostig
everybody should be doing these things
right everybody who's operating on aws
you use the cis aws standard right but
the thing is that each house is
different how my family operates is
different than how my neighbor's family
operates right
you know so for example you know maybe
my son you know goes to the medicine
cabinet to get the asthma thing but you
know that other person doesn't the
neighbor doesn't so it's going to be
common for my son to be going into the
medicine cabinet but then all of a
sudden i see an eight-year-old child in
my neighbor in their house you going to
the medicine cabinet
why why is he going to the medicine cat
he's eight years old he doesn't you know
you get the point right so that's
anomaly detection it's really it's it's
giving me something beyond these normal
detections and these usual standards
right
um so
pulling this into the cloud arena right
let's look at this example here right
this is essentially a model right
essentially a baseline i said the name
of the talk is baselines and baseline i
don't know how many people came for the
music part or how many people came for
the security part
i think the security of majority of
people probably you know but but um so
this is a baseline right i basically
built a logical model
of the operations of my
cloud my application my kubernetes
cluster here i have these two accounts
right connecting to the aws api
through these geographic locations
right
portland oregon columbus ohio i have
employees there
right i don't know all of a sudden
getting you know connections from japan
okay maybe you know somebody's on
vacation in japan and they're connecting
to the vpn right
which which which uh you know which
service principles i'm using right which
credentials i'm using right what are the
resources that i'm affect um utilizing
in which regions right some people don't
even have applications in multi-regions
right then all of a sudden i'm detecting
that people are launching all these
stacks on this other region a crypto
miner or whatever right
so this is a typical model of what it
will look like and these are the nodes
and the relationships between the nodes
to alert me and advise me and give me
insights about my individualized model
right
prod is going to be different than
qa than dev
right so i have to be able to build
these models
for the different environments where i'm
doing compute
so you know relating to music you know
it's not a huge thing right but but it's
like you know if you look at the bass
line you know for those of you that like
music you know it's really sort of the
the glue that kind of glues the whole
track together the song together right
it's really the bass that's like driving
that song and then dynamic along with
the rhythm right but you know i pulled
out a quote about groove right it's a
feel that's created by a repeating
framework but also contains variations
right that's kind of like us right we're
creating these applications and these
services to serve our businesses and to
serve our community as the case may be
right and when things are working nicely
everybody's operating you know according
to that underlying infrastructure
everything is groovy right everything is
good but all of a sudden if you hit the
wrong notes that can throw the groove
out right that's the idea of baseline
detection and really understanding your
services your applications your
different topologies to
you know bring up better security
insights and make you more effective as
security professionals
so you know good you know we know that
there is a problem in cloud security
cloud security is not a solved problem
right there is a need for new tools and
new approaches
anomaly detection seems like it still
would make sense for this cloud native
paradigm right we get a basic sense of
what an anomaly detection model is right
so
what's the benefit right i think it
touched on that a little bit but i want
to spell it out a little bit more right
this is good if you're going back to
work tomorrow and you're sort of like
you're you know you are a cio a cso you
know and you're thinking what tools
should i do you know should i buy you
know or what should i develop what
should i focus
my my resources on right so i think that
anomaly detection brings certain you
know benefits
that are going to be really critical for
cloud security and cloud native security
right um and it's not an area that
there's a lot of um
discussion about yet right there's some
vendors that are doing it really well i
saw abnormal here today
sentinel one is doing it as well you
know there's some really good companies
that are starting to do that and it can
really change the equation here for us
so anomaly detection i mentioned insider
insider threats right masquerade attacks
zero day attacks right
these are things that because i'm
looking at the behavior and the topology
of applications i'll be able to catch
those
and the thing that i think is really
interesting as well
is if i look at a malicious actor
if i have an anomaly detection
well you know a good one
in that cloud environment
it makes it it's quite a barrier right
because
i can you know kind of look at the cis
you know sort of standard i can look at
my stig you know hardening on my servers
and stuff like that
and i kind of know the landscape and i
kind of know that like this attack more
than likely will be successful right now
the thing is um if i don't know what i'm
expecting right because i don't know
what's you know what's going to be
detected as an anomaly in this
environment that i'm operating right i
don't know what's the typical behavior
and what's going to be alerted that can
be really powerful right the other thing
that anomaly detection is doing when
it's implemented correctly is kind of
move us away from that sort of you know
huge backlog of false positives like
that needle in a haystack i get so many
alerts how many are actually relevant
right because i'm actually alerting you
on things that are not part of your
architecture not part of your normal
operating behavior i'm getting less
alerts and i'm getting more objective
you know and actionable alerts
the other thing too is alert storms
right alert storms are a huge bane in
sort of like the cloud security cloud
native space why
immutable infrastructure right
infrastructure is code i have a lot of
the same i have a lot of resources that
are identical or at least i want to
right that's the whole idea you know
like
pets and cattle the whole thing right i
have a bunch of identical resources now
a flaw or a rule gets triggered i get 14
alerts right my jira
you know that happens a lot you know and
it can be a real distraction right and
it can really kind of pull the steam off
you know take the steam off my alerting
framework right so because i'm building
that logical model in cloud i know that
you know these 14 nodes are a cluster
right they are kubernetes cluster i know
that all of these containers are a pod
right that's the idea right these are
part of all one auto scaling group so if
there is something unusual about them
send me one alert
right that's the idea here so to kind of
move away from the alert storms
um so you know
okay andre if it's so good and it can
help me so much is it perfect has it
been challenged yes this has been
challenged right i was talking about how
much
uh dennin's
research has been
influential and survived
decades right still influential today
but there's been challenges to the model
from a conceptual framework right
conceptual um
viewpoint if you will
there's a famous paper you know a sort
of
very widely cited paper by gates and
taylor 2009
where
they challenged the anomaly detection
paradigm by saying
anomaly detection assumes that attacks
are anomalous or different than the norm
right is that always true
maybe maybe not right i think the
previous speaker um was talking about
how people you know and this is happens
a lot in network security where people
will hide the payload on the normal
channel like so my my server
is a web server that receives traffic on
port 80 right
and then the they hide their tracks
right they'll put like a malicious
packet or other types of payloads it
could be different things it could be
you know messages on the queue or or
like a batch
transfer that i'm doing right where it
is a normal behavior but that attack was
disguised because it wasn't unusual it's
what that system does normally right
so attacks are rare
that's not always true
um right you know so you know have you
ever opened a ssh server
to the dmz or put it in your house what
happens almost immediately
right logins people trying to brute
force your ssh server right so that
would be hard to detect because these
attacks are very common it's happening
all the time right and the other thing
is anomalous activity is malicious
that's the base of denning's model right
is that always true no
right it's not always true applications
especially now cloud native right we're
trying to focus on sort of the cloud
security space and cloud native
is this true
no because there's tremendous
experimentation right there's tremendous
you know velocity of development where
people are
using new apis they're trying to use new
server new services all the time and
make modifications to the services right
so there are some challenges to the
anomaly detection model and that's why
we want those layers right where you
still have the traditional
security um so a couple of quick
practice practical challenge so you know
i was asking myself this question right
so if you know anomaly detect this is so
cool right how come this is not how come
i haven't heard of this before right how
come
every tool doesn't have this right
because it hasn't been easy in the past
in the 90s and even in the 2000s right
because you got to
analyze
all of that data all of those things all
of those signals all those data points
fast enough
right to create a model right and and
that's been computationally very
difficult in the past right you know i
have a bank i have thousands and
thousands of servers and everybody's
talking to everybody right
okay you know like what kind of system
do i need to analyze that in the past it
was almost impossible these systems need
to be fast enough and they need to be
scalable enough for the challenge of the
cloud scale right you know there's you
know i think this um speaks for itself
streaming data right this is almost
requires an online analysis right
because everything you know um
things are moving at the speed of cloud
right so these things need to be fast
enough these models need to be fast
enough to do that
and you know that's been a problem with
machine learning and data science for a
long time right like a sort of a
fundamental problem that as the data set
grow the dimensions of that problem grow
and it's harder for you to find the data
points that are relevant within the the
the haystack
gets so much bigger it's harder to find
the needle right so that's been a a
barrier before
um the other thing is that
rich domain knowledge is needed
right i can build a logical model
right about how am i going to know
what's actually relevant so i can
surface those alerts
right
great data scientists are a must-have
but you also have to have a great
security team to make sense of that data
in the tool right as you're creating a
platform like this right you need to
have um you know a great
uh world-class sort of security team
that can map
those data dimensions to actual security
insights right and and that you know
hasn't it's not easy right
for example
there's so many new apis and services
all the time and their behaviors are
changing all the time amazon reinvents i
don't know 200
services every year right
this is all stuff that needs to be
processed and kind of taken into
consideration on the model
um talked about development velocity
right things are moving very fast
auto scaling continues to be a problem
this is all makes it very difficult for
anomaly detection intrusion detection to
be effective
uh one last thing on this is disparate
data sources right
we have um so many sources of data we
have point tools i have some tools that
are scanning my code i have a different
tool that's doing my pipeline i have a
different tool that's doing static
analysis something else for cloud i have
inspector here but on azure i have this
other thing right for me to gather all
that data into the anomaly detection
model is extremely difficult because
there's so many silos of information
right so that's been you know difficult
in the past so what you really need is a
platform
right that can either concatenate and
correlate all that data or sort of tool
consolidation is something that's
considered in this arena as well
um finally you know one of the big
challenges for um and i think i'm doing
good on time i can slow down a little
bit ten minutes maybe we'll have time
for questions um
so you know what about um you know
malicious actors that are trying to
attack
your anomaly detection
uh platform or you know effort right
that does happen right so i was you know
as i was doing this research i i found
some some really good stuff where people
are saying here's how you exploit
anomaly detection systems right so i
picked out a couple of things that i
think might be relevant for the cloud
framework
right one of them is target recon right
like casing the joint right as they say
you know we talked about um insider
threat
right so you know and we talked about
how anomaly detection can make the
the ground a little unknown to a
malicious actor right but potentially an
inside
um
inside actor
could tell you what's usual what's
unusual about that environment right and
then can help you kind of develop
attacks and vectors that are not that
out of the ordinary for that particular
institutional organization
right the other way that anomaly
detection systems can be attacked is by
generating noise you know you start to
create a lot of anomalies right in
various ways you know if you are able to
do that
then you know that system is going to
generate too much too much noise
and
you know it's going to be harder for
that analyst to really make sense
of that anomaly or surface that anomaly
with um
with the correct severity right with the
correct um you know urgency
and we talked a little bit about covert
channels where there are you know
um you know malicious actors are trying
to figure out ways where essentially you
you know hide your tracks and kind of
come in through non-anomalous ways
um so you know at this point you may be
losing hope right it's like okay that
stuff is really promising you know it
looks like you can help cloud security
but there's all these challenges and all
these difficulties you know so this is
never going to be more than a niche
thing in our industry right it's not
really going to be the thing
but i think that there's good news you
know and i wanted to bring this up a
little bit right one of the things
that's really driving the
state of the art of anomaly detection
intrusion detection has been the idea of
unsupervised machine learning right if
you look at dennin's original model it
was just statistics right i would say
the typical user doesn't access more
than 100 files on a given day this guy
is accessing a thousand files you know
models have become more more dynamic and
more um you know sophisticated where you
do machine learning and you don't
necessarily need to set the thresholds i
look at what joe does
you know on a typical day you know i
look at what that application does on a
typical day a typical month and then i
give you the model based on what i'm
observing right the thing with that is
that you know machine learning normally
relies on
essentially you tagging that data right
what is normal this is normal this is
normal this is not normal you know so
unsupervised machine learning the
advances in data science
allow you to basically detect behavior
and create those baselines without any
human intervention right so from the
point of view of cloud security you just
provide your aws api your cloud trail
you know your your you know install an
agent on the servers and you collect
that data and the the system will
generate that model for you right faster
you know so that's really you know
driving you know advances on the state
of the art here
the other thing has been the scale and
speed right so you know i mentioned that
one of the challenges of anomaly
detection is the speed and the scale of
cloud
but that also also works in our favor
right because
we can build more scalable solutions in
cloud right we can build um
architectures in cloud that are
essentially infinitely scalable right
and you know using certain techniques
you know in architectures we can make
the stuff really fast as well
so you know i put a couple of questions
here that we may want to ask um as as
if you are evaluating vendors that have
in their marketing brochure i do anomaly
detection right how scalable is really
this tool right how many resources
can you analyze right some people will
tell you 10 000 resources
right
you know
you probably have more than 10 000 cloud
resources in a typical organization
right so make sure that as you're
evaluating anomaly detection platforms
that they can scale scale to the size of
your environment right
so that but but but yeah that's
something that's been a positive that
there are
companies that are doing that and
they're doing that very well today
you know i was talking to the folks at
an uh abnormal and once they built that
model they're able to evaluate an email
in
0.7 seconds you know it's it's pretty
impressive all as a software as a
service
um better research better data science
is available today right there's been
huge advances in the in the science of
this right of unsupervised machine
learning if you are interested in this
stuff if you are someone that has um you
know um that inclination you can look at
stuff like isolation forest
right a local outlier you know all of
the stuff really makes the ability to
detect those anomalies
consuming a lot less memory and a loss a
lot faster right again lending to that
scale and speed that's necessary to
create viable solutions here
so
you know the scale is better the speed
is better the data models are better
um and i think i'm closing i'm going to
start closing this up so you know
what's the future of anomaly detection
right and how it plays into um cloud
security so you know that's the good
news there are better tools right so if
you looked at this in the past you know
like you looked at
some tools like 10 years ago even five
years ago even a couple of years ago i
knew i tested it at our poc that it
didn't really do what i needed it to do
i would encourage you to kind of take a
fresh look at it talk to your friendly
local
you know
engineering head or solution architect
at some of these top
you know anomaly detection companies and
you may be surprised it may be something
that can add a lot of benefits to your
cloud security portfolio
so the second thing that i'm i'm really
looking forward to that you know i hope
is going to be the evolution of anomaly
detection platforms is the idea of
combining
signature base with anomaly detection in
the same platform right that can be
really really powerful so you are taking
you are doing compliance you are doing
vulnerability management but you also
doing anomaly detection right into one
cohesive better tool right we i hope
we're going to see more of that whether
you know but if if done correctly right
the talked about the better data models
get into that it's definitely worth
taking a look at it and i think you you
know just for your own knowledge
understand how some of these things are
are being created it's something that
it's very very impressive
the other thing that's very very
important is it that it's not done
super well yet from the research that i
did is correlation
of the signature based with the anomaly
detection that can be really really
powerful right
so for example i can say
i have these vulnerabilities this system
is only partially compliance with our
hardening standard and i'm observing
this behavior right into one signal and
one alert
right that can be really really powerful
that can really um
reduce those false positives bring other
things that will be difficult to to
arise the other thing too that's
important that a lot of the models are
not doing yet
from my research is correlating multiple
events right i think a lot of the
platforms that i you know research
preparing for this there will be they'll
be able to tell you one anomaly right
this individual anomalous action right
um you know but not necessarily to say
there's a bunch of things that are
mildly suspicious but then putting all
of those together
here is something that deserves
investigation right that's something
that needs more work and that's the last
thing i'm going to say is that um r d is
needed right this is not necessarily no
we need to continue to evolve these
platforms but it costs a lot of money
because as i mentioned you need a
world-class data science team and you
need
a world-class security team you need
people that know how to scale these
services in various clouds right this is
all expensive you know so what's been
happening in our industry that's been
great is all the startup innovation and
the vc cache right that's you know some
folks have been able to get huge piles
of cash to build that rnd right
current economic conditions you know may
or may not change this in the future
right so i would welcome and love to see
more r d happening in there and i hope
that that continues to take place into
our industry the last thing that i'm
going to say is get into the groove
quote unquote right this is worth your
time to investigate is worth taking a
look at that try to bring this into your
security portfolio i think that we're
all going to be better off for that
thank you any questions if we have time
50 seconds
that's it
thank you rva
[Applause]