all right how's everybody doing
we gotta
stay awake after lunch
so guys I'm going to talk to you today
about apps deck we're going to talk
about actually building an appsec
program
um we're going to walk through a bunch
of different stages some technical stuff
and things like that but we're also
going to talk about the psychology
behind it we're going to talk about the
relationships you have to the company
and the things that everybody forgets
about
um but let's jump in
okay who am I uh my name is David girvin
I have a big dumb mustache and I'm a big
weirdo I'm a husband father Surfer
hydrofoil I love Brazilian Jiu Jitsu and
travel
um
yeah I
I have a real weird background there's
just a few things I'm a ship captain and
a pilot I had a fabrication engineering
company and I was a missionary in Africa
and Southeast Asia
so basically that's there just to show
you that I am not the normal got my
masters in cyber security went to cyber
security
and that gave me a very different
perspective on things that's my lovely
family they're way better than I am at
everything being a human and some of the
places I worked were one password we
hacked purple uh bit Discovery and
currently I'm at Red Canary
okay we're going to outline building
your abstract program with a different
perspective on management and
integration
um some of the things that will hit are
social engineering for good I know
everybody's been to Defcon they don't
understand that statement like social
engineering that's what we do to be bad
but there's a good way to do it appsec
is internal sales
be a part of the team
technical sdlc dive and what has and
hasn't worked for me I've failed a lot
and from those failures I figured out
how to do some things right which is
amazing that I could do that but
um warning Concepts thoughts they're all
based on anecdotal evidence from
building application Security Programs
they're my personal opinions so if you
do disagree that's fine if you need to
complain there's my email I used to have
one that was more vulgar but this is
family friendly uh if you find me
abrasive and sarcastic you know but
somewhat Charming you're not wrong I am
but uh one thing I do do well is I care
about people well I just am a broken
human so I come off like a jerk but uh
that's part of appsec right we're
offensive security guys that you don't
want anybody actually talking in public
that's in offensive security and if you
hang toilet paper over the back of the
Roll
get out of my talk
I don't like you there's something
broken with you and if I'm saying that
you're really broken so there we go uh
syllabus these are the things we're
going to hit what's an absec program why
spend money here how to hire
relationship you know threat modeling
stlc blah blah blah I'm just putting
this in there to show you
if you're management and you've been at
technical talks falling asleep uh I'm
gonna have something for you if you're
Technical and your your boots to the
ground you're doing stuff I'll have
something for you I'm trying to make
this fit the conference uh so you can
sleep for part of it whichever one you
don't want to but I will wake you up
um so what is appsec
um application security or we call it
product security at my company yes
people argue there's a difference I
don't care uh but it's it's a team it's
a program designed to protect the code
that you own
um it is uh includes all the code your
engineers write uh third-party libraries
open source tools you use all that stuff
is vulnerable it's a strong relationship
between you and C Level
and any stakeholders in your company
it's internal sales and this is one like
all the super nerds like what sales guy
are the devil and I'm like I'll I'll get
there but you know you have to learn to
be sales and appsec
um it's a smart use of tools and testing
uh it's also understanding that business
doesn't flow there's no product if we
Jam everybody up we don't make money you
don't have a job I mean these are hard
Concepts
um but it's not old school grumpy
gatekeeping they're like pushing the
glasses actually guy you know I have him
in one of my memes
um it's definitely not dumping a
thousand vulnerabilities on your
engineering team and being like fix it
you guys wrote crappy code
um that does not work I can hear the
laughs like the and that's actually not
laugh that's a cry it's like heartbreak
inside
um
uh yelling when something can't get
fixed right away you know
you I am that person I'm an angry person
but we have to learn how to control
ourselves and uh building a wall you
don't want to start a war with
engineering those dudes have been angry
for a long time so you know
um
but you know for the CTO or CFO or
whatever you know why spend money in
here uh here's just a few things in 2020
average cost to businesses affected to
data breach the United States 8.6
million that's an average
sucks if you're on the top end of that
you know uh reputational damage in my
opinion is far worse when I threat model
companies I do the business side of
things too I enjoy SWAT and like looking
at product development planning uh I
talk to them extensively like this all
these small Niche companies like who I
work for uh when I work for one password
you don't use them necessarily
because you like them even though you
should you use them because you trust
the name everybody here's like I use one
password it's my password manager it
works I know them they're good
um so you know same with where we're at
now so uh reputational damage is such a
big thing we have to be so careful with
that and making sure that we protect our
company
that employs us
um
you want to protect your customers this
is a huge thing I think sometimes in
Tech we forget that we have customers
and their people and they do good things
and they have their own businesses and
you know and when it comes to appsec we
want to detect our internal customers
which is our company so
it's uh also estimated that we lose 250
to 60 billion dollars of intellectual
property being stolen is just I can't
even understand that like it's insane to
think how many good ideas of ours get
stolen by other countries and hackers
and nation states all the fun stuff
um hopefully your insurance mandates it
I know Jake's laughing somewhere uh but
uh you know it's one of those things
that we need uh every single company
that has code should have application
security this isn't 2004 and you're a
damn adult so learn it
okay we're gonna start with hiring
um
I love Zoolander memes so there's going
to be too many memes I apologize already
but um you know soft skills are more
important than being a schmee
to all the schmeeze in the room you're
important
I'll give you a hug after the conference
come find me I have the green lanyard we
can hug
um but it's it's true if you get the
smartest dude on your team but he's a
dick nothing happens so if you hire a
jerk nothing will get done
your first hire should be a 50 50 mix of
amazing soft skills and application
security not saying they should be a
dummy I'm saying that they need to
understand how to talk to people and no
application security so higher levels of
understanding of application security is
okay if someone can go okay
giving them tokens is bad
hopefully they have a little bit better
understanding of certain protocols and
stuff like that but
if they get the ideas if you can ask
them like how does this work and they
can tell you but they can't write the
code guess what that's okay
because when you get into real
engineering and you have really
complicated code bases you're not going
to be able to keep up with the engineers
unless you're in that code base every
day
so it's okay to hire newer people who
understand the basics and have amazing
soft skills
um I have neither and they hired me and
now I talk in front of people so
um you know while it's nice they don't
need 10 years of Dev experience you do
want when you start building a team out
you're not just one guy you do you do
need good Dev experience you know on my
team I have a mix of Breakers and devs
and and you know I'm make sure that
we're all learning each other's skills
you know I can write code it's pretty
bad code but I make sure that I team up
with uh one of my awesome devs who's on
my security team and we we code pair
together you know we I make sure that
I'm improving and I teach him how to
think like a jerk so it's it really
works
um you can't find that unicorn and you
definitely can't find that unicorn for
subpar pay
so you have to be realistic in how much
money you can pay people I hear guys all
the time like why can't I find a guy
with 15 years death experience 15 years
of breaking experience has run a
security team and I want to pay him
seventy thousand dollars a year
I don't know dummy like why can't you
find that guy it's math you know
um you can't afford that guy that's just
realistic and you have to find other
ways around that problem it's okay I've
done it before and you can too
um you got to balance your team with
people who have experience in particular
skill sets but are still jack of all
trades uh this is something I really
just smash about all day on my team
which is we need to learn how to do
everything
application security is so big and so
broad that takes 25 years so what do you
do you're humble and you ask questions
and then when someone on your team is
awesome at something like you just have
some just amazing breaker every time
you're doing an internal print test
every time you turn on Burp Suite guess
what we jump on with him for an hour and
he shows us tips and tricks you know if
you have someone who's just an awesome
scripter and he can hook every API up
like it's nothing you know we jump on
with him and we look at like oh my
python sucks compared to yours why is
this you know so these are the things
that you have to do because this is not
something you can just pay your way into
it's massive massive undertaking
um good bridge building can make up for
Less technical skill
but amazing technical skill cannot make
up for a Bridge Burner
this is huge and I'm not
anti-hypertechnical apsec people like
some of the guys on my team and I work
with some amazing people like Matt
Graber like just Monsters of reverse
engineering and stuff they're some of
the best in the world but they're nice
and they're nice to other people in the
company so
can you tell that I came in when
security was a little grumpier than it
is now
um appsec has insane salaries if you
can't afford take a take a chance with a
passionate new person uh we talked about
that a little bit already but uh funny
sarcastic people can be great bridge
builders
um we work primarily with engineers and
it's a different audience than
traditional infosec a lot of traditional
infosec is more
dealing with network you're not dealing
with Engineers or your GRC you're
dealing with Auditors it's very like
Thai and and that kind of thing apps
that's different Engineers are special
people and from what I've seen they're
all different
but they take sarcasm very well
um and it's a it's a great group of
where you can take someone who might be
annoying to the GRC team and you can put
them in the appsec team and they make
people laugh because they're stuck
behind a computer coding all day you
know it's it's a different reality and
um
and we're the best we're the most fun at
the bar I mean let's just be it's just
how it is I don't know why that is but
appsec when you take people out to
dinner we're better than sales people
we don't pick up the tab though that's
why you bring the sales people
um opposing view higher Rockstar
Rockstar security developers to fix all
the bad code so I have friends in this
industry that are very good at what they
do they think what I say is wrong
because they are amazing developers and
they're like I got hired as a security
deaf and I just go in there and fix
everything
that works when you have 100 people
how many here have 5 000 developers in
their company or 10 000 developers in
the country company can anybody jump in
and fix that code base no you might be
able to patch a few things
um so
that kind of security I think worked
really good 15 years ago
I think it's changing though
we have so many more people in the
industry we have so many important
people writing code uh I don't think
there can be a schmee to fix every
single uh vulnerability I just I don't
see how it can scale on a good level
um so you know obviously the baby says
that's just wrong
I just had like my second kid and for
some reason baby memes are funny to me
now and and I apologize for being a dad
and old so it's just working that way
um but you know
what gets us some more uh the technical
side of things here in a second but
we're kind of going through just this
whole thought process on on management
and and how that's all working
um so I teach leadership stuff outside
of work uh real passionate about this I
feel like good leaders raise up people
around them and it changes people's
lives so
if you build an application team
you're going to be a team leader right
um even right now like I have a
leadership role in our team and I'm not
the director
but it's more of a cultural leadership
role I make sure people are doing well
so just a couple of thoughts on on
leading your team
uh it's really easy for your team to
fail from Bad leadership because you
know runs downhill so a good
security person isn't necessarily a good
team leader if your team leader doesn't
generally care about the individual
success as well as the teams you get
shitty middle management uh I see so
many heads nodding right now so you guys
have been there uh when you have the guy
above you who isn't really that good at
his job and he's a jerk uh that makes it
a lot worse you can put up with someone
who's just a monster and they're so good
you're like yeah he's just a little bit
there
um or you can put up with someone who
cares about you you know but when you
get them both and you gotta like take a
step back when you're building these
teams and look at like yourself and
really ask like should I be leading this
team what are my blind spots like this
is hard like humanistic things to do but
um
a few quick things I'm a big proponent
of servant-minded leadership uh customer
focused which is your team uh you know
you're focused on your team members
success
you know if you focus on your team
member success your team is going to
Excel all the other stuff your metrics
hitting your kpis all that kind of stuff
is going to hit
because you're making sure that
everybody on your team is crushing it
they have good mental health they have
the right work you're not putting them
in positions that are too easy or too
hard for them like these are all things
that really matter
um and you know the whole servant mining
leadership thing is leading from the
front you're out there
working just as hard you're a shield
you're not going well Bob just didn't
pull his weight this this uh Sprint
sorry you know like you don't do that
and that just ruins all this because
this team is a really weird team you
have to be technical but you really have
to
be able to push through all the soft
skill side of stuff and and actually
build all these relationships and
bridges which we'll talk about
uh humility and honesty make up for not
knowing everything if you cannot be in a
meeting with developers and they talk
about something you don't know and go
hey whoa I have no idea what you're
talking about
that's a pride thing and you shouldn't
be an appsec you should straight up get
out because there no one in this
industry in application security knows
all that like I don't care who you are
you just don't so you have to be have
humility you have to be honest you have
to like ask questions and be good at
asking questions that's a huge skill set
um you know
honest visibility uh be open when you're
crushing it and when you need help it's
not just being honest and humble it's
also having real visibility you know you
need to make sure upper management your
team knows everything that's actually
going on you're not hiding things all
that kind of stuff it's weird I've
worked around a lot of weird people
um but those things really matter uh
taking responsibility for failures uh
own up right off the bat like I've been
in so many Dev meetings where I did
something stupid
and I'm just like I screwed up I'm
buying everybody here beer and nachos or
whatever we want I apologize
um but I'll be here with you to fix it
you know
that shows those people that you're in
it with them it really does make a
difference when you're just grinding
through all this code
and uh
yes this is my favorite one learn to
care about other people
have you met other people
do any of you drive we already talked
about that earlier
I hate every human on this planet when
I'm in my car
is isn't something that comes naturally
I'm not like I don't wake up and go I
love people I have to like talk myself
up I have to be like okay this is your
job your job is to go in there make sure
these dudes succeed crush this and care
about them on personal levels
you know uh obviously I don't work in
corporate infosec you know because I
actually like have all my friends
numbers at work and stuff like that but
I want these people to win and um I
think that's what leadership is you know
you're invested in their personal lives
so it's hard it's real hard because as
we said we've all driven a car before
and people suck so it's uh it's
something we have to continuously keep
pushing for
I told you he was in here I love this
meme I don't know uh what's our
relationship with the company
um I think this is kind of a different
view than you're going to hear in a lot
of abstic talks
um I don't think that security should be
the nerds in the closet uh and and I've
proven it at my company now
um we're loved by our company we are we
bring value and revenue to the company
uh which is rare to hear uh for appsec
but uh every company would be different
and this is how I try to place us we
view all of our positions as internal
sales and customer service I don't know
if you guys have ever been around a real
modern I.T program but they position
themselves as sales or customer service
to the internal company you know they
treat all the internal employees getting
their jamf updated or their new Macbook
or whatever as customers so they treat
them like humans and they're nice to
them unless you work at a crappy company
we don't treat them like those customers
dream like good customers
um and that's what we try to do too I
look at engineering as a customer base
as valued people that if I don't have
them I don't have a job just like in
sales if you don't have customers
there's no money so we don't work and
then we all have to go back to getting
real jobs where we have to use our hands
um
but we also have a unique place we touch
the sea level we talk product managers
Engineers managers I.T sales GRC
absec done correctly is really
interesting because you actually
influence all these things
um is anybody here like
you know ever done us a offensive view
of product
like I've done that multiple times uh
you know like the salesy term is SWAT
um but I look at as red teaming our
product so I'm not talking about the
code base I'm talking about where we
stand in a business you know who's our
competition uh you know
are we going to be
ousted by this technology what do we
have to look forward to I mean this is
from being an abstract minor person you
think like a criminal that's why you're
an appsec and somehow we're not in jail
and people pay us money to be criminals
it's a it's an impressive thing but we
actually can add value to everybody we
can show the c-suite how much money they
can save and how much money they can
spend these are all different things
that you have to think of it we're not
just going to go run tools that's not
appsec this is appsec
um
yeah and like I said I want my team to
be loved by the company
um
it you'll see why more this isn't like
the weird ego thing
um I know I'm an idiot I don't need the
company to love me for that my wife
loves me and that's all I need and she
really bad taste but
um it's it's a it's a thing when you're
loved by the company you can get things
done
and we ask for the worst things when
something really bad and we go we have
to stop prod and fix this
if it's Chad in the basement going hey
you you didn't do this right
and you can't code anything now we have
to stop production you're not going to
do it right but if it's your buddy that
took you to beers and likes you and like
sent you some cool lock pickings crap
and all this weird nerdy stuff you're
like oh Dave doesn't suck that much I'm
gonna do this for him
it's really about winning people and
getting things done in the company and
and that's you know that's how abstract
has to happen because everybody here
that has worked in appsec has as an
engineer dig his heels on the ground
until you know
it's tough but there's ways to get
around that
so where do we start before anything I
already talked about hiring all that
kind of stuff but where do we start with
our program
um threat modeling
um I heard there were some feds here
welcome
Maybe
if one of you is my Handler I hope you
got my cookies at Christmas
um but yeah
let's threat model it's just what I was
talking about I threat model everything
I threat model business I threat model
my house I threat model appsec this is
this is awesome
uh the normal appsec path is git tool
run tools send 5000 volts to engineering
about them being dumb and not
doing it and has that worked for anybody
I have not seen that work in a company
yet
um I've seen guys making like 200 000 a
year doing that and not getting anything
done that doesn't make any sense to me
in my head
but uh threat modding should help you uh
find real areas of concern uh
exploitable vulnerabilities from right
off the bat you know I've definitely had
threat models where I'm sitting there
and I'm like oh we have everything's
done kubernetes and Docker okay cool
what are we using for our Docker images
oh cool uh
huh did you write all those Docker
images and root
yeah
yeah we're gonna have to change every
single one of our documents now you know
that's a real exploitable vulnerability
that you can just find through threat
modeling and um
you need to build out your procedure
first you need to really understand
threat modeling read some books and then
write it all out and build a policy for
it so anybody can do it don't be a
gatekeeper you build something that
every single person can do
and then you don't have to do things
alone so threat modeling should be
sitting down with that engineering team
with Engineers or even with sales
Engineers I've had Kaizen marketing find
vulnerabilities through threat modeling
programs because they want to sit in one
so you need to build something that
everybody can attain to and jump in with
you and this is building awesome Bridges
um
when you have an engineer in here and
you're talking over something and
looking at an information path or where
you're sharing data or whatever and that
entry goes you know what
this direction we'd be able to exploit
that and he's never thought like that
before hey guess what you have a new
friend
he's going to be stoked he found some
cool weird hack you can even like
exploit it you know with him or her
and do it through that way and then
they're they're stoked now you have
someone on your team forever but
all this stuff
actually gets you ready to start doing a
security sdlc all this stuff gets you
ready to build your program because if
you know where your real weak points are
guess what that's where you start and
that's the hardest point but you got to
make it fun I put you know beer food
give them black hoodies tell them
they're hackers you're a hacker today
they're like oh cool I got to go I feel
like this I don't act like that um I
usually wear purple pink but that's just
because I'm weird
um so the secure software development
life cycle our secure sdlc
this is
what most people think of app set
this is uh how we're going to secure our
our entire code base and the whole life
cycle for development and continuous
Improvement
um
but again this is where people get too
excited this is where people just start
running tools and sending phones and
jumping in and they hear the sales guy
the sales guy told me shift left awesome
you know like uh so you're going to
threat model first before you do any of
this because you can't secure what you
don't understand if you don't know what
your attack surfaces how are you going
to secure it right you're not if you've
done an audit have you done any of the
the footwork stuff first if you don't
there's nowhere to go
um
and uh pushing left isn't always the
right place to start I'll go over that
sorry there's a couple apps like peoples
here their head is exploding that I just
said that but you won't be mad in a
minute
um you need relationships to build and
Implement these controls
if not you will get ignored I'm gonna
I'm gonna say that one one more time you
need relationships
built to implement these controls if not
you will get ignored
uh if you go and run a SAS tool on your
code base and you get 30 000
vulnerabilities and then you go drop
that in jira you might get shot
you know like if you want to piss off an
entire fleet of Engineers go do that and
I have had multiple guys come up to me
they're like dude I tried to start
appsec and and I heard you and I heard
Tanya and I tried to do it and they all
hate me now that's why don't do that we
don't start there uh you're gonna start
with one control
and you're going to plan out your next
year
the whole year you're gonna everything
you're gonna do with that control for
that year
you can do other controls but that's I
need that planned out first I have the
next two and a half years planned out
for my controls right now on my team
um that that includes maturing but
they're out
um you have to be flexible some things
don't work in your work culture don't
listen to every talking head like me
like I'm an idiot like if I say
something you're like well dude so this
but I don't think it'll work in my
company guess what it won't work in your
company like I'm never right
um just sometimes uh and uh after
implementing control
step back build a plan for the
continuous Improvement for that control
or already have in place don't just jump
into the next one
if a control is a blocking control like
it's something that's going to stop the
CI CD or whatever and and stop builds
really be careful with it I always start
it as an education thing where just like
bring something up you know in uh Visual
Studio or whatever and it's like that
was stupid
and then it becomes a suggestion and
then I write policy for it and I slowly
slowly move it after multiple lunch and
learns and stuff like that into a
mandatory blocking control because
blocking controls make people very angry
and you need to have buy-in and policy
to back up those things before you do
any sort of stuff like that
um
but
these are kind of like the basic steps
for looking at this uh it's it's not a
short process the security Guy TV he was
asking me he's like why don't we just
patch everything and start our apps that
program what's it take like two months I
was like
like my first control for this company I
I had to sit through I don't know 20
sales
lies and uh our demos and and then I had
to look at how I'm going to implement
this how I'm going to fix all this how
I'm going to tune the machine or the
tool before I can even implement it like
I mean it takes months to do this and
they're like we want it now well you can
have it now but it's going to suck it's
not going to work if you do it this way
you're going to introduce something
slowly and surely and you won't make
everybody as mad
um and so that's just where I got with
this kind of stuff
for each control uh you know we learn
what problem we're going to solve I
write these out I know it sounds kind of
silly but you know
I dropped out of school in third grade
so uh not really but what technology we
use what part of the company we need to
understand we enumerate it just like
you're doing a penetration test you need
to enumerate these things you need to
write them all out you need to figure
out all your paths we're going to plan
it out we get all the people involved
we put together a good plan of action
including metrics and stakeholders and
everything
and you need to have that in the
beginning how are you going to show
worth how you're going to do all this
kind of stuff uh design look at how
important this control is in your
company it's going to be a holistic
approach I hate that word but I can't
really think of anything else so it's in
the slides a few times but I sound so
corny wait a single pane of glass
Quantum come on give me another puzzle
Synergy okay now we're good do I do I
feel like a CEO now
I feel like going okay and then you need
approval and buy-in uh this is huge
if you don't have real buy-in like if
your VP of engineering does not buy into
the control you're about to put in is
not going to happen just trash it
step on it light on fire it's dead it
will never happen without that buy-in
it's it's a massive part this is we're
getting into the social side of things
right
um and then execute go through your plan
again really like I know people always
say like go through your plan again to
look everything over I mean really do it
like spend time on this because this is
where people get pissed when you turn on
that Tool uh and then improve and this
is where you fix everyone being pissed
this is where you immediately bring in
staff level
uh principal level Engineers to talk to
about the tool that you just did you
communicate with them because you know
them because you've already built those
relationships right right all right
um and then you also make sure you get
in the higher level the people who were
had you get to get their Buy in and then
some newer Engineers you need all points
of perspective you know if this is too
complicated for someone who just started
developing at the company then you need
to make some adjustments for it so you
need to look at it from All Points
so I'll put my slides up somewhere but
this is like an sdlc uh
this is actually one that I just did so
this is real I think I took all the
important stuff out
yeah just making sure I'm not like
throwing my company under the bus on
anything but these this is the way that
I go I look at everything in
architecture you deliver
your develop release your iterate and
then continuous Improvement and you know
you can see all the like normal apps of
stuff in here we got SAS and SCA you got
your container scanning and
configuration
and then you have some other you know
pull request review like where you
actually have to check each other's PRS
I know it's crazy but uh you can't just
in devsecop environment you can't just
let guys go wild but
um you know and then you get into some
of the fuzzing and all this kind of
stuff right I mean this is pretty
straightforward you can look this stuff
up but this is all stuff that does work
so you need to look at a list like this
and I'm always available I Mentor people
and and I consult on things and stuff
like that
I can help you kind of go through this
kind of stuff and figure it out
so your first control should be
completely holistic based on your
company but here's some thoughts don't
start with sassed I've already said this
once SAS is a great control is not the
first control everybody loves SAS SAS
vendors love SAS I don't know they like
took over conferences for too long you
could piss off everybody uh pick and
control low false positives writing
policy for backup your control with
buy-in is a great idea secure coding
standards is something you need I wrote
all of ours for a company and guess what
I'm not the best developer but I studied
this stuff I learned it and I wrote the
policies for it oh wasp all that kind of
stuff has great information on those
kind of things
again cookies and beer because you'll
piss people off and you need to be
thoughtful you know I think that's
something we forget about when we're
trying to build these These are actually
programs that will affect thousands of
people's daily life like
don't make everybody's life suck we want
to care about people
um that's my shift not left backwards
sign
trigger warning for all your appsec Bros
or broets or whatever people who get
super psyched on the stuff don't get
dazzled by shift left sales guys lie not
all of them I was in sales that's why I
say this uh sometimes better off
shifting right for the first control and
you always should end up left you want
to get down down there but shifting
right you have far fewer false positives
um so then your next controls
different for each team uh these are
just some questions I threw in there to
kind of help you think about things but
do you have a budget a lot of code
issues shift left SAS SCA
you hate your developers
um is it just you and you're overwhelmed
security Champions programs are awesome
I love them and slack Bots are awesome
if you can ride a slackbot you can
change people's lives because you know
what slackbots do they answer stupid
questions and we don't like stupid
questions so we make a select button
it's awesome
um hired some folks got a little team
going embedded security Engineers one of
the best controls there is I'm embedded
on a team of people who are all smarter
than me but for some reason they think I
know security and it works is there some
fancy new product coming out
threat modeling and SRA security risk
assessments those things are really
really really important and can save the
company
hundreds of thousands of dollars if they
put out some sort of product that you
could have threat modeled and change the
code's base change the way that we
implement it use a different you know
AWS procedure whatever
and they don't have to go back they
don't have to have 30 to 40 devs working
on it for a month to fix it that's money
so that's your value right there you
just save the company x amount of
dollars and you need to learn how to
tell people how much you've saved
so what worked for me uh for that was a
hair trigger uh what worked for me for
first control most recently I did a dast
uh and threat modeling I found an
engineer he's going to be a security
Champion later she actually uh we
grabbed a quick meeting light thread
modeling discussion we went over this
kind of area uh took burp Suite crushed
some stuff worked real hard to make sure
that I'm not handing them a bunch of
false positives then I got with that
actual engineer went over those to make
sure there aren't false positives and
we're like no these all look real
they're exploitable your mediums and
your lows usually aren't
we looked at their crits and all those
kind of things and then popped in jira
guess what everybody trusted me and this
is starting from scratch I was the only
guy
they trusted me and they got it done
that week all of it
that's because I put the legwork in not
because I'm good at any of this
anybody can do this if you're nice or if
you have a bad personality but you care
about people those are the two things
remember that
um so embedded with engineering I talked
about it a second ago but embedded
security Engineers this is huge this is
new appsec if you have enough people to
map to product get your app set guy in
there in the stand-ups listening they
don't need to write code some I have a
couple guys that do a couple that don't
I do every once well my code's not
always great but um you know it's
important uh they can also get ahead of
those threat models because they're in
those meetings they know it's coming
they can get ahead of the security risk
assessment because they're looking at
the jira tickets coming through
um it shouldn't take up all their time
I'm in stand-ups 10 minutes three times
a week plus planning meetings for an
hour every two weeks on sprints
that's not much time right I have
visibility in the company I know what's
actually happening in the code base
how many apps like Engineers can say
that like really say that it's a it's an
amazing control
so tools
two Acquisitions long and hard uh you
got to do it right trust the hype sales
guys can be sketchy uh all my sales guys
like at the booth are probably just
cringing every time I say that
um less tools you can do to do your job
is the better you don't need 18 things
if you have budget you're just going to
make everybody crazy
um build a plan before you can acquire
tools uh centralized location for
everything in the beginning if you map
this out in the beginning and you have
data coming into one spot you will have
a lot better because I've had it for the
15 Spots I'm clicking through different
tools every single morning trying to
figure things out when all I had to do
was write a few API calls and some silly
stuff in the beginning and my life would
have been better
um
yeah test the tools API before buying
that's a big one
how can you be a billion dollar company
and your API sucks
I don't get it no cyber security if I
had a newspaper I'd hit certain
companies over the nose with it because
it's horrible how bad their apis are I
just don't get it they're billion dollar
companies
um and checkout lost awesome stuff in
there
sorry I talk too much so I'm trying to
push through a little
um no budget no toys
so how do you get budget you've talked
about value right talk about how much
money we've saved the company talked
about how much money it'll cost the
company if they don't give us money it's
like extortion it works
um but that's what you do you know
don't jam up engineering plan everything
out good metrics build those bridges
that's how you like start to get in
there you start to understand these
things useful metrics
metrics are stupid if they're not done
well no one cares about your stupid pie
graph that doesn't make any sense they
drive me crazy it's like the biggest
waste of time out of all the meetings I
sit through are metrics meetings so make
them count make them tell a story ask
the people that you're accountable to
what story needs to be told and build
your metrics to tell that story and
that's also for continuous Improvement
get your metrics to build and show you
where you're failing and where you're
improving and then you can change the
way you're doing things this is
continuously improving things it's
important
um I love Education and Training it's
the biggest thing
um it's super hard it's so so hard uh
there's
a million different things but if you're
building those relationships you're
going to figure out what you can do
lunch and learn ctfs buying some
software all the kind of cool stuff
you'll figure it out because you know
the people that you're working with if
you don't know the people you're working
with I understand some of you have 15
000 person developer companies it's just
you're never going to know it so you're
just going to buy a software and send it
to them that's better than nothing right
but if you're in a company under a
thousand people you should know what
they really need you should also know by
the vulnerabilities you're pulling if
they're making the same mistakes all the
time guess what do a lunch and learn
build a CTF on that vulnerability teach
them these things don't be a jerk
okay social engineering security culture
good social engineering benefits both
parties they know their audience they
have buy-in from all parties needed to
build a culture based on trust and
visibility and servant leadership I know
it's corny but I love it uh bad social
engineering self-focused goals does not
benefit all parties manipulation zero
visibility using the stick instead of
the carrot does that sound like your
manager that sounds like your manager
I'm sorry because I'm finally at a good
company but I've been around those
managers a ton in the industry so
uh educational programs we kind of
talked about that I'm running a long
time so we're just crushed through that
uh continuous Improvement one shitty
control can ruin your whole program
I guarantee you if you just let SAS run
and you don't tune it it will ruin your
whole program uh you need to refine
everything this is just the way that we
get better at what we do automate
everything you can because there's not
enough of us it's a it's a small group
of people and be customer focused your
engineering teams they're your customers
you love them you learn to nerd out with
them on everything that they care about
and make their life better not harder
and it and you really can't and be
objective in where you suck this is
super important if you want to be good
at this job because everything's
constantly changing and you you get a
big head about things uh you're not
going to see that
so these are some ways forward there's
no one size fits all plan everybody's
company is going to be different and I
can't tell you what to do this just work
work for me and I know I talk with
authority like I figured it all out but
I'm just a knucklehead that doesn't
really know anything but I've had some
success in appsec so thank you guys so
much for your talk does anybody have any
questions
go ahead
in my mustache
um this is a mix of insecurity and
arrogance
it's it's hard to figure that out
yeah go ahead
yes
I have amazing visibility with up to sea
level I know CEO CEO and CTO on a
personal name basis I can call them or
slack them anytime I want even though I
have a director between me and them
um my director has meetings with the
rest of our trust team which is Our IT
team and they make sure that everybody
knows the controls that we have planned
for the next two and a half years as
well as engineering we're super big on
visibility no secrets in our company
good question oh and sorry he asked what
visibility do we have uh for our two and
a half year plan on controls
does anybody else
run tools
yes
ah
how do we
portray to leadership that we need the
extra time to build these relationships
and take a holistic approach threat
model those kind of things basically
instead of the old school like buy tool
run tool piss everybody off in the
company
um you have to come in honest I try not
to get hired
I came in and said if you want me to run
this appsec program
this is how I do it
I need time
and if I cannot build relationships you
will not have a successful appsec
program you need to tell your your your
leadership now that even if you're
already hired be like listen
this weird guy made some sense for the
first time in his life
and we need to build relationships and
he's like you're an idiot go run the
tool
but you can show value in making
progress if you start small find a find
a group of people pour into them ask
them like what do you need how can we
make this safer what's going to make
your job better but we're still going to
like grow in our security knowledge and
all those kind of things because you're
actually social engineering a culture
that's the trick here if you can to the
devs yeah if you can social engineer a
security culture into their group
then you don't need a hundred security
Engineers because they become the
security engineers and they know the
code's so much better than we do
so that's usually how I do it I try to
do small things and and I'm really
honest like okay I tried with this guy
he hates me but this guy likes me so I'm
gonna see what I can get done over here
and we're going to leave them alone for
a little bit and it really does make a
sense
did we roll our own threat modeling
program okay so funny enough when I came
onto the company there was nobody and uh
and then someone the VP of security took
a leave for like a few weeks uh going
through some stuff and he was like
you're good at threat modeling just
threat model so yeah I wrote out an 11
page how to threat model document
maybe I wrote too much uh we and then I
threat modeled the entire company I met
with all the Architects I met with devs
and I sat down and Drew out these
horrible drawings because I didn't want
to use threat Dragon so I just used
Google Docs because I'm dumb dumb and
then uh now we're at the continuous
Improvement stage and me and another
security engineer because now we have
like eight people or something or seven
and uh me and him are going through and
revising it and making it uh basically
to a more Elite level we're using
programs to help us have a macro view of
it and then also for individual products
and stuff like that
um but yeah o wasp has some really good
stuff on their threat modeling and it's
a great place to get started but I think
everybody kind of needs to write their
own policies
um and if you have if you get stuck with
that kind of stuff we're all people
don't be like you know I was definitely
like worried about writing policy for a
company I'm like who am I the Right
policy I'm an idiot
um but then you realize oh yeah
everybody else is a person too and and
if you write something that's
personalized for that company it really
does change like the way everybody looks
at it
anybody else before I get off one more
you're all screwed
no no
she she asked uh what what are our
thoughts for larger companies with uh
with embedded security Engineers
um
it depends on your leadership if you can
figure out how to tell your leadership
this is what really does work embedded
security engineering works and we could
prove it
um you might be able to hire
chances are you won't
so you do the best you can because
that's all we can do right so if you can
get you know if if you have you start
breaking up by product then you start if
you don't have enough for product then
you start breaking it up by
um you know I don't know I hate to even
say like front end you have one front
end one for back end and that person you
know jumps around I've definitely had it
where I'm on four different product
teams and I'm doing a ton of meetings
while we're trying to hire and stuff
like that and it still works you still
have visibility you need to figure out
some way to get visibility in there no
matter what and that's the really tricky
part right you have to be creative we're
in app set because we're creative
criminals like so we got to figure out
good things to do I know everybody's
like I'm not a criminal I am so deal
with it is that okay it's not the best
answer I'm sorry
okay guys thank you so much I apologize
for Jake for letting me come up here