hey uh good afternoon for one thank you
for being here i'm pretty sure i'm
competing with this time slot with
spinach article artichoke dip so
you know really i know you guys
really are passionate for being here
um but yeah so let's get into it just a
quick who is this guy standing up here
um so currently the ceo and co-founder
of a data security startup named
failings um we're focused in secure file
transfers and storage uh but prior to
that um well part of that i was in
industry doing so a couple different
hodgepodge things data science software
engineering
and then before that i spent a number of
years in the military specifically with
army cyber
which i still after active duty one is
the reserves um mostly as a cyber
capabilities developer so you know
really focus on building all the fun
tools for
people to play around with
um and then also do a phd research
focused again kind of
artificial intelligence cyber so as you
can tell i'm passionate about it
so um if you guys want to
uh roast me on twitter feel free that's
my handle i have that spread out
throughout the presentation so feel free
to take pictures
and but my only ask is if you roast me
make sure you add me
so what does this next hour look like
talking about the future of cyber
security um i got a lot of stats so
they're not going to try to make it you
know boring but um it's actually gonna
be good picture fodder for you if you
you know prove to your loved ones that
you actually uh came to rva sec uh
second there's gonna be a number of
polls so please uh
please participate um there's some
interesting ones that'll uh really be
telling for you know the the crowd and
then uh third again if you want to tweet
angrily at me feel free to do so just
make sure
um yeah me so i can uh try to be witty
and respond
so first poll of the day
um actually first poll is how early did
you think i was going to do a poll but
who thinks uh human error is an issue
see a show of hands
all right not not everybody so this
might change your mind when you think
about how traffic doesn't actually exist
and it's just human error over and over
again
it really does piss you off so
given that
who thinks human error is a problem now
any anyone's mind's changed
so you know going into like what what
are why are we talking about human error
specifically cyber security for the most
part if you
i'll say a survey or talk to a lot of
cyber security professionals and you
mentioned that you know how bad how bad
are your users you know how bad is human
error people generally agree that hey
there's a problem here but you know what
i'm going to talk about over the next
course of the next 40 minutes or so
is that really we're not spending enough
time focusing on solving for that um so
you know again why is this important um
this is focused a lot on you know
healthcare data but for the most part
this is applicable across all industries
um
but picked healthcare because you know
for when we spend a lot of time talking
to healthcare professionals security
professionals um and healthcare is the
most expensive type of data breach out
there so yeah we'll go that into some
cost centers on like why healthcare is
so expensive but as of you know on
average is the most expensive type of
data breach um
and uh this is a little um
not maybe not the awards you want to win
but healthcare has topped uh for the
last 11 consecutive years
topped as the highest cost in data
breaches so you know for over a decade
now
it continues to be very expensive so
where are we in terms of the you know
state of the breach
it continues to go up and it's not
because of inflation there's just more
and more data out there and therefore
there's more and more data to be stolen
um the average cost of a data breach you
know as you can see i highlighted it
it's increased nearly 10 percent year
over year that's from 2020 to 2021. um
we're only halfway through 2022 but you
know what we're seeing is that trend is
going to continue on um
and and last year or 2020 to 2021 was
the largest single year cost increase um
in the last seven years so again we're
not seeing this pace slow down at all
we're actually seeing it get getting
worse um so you might ask yourself what
kind of data is actually getting stolen
because you know when people say
information data it's a very
ambiguous term so what actually is being
stolen is a customer pii for the most
part um so customer pii patient data you
know that's all very uh
interesting data to breach and there's
actually a
per per record cost so it's about 180 as
of today um for each patient or you know
customer pii data that gets out there um
and that's again that's up 30 dollars
from just just a couple years ago
and then so another question is why now
it's like hasn't data breach has always
been a problem um you know for one yes
but for two if you think about it you
know right now with the remote work with
kovid um
or because of covet in 2020 you know a
lot of organizations moved to remote
work and they weren't ready for that and
at the end of the day you know they had
built a lot of systems that are based
off of a you know perimeter but all of a
sudden you have a workforce that's you
know working at their house
but maybe working at a coffee shop
especially now that you know things are
getting better from a pandemic
standpoint you know you're going to see
a lot more people on workcations
working you know all over the world so
you know depending on what kind of wi-fi
they're connected to and all that it
causes a lot of attack vectors now um so
it's really just without adapting to
that um
it just opens organizations up for a lot
of different ways to get breached um so
and there's actually numbers associated
with this which is pretty cool so the
1.07 million dollar uh difference in
data breaches um collected over you know
seeing if their remote work was a factor
versus not a factor so um i don't know
about you phalanx doesn't particularly
have an extra million dollars lying
around in the case of a data breach um
to deal with remote work but you know
it'd be a lot cheaper to just
implement security uh features to to
work around it
so
here's another poll
whose organization experienced some sort
of data breach in the last three years
we've got a couple awesome
so we have a follow-up poll
who of those people who had their
organization experienced a data breach
who's in the healthcare industry
looks like we got we got a winner yes
so here's a fun fact
more than 93 percent of healthcare
organizations have experienced a data
breach in the past three years
just out of curiosity is anyone in the
healthcare
in a healthcare organization in here
that didn't get breached in the last
three years
uh
i guess no so hey 93 is really high
um
so yeah again getting more expensive
it's up a couple million dollars than it
was a couple years ago and at the end of
the day you know that this is a double
than the global average of a data breach
cost so it's just getting more expensive
healthcare continues to be a very
profitable business to attack um and the
more profitable it is the more it
becomes a um focus so
you know you're wondering maybe
you know what what's some more reasons
why healthcare is a big target um is
hipaa involved so the short answer is
yes so 50 50 000 is the number of um
what a hipaa violation could cost you um
you know it couldn't cost
as little as little as a hundred dollars
but
you know fifty thousand dollars is is
not cheap for smaller organizations a
health tech company you know that's the
kind of thing that could put you out of
business if you're a small business um
400 about 400 000 the average hipaa
penalty cost in 2021. again this is
these aren't small numbers for smaller
organizations even for a large hospital
system i'm sure you know they're not
looking to spend um half a million
dollars because of this hipaa violations
and then post breach response is the uh
one of the biggest issues with or one of
the biggest cost centers associated with
with a hipaa breach in particular
so you know talking about
the cost centers
i wanted to spend a little time just to
break down like again not everyone's had
experience with uh paying for a breach
hopefully but if you're looking if you
have been what we're looking at is this
is the breakdown of
uh where the where the costs are
associated with so 29
um is actually just you know of the cost
is trying to figure out what happened
what got breached um part of hipaa
actually should have included this
graphic but part of hipaa is if the file
or if the data was encrypted then there
was no breach but if there if it wasn't
encrypted then there's a number of steps
you have to take to determine
if a breach even occurred and what got
breached
so that's actually really interesting
because if you think about it
organizations have to pay for data
breaches
pay for more data than was actually
truly breached because they don't know
what exactly was breach so part of that
again
detection escalation um 38 seems kind of
obvious but in terms of what it is but
lost business so you know what can go
into that is
um even uh or people just not trusting
your organization anymore so
um
there was a target breach a number of
years ago that actually affected their
sales after that because people were
like well i don't use my credit card at
target um if it's just going to get you
know on the dark way afterwards so in
addition to
uh not trusting your organization and
and distrust and obviously um let's say
it's a ransomware attack and things are
shut down then at that point you know
there's nothing you can do
um business-wise until you fix that um
six percent notification and that's just
letting people know that their data was
out there um pretty sure
quick side poll again has anyone not
received a letter
ever that that says your data has been
breached and we're paying for a year of
sir
wow
i hope
keep that streak going
um
that's amazing okay so one day
you may receive in the mail
a letter that says your data has been
reached x y and z like could have even
been four years actually this happened
recently i was talking to somebody
um
they had gone to the hospital four years
ago um and they received a letter this
week that said their their data was just
breached but because their data was
sitting in a database um four years ago
that data left too so you know pretty
much what you get is a year of
monitoring so
that's the the consolation prize for
having your data out there um
but anyway so six percent of the cost is
associated with that kind of
notification and then 27 percent again
the post uh post breach responses
and that's just dealing with the
aftermath of a breach whether it be um
settlements or you know even like
additional controls that kind of
knee-jerk reaction of oh we lost all
this data maybe we should fire our ciso
and go buy a dlp tool um which
we all know is not gonna be worth any
money um
so anyway so the best way to kind of
walk through this wanted to walk through
an example right so
um we have a real company using it this
is a real
scenario that happened um fake name uh
but i didn't try too hard to make it
fake so if you know this organization
uh i just shortened it down to m so for
their privacy's sake um
so anyway hopefully none of you are from
mhealth
uh so anyway we're going to walk through
kind of a data breach at mhealth see how
that went through for them um
you know see how the effect of that
cyber breach can have on a health
organization um and then you know to
kind of talk through what went wrong
and um spoiler alert
people went wrong
so
uh
backstory what what happened what
alerted the organization how do they
even know the breach a breach occurred
um so they actually got a missed payment
so they're like huh well that's strange
um if they're i guess a vendor i got a
missed payment so the vendor was like
hey you know there's something wrong
here um
so they're like hey by the way m health
um there
is a is a missed payment and this is a
july of 2021 so this is a pretty recent
less than a year ago uh event so mhealth
of course is like well we got to now go
figure out if a breach or what what is
going on right now so
again not kind of not surprising here is
a uh
sorry
is a business email compromise so what
happened was a their vendor
contractor had a business email
compromise and it was actually several
threat actors got in so it was kind of a
party in there so to speak um pretty
much everyone but maybe the contractor
was was producing those emails
and then they were able to essentially
use that uh compromised email as a way
to fish other people to get you know
work through the organization
essentially being able to
legitimize themselves with that email
account because it's coming from a
actual
email from that organization so
the infamous supply chain tax so gg
this is another case of a supply chain
attack which is annoying obviously for
all of us as
you can spend all the money in the world
securing your
uh your organization especially if
you're using a perimeter-based system um
or architecture and if your vendors get
hacked then and they have your data then
there's kind of nothing you can do about
it
so
speaking of gg supply chain attack
another poll so i don't know if that's
like a dated reference is gigi still
cool do people still use gg
looks like i'm getting zero
all right is there
oh no we got one we got two
um
so
uh i wanted to also translate this for
our gen z folk um
which i believe would be
does gigi still slap no cap
if that helps
all right so
i'm kind of going more into you know how
did this attack occur walking through
the data breach itself so
again that uh the contractor's email was
compromised threat actors were able to
use those emails to legitimize
themselves
and then perform more phishing attacks
so uh they were able they were able to
fish for over three months of again kind
of honestly i'd very curious about the
contractor who i don't know if they like
looked into their send box and was like
oh hey look there's a bunch of emails
asking for a bunch of sketchy
information
that i don't remember sending who knows
maybe they just don't do a lot of work
on their email um
but anyway so the the compromise
accounts that they ended up getting
through those phishing attacks had
patient information that were included
and um you know again employee data for
mhealth too so in this case they were
able to steal not just only uh you know
customer pii patient data but also
employee data which they can you know
obviously use and sell but they can also
use that to perpetrate more attacks so
they can use
pretty much as mhealth as a vendor to
other organizations they can jump across
even more organizations because they
have a legitimate employee data
so looking into the aftermath of what
this attack cost so it's a 7 million
average you know the average cost again
using the 180
um
pii
7 million dollars like that's not cheap
again not a lot of organizations uh
small businesses don't have that lying
around just waiting for a settlement um
the hipaa violations alone were almost
four million dollars of that and and
again um
part of that goes into the
post breach response
again was the highest part of that
payment wise sixty percent um
same for uh and then the most the other
was uh the detection and escalation
again just paying for
or the money involved and just figuring
out what data got breached
and having to pay for the ones that they
couldn't prove that wasn't breached
again seven million dollars is is pretty
pricey for
a supply chain attack so
what is
the leading cause of breaches
we got a people guess we got any other
guesses
attacker man
no i'm kidding
it's hackerman let's just call it a day
no um
yes so people human error not surprising
um and it's something that we've all um
you know all have experienced and dealt
with so
basic and it's not even you know big
you know massively orchestrated attacks
or you know massive errors on a
employee's fault but it's just like
really basic small things that add up
and and open up um your organization to
to to have different attack factors um
and it's been the same issue for
for who knows how many years um
but really interestingly if you think
about like again kind of like so human
error is
not very specific what what are some of
the human errors that are causing these
problems
obviously you know phishing is you know
being not being able to determine a
phishing email again that's probably the
most common that people think about but
missed delivery 36 percent of errors is
mis-delivery
and that's just i i accidentally sent
you data that you shouldn't see um and
obviously that is it's actually pretty
scary if you think about that 36 percent
of data breaches if somebody just didn't
pay attention who they sent the data to
um indexes yeah publishing errors and
misconfiguration again that's pretty
pretty scary and sometimes out of your
control so there's a case of microsoft
um for one drive so
there's a person who logs into their
corporate onedrive account and they
notice that all the files were not their
company's files but just another
company's files um and what happened was
on the server side of microsoft somebody
did some sort of uh misconfiguration on
the policy and yeah they just like
just were showing other people other
people's data so i don't think that
actually resulted in any stolen or lost
data from a breach perspective but um
very well could have been right so it's
really
um
especially now we're moving more into
like cloud services it's hard to say
that we control our own data when
something like that could happen
and then the
the next one after that is a web
application attack so that one
you guys have know all about web app
attacks so we will go too deep into that
so how bad is human error
again fishing not surprising there but
it is on top continues to be a problem
there is not enough fishing education
out in the world to stop people from
just clicking the thing i mean and again
this isn't a security professionals get
it right all the time
i've clicked some scheduling links
sometimes and and it fell uh victim to
an internal corporate phishing campaign
to like suss people out so you know it's
like
it happens sometimes you're tired not
really paying attention like you know it
it happened like human error happened so
instead of trying to
wipe away the fact that it happens you
know we really need to start focus on
and um you know addressing it and
acknowledging that it is and how do we
help people to not um
not do this kind of thing so again
humans are the problem
with two r's um
unintentional but hey human error
right if that two r's was me
accidentally typing someone's name wrong
and sending some data to a different
email account that would have been a
data breach um and then and even with
ransomware uh 13 of that deals you know
has some sort of human related aspect to
it
um
so again we're digging deeper a little
bit like what is what is human error
really costing us um at the end of the
day you know from a business perspective
a lot of business owners that's you know
the bottom line right that's what
matters to them but at the end of the
day if you can quantify how much human
error costs it piques a lot of people's
interest so business email compromise
continue to be the most expensive type
of data they're not the most common but
they're the most expensive
and the most the reason why is that
a lot of people again sometimes myself
included
use our emails like a
ghost file server
so that's not good
so let's say you're you know you're
sending these massive excel files uh
full of all kinds of data even if it
stays within um you know within your
organization not even including the fact
that people are emailing themselves um
to their personal accounts you know
corporate information
but yeah those things just sit there
unless you're cleaning out your inbox
all the time um
there could be years of files in
people's emails um just sitting there
could be breached and
yeah so just ghost uh file server so
um yeah there's not
who does not
like send
attachments and or who deletes
attachments all the time when you send
and receive
um
i don't think anyone because it's
burdensome right like that's just that's
just the way it is um but yeah looking
at so five a five million dollar average
on the business email compromises and
again that's because if you think about
data
like pii as a per pii record cost and
you know who knows how many like
again excel files pdfs
and it's like not even including when
people just straight up like put social
security numbers in the email um
but yeah i mean if you even think about
like uh for you know if you're buying a
house or your accountant they're just
like hey just shoot me all this stuff
with your you know all kinds of
sensitive information and you're like
you just want me to email that to you
and they usually
sometimes they have a a data room but a
lot of times they're just like no you
just just send it it's fine um
it's not fine
but
yeah so going
going into like what is the real
fundamental issue here um and it's the
clash between security and you know
generally what we as humans are trying
to do with our lives
even security professionals
our job is isn't to
do the secure practices it's to try to
secure the organization so again
requirements versus security uh human
error really deals with the fact that
um those are just fundamentally two
different things when people are trying
to do their job trying to be productive
it's counter to
doing a secure
excuse me a secure reaction it's at the
end of the day if it's between doing
something for your job and doing the
right thing from a security perspective
um often people are like well i'm not
getting paid to make security decisions
i'm getting paid to do my job and again
like the best you can get is security
conscious people who are like let me try
to do the right thing but you know there
is always a you know there's a point
where where people break on that so
given that
we're gonna play
a little game
um
and it's gonna be a pull-based game so
pretty much what we're about to do is
we're gonna walk through a number of
scenarios of
would you rather
uh you know would you rather
if you did this security decision and a
negative um implication of it so we're
gonna start easy
so who would do what's right from a per
security perspective
but you'd lose your job so would you do
the right thing security wise knowing
that you'd lose your job if you did it
who would who would do it
we got one we got a couple all right you
know
[Laughter]
if you
if you uh don't do it you might lose
your job
um but yeah i mean it's tough right it's
like hey you know doing the right thing
protecting corporate's data
uh what if you lose your job doing it
like at the end of the day it's not your
data it's their data but it's your job
so it's interesting um so here we go
we're gonna walk it down a little bit
who would do you know would you do a
security perspective but uh do the right
thing from the security perspective but
you get a bad reputation so let's say
um that's good you honest people i love
it um because you know at the end of the
day
not
everyone
values uh privacy or security so you
know there's a time where if doing the
right thing does make you you know a bad
person um but it's tough
so let's get a little bit more
loose with it how about you do what's
right but you're like late on a deadline
all right
and what about you are about to like
it's either you do the security thing or
you don't do the security thing you're
gonna miss your flight so who would
i realize i didn't reward these as great
but who is willing to not do the
security thing to not miss their flight
or i guess or do the security thing and
miss their flight
we got we got a couple but i mean if you
think about it like again good good on
you guys but just
you know we're at a security conference
if i ask this to non-security people
imagine what these answers would be
vacation vacation flight
this is
this is your
so you've been running
you've been running these security apps
for
a full year straight 16-hour days seven
days a week and this is finally your
your two-week vacation that you're going
on
and if you miss this it's you're going
to like australia or something it's
gonna take you like 36 hours so if you
miss this flight it's a big deal who's
missing the flight
all right so here's i think the last one
um
and again this it feels easy to say
like i'll do the right thing from a
security perspective
and stay a little late on a friday night
um so who would who's willing to do that
yeah so that's good a lot of hands i'm
glad i'm glad as especially as a lot of
security professionals in this room i'm
glad you're willing to stay a little
late on friday and do the right thing um
but again like if we're if we're asking
this to a crowd of people that aren't
security conscious aren't security
professionals don't care don't care
about you know the corporate security
per se um this actually becomes this is
this is like the the crux of the issue
right like the people
in
and again if they're honestly if you
tell them if you ask them in corporate
training then people go yes i'll do the
right thing but you know honestly do
people do the wrong
do do the right thing when they all the
time like
and again there's like who knows like
let's say it's do the right thing from a
security perspective or
like i need to go pick up my kids or
like i'm gonna be you know late to
something else big or some something
negative is going to happen to me in my
personal life right so it's like that
the more
people there are the more
exceptions to the role there are and
there's always room for you know that
gap between what is right from security
and what just people living their lives
and that's where the human error comes
in
so
and another issue with uh cyber security
or with the human error is the shadow
i.t right so like we all love to think
about and oftentimes talk about um i
don't know if
for all the security certifications out
there one of the if you've ever gone to
a boot camp for them one of the first
things they always tell you is don't
think about
they're like these certifications will
be harder for people with more
experience because you're gonna know
you're gonna think about what really
happens and you're getting tested on
what the ideal
should happen
um
and the reality is you know shadow i.t
exists because
oftentimes organizations start with a
security control and push that out to
people but they don't really think about
like how do people actually operate on a
day-to-day basis
um
so you know again they're they're
they'll use unapproved tools they'll use
um you know maybe like google drive
personal accounts personal emails
anything that just kind of make it make
their day lives easier because you know
at the end of the day again it's
security decision versus
getting the job done for what i'm
getting paid for to get a paycheck so
again like those two don't usually play
nice together and the harder you make
the security side
the harder they're going to try to
bypass that
so instead of just pretending it doesn't
exist i think we should really just
focus on and embrace the reality the
shadow i.t is a thing and instead of
trying to tell people to do the right
thing again instead of if if you're
relying on your users to do the right
thing
that's a it's a losing battle
like you can't you can't know 100 right
so that again part of what you know we
need to be doing is focus on um
addressing and embracing that this stuff
exists um and really try to think about
you know start at the human layer and
build security on top of that like what
are people actually doing are people
using their personal accounts how do we
make like what is the problem that
they're using their personal accounts
for that our you know organization isn't
supplying them from a productivity
standpoint so if you if you really start
with that build security around that and
then
and then you know these shadow it issues
will go away because at the end of the
day people don't want to make a negative
security decision they want to just do
their job and go home you know it's like
at the end of the day that's that's what
they want to do they're not trying to
open your organization up to um well
insider threat is a different thing but
for the average employee isn't actively
trying to hinder the organization
um
but actually that last point if you look
at it the uh the more risks so that's
actually a really interesting uh stat
right so like uh 54 of it teams
considered themselves more at risk
of a data breach after code 19 and in
the remote work and all the policy
changes that went along with it so if
you think about that like
things are getting worse
but they don't have to be but if we're
not addressing it and we're just trying
to operate in the same day-to-day that
we were doing um back when perimeter
security was fine then it's you're just
gonna have a bad time
so
um
what are we doing about it
today
um
honestly that number one one is is
probably the number one uh
knee-jerk reaction that organizations
have in the in the state of a breach
they say uh-oh we got breached probably
with a phishing attack um what are we
going to do about it oh let's
run
simulated phishing attacks against our
employees let's have them sit through an
hour of training on how not to get
phished and let's keep doing that over
and over and over again and
maybe it won't happen but all it takes
is that one person to forget to do it
click on the thing be a little tired
less vigilant you know it's like there's
all kinds of things and it
education is very important but
isn't the be all end-all and shouldn't
be the only thing an organization is
doing to combat human error
not to mention
getting high quality um cyber education
is is difficult right so it's it's hard
to be able to distill it down so that
your everyday users and employees um
it's meaningful to them and it's not
just you know just a joke to them um and
worse off it's actually hard to also get
uh education that isn't isn't fishing
focus right so at the end of the day you
know it it's like how do we find more
ways to engage people and teach them um
you know more about security and and
less about just specifically like please
stop clicking links um
and yeah
the second one is what i was mentioning
earlier
like what do we what are we doing we
keep just tightening the controls even
though that's the problem the problem is
tight controls so people bypass it with
shadow i.t
and then there's a breach
and then we tighten down the controls
even more so that there can be less of a
thing and then so people find another
way around that and it's just a game of
cat and mouse if we keep approaching it
by saying hey let's lock let's lock it
down and make it hard for people to do
their jobs
so more policies more controls that's
not not helping but that's what a lot of
people do because again it's a knee-jerk
reaction of what how do we solve this
problem let's do so by uh like let me
let's go just buy some stuff like
if we talk to some sisters like that
they're just like you know frazzled and
they're like i don't i just let's just
get some things let's
let's say that we're doing more
more work um but at the end of the day
you know if especially if it's policy
based um
controls
that's a lot of hours that's a lot of
time
my co-co-founder and i spoke to assisto
that
had purchased like a million dollars of
dlp that's just been sitting on the
shelf for like nine months because he's
like yeah i just don't have the time to
have my team put it in place yet he's
like i know i'm pretty sure i'm gonna
hate it once i'm done with it but i
paid for it so i need to
like eventually do it first before i
look at more solutions but i mean that's
a huge problem right that's super
expensive that's um
just going to create uh actually what
it's going to end up doing also is talk
to another sister that
was was saying that he
just
any any of these policy-based systems
just create um exceptions in terms of
it's like an exception mill so it's like
and he's he's at a health system and he
says like pretty much they put into
control that requires these policies and
the next day they get a bunch of their
doctors that are like you know what like
i get it i get it you know that's an
important control but i
it shouldn't apply to me
and then so you know that happens every
single so they make a exception for them
they make another exception for them and
then that goes around opens up some more
issues and holes so they build some more
policies around that to try to fix that
and then it just becomes a huge mess um
so tighter controls more policies not
working for us
uh that's not what we should be doing
more of so
what should we be doing um what is the
future of cyber security um look like
what are like what how do we adapt and
evolve to you know the growing threats
and our change in work environments and
productivity so
you know the number one bullet point
right there it's like reduce the number
of security decisions that people need
to make because again if you're leaving
it up to the end user to make the right
decision 100 of the time then you're
going to be
disappointed
pretty much the entire time because
again there's that fundamental rub
between that security decision and what
their goals are so if we reduce the
number of security decisions they make
um you know through automation through
anything else uh that'll help make it so
that when they do have to ultimately
make a security decision you know
they're not burned out on it they're
willing to think a little bit more and
you know you've made their lives easier
for 90 of the way you know they're like
a little more likely to do the right
thing on that last 10 percent
um
next thing kind of tied directly into
that you need to focus on the
inefficiencies and particularly the the
human factor right so instead of
starting with the control pushing it
down to the people start with the people
figure out what are people doing
why are they trying to you know use
their personal accounts why are they
passing through things through google
drive why are they doing this why are
they doing that and you'll find that
there is a there there will be a
productivity
um
issue that the company isn't addressing
and causing that so again instead of
saying well you're bad you shouldn't do
that sit through another hour of
training it's like hey let's actually
provide you a tool
that solves your problem and does so in
a way that ultimately does what we want
which is
a higher security uh posture because of
it so
instead of saying hey let's put a
control in another policy and it's like
let's let me buy you a security focus
productivity tool and use that instead
of doing what you're doing and hopefully
and ideally that makes your life even
easier than running your stuff through a
chain of shadow i.t um
and speaking of that going to
acknowledge the fact that shadow t
exists um the more you ignore it the
more you it's same with the remote work
so organizations that
aren't embracing it in terms of just
acknowledging that it's happening like
people are working remotely even if
that's not the company's policy right
like people go home and do work um and
for sure if it is a company's policy but
when it's not and that's actually where
the shadow it comes from right so if you
aren't embracing that in this day and
age people will find a way to get to
make it to make it work because at the
end of the day you know a lot of people
are just trying to do their jobs and the
more security gets in the way of that
the more shadow i.t exists but if we
just try to say hey don't use your
personal accounts here's a training for
not using your personal accounts it's
never gonna be solved um
and then again embrace just embrace that
remote work is a thing even if the
company's policy isn't a remote work
policy make sure you have a way for
people to
to safely
work remotely so you know a lot of that
was
hey we have a vpn it's like okay so what
else are you doing to protect your data
as it sits outside of your office
perimeter
last one there automation so don't
you dare
buy anything that says ai in it until
you've fully automated things
don't even
bother with the ai stuff until you've
automated things because at the end of
the day against
solving what the issue is is a
productivity issue
so being able to automate past security
decisions being able to automate why
people are um doing the wrong thing you
know bring more automation do peop
if you want people to do something
the more you can just do it for them you
know they'll accept it people are
willing to accept a security
decision that happened upon them versus
making that decision so again automation
is the way to go on that and the more
you can automate from security you know
the better because at the end of the day
the
attacks are evolving and
they're using automation to attack so
you should also use automation to defend
um
this one's more aimed towards obviously
smaller organizations like maybe even
like smbs but there's a lot of existing
controls out there
that are just being underutilized so a
lot of a lot of tools that you have have
multi-factor authentication available
um you know their password managers are
proven
to
reduce
um any kind of attacks related to
passwords because at the end of the day
you can actually have secure passwords
in a way that people will
be able to use them versus them using
the one password for all every single
login right so
because when that happens as you all
know maybe
you know bank of america is hard to
break into but maybe
myfunsite.com
isn't so hard to break into and if
you're using the same login password for
bank of america and myfunsite.com like
hey that's just
username and id password just let me
just try out on all the banks and see
what works um
so yeah i mean just just really just
just leaning into existing stuff it
doesn't cost anything extra um both on a
personal level and again if you're a
smaller organization like this this is
the way to go and then you can look at
hey what are my gaps after that what do
i actually need to spend money on
um this is actually so i had built this
slide
uh a while ago but this seems to be the
theme of the conference in terms of uh
talked to a lot of people that are the
have mirrored the same thing is just
stop just just stop it with the
perimeter like we're we're past that you
know again that's not how we this that's
not how it works anymore you can't
say
we're gonna keep attackers out 100 of
the time and we're going to keep data
from you know egressing our organization
100 percent
it's just impossible so instead of
thinking about just out versus in we
need to think about and this you know
buzzword-wise goes into zero trust but
we need to think about um
how do we actually protect our assets in
a way that assuming that attackers are
getting on our devices assuming
attackers are getting in our networks
how do we protect our assets um one of
those assets is data one of those assets
is your devices how do you actually
secure on an individual as individual as
possible as granular as possible
way of you know securing that so that
way
remote work if you start with that
everything else becomes not so bad right
so
if you solve that problem then remote
work all of a sudden is not a big deal
right they can they can travel anywhere
with their with their devices because
you solve the the asset protection
problem if you don't then it's like how
do we make sure that people are
going through the vpn how do we make
sure we have enough bandwidth on our
vpns and throughputs that we're not
slowing everyone down so that they turn
the vpn off and then oh hey look now
they're connected to sketchy wi-fi um
so again like if there's anything you
remember
if there's anything you you tweet out
there uh this one
um
yeah so
it's it's really the difference between
the at the bottom the highlighter point
instead of hoping
and wishing on a prayer that people are
going to do the right thing
um just plan for them to do the wrong
thing and then how do we build a secure
posture assuming that the wrong thing is
going to occur because if we're hoping
for the best um
that's not a good security strategy
so last slide here
and just next steps right so what are
some some easy easy to do
next steps if you wanted to implement um
kind of the evolution of cyber security
uh number one to just stop stop buying
the buzzwords right so
they at the end of the day i said like i
said there's a lot of existing um
capabilities that you already have in
your organization that just need to be
leveraged you know correctly um or used
period like straight up used um
and again really just focusing on the
on the productivity aspect will flush
out a lot of error a lot of issues with
the human error
so again also with the education
instead of only doing fishing education
you know let's focus on teaching users
about
about those other things out there about
password managers give some references
maybe buy a corporate one for everybody
you know using mfa why mfa is important
making sure people are turning it on
their personal devices
um
and the more you know education we have
surrounded by you know about kind of
daily um and personal security the more
that's gonna be reflected as they're at
work um with the organization um and the
last bullet point is what i'll leave you
with here is just solve the real issues
at hand which is just a lack of time and
a lack of interest from the user base
i've never spoken to any security
professional who says oh i have too many
too many employees that work in our
security staff i don't know what to do
with them all or i have we have so much
time yeah i've never talked to a sister
who's like i got just
all i got is people and time and money
um and he's like oh yeah right
where do you work
um let me jump on that team but um yeah
i mean there's a there's constant lack
of time both on your end user's
standpoint you know they're they're just
trying to get their job done and the
constant lack of time from a securities
professional standpoint in terms of you
there's never enough you can do and
there's definitely never enough you can
do if if you're focused on just chasing
your users and telling them to try to do
the right thing
and then again that last one just
assume people aren't interested assume
people are going to do the wrong thing
how do we protect our assets if they're
going to do the wrong thing
and with that really appreciate you
picking me over spinach artichoke dip um
hopefully you don't regret it and yeah
if you have any questions find me on
linkedin
twitter i'm happy to answer them also uh
i think we have some time i can answer
some questions five minutes
otherwise if you see me afterwards come
up to talk to me i'd love to talk but
yeah any questions
yes
is
um
yeah
yeah definitely so the question is uh
acknowledging the fact that most
organizations do uh acknowledge human
error as an issue and currently are
pushing out uh education for that but
the issue being not a lot of
accountability based off of that
what do i feel about
implementing accountability into that
training as a part of performance review
for example um so yeah great great
question and great point i actually do
think that
it does go back into what i said in
terms of the big fundamental issue is uh
security decisions versus job doing
whatever for your job so if you make
security decisions part of their job
then yeah that actually does solve part
of the part of the issue and again the
more we
spend time
um putting some sort of value on
security beyond just like you should do
the thing i think it will help so yeah i
mean i i would say
i would 100 agree with adding if if
data security or any kind of security is
important to your organization adding a
level of that into someone's job
performance review um and then after
that it just really would just take how
do we
properly um
capture those metrics how do we you know
how do we be able to build that provably
into that person's performance in a way
that we can say hey you know you aren't
doing the right thing you are doing the
right thing yadda yadda but overall i'd
say i think that's a great idea
uh yes
i'm sorry about what might be a
significant cost center i've heard that
charles darwin and charles dickens only
work four hours a day
and they changed the world how many
people
are making more mistakes just because
yeah i mean
that oh so the the question is how many
people are making too much mistakes
because they're tired and like i myself
have
almost clicked on a sketchy phishing
email i was just and honestly the reason
why i didn't fully click it was i got
distracted um but
but i was i was tired right i was tired
it was like i forget what what the email
actually was but it was it was something
that's similar to like something i was
dealing with and again i was tired and i
was like oh let me just like because i
pretty much was reading much emails
queuing up a bunch of links um so i
almost clicked it and then um actually
i'm pretty sure my co-founder called me
and i got distracted but um
or maybe i was just watching a youtube
video but uh we'll leave that up to your
imaginations on what i actually got
distracted by but yeah i mean i i almost
clicked it right so it's like i i know
the right thing the right thing to do
but the more tired you are the more
you know the the less
vigilant you are right and again it goes
in the driving like you wouldn't want
someone on the road who hasn't slept you
know you know for 24 hours let's say so
why would you want them to
make security decisions yes
what they think is a phishing email
they're like so then they go on their
side and they're like guys
i have not i mean i i actually really
agree with that so the question being um
instead of just waiting for people to
make a mistake let's normalize um
kind of a community looking together so
i've seen versions of that but so that's
a way better version than what i've seen
and what i've seen is um it's and
security staff saying hey you should
email me when it's a sketchy email and
i'll look through it um the issue there
is again going back to the security
staff time people don't have ain't
nobody got time for that
and they get a lot of emails that like
aren't phishing emails which from again
going back to human error if you have a
human looking at a bunch of emails
eventually they're gonna slip up um and
again it just becomes just a uh
just a way to you know just it's not
effective so i agree with the uh
community approach um that's time for me
but again if you have any other
questions find me thanks
[Applause]
you