everyone i want to thank everybody for
joining me today my name is chris wall
and today we're going to be talking
about
digital forensics and reconstructing an
attack on a modern web application a
little bit about me i am the chief
technology officer and the co-founder of
critical fault a cyber security company
uh based out of oklahoma
i have been in it
for damn near 20 years um it's almost
there recently
i made the switch well not recently
several years ago i made the switch from
doing it working at an msp to switching
over to being a developer for several
years which i realized i'm not a very
good developer i make a lot of mistakes
a lot of common mistakes
and these these mistakes
presented vulnerabilities in the
software that i was writing i had worked
for several um
i worked as a freelance and for several
different projects and i was introducing
vulnerabilities into the software i was
writing so i became obsessed how do i
fix these problems how do i stop having
these vulnerabilities inside my own
software and so as i came up with
solutions and did my research i started
sharing this information with the
community and that actually got me my
first job in security and it's been
history ever since
okay so i have a picture of a kiwi up
here i need
a safe word preferably a fruit does
anybody have a safe word for me
banana we have banana okay so the reason
why i ask for
a fruit safe word is i have a tendency
to talk a little too fast get really
excited
i am pushing forward real quick if
for any reason if i'm talking too fast
or not close enough to the mic or you
just want me to go back and cover it
again please yell out banana
once
just once
all right well we're going to go ahead
and
jump straight on into this
okay so
there's some av problems uh we had to
seriously reduce the resolution so if we
can't read something i'll zoom in or
just yell out banana and i'll tell you
what the screen says but we're actually
going to do a live demo that's why we're
we're running it this way
all right well let's let's do a quick
crash course into digital forensics
there's a couple key pieces of
terminology we need to go ahead and
address and some other pieces of
understanding what is going on
so real quick for those that don't know
about the verizon data breach
investigation report it comes out every
year it is an excellent report that
talks about
with companies that are willing to share
their breaches their incidences the the
attempts to hack their organizations or
just social engineer their way in and
they compile a huge listing of this
information so we can better understand
where the attacks are coming from now
what's very important here is that in
the 22 excuse me 2022 version of this
report that
we saw that
roughly 45 of all attacks were based on
web applications now that can be
trying to hack your way into the web
application that can be trying to use
stolen credentials through a web
application but
the vast majority of all attacks came
through
some sort of web application and so it's
important to talk about well when an
attack actually occurs how do we how do
we get started how do we understand what
was it
what was affected
and so we do know when we're talking
about hacking at the actual act of
connecting to a system and sending
payloads and trying to breach the system
through some sort of technical means the
vast majority of all attacks are against
web applications this is wildly
different than it was five ten years ago
but web applications
i'm convinced is the next frontier of
cyber security it's the place where we
need to be focusing there was an
excellent talk yesterday on
setting up a apsec program that was a
fantastic talk if you haven't seen that
one definitely find david he's here
somewhere and definitely have a
conversation with david
okay a couple quick bits of terminology
so in digital forensics digital
forensics is the formal process of
collecting evidence and storing it in a
formal chain of custody to prove that
that information was appropriately
acquired and not mishandled at any point
oftentimes when we do present in court
we do have to be cross-examined and we
do have to show that the evidence is
correct that it is it is officially
there that it was acquired using
industry best standards that if somebody
else were to do the exact same digital
forensics examination they'd come up
with the same results
there's also what we call the chain of
custody this is very important we need
to prove that the evidence that we're
presenting to court
made it in its full
full entirety
that no
bit of integrity could have been
possibly
misconfigured deleted changed anything
nothing should be modified when it comes
to the chain of custody
in some response i love this slide
they're hiding under their folders
so instant response is different than
digital forensics instant response is
the act of responding to an incident
while it's happening it's mitigating the
active threat so the reason why i bring
incident response in here is there's a
lot of overlap
at least when an incident occurs and
we're going to talk a little bit about
incident response and how incident
response occasionally can
derail later investigative efforts so
that's a important piece that we want to
talk about and then there's expert
witness testimony this is when somebody
like yourself presents in court and
they ask you all kinds of terrible
horrible questions and try to discredit
you as a human and you have to prove
that you are worthy of being in the room
okay so we're going to do a live demo
today
that's why the
audio visual is a little little wonky
just to make sure that it all works but
this is a simplified example
the whole point of talking about modern
web applications is they're not so
simple they they don't exist on a single
system they don't exist in a single
their ecosystem's not shrunk down to a
single piece and so we're going to talk
about
what the modern
web application development pipeline
looks like
now
you probably can't read everything on
this page that's the point
this is i mean we we have a continuous
integration so ci cd going on we have
things being fetched from uh repos we
have a slack uh component that is
pulling in information we have docker we
have all kinds of things happening in
aws
this is one single application example
but a breach an actual attack can occur
anywhere within this
with this framework and just because you
see the output of what would actually
occurred doesn't allow you to see the
inception point the origin of the attack
and oftentimes you have to work your way
backwards you know what went wrong but
you have to work your way backwards to
figure out how did it happen
this is a little bit more of a
simplified view this is more the older
view the the three tier system
where you have the web application
excuse me web servers the application
servers and then the database servers
behind the scenes this is a little bit
more of a traditional view it's easier
to understand but all of this everything
that we see here translates back into
what we see here it's just so many
things are spread to serverless
components or to other sas providers
that may have
may provide some piece of that puzzle
but technically speaking it boils down
to what we typically typically see here
where
you have
web servers you have application logic
servers and then you have database
servers
there's so much more that can happen but
that that's the gist of what occurs and
in modern web applications there's a ton
of different tools that
you're going to be expected to at least
know how to work with them how to
investigate them how to understand what
is there
again we don't have to read every single
piece in here the point is it is
difficult it is difficult to know where
to get started where did the breach
occur did it did it happen in jira and
we have to work our way up to jira so
there's a lot of different pieces
i added this slide just uh just today
after i listened to nick's talk about
doing phishing from sas providers using
disguised
invitations so invitations to projects
invitations
to
the cloud providers and whatnot that's
excellent and when you have attacks
coming from this particular perspective
how do you even figure that out
especially when you spin up a tenant do
whatever the attack is and spin it back
down how is an examiner
able to figure that out figure out that
information i also put um so the one on
the left is uh proxies or vpns or just
anytime server-side requests forward
where you let another system do the
attack for you
so if that if that's the case well how
do you determine where the real origin
of that attack came from and then
finally on the right is databases
oftentimes and we're seeing this more
increasingly that when we do see the
inception point where we do see the
attack actually occurred that generally
people think oh they dropped a file on
the system or they made modifications to
the system but nobody really ever seems
to think about well could they have
dropped a payload in the database could
they be operating and living out of the
database which is a very real thing
especially with stored procedures uh if
you're in the sql ecosystem so there's a
lot of ways to hide your tracks and
unfortunately in the forensic
examination process we have to be able
to look into frankly everything and i
will say the sas part is going to be by
far the hardest
okay so anytime you're doing an
examination there's always some must ask
questions that are always going to be
presented to you the first one is always
how long will this take
it is all that is always what people
want to answer or what you want they
want you to answer that information uh
as quickly as possible how long will
this take i
we did one uh not too long ago where i
had to drive six hours to go pick up a
server pick up the server do the chain
of custody and bring it back and before
i even returned back to our forensic lab
we were already getting questions hey
what did you find
what do you mean i haven't even i
haven't even gotten to the lab to
actually be able to unpack everything
but
this is not this is the norm people want
to know because sometimes whatever the
breach may be may affect business in
this particular case it was ransomware
and this particular satellite office was
cut off from the main office until they
figured out where the ransomware came
from so
i had to get a report out as quickly as
possible but you don't want to rush the
the process and give bad information or
incomplete information but at the same
time the client is down and frankly it
was a hospital so meaning they couldn't
deliver their services to the patients
to the patients actually admitted to the
hospital until we got our information in
there because they couldn't record or do
anything because everybody uses
electronic health records nowadays
the other question always is what
happened
we're going to talk about a lot of the
different ways of getting there what was
affected very important uh frankly the
fbi guys did a great job of explaining
the slide for me just a few minutes ago
um and of course how did it happen and
then this is the question
it's a super dangerous question how do
we prevent this from happening it's not
really the digital
excuse me forensic examiner's
responsibility to provide that
information we're supposed to tell you
what occurred
how did it occur but
oftentimes we get that question well how
do i keep this from happening again so
we do have to give some general best
advice generally it's not uh rolled into
the reports it can be but we can give
industry recommendations for for moving
forward
okay so i did say in some response
digital forensics there is a bit of
overlap unfortunately with incident
response
there's a mad rush to fix whatever the
issue is things are on fire you're
trying to get that situation un under
wraps as fast as possible oftentimes
this can be wiping systems restoring
things from backups taking systems
offline
who knows rebooting systems that's
anytime that as an examiner if i need to
preserve
volatile evidence that's in a cache or
that's in memory
how am i going to get that information
back when the incident response guys ran
by and rebooted everything
how am i going to do that
so unfortunately the instant response
is almost never perfect it never never
goes right
and that's that's just the nature of the
beast so
our job oftentimes is to work with
instant response and provide guidance so
that this information is preserved that
evidence isn't destroyed in the process
it's very important
to have that open dialogue with your
incident responders
so that
i mean i've been an instant responder
i've addressed a lot of different issues
and i have even
you know in the past realized that some
evidence was destroyed in the process
yeah the client's back up and running
and this is this is the case anytime
that we have a case like this this is a
recovery effort you're trying to
understand what exactly happened and
make sense of what logs and
evidence still exists
and again this gets really hard to
figure out what occurred where and where
did it start and you have to suss out
is this traffic is what is occurring on
the network based on the attackers
did the attackers cause the activity
that you're seeing was it incident
response that caused usually they cause
a huge uh amount of activity on a
network on a system on different
locations throughout the network and so
now you have to
separate that out what was it instant
response that ended up making a change
here or was it just regular everyday
user activity we have to strip that
information out to be able to
focus in directly on where the attackers
came in and again there are so many
different places to start especially on
modern web applications
okay so we're actually going to do a
live demo
that's why
again the audio visual setup so we're
going to get started if you guys can't
read this i will zoom in or just read it
out but uh in short so we're going to do
a live demo on
an application server that
a new user has been created
the user's name is bob he's the local
admin what's going on here we need to
figure out why did bob appear what what
is going on and there's some other bits
of information so whoever became aware
of this said oh
that's weird
there's a executable program called
program.exe running
and we have a pid a process identifier
of
9832 okay
what is that
what's going on here
so
generally
old school tool netstat just take a
quick look figure out okay
let's let's find the pid so we have uh
9832 over there
so we have this pid and we're able to
see uh different information
and we can see that 9832 is connected
uh to a ipn.33
on port 7777 so this is this is a good
indicator that something interesting is
going on we also know that uh
netbios and other other common windows
tools are sitting there listening
to different traffic so we already have
some information of maybe how somebody
was beginning the breach efforts
okay so
the person who noticed what was going on
also took the time to just fire up a
process explorer to take a quick look
and uh okay we need to figure out where
is this program.exe so they can open up
the file location uh-oh
it's on the c drive
that's definitely a problem
i'm sure somebody knows why but we're
going to get to that here in a moment
okay
so uh here before we switch to the the
live demo we're going to talk about a
couple common tools this is not a tools
talk
there are tools that we use such as
forensic imaging but i'm not here to
tell you exactly which tool to use
that's for you to decide especially as
you're working you build your own
digital forensics
department or you work with others so
it's important to know
what tools that they used that should be
in the report but again the tool serves
a purpose we're not here to tell you
which one is the best one
so anytime that we are doing an
examination oftentimes the most common
thing that we need to do is to do some
sort of forensic imaging this is the
process where we capture all the data on
a storage device
all of it including unallocated space
very important that we get that space
uh let's think about it if the
attacker's on a system and they're
writing files to disk and then um they
want to clean up their tracks and they
delete their records and then they move
on so at this point if we did an image
and we only imaged every single file on
the system that's still there in the
master file table record or or however
whatever a
file system that you're using if we look
at it that way then we can only see the
files that still exist but what about
the deleted information what about the
information in the slack space or on
allocated space what other information
can we go and find so we do need to do a
full capture of the the storage and
frankly that's a lot of data i mean
we're talking about um
images that are the exact same size as
as the the actual storage device so you
have a 500 gig ssd you have a 500 gig uh
image that comes at it yes there are
compression methods out there
that is that is a bit of a
problem that when you try to argue in
court yes i used a compressed method
you have to prove that it worked and it
worked correctly but still that
compression only works so well
another piece that we're going to be
talking about is the timeline view so
the timeline view pulls from a ton of
different sources
so let's say i get an image and i take
that image and i want to process the
timeline so windows is a pretty easy one
to understand
that there's going to be a lot of
information that's going to be specific
on that system so windows as we know it
has date modified date created last
accessed these information that we can
use to build a timeline to understand
but that's just for files we also have
the event logs we have other any kind of
other operating system logs or
application logs that may be on the
system we also have artifacts this is
for example when you
launch an application from a gui uh that
there's going to be information that
explorer will automatically create
behind the scenes there's going to be
information inside the uh the registry
there's going to be tons of information
all over the place that we can come back
and examine and understand exactly what
happened because all these artifacts are
get created but this isn't the only
place we're going to be looking today it
is you know it's more of a simplified
view but we also need to go look at what
other systems were touched in the
process did they pass through a firewall
was there a proxy involved is the proxy
logging
did they trigger any canary tokens did
we have extra information does the sim
have the answers that we're looking for
these are other places that we go and we
try to find out the information of well
what exactly happened and how did it
happen
hex editor doesn't again i don't care
which one that you guys use but a hex
editor can examine i mean we have a json
file opened here and we're looking at it
through a hex editor view where i can
actually look at the contents i can see
the information that is stored inside
the sectors on the hard drive and be
able to understand exactly what they're
doing and
while extremely rare i have seen plenty
of times where um an
attacker will use some sort of bitwise
operation and will shift the columns or
we'll will make some tiny change to a
header so it's not as obvious what the
file is where or why it's there they
they may even do some sort of bit wise
always uh encryption using just simple
xor that would make it even harder to
understand exactly what we're reading so
hex editor is one of your best friends
and once we have this information we can
come back and process and understand
what's going on
file carving i do like this this is this
is the image that you see here is a
sector map so it basically gives me
excuse me a cluster map a little bit
different but
it is all the storage information that
we see
graphically on a
on an ssd it's 232 gigs for those that
i'm sure it's hard to read up there but
there's a ton of information here even
though this drive is white this drive
was quick white
for those that don't know with a quick
wipe quick wipe uh if we're talking in
the windows ecosystem only wipes the
first three thousand sectors and the
last three thousand sectors all the data
is still there so i can use a file carve
so you'll actually go to the system it
will go to the drive and it looks and it
looks
thank you and it looks blank
looks like nothing is there
thank you
um
so
you won't be able to see it because it's
not in the master file table record if
we're working in the windows ecosystem
but the data is still there we can use
file carving to actually do a sector by
sector scan and figure out based on the
information that's that's there
well maybe the file headers and be able
to understand where the files exist how
many sectors those files are of course
when you talk about fragmentation this
gets even weirder so that's why the
those file table records are so
important
also file carving is a way that we can
use to prove if disks are actually
cleansed so what we saw was a quick wipe
a moment ago this is a full wipe there's
still technically information on there
we still have a couple pieces written to
some of those sectors such as master
file table
a record that you guys can see below
ntfs log files just some basic
information but there's very little
information
inside a fully wiped drive now
there are some very interesting ways to
do recovery processes on a fully wiped
obviously there are systems that do
multiple passes but that's not not what
we're here to talk about today
some of our other more advanced tactics
sometimes we want to go look at page
files swap space memory dumps that's a
it's not on the slide here but memory
dumps are a gold mine we can find so
much but what are the chances that
there's going to be a memory dump at the
same time
that there's an intrusion
it's very low chance but memory dumps
have huge amounts of information that we
can be able to pull from so uh also
instead of uh just pulling from a memory
dump let's say the system is still live
it's still booted it's still lit
listening applications still running
well we may want to do a live capture
and be able to pool
actually do our own memory dump to be
able to pull everything that's there be
able to grab what's in memory
it's very rare but in some cases you can
even take that memory you can
freeze it with liquid nitrogen and take
it away it's a very delicate process but
you can actually capture the information
that's still on the uh the memory sticks
and be able to pull that
we do oftentimes look at slack space and
unallocated space but these are for more
sophisticated attackers they're the ones
that are trying to hide their tracks or
maybe hiding things in the inodes or or
the file ids depending on the system
you can hide information all over the
place and one of the places especially
on windows systems that uh that seem to
always be forgotten is if a full day
passes
or you know it strikes 12 or depending
on whenever you have your
shadow copies configured
oftentimes by default they just run at
night so you can pull information out of
the shadow copies and
fortunately uh most attackers seem to
forget about shadow copies they don't do
anything to try to cleanse uh cleanse
away the shadow copies so you may not
have the evidence directly on the disk
but it's all hiding in the shadow copy
or maybe it's located in the backups and
you have to be able to mount the backups
and be able to have perform a full
exhaustive search of that
and then finally there's the report this
is the part that nobody likes doing
but this is where you have to come back
you have to hit those must answer
questions your report is going to live
beyond you when you turn in the report
to to the client or to uh the company
that you work for when you give them the
report that information
leaves you you aren't going to be there
to defend it it's going to go in front
of boards it might even make its way in
front of law enforcement and i've had
several reports that made into the hands
of the fbi and at this point
you're not there if you made a mistake
in the report it's going to reflect back
on you if you missed something it's
again going to reflect back on you this
is the perfect opportunity for you
to really it's almost like a little
resume you are creating a resume for
yourself every time you generate one of
these reports because you want to be as
accurate as possible and
be able to provide the necessary
guidance to an organization to be able
to recover from that
okay
so
last couple slides and then we're going
to jump into the into the actual
um demonstration so anti-forensics
these are pretty uncommon with exception
of time stamps i do see time stomping
quite often um where an attacker will
change the clock and then perform their
actions and then change it back so it
does get a little confusing especially
when you're trying to build a timeline
to understand exactly what happened so
time stamps probably the most common
stenography this is the act of hiding
information inside of other information
most attackers don't have time to do
something like this but if they do
often times they're using some very
generic ways of doing that they're going
to find a tool that exists
that maybe use for example least
significant bit so if you have a image
and
every pixel let's use a bitmap as an
example every pixel has a byte of
information that is that is configured
for that and in that byte you can change
the least significant bit meaning
instead of 255 for red
you can do 254 for red and at that point
that we know that there's
we can see that that small change and we
can extract that information be able to
have a better understanding of exactly
what they did and unfortunately well
fortunately i should say attackers don't
spend a whole lot of time uh trying to
hide their steps especially using these
anti-forensic processes what we do see
on occasion are encryption on payloads
that's a pretty common piece that
they're trying to hide their
communication they're trying to not
alert whatever xdr av whatever acronym
you want to throw out there they're
trying to fly under the radar and so
encryption does help with that that
process but once it's on the system
unless we're talking about ransomware
very rarely is the actual payloads or
actual tools that get loaded on a system
do they get encrypted
onion routing so tor dark web whatever
you want to call it
that oftentimes we do see we do see
communication going through onion
routing that does make it more difficult
to figure out the origin of the attack
and so it's just a piece that we need to
be aware of
overriding data is an excellent way to
hide your tracks so we talked about
deleting files well
it's actually better instead of deleting
files of just overwrite them put some
other information in there once you're
done with them and then we can't make
sense of what you were doing we can see
the time we can see the file ids we can
see the time stamps we can make sense of
what's going on
on rare occasion we also see program
packers so for example taking executable
and hiding other information within
within that you can package those up
so we do see that sometimes they're
hidden in there and you can do an
examination of
executable and have a better
understanding of what's going on
memory droppers are hard to find very
hard to find for those that are familiar
with what happened with solarwinds there
were memory droppers all over the place
this is how a lot of these attacks
did occur
not the initial attack we're talking
about the subsequent attacks once they
actually had access they used memory
droppers to be able to pull tools into
the environment operate in memory and
then exit and this is why volatile
memory volatile evidence needs to be
preserved as much as possible so if an
instant responder comes by and reboots
it's gone sorry not a whole lot you can
do then uh optification it's kind of
like encryption but it's just taking i
don't know let's take let's take a um
applica
[Music]
aspx
web shell which we're actually going to
look at here in a little bit
so that web shell
you can obstruct it and the whole the
whole point is just to make it harder to
be able to
to understand unpack what exactly
occurred on that system and have a
better understanding of what the payload
is trying to do
and then uh digital signatures uh this
is a pretty common piece we also saw
this in solarwinds where once you have a
payload on a system once you have that
executable that
you want it to fly under the radar and
one of the best ways of doing that
nowadays especially
as we're getting better and better
application
protections is to sign it if you have
access to the internal ca of the
as an attacker if you have access to
internal ca you can use that information
to sign your packages to sign what you
have and be able to hide your
information
okay so we're going to attempt the demo
gods here so give me one sec
and yes that was mr bean
all right
okay
not a big deal
there's a notebook upstairs could you
there's actually two of them can you
grab both of those please
yes yes thank you okay not a big deal i
just have a couple notes for myself
well we we we're doing an examination i
do have a couple spots i wanted us to
look at if we were doing a full
examination this would take us hours to
days
and i really want to get to some of the
hot spots as quickly as possible
all right so we have a tool up here this
is a graphical tool there's a ton of
tools that um that live in the windows
or the linux ecosystems
that oftentimes will use i'm using a
graphical tool
for your benefits so we can have a
better understanding of exactly what's
happening but oftentimes we do use a lot
of more advanced tools i just wanted you
to be able to see this information so
we're going to create a case and we're
going to call it
rva sec it doesn't matter we can provide
other information in here
and
in this particular tool we've created a
case so now what we're going to do is
we're going to add a device
and we already have an image file
remember how we we had the system that
bob has created we're going to go load
that that location
okay
i might want to go back one sec for
those looking at this this is a windows
2016 server that has a piece of software
on it called gfi archiver
gfi archiver has a known vulnerability
on the system right now it's actually
been around since 2018 but the gfi
software was written this year so this
is a known problem uh it has yet to be
patched so if you are using gfir
archiver i'd recommend that you don't
all right so we we have a full disk
image that includes partitioning
information so we do have a boot
partition uh very simple windows does
that for you automatically and then we
have the partition with data so we're
only going to load one of the partitions
i could mount the entire image but i
want to focus on the second partition
with
about 80 gigabytes of information
okay
so now now that we actually have it
loaded we have our
our image loaded into our software we
can start doing some analysis now
oftentimes
we're we run ingestion modules uh so for
those familiar with
sleuthkit or autopsy that they generally
call them uh
ingestion modules and what i mean by
this is that
for example we may want to come through
and index every single file on the
system and be able to understand
where
keywords are so it allows us to do
keyword searches there's a ton of other
tools especially the timeline it does
take a while to be able to produce that
timeline so what we are going to do
we are going to go ahead and run a user
activity which is basically a timeline
view
different tools call it different things
but they are generally
performing the same actions so what we
have here and i knew this was going to
be a problem
on the smaller resolution
is i can't get to the button but that's
okay
so
so um this is going to look for
operating system artifacts internet
artifacts it's going to pull a bunch of
information and these are just common
spots in windows where you would want to
look on a system that you think some
that some sort of crime some sort of
intrusion has occurred that you want to
be able to pull this information it's
going to give a ton more information on
the system so we're not going to
configure anything it's already set to
defaults and what we're going to do is
just a quick scan so we're not going to
do a deep in-depth scan on this
thank you
all right
just takes a moment
perfect okay so these were common spots
now
these are we are looking in common
places for common problems
that we might be able to find so looking
in the recycle bin we're looking at
downloads we're looking at the event log
there's so many other places we could be
looking at but
a quick examination for example that
client uh the hospital that was wanting
to know how long are they going to be
down this is a way that i can start
feeding them information faster they
don't like the answer i don't know we're
investigating so there are ways to
shortcut some of your some of your
pieces
all right so what we have here is a
timeline of events
and what we're going to do is
we have
some different events here
and so we have some failed logons we
have
login
using let's take a look at this one now
this one may be a little hard to read we
have logins using
explicit credentials does anybody know
what we're talking about when we're
using explicit credentials
the f word
no explicit credentials are uh generally
any time that we have a service with
credentials set
that that service needs to run with
those very explicit credentials you'll
also see this with scripts you'll see
this with scheduled tasks again we're in
the windows ecosystem so you're going to
see these spots where we're going to
have
very specific events that are coming
through
all right
so uh we can also jump to
give me one moment okay we've got a lot
of activity going on here okay
so here we are we're in the timeline
view
and what we have is we see that there is
a couple of weird files getting created
so we have this reverse.aspx we have
we have access to the gfi directory uh
software that is a part of the archive
service we have you know it looks like
there's some activity going on in here
so
and we have reverse uh aspx we have the
reverse aspx in the recycle bin ah
so let's go take a look let's go have a
look at the recycle bin
so now what we have here is we have
the ability to actually examine what's
inside the image now this does process
off the mft so if you don't have an mst
this particular process doesn't work and
you need to do file carving but since
the mft is preserved and
hopefully not too much data is deleted
we can look at some more of the common
locations so the mft is still aware of
deleted items in the recycle bin and it
includes the file ids so there's two
different types of file ids here the
ones that start in i
will tell you generally where the file
is the ones that start in r
will tell you what's inside the file so
they always end in the same file id so
2g
2v48 so there's 2g
2v48 and we said we have the one that
starts with an i and one that starts
with an r so we load the r
well there's some sort of a file here
that says you've been pwned so something
something's going on here so what we can
do is we can start examining seeing what
other information is in here
and we can work our way down so there's
a couple you've been phones so it looks
like what they were trying to do is is
upload some uh some different files just
to see if it even worked we can see that
there's an exe here and there's a lot of
information in here so let's do let's do
an extraction let's see if we can have a
better idea of what's going on in here
now when you find exes or any kind of
like l file or or or binary file that
you may want to uh have a better
understanding a dll understanding what
exactly they're doing sometimes we do
have to uh run reverse engineering
processes that one's a hard one in court
to be able to tell people exactly what
you did so much harder but we do see
that there's some some calls going on in
here there's some different information
and there's this weird little one
for those who can't read what it says it
says payload so there's an exe on the
system called that has something that's
referencing a payload we can see it's
calling the kernel32.dll
there's there's some weird things going
in here and without doing a full like
launching gear to and being able to do a
full reverse engineering which we
definitely do not have time for what we
can also look at is this one is an 87
here's the one the corresponding
file id for 87 and we can extract that
to make sense of it
c dot program.exe okay so we're starting
to be able to piece together what
exactly is happening here
okay so we also have these aspx files so
i want to go down and look at the aspx
files
okay well
that looks like a web shell to me
if we work our way down
that one is blank and this i think this
one's yeah that's our big one all right
so there's a lot going on in here
there's even shell code going on in here
so the shell code
for those that don't know shell code is
a fun and handy way of being able to to
write code
written in a very specific format that
computers will will be able to
understand if you're able to process the
hex code so that's a very brief
simplified explanation of what shell
code is but yes we're seeing a an aspx
file it's loading the kernel 32 we see
that there's information going on
and then it's processing this big shell
code so that's
that is definitely concerning so let's
let's do some other couple pieces we
know bob is an administrator at least
bob looks like an administrator but
sometimes when you're doing your
examination you don't know that maybe
the responder didn't identify that and
there are ways of for us to be able to
figure that out for be able to actually
understand what exactly occurred so one
of those pieces is for us to load the
registry
again windows ecosystem
it's a little easier on linux
but we can load this up and we can start
working our way through
the sam file excuse me the sam registry
hive
and inside of that we can we can start
working our way down
we've got a couple locations that i do
want to talk about
so
we do have
accounts we have users and we have some
users so we have some different
information we also have the names of
the users and so we have these weird
numbers here not letters and numbers
here
for those that don't know that's just
simple hexadecimal and so what we can do
is we can look at the administrator so
we can just load up our calculator
and we will
make that a little smaller and we're
going to type in 500.
okay so 500
this may be a little hard to read but in
hex 500 is one f4
there is one f4 so we know
the administrator which always has the
sid of uh well specifically the id
of 500 and we can see
that one f4 is right here so what we can
also do is we can look at bob so bob has
so 1002
we can see that's 3 e a
so we have 3 e a right there
we also have a couple others there is
one here that is sitting that doesn't
quite
it's not a default built-in account or
anything called the gfi directory
account directory excuse me directory
admin and we'd see that one has a
id of a thousand so if we put in a
thousand
there's a very simple
way of uh converting that to hex we see
three e8 we have three e8 there so we
know that there's some other information
we can even see um the flags that are
set on the account whether that if the
password needs to be changed whether um
the password never expires we can see a
bunch of information like that
so there's other spots that we can go we
can go and look in
let's see
all right so let's look at built in
let's look at aliases and let's go down
to members
okay so now we have an s id
here and so this is an sid for a group a
built in group and we can see that
there's some accounts that are added to
this to this group
we can see 1f4 is in the group
and we can actually work our way through
and be able to understand exactly what
that group is but this is the default
local admins uh group on the system so
we have one four is in that uh account
excuse me in that group we have three e8
which we confirmed was the gfi directory
admin and we also have uh 3ea on that
system uh as well or in that group so
this is information
that we know
is valuable to us so we know we can
confirm that they're actually a part of
this so another piece that i do like to
do we're going to launch that guy again
and we're going to load
the
believe it was yes
all right
we're going to work our way down so
we're running the the
system hive the uh the
registry hive we're gonna we're in a
load up system so when you're when you
have active system and you are in the
registry hives you're gonna see current
control set that's how it will read but
when the system powers down that it gets
converted and we'll say control set and
uh whatever your latest control set will
be the highest number and so we can walk
through that we can have a better
understanding on the control set when we
jump into surfaces and so the reason why
i want to jump in here this is one of
the highlights so as we're doing an
examination we can see what's going on
inside the services and i'm trying to
figure out the key reason
i'm looking in here is because i saw
that explicit credentials were used so
there's a couple different spots i'll
look i'll look for scripts i'll look for
scheduled tasks and i'll look for
services these are places where
oftentimes
specific credentials are set
and what we're talking about here is
just so people know
what we're talking about
is this is my own system and we have the
log on as and right now we're looking
for a log on as that is different than
all the others now this doesn't match
what we're seeing in our image we're
looking in here and so we want to have a
better understanding of what's happening
and we know that the gfi software is
here we know the gfi software has a
vulnerability and so we can jump down
and we can actually find the
the service count information
for the gfi software and here we have it
we have it right here now this is going
to be a little hard to read but we have
the gfi directory services that that
manages we we can see the username that
the system that the service is using we
have gfi directory admin and we have
this little line right here that says
see program files gfi gfi directory
you guys can read but
we have this information here
does anybody see
a problem here
does anybody have a quick giveaway of
what may be going on here and
what exactly the attack one of one part
of the attack the actual attack chain
that has occurred
i'm going to jump to another one and see
if it gives it away we'll jump to chrome
here's that image path again does
anybody notice something different
it's really hard to see
this has double quotes
gfi does not
gfi does not have double quotes so
if you're on a windows
system when does this funny little thing
that when it tries to call a a
an executable from some location when
it's instructed to to run that system
it's going to try and work its way down
excuse me if it's not quoted it will try
to work its way down and try to figure
out exactly where that is and it will
have problems anytime it hits a space
this is where things go haywire and so
um by by default what the system will do
is it will try to run
it will look for the c drive it will
look for program
but i won't look for program files
initially it will look for program so
we'll look for a folder name program it
will look for an executable named
program such as program.exe and it will
just automatically run it so we know
that that program.exe
is was sitting on the c drive we know it
was deleted and so we know that it's
very likely what the attack in this
particular case is is that the attacker
once they gained further access to the
system
was able to uh uh
be able to modify a service well really
just find a service that was running
with unquoted paths and be able to drop
a program.exe which is a payload on that
system and just wait for the service
account to run which would essentially
once that service actually ran it would
load with whatever credentials were
stored it would load uh program.exe
instead because it was trying to load
this but we were able to intercept it
the attacker was able to make this
happen and we were able to be able to
figure out
exactly what they were trying to
accomplish so this is one spot that we
can look in so there's a couple other
pieces and we're running a little short
on time
so we are going to jump down
to
looks like
3 45. okay there we go so we have more
activity going on in here so we have
inet pub we have some logs it looks like
they were accessing the logs for iis
that the different activities occurring
we also have
explicit credentials again where people
are logging in
there's several places oh we can even
see what
what accounts they were using we see
that the gfi directory admin was logging
in that's that's a little bit of
alarming why would that account be doing
an interactive log on onto a windows
system there's no reason for that it's a
service account it shouldn't be doing
that so this is giving us extra
information
and so we can see the logs so let's
actually jump to the logs
and we are a little short on time so i
will make it brief
we can follow the logs have a better
understanding again this all provided
information from the timeline
again a lot of tools that we haven't
been able to address today but that's
okay
so we have the log files we have a
virtual directory right here so uh w3
service one is what we have and so if we
load this guy up we have two log files
and that that's fine so the the dates
i know it's probably pretty hard to read
but that has uh 2204.07
so that's april 7th of 2022. we also
have a log file for
220408 so the following day so
let's let's start at the oldest one at
the oldest piece in the log and we can
see that there appears to be some extra
activity here
what we can do is we can
right now we're looking at a hex edited
review let's switch to text view so we
can have a better understanding of what
what is exactly in here
and we'll give that just a moment to
finish processing these
logs now we're loading an is log i still
may be needing to go look at the proxy
logs i may need to look in the the sim
so what we have here in here is a ton of
information we can see all kinds of uh
uh
bits in here and what i want to do is so
we can see there's active connections to
the archiver software which is part of
the gfi archiver piece we're going to
scroll down
and just here in the middle and we see
there's connections to the archiver
introduction.htm default.html
and we can see where the connections are
coming from what port they're they're
talking to and
we can see the user agent does anybody
notice anything weird about that user
agent did anybody recognize that one
that's a directory busting
utility so when uh if you have a bad
attacker who just uses tools configured
as default that oftentimes you're going
to get user agents that are going to
just identify what the tool is that
they're running in this case it's ferrex
buster which is a way of busting and
figuring out different um directories on
the system so we have a ton of activity
a ferrex buster all over the place
and to wrap this up
let's jump to the very bottom and so we
have some other information in here we
can see
that there's connections going to
archiver
telerik web ui web resource and we can
see that they're post requests a post
request is when you send data to a web
server instead of asking for data you're
sending data so we see these requests
and we can see the user agent in here
again is python
that's weird why is python communicating
with our web server we can see the
pwn.txt that we saw earlier we can see
the reverse.aspx information in here and
the thing that happened just before that
is we had a post request from uh to the
archiver telerik ui web resource and we
can follow this information back and we
can see it came from this ip and again
this is highly simplified it is
generally not anywhere this easy the
this ip address could be masked it could
be proxied who knows we know it ran
through python
and we know that it was posted with a
http status of 200. the very next thing
that they did
is they ran
uh they made a request to this
reverse.aspx
sounds to me like they uploaded it right
here which in fact they did this
application is vulnerable to a
arbitrary file upload so essentially
they uploaded this reversed reverse.axpx
which is a webshell then they ran the
webshell by accessing calling on that
web shell to actually build a process
and we were able to come in
and be able to understand that so
i'm getting the stfu
flag that's okay so i'm going to step
away here if you guys have any questions
please just join me out in the hallway
here in a moment so and thank you so
much
[Applause]
you