ladies and gentlemen after this
intriguing insight from the cyber
commanders we now turn to a glance at
the future challenges of cyber security
for infrastructures and for the academic
keynote speech it's my pleasure to
welcome professor Alberto san giovanni
vengeance le who is the at Carell and
Harrell h partner chair of electrical
engineering and computer sciences at the
University of California Berkeley in
2001 professor san giovanni Vincentelli
received the kaufman award for his
pioneering contributions to electronic
design automation from the trolley
science Mason consortium in 2011 he was
awarded the OEE /r se maximum medal for
groundbreaking contributions that have
had an exceptional impact on the
development of electronics and electric
and electric engineering or related
fields he received an honorary
doctorates from my home country all
Brook University Denmark and one from
kth in Sweden
professor Sanjeevani Venter telly has
published more than 950 papers and 19
books finally professor san giovanni
vegetal ii is not only a great academic
but also the co-founder of two companies
in the electronic design information
space both of them very successful each
with a billion dollar revenue so it's my
great honor to give the floor to you sir
and I'm sure that you will give us a
great academic keynote speech Hank
thanks Ari thank you very much
[Applause]
thank you for and for being here and my
question about the relationship between
military and civil at the reason because
I'm going to focus on the importance of
infrastructure and how important it is
to defend the infrastructure so the what
I would like to talk about is in fact
what kind of risk we are going to have
it infrastructural level and what kind
of challenges that we find to battle
against all kind of negative forces out
there some of the important
infrastructures are of course energy
infrastructure and which has been the
subject of the most important attacks to
severe infrastructure and the
transportation system where we have not
seen yet an attack but I'm afraid we
will see it very soon the other
infrastructures kind of interesting is
health now we are depending more and
more often on cyber solutions to health
problems from devices that we carry in
our own body and my own University we
have developed a chip that can be
implanted in your brain and with this
chip you can communicate with the
Internet is research but it is possible
to do so and then you can imagine the
danger of being hacked by someone
directly in your brain right so
infrastructure is important so without
further ado let's going the body of the
talk so we said the energy distribution
infrastructure and we know that have
been attacked you know Ukraine is has
taken down the energy network in United
States there have been a number of
attacks some known some less known why
is that because it's easy to take down
we energy infrastructure so much so that
the fear of the United States is that in
the next few years very few years the
Lee hood that someone is going to take
down the entire energy infrastructure is
very real so much of a 3/4 of the CEOs
of energy companies are sure that within
two years the energy infrastructure in
the United States is going to be down
now a estimate of the damage of such an
action range from 250 billion to one
trillion dollar okay so this is real and
this is very very dangerous
in my opinion is a mistake to think that
infrastructure or what is the world of
companies for example energy companies
should be left alone to fight the battle
against cyber attacks this is a
something that we all have to join
together to stop and to prevent now one
of the issues that we see as being the
danger in distribution network and this
is just a literacy tea but could be gas
could be water is the fact that there
are a lot of devices in these systems
that are old and they are non protected
the moment in which you bring in
digitalization which is like the key
word that everybody is talking about for
the future of the economy you are
exposing all these all devices to
attacks and they are completely
defenseless now by the same token we
have to consider that things like the
smart grid is opening all kind of holes
in the infrastructure now anytime we
think about digitalization we think
about two or three things one is
artificial intelligent and the other one
is Internet of Things and Internet of
Things means that all devices that you
have around you are going to be
connected mostly through the internet
and that's the reason why it's called
Internet of Things but these devices are
very small and not very powerful but
they can create
havock because of the numbers of these
devices so it is estimated that by 2020
we are going to have more than 50
billion devices by 2025 we are going to
have 1,000 devices per person worldwide
so no matter if you are a young kid or
an old guy 1000 devices every time you
add a device to the interconnection you
are opening a door and so think about
the vulnerability that we are going to
face so in my opinion the major obstacle
to the future of digitalization is
security because of this issue of
opening doors all over the place now in
fact you can even use the Internet of
Things to attack the infrastructure and
we have seen for example we attack in
United States that has been flu lamps
you know intelligent smart lamps that I
have created denial of services that has
taken down the major corporation in
United States and that I started from
Internet of Things so of the famous door
which were opening and we are not
realizing what are the side effects of
opening these doors now if we look at
the number of sites that have been
created in the Internet and we have seen
because many more probably are there but
we have not seen them what you see there
is doubled from 2017 to 2018 these sites
are the ones that are used to control
the Internet of Things in a negative way
so they are going to take over the
Internet of Things and then creating a
serious damage to the infrastructure now
it's not only the Internet of Things but
this vent our enterprise is very
vulnerable so the number of
vulnerabilities for a single enterprise
is grown up tremendously the past few
years so we have the distributed
infrastructure we have application and
API of all kind
we have cloud infrastructure and
services and so the attack surface is
growing but mind you in general the
weakest link of security is us is people
not machines
it's people and we have seen a number of
attacks that have used remote access
employees to gain access to the company
data and control systems now so we are
in a battle
is this a real serious battle so this
one is one of my favorite painters Paulo
China and so this is a very crude
depiction of what about a looks like and
I take one I mean I couldn't put down
the name but this is one of the
companies that I found it and we have
about 10,000 attack per day most of them
have not gone through because we are
well defended but boy we would I like to
have some information about the attacks
that may come down the pike and so why
can't we also put to work and secret
services military everybody to try to
stop these damaging situations now they
this one is an example for
transportation systems less interference
it even notices there are two people far
away they are controlling a car to under
my the way the trick started small oh my
god there was a picture of Charlie and
Chris in tracksuits
it just appeared on the dashboard but as
I drove down the interstate things
started getting unpleasant and very loud
[Music]
at this point the sound system has been
activated remotely and then now the wine
wipers are going ok so the engine stops
now in this very real very possible you
can imagine what kind of terroristic
attack you can have by activating a car
from remotely you can provoke accidents
everywhere in a town and you can cripple
completely a town or infrastructure such
as a freeway and in fact if we look at
the surface of attack of the car is like
coal under right I am Italian so I like
pasta this is like a colander so you
have so many holes but you can penetrate
into a car in any possible ways it's the
simplest thing that you can do I bet
that my son can do it easily and he is
19 so I can do this no problem at all so
how come it has not happen yet because
there is no money to be made as yet but
will this will happen so there will be
an attack on the transportation
infrastructure so if we think about the
future of transportation there is no
doubt that some degree of autonomous
driving is going to take place now what
is the issue with autonomous driving
well you're adding automation hence you
are adding sensor hence you are adding
nodes hence your open doors even more
and what is already open let's look at
what is the four fundamental question of
autonomous driving so first one is where
am i right so how do you detect where
you are
technology of GPS inertial navigation
system and then mapping technology well
you can fool a GPS system you can give
the wrong information to your car what
it is and so you can have your car going
down a cliff because you are giving the
wrong information to the sensor the next
question is what is around me and so you
need vision systems like radars Lee
lighters and so on and you can fool them
as well remember and this has not been
the result of an attack but think about
they be the Boeing 737 max that you know
to accidents what was because of eight
accident with the interaction between
sensors and control system now that was
caused by malfunctioning but if I am a
terrorist I can do that as well right
and so I can provoke huge number of
damages in that domain now what will
happen next so when we have an
autonomous driving system given the
situation that I can see what is likely
to happen so that I can react to it so
it's predictive system so software and
algorithms in general and the next one
is what should I do and what should I do
is a decision that you have to take and
this decision system today are basically
taken with neural networks so artificial
intelligence topics so if you look at
the enabling technology of autonomous
driving is sensor fusion and big data
but we say the interaction between
sensors and the computing part of the
car is a weak point you can attack it
simply what about artificial
intelligence is that a robust technology
well I have my doubts so here is an
example that you can find is a paper
published by Stanford but we also have a
number of example like this and the part
of our research in Berkeley of my group
is to try to fool neural networks so
that we can prevent bad things from
happen so if you train
neural network on recognizing objects
you can get pretty good results but take
the image of the right we perturb the
image and we introduce some random noise
now what you see there is a pattern it
doesn't look like a penguin at all right
but yet neural network decides with
99.99 percent assurance that that is a
penguin right so I can do exactly the
same thing on the decision mating of an
automobile as well as any other decision
systems so I would like to stress the
fact don't trust artificial intelligence
too much understand what the limitations
are people I hear people say well we use
artificial intelligence to fight cyber
crime be careful understand what you are
getting into and what I have a
limitation now in all of this we have to
think about the basis of all this
internet and all of this capability
digital capability which is the
semiconductor chip that's the basis
that's a common denominator well you can
hack chips too and we'll see how that
Intel is decided to try to use
microprocessor to defend against
software attacks so we have devised a
particular algorithm because is called
SGX
but allow programs to have an inkling a
particular zone of the memory which is
not accessible except for red one
application well it so happens that if
you give to some researchers at the
University a target like try to prove
that it doesn't work well very well
right and so they demonstrated that
actually is more damaging than good
because you can put a negative malware
into that protected area and there is
nothing you can do once you have it you
have it you cannot get rid of it but
there have been two instances of bugs :
quad which are at the architectural
level is not
softer miss architecture of the chip
that creates a vulnerability and these
are called meltdown inspector and they
were discovered a year ago more or less
but they were present in the chip since
2010 so it took nine years to to detect
that particular but why did it take so
long because it's not simple it's really
difficult to do so this is a
illustration on the mekinese but
essentially what happens is that to make
your chip go faster you take some
decisions that are iffy
one of the basis for making your
microprose to go fast is to do what is
called speculative execution so you are
trying to guess what your program is
going to tell the chip to do and you
start doing it before the software tells
it to do it and that is a vulnerability
so you can attack that particular step
of speculative execution to siphon off
the cryptid password database and so
that is the ultimate security that we
think it is so to encrypt our passwords
well they are not secure at all you can
get to it
so now what is the solution of this box
at the chip level well our research
tells us that we can design chips in
such a way that this kind of bugs quote
unquote can never occur and this one is
a very complex mathematical proof based
system but it is possible but you have
to think about security at the moment in
which you are designing the new systems
if you patch it later on it's too late
you have to start thinking with security
in mind no matter what you do software
hardware think security seems to a very
first line of code since the very first
line of Reggie's transfer level so what
can we do here so this is another
painting by Paulo cello in st. George
slaying the dragon so well one thing is
that
hardware in such a fundamental basis for
security that you can look at anomalies
that are occurring at the hardware level
by placing a watchdog it's difficult
what you do for example in the case of a
system that made misbehave because they
are broken right so it's a reliability
you check reliability by observing what
happens on the chip itself same thing so
we are proposing to do the same at the
level of the chip to analyze if the chip
is behaving like you think it should
behave by the same token the companies
for example in energy like NL is the
largest company in energy in Europe I
believe and what we decided to do is to
team up with a start-up and we startup
is design hardware which is connected to
their SCADA system and they can watch
what is going on at the network level
and detect anomalies is the same
solution as we have seen on the chip and
this time at the network layer this one
is another solution which is fund
startups right so the private sector and
the new innovative company is always
been very good in solving complex
problems so these are 28 startups that
have been funded in the last 3-4 months
so in 2019 and each one of these
companies is attacking a particular
domain of cyber security now some are
very promising so for example oma Marc
fig encryption has been a dream of
cryptography since the time of a critic
Rafi was born which means that you don't
need to decrypt data to edit the data or
to do something with the data itself you
can operate on the data in encrypted
form so you are removing it puts
potential a big potential liability of
your systems now the other way is what I
was asking before to the panelist I
can't we
get together can't we have a
private-public partnership now in energy
which is sector I know very well the
investment of companies in security is
dismal it's very small compared to the
risk why because they don't have enough
money to invest in security but the
energy infrastructure is vital for a
country so that is a very clear place
when a private public partnership should
take place there are some attempts in
United States but I think that the issue
of resiliency of our infrastructure is a
key one not only in the United States
worldwide and in fact I think this one
is a study that we did in United States
and National Academy of Engineering and
I trust that this should be also
something that the NATO should encourage
in Europe so take a look at the
infrastructure see what the
infrastructure in Europe is capable of
doing or not capable of doing this my
slide in this is in my opinion possibly
the strongest weakest worldwide that we
have is the lack of people so we buy a
estimate by USC square the number of
people that were missing in cyber
security is something like almost three
million people like when we talk about
the future of jobs when we talk about
people who should be literate in digital
technology security is one such a key
thing so if we want to solve part of the
problem we should invest more in
education of people that are very well
versed in security thank you very much
[Applause]