may I have your attention to announce
the cyber commanders panel our
distinguished commanders will be
introduced and moderated by none other
than the former commander of US Cyber
Command and Director of National
Security Agency and Merle Michael Rogers
Mike Rogers yes applause will be in
order
[Applause]
I'll pose is in order because Mike
Rogers retired from the US Navy in 2018
after almost 37 years of naval service
rising to the rank of four-star Admiral
he culminated his career with a
four-year tour as the commander of cyber
of US Cyber Command and Director of
National Security Agency in this
position Admiral Rogers was in charge of
creating the DoD's newest combatant
command and running the US government's
largest intelligence organization
currently retired Admiral Rogers is
supporting companies in the private
sector serving as a member or a senior
advisor in various ports here at the
CCDC OE we are very proud to have Mike
roaches as one of our advisory board
members so Admiral Rogers I hereby give
you the command of the commander's panel
I have the Conn and I have the deck as
we say in the United States Navy well
thank you all for being here today and
participating think you are fellow panel
members I'll introduce the panel what we
thought we would do is each will provide
an overview of their respective nations
efforts in the cyber arena and how their
organization fits into that then we'll
have a discussion amongst the four of us
and we'll conclude then with time for
the audience to ask questions on for the
panel on any topic that you would like
so first let me introduce the panel to
my left lieutenant general Ludwig line
host who is currently head of the German
cyber and Information space command his
background expertise and electronic
warfare information technology c3 and
signals intelligence continuing down
Brigadier General Maria biank a signal
officer in the United States Army
currently the j6 at US European Command
in Stuttgart in Germany prior to this
current tour was the j-3 or the
Director of Operations for u.s. army
cyber and lastly at the end Brigadier
General Francisco vestido who a tornado
pilot who currently is the commander of
the Joint Command for cyber operations
and prior to his current tour was
leading the center for defense
innovation so to my three panel members
thank you very much for your willingness
and if I could we'll just start down the
line we'll let you start it off thank
you very much Mike inviting me to this
distinguished panel and it's always a
pleasure to be back here in in Tallinn I
would like to start with a quote wet
also was mentioned by adenoids and
already by NATO former Warsaw summit
communique in 2016 we recognize
cyberspace as a domain of operations in
which NATO must defend itself as
effectively as it does in the air on
land and at sea and which brings us
immediately to a new dimension and what
distinguishes the military dimension of
saipan information space from
traditional operational domains despite
the complexity that connect you can
argue for all domains there's one thing
which you have to mention in the
beginning its authority is complemented
by virtual reality and cyber information
space cannot be divided into combat
sectors with clear spatial boundaries
with a significant difference the same
is true for maneuvering of troops or
counting troops and divisions this is
not the same in the dimension of cyber
and also but you must not be let
yourselves be fooled by the term virtual
in cyber information space two physical
effects can be achieved however the
place where cyber information
domain operations create an effect can
freely be tens of thousands of
kilometers away from where we actually
was initiated that's also a difference
time to has a different meaning in cyber
information space for example an effect
can be achieved over any distance
without delay so effects are achieved in
real time so all of these things and the
growing digitalization has resulted in
the join bonus were to establish a new
service as a consequence out of these
developments this service is called
cyber information domain service and it
was inaugurated in April 2017 what we
have done in a nutshell
we have centralized the core of a J 2
and J 6 capabilities of a Bundeswehr
with a jeffrey flavor to put it in a
very short words this six German armed
forces service comprises roughly about
fourteen thousand soldiers and civilian
employees so by doing this we took a
reaction on the importance of this new
dimension domain but we are also
contributing to a national security
provision with it we have by intention
no I made this service a little bit
broader from content when the NATO
definition because we have also included
the information space so that it's an
important effect not just dealing with
the technical aspects of cyber but also
what is done within which techniques the
information but it's perceived in
different ways and it's also an
important factor we have established
already our own situation center for the
cyber information two domains space
space domain a valid situation picture
providing the basis for options for
action and Zuno G's is generated
generated by merging situation reports
from all areas that may be relevant for
the cyber information domain so with
this situational picture we can actively
support the idea of future joint force
in which a joint operational commander
is enabled to achieve the side effects
throughout all domains be it see land
air space and cyber information domain
so there may be future consequences
which may result in an establishment for
example on cyber information two main
component commands or something like
this likely haven't we have our domains
in addition to risk clearly military
aspects we are looking on close national
international cooperation because I
strongly believe that cyberspace plays
in Ossining role in today's
understanding of national NATO's over
deterrence and defense posture we have a
military capabilities for national cyber
operations available and Germany is
spending on a national political and
legal mandate in general willing to
contribute to nato-led operations also
with regard to the cyber domain nato as
well as NATO member states have to be
completely aware of where cyberspace to
understand minute by minute
state of our network so that commanders
can rely on them we have to deepen our
close bilateral cooperation as well as
our cooperation at European Union and
NATO levels close dialogue is essential
at the international level since the
Simon information space is not a
respecter of national boundaries but we
have also a national cooperation and
from German perspective this is based on
the German federal federal government's
cybersecurity strategy which was
published in 2016 already in 2011 we
established under the lead of a Minister
of Interior national cyber defence
centre since then it served as a forum
for cooperation between the various
sectors government bodies in the
sovereign information domain the center
is currently being developed into an
inter-ministerial operational
institution involving all key
stakeholders a crucial important step to
ensure Germany's future capacity to act
in this field our national cyber
information domain service is already
closely connected with all key
authorities and government agencies we
have also entered into our first
partnerships with academic and business
institutions for example with Internet
service providers with German telecom
but also with research institutes for
example Fraunhofer Institute in summary
only together nationally internationally
can we guarantee resistance to threats
from the cyber information space which
is an essential requirement for future
development and welfare of modern
societies and my service will make a
significant contribution to achieve this
important task thank you very much thank
you Ludwig Maria
good morning Maria biank from United
States European Command and it's been an
honor to be asked to be here
I certainly appreciate it my first visit
to Tallinn and Estonia so it's been been
wonderful and I certainly appreciate the
hospitality
so Admiral Rogers mentioned just one of
my three jobs so my first job really is
a very traditional j6 job and you know
that deals with what I would call you
know operations and plans communications
satellite communications terrestrial
communications we focus on
interoperability we work very closely
with NATO and obviously we do quite a
bit with exercises I have a second job
that's you know it takes not much of my
time but a little bit it's the chief
information officer for the theatres the
European theater and that is really the
governance and policy there's different
laws and regulations of what we can put
on our networks in and it's just part of
our part of our layered defense
mechanism I spend most of my time on the
3rd job which is the commander of the
joint cyber center and the joint cyber
center plans coordinates synchronizes
and integrates cyberspace operations
throughout the European theater this is
a this is a significant lift I have a
great team of folks that that assist
with this and what's I think a little
unusual for European Command as a
combatant command is that this
organization the joint cyber center
actually works directly for our Director
of Operations at European Command so the
j-3 I have a the the position of j6 has
an additional duty as the deputy j-3 for
cyber and that we use the the joint
cyber center as a mechanism to do that
that takes up a little over half of
of our time when when dealing with the
many threats and vulnerabilities and and
that sort of thing our goal with the
joint cyber center is to normalize cyber
operations and what I mean by that is to
treat cyber like we treat any other
domain air land sea we use the processes
that we already have in place at the
command at the headquarters and we we
have we use we use those processes for
cyber we don't develop new processes and
that at times you know that's a that
that that has been maturing over the
last few years I'd say we're probably
we're well into that we exercise like
that but most importantly we work day to
day as an integrated element out of the
j-3 shop and what I mean by that is that
you know so there's a targeting process
like any other domain well cyber is part
of that targeting process there is a
process for you know staffing certain
things making decisions there's a whole
process there's a whole battle rhythm
process battle rhythm events that we
have integrated cyber so cyber isn't you
know isn't the trailer on you know
hooked to a car or something like that
cyber is is completely completely
integrated and that allows us to provide
a common operating picture as best we
can there's much growth to be done there
in terms of a cyber common operating
picture it allows us to assess risk in
terms of what commanders would
understand it allows us to assess and
develop mitigating strategies to to
mitigate those risks and and we do that
best by emphasizing quite frankly
collaboration and coalition building we
share a lot of our information we work
very hard to do that we have a cyber
information sharing cell
sell quite frankly we've had a lot of
luck getting things important
information down to the lowest possible
common denominator classification wise
and we have a great partnership with
with NATO allies and other partner
nations to do that we also have a cyber
analytics team that shares at the
unclassified level using threat connect
and slack and that is a that that team
has had great success also in in sharing
the information and you know the purpose
of sharing that information is to
provide common situational awareness as
well as a common understanding of
network defence and so we've had a much
luck in that we're the only combatant
command to do something like that
so this cyber information exchange cell
as well as well as the cyber analytics
team and so we we we we realize that the
the best defence is a collaborative
defence it's a common defense a common
posture that we all understand the
adversary the threats against our
different networks are different
nation-states and so we we understand
that that value and it's a quite frankly
it's a full-time job and we've got a
good team at a US European Command to do
that Francesco
[Applause]
thank you for the opportunity the CCD
Center of Excellence has given Italy the
minister of defense to represent and
they bring the regards of the chod the
general naturally with my authority in
direct line of command through the
Minister of Defense and we are here
because Italy is one of the supporting
nation thanks a lot to the director of
the center the great support you gave to
the cyber community I'll bring in my
experience in the next 8 and 10 minutes
on what I do what my role is three years
ago I was given the task to build a
Cyber Command by scratch my attitude was
I know I have to build the cake which I
don't know what the cake is going to
look like I have some ingredients three
years later now I realize I know which
cake I need to make still don't have all
the ingredients so it's quite
interesting and there was a chef in meat
and they said build cakes and so my real
duty here is my background is a tornado
pilot I'll bring some considerations on
commander control role of industry
recruit me the use of range and legal
studies these were all doing the next
seven eight minutes believe it or not I
have three thousand plus hours on the
tornado air-to-ground role the very
first one live in the formation there
and when they gave me this task I came
in an environment and what I'll bring in
today is the perspective of being having
an operational background and insider
3,000 plus hours on tornado zero
knowledge on networks clouds and all the
things you say which brings the first
consideration cyber operations is really
an operational art using the principle
principle of Wars two wars to design
your campaign one day you can go law
the next day hi in the dark daylight in
the clouds and you need to think
nicholae like your enemy is thinking of
you this is the perspective I bring in
in my zero knowledge of CAS with all the
respect with technicians and after all
it's a teamwork and you need to bring
together all these perspective why
because as a bomber I had the task an
effect to produce standing 10 hours to
understand how to penetrate the lines
get there alive
produce some effects come back through
the same line of defense people were
even more mad than few hours before in
that case lend measure the effects plan
again and do something else this is just
a cyber operation and my command in
Italy takes care of the military domain
the information and the network in Italy
and wherever we have military operations
if the nation calls upon I'll be ready
with my command
to participate to the support of the
defense of the nation
that's why without going into details in
Italy the cyber domain is an
intelligence driven organization the
services are in charge
I'm the brown part on the right hand
side of the screen I do look at the
military domain and I give all the
support taken on the left hand side
there are people with certs
incidence response team taking care of
the public administration and the
private companies we all fuse all this
information in a single point of fusion
which is the das department for
intelligence and they refer to the Prime
Minister also there's a connection
between me and in the military
intelligence and the national
intelligence so I only take care of this
and my only duty is cyber defence this
is written in the books I'll be ready to
do operations in the theatre with an
appropriate legal framework which is
probably the most complicated activity
I'm facing in the past three years which
is there
rules and laws to obey to tumbly man one
in six hundred pages pretty much says
keep in mind you are the civil law a
common law shared the principles in it
but come out with a national concept or
now to do legally cyber operation and I
am very grateful to the expertise we
have been Talon and we are doing the
same in my nation and it's easy I only
have to take care of command and control
and ever deployable cell they be able to
go somewhere in the theater and fix
things the gig guys with the a mix of
intelligence expert operational guys the
physical world has changed I was able to
recognize ships tanks in few seconds
from 20 miles away what I need to scope
now my attention on is there's a digital
domain under every single platform and
this is the focus of my team it's not
just a matter of IT
it's the OT behind be behind the things
they make and produce cyber effect in
theater that's why the domain scope of
the Ministry of Defense and the Ministry
of Defense has declared this is
resilience and values wire resilience
because we need to have platforms
equipment tools to work efficiently and
how do we make this work efficiently we
need to understand that resilience is a
matter of how we do things at night in
the air domain we could send radium 5 a
couple of jets to respond to the threats
now it's a matter of milliseconds and
that's why we need to produce a card of
young experts who have to operate in
this domain recruitment is the most
important things we have touched this
recently I think we need to intercept
those high school guys who are about to
approach the professional attitude
and the university we cannot wait for a
full cycle of universities to pick up
just two or three guys we need to
intercept this digital generation which
is there and the last recruitment I've
made was picking up 17 18 years old guys
dual use means how to communicate
command the control yes it's too easy
for me to take care of the military
domain in my command but I need to keep
in mind that there's a national other
side picture that looks at the cyber
domain so soon in a matter of seconds we
need to transit the operational picture
which used to be the one of land air
maritime now there's a cyber picture we
need to transfer to Everest the chief in
command of that operation that night why
because with my operational background I
kind of understood with my people that
there's a hybrid side of the cyber
warfare which of course we talk every
day but which is capitalizing on
psychological warfare everything let's
say crime espionage and terrorism and
probably someone doesn't have any
interest in going to cyber warfare and
so we need to get together with the
civil society and transmit what I would
call the tactical altitude attitude of
the military camouflaged people in
defending networks and the nation and
the domain we are protecting how do we
do this the same as I was trained on a
tornado let's discuss a range are
popping up here and there we abuse the
range for the locked shield we have our
own range in Italy called univox done by
the great company Leonardo with a bunch
of universities we have some
representatives here all I want to point
out is range is not just a matter of IT
we need to teach our guys 24 hour 7 how
to protect the military domain that's
why we need to discuss the
military operational technology which is
we need to have a multiple stakeholders
multiple end users a thorough system
cyber range which is able to train on
the military platforms avionics naval
satellites and so on
academia the young guys were going to
become the cyber operators and small big
industries were the the real tissue of
the nations and that's why we are
conference concentrating on this on the
experience of what shield we are
preparing our multi-stakeholders
exercise in Italy and we use this range
as well I'm closing down with this
instance with that with all the respect
for the scientists who came up with this
is if you want to protect your
environment energy and so on you have to
make your own situ and so we are being
in here today we're going to discuss
this with University of Geneva and
modern and regime Illya are the two
University doing cyber science and
masters for us I think we need to bring
our tactical intuition the military one
in exercising the experiments that
protect our networks we need to know
exactly right now what is running in our
networks so we think the same way the
enemy under sorry is what I bring in
side the range we need to give the guys
the operators a system which is even
open a night to practice to practice the
less likely scenario the most dangerous
scenario also procurement we need to
produce cyber operators for industry
because I've flown a jet for 40 years
the tornado has gone through six seven
lifts an update I think we need to have
teams work pretty much from three five
years time span in procurement so that
when a team is building the new
capability another team is going to
think in the next 10 years also
electronic force protection we are
concentrating on
because there's an environment which is
really hybrid is the mix of networks and
electronic warfare we are we have a very
tight connection with Special Forces
psyops and so on and in fobs
close down resilience dual use if you
should look at the same picture in the
nation then no matter what everyone is
looking at the same situation I think
this is pretty much it by the end of
this year my command will let the full
operational capability thanks a lot
thank you very so you have each laid out
a structure and approach if you will to
the military execution of cyber slightly
different one has gone on the service
route - I would argue have kind of gone
with traditional joint kind of structure
I'm gonna give you a minute to think I'm
gonna ask you about assessing where you
think you are when I was a commander
what I used to tell my bosses that our
chief of Defense the secretary and our
political leadership was I thought there
were four keys to our ability to execute
military operations in cyber so number
one we have to develop the technical
means to actually execute defense in
offense number two we have to generate
the capacity in the form of a trained
work force that's dedicated to apply
these capabilities to maximum
effectiveness
number three we need to make sure that
we've got the operational processes and
structures in place with a well-defined
command and control structure that both
the cyber side as well as the broader
operational construct that cyber is a
part of all understand and then lastly
we need to make sure we have clearly
articulated legal and policy frameworks
that actually allow us to execute our
cyber activities within a legal policy
framework that everyone understands it
is accepted so if you look at those kind
of criteria do you have the technical
capabilities do you have the people with
their enough and the right training do
you have the kind of operational
processes and well-defined command and
control and do you have the legal and
policy authorities you think you need if
you use those criteria how would you
kind of grade where you are right now in
your jury
Ludwig I'll ask you first now let me let
me first start with the main fault when
you're looking at the major
organizations for every domain the
classical domains you have established a
service so we have now a new domain that
was rationale to establish was this new
domain also a service not just that they
have a service but you have
preconditions to do with things that you
are only authorized if you're at a
service level but starts with getting
the right people to train and educate
the people this is an our system
depending on a service level to have a
significant influence also to
development of capabilities so since we
are a relatively young organization two
years now in stage I think we are on a
very good path we are not at the target
at the moment but I don't think we will
ever be so it's really a constant
process but with the organization set up
we have brought the preconditions for
the things that we can do as a military
concerning more of a legal side and I
think there are still a lot of debates
and a lot of nations which brings me to
with scenarios because looking in future
scenarios we had previously classical
military sonars you have at a certain
point time a declaration of war or
whatever we have now to face with
scenarios where we have probably
conflicts but are below the threshold of
a formal declared war on low tension and
there you have different questions now
what means by what organization can be
used in this type of conflicts and I
think there's the discussion to be
needed on a national basis but also
internationally places how to deal with
these things
who can execute certain things what are
the what is the legal basis for this so
we ciphered scenarios I think it's a
it's an area where organisations still
have need a discussion internally
depending on the legal set of I am Maria
where would you say you are in your
journey sir so I think from a technical
means and a generating capacity
perspective we have the the the US has
invested quite a bit in those two areas
and you know we we train our cyber
mission forces are trained to a joint
standard that standard is
is determined by US Cyber Command as you
well know sir
we are an inspired idea and so we you
know we I think that really makes us
very very unique so a commander gets you
know an Air Force commander gets an army
team on their on the on an Air Force
Network that's it's the same standard so
that that's that's that's a big part of
it our challenge quite frankly on the
technical and generating capacity side
is there is fierce competition for this
talent that's probably our biggest
challenge how do you recruit and as you
train and then retain the talent is is
significant and each of the services
department offense or have several
programs in place to get after that from
the the perspective of the operational
processes I think we're in a in a better
place than we were when when I worked at
jhq Joint Forces headquarters
doden a few years ago as we were
standing that opera organization up as a
as the defensive mechanism if you will
for defending Department of Defense
networks and so we're in a lot better
place with that I would offer that will
always have to grow that will always
mature and especially as your fourth
point as Sir was the the legal the legal
side of this the policy framework piece
I think I think the US has made great
strides there's great momentum right now
when it comes to the full spectrum of
cyberspace operations we are seeing it
in our national defense strategy we're
seeing in our national military strategy
we're seeing it in our national security
strategy very input this is overarching
cyber operation guidance these are
national level strategies these are not
just focused on cyber
now we also have cyber strategy the
department defense as a cyber strategy
there's a national cyber strategy that
further delineates and gets more into
the nuts and bolts of of certain things
so I think we've made really great
strides you know in that we've worked
the the US has worked very hard in terms
of a whole-of-government perspective and
and specifically for the for the DoD
getting additional authorities in place
so that we can be timely and relevant in
the cyberspace operation so I will offer
that just like general line who had said
it's a constant it's it is something
that is a constant process these things
and so as something changes there's some
there there's there's a refinement and
adjustment to to these four areas but
you know I I mean I'll offer a grade
just just because so I I think we're you
know I think we're probably at a at a
b-plus and I think we're doing well
great Francesco
yes thanks a lot for this question from
a philosophic Socratic point of view
this is an environment where I've
realized that the more you know the more
you realize you don't know everything
and with this paradox I think that the
major point I need to face every day is
convince the leadership the decision
maker that you are doing something good
and you have to make them understand the
decision they have to make so as the
president well laid out few minutes ago
we need to establish clearly a flow of
decision making activities which goes
from United Nations international law is
it an act of war or not and tell our
leadership that we need to act or react
and this is the first thing we are
trying to face this year so I'm working
with my legal team likely as a
representative here in CCD Co Center of
Excellence and try to get together and
there be another Italian lawyer
expert in legal activities and what we
need to try to understand is we need to
have a clear define see to command and
control legal background with the legal
background that tells the decision-maker
act now what we are trying to do also is
when I said at first I had ingredients
all I had was very expert technical guys
very Loring's coming from the every
single service
nowaday what am missing is guys who are
very expert but that the an operational
overview on things how to conduct
military operations that's why we need
to have the J two three five six series
with a bit of one and seven able to
design in shaping how we act our
professional education in order to
conduct military operation and how I'm
trying to do this trying to get together
with the operational tactical level say
ops special ops every single air land
maritime domain so that we produce
effects which are explainable to our
military leadership and I think we are
pretty much at a good stage and this is
the most demanding part producing a
legal framework and an operation of
design of the military operation very
good so we've talked about the different
structures or approaches you have each
taken we've talked about so where do you
feel you are in your journey you know
clearly the military piece is just one
part of a much broader component for
governments and so my next question
really is so how does the work that you
were doing from a military perspective
fit into the broader national effort
that each of your respective nations is
attempting to execute in cyber Francesco
I'm gonna ask you to take this one first
you didn't give me time to think
you're a tornado guy
and luckily I'm a tornado guys already
of the answer so I was thinking to
connect luckily in my nation I have a
good framework with the national
strategy or now to do things and take
care of the legal background which
supports cyber operation the main
framework is designed on democracy and
transparency and rule of law and um a
part of it the great consideration to
bring in is to build trust between the
military war that in civilian words
educate the people let the people of the
nation the old millions people
understand that the cyber is a real
threat that finally someone has got the
tool to reach directly the center of
gravity that Clausewitz said with the
instrument that sunsuit thousand of
years ago said don't even come to a war
just control the enemy and so we need
people understand that someone is
probably in the networks is doing some
harm already and we'll see defects
probably in a matter of year so I think
it's a matter of communicating trust in
the nation everyone staying in its
institutional role
Maria saying we're so I think
whole-of-government is a is a key piece
of this Admiral wheeler mentioned in his
keynote speech about the defense of the
the u.s. midterm November 2018 elections
and I think that was a you know we did
quite a bit there and there was a
whole-of-government we learned in in in
the Department of Defense and that type
of thing is that we're we're in a
supporting role so we support the
Department of Homeland Security we
support the Department of Justice and
the Federal Bureau of Investigation so
that that
that is a supporting role that's clearly
defined and so I think that's kind of
how I would see it we also though it in
the department offense we still interact
with other interagency partners across
our government and I think you know the
the the fact that we have published
strategies at the national and
Department of Defense level we get very
clear policy guidance in terms of
cyberspace operations our legislative
our mark our Congress has also passed
certain authorities as part of our
National Defense Authorization Act for
2019 and that ensures that all of us it
is set and especially US Cyber Command
can't quite frankly operate at the speed
of cyber to be timely and to be to be
relevant and so so when it comes to you
know the cyberspace operations at a
national level it is a very
collaborative whole-of-government
approach and it takes a lot of work
because sometimes that's not always
clear and it takes a lot of a lot of
teaming it's very much a team sport
moving I think what Maria mentioned the
role of government approach is vital in
that domain but it's also a difference
of this domain to be about classical
military domains I think and this is
reflected in Germany in the government's
cyber security strategy lettuce has been
published in 2016 under the lead of a
Minister of Interior and the core body
to reflect this a whole-of-government
approach with national cyber defence
centre where we have all the
institutions that have a role in on
cyber security in Germany under one roof
so when it's including my organization
but it's also including the intelligence
services it's including the criminal
office it's including the federal office
for IT security and also all the major
players and the most important thing is
I think you have to get at the whole of
government at a government level
situational awareness and there's a lot
of entities contributing to this but are
not all under the light of a Ministry of
Defense so this is the basis for any
action that you might intend to do and
also to get the resilience and with
therefore this defense center where we
are part of it is for us a crucial
element and we have to look how we
further evolve this what has to be done
to get this in a kind of operational
able to act at a state level to certain
threats um one of the themes we've
talked about broadly so far and some of
the opening comments this morning is how
cyber really is that is the ultimate
team activity that it takes multiple
expertise multiple different
organizations so I'd like to focus on
partners and teammates for a moment so
I'd like you to talk about who are your
key partners and I'd specifically ask
you can um finito specifically as you
talk about who your partners are can you
specifically talk about the role of
industry with what you're trying to do
and the role of the academic world so
Ludwig I'll ask you good I I start with
the partners of course I think
International Cooperation of course is
mandatory necessary a bit under the
classical organizations NATO and
European Union for many reasons in order
to standardize to harmonize to establish
processes so that we have a mutual
understanding if you are using certain
words but not one nation is
understanding a and the our nation's
understanding V so there's a lot of
reasons for international cooperation in
this has to be done on a on an
organizational basis but also I think on
a bilateral basis we are doing both of
it on the national level industry I
think is an important factor as well
because there's a lot of things where we
already depending on industry because
industry is providing our capabilities
that's one thing but also if you're
looking internet service providers for
example they only very have the key
force to do certain things it's not in
our hands so we need also to to consider
how we involve in a whole-of-government
approach at least some key industries
and that's a discussion that we are also
taking on specifically the Internet
service providers in order to be able to
provide resilience and to react right we
need them as well
academia is another important thing
because we academia is driving our
capabilities we go in the future and we
have established for example at the
University in Munich an institution
where we bring academia industry
Universal University training together
in order to foster these topics as well
Maria
but teammates for you so when it comes
to partners NATO the Alliance there
other European Union that are not NATO
partners necessarily that are not part
of NATO rather our key for us any ally
in in Europe is is their very key and as
I mentioned earlier we do a lot in terms
of information sharing with those those
partners and because it's really you
know quite frankly it's a it's a form of
deterrence and so when it comes to the
commercial or industry piece we we work
very closely with that and not just so
much in our communication side but also
on the logistics side and so you know
the it's it's really important for us to
understand what are our partners and
allies have their capabilities in terms
of critical infrastructure and so so we
work very closely with that we try to
exercise that and and understand that
better as well as reach out to those
those specific those specific industries
and then finally when it comes to
academia from you know from a from
European Command perspective we we do
quite a bit with John Hopkins University
and we've done some things with Lincoln
labs
Abed with MIT and and that's the
Massachusetts Information Technology
Institute of Technology sorry and so
we've done you know and and having them
come in and look and talk with us and
look at some assessments with critical
infrastructure
there's certainly a it you know it's it
whether it's industry or academia very
much our our key players in that we also
have several long-standing relationships
with the National Defense University
also out of Fort McNair that's you know
out of the DoD in Washington DC thanks
Francesca yes thank you for this the
beauty of being part of the cyber
community is you belong to an ecosystem
where is not just a matter of being
specialized inside but you need to
communicate with different environments
which is if you are a University's not
just a matter of computer science it's
also psychology anthropology social
study and so on and so on
so I think the best example of
collaboration comes from the what the
Admiral called ins Shakti the FFC I the
framework for collaborative initial
initiative so what we have done in Italy
like Shakti does in the world especially
in the mc/dc serious the multiple
capability development campaign we take
hand by hand an idea and and support the
industry expert in that part and get
together with University so that with
the research we deployed the best
solution at that time for it
we military refine the idea and so we
probably come out with the best
procurement and because I said you need
to build your own commander control also
I think a consideration to bring in is
the role of the center of excellencies
let's not forget Shakti as more than 20
center of excellence around the world so
if it's really an ecosystem then there's
need to be communication among all the
center of excellence you can participate
I'm thinking about modeling and
simulation security force assistance or
C to center of excellence and so on so
that we pick the best from every single
area of expertise so thanks a lot to
society the great job they do with these
new solutions in the multi national
domain
very good we're gonna open up to
questions in just women amendment do one
last final question for my German and
Italian teammates the US has talked
about the role that Cyber Command played
in the election process Europe has just
finished an EU election cycle this week
as a matter of fact I'm just curious for
my German and my Italian teammates did
you have any role in election security
in your respective nations or no is that
outside your responsibility in Germany
it's not my responsibility it's on the
Minister of Interior it's not by my
responsibility as a military command but
I'm part of the cyber system in Italy
there was a particular attention have no
report I was there they probably called
yesterday in the office check and with
that let's we have 10 minutes left let's
open it up to questions any questions
for the panel I see one about third row
back on that side over there good
morning Madame gentlemen thank you for
coming in speaking to us today so you
mentioned applying traditional military
taxes and understanding to cyberspace so
my question is how can NATO deny our
potential adversaries freedom of
maneuver and impose costs on them as
well as dictate the tempo of these
battles and conflicts when capabilities
and defensive lines are dynamic any of
the three give him a yes or no I'll go
before I forget Ian I think the matter
is just lately in the past few years in
the conference's we have seen we have
associated that deterrence to a great
defense of the system more than
offensive we need to continue in that
because someone else will build a higher
level than the wall itself and so
someone is always going to be able to go
through the lines of defense I think
what really we need to do is info
sharing we had this discussion yesterday
at the cyber commander forum which means
an Eightball neighbor watch program
where you can tell your ally and friend
what is happening in your networks and
share this experience with the others
because for sure
someone else will be infected by these
intrusions because there's a proxy
approach to the network warfare so M for
sharing I think is the key solution key
I agree with that and I would also add
talking with a common vocabulary a
common lexicon which you know NATO is
working on doing for cyberspace
operations specifically because it you
know just like we saw a little bit
yesterday even you know different
different words mean different things to
two different nations when it comes to
cyber cyberspace and I just a foot stomp
what my colleagues said is you know
defense is deterrence in this area and
we have to have a common defense a
common cyber posture and that's why I
think situational awareness is so
important and as well as the the
information sharing ok next question and
I see one it will go towards the back a
little bit is it not all right I think
you very much differences until senior
researcher from the 80s relation my
question is for Mia Marie or Mike what
defense posture in cyberspace would you
like to see your European allies adopt
or as caress differently should the
Germans and Italians be able to defend
forward in u.s. infrastructure and a
quick yes and no question if I may this
is one part right does neutrality exist
for you in cyberspace meaning is there
green space in cyberspace Thanks
so you can pick any one of the four
questions I thought I heard actually
pick the one that you like so I think it
goes back to a common you know defensive
posture an understanding situational
awareness you know we all you know all
nations are sovereign nations with with
laws and and national laws and policies
and governance and so I think it's
important that we have some level of
commonality it might not be the same
in Italy as it is in Germany potentially
or in the US but that's okay as long as
we have some some commonality and we
have common situational awareness on the
defense side and again it just I think
that's why the the information sharing
is so important I in and I stress it's
information it's not intelligence
sharing so I think that's what how we we
can get after that next question
I'll try right up front
thank you and my question is about the
collaboration between the military space
and companies but not so much companies
helping the military space but the
opposite so we know that the majority of
attacks are actually on companies and I
believe that the military could have a
role in defending companies from attacks
do you have any policy on that so
thoughts please Francesca I'm gonna use
the yes and no card yes we are doing we
are applying this approach also a kind
of answering to the to the other
question and give you the real answer to
what you asked
si cyber commander a military cyber
commander what I really want is a
permanent role in the watch room I want
to know everything that is happening
right there as a fighter pilot I would
never enter a fight without knowing who
is their enemies friends allies
everything and so on so I need the
permanent radar on the networks if I
have that then I think I need to guide
the industry in the academia in
designing my real tool to do cyber
operation and I'm doing this with a
close connection with the industry and
explain them clearly every single
details or of the capability I won in
every single sector anyone else just
really in Germany the responsibility to
defend the networks of industries or to
protect the industry it's
ability the first place of Industry
itself and of course there's an office
under the Minister of Interior of a
federal office for IT security that is
provided providing some some guidance
also some commitments that they have to
do in if something happening in of a
certain scale they have to report
certain things to the government but
it's a responsibility of the
organization itself first to protect it
time for one more question
we'll go and towards the back here
members of the panel my name is Kevin
deploy from the United States Military
Academy and I was hoping you could
explain how a state analyzes the
proportionality of a response to a cyber
attack given the disparity in nature and
effect of different attacks thank you
so proportionality comments yeah I think
there's a decision by heads of states at
NATO but also a cyber attack can cause
an article 5 situation but does not mean
but in cyber tech has to be answered
with a cyber attack but it's all
possible actions possible with me
starting with diplomatic actions
economic actions cyber actions or even
use of kinetic so this is not a
one-to-one relationship it's it's open
if such threshold is reached by a cyber
attack any other this is the topic of
the air and the CAS a probably will take
a couple of years to define every single
response this studies on the table I
think we need to prepare first
capability how to respond and then
measure proportionality which we pretty
much don't know yet how we can cause
collateral effects and I'd only make one
comment having participated in
discussions in the US with our national
leadership as we were thinking about how
we were gonna spawn Sony not petya other
incidents we used you know my input
always was we should use the exact same
framework for proportionality in the
cyber world that we do in the physical
world there shouldn't be difference we
should use a standard methodology here
and clearly the legal and policy
framework is going to be very critical
here with that I'd like to thank the
thank you very very much for a very
comprehensive and very straightforward
dialogue to the audience thank you very
much for some great questions thank you
[Applause]