thank you to CCDC OE with entrusting me
there's a really great panel so this is
the after lunch conversation the after
lunch conversation and before the
cocktail hour conversations are the most
challenging so to keep you all focus
today there's gonna be a little quiz at
the end to make sure you win all paying
attention that is just a joke but let's
start with a little poll so how many of
you in the room believe that we this
global silence this constant engagement
we're seeing is going to continue like
it is now this forever war that some of
our are talking about who thinks it's
going to stay like this who things we
are leading towards escalation and that
we're going to see more state-on-state
non-state actors two state actors
attacks and that it's things situations
will just get worse right I will see if
you will you will have the same opinion
at the end of the panel so we have we
have a three speakers today and and that
as much as I mentioned that the title is
global silence or global battle so we've
been asked or the speakers have been
asked to talk a little bit about who are
the new entrants in this space or what
are some of the new tactics and
techniques of the old and known actors
but we're also going to talk a little
bit about what the diffusion of power is
doing to the concept of the Terran so we
have three speakers we'll do things a
little differently than the other panels
we've seen each of the speaker will
present separately for about 20 minutes
because they had their presenting on
different regions and different
countries and then we will go to to a
Q&A so our first speaker today is the
first lieutenant miss Kong who is the
Korean who works at the Korean Air Force
but she's also active at the Department
of information security at Korean
University so she will share with us the
analysis she and her colleagues have
done on North Korean operations and
strategies I think given how little we
know about North Korean the way they
organize their cyber forces their
strategies she'll shed some light on the
recent operation
and what they what they can mean for for
the alliance so with that the floor is
yours thank you okay so hello I would
like to thank NATO and cCTC OE for
inviting me to saikhan and I'm truly
honored to be here today and before I
start my presentation I would like to
inform that all the views thoughts and
opinions made in my presentation do not
represent the official position of
Republic of Korea nor the ROK Ministry
of National Defense and okay so let's
begin so this is the table of contents
and I would like to start the brief
introduction of North Korea's interest
in cyber capabilities so the interest of
North Korea's cyber interest in the
cyber warfare have predated from the
beginning of the Kim jong-un's regime
who is the current leader of North Korea
right now Kim jong-il the formal Korean
North Korean leader he have he have
perceived the advantage of having
networked military by monitoring the
Gulf or the Kosovo war and the Iraq war
he have strengthened his
built the sorry $2 he has strengthened
the importance of building the cyber
capabilities by stress stretching out
that in the electronic warfare reference
guide in 2005 saying that a modern war
is decided by one's conduct of
electronic warfare
thus cyber units are my detached force
and detached backup power based on his
father's work Kim jong-un the current
leader of North Korea also stressed on
building the cyber capabilities in North
Korea his major what his major in his
major is computer science and the
military so he knows the importance as
well and he have stated when he visited
the cyber units
reconnaissance general Bureau which is
the key cyber unit in North Korea in
2000 in February 2013 he have stated
that with intensive information and
communication technology and the brave
RGB with its cyber warriors we can
penetrate and sanctions any sanctions
for the construction of a strong and
prosperous nation likewise despite of
the of North Korea's weak environment
North Korea the upper leadership of
North Korea have put continuous interest
and effort to build these cyber
capabilities in that sense they have
sent 50 to 60 elite soldiers and nearly
to abroad to study computer science and
then when they come back to North Korea
they work as the cyberattack attackers
in cyber units and then so therefore
their estimated 6000 and 800 estimated
cyber soldiers in North Korea currently
therefore cyber warfare is an optimal
choice for North Korea due to the
following costs and effects cyber
warfare ensures continuous effects
during wartime and peacetime
in covert and LOC low cost cyber
operations achieve various missions from
the upper leadership of North Korea and
moreover they have really limited
Internet dependency because of the
because of the Kim's Kim's thought that
open information would harm his regime
so North Korea has nothing to like it's
hard to get into their systems so this
picture is the military unit of a
military command structure in North
Korea and I would like to say that the
shaded units are direct or possibly
relevant to cyber operations so on the
above Kim jong-un is over there the
current leader of North Korea and he
serves as the chairman of state affairs
Commission and supreme commander of
Korean People's Army
and also chairman of Central Military
Commission of Workers Party of Korea
which means he has the he is he
maintains the overall control and
comments of North Korean military
I would like to throughout this picture
I would like to mention that the cyber
units that there are relevant to cyber
operations are divided into two groups
the first is General Staff Department
and then the second is recognizance
general Beru General Staff Department is
under the Korean People's Army and they
conduct cyber operations within their
conventional military capabilities while
a recognizance General Peru acquires
tests and reports directly to the upper
leadership of the state affairs
commission which means the leader Kim
and then it means that the direct
relation and direct reporting system
shows the strategic importance of
recognizance General Peru so let's move
on to the cyber operations attributed to
North Korea in in our paper we have
categorized the cyber operations
attributed to North Korea into three
objectives first this information
espionage secondly cyber terrorism and
then financial warfare finest are the
categories may not be exclusive so may
be an operation can fall into more than
two categories financial warfare
differentiates the state-sponsored
actors of North Korea to those of other
nations things because generally
state-sponsored actors focus on the
first two objectives the espionage the
information as peonage and cyber
terrorism and criminal groups focus on
gaining the financial gains however
North Korean cyber forces conduct
operations of financial warfare due to
the international sanctions I will go on
later so I'll due to the time limit
station I will not go over all the
operations discussed in my paper but I
will just briefly go on the operations
that have significant meaning for
today's talk for information espionage
operation I would like to talk about the
campaign game suki campaign game suki is
the most representative information
espionage activity that is attributed to
north korea the reason why I put
campaign instead of operation as a
campaign stands for the stains for a
series of military operations to achieve
a goal in this case North Korea is
targeting South Korean government South
Korean government agencies military or
defense industrial base to get to
collect intelligence of national defense
Foreign Affairs and other secret
information the funny are this
statistics
it shows the newly discovered malware
code every month by the attackers who
have first created the malware Kim Suki
the interesting point is that the
espionage activities go it's still
ongoing and it's going up and up so the
activity is more active right now and
the more important thing is that the
number of the number of newly discovered
malware increases substantially before
and after the key political events so in
here you can see that after the
breakdown of the second u.s. and North
Korean hano estimate the number of
discovered malware have been the highest
I would like to go over to the cyber
terrorism operations it's about the
operation blockbuster many of you have
been known about this operation almost
on november 24th 2014
almost half of personal computers and
servers have been wiped out by a cyber
attack caused by
on Tiger coat guardians of peace not the
galaxy's yes and then so the US
officials have announced that it it was
retribute the operation was retribute it
by the upcoming Sony movie called the
interview which has the plot of
assassinating the leader came at that
time President Obama has warned that the
United States will launch a proportional
response to the attack of some attack
against Sony just a few days later in
North Korea
all the internal have been went to
completely dark
I mean offline whether the United States
have conducted that oh and then the
internet um block sorry internet went
dark and it is assumed that there was a
DDoS attack that has caused the blackout
it is not clear that whether the United
States have conducted ddos attack
against North Korea but the Sony hack
the operation blockbuster still shows an
important sign that a state-sponsored
actor can still attack a private firm
which is sunny in this case and I would
like to move on to the our last category
the financial warfare international
sanctions have been put pushed to Kim's
regime to conduct operations at cyber
operations to generate their income for
their their regime operation and wanna
cry Bangladesh is central haste and
cryptocurrencies theft or exemplify the
operations of financial warfare on May
12 2007 teen wanna cry ransomware have
infected more than three hundred
thousand machines and then the
widespread the widespread of one wanna
cry show demonstrates the fact that
one wore mobile malware is very
spreading and then it has the power to
spread out by replicating itself to
over-consume compromised the systems
Bangladesh central bank aced happened in
February 2016 and it show North Korean
the state-sponsored actor of North Korea
have abused Swift Network 250 Network
they have stoled with the stolen Swift
credentials they made several fradulent
transactions and one has succeeded which
made to the 81 million u.s. dollars
transaction from Bangladesh central bank
to whatever to the to the regime yes and
according to the recent UN panel of
experts report that was in March 2019
and it says that North Korea has amassed
600 around 670 million u.s. dollars in
foreign and cryptocurrencies since 2016
so after going on to the on cyber
operations I would like to ask Ben what
will be the next or current the military
strategy for North Korean cyber forces I
believe that they will develop their
cyber operations in more strategic forms
by choosing their targets with more
consideration and more creativeness
moreover they would like to mix their
tactics techniques and procedures it
appears in short with other countries to
make their attribution more difficult I
will just briefly explain about the
TTP's tactics techniques and procedures
mean the behavior or a modus operandi of
cyber adversaries TTP's helped to
highlight the Prudential information
in cyber operations and define attack
Ursus attributes such as attack vectors
scenarios and identities this is why
every like security cyber security
analysis tried to find the TTP's when
they discover new malware so how do they
make study t-piece with other countries
North Korea is mixing TTP's with other
countries by sending their cyber forces
to the countries and there are two
methods that they can deal with this the
first involves conducting operational
operations based on preset coordination
through diplomatic military and
political channels for example China
there are have been many continuous
reports the North Korea have been
sending their troops to China and under
the shadow of China are conducting the
operations that there are North Korea
can avoid make the attribution more
difficult and moreover when they are
attributed they can avoid the diplomatic
issues since the because of the
jurisdiction problems in fact the
Chinese embassy in Washington DC have
been refused to answer the questions of
whether China is supporting the North
Korean cyber operations I would like to
also add another example to this this
method that Iran also has the connection
with North Korea they had the technology
sharing thread v3t since 2012 and it was
focused on the cyber spear Iran based on
the treaty they had a sharing share the
treaty technology sharing corporations
on cyber experiences on cyber warfare
and also their TTP's several security
analysis have said that the operation
Shamoon which
said to be iran-backed case they have
found the similar cyber a similar TT
piece and also the same commercially
sorry commercially um
driver files that have been used in
operation blockbuster of North Korea
the second method involves dispatching
cyber forces and conducting operations
without the target countries
acknowledgment according to the recorded
future in 2018 ten nations were
identified in which North Koreans
maintains an actual physical presence
and virtual prisons the Tang countries
include Bangladesh Thailand Malaysia New
Zealand Mozambique Kenya and India and
China and so on you can look at the
report if you want to know the rest of
the countries and then yes further
information of the operations and
further details about the preset
coordination between North Korea and
other countries are discussed in my
paper so if you want to look at them I
will be very appreciated and thank you
for listening my presentation even
though I was too nervous and thank you
very much thank you
thank you very much also we are not
going to go too far in the region sir
our next speaker is Miss matsuba Mihoko
who is achieved security strategies as
MTT which stands for Nippon Telegraph
and telephone company she has a great
background including private sector and
in the government she's also done a lot
of thinking and writing and speaking
with think-tanks academia and she will
talk a little bit about what is the
threat landscape in asia-pacific and
what the Japanese government and the
private sector are doing about it so
with that the floor is yours thank you
so hello so thank you for your time and
I'm really appreciative that in the NATO
CCDC OE and Estonian teams are giving us
a great opportunity and also hospitality
and thank you Vincent to organize this
and so today I'd like to share the
threats and risks happening in the
asia-pacific region but I also want to
be optimistic and I all want to talk
about the opportunities for
collaboration in asia-pacific so I'd
like to expand the scope of cyber risks
and the cyber attacks beyond North Korea
so Jiyeon just gave us a wonderful
presentation about espionage our
financially motivated crimes and
destruction such as wanna cry and we see
so many problems in the asia-pacific
region unfortunately but because I'm
from industry I also want to talk about
the risks happening critical
infrastructure sectors because I'm from
the telecom company and also know how
big companies and also government and
academia can help the small and
medium-sized enterprises so for example
hacktivism
so India Pakistan have been having the
geopolitical tension over Kashmir over
last decades and unfortunately this
tension also exists in cyberspace and
which started to happen around 2000 and
hacktivism and website defacement
occurred over Kashmir but this
hacktivism researched around 2000 when a
coordinated bombing and shooting what
happened in Mumbai and every year on the
anniversary of Mumbai terror attacks
defacement activities happen from Indian
hackers against Pakistani websites and
this is not only about website
defacement or hacktivism they started to
take advantage of new tools social media
so the Kashmir attention went up again
in February 2000 19 when the suicide
bombing by car happened in the into
India controlled part of Kashmir and the
social media feeds started to emerge to
claim that also this capture of Indian
fighter pilot is a fake or this is to
something right out and this kind of
disinformation campaign doesn't exist
only in Pakistan or India so I talked
about two cases of Chinese
disinformation campaign against Taiwan
so a huge typhoon called a JB hit Japan
last year and it especially hit hard the
western part of Japan and also a
diarrhea I'm not sure how many of you
have been to my country and so after
that the serious flooding and a pan
smashed into the corridor of the Kansai
Airport which is located in the western
part of Japan
five thousand passengers and airport
workers got stranded in the airport and
can you imagine five thousand people
start had to spend the night in there on
a foreign country and five thousand
people included 750 Chinese passengers
and also 500 Taiwanese tourists and then
the first component of this information
campaign started to emerge so what
happened so social media started to say
that oh the Chinese embassy in Japan
sent 15 buses to pick up the stranded
Chinese passengers from the airport to
the city area and then the second
component of the campaign started to
emerge the unica Oh so the Chinese
passengers on those five 15 buses
started to date Taiwanese to get on
board
only if Taiwanese declare their actually
Chinese however both of them proved fake
and inaccurate days after however it was
too late why because it's social media
people tweet about it on people D post
over and over again and it was picked by
not only the social media but also the
Chinese state-owned media outlets and
also unfortunately Taiwanese media
outlets and can you imagine a huge
amount of criticism emerged against
Taiwanese government and also a
Taiwanese version of the embassy in
Japan and called economic and cultural
office they criticized also the Chinese
government is helping their citizens so
how can Taiwanese government is not
doing that
even though that the it was based upon a
fake crane and then tragedy happened
taiwanese diplomat who was the
director-general
the osaka branch of the economic and
cultural office committed suicide
and he left the note saying that he is
he has been really troubled by the huge
criticism and coming to the Taiwanese
government and his office and this year
three are two months ago that the
organization called our reporters
without borders published report about
chinese disinformation campaign and
during the press conference they
referred to this tragedy and also the
suicide and chinese disinformation
campaign didn't stop there so the
taiwanese had a series of municipal
campaigns and elections last november
and then the fourth taiwanese foreign
minister joseph raised his concern he
said that well this information and
election interference have been
happening from the chinese over the
years and years but it started to take a
new form using the social media and sure
enough they use the social media and
also that online britain post to send
out this information so can you see this
followed so it's a bit small but so ten
you see that notice also he is a DPP
candidate before running for this city's
mayor and so this photo is actually fake
photoshopped but he's he looks like a
wearing an earpiece so the social media
and the online readings
fees study the Kramer's oh he's actually
wearing an earpiece to get a real-time
fist to answer his tough questions over
political promises are held by the
Taiwanese TV programs but it was all
fake but it was tweeted and be posted
over and over again so it kind of eroded
his confidence and of course each and
this election led to the huge loss to
DPP and huge victory to the KMT and the
huge concern over this information
campaign the not one that happened in
Taiwan but also in the United States so
six US senators for three from Democrats
and three from Republicans sent open
letter to FBI director DNI director our
Secretary of State upon bail on
Secretary of Treasury of Nugent to say
that oh so we should actually
investigate and help the Taiwanese
friends are the not to address the
concerns or over allegation that the
Chinese Communist Party in the field
that the Taiwanese elections because
they are partner and North Korea is also
another our concern in the asia-pacific
region and beyond
so as Dion mentioned they are working on
financially motivated crimes and also
not only that our distractions to this
business continuity so it's not only to
the concerns to the government but also
the business because wanna cry created a
so many problems and we just continued
continuity so industry started to
rethink that especially because nowadays
we have to
on global supply chains and global
partners outside the national borders so
they have to rethink unleash shape the
cybersecurity strategy and the
deterrence and resiliency and speaking
of critical infrastructure protection
the environment we are sitting in are
getting tougher and tougher so we see so
many cyber attacks we also see more
regulations and trade change to trade
tensions but despite of that critical
infrastructure companies are responsible
to provide 24/7 our services to
customers because it's a foundation of
social welfare economic growth and
national security
so that is why cyber security physical
security sectors specific and also
cross-sectoral and public-private
partnerships are getting more important
to continue to provide good services to
customers but cyberattacks and not only
the headaches to the critical
infrastructure companies so it can be
system failures because they happen
unfortunately and also natural disasters
like typhoons as I mentioned and also
flooding or earthquakes and sometimes it
is easy to distinguish all this cause
and this calls coming from cyber tech or
the system failure right away and
sometimes not so in our case at NTT
cooperation we use network operations
center in TT cert cyber security team
and disaster management team to work
together to eliminate any potential
element of course one by one and to do
that we also have to have a good
consistent communication risk management
and also joint exercises not within NTT
but also with other companies and
government
why because critical infrastructure have
interdependency to each other
telecommunication depends on electricity
or energy and we also have to rely on
transportation so that is why the
Japanese government has been doing a
fantastic job to have an annual joint
exercise not only between the central
government but also with different
critical sexual sectors every year and
the last one happened in Tokyo last
December so this photo is from from the
last December's exercise and we actually
had 3000 participants from the
government and also from every sector of
the 14 critical infrastructure sectors
and they tested multifaceted cyber
stress so cyber attacks - electric grid
transportation and they also added a new
element are this information expansion
by social media and but we also have to
include small and medium-sized companies
into our cyber security or risk
management discussions because their
fundamental part of our supply chains
and economic growth on national security
however because they are so small they
don't enough resources manpower or
budget so that is why the bad guys
exactly know what they should be after
so 60% and 43% of cyber attacks target
small and medium sized companies and
unfortunately 60% of small companies
attacked go out of business within six
months so we should do something about
it
and this is a duty problematic
especially in the asia-pacific region
because 90% of the companies exist in in
the region are small or medium sized
companies so but what exactly what kind
of problem actually the small and
medium-sized companies have so this is
statistics taken from western part of
Japan called Osaka so according to their
survey two years ago the small and
medium-sized companies have only five
thousand US dollars to use annually for
cyber security and five thousand US
dollars are not that much to spend on
cyber security so good news is the most
of them have antivirus software but not
know more than that and most of them
don't have passed even passwords or even
encryption so not so much data security
covered for small medium-sized companies
so what should we do with it so that
most Japanese are big companies and
Japanese government started to take more
efforts and our actions to take for
small and medium-sized companies and
also for the protection of a critical
infrastructure why because now we have a
clear deadline on the cria go to the
more successful in cyber security so six
years ago the Tokyo was selected to host
the 2020 Summer Olympic and Paralympic
Games and this is a huge sports event
and everybody gets excited about but
it's more than sports because it can be
also political it can be also diplomacy
and it also about national security and
it showcases and technology level
including cyber security so it dearly
prompted not only the Japanese
but Japanese industry and Japanese
academia to work together across and in
the organizational silos to create more
information sharing on cyber threats so
gene said that North Korea and Iran are
working together to share their
knowledge and if bad guys can do that
good people should do that to be better
because we need collective knowledge to
the better in terms of cybersecurity and
the Japanese major companies created a
forum code across sector forum to create
a great ecosystem to educate hire train
and retain cybersecurity professionals
in cooperation with Japanese government
and Japanese academia because we need
more good cybersecurity people in this
field and it's not only for Olympic
Games but only also to live a positive
cybersecurity legacy for the next
generations we have more cyber exercises
joint exercises or internal exercises
and another to be more successful and to
be better at cybersecurity and the
Japanese government is also helping the
small and medium-sized companies and
also IOT to to be more resilient and
until increase or deterrence in the
cyber space so if we have a create
vision on Korea go and clear dead wrong
we can be more successful and you have a
good case in Europe too because some
Olympic Games is coming up in Paris in
five years and also in the United States
and Los Angeles is hosting the Summer
Olympic Games in 2012 and actually the
the Los Angeles started to fall
cyber threat intelligence framework
including the small and medium-sized
companies and before this session I was
having a small chat with Clara and she
told me that and how organisation is and
making a toolkit for small and
medium-sized companies cyber security so
I think that is that this saikhan
conference is a great platform because
we are all from like-minded countries we
are from different sector different
company different government different
universities or think tank but we have
the shared goal to have a better
cybersecurity not only for their own
organization but also for our team the
global teams to be better so ideally
appreciate NATO CCDC OE and Vincent to
give me this opportunity thank you thank
you and also thank you for the great
plug for the global cyber alliance so
last but not least is kaki know who is
the senior director at fireEye
cocoon has a long career in the private
sector but he's done and probably equal
if not more work thinking about the
international law deterrence and
everything in between so he'll talk a
little bit about the diffusion of power
and how we can deal with the Terrans
with this diffuse power so with that
thank you Thank You Clara
good afternoon hey it's a pleasure to be
here it's both an honor and pleasure to
be here especially I'm the only man in
the panel so today I'm gonna be talking
about the row of legitimacy in
deterrence framework right so ten years
ago I took some time off from my
full-time job and I went to do
counterterrorism research and one of the
things that I wanted to do was to look
at you know violence profile basically I
wanted to know what drives terrorist
groups right and one of the key group
that I looked at was this group called
al-shabaab al-shabaab if you are not
familiar with them they're based out of
East Africa so countries like Ethiopia
Somalia in Kenya and they are closely
affiliated with al-qaeda and you
probably have heard of you know
al-shabaab with this terrorist incident
is basically massacre and in the mall a
shopping mall called Westgate back in
2013 71 people died in that incident and
more than 200 people were injured and
many of whom were critically injured so
I was actually in Nairobi a week plus
after the incident and I met what you
know people who over the past one week
who had to attend six seven eight
funerals because you know they had a
friend their neighbor their family who
died in that particular incident so the
amount of grief the amount of sadness
the amount of pain totally shocked me it
shocked me to the core and you know when
it comes to violence profile you know
it's very hard to ideally you want to
interview terrorists you want to get out
Shabaab in the room with you and say you
know what drives you right and that's
presumably is gonna be difficult even if
I were to be able to do that I probably
won't be here standing and talking to
you about that so what's the alternative
the alternative is really about you know
look at what they put out there right so
they put out a lot of Twitter messages
so what I did was basically I took all
these Twitter messages thousands of
messages and I meticulously look into
all these messages and I basically find
that you can actually group these
messages most of them into three buckets
three main drivers the first driver here
is called legitimacy that is to say you
know where do they derive legitimacy
from so if you look into these tweeted
messages they basically look at and say
well they derived legitimacy from God or
Allah okay because Allah is with us okay
the second driver there is needs and
these really talk to live needs that
provision
and oppression and the way they
articulate this is that they talk about
indiscriminate killing by the Kenyan
Defense Forces they talk about women and
children suffering and yes they also
talk about Western colonization the
continuation of Western colonization the
last driver that I found was this thing
called confidence right where do they
derive confidence from and you know
there are two parts to that the first
part is really about you know
operational success that is they have
the capability to inflict death and
injury do government forces okay and
that gives them a lot of confidence the
second part of that is really about you
know dehumanization of Kenyan defense
forces you know you know you see a lot
taunting going on right there right so
these three variables legitimacy need
and confidence they actually you know
pretty well research and I've included a
couple of sources that you see on the
bottom right-hand side here but what I
wanna do is talk a little bit about the
interrelationship right the bad news is
that if you look at this picture here
the bad news for us is that you know
they are mutually reinforcing okay a
nice to say that you know if I am
successful in killing government forces
and you know that gives me not only a
lot of confidence but essentially what
that tells me also is that well God is
on my side right and if God is on my
side then what should i do I should
continue to fight oppression and with
that I need more capabilities I need
more weapons so you can see that is
reinforcing mutually reinforcing the
good news is also that is also mutually
reinforcing and that is to say that you
know if you hit one of these three
variables you essentially could disrupt
them right so give you example so if I
have let's say full legitimacy God is on
my side I have you know the need the
required need that I need to address but
if you hit me on my
feeders that you if you take out my
capability I'm not gonna be better hit
you back right so you know you can
disrupt me or you can think about it
like that's - I have lots of confidence
I also have lots of needs but somehow
you undermine my thinking and you still
you tell me and I believe you now they
say well Allah is no more in my side
okay so the legitimacy is actually gone
and I would also not attack you right so
this is the good thing about this stuff
here right and so and so so what's
important to note what's important to
note is that these three drivers are
gonna be very key when we think about
you know cyber right so the lessons from
counterterrorism is such that you know
if you focus on attacking the actors on
the confidence part taking out their
capability what do you get you get quick
result you're absolutely gonna get quick
result but the problem with that is that
the result may not be very effective in
the long run and this is the lesson that
I bring with me to the cyber domain in
that I think there is going to be a
limit to what cyber offensive capability
can do for you it's very simple you hit
someone you hit someone hit a group they
can reconstitute they can regroup and
reconstitute if you're talking about
North Korea you probably don't have a
whole lot of target that you can look at
that's well okay the other thing is that
you know you may also feel escalation if
you are in an advanced country you're
very dependent on i.t and you have a lot
of attack surface here that you know
people can come back at you as you
attack them right so that's the
challenge right there now if you look at
the other two variables they're okay
legitimacy and mean they are slow at
work they may even be you know walking
indirectly
but potentially potentially they can be
more effective in the long run so in
this presentation I'm just gonna be
focusing on legitimacy right so one
source of legit
ceefor earth is yes international law
okay now with reference to the
deterrence framework I would argue that
you know you need at least two
preconditions before deterrence can work
properly
the first one is attribution that you
got to know who did what to you and why
that's the first thing second thing is
recognition of sovereignty that you have
to have recognition of sovereignty now
you don't have to take my word for this
okay especially now when sovereignty is
such a contentious topic all you have to
do is look at what's happening in the
South China Sea if I take you back to
the history of South China Sea right
after Second World War
none of these coastal states in the in
that you can see here none of them
actually make sovereignty claim over
these pieces of rocks and islands in the
South China Sea why why is that the case
because they will consider useless
worthless okay and it doesn't make sense
to commit national resources to defend
something that is considered worthless
or useless but things started to change
in the late 1960s the United Nation led
a survey of the South China Sea and what
did they find or reserve awesome all
reserve now I got oil in 1970 the
technology also developed in that you
know people can now drill for oil below
ocean depth level that's the second
thing I get now that's all I can get it
in 1973 the law also changed UN clause
came into effect in a nation Convention
and law of the sea which basically allow
or based in those states or coastal
states to form economic zones exclusive
economic zone so these three factors
this oil there's a way to get it there's
a law that allows me to build economic
zone basically made all the states here
make sovereignty claim over South China
Sea by far by far the most dominant
player right here
yes China okay and China basically if
you can see here called the nine dash
line this green line that you see here
China's basically stood making
sovereignty claim to say the entire
South China Sea belongs to us okay
in fact what China has been doing is
basically you know they're conquering
Islands they're building military and
also civilian infrastructure right there
right so today this is law or sea lines
of communication called the South China
Sea is of immense value it carries 30
percent of the world
crude oil three trillion dollars of
trade goes by every year okay lots of
fishes there you like scuba diving
there's 2,000 fishes there I'm trying to
get you to go to these places here okay
so food security is important and not to
mention lots of oil so ladies and
gentlemen this combination of immense
value immense value of the South China
Sea plus lack of sovereignty recognition
basically contribute to this domain
being one of the highly contested domain
in the world today cyber is exactly like
this the reason why I say that is
because sovereignty is not clear is or
it is either not clear or deliberately
made unclear at the same time it has a
lot of value because we put so much
stuff in the cyber domain right lack of
you know lack of sovereignty plus high
value again that's why cyber is such a
highly contested domain okay you guys
believe me no yes okay awesome okay
now if you'll believe me if you are with
me on this one then the next question is
well if this is so simple just settle
the sovereignty question and we have
lots of value we have some stability
right Jay was talking about stability
why don't we just have sovereignty in
place why don't we settle the question
now listen to a lot of arguments and one
very common argument is this thing
called freedom of action
the states right the states won that
freedom action to do something they do
not want to be you know burdened by some
some laws to be in place right so
consider this last year may 2018 the UK
Attorney General basically you know made
a speech it at the Chatham House and he
basically said that you know sovereignty
is not a rule there's no such rule
called sovereignty in international law
now if if sovereignty is not a rule if
sovereignty is not a rule then the UK
can do things to other countries and
there won't be any violation right if
there's no rule there's no violation
that's easy so I understand that freedom
of action right in the name of national
security all right so if you look at
where they are going with this is that
you know going back to that circle that
you see there
what are they prioritizing the
prioritizing about what hitting the
capability of the adversary taking their
confidence level but I would argue well
that is true they are doing so at the
expense of what legitimacy right because
in such in international law there's
such a thing called sovereign equality
is as you can do stuff to other people
so can other people do stuff back to you
right now interesting enough five months
after he made the speech the UK NCSE
national cybersecurity Center basically
put out an article right here that says
well records campaign of cyber attacks
by Russian military intelligence so you
read that article it basically outline
all the cases that you know the UK said
this is attributed to the Russian
military intelligence and I especially
want to draw attention to the writing on
the right hand side there that says the
GRU did all this and this is this attack
has been conducted you know in violation
of international law
so so I looked at this and I say okay
let's look at all the cases there and if
a violation of in
national law the question then becomes
which rule which drew are we talking
about here and I'm guessing and of
course it's not being outlined in this
particular article I'm guessing it's a
sovereignty rule but hold on you're
Attorney General just say the rule does
not exist if you're Attorney General say
it rule does not exist how do you say
the Russians are violating international
law parcel Russia has say you must be
joking
you say there was no rule and how can I
now be violating the sovereignty of UK
right so that's one thing that we need
to keep in mind that this debate yeah I
want freedom but you losing legitimacy
right there okay the second thing I want
to talk about okay is that I think we
need to rethink about you know how we
interpret harm when it comes to the
cyber domain now the language that we
always use when we talk about harm is
this thing called injury and death to
individual and destruction the property
now it makes sense if you are thinking
about weapons like kinetic weapons
chemical weapons and biological weapons
because these weapons have violent
consequences right if you throw cyber to
the mix there if you throw side whether
the mix there well cyber has both
violent consequences and non violent
consequences right there okay so what
that means is that for cyber operations
that are potentially below that use of
force threshold you know you are
potentially going to be looking at more
harm than you originally thought about
okay and and you know take for example
pics for example you know with the aid
of cyber tools and artificial
intelligence artificial intelligence
that knows you more than you know
yourself okay foreign adversaries can
steal election outcome undermining
democratic institutions and undermining
call democracy values how much harm is
that is non-violent but how much harm is
that okay
so we gotta think about that now I'm
sure
all of you here would have a few
examples that you can think about okay
when it comes to big you know this here
right this below use of force here right
now immediately you know how do you
drive consensus right like this right
this is not what we're used to but how
do you drive consensus it's gonna be
very very hard this is why I think you
know going forward states will have to
look at you know very narrow feel for
example like finance where people can
agree upon right so if you look at what
the Carnegie Endowment for international
peace has done is that they basically
urging g20 countries to refrain for
manipulating of financial data how many
of you are familiar of this work here
okay that's great okay so this is very
very important that is you know you
gotta walk somewhere you gotta walk
somewhere and say how do I get stability
into the system okay
the last point I want to make and you
know you probably remember what I just
say early on that is you know the proof
the two preconditions okay the the
deterrence of proper deterrence
framework is one is sovereignty the
other one is called attribution
attribution is key
why because you know you gotta know who
did what to you and why okay so with
attribution you gotta have strong
intelligence capability there's no
question about that
strong intelligence capability now I
come from a private sector I'm from
fireEye and when it comes to
intelligence our focus is really about
you know how do we uncover the TTP's
that the ji-yong talked about of the you
know the adversaries we're very very
focused on TTP's when it comes the
attribution then we are good at just
attribute in to let's say a group like
apt 10 a PT 28 not necessarily a you
know this is job to put in did this you
know see Jean King did this okay but you
know attribution to that group level
basically okay and we feel that we have
the breadth of coverage out there
because right now we are probably
tracking about 1,200
different threat groups out there now I
doubt any government any government will
attract 10 or 20% of what we try in
terms of the you know the threat groups
out there but where the government lacks
in breath they make it up in death and
the reason I say that is that government
has tools to go deep into a threat
actors organization and the other ones
who have in order to the national power
to say hey who is behind this thing yeah
so who did what to us okay you gotta
have the private sector and the
government basically combined forces
because you have this deaf and birth
that you can take into consideration so
with that ladies and gentlemen I like to
close I look forward to discussion later
on thank you all so we really unpacked a
lot during these three presentations
from North Korea to AIPAC to to threat
intelligence I'm gonna take the
motivators privilege for the first
question but I invite you to start to
think about your questions to the panel
so I just want to go back to North Korea
and the first presentation and will you
describe in your paper in your
presentations all these North Korean
TTP's make mixing TTP's with other
countries operative launching attacks
from third countries with or without
their knowledge can you share a little
bit about how the Republic of Korea
thinks about countering some of it and
what are some of the lessons learned for
NATO and a transatlantic space from you
know how to really deal with an
adversary who does all this okay that's
very interesting questions since there
are last two but not to answer first I
would like to mention that the lessons
learned from overseeing the upper cyber
operations conducted by North Korea is
that they are developing and still
developing their offensive cyber
capabilities and developing their
technical development to circumvent the
international sanctions and as long as
they are mixing the TTP's with other
countries a targeted country has to
prepare and counteract cooperate in
countries so it means that it will be
more greater threat for the targeted
country and as Republic of Korea which
has been attacked by a lot attacked
attacked by North Korea for several
times in the past history and still
getting attacks from North Korea is
trying to build the global global
corporations with our intelligence
agencies to cooperate and share
information and I wish that will go more
active and then to the brother means of
sharing systems and then yes thank you
are there any questions from the
audience
jae-hee Lee
I thank you Jason Haley's from Columbia
University uh sorry to do this Claire
won't comment one question um young the
John Carlin book I think did the best he
had been the head of the National
Security Division at the Department of
Justice and in is the closest I've seen
to an official denial from the United
States that they weren't behind the
denial of service attack following the
Sony attack the White House when I was
talking to them afterwards inside
they're like man I wish you would just
deny this this was a nos this isn't our
style of this apparently they didn't
want to deny at the time because if we
start denying things then we get caught
up with was a covert action you know we
don't want to confirm or deny said John
Carlin spoke on this is really really
strong and he does come out and say it
wasn't us it was some private group and
yes it's a really good book so thank you
and thank you all for the for the
presentation cocking the you know you
finished with you talk about legitimacy
and you talk about confidence and you've
finished for the slide on attribution
yeah and many of us here have been
caught up in the talks on the cyber
peace Institute that's been proposed in
maybe an independent attribution
organization and it kind of falls in
between your model there on the depth of
the government and the breadth of the
private sector I'm curious your thoughts
on that and maybe miho if you have
thoughts on that as well thank you sorry
Jay can I just clarify I mean
independent in tribution organization
yeah so there's been this push that you
know tied up with tech accords
individual Geneva Convention and
Microsoft and others and saying maybe we
need a a separate group because maybe
some countries don't necessarily
understand a fire I or agree with the
fire assessment they're looking for a
state assessment but the states aren't
necessarily doing public attribution so
maybe we need some kind of independent
nonprofit group that would come out and
in do attribution I I think Jay there
was a discussion in the UN around that
particular topic to in fact one member
state basically say I we agree to that
so long as that independent organization
is in my country
so I I think it's gonna be very hard to
get consensus around this in terms of
either who do you trust
I mean I I know of that incident so I
think it's gonna be hard I mean if you
get my thoughts on that there's gonna be
ideological differences between
countries so that's why this country
says yeah I like it so long this is my
country
yeah so you know yeah
oh so thank you for your question so
when you save as an attribute are you
talking about the public contribution
who are more private attribution public
contribution so so public attribution is
important for states or government to
make a achieve response to cyber attacks
like Diigo the indictment Neiman
ashaming
[Music]
financial sanctions or even the media
response to do that you have to have an
accurate attribution but for from
industry perspective I don't think that
public activision is necessary for
having a good deterrence or good cyber
defense because if you have a good cyber
hygiene or good understanding with
cybersecurity or solutions then you're
gonna have a better chance to protect
yourself from cyber attacks or at least
your minimize the chance of the
expansion of infection so for example I
talked about the issues surrounding the
small and medium-sized companies and
they don't have budget or people to do
that but and they only need a small
solution at a reasonable price was best
practices to how to make it better and
you don't need attribution to make it
happen
Thank You Tina Park from the NATO
Defense College
I wonder if our two speakers could
comment about future prospects for
collaboration Republic of Korea and
Japan are both partner countries for the
Alliance and our moderator sort of
hinted at this prospect earlier and I
wondered if you see any room for greater
collaboration on the cyber domain and
moving forward and if so in what
capacity because both of you did a very
good job of highlighting multi-faceted
nature of cyber capabilities from North
Korea as well as you know other threats
in the asia-pacific region so when we
look at the future of the Alliance as we
reflect upon the 70th anniversary this
year where do you see actual tangible
collaboration taking place you mean
cooperation between NATO Japan and NATO
so I think it was an hour earlier today
after before the missus uh Nora gave his
presentation about Japanese cyber
deterrence on a cyber defense strategy
not an answer NATO CCDC or II mentioned
that the growing cooperation between
Japan and narrow and also Estonia about
cyber security and I I think it's great
because if you limit it to yourself if
you if you crawl yourself from outside
knowledge about NASA because
individually we can have only limited
knowledge under the only limited
visibility of a cyber environment cyber
threats and solutions or technologies
but if we can work together and
especially Estonia has a unique history
of cyber security and NATO already have
that the corrective knowledge of cyber
defence and cyber security so I really
appreciate that
to hear that Japan is increasing the
cooperation on cyber security with NATO
and also Estonia okay since Korea
Republic of Korea is not to have not
joined the cCTC we
I will I mean in my opinion I expect
South Korea to join the CCT cos soon and
then I would like to mention a brief a
past case to talk about the
collaboration among other countries for
South Korea in 2018 the Pyeongchang
Winter Olympic during the opening
ceremony there was a network failure
caused by an anonymous group which is
which is attributed to countries that
are not defined yet however to prepare
the incident like South Korean
government had collaborated with other
intelligence agencies from the United
States or England or other countries and
then they have collaborated to rebuild
or restore when the network goes down so
when the network went it went into the
failure at the opening ceremony they
worked in the collaborate movements to
to rework it in 12 hours so after the
incident the Korean government realized
about the importance of like
collaborating with each other so I know
I have heard that there are still
movements to join the international
organizations to collaborate more
actively thank you
and how can I know you've done a lot of
work with NATO so I'd be really
interested in hearing you know in terms
of collaboration but also how do you
think the alliance should should change
or is changing its approach when you
think about the diffused power in cyber
I mean there's been major adversaries
the organization's been working to to
address but I mean there is a whole
other range of actors out there that
that I think NATO should think about so
how what what do you think is there to
do on NATO side I think I speak more
towards NATO member states how many of
you were here when the president Estonia
gave a speech and basically make a
declaration saying that international
law applies to cyber operation or you
guys were here okay if you were not here
okay you miss something very important
okay
me that was basically you know the first
step right so when you have diffusion of
power you're gonna have many many
players here so you know you and in
classical security dilemma probably will
kicked in in the sense that you know if
I see this country investing in cyber
capability then hey maybe I should too
and so the the question becomes you know
what rules are available to govern the
behavior of all these different states
out there so so for the Estonian state
leader to come up and say you know
international law applies to cyber space
it's a very big thing in fact you know
this is basically saying you uphold the
rule of law and rule of international
law that is one rule that we make sure
that everyone plays with so that's the
important thing here the second thing
I'd like to mention there is really
about stability right so you saw that
picture that the graph that I mentioned
okay and I also you know really liked
what Jay was saying yesterday about you
know we should do everything we can okay
so that we don't come to this use of
force threshold a we try to keep things
really really stable there so I will
encourage one you know different
countries leaders to do exactly what the
Estonian leader has just done say okay
this is classical opinion of the u.s. to
is that support in the norms that you
know promote stability especially those
areas that are under the use of force
right I mentioned one just now and that
is the you know the the Carnegie
proposal there are a few that I can
think about also like Perry's call which
is actually you know a feature event in
this CCDC ohyeah the challenge with
Paris Codel is that for anything to if
you want to get anything done in in a
cyber space you could have at least US
Russia and China in there I don't think
you have us in the Paris call
I don't think yet Russia in there I
don't think you have China in there and
that's the challenge right there so the
financial proposal by Carnegie I am sure
because of the security in the
dependency in the financial war I'm sure
the Chinese will agree that this is
important the Russians will agree the
Americans will agree on that too so I
think you need to have major powers
buy-in as well thank you can I add one
thing yes sorry also I forgot to mention
that in how Japan can contribute to the
collaboration with NATO so Japan has our
nearly a unique experience is caused by
natural disasters and cyber attacks and
Japan faces lots of different types of
natural disasters fraud in earthquakes
and typhoons so Japan has a huge amount
of knowledge and expertise to how to
react on how to respond to risks caused
by the combination of natural disasters
and cyber attacks so because in
interdependency of the critical
infrastructure sectors and also between
the private sector and the government I
think that the Japan can share how we
make it happen to have bring the
resiliency to the protection of critical
infrastructure from the physical domain
and also from cyber domain to bring it
back to NATO countries there's a couple
of there in the back
and then app then there's some more all
the way at the end thank you so this is
also a collaboration question but
perhaps a little touchy er there was a
lot of talk about China and its growing
influence in the region um and I was
wondering how firm the dividing line
between China and Japan and South Korea
has become and if there's any areas for
cooperation in cyberspace between
participants in the region or if it's
really and us/them dichotomy at this
point is it look cool a couple questions
on oh please just got like to answer
this question and down we'll go we'll go
to the back please go ahead feel free to
answer now so so ji-hyun canal on one
example data corporation so the Japanese
and South Koreans and the Chinese
actually had a cybersecurity dialogue
twice in the past to discuss of what
kind of a cybersecurity strategy and
each country has and what kind of
cybersecurity actions that they are
taking so I think that way that they can
continue to identify whom to talk to
and what kind of national strategies and
actions that they are taking so it is
not novel for the confidence building on
a weekend person thank you question in
the back
hi had a question more geared towards
mr. ho and first lieutenant Cong what
would you say to the idea that countries
like North Korea and non-state actors
like terrorist groups get their
confidence and legit legit Ameen see
almost boost by getting exposed by media
outlets on different television networks
so I guess the question is you know
we're kind of helping the legitimacy by
talking publicly about what these actors
are doing oh absolutely I mean if you if
you look at terrorist group terrorist
group has been using the media to to
promote their cause right so one thing
that they do a terrorist job is to is to
create terror right so if they can
create terror in in the population and
they can also show that the government
is actually powerless right it has they
are powerless to stop them
you know it's gonna boost their
confidence level right the legitimacy
part is not usually done with media I
think is usually looking at you know
terrorist group they derive legitimacy
from you know some some higher being
right in this case God right there right
so it's always God was you know
sanctioning what they do right there
now speaking of General Petraeus talked
about a terrorist called Anwar Awlaki
yesterday and I thought that was a
really interesting discussion because
this man he's actually you know he's
actually worth more date than he's
actually alive and the reason it has to
do with legitimacy right there is so if
you look at Anwar Awlaki you know he
this MV M&E American you know cleric
which is associated with AQAP or
al-qaeda in the Arabian Peninsula and
General Petraeus talked about you know
he was actually killed in a in a drone
incident with the editor of the inspire
magazine AQAP had a
magazine called inspire the guy who got
killed is called some milk on this
editor right there and I think a lucky
son was also in the same car and they
all three died in in that incident so he
has been preaching a lot and and you can
see that before he got killed he
basically inspired maybe two or three
incidents but after he was dead and you
know people keep on uploading stuff his
sermon on YouTube and that basically
went on to inspire many more terrorist
incident right so San Bernardino
incident the Boston Marathon incident so
you know sometimes we buy meat you know
so what the United States did was
paralyzing what they want to kill
capture the terrorists right they want
to keep them on the capability the
confidence level what is that is that
done that has expense of what legitimacy
that guy you know became even more
legitimate when he went on after he was
dead to inspire many more terrorist
incidents so I think we have to be very
careful about this it's probably a lot
easier to try to undermine his
legitimacy instead of just you know
shooting him in the head or drop a bomb
on his head I just like to add the North
Korea it's hard to get them into a pie
by international norms so even though US
officials have been accused on South um
three North Korea to for their cyber
attacks um they have been publicly
denied but no more actions nor no more
like publicly saying about the there are
three positions
so we've I'm gonna again use my
moderator privilege because we really
wanted to talk about some of the
deterrence issues and some things we we
talked a little very little about the
turns today and how the diffusion power
impacts the turns so I'd like to hear
your opinions on you know what how are
the changing strategies in your
respective countries with respect this
diffusion of power so Japan has
published a new defense strategy I liked
a little bit about the the south korean
defense strategy and how they are
reacting to to the changes we're seeing
in a Fed landscape South Korea is it's
realizing the importance of cyber
security and intelligence of course and
it's trying to get more active on these
cyber corporations but I think in this
to be more the government needs to state
more stronger organization to put off
first and then reach other intelligence
agencies to cooperate and then share
information more and then stuff like
that and then for I think for the
lessons taken from the mixing TTP's with
other countries like North Korea does um
NATO should be the first to be the
baseline to make other nations to join
their information sharing system to get
more bigger and more massive a system of
like sharing information to get be
trusted and then to make deterrence for
the actions something like the mixing
TTP's cannot be happened anymore
even when they are attributed we can
counteract with more strong intelligence
with the sharing information so so Japan
not only to have a successful Tokyo
Summer Olympic Games and Paralympic
Games in 2020 but also to to have to
play important role in the international
cyber security community
so the Japanese government and also
Japanese industry are taking important
steps so for example the Japanese
Ministry depends on self-defense forces
issued a new national defense guidelines
program in the last year's to
specifically mention the cross sector
across domain of security and importance
of our cyber security but not only that
the Ministry economy and Trade and
Industry and Ministry of Internal
Affairs and communications are creating
the guidelines for IOT security and also
cyber security guidelines for
specifically for each sector in critical
infrastructure sectors and also then the
industries are helping to provide early
life experiences and also to to make it
happen we have to have a good
cybersecurity people so we are
cooperating with academia and the
government to have a good ecosystem or
two to cultivate cybersecurity
professionals so I think that is being a
multi-layered efforts to have a good
people good technologies and good
processes to have a better deterrence in
cyberspace I would like to offer my
thoughts on you know I listen to this
conference yesterday and this is the
u.s. strategy on PE I think he's
persistent engagement and then DF is the
defence forward so so you know I've been
thinking through this you know over the
course of yesterday and also today I
think we have to be very careful when it
comes to you know this idea of defending
forward okay
I hope the United States do not do so by
let's say removing that sovereignty rule
like the the the violation of
sovereignty rule because I think it has
you know really bad consequences if they
did that right so now it may sound like
a really great idea that the United
States can say okay you know this Isis
group let's say there's no rule call
sovereignty in place
okay these Isis guys you know they have
cyber assets in different parts of the
war we can go in there and we can just
take them out okay we could mean damage
their stuff blow things up whatever
right and that may sound like a really
great thing until China comes in and say
hey we also have terrorists that you
know we like to address to we have
dissidents from the cynjohn province
that we've got pro-democracy people in
Taiwan and they have cyber assets in the
US and then cable and then Indonesia
comes along and say hey you know you
know we have a terrorist group called
jamya
Islamia that we like to take out and
they have cyber assets in the United
States - and both Indonesia and China
say hey if the u.s. can do defend
forward we should also do defend forward
and they say well let's you know let's
defend forward and break stuff in the
United States and so when you don't have
a rule like that in place it's going to
lead to very bad consequences because in
the war of diffusion of power you know
we're you know not that US can just do
that
the Chinese can do that the in donations
can do that then we can have a big
problem going forward right so this is
you know I think we have to be very
clear now of course the the question
then becomes if you had a rule called
sovereignty is that an absolute rule
does that mean you cannot do anything at
all and that's entirely not true right
so if anyone is reading the Italian
manual you should refer to rule number
four okay rule number four talks about
you know the sovereignty issue and how
do we dissect you know what you can or
you cannot do within the sovereignty
rule right so I would urge you to look
into for and really the discussion going
forward is couldn't be States thinking
it okay we have to rule in place we need
to come into an agreement as to what is
permissible and what is not permissible
okay
and so and I think that's that is super
important going forward
thank you any last questions or comments
well then on this very high narrow
thank you also for Mikey oh sorry there
is a there's someone in the back
apologies
sorry I promise it's quick please with
cyber law international I have a
question for a cocking and for miss
matzah bottom so you both come from the
private sector and past years cyber
incidents have clearly demonstrated how
companies can end up being tangled and
interstate Affairs so what do your
respective companies what kind of
expectations do they have towards
governments in order to ensure that your
companies do not become the victim of
such malicious cyber activity and should
this happen
especially those very high end
devastating operations what kind of
expectations would you have towards your
government to mitigate you may be
compensate what would your corporations
expect of your respective governments at
least you ask all the hot question to
have a better cybersecurity you have to
have a good visibility because if you
don't have a good visibility how you can
control your risks so to make it happen
before the industry you know that you
you have to raise cybersecurity
awareness especially from the executive
levels and it's been already happening
in Japan and now you also have to have
continuous dialogues between government
and the private sectors because
government is responsible to the having
practical cybersecurity strategy or
recreations or policy and by the
government the judges and companies have
better visibility and access to
technologies and also the problem is
happening in industries so I'm pleased
to see that neither these conversations
are happening between the Japanese
government and industry and of course we
will continue to see different types of
cyberattacks and risks around Japanese
government in the industry but now I'm
sure am I'm certain that Japan can
corroborate with
like-minded
countries and also NATO's to meet to
have a better cyber deterrence on the
cyber defense thank you I have to wrap
up unfortunately here I don't want to
get in trouble with the uniformed guys
here at the native CCD series so join me
in thanking the rest of the panel for
the presentation