generals official indeed gentlemen it is
a great pleasure to be with you again
ere and immediately I beg your pardon
for my French accents today after six
years at the aid of the French zebra
defense as the first calm summer and
then two years as general director of
the digital information and data for the
friend reserve defense I can measure the
progress we have made in your French
Estonian corporation notably within the
center of excellence that so the reason
why I am honoured to contribute to this
conference Estonian is for us the most
advanced country in Europe in terms of
digital technology once again I would
like to act like an acknowledge the work
done by Estonia during his time as
president of the European Union and its
influence on International Forum today I
can only observe the digital society is
on the move
observes an Estonian is Europe's
Laboratory in jazz new digital societies
and that the Data revolution is
preparing us for it consequently we must
foresee the structure of those societies
and erect security and confidence as
component of its DNA data is a
cornerstone of all your challenge
whether we are talking about cyber big
data cloud or artificial intelligence in
this field Estonia is opinion for
instance explode is mentioned as an
example in France by authorities notably
by the Secretary of State for digital
technology the 2010 were intelligence
and espionage times then the are aware
of the case such strokes net or coffee
curve shows us
that sabotage attacks we're accessible
is in a targeted or a general way in
2014 we have pasted dice propaganda with
disabilities and fragmented war
societies whether in Europe or elsewhere
and we work the real war through the use
of reference cyber forces against this
propaganda today I am happy to say that
a french-language propaganda has
declined considerably and that the
armoured forces that ladies files were
able to hand over to the internal
security forces at least for French
language propaganda we also saw the
emergence of erected interferences in
elections attributed to the results then
the issue of fake news became one of the
deck national team stems or yoga with
leaders we are therefore a new new era
of conflict that can no longer be a nerd
friends like many other states are fully
taken it in a new account in this view
military capacity has been created it
will have 3,000 expect today and three
four thousand and five hundred by 2022
in comparisons the aspect where less
than 300 in 2011 at the each of those
forces we have an operational command
the calm cyber well step by step since
2011 it has allowed it has a large scale
of experts and many other operations in
which they are engaged whether in
support of intervention is a sale muddy
or in the Levant Syria and Iran for the
protection or difference of all networks
and against propaganda and we talk to
say that cyber we have been yet
I'm seeing extremely important until
2020 2015 and 16 is taking on a new
dimension until 2015 in France the focus
was on attacks of information system
that were inside your structures I think
that we must look forward to the
channels of data security and data
Trust's we are facing two new
revolutions we'll be needing unknown and
we took and which took off with the
explosion of Technology first we cannot
talk about Austin without talking about
cloud notable data processing without
talking about artificial intelligence
there are the challenges that are
emerging so I think it is important here
in Terran at the sacrum to look at the
road travel and the one that remains to
be travelled this journey particularly
and ply to review the notion of
sovereignty and therefore we can see
alongside sovereign states that digital
have arrays are your borders we have
seen the arrival of major players who
are almost at the same level of power as
States well surprisingly the other
gavin's with warm which are common
values however we cannot enjoy the
emergence of other major players notably
Chinese players with one we do not share
the same culture or visual of mankind or
even the same notion of democracy taught
as far as a government is concerned
there is a certain shared vision of
progress it's a middle in the middle is
Europe with us it's out culture it
interesting to note that this is not the
first time in history that eternal
transnational corporations with which
our experiences wrong loss through trod
of
the power of states as so the energy
because a digital world and the Maritim
world seems to me to speak for itself
thud start with the cargo transported
nowadays cargo is a data at the 18th
century the big shaping companies like
the East India Company the French one
but associate Lee the British one were
almost as powerful as Kingdom but this
phenomenon was then regulated by analogy
I think we are at the stage states and
just large company must work together to
get to know each other better and
understand that mutual expectation also
we can consider that data have become a
sovereign common good Thurid by all
citizens and by the respective nation
First Nations sir shall protect data
acreage new means to do so data
protection not limited to the general
data protection regulation should be
constructed by laws taxes cryptographic
means and by Osaka read digital borders
in a matter of third digital borders are
two strings of partners relationship in
data and adorn which matters they will
find the roots in am indeed social
contract when the main parties are
states web players and citizens then the
implication is term of strategic
autonomy the drive server and digital is
above disabled above all trust Trust is
by by two main elements is a one and
security it is miserable
today we can say that such security of
government is as well unsure at that of
many states indeed the old data centers
they are transatlantic links they have
them our cryptology and the order of
servers in conclusion they are serenity
worthy of a state over all part of the
digital space
the second element to be taken in
consideration is a community of
destinies between the partners do we
have trusted partners this is going
beyond security aspect today between
Arab of France and Microsoft Amazon of
Google the question is how can this
company B's trusted partners other
concern about your strategy or strategic
autonomy other concerned about
preserving the personal data of all the
citizens do the distinguish between a
citizen and a customer this is a
fundamental distinction because we are
in a democracy well we shall not only
find customers but above our friend
citizens was dignity must be respected
just questions our stake and will
reflect our reflect on the relationship
between states and the major web players
at least for those with transit rhotic
values value Sharon for very long term
your American friends Gotham and argue
merge they learn to work together to
work better together to work together
and to respect citizen personal data and
dignity the first duty of a sovereign
state it was different this territory
and jeribai defend his sovereignty
Nevada ISM start shall increase as one
of the first duties the difference of
citizens that are in extension of
cytosines defense
that that protection misery for be
proteins were fulfilled by all states a
business subject of indeed work but
politician in order to move away from a
purely commercial approach if you are
already experiencing difficulty in
cooperation between Europeans and
Americans Gotham it is important to be
fully aware of the tsunami represented
by the illiberal of new bazarov players
in this field namely the Chinese with
one we shall very few common values in
particular the way in which citizens are
viewed we must therefore act on this
huge challenge may evolve or accelerate
your cooperation
finally in order to come back to a
military area that directly concern us
within military coalition one of the
imperatives each mutual is neutral and
reciprocal trust to watch each other
towards each other this trust implies
that the decision is not best to do so
it is necessary to wrestle your partners
of the origin of data and the way in
which algorithm which can be bending of
the members of a coalition have been
developed and trained is it is therefore
extremely important regarding artificial
intelligence and big data beyond beyond
Austin storing data to a formal side and
knowledge of the data producer it's
equally important to be able to assume
to ensure that the data are available
that they are not they have not been
gazed and that they are not provide to
serve the strategic interest of only one
of the partners in the coalition
moreover when this data are processed it
will algorithm it is also crucial to
know who is doing it and what data
it has been trained with an algorithm
trained with desert data will inevitably
lead to better decision to conclude to
conclude the way we possess more data a
way of answering trust with the military
coalition which will be one of the main
area of works for the Center for the
Terran center of excellence in the
future when Boeing's together all the
nation interested in this field this
work revolving about the data and
supporters in an its process may ensure
the best transition from system similar
security to a trusted data revolution
thank you for attention
[Applause]