well thank you very much for the
opportunity to speak with you for a few
minutes today and what I was hoping to
do today is to update this group on the
work that Microsoft has done in the year
since my colleague John Frank had an
opportunity to address you a year ago as
well as to talk about some of our
thoughts about what we need to do to be
successful in this space going forward I
don't need to convince this group of the
real empowerment that technology brings
to citizens and communities around the
world whether we're talking about
communication creativity productivity
there's just such a wide range of ways
in which the technology can advance the
welfare of our citizens and that with
the advent of cloud computing the
opportunity for that is really limitless
but we see and we fear that the dark
side of technology can impose
limitations on the ability of the world
to really benefit from the opportunities
of Technology again there's no one in
this audience who isn't aware of both of
these key considerations nation-state
attacks and cyber crime for profit and
how they both are continued to grow
and to be very impactful on citizens and
communities around the world and what
we've seen in the trend especially in
the last year is that the lines between
these two have continued to blur as
we've seen increasingly that there are
whether you think of them as mercenary
organizations state control
organizations sometimes it's hard
especially for those of us in the
private sector to really know but we see
the same activity groups engaging in
espionage activity in nation
state-sponsored attacks but also in
efforts to simply steal money and
working in that way and we see that
increasingly among all of the rogue
nations that are engaged in activity
that we think is is reprehensible and
just for a moment to talk about
nation-state attacks and the evolution
of those attacks there's a couple of key
lessons here you know starting with the
early attacks like the the DDoS attack
on Estonia in 2007 and the Stuxnet
attack which actually showed that a
nation-state could reach across the
border you
using cyber and no kinetic effort at all
can influence an exam extend its power
and authority across the geographic
border to actually disabled nuclear
centrifuges and these lessons have been
learned by the nation states that engage
in these attacks and you see over time
how this is evolved from those kinds of
targeted destructions to massive data
exfiltration to the supply chain attacks
that we see today becoming much more
sophisticated including things like the
not pecchì attack where the adversaries
recognize that by infiltrating the
update system of a popular software
package they could quickly gain trust
and get their malware distributed
broadly throughout an entire country and
then of course through all of the
commercial enterprises that had
activities in that country causing
billions of dollars in economic damage
we see attacks on critical
infrastructure and how that continues to
evolve and is a significant concern for
governments around the world and then as
we get more current evolutions you've
seen things like the evolution of
espionage and attacks for a service with
for-profit companies operating quite
openly and supplying these kinds of
weapons and exploits to governments that
don't have the resources to do it
themselves and in we now are clearly on
the edge of seeing machine learning and
and AI technologies being brought to
bear not just on the defense side but on
the side of the attackers and what they
can do to improve the the scope
effectiveness and power of their attacks
and what's significant about this and
what you see in just slightly over a
decade in terms of the evolution of how
nations are using cyber to engage in
these attacks and I'm not just talking
about the kinds of espionage that there
are traditional activities of the
government that we have to anticipate
will continue to be traditional
activities of government but really
attacks that harm citizens and
enterprises in times of peace that's
something that's really unique and I've
heard many speakers talk about how
that's operating under the threshold of
armed conflict but two recent
developments are of interest here one is
just this month when a cyber attack
against Israel resulted in a kinetic
response with Israel bombing the
location from which they had identified
that that cyber attack by Hamas had
emanated that is a concern I know for
governments around the world
when will cyber attacks and the
influence of cyber attacks result in
kinetic responses and it's just to see
that happening of course in reality
which raises the visibility of that
concern for us all so what I'd like to
spend my time today talking about is
what is Microsoft doing what have we
done in the past year in our efforts to
address these issues to raise visibility
to encourage dialogue and to actually
encourage action to to to try to bring a
greater sense of security to cyberspace
so one of the things we've done is we've
taken action to disrupt nation-state
actors we've actually done this three
times with legal process and once with a
purely technological effort in which we
have now targeted nation-state actors
operating from North Korea from China
most recently from Iran and probably our
most intensive effort has been to to
wrestle with a nation-state actor from
Russia one that we call strontium it's
also known as apt 28 or fancy bear but
this is the group that was responsible
for a lot of the efforts to influence
the u.s. presidential election in 2016
the the Mueller investigation resulted
in a very specific and very interesting
indictment against the individuals
responsible for some of this activity
but Microsoft have engaged in a legal
battle with strontium now for a couple
of years starting in 2016 when we saw
strontium registering fake domains using
our trademarks and trade names and the
trade names of other technology
companies as the basis for conducting
the infrastructure for a lot of their
attacks
and so we went to court treated this
nation state actor like a botnet we're
my team are my digital Crimes Unit at
Microsoft is really the world leader in
disrupting and taking down for-profit
cybercrime botnets and we took the same
legal approach went to court and got
orders transferring to our sinkhole this
long list of domains that strontium was
using to conduct its operations and we
also constantly watch their operations
that is called out here we saw it
announced earlier this year the
targeting by strontium of organizations
that seem to be associated with the
democratic processes in six different EU
countries and we notified those targets
so they were aware and could take steps
to protect themselves but the activity
of strontium is not focused just on the
US but it's focused on processes around
the world and so what we have managed to
do with in 12 different times going to
court is we've taken down to eighty four
domains used by strontium and we
actually have one we just got another
order we're about to execute on to take
down several more domains by strontium
we don't pretend that this activity is
going to stop what strontium is doing
there to well-resourced
they're too much of an important part of
the strategy of Russia to engage in this
kind of activity but what it does is it
does add some friction we have seen that
strontium is much less frequently using
Microsoft domains as part of its domain
structure for its infrastructure which
means that much less frequently our
customers are deceived by strontium into
thinking that the communication they're
having with those domains is really
communication with us or some of the
other technology companies that have
given us permission to police this
activity by this organization on their
behalf so so we have had that impact
we've also as a result gotten quite a
bit of data about the organization
that's that strontium has effectively
compromised and we've been able to
advise those organizations the fact that
they have been infected by strontium so
they could take action to clean their
environment but much more needs to be
done this is just our effort to say what
can we do
with the relatively limited resources
that we have to bring to bear to this
effort to try to do some disruption and
to let these actors know that we are
interested in stopping their activity
when they're targeting citizens and
enterprises in times of peace in
addition to that activity of course as I
think you all know we've been very
active on the public policy side on
trying to work to develop the norms and
the principles that governments will
live by in cyberspace and there's some
reason for progress there's been
progress in the past year and reason for
hope in addition to all of these
different as part of all of these
different efforts that have been engaged
in the past year and that are going to
be going forward with the the two
different UN processes in later this
year in in coming years we were
particularly gratified to have the
opportunity to assist the French
government in its effort to develop the
Paris call for trust insecurity in
cyberspace when we heard that the French
government was making this effort we
joined with them to advocate for
governments for for civil society and
for technology companies around the
world to come together and endorse these
principles as a step of pulling together
a truly multi-stakeholder voice
supporting these key principles of
cybersecurity and it's interesting we
did some work to chart out the nine
principles of the Paris call because
each one of them is derived from a
previous governmental statement of some
kind about principles or norms of
cybersecurity and it's interesting to
see how some of those have been repeated
in different ways over the years some
were relatively new but we found all
nine of these principles to be key
aspects of what we need to do to
preserve the security protect the
security of the cyber world much more
needs to be done and we are hopeful that
we will find the opportunity to join
together with other interested parties
in this in a set of communities that
will take each of these principles and
say what can we do with each of these
principles what needs to be done to
to move them forward into international
law what needs to be done so that we can
actually have deterrence for those who
seek to violate these principles there's
much that needs to be done to make more
of the Paris call and not let it just
stop with this endorsement but the
endorsement itself is very important 65
countries have been signed the the Paris
call principals but over five hundred
and fifty different entities between
civil society the technology industry
and governments have signed the paris
call the largest multi-stakeholder
statement of cybersecurity principles
ever we need to take that momentum and
use it to develop more in terms of what
we can do to take those principles and
make them real and make them effective
and not just a statement and so we're
committed to working with other
interested parties in developing these
communities to continue the discussion
and move forward because as you could
see from that evolution of cyberattacks
the one thing that we know for sure is
our adversaries are not spending times
at spending their time at important
conferences like this saikhan conference
they're not spending their time
wordsmithing
the precise words to be used in stating
a norm they're not spending their time
thinking about how do we transfer those
those those norms into effective
international law and how do we then
move from international law to actual
deterrence they are simply taking action
and they're evolving quickly and they're
moving quickly and so as a community we
need to increase the pace of our
activity increase our resolve to combat
those adversaries by moving in the
appropriate ways in the ways that we are
with thoughtful discussion but we need
to move forward more quickly into
deterrence and that's why we support the
United States defend forward effort that
it's engaged in with as we understand it
many allies because we think that we do
need to find a way to create deterrence
so that the nation states who today
operate with really no consequence
whatsoever begin to recognize that
misbehavior in cyberspace isn't
free isn't free and there's not freedom
of action but with all of this work that
we've done and the work we've done to
support the Paris call the work that we
do at Microsoft to work with governments
around the world on how we can
strengthen cybersecurity we also
recognize that the first responsibility
lies with industry the cyber that this
as a domain of conflict cyberspace is
unique and we heard this from a couple
of the keynotes yesterday because it is
the creation of private industry it is
maintained by private industry and it's
evolved by private industry and that
means we also have the responsibility to
ensure to the best of our ability the
security of cyberspace and so one of the
things that we thought we should do and
you heard about this last year was try
to bring together the technology
community to endorse core principles of
cyber security because somewhat
surprisingly you did not see the
industry itself coming together to agree
on core principles so we established the
cybersecurity tech Accord and the tech
Accord we just asked technology
companies to stand up for four key
principles first that we would do what
we could with our engineering and our
process to protect our users and
customers everywhere secondly that we
would not support in any way government
efforts to develop weapons or launch
weapons that target innocent civilians
and enterprises in times of peace third
that we would work with our customers
and governments around the world to
increased cybersecurity resiliency and
finally that we would work together for
how we could respond to cyber attacks
more quickly and more effectively and we
started with just over 30 signatories to
that to the tech Accord on when was
launched a year ago and i think i think
john frank mentioned this at his speech
but today we have over a hundred and six
companies from around the world from 21
countries that have endorsed the tech
accord and i'm pleased to say given the
leadership of estonia in the
cybersecurity space that one of the
signatories is guard time
one of the companies spaced here in
estonia
but not only do we have a hundred and
six signatories and the number continues
to grow as the technology industry
recognizes the importance of these four
key principles but I'm very gratified to
see that that organization has moved
beyond something that Microsoft
originally inspired to an organization
that is acting very much on its own
behalf to address key issues of
cybersecurity policy and to endorse
those that we as a community a tech
community a global tech community think
should be adopted and expanded globally
and we also are working on what we can
do as a technology industry so for
example right now there's an effort
within the tech Accord to make sure that
we all have endorsed our processes for
coordinated vulnerability disclosure so
these companies increasingly as I meet
with governments in North America South
America Europe and Asia
I find that governments increasingly are
pleased to see that we have now a voice
for the technology community on cyber
security that they can turn to to ask
and query what does not just a single
technology company but the global
technology industry think about these
cybersecurity principles there's one
other thing that I want to address in
the time I've got remaining which is the
defending democracy program this is a
program that my team launched a year ago
and that I am really excited about it
was inspired of course by the activity
we saw of our adversaries attacking
democratic principles and not just in
the US but in the in France right after
the 2016 election we saw activity in
many other countries around the world
we've seen efforts to actually disrupt
the democratic process and it's not I
think it's less important to our
adversaries that they actually favor a
candidate or another candidate it's more
a part of their strategy to simply erode
the confidence of the citizens in the
democratic process itself and to create
conflict on key issues in the countries
where democracy prevails and we've seen
them be incredibly effective with their
disinformation campaigns and their other
efforts to influence
the vote and we've learned more and more
over the last few years about how close
the Russian adversaries in particular
came to actually impacting the vote in
the United States and their efforts to
hack the voting systems of the US so we
created the defending democracy program
focused on these three core pillars what
can we do what can Microsoft do uniquely
and bring to the community to the two
democracies of the world to support
election integrity the security of the
campaign's themselves and to combat
disinformation and we started with this
thing we called account guard I'm a
count guard was an effort to increase
the security of the campaign's where we
told any political campaign but also a
wide variety of associated organizations
that if they were office 365 customers
so that we had visibility into efforts
to attack them if they signed up for
account guard we would notify them of
any threatened attack by a nation-state
actor or any compromise by a
nation-state actor and in addition to
that we would conduct cybersecurity
seminars we would help the campaign's
understand how to operate in a secure
way and we would help them in the event
that they were compromised
as to how to solve their problem and
continue on securely we started in the
United States we then came to an of
countries in Europe we went to Australia
India and we recently expanded to
another number of other countries in
Europe we now cover 26 countries we've
had 36,000 separate campaign accounts
that have signed up for this account
guard and we've made many notifications
of nation-state attacks on those
organizations that has been a big
success for us but it isn't nearly
enough and we learned through this
process and if there's one thing that
I've been in my career at Microsoft
that's really enthused me about the
company is our willingness to learn too
as we try something and we get feedback
and we learn more than we we change we
evolve what we're doing to try to make
it more effective and we did that in
this case because we learned that as
good as a count guard was we were
constrained by the fact that office 365
was too expensive for campaigns which
often operate on very thin
budgets and it was too hard to deploy
securely so we have now announced
Microsoft 365 for campaigns and this is
an offering of our commercial Microsoft
EMM 365 service which has all our most
advanced security services included but
we are offering it to the same group of
organizations associated with campaigns
and democracies at our nonprofit price
which is a very very significant
discount and it's coming pre-configured
with Wizards that enable even
unsophisticated IT staff for campaigns
to easily deploy M 365 in a highly
secure way for the campaign process and
so that's our next step to trying to
help protect the campaign process itself
and we will be that's being launched now
this summer initially in the United
States but again we expect to make it
available in many other democracies
around the world and while I'm excited
by that because I think it will help us
help protect campaigns we've spent the
last year working on a project that we
just announced to really protect the
vote itself a program that we call
election guard and election guard is an
open source free software development
kit that we're gonna make available as a
project on github for everyone to help
us evolve it to improve it to make it
more effective
but what election guard is is a software
development kit that enables the
application of sophisticated technology
to provide a verifiable encrypted vote
so that the voter goes to the polling
place and votes and their vote is
encrypted and that encryption is
maintained the vote gets counted the
voter gets a receipt that they can then
use to go online and check and see that
their vote was properly counted and was
not tampered with but more importantly
than that the SDK enables voting
officials voting watchdogs journalists
or other interested parties to build
their own verifier app based on the sdk
so that they can look to
see that the vote was properly counted
and not tampered with now the
combination of encryption and the other
security features were building into the
SDK should make it very hard for an
adversary to hack the system but we know
that very hard and absolute are two
different things we don't pretend that
it's not hackable but what we are a
certain of is that if there's an effort
to tamper with the vote or the vote
count using election guard that effort
will be visible and known to the
election officials and in the way that
we are proposing it there would be paper
ballot backup that could be used you
could do the risk limiting audit which
is supported by this SDK or just
actually count paper ballots to ensure
the integrity of the vote we're going to
be making this available as I said as an
open source free effort this summer and
this summer we will also be creating and
providing for public inspection a
demonstration prototype of the kind of
very simple voting machine that can be
created from off-the-shelf inexpensive
components to enable this to occur so
that it's less expensive for voting
officials it's much much more secure and
it's also more accessible because we can
use this with accessibility components
so that so that people who are
challenged by using paper ballots today
will have the ability to vote and then
confirm the accuracy of their vote you
know I'm sorry just very quickly a video
on this topic suggested that a majority
of the country did not have confidence
that in fact votes would be counted and
counted accurately voter participation
is about confidence in the vote and to
be able to cast your vote and know that
was being counted properly the election
guard technology starts with our
software development
the voters vote remains encrypted
throughout the process in addition to
printing your ballot it prints a ballot
tracker that has on it a cryptographic
code any interested party can take our
open-source technology and look at the
vote as a whole and verify that it was
properly accounted there's so much
passion around these issues and watching
that come together to actually improve
our security it's extraordinary
[Music]
so I'm out of time but with all of this
work that we've done and that all of you
in this room have done looking to the
future we Microsoft remain committed to
our efforts to advance the cause of
cybersecurity defining the right Public
Policy the right rules of law to apply
the right ways of having a consensus
across the cybersecurity community as to
what rules of government should apply
and how we can deter the rogue nations
that insist on violating those rules we
will continue to apply our technology
and our advocacy to these goals and I
really appreciate all the effort by the
organization here to maintain this
conference which is one of the best
conferences to bring together so many
different voices around the world to
share our information that this the
panels yesterday we're great I look
forward to the ones today and I thank
you for your time
[Applause]