everyone for joining us this is an
exciting session and I think although
even though we're in just the first day
of saikhan it wouldn't be premature for
us to congratulate CCDC OE on yet
another superb event if like me you're a
follower of their event and and their
work mmm you'll know that the subject of
this panel has been one of a consistent
strain throughout their events the
problem of attribution if you look at
the early versions of the event I think
which you see are relatively siloed or
stove-piped approaches to attribution
early on I think the various communities
involved in cybersecurity
each realized they had perhaps a
peculiar or particular perspective that
is from the technicians there was I
think a logical focus on the digital
forensics that are involved in a cyber
attribution effort from the from the
political track of course there was
interest in the political will or the
diplomatic climate that surrounds an
effort to do a cyber attribution and
then finally the community that I come
from that I'm most familiar with
we international lawyers explored what
attribution meant to us and of course I
think cyberspace and and the the
conversations we've seen ATS icons have
to some extent resurrected our interest
in the articles of state responsibility
how international law and how states
have agreed to assign responsibility for
internationally wrongful acts this has
led to us I think two helpful
discussions and elaborations on notions
like control what does wielding
effective control over a non-state actor
mean how can States assign
responsibilities among organizations in
a way that holds them responsible under
applicable international law but there's
a flaw of course to these stove-piped
efforts or these siloed efforts it seems
to do the to do the real work of
attribution requires an intersectional
effort that these are cross-disciplinary
efforts and so in that vein
we have presentations from three
panelists that I think will emphasize
that the theme you will find in each is
an effort on the part of an
international lawyer in each case or a
policymaker
to weave together the technical the
political and the legal elements of
attribution so I'm very much looking
forward to their presentations we'll
begin with MS Lee's vakul Lee's is the
chief executive officer at cyber law
international she's also a member of the
Estonian delegation to the United
Nations group of government experts and
finally she is an ambassador and an
alumna of the CCDC OE itself and Li's of
course was managing editor of the
Tallinn manual 2.0 on international law
applicable to cyber operations Li's the
floor is all yours
Thank You Sean ladies and gentlemen good
afternoon welcome to this session and
attribution indeed as someone who spent
several years working at the CCD theory
it's always a distinct pleasure to come
back to saikhan to come back to an event
that really feels like home today what
I'm going to talk about is how
international law standards governing
the issue of attribution how they apply
in the cyber context and then secondly
if into what extent the international
law standards affect the policy
attribution of malicious cyber activity
so without further ado I'll just get
straight to the topic first of all to
understand how law of X policy I should
briefly tell you about how international
law regulates the issue of attribution
and in law attribution is actually a
two-step process the first step involves
identifying what the legal standards for
attribution are and there are several
and international law I'll briefly go
over those and then the second step in
the international law of attribution is
to apply the law to the facts in other
words it's the evidentiary question
with regard to the first step like I
mentioned there are several bases for
regarding acts of certain entities as
those of states under international law
the ground rule the most common the most
uncontroversial rule is that when we
have what are called organs of states
acting then their actions their cyber
activities are attributable to a state
what are organs organs are entities that
make up the governmental structure of a
state so if you wear a uniform you're an
organ of a state when you engage in
malicious cyber activity that violates
international law your state has
violated international law if you work
for the Minister of Defense if you work
for the Minister of Foreign Affairs
you work for a cyber center of
excellence or a national cert then your
actions qualify as actions of an organ
of a state therefore they're
attributable and if you through your
actions engage in some sort of conduct
that is in breach of international legal
obligations then your country has
violated international law the other
test has got somewhat of a clumsy
articulation it has to do with entities
that are empowered by law to exercise
elements of governmental authority the
first two tests are based on an
institutional link and the second one
the entities empowered by law these have
to do with certain parastatal entities
that engage in governmental functions in
the non cyber context we will talk about
private military companies in the cyber
context for example the cyber security
firm that does intelligence for a state
and as you know some cyber security
companies have a very close relationship
with a particular government they do
intelligence for the state employees
hold high-level security clearances so
in such a situation we might have an
entity that is empowered by law even
though actually it's a private company
to carry out governmental governmental
functions and therefore that entity's
actions are attributable if the entity
the cyber security firm Inc
is an intelligence collection and
excessively infringes upon the privacy
of individuals it is actually the state
that has violated international law and
then finally the third third common
basis for attribution has to do with a
factual link between a state and a
non-state actor and the rule goes as
follows if you're a state and you're
instructing directing or controlling a
non-state actor to engage in malicious
cyber activity then that actors
activities are attributable to you so
that's the law in a nutshell very
simplified but these are the key legal
bases for attribution in international
law now the second question really has
to do with applying the law to the facts
like I mentioned and this is especially
relevant in the cyber context because as
you will know States very rarely will
have absolute certainty that indeed an
organ of a state was behind a malicious
cyber activity or that a state indeed
was instructing a private company to
engage in malicious cyber activity so
the legal question for us is how much
evidence is enough evidence what does
the law say about that how well do the
facts need to be established and here it
is important to distinguish between
different purposes of attribution
because the rules are somewhat different
one purpose of attribution are to be an
emerging practice of attribution is to
name and shame other States for having
engaged in cyber operations that violate
international law to my knowledge only
one state has done so it was the United
Kingdom in October last year when they
attributed several cyber operations to
the Russian GRU and there the UK
national cyber security center said that
those operations without specifying
which ones constitute a flagrant
violation of international law to my
knowledge this is the only example of a
state naming and shaming another country
for having violated international law
how much proof does the country accusing
the other state
in violating international law you need
to have what the answer is
the state as a strict matter of law
doesn't need to have any proof
international it doesn't prohibit lying
so the state may even be making up this
claim without it being a violation of
international law for rule of law
countries of course this is something
that I personally would not anticipate I
would not anticipate them going out with
those fake statements and this was also
confirmed last April by the ambassador
for cyber affairs of Australia he said
that we wouldn't be saying these things
in the international environment just
for the fun of it it's the fact that we
have evidence to prove that this
activity is attributed to you to you so
this is the practice of states but
international law doesn't require States
to have any level of confidence in the
facts for the for the simple purpose of
naming and shaming the situation is
somewhat different when it comes to what
are known as measures of unilateral
self-help and those of you who were in
the deterrence panel you heard some of
them being mentioned for example the
inherent right of states to engage in
self defense is a measure of self-help
the right to engage in countermeasures
or the right to respond to cyber
operations based upon the clear
necessity these are measures of
self-help and with regard to the
exercise of self-help international law
is perhaps even surprisingly
accommodating of the concern that states
will not have 100 percent certainty when
it comes to the attribution issue for
the right of self-defense for example
most international law scholars would
say well the standard is we ask what
would a reasonable state in the same or
similar circumstances conclude about the
author of the operation what would a
reasonable state conclude about
attribution and if it is reasonable for
a state that is suffering from a cyber
armed attack and you should know that
this is a very high threshold if the
state is faced with such a national
security threat does the state need to
have out
certainty with regard to the attribution
issue answer is no we asked what is it
reasonable for the state to conclude as
to the author of the operation the rules
are yet different for judicial
proceedings we haven't seen it yet but
I'm certain somewhere down the road this
is going to happen we're a cyber dispute
will appear before an international
court or tribunal the International
Court of Justice for example if the ICJ
were to hear a cyber dispute the court
would apply its own standard of proof
for the ICJ it's going to be somewhere
between beyond a reasonable doubt and
clear and convincing evidence somewhere
along this spectrum for an International
Criminal Court in a criminal tribunal
the standard will be beyond a reasonable
doubt so the standards will vary
depending on the court or tribunal that
we're talking about and then finally
since most disputes between states are
settled outside of court they're settled
in negotiations then if States were to
sit down at a table and negotiate a
cyber dispute the standard of proof that
will apply will be whatever the the
parties to the dispute to decide it may
be the preponderance of evidence facts
are more likely this than not so really
the standard of evidence in
international law will depend on what
kind of attribution are we talking about
what is the purpose of the attribution
so this is international law
what does policy say what are we seeing
States do with regard to policy
attribution I've arbitrarily picked
three statements where states have
accused other states of having engaged
in malicious cyber activity and
statements that also articulate the
level of confidence of the accusing
state and you'll see that in 2016 the US
government for examples that the
intelligence community said that they
were confident that it was Russia who
interfered
in the Democratic National Committee's
communications and released them the UK
is the national cybersecurity center two
years ago in December 2017 said it was
highly likely that one a cry was
attributable to North Korea and the same
Center in the UK said that the GRU was
almost certainly responsible for the
various cyber operations that were
attributed to the GRU and the national
cybersecurity center made that
assessment with high confidence finally
you'll see that in the US the Office of
the Director of National Intelligence
has put out guidance on what certain
confidence levels mean and you'll see
that high confidence really is a very
high confidence level indeed high
confidence for the odni is proof beyond
a reasonable doubt without a reasonable
alternative that's a very high standard
and moderate confidence is also to my
eyes a very high standard clear and
convincing with no circumstantial cases
for alternatives so these are very very
high standards the point that I'm trying
to get to is that policy experts are
often very careful to emphasize that
political attribution statements like
these are solely political
determinations and law doesn't play much
of a role in those determinations it is
true unless we're talking about a state
accusing another state of having
violated international law but as you'll
see as you just seen States even for
political attribution require a very
high level of confidence in the facts
they as a matter of political practice
employ a very high standard of proof
before they go out and accuse another
state of having to engage the malicious
cyber activity so perhaps the concern
about mixing law and policy at least
when it comes to public attributions is
a bit overstated
now when states attribute cyber
activities in the policy sense they
don't just say a state did it but they
also make sure to condemn the cyber
activity here again I have three
arbitrary examples from last year three
different countries accusing other
states of having engaged in a bad
behavior in cyberspace and what is
interesting here is the language that
they employ when you take a careful look
at those statements can you see that the
wording is very very careful it's very
laid back it's not categorical Estonians
saying that Russia is called on tact
responsibly and in accordance with
international law Australia says that
Russia is acting contrary to the
consensus and international law and
norms the Netherlands the GRU was
undermining international law so these
are very opaque very vague statements
they're not horribly specific so the
question that I ask is why are we not
seeing States come out with more
concrete accusations why are they not
saying that country acts violated
international law in particular rule
acts as well as three rules on this
responsible state behavior which are the
following so why are we not seeing
States do that probably one of the
reasons is that US states apply
international law and norms of
responsible state behavior in this
domain they are acutely aware of the
fact that they are engaged in a
balancing act and this means that as
rule of law countries are investing
heavily into cyber capability
development they are cognizant that once
they start drawing the lines in the sand
they are not only creating rules for
other countries but they're also
creating rules for themselves and
they're careful not to prematurely tie
their own hands also rule of law
countries I suspect are take account
take into account the fact that when
they draw those clearer lines
then their adversaries are not
necessarily rule of law countries
so in effect countries are creating
rules for themselves that their
adversaries are unlikely to follow I
personally find this a troubling
consideration why especially in today's
international security environment which
is which is very flammable which is very
worrisome I think States should not walk
back on the norms a normative order but
rather enforce the normative order
insist on a rule space the cyberspace
rather than leave it as vague as gray as
open to action as possible and and this
inevitably raises the question well okay
we may have rules but how do you ensure
compliance with those rules how do you
ensure that both rules a responsible
state behavior as well as international
law really make a difference that it's
not just that good countries if you will
that abide by the rules but that all
actors who are active in this domain
abide by those rules now the first
comment that I would make here is that
rules as a general matter they're meant
to provide guidance for States at Fonte
if you again were in the deterrence
panel you heard Jay Healy say that the
way rules are being worked out at the
moment is on the go on the battlefield
in action states poking elbows at each
other rather than externally determining
what is acceptable behavior and what is
unacceptable this goes against the logic
of norms of having norms of having laws
which prescribe in advance which
behavior is acceptable tolerated and
which is prohibited thereby putting
actors on notice what kind of behavior
is expected of them the related issue of
course is that of enforcement which is a
whole can of worms in and of itself but
we probably cannot talk about
enforcement unless we have articulated
at least some rules because how do we
enforce rules if you don't know what the
rules
enforcement again there are several
several ways of enforcing rules
some of them come from international law
itself self-help measures are a tool for
enforcing international law judicial
process is a form of enforcing
international law but other
extrajudicial extra legal measures of
course are available to enforce
international law as well be they
economic diplomatic military you name it
and then final point because this is a
panel on attribution what about all
those states that do not have the
capacity to attribute to that do not
have powerful allies with whom to do
joint attribution
what are they left with and the answer
at least import lies in a notion that is
known commonly as due diligence and the
due diligence the notion says that
states masters should take reasonably
feasible action to ensure that their
state is not used by by third parties to
the detriment of other states now due
diligence unfortunately has proven to be
an controversial issue in international
relations if you ask almost any
international lawyer they will say that
due diligence is a rule of international
law in other words states not only
should do so but states must ensure that
their territory is not used in such a
way and there are several countries that
say yes this is international law
including Gastonia in this morning's
speech however it's it's mostly bigger
more powerful countries that reject due
diligence as binding international law
we can speculate why different countries
we check this and to an extent they
probably have different rationales but
as a generalization I feel that bigger
countries are much more willing to
ascertain rights under international law
rather than than they are willing to
self impose international legal
obligations on them
but if due-diligence was treated as law
it's man it would mean for those
countries that do not have the capacity
to attribute that what they need to do
is to find is to only trace back the
cyber operation to the territorial state
where it is coming from it doesn't need
to prove an axis between the territory
and that territorial government or a
third government all that the state
needs to do is say it comes from your
territory it's causing serious harm to
me and you have a legal obligation to do
everything that you reasonably can to
put an end to it so with that I thank
you so as a matter of how we'll proceed
let's hold the questions till the end
but as the moderator I reserve the
prerogative to ask questions now le's
while the others are presenting I wonder
if you could consider this attribution
or the attribution game no longer seems
to be the exclusive prerogative of
states we've highly capable and well
resourced actors I'm thinking of
CrowdStrike and mandiant making very
public attributions at least in a
technical sense do these frustrate the
delicate balance you referred to that
states are engaged in their in their own
attribution efforts are they forcing
States hands are they doing attribution
differently than states are in a way
that frustrates their efforts perhaps
you'd be willing to think on that and
we'll come back to you after the other
presenters okay our final presenter then
is a professor Rob Barnsby Rob is
retired United States Army officer with
experience in military intelligence and
in the judge a cadet Advocate General's
Corps he's currently an assistant
professor at the United States Military
Academy at West Point can I get a beat
Navy there we go he is also a cyber
fellow at the army cyber Institute and
he's learned most recently that this
fall he'll join the Faculty of
University of California Berkeley Law
School as a visiting professor Rob floor
is all yours
Thank You Sean for that very kind
introduction
like to also thank the organizers for
another great event I remember last year
around the time of saikhan there was an
Iron Maiden concert here pretty cool
this year I get off the plane and the
taxi driver says Metallica is coming in
the next week or two and I just thought
even the concerts are getting better and
better here now the cadets are is said
sir what is a Metallica and I only the
best band ever but I do want to welcome
our cadets and Midshipmen too we
actually have a second lieutenant here
who just graduated on Saturday she
actually gave up her leave Jenny
congratulations on that graduate in West
Point gave up her leave and vacation to
come here the next day on a plane and
that just shows a level of our
determination our young officers have
and that sort of thing and we'll talk a
little bit later about her
decision-making as far as giving up free
leave but and I don't remember as a
cadet having these opportunities to come
to saikhan or Estonia but I'm very glad
that you have them I don't even remember
getting outside of the gate to Highland
Falls which is a town outside of West
Point but want to thank the leadership
of the ACI the army cyber Institute
chris hartley and andy hall for
continuing to support the cadets coming
here and Paul Torres crew the mids uh it
is of course a disclaimer is necessary
for someone in the Department of Defense
the u.s. I'm here my personal capacity
not speaking for the United States
government the United States Army West
Point or anything like that it's I'm
here in my personal capacity my fellow
panelists have done a great job and I
certainly agree with everything these
and Menaul have had to say but if we all
say the same or agree on everything that
would be boring so I'm gonna maybe be a
little provocative here
what I'd like to suggest is maybe an
observation that certain states are
perfectly happy having cyberattacks
attributed to them or at least they
don't seem to mind having them
attributed to him I just have a couple
slides here to help frame the discussion
you've heard the legal aspects of
attribution as I think about the issue
though it's occurred to me recently that
we may want to look at attribution
through a different framework you hear
about all the incidents we don't have to
get into all of them necessarily but we
certainly can you you hear a lot of
association with states
you don't hear great worldwide response
you hear some denials certainly I agree
but you don't hear it as much in as my
thought that maybe certain states don't
mind being labeled perpetrators in this
regard
the current framework is victim focused
the typical question being is a victim
state willing to publicly attribute the
attack to another state as you've heard
sometimes that is a question and also
assumes that the perpetrator I think as
a town man you said purportedly
responsible state wants to avoid
attribution and I would like to change
that to suggest I don't think that view
is wrong but I would like to add an
inquiry of basically looking at the
perpetrators motivations in addition to
the victim and whether or not the victim
state is willing or able to attribute
certainly the examples are many and
Lee's went through a lot of those and we
know the states that are generally
associated with them not pecho want to
cry ENC financial institutions
intellectual property theft even Stuxnet
we're not always talking about quote
unquote bad actors that want to avoid
attribution it can be for a variety of
reasons that we'll get into both policy
and legal
a minute and this is all open source of
course none of this is based on any
classified knowledge this is this is
just very public reports and you've
heard from these now the most important
part is to what I think do not assume
the perpetrator wants to avoid
attribution oftentimes we we think
that's the case and the questions to ask
which the answers to which may inform
this approach I would offer a few what
explains a lapse in tradecraft you see
sloppiness you see language time zone
indicators of certain attacks that are
they're quite clear was that intentional
or is it just simply a lapse in
tradecraft I certainly leave that to the
technical folks but it is it does occur
to me that that's a bit of sloppiness
and a surprise why are the denials
unconvincing and or non-existence states
do deny as I've said but the silence can
be deafening sometimes and it feels like
they're okay in some cases with being
attributed to them and I say also what
is the most obvious explanation
the Occam's razor of international law I
would say I applied to international law
the most obvious explanation may be the
most likely for who conducted the
operation if you look at Sony Pictures
my 11 year old daughter could probably
figure out there's a movie about a
dictator who might want to respond to
that notice I did not see my 13 year old
son I'm not sure he would get I think he
would I think you figure it out but that
one is sort of obvious so then the
question becomes why why would anyone
tacitly maybe not overtly as a state
accept attribution I offer several
possibilities again this is this is just
a way of thinking about it and what I'm
considering here
first that the state is seeking
attention right we have we have clearly
a statecraft argument that certain
states want to increase their world
standing we can think of those even with
some human rights issues and that they
may want to hide that or to embellish
their standing in the world by having
this capability in the cyber realm as a
great scholar and friend recently
reminded me from dr. Strangelove I think
Peter Sellers said the whole point of
having a doomsday machine is loss if you
keep it a secret and so kind of like
celebrities in the US and other places
no press is bad press for some of these
countries or states and international
law and they're perfectly fine with
having things associate with them or
being in the news for something other
than failures at the political economic
level or even just not being at the same
level as other states classic asymmetric
warfare right if you can't fight on the
same battlefield maybe go go asymmetric
go hybrid go unconventional and have
that sort of leverage and that sort of
power and we see that it may be working
the US Department of Defense Cyber
strategy just this past year came out
names for countries so we're not
surprised China Iran North Korea and
Russia and so even the naming of them as
an adversary and a worthy adversary in
the cyber realm raises their stature
certainly in some way I would also argue
that states seek to illustrate their own
capabilities while demonstrating a
victim states vulnerabilities this is
kind of a deterrence flipped around
right if you want to go specific they
will want to show the country that they
may be attacking or tacitly
acknowledging a cyber attack having been
attributed to them in a way of saying
don't do this again
generally showing the power of the world
if we want to talk general deterrence
but again flipping that from the victims
perspective to the attackers perspective
and in a way of preventing others with
messing with them if they don't have
power in other areas it may be as simple
as leadership seeking domestic favor to
show their own state that they have
power and strength that we could think
of some countries that might be
interested in that and just as a way of
showing their own population that they
are still relevant or it may be simply
that the costs are just not high enough
at least technically they may be I'm not
a technical expert in any way but at
least in terms of policy in law
maybe we can suggest that there's not
enough punishment to deter them this
simply the costs are not high enough so
they don't mind having attacks
attributed to them simply put certain
states benefit from having cyber attacks
attributed to them regardless of where
we draw the line
now once properly framed I think we can
ask the same question from a legal
perspective if you're the perpetrator
why tacitly accept attribution from a
legal perspective and I have just a few
thoughts on that and the first may be
that the state does not believe it is
committing a wrongful act you see is
again relatively underwhelming efforts
to hide identity even you could think
about states commonly linked to to
Stuxnet maybe suggests some belief that
the state is not committing a wrongful
act legally which leads into other
debates for which we don't have time but
its sovereignty comes to mind where the
action may be justified if it's for
example to thwart a nuclear capability
again I'm not suggesting this is all my
thoughts I'm not aware of anything in
particular where this is a case but I
just it makes sense to me or the UK view
in such areas as we see now about
sovereignty being maybe being a little
bit more of a guiding principle than an
inviolable rule according you know in
accordance with the UN Charter but again
flipping the the view and notice we do
not say just bad actors are willing to
have attacks attributed to them it could
be quote unquote good actors it's just
the idea that they might accept it it
could also be that the state is trying
to influence state practice or move the
needle on lawfulness I think this is not
likely but we want this as something
states think about before acting right
certainly as lawyers we would want that
but I'm not sure they do as you know
state practice can lead to the
development of customary international
law and it may be some attempt to nudge
that forward as a demonstration of state
practice but I don't know that that one
is is the case it could be that the
state is attempting to exploit a gray or
gray zone of international law you've
heard this point before again a type of
asymmetric warfare is it not
we're States committed to rule of law
less likely operating the grades on the
states that do not share a rule of law
commitment as these mentioned I think
very nicely state seek to exploit
international law rules that are poorly
delineated attribution may be the same
opening and possibility what is
direction mean what is control what are
instructions as Lee's laid out the law
and the legal ambiguity hobbles a
response as many great scholars have
written but make it no mistake when an
attack is minimally destructive but
maxim maximally disruptive it still can
be below the threshold of wrongfulness
legally and that can get into the grey
zone piece of course it could be
anything else we don't know we maybe
think about some of those possibilities
during QA or after and I would just
offer we never know what estates
intentions are obviously but knowing or
thinking about things at least
differently can help us close legal gaps
so there is a legal connection here
every situation is different here come
my caveats every situation is different
I realize that we'll never know what the
true intentions of a state are and my
way is just another consideration in a
difficult area and with those caveat
said I am more than willing to be pinned
down and recorded as saying certain
states may be happy in certain
situations to have certain things
attributed to them thank you
thank you rob
and I'm sure Metallica would endorse
your your swimming upstream you're
you're running against the current yeah
this is flies kind of in the face of the
whole title of the conference right it's
silent battle and here comes Rob so I'm
with maybe not so silent you know some
of what you describe Rob reminded me of
of herb Lynn's work on loud cyber
operations I think from the technical
community and from the policy community
some of what you've explored has been
has been addressed but not in the way
you did particularly can you distinguish
some of his work I think some of the
room may be familiar with his work on
loud cyber operations is there a
distinction or a difference between what
you are describing and what and herbs
work there so stew on that you've got
the shortest time to work with I know I
know that
so Lee's now to you on the question that
I posed to you these private efforts so
Mandy a CrowdStrike friend or foe to the
really nuanced or or subtle approaches
that states are taking to political
attribution it's probably both there are
some aspects of non-state actor
attribution that I'm sure frustrate
State mean States may feel compelled to
respond when a non-state actor when a
private firm has attributed malicious
are activated to a state there may be a
reputation or concerns States may feel
that they're out performed by a private
company and not like that horribly but
on the other hand and there are Studies
on this as well the private sector
attribution can be very helpful for
states can help them bypass the
classification dilemma they don't
necessarily need to come up with as much
previously classified information as
they perhaps otherwise word and some
companies surely have access to some
type of information that the state
itself does not have fireEye has got
sensors all over the world where states
typically tend to have their sensors
rather in their own territory than all
over the world
so from a policy perspective and I'm
sure policy experts are much more
qualified to opine on this I think there
are pros and cons but as a matter of law
I don't think that private sector
tribution frustrates the law at all
international law has dealt with
non-public private sources of evidences
since the very beginning international
courts they accept witness testimony is
to accept expert expert testimony so I
don't think that's a problem per se for
international law at least thanks Li's
no yes so your question was the
interaction between the highly
coordinated and delicate feeling very
diplomatic feeling process you described
it the EU and then some emerging
proposals in some sense to outsource
attribution to make it a private effort
even adjudicate adjudicative functions
feasible to have state buy-in to these
processes and second if yes with what
conditions are what provisos I would
also like to pick up on Lisa's answer
and I think we'll roll into only one
question I would say twisdon second one
doesn't count
so indeed I think it's it's it's very
useful and I think the private sector
has a lot of information that can be
used for attribution in particular for
instance when it comes to to imposing
sanctions as that must be based at open
source information and indeed you can
you know divert from the classification
project problem etc you also see the
cooperation between states and private
sectors when it comes to sharing of
information I mean there's a lot of
private public cooperation when it comes
to certs
but also for instance Europe also law
enforcement so you see this this is very
successful cooperation taking place
where it becomes problematic when
private companies want to take over the
responsibility of states when it comes
to international law or when it comes to
international relations and in that
sense initiatives of either private
companies proposing that we should
negotiate a treaty estates cyber Geneva
Convention I mean yes indeed or stay a
private company saying that they will
establish an attribution Council that
will then give us everything we need to
impose consequences that have
significant or could have significant
effect on international relations and
even on on peace and stability I think
that's something that is not desirable
states pertain a special responsibility
when it comes to this and it should
remain like this
although the I mean the EU does
recognize the responsibility of all
actors including the private sector and
that could be in need when it comes to
sharing information which touches upon
attribution but also when it comes to
developing secure products and services
so other stakeholders have other
responsibilities these are ours so to
say so therefore that answers the first
question and leaves the second to to the
crowd so fair enough so crowdsourcing
the second question here then Rob are
you in her blend seeing eye to eye on
this or are you talking about different
things I'm familiar dr. Lin's work and I
think it is a little different I
distinguish his there's a little louder
than what I'm saying like Metallica loud
pretty loud okay silent battle you're
gonna have some folks writing on loud
cyber but or we can also see what dr.
Lin says after this I think he's
knocking them out but he but I think if
I know dr. Lin's work it's more about
self attribution from the beginning a
state actor could could say right away
this is our attack mechanism and self
attribute in that way mine's a little
less visit of all
of 10 out of 10 might not be like a
seven or eight all between foot between
there and and the silent battle my
analogy is you know if you get to the
individual person level if someone were
to be accused of doing something wrong
the loud would be someone saying yes I
did it and I'll do it again and mine
would be more like maybe I did it maybe
I didn't what are you gonna do about it
but again I those are just some some
things I like to think of a lot of great
scholarship in this area even in our
conference book noticed this yesterday
there's there's a really neat article on
on loud cyber so again it's a lot of
folks are thinking about this and I
would just put mine a nots below that on
the volume fair enough okay well we have
time remaining for questions from the
room the protocol I'd like to use is
that the microphones used I'll just call
on folks and the first hand I see is
Kubo go ahead please yeah thanks Shona
oh it's Cubana Chuck University of
Exeter I have a question for lease and
for Rob if I may so lease if I
understood you correctly when you talked
about unilateral self-help you suggested
that the standard of proof to use is the
standard of reasonableness did I get
that right right okay so I would just
put it to you that this is maybe the
wrong lens through which to look at this
and I wonder what you think about this
to my mind standard of proof is very
directly linked to burden of proof and
so these are concepts that we use in
adjudicatory settings but not in the
situation's of unilateral self-help
they're the correct lens to my mind is
simply the allocation of risk so if you
are acting you're acting you're placing
the risk upon yourself that you might be
acting unlawfully and so whereas if you
look at it from the reasonableness
perspective then basically what you're
saying if the state makes a mistake but
it's a mistake that the reasonable state
would make in those situations it would
still be acting lawfully and so I would
put it to you that this poses a risk of
escalation
especially as countermeasures are
concerned that it goes
against the Orthodox understanding of
the law of countermeasures so that's
that's my question about reasonableness
and Rob I think the elephant in the room
here is the geopolitical considerations
so if we talk about attribution you know
there are basically three categories of
countries those that are outside of the
attribution game then those who
attribute and those who are attributed
to and it's something that you didn't
mention so I just wonder to what extent
these geopolitical considerations play
into your analysis could those be some
additional you know reasons why some
states are happy to be attributed not
thanks.thanks good lease you want to
start sure so I think we're actually in
in agreement and I would interpret the
law the same way it's true that in the
context of unilateral self-help that the
term standard of proof isn't normally
used but I think it's helpful just to
think through the issue so for the right
of self-defense the first question would
be does the state need to have absolute
certainty as to attribution of the armed
attack to a state or a non-state actor
if the state buys and buys into the
argument that self-defense can be
exercised against non-state actors so
does the state need to have 100% proof
before it can resort to self-defense and
here my answer would be no and I suppose
you would answer the question in the
negative as well and then the secondary
question arises what if the state makes
a mistake and and I would say that if
the state makes the mistake then yes the
state has acted on its own risk so if it
uses force against an innocent state it
is not excused in international law so
it may be obliged to provide reparation
for example but the first question is
really important do you need 100% proof
to be able to resort to force in the
first place because if that was the case
and in almost every circumstance whether
it's a cyber armed attack or it's mining
a vessel or the launch of a missile I
mean in many cases States won't have 100
percent proof so they would have their
hands tied in the vast majority of cases
if I may just a brief follow-up so like
that the point is that before you get to
a judicial organ the
the use of the term standard of proof
doesn't help it's neither here nor there
you need to be before a court and only
then there is a certain standard of
proof that's required of course you
don't need to have a hundred percent
certainty but to say that the standard
of proof is reasonableness doesn't say
anything because by that you're just
saying it's case by case and then we
will see how things go while still
risking that a state might say well we
were acting under the standard of
reasonableness because everybody would
have thought the same thing
and thus we didn't act unlawfully but
what I hear is saying is that we're on
the same page that the state that makes
a mistake takes the risk of acting
unlawfully and it would be acting
unlawfully so I would just put it to you
that we should probably leave you know
the terminology of standard of proof and
burden of proof or judicial
determinations and it's not appropriate
because we don't have an international
law of evidence to use it in these
bilateral relationships I'm perfectly
fine to refrain from using the term
standard proof although the subject
matter is still the same how much
evidence how well does the state need
how well do the facts need to be
established for the state to respond
unilaterally Rob yes Sean good boy I had
a question for you
yes Cuba I think the first thing I would
do with any question is absolutely
without doubt consult the cyber law
toolkit but assuming that it's not in
there because I admit this is not a
tightest legal argument I've ever had
where of a policy I think the categories
you lay out are exactly right
I think they reinforce in a way what I'm
saying states enjoy being in a
particular category regardless of what
it is and I'm just suggesting they might
double down on that behavior enjoy the
cachet that that represents whether
they're always attributed to or part of
groups that are always attributing or
may be unwilling to and that they I'm
suggesting that they may enjoy that
category I do think some of written
about you know centralized attribution
body which removes the politics perhaps
whether it's private or public actor
as part of that mostly private I think
we might have and that would remove a
little bit of politics a willingness to
to attribute as has been suggested or
the ramifications of attributing to
anyone or having something attributed to
you so I I certainly agree with you but
I think there's a lot of possibilities
here for for scholarship for research
writing and for moving ahead in the
future
there were and there were two questions
then on this side of the room my name is
Lisa Post and I'm with a McCain
Institute of international leadership
I'm not a lawyer so I feel the rod
flawed and faulty after the formidable
doctor much I care but my question is
really why would you in terms of what
attribution gives just in the policy and
diplomacy world so why would you even
attribute unless it gives you a
political advantage in particular in
terms of deterrence which makes for me
as a practitioner the finer points
almost irrelevant and given that the
economic and diplomatic measures that
we've gotten access to as currently
responses on the international law don't
really work anymore naming and shaming
as Robert pointed out doesn't work if
you get bragging rights out of it
so what attribution Scott getting us in
this current world where our responses
are so limited unless the activity is
above the threshold of an and attack are
limiting to a point where everyone else
is learning from the Russian playbook
yes so what would you wish international
law gave you access to or gave nations
access to in terms of responses still in
peace time so that that tribution would
be meaningful again
okay so for the panel you know Lisa's
comments seem most directly addressed at
the fit between maybe changing state
behavior in attribution more public
statements although equivocal as you
pointed out is that change in state
behavior somehow a comment on the state
of international law are they subtly
signaling to us that it is inadequate in
some sense are these the beginning
stages of movements in international on
attribution but to answer Lisa a
question directly you often need to
attribute in law in order to protect
your legal rights you don't only need to
attribute to engage in self defense
pursuant to article 51 of the UN Charter
you also need to tribute to engage in
for example countermeasures you can only
engage in countermeasures against the
state if there is a state behind a cyber
operation so there are reasons for which
attribution is required also in law but
as to the public statements and whether
they whether they reflect a
dissatisfaction with international law
not necessarily I would say I just think
that states are unwilling to draw those
draw those lines in the sand to be to be
quite honest and and there is a lot of
talk about cyber stability maintaining
cyber stability well maybe it is in the
more powerful states interest to
maintain this type of stability that we
have right now rather than to have
restrictive rules that not only take
options off the table for other
countries but also options off the table
for themselves other panel members on
the question no I mean obviously I said
there are reasons that attribution could
benefit I mean that reasons are showing
publicly that there are rules that these
rules when you violate them that there
could be consequences
it could be pointing out certain threats
it could be making sure that you engage
directly with the perpetrator to to have
an understanding what's right and what's
wrong
however attribution is never something
in itself it's not something that you do
and that's the end of the case and just
pointing out because you can it's also
not leading to anything so I think when
you look at attribution and why are you
doing it it's because it fits into your
wider approach so you have a certain
perpetrator you see threats maybe
incidents coming and then you're
thinking about what is my strategy what
kind of measures do we I have in my
toolbox
what do kind of relations do I have with
third countries or with international
organizations and how can we leverage
everything we have to influence the
behavior of this particular state into
the direction of responsible behavior
and attribution could be one element of
this but it's certainly not the only
element because in the end if you if you
name and shame some states are not even
receptive to that and I like the
thinking indeed of some states might
even like it because it gives them the
posture they need on the international
stage so my plea is to really think
about okay what can a traditional
attribution do in our wider approach to
make sure that we influence behavior in
the endgame of cyber civility well great
points I totally agree
you can't some if many have said this
before me but it's hard to shame too
shameless right so we escalate maybe
sanctions may be offensive cyber
operations and I love the question
that's a great question it just reminds
me of sort of a military thing that we
think about is especially as legal
advisors can you do something and should
you right so again this is not directly
responsive but there's many things we
don't want to reveal sources and that
sort of thing we don't want to escalate
not necessarily any one particular state
but a lot of states are thinking of that
so even if you could as a matter of law
or your you willing to as a state should
you so that's just something that I
think it reinforces your point Lisa and
it's it's a great one but it does fit in
nicely and I I defer to these a manam on
their points okay there was one more
question I believe in the middle
gentleman in the blue jacket yes you sir
we do you have a microphone I think
we're being recorded here we go it's
coming your way thanks for that okay
specifically I was gonna ask about the
attribution and more in depth about what
plans do you have for what you were
talking about doing a body that could
sort of centralize this process the
reason why I want to ask this is because
actually I'm from fire right now you
mentioned mandiant earlier for example
our organization does a lot of this
attribution process and what I can see
as an Intel analyst is basically
different organizations come up let's
say we come up with different results on
what the clusters of activity look like
because oftentimes sometimes we can find
very clear stuff something it's very
easy to know who it was but something
it's a bit more complicated and you can
find different closer of activity that
do not match for one or another reason
so if we were to have a body in the
middle trying to make that decision I
just wanted to ask about your thoughts
of how would it look like like would it
go to private sector and see I don't
know like the results from many
different companies in trying to
moderate would it be that we have a new
organism that does attribution and
that's the attribution that counts I
don't know like how would you solve this
uncertainty over the attribution I know
it sounds like that second question is
coming around yeah not because we have a
body and that's a state and you know the
state attributes it's their sovereign
decision so if you have data put it out
there great open source intelligence
open source information can be gathered
by States and states can take that
decision on their own so there's no need
to have a private entity it's attributed
for a state the state has this has his
own capability
to do so and if they want this they can
do to certain EU level coordinated or
with other partners so I understand
there's a need to well present the data
that you have but great put it online
we'll use it this is sort of a well-worn
approach to international law right that
we could just fix it if we took it out
of the hands of states any are we all
sovereign tests here on the panel and
any warming to the proposal that maybe
this we'd all just be better off if some
some neutral independent detached body
we're making these states rather than or
making these decisions rather than
states pleased to be honest I haven't
given a lot of thought to this I think
those proposals are born out of
frustration with the status quo there's
this feeling that we need to take the
situation further somehow and if states
are not attributing the states are not
taking action states are not drawing
lines in the sand well maybe somebody
else should so I guess I'm somewhere in
between
I too am somewhat frustrated with the
states to be honest with you especially
the more capable states who are in a
position to to advance normative order
in cyberspace I think most countries
actually in the world today are not
involved in this debate at a very high
level they are only catching up but but
the states that could advance rule of
long line norms of responsible state
behavior online and they are reluctant
to do so for various reasons and and
often I do think they should Ron I think
we have seen some private companies
attribute right private industry folks
and again not going into a ton of
examples but not in a definitive or
abiding way right right yeah some have
argued they're faster they're more
detailed their broader different
motivations different implications of
private sector attributing over public
obviously and but one thing I found
compelling for that argument and the
sort of the reason I meant is you could
persuade different audiences who may
sceptical of states motivations as a
combination of law policy and that sort
of thing you you certainly could reach a
different audience if you had a central
attribution body or just private-sector
attributions and I think that's
important too
of course the analogy you could have a
bounty hunter be very quick about
something that a law enforcement might
not be able to and that doesn't mean we
shouldn't have law enforcement do the
job it just sort of something I think of
there are considerations on all sides so
it's like a great job security for law
professors right yeah yeah John Kennedy
maybe pick up on what what has been said
because horseman I I recognize that the
audience part and the credibility part
but if something happens it's not that
private entities are not engaged in this
and not putting it out there so they are
the question is should they bundle their
sources and should they come together in
a council and then provide one advice to
States and now you know please act on it
so of course when I'm I'm assure that
when the state will respond and I mean
will when they will do it with measures
that go beyond just declaratory there
will be definitely private sector
engagement and private sector
conclusions that supports this action so
I don't see one or the other as it's not
a contradictory so not wanting a
partnership sorry time is winding down a
bit but I think we have several
questions why don't we take them sort of
in serial order I see a question here
the gentleman the bass jacket as well
one in the back could we take all three
questions back-to-back and I'll let the
panelists take those up as they as they
choose please professor Barnes be with
your proposed framework do you think a
standardized punishment procedure would
affect a state's willingness to accept
attribution okay well well hold that one
that one's directed at Professor Barnes
be the gentleman in the front here
hello Kooskia in krakow so my question
also goes to Professor bronze B and so
you spoke about one of the motivations
for the states of not caring about
attributions is the exploitation of grey
zones of international law but my
question would be are we not in a
certain way contributing to this grey
zone by for instance certain states
denying the the existence of certain
rules such as the rule of sovereignty in
cyberspace and therefore you know why
should a state care about being
attributed with a conduct that is not
really a violation of any particular
rule of international law thank you
thank you and in the back oh this is
Barry yeah right right there on the side
here yeah Barry the final question is
yours okay thank you
Barry sanda FGP Brazil I just want to
return to the earlier question because
although it was a really interesting
question about the value added of
international law the value added of
attribution because if you ask an
international lawyer what's the value
added of attribution of below the
threshold operations the immediate
answer is well you get access to
countermeasures but I think that's the
elephant in the room is that states
haven't really come up with effective
countermeasures which motivate them to
actually attribute and I think we maybe
could benefit and this is the question
would you agree we could maybe benefit
from a wider discussion of what
effective countermeasures would be
against peacetime cyber operations
thanks Barry
so Rob let's start with you and then
we'll work our way down the panel for
Kevin our cadet I feel like you could
have asked that question three weeks ago
about 5,000 miles west of here I was a
kidding
great job stepping up asking questions I
love it so standard punishment structure
I just feel like it's a great idea I
feel like every every situations
different so it'd be hard to
standardized right classic answer we
there are the motivations we have to all
talk
about and so you probably would not see
that it feeds into the second question
right a little bit which is are we
helping things by by taking what could
be a very clear standard instructions
Direction control and saying well this
is this is very hard to figure out what
instructions are and that sort of thing
perhaps there you know again or a lawyer
talking making policy arguments like me
not helping out very much and I think
it's a great point I don't quite
disagree with that question either so
classic response but that's those are my
initial thoughts I know your thoughts
well I think just would like to respond
to the last question because although we
need to discuss these issues indeed the
question is if they would always need to
be put to the forefront
there's work ahead this work should be
done in the UN gge we should discuss how
international law applies and we should
further work on the norms of responsible
state behavior in particular when it
comes to implementation but we should
also bear in mind that we do not want
escalation in cyberspace we do not want
cyberspace to be used for all kinds of
strategic objectives by States because
in the end who will suffer from it all
of us so yes there is a discussion about
how countermeasures work and all the
conditions etc but we should also bear
in mind that in principle we're working
here on stability
so if attribution could contribute to
that yes we should do it and there are
several ways in which we could apply it
even non-public ways it should not
always be out in the open naming and
shaming and pointing fingers sometimes
not even effective but we should keep
our eyes on the ball and and not try to
to escalate unnecessarily because it's
fashion please the first end the final
word goes to you
so pick the question about
so what is the value of naming and
shaming different not naming and shaming
for violations of the law I agree with
you that cherry-picking
irrespective of which country which side
is cherry-picking is problematic and it
takes away the moral ground of a state
to say that cyberspace is governed by
international law if the state at the
same time is cherry-picking which rules
of international law apply and do not
apply so I agree that this is a problem
the dew accusations of states having
violated international law carry more
weight than accusations of states having
reached norms of responsible state
behavior I think to an extent they do
yes sometimes states may not mind them
but probably there is only one country
in the world that doesn't care at all
when it's labeled a lawbreaker that's
North Korea but even countries like
Russia and China they do care when
they're labeled lawbreakers Russia
worked quite hard in the Security
Council to justify its invasion of
Ukraine as an exercise of self-defense
China outside the cyber context works
very hard to justify its an evil
maneuvers in the law of the sea
so no country maybe except for North
Korea wants to be labeled a lawbreaker
in international relations and even if
this the naming achievement for having
violated international law doesn't
change their behavior it nevertheless
imposes cost even if it is minimal cost
it imposes reputational cost on them
well we are precisely on time please
join me in thanking the panelists for
their thoughts
you