welcome back from lunch to the first
tech track of this saikhan machine
learning as the way forward to defend
against the emerging sets my name is
Arturo Ramos I am technology researcher
at CDC OE and I will be moderating this
panel my main field of interests are
rebel network security and lately I have
been focusing more on the network
security research which often results in
huge datasets that can be processed by
humans even in semi automated way
so after considerations investigations I
have come to conclusions that my and
many other researchers you can move
forward only by applying machine
learning techniques and I am very
grateful that I have colleagues that are
much more knowledgeable in this field
sadly machine learning is not the magic
bullets it automatically solves all the
problems it would be very nice it's
applicability is highly dependent on the
problem domain and also experts it seems
that the approach of joining together
machine learning experts and cyber
experts is the most efficient way have
to proceed because these fields are very
large and complicated and becoming
expert even in one is is quite
problematic and today we are going to
see machine learning experts that have
joined as their forces to solve cyber
problems in this session first we will
have mr. Ilan mayor from MIT house
eureka introduce us to their approach to
detecting command and control channels
our next panelist is dr. Roman graph
from Austrian Institute of Technology
who will explore applicability of neural
networks for Android application
classification and our third panelist
professor Mikhail kyani from University
of Modena
and Reggio Emilia will provide closer
look at the other sink adversarial a
text against machine learning algorithms
as you just heard we have very research
centered panel we have distinguished
speakers from two universities and one
research organization and before we
start just a few words about the format
of this panel we have one half hours and
three speakers every speaker has up to
20 minutes to present the research after
that he will have a chance to ask a
couple questions for everyone so listen
and come up with questions related to
the specific presentation and please
keep the questions short and concise and
if you have something long long formal
questions or discussions for specific
topic you can always find the outers
after the panels till the end of saikhan
week and at the very end we will have
about 10 minutes of panel discussion we
will try to tie everything together and
if you have topic you want to hear being
discussed you can you can propose end so
first stone you have mr. Ron mayor who
is PhD student at the historic he is a
part of networked systems group where he
is research focuses on the security of
computer networks in particular he works
on solutions which leverage recent
advances in network programming
programming program ability to make
networks able to detect and mitigate
attacks and provide more security and
privacy roland is presenting already sir
dear and first one was in 2017 when he
won junior scholar award his presented
research investigates machine learning
applicability for detecting of command
and control channels in Lock shields
defenders data set ok
please roll on the floor is yours
thank you very much and I'm very happy
to present our work on detecting command
and control channels in the Lock shields
exercise here at saikhan most of this
work was done by Nicholas kensic and the
project was done for further
collaboration with Luca combat sea and
Vasa lenders from Armistice and Laurel
and Weber from ETH Zurich to start with
I'm sure all of you have heard headlines
such as this one
describing large-scale cyber attacks
against critical infrastructure this is
an example of a ransomware
attack that hit many UK hospitals or
another attack that was targeting the
power grid in the Ukraine and apparently
there was even a high tech war here in
Estonia taking place two years ago and
from a research point of view from what
we are looking at these attacks are very
interesting or would be very interesting
to learn from but it's very difficult to
get data so data in terms of for example
network traffic that was exchanged and
data that would be required to learn how
we can defend against such attacks in
the future however the last example was
actually slightly different most of you
probably realized that this was not a
real war but this was just the log
Shields exercise which takes place here
every year and in fact it's the largest
cyber defence exercise of its kind and
it is a red team vs. blue team exercise
which means there is a right team
running attacks against blue teams which
have to defend against the attacks and
in the case of log kills the the red
team is one central team and the blue
team are usually one blue team per
participating country this attack this
exercise launched
runs at a very large scale with over
1,000 experts in the intervals of these
red and blue teams and these experts
come from all over the world there are
thousands of systems that are attacked
and thousands of attacks that are run
over a period of up of about two days of
this exercise and the unique thing about
this exercise is compared to real
incidents that we do not only have to
in terms of the network traffic that was
exchanged during the exercise but we
also have a ground truth which tells us
what the attackers were doing or so what
the red team was doing and what the
infrastructure was that they were using
to run the attacks this you usually
don't have in the case of normal attacks
because the attackers will not tell you
what they did you only know what you
found out yourself through forensics for
example and the goal of our project was
that we got the data from the Swiss blue
team in this log shields exercise and we
wanted to develop a system that helped
the Swiss blue team or blue teams in
general to improve their defense in the
following years and what we could
already tell from the evaluation results
that we got with our data is that if the
Swiss blue team had used our system in
2018 they could have discovered more
than 80 percent of the command and
control servers by looking only at data
that was exchanged over about 30 minutes
of the first day of the exercise I will
later present you more results from our
evaluation but first I would like to
cover two other parts in the first part
I will speak a bit more about locked
shields and how it works from a more
technical perspective then I will
present you how our system works that
that takes network traffic and tells the
defenders which of these flows are
command and control flows before I will
present you more evaluation results in
the last part so a few more words about
locked shields I already told you that
there are blue teams that have to defend
their network and such a network is a
very fairly big for example it can be
the one of a military airbase which
consists of Industry control systems of
maybe air vehicles of traditional coma
and client-server infrastructure and so
on so we have many different systems
that have potentially vulnerabilities
and can be attacked by the right team
and then there is a for each blue team
that is participating there is one
instance of such a network or such a
virtualized Network and there is one
central right team that is running
attacks
and all these networks and the red team
is quite free to use whatever techniques
they want to attack but at least part of
the attacks are run over a command and
control infrastructure in that case
using the COBOL strike framework so
therefore the setting for the red team
during lob shields even though it's only
an exercise it's very realistic
these are very skilled people that are
experts for different types of devices
they know how to run attacks against
these devices and at least part of the
attacks are on over a control command
control infrastructure on the other hand
we have two blue teams which need to
defend their network there is one blue
team for each network and usually it's
one blue team per participating country
and these blue teams they can access the
network that they need to defend over a
remote connection over a VPN tunnel and
they have some virtual machines some
devices where they can run their systems
within the within the network that they
need to defend and these two things I
mention it because it's important for
the approach that we developed and these
are two constraint that first the
bandwidth that they can use to access
their network is limited so it's not
possible to exchange large amount of
data between where the blue team is and
the network that they need to defend and
second the infrastructure these virtual
machines that they can use to run
attacks are limited in terms of
computing power and in terms of memory
so it's also not possible to run very
complex systems within this network in
general also the blue team setting is
very realistic despite even though it's
only an exercise and when the blue team
arrives the network is already under
attack and some systems are already
compromised and as usually it's not not
only the they do not only need to
defense the network but they also need
to may keep its availability because
there are normal users that need to use
the network for checking their emails or
browsing the web or whatever so just
turning everything off cleaning it and
starting it again it's not the solution
for the defenders so that was the part
about locked shields and now I would
like to describe the system that we use
to in that context of Lock shields
detect command and control servers we
started by our goal which was to have a
classifier that can tell you given
network traffic which of this traffic is
commander control and which is other
traffic that referred to as normal
traffic here so in the end we want you
to end up with such a classifier in the
beginning we had as input data we had
the network traffic from the Swiss blue
team and we also had the recordings of
the activities of the provided by the
Red Team that we could use to as a
ground truth for this network traffic as
usual in machine learning projects we
then splits our pipeline into two phases
first of all we had an offline phase for
the training which is done before the
exercise and which is not time critical
and the second phase is the online phase
where the classifier is applied in
real-time to a network traffic during
the lab chills exercise we further split
each of the phases into four steps where
we first get the data for example from
the recorded data of past year's
exercises and from the reports that are
provided then we need to do some
pre-processing which is more a technical
detail to align the information that we
get from the network traffic and from
the reports then we extract features
features are kind of properties that we
use later to distinguish between command
and control flows and other flows we
then come to the machine learning part
where we label the data so we have a
list of flows we have all the features
that we extracted for all the flows and
now we need to add a label so for each
of the flows we need to say whether it
is normal traffic or command-and-control
traffic and once we have this we can use
this information to select a subset of
the features that we previously
extracted this is done in order to make
the system more efficient and more
perform
and after we selected the features that
we used we can train the classifier
based on these features and we end up
with a classifier that we can then apply
to traffic in real time that is captured
during the exercise where we extract the
same features and get a label for all
the flows afterwards whether it is a
command and control flow or not so this
is the overview of the entire system
that we were developing here and I will
now go a bit more into the details of
some of the phases here starting with
the feature extraction here we used we
extracted 77 widely used network traffic
features of three different categories
first we had metadata such as the flow
direction or which protocols were used
then we had time related features such
as how long a flow takes or how many
packets it sends per second and third we
had volume related to be features which
include features such as the number of
packets or how many bytes are exchanged
per flow or how big the individual
packets are so we have about or we have
77 features of this kind and we compute
all of them we then have a list of all
the flows to and 77 features assigned to
each of the flows and we now need to
compute the label for the flows and this
is fairly simple we get from the Red
Team reports a list of all the command
and control servers that they were using
and whenever a flow either has the
source or the destination as one of
these servers we label it as a command
or control flow and if not we label it
as a normal flow so at this point we
have a list of the closed features and
labels and we can use this to select to
reduce now the set of features that we
need to consider to make the system more
efficient that to make it run in the
restricted environment of the log fields
exercise and to reduce the set of
features we apply kind of a recursive
elimination scheme where we first train
a random forest model on all the
features that we have so 77 in the
beginning this then gives us a score for
each feature of how
this feature contributed to the
classification result and we can remove
just the feature with the lowest
contributions or the least important
feature write it to a list and remove it
from our set start entire process again
after the second iteration we will
remove the second least important
feature and so on until we have no
features left in our set that we use for
the training and we have a list of
features ranked in increasing importance
and later if we want to use the 20 most
important features we just take the
lowest 20 entries of this list so the
next question now is or next task now is
to train a classifier and the question
here is which one we take there are many
different classifiers usable in machine
learning and for our circumstances where
we had one set one challenge which is
that while the command-and-control
traffic is expected to be similar over
many iterations of log shields the
normal traffic is probably very
different because the network might
change a lot so maybe one year it's a
military air based network another year
it's a network of a city and we also
have the constraints of the limited
computing and memory that is available
and that we want to have a system that
performs in classification in the real
time or at least close to real time what
we observed over after trying many
different model is that a very simple
one works very well and that is random
forests and so these models are very
efficient to compute and they achieve
good results as I will show later ok so
now at this point we have our classifier
and now we can apply it in real time on
the network traffic that is exchanged
during locked shields now if this I come
to the third part of my talk where I
want to share some evaluation results we
did this evaluation based on two data
sets that we obtained by the Swiss blue
team and these are the data sets from
locked chills 2000 17 and 18 which gives
us the possibility to have two models
one
that we train on the data from 17 and
evaluate with data from 18 and the other
one that we train on data from 2018 and
test with data from 2017 again this is a
very nice situation where we have two
real data sets that are independent
because they are from two different
years of locked shields and they are
realistic because it's it represent or
it contains traffic generated by humans
by skilled attackers and skilled
defenders which is very rare to be in
such a nice situation when you do
machine learning we then train these
models we tried many different
parameters and found that these ones
obtain good results if we take random
forests with 128 trees each tree maximum
depth of 10 and we take the 20 most
important features so when you do
machine learning that one important
score for the evaluation or 2 importance
course or precision and recall and
precision kind of tells you if you get
an alert what is the probability that
this alert was actually a true alert so
it represents real Emily Emily malicious
or command control flow and recall is if
you take all the alerts that you get how
much of the command and control flows
did you cover or data system cover with
these alerts and especially the
precision is quite important because if
you have low precision it means you get
many falls alert and in the environment
of log fields where you need to run this
in in real time and the defenders need
to decide quickly whether or not an
alert is true or not it would be
suboptimal to have many false positive
alerts what we observed is that our
models achieve more than 99 precision
and also higher currency of 98 or 90%
depending on the model the next aspect
that is important is the run time
because we want to have the
classification in real time or as close
as possible to real time and there what
we found is that on our machine it takes
about three microseconds to classify one
flow which is very fast
so now that I presented this approach
here and that maybe if members of the
right teams are listening they might ask
themselves how can we avoid this
classification so how can we modify the
command and control traffic such that
this classifier does not detect it
anymore and of course this is always a
problem when you do machine learning
there will be a talk later about
adversarial machine learning and we also
did some steps in this direction I think
there is more work to do but what we did
so far is that we looked at what happens
if the blue team can obfuscate some of
the features that we are using to do the
classification so features like the
packet size timing aspects or the volume
of flows and what we found is that up to
eight features so vias were zooming here
the red team can choose the eight most
important features from our list
arbitrarily so we cannot use them
anymore for classification we observe
that there is no impact on the
classification result and only if you
modify more than eight features which is
highly non-trivial in practice then you
would see the score dropping at least
four in this dataset so that was it for
the evaluation that we also have in the
paper and where you can find much more
details in a paper in the last two
minutes I would now like to share more
insights about something that is not in
the paper because it's very recent and
this is that the Swiss blue team
actually used that system in log chillz
2019 just a few weeks ago and from the
feedback that we got we were happy about
happy to hear that it actually helped
them to discover command and control
channels that they didn't see by other
means and it also helped them to confirm
alerts that they got from other systems
or maybe other intrusion detection
systems but because they had an
independent source here of the same
alert they could be more certain that
this is really a malicious server behind
it or a command and control server
behind it they used exactly the same
models that we reused
in that we developed in our project the
user a slightly different way to extract
the features because their workflow was
slightly different and the this might
have had a small impact on the results
but again from the feedback that we got
is that they were happy with the hydro
positive rate and it helped them to
detect command and control servers that
they didn't detect otherwise or to
confirm result or alerts that they got
from other systems with this I come to
the end of my talk I hope I could show
you how we identified command and
control channels at the example of the
lock yields exercise we did all these
evaluation development with data from
the Swiss blue team we are extremely
thankful for this collaboration for that
they shared the data and their expertise
with us if there are blue teams of other
countries that are interested in testing
this system or collaborating with us to
develop it further we are very
interested in and these approaches in
that case also if you have more
questions the first four authors of the
paper are here at saikhan and please
approach any of us if you want to know
more about the system and I'm also very
happy to answer questions now thank you
[Applause]
thank you all for your insights into
detecting team activities we have the
time for a few questions from the
audience
okay the microphone is coming towards
you
thanks for your talk did you try the
model in a real real world scenario and
not so far nope okay because we we don't
have a comparable data set to test it
there but you but you just using the the
various features anyway so who didn't
matter if yes well that there are papers
that show that exactly random forest in
in other data set there were that were
synthetically generated to work very
well so we expect we would have the same
results for this
other data set but we were focusing here
on the on the locked shields and yet
elevators okay okay thank you for the
presentation it's a pity that the domain
controller people didn't perform better
in our blue team despite the fact that
we had do list information so the result
was not so good but that's it
is there is the route dependent is the
training set you obtained or the Train
machine from the tools used by the by
the by the red team or how could one
enlarge the number of recognized command
control channels using auto perhaps a
tool sets and attack tools you mean
other other command control infrared at
holes etc I think right now so it's
always what you train the system with
this is what you can detect later so
since we train it with this command
control traffic generated using cobalt
strike it will detect this if we include
other types of attack traffic I would
expect we can also detect other types of
of command and control actually
what is nice if you do if you have this
command control channels is that you
kind of can attack at the root of the
problem and you don't get to the very
deep attacks that are probably very
different if two very particular attacks
that cause different traffic depending
on on the environment in which you're
under
okayhow question from the back yeah cool
presentation first you used your tool
just for detection or also for
prevention to help the blue team and the
second part of the question is if so do
you see adaptation from the red team
sir can you repeat the second part yeah
so this is detection tool yeah
but the added value is to go into
prevention what you detect as a CNC you
block it yes with automation or what
whatsoever you want you want to
integrate with with solution did you
well did the blue team did prevention
based on your observation and if so is
the red team also even evolving into the
attacks or it just launching the attacks
so I'm I'm not part of the blue team I I
don't I cannot provide all the details
here but from what I see I think there
was no reaction from the Reds yep yep
yep okay no questions here
microphones coming together
thank you for the presentation relay
common transformation we are using
machine learning to detect inside the
threat detection and modeling we
navigate the levels of detection that
you mention like ninety and ninety eight
percent and the reason is that the let's
say the radio of of actual traffic
versus the variability of common traffic
on a network it's simply too low which
extent would you say that your
measurement conditions are realistic and
they are realistic for the environment
of log shield for sure because we have
this two data set but I don't know how
realistic they are to or if you would
have to same the same activities but in
a in a different network environment
rephrase your question if that air base
that you mentioned is modeling is a
model of your network if that was a real
network on an air base with a real
traffic of different users applications
and hacker intrusion activity do you
think that you get you would get by far
to those detection results it is the
case during also during lob chills
during this exercise that you have real
user traffic and you have generated
traffic to to load the network so it's
not I think that the traffic is
realistic and to some extent generated
by real users so I think from that I'm
confident that it would work also in in
other settings but I don't have results
for them
well there was let's take last question
and you can remember your question for
the discussion around you
thank you as far as I understood you
trained your system on one sort on one
type of button infrastructure do we have
an idea how many different types of
button it researchers out there in the
world I don't have a number what many
yes
too many yes okay thank you Ron
okay okay next up we have dr. Roman Graf
who is the research engineer at center
for digital safety and security at
Houston Institute of Technology he works
on cyber security and data analytics
topics contributing to the development
of several European research projects
like a Gaussian planets assets and scape
he has published widely in the area of
cyber security and risk management Roman
has supported development of cyber
threat intelligence solutions like
Caesar and also the one we all at NATO
know and love missed so his present
topic is very relevant to all of us we
use Android phones because as you might
know that even if you take applications
from the trusted sources like Play Store
you actually can be hundred percent sure
that it is it is safe so Roman is going
to do to try to explain how they are
trying to make it safer at least the
floor is yours thank you
okay I will I would like to present our
research about network based technique
vondre smart with application
classification I prepared this with my
colleague Aaron Copland from Sirte ET
and with my boss Ross King the beginning
I will briefly describe what is the
problem why is it necessary then I will
explain two real-life scenarios and I
will turn to base of our associates
Drebin solution for pick a
classification and then I will describe
our approach for neural network for this
solution so by it is dangerous to upload
Marvell
because then user can lose money or his
private data for example here is a porno
player example so I should mention we
got our samples from a kickers company
which is antivirus company from Austrian
and they have a lot of malicious samples
and also been in samples this is one of
malicious samples and it's belongs to a
drone family of Mario applications you
will see in a red circle
user has installed Marga application
because he was motivated by work or not
and what does it make this location
it sends expensive calls too expensive
SMS to some numbers as you see I will
show you the source code later and tall
so why we found it out and and why it is
possible because user gave permission by
installation to do it he hoped it would
be interesting application maybe and so
it's a source code and with red color I
marked important parts of the source
code you see
it is SMS for this expensive numbers and
it's all features I will explain in
details more how we get them but you see
also marked in red why we decide our
approach decided that it's Marvel
occasion so in second sample is take
Netflix application you see the user
also tries to install nest Netflix and
accepts and expects that it is a major
application to see videos of some sales
and application ask him to insert
passport and login then it notice give
not that not that hard doesn't match to
this application he should in the
install this but if he doesn't want to
the install it will try to do it by
itself and in the meanwhile already his
leg in data was passed to Marlboro
server and he has lost his data and in
this sample we found out that it was a
encrypted and he was interesting it was
in source code in plain text almost just
a little bit encoded and for this
application only one scene was important
that application could connect to
internet so you see it's also marked in
red key and also encoded or and below
you see it's a rule - if it's decoded
it's all - a malicious error there are
multiple permissions that user provided
but actually attacker just needs only
one marked in red so if you post an
internet connection
our research started from vapor of
Drebin project done by NASA researchers
but very famous research and Iran with
his students provided further research
and applied support vector machine and
compared to other machine learning
algorithms in order to improve the
results the idea of this Drebin project
was to classified my application for
android and to distinguish from been in
applications this approach was good
because as you see we have different
features splitted by groups and then
they created director and classified and
at the output they could say is it is
possibly a Marvel application and they
could explain why because all features
belonging to this Marvel families in
plain text read the moon feature sets
are combined in some subsets you can see
a brief list actually Android package
contains manifest file and some features
belongs to this mini festival and for
other parts as there is as the source
code analysis and also it contains
different groups subtopics here are some
samples of Marvel families and
associated subsets of features features
are actually a plain text and we analyze
plain text but it's it was Drebin
publication so support vector machine
provided good results it was up to 97
purity of true positive rate previous
speaker already explains is estimation
method
and a false-positive rate is about one
percent but it was a huge feature set
and that was a really a problem because
for some for our sample it was 200
gigabyte it will do con a gigabyte of
ram and that's why we decided to try to
find a nicer approach and developed a
neural network approach it was it it is
good because it requires less ram but
problem is that is not explainable you
know possibly that mostly neural
networks are not explainable because
there are neurons that that have rights
rights are initialized randomly and then
they during the trainings they adjust a
rights so it's not explainable there are
some attempts to make explainable neural
networks but again it is it making
explainable with another neural network
so we don't really can explain this and
we have sets of samples about 1 terabyte
now and it's about 56,000 of marvelous
samples
it's our approach overview we have
situation awareness system and we get
epoca applications code and we use
Drebin code is not public actually we
use source code of simple researches
that try to who try to repeat this quote
according to driven publication actually
it works well and we get features using
this code of hitches as I said some text
and then we parse it and prepare feature
model split we split out the set of
samples into training covilhã Dacian and
test sets
trained our model use these features
I'll explain later in details how we do
it exactly and additional part what is
important this applications the unions
the time changes also attack attacker
methods changes early it was SMS now it
is not more same as some other methods
that's why it's not possible to train
just one model and we decided to train
different models distinguish it by
different rules for instance time from
where we get the smarter samples so each
of these modest ease and situational
warning system one two or three and then
we share our results with people who
requested it
we plan that we had a service where
somebody can upload application and
check if it is already known that is
marvel or not we apply employed for 10
meetings method in our neural network
because it's one of the best to analyze
such text fishes how it works
text cannot be analyzed by neural
network that's why we converted to
arrange into numbers and then for
instance if we would have sentenced
icons very interesting very helpful so I
would give index for each word if what
repeats and it has the same index and in
the next turn we converted to embedding
vector which is where we can just
provide the size and it will be done
automatically and you have seen you you
see here a sample of this is it's just
some numbers and but it's a vector and
which file will create a list of size M
but in embedded words and that is input
for our neural net
for train here is our workflow how we
train it as I already mentioned we get
Fischer first then we check if it's
already now trained model or not if not
then we add it to the model and return
it if yes we just query the model and
then go through a rule engine as I
already mentioned and provide the
classification result which Marvel not
here is a brief overview about about our
rule engine we have for instance just
simple rules for instance which date
which operation system which render
produces static and using appliances
rules we could additionally improve
quality if we have additional knowledge
about some things and we could implement
it in such rule system so this blue
icons are if statements actually and
they produced in conclusion and we
aggregate conclusions and go to results
in some conclusion we our neural network
has different parameters such as
learning rate and vector size maximal
vector size embedding vector size then
we have training loss training accuracy
relation loss validation accuracy and
combine in different settings we
analyzed what is a better performance
for our model and in result we have list
of true positive raise rates and most
post positive rates so then we can
estimate which setting for particular
model provides the best accuracy here is
summary about neural network training
process you see do we have we can
provide how many iterations
of training we will do so here is say
five iterations it was enough and you
see that accuracy taking accuracy and
validation accuracy constantly increases
and then is fix it at some point and
error validation error and training
error as expected are reduced the end
and we used the input layer then we
flatten this input data and we used
addition area the hidden layers to
calculate our model and Sigma it was the
activation function for training model
this is relative operations operating
characteristic that also provides visual
visual result of our calculations with
different settings so on the right in
the right part above in the upper side
you see the perfect classification point
and this red line divides good results
from not so good results and you see
that our all our results are located on
the left side in the higher part so we
can see saying all of them are quite
good results and so perfect
classification point is on the x axis
it's near the one so near to this point
the Baptist result section so I can
conclude that we developed real-time
automatic solution that analyzes
classifies apks in my opinion and we
combined rule engine feature extraction
and neural networks to achieve this
decision support method and I would like
to thanks equals company for provided
samples
[Applause]
see
yes thank you Ramon for trying to keep
us under it user safer we have a time
for a few questions
oh it's a nice question
thank you very much for your great
presentation I have one question
have you been able to test AP case that
actually passed a Google verification
test and ended up in the Play Store and
if so have you been able to detect
malicious apps that ended up there no
it's just draft so prototype and we just
used samples that we got from the Icarus
company we are just related on these
samples also it was important to compare
because we wanted to compare previous
calculation is support vector machine
and if it's new application improves
previous application and previous
application was trained with the same
data to have the same ability to compare
them we need the same data but we are
working in one project now and we
collected we want to collect now much
more samples and would like if somebody
can provide especially Benetton samples
so we would like to try our model on
this new samples yes because it will be
interesting if it would this would be an
additional layer on top of the standard
verification procedure of course
another question what kind of a neural
network did you use like a traditional
let's say shallow neural network or you
went into deep networks if deep neural
network with Walter Manning's sorry it's
a deep neural network with embedded
World War 10 buildings of wartime
buildings is a general approach for this
ok and so if you use a deep neural
network weren't you concerned about the
sides of the train network and and the
computational power required to run it
on the actual phone we run it on server
with Hadoop and GPU but currently we
don't have so much data it was not a big
issue we will look at that problem later
when we have more data but which
actually training itself was quite fast
training yes but what about deployment
because SVM is a very compact model once
trained whereas deep neural network is
can be fairly large even when trained I
mean so yeah but we have splitted it in
different smaller models and we will
also apply this rule engines that we
select which model we apply so it is not
so big in any way
ok thanks ok we have another question
here Roman was any a priori information
known any contextual information known
to the classifier actually not we just
looked some samples we didn't know
anything about the nature of the
applications no we just but we of course
we had a label set from provided from
Icarus company they have possibly say
rules and methods but we just use this
sample the classical unsupervised
learning you know it's supervised
because we had labels also you had but
it was provided by ikarus and how they
decided it it's they
the rules we don't know this rules but
we already had a label that said thank
you okay I have another question here
thank you for the presentation you
showed a very high accuracy of your
system and then you told us that you you
tried your your classifier on several
hundreds of gigabytes of apk
but what was the size of the often
labeled data in order to train us such
as if I label data was fifty six
thousand samples the size it's not not
so extremely big but we know we got
bigger size we will proceed with this
okay do you have any other question no
okay then I will ask you one question so
what should the adversary do to avoid
your detection can another three just
take most popular common application
from Playstore and add some some unknown
malicious code that was not previously
used anywhere something custom oh no
this is a static of course if people
produce customized applications they
have chance to circumvent our model but
it's quite complicated because we also
don't know by ourselves which features
we analyze them automatically and there
is possibly a chance to circumvent it
but possibly not
if this customized quad has some
specific features that we already had in
our trained models and it also will be
detected so if you'll take already known
as caught it possibly will be detected
and just just adjust it somehow okay
thank you no more questions and we can
continue and our next speaker is Mikkel
ko Yuni who is full professor of
security of engineering at the
University of modern energy emilia italy
since the house
his research interests include system
and network security scale vulnerable
architecture and security analytics he
directs the research center on security
and safety the cyber Academy for ethical
hackers and masters in cyber defense
governance for zermatt four sons Bologna
Business School today he is presenting
possibly one of the most important
topics for this future of cyber security
systems that are based on machine
learning so adversarial attacks against
them which are trying to poison machine
learning colleges please thanks very
much those were very kind introductions
so I can leverage the third position
because my colleagues already presented
all the technical details about machine
learning and so I will try to actually
to answer the main question of this
session if artificial intelligence
machine learning and learning canal pass
now and in the future so just a
precision because I'm sorry I'm a
professor I need to to clarify all the
terms so because some people say okay
artificial intelligence is 60 years old
this is not true because in the first
part what we can call the artificial
intelligence 1.0 we tried our goal was
to teach to the machine to resonate so
we define Haunt ologies semantics a lot
of formal meters for reasoning and
actually it didn't work but in the last
10 years we changed completely the
approach now we are trying to teach to
the machine
how to learn and this approach is
working much better the novelty is also
a technological novelty we have a huge
amount of data huge computational power
and so we can introduce a lot of fancy
algorithm
she learning deep learning and whatever
the other colleagues explained so
another point agree that we should
clarify is the real priority the real
importance of all these methods in my
metaphor artificial intelligence is like
a refinery but the refinery is useless
if you don't have oil and oil is
represented by data a notion of data you
need a large amount of them and the
declaration the claims at the end of the
slide are clear which is more important
is the amount of data the amount of data
and the type of data that you choose for
machine learning to train your systems
you made a mistake there the output is
brought fresh in treasure so you need a
huge amount of data a huge amount of
useful and data is not the reality data
is just a portion of the reality is a
representation of the reality so if you
look at this picture you look young
people smiling people we look at data so
the definition of these people is not
the reality nevertheless artificial
intelligence works there are several
problem domains where artificial
intelligence work and this doesn't mean
that artificial intelligence works
everywhere so artificial integers works
very well in computer vision in speech
recognition text interpretation
analytics micro profiling and neuro
marketing is very perfect for profiling
each of you what's very well in games
Ches you remember deep blue didn't go
and even poker this is an interesting
game because is that you have a partial
information about this game on the other
end all the pieces of the chess are on
the table so it's a different problem
and actually artificial intelligence now
helps a lot the bad guys at which
intelligence is used for malware
production at visual intelligence is
used for chat BOTS for information
warfare so there are several problem
domains where artificial intelligence
actually work and improves here by here
but which are the common features of
this problem domain they are clear
definition they have rules you can have
an optimization vector because you know
when the problem and the solution is a
better solution in comparison to the
previous solution on the other end I
think that we are working on the most
complex domain we have no rules
we have no border definition of our
problems and even worse we have to model
human behavior we can model in a certain
way when a precise way the machine
behavior but what about the attackers
what about your people the user of your
machines the insiders I mean is very
very difficult and there is a third
problem we are facing a dynamic a
continuously dynamic problem the other
problems are static if you have to
recognize a cut a cut is always a cut in
our context the data change the problem
change the system of a medium large
enterprise change continuously so we
have this to face this very well-known
problem there is a concept drift where
we don't know the real correlation
between the inputs
and the outputs and the dis correlation
change evolved over times and we have
another problems that the other
presenter explained we have a lot of
good samples even in networks and the
very few malware samples so actually we
can train the machine to recognize the
good but it's very difficult to
recognize the bad because we don't have
enough Sam and if this is not enough and
this is my last challenge is we have
adversarial on the other side on the
other side and this is much much worse
so someone said that this is the
direction I mean I agree that this is
the direction the static solutions the
antivirus the static anta valves the
typical pattern metro solution don't
work anymore
the typical rules for devices firewall
or whatever don't work anymore because
we are facing a continuously evolving
domain so and we cannot manage indeed
the human cannot manage all this amount
of data I mean it's not much whether in
a in a company something like traffic 20
millions of packets per day there is no
way we cannot manage so we need to go
this is the direction the problem is
that the attackers are human as marked
are motivated and so they know that we
are changing the detection rules we are
changing the devices and so they are
also improving their attacks they know
and they are studying how to evade the
dynamic rules that you use for detection
and that versary attacks is very
well-known professor incent early
already explained in
great talk this morning in adversarial
any when with few introduction of pixel
the same algorithm that in the first
part on your left part recognized was
able to classify exactly a cat on the
right part with a small number of pixels
that you cannot recognize was recognized
as a whack-a-mole is a South American
source that in some sense if you saw
this and it's not so different there is
some gray part is some difference so
extremely new is extremely challenging
on the other end the problem with
adversary attack on cybersecurity so in
the paper we tried to introduce a small
taxonomy is not a very huge taxonomy
because the the adversarial can
intervene can influence the data set so
if he knows which is which are the main
feature in a in a random forest model
that I use to recognize to classify a
malicious packet it can introduce more
changes more very small changes that are
not recognized as as an attack but that
change the training of the continuous
training of the algorithm or you can use
the same approach at the operation time
at the test time where there is a there
is a trade-off here if you want to the
tech to detect adversarial attack in
some senses you have to enlarge the data
set you have to have a larger data set
that is recognized as an attack but if
you enlarge that other sects on the
other end you have a lot of false
detection so is a difficult trade-off to
find the right definition of true
attacks and false attack you can violate
the data set the integrity you can
introduce a loss a lot of packets just
to arise a huge amount
alarms that force in some sense the the
system operator to turn off the the
detector so since the first presenter
discussed about random forests we the my
example is on the same direction random
forest is in this case is a good
detector a simplification for our
problem is that we are we need just a
binary classification because the random
forest K user can be used also for
larger sets of a classification the
other end we need just a binary
classification so the idea is that
random for original random forests whose
use uses static parameters and this is
fine for the static problems but in some
sense our problem domain is more fuzzy a
packet can be malicious or not so it can
be malicious with some probability so
instead of reducing the probability part
as a deterministic part we preserve it
the probabilistic path in some sense we
could have a first part of a classifier
with the probability that remains in the
in the model and then which we we train
the the system with this flexible
parameters and then we used in the test
part the interesting point is that you
need to continuously update and train
your model if I can keep your question
this was an interesting question about
can the random forester can be used in
another network oh I'm sure I can guess
that
it will work in another system in the
another method with a different traffic
the question is what if saikhan 2020 we
use a different botnet a different
malware family
this is the real quest and we don't know
we don't know I I can suggest that we
have to change whether wises whistlin
will win I mean they have a good support
so first hint is to change because they
are it and the result was about the
results I I cannot sell you anything on
the on the table you have the the data
set the data set is extremely realistic
we have something about 1 billion
packets in I mean normal traffic where
we introduces 13 types of botnets
so 13 types of malware from this table
you can recognize the problems we have
an a number of net flow in terms of
millions but in the militia flow are two
of three orders of magnitude lower do
you remember my problems how I can train
an automatic and machine learning with
this few in some sense packets with
respect to the normal net flow and okay
I can present just the last results
where you can appreciate that
our algorithm then the state-of-the-art
because our results are always on top of
the previous result indication the
detection rate is high in some sense but
I want to say the truth all the truth
and if you look at the entire picture
that is the 13 or 14 instagrams
top right where an adversarial attack
could change some parameters of the
features that we used for detection so
there are four the first for Instagram
the adversarial attack was could change
just one fifth so in the in the second
set it could change two features and so
on until four features and the final
results is what we expected is a
continuous discrete and decreasing and
this is the truth today
now we can improve the state around
research is his based on this a
continuous improve this improve our
results so the truth is that there is an
assumption an abstention behind the
scene the assumption is that what is
anomalous is also malicious and what is
malicious generates an anomaly but
unfortunately this is not always true so
we have false positive and false
negatives and would you buy a detector
that is precise and 99.99 percent four
four five four nines
will you buy hit yes or no why not come
on 99.99 no it's yes or not it depends
on the number of flaws number of packets
if you have a ten millions packet per
day that is normal 99.99 means at least
1000 false alarm birthday you cannot
manage one
if you know so we don't need 99 we need
99 I mean at least five or six nine
precision and we are not yet there this
is the truth this is the truth on the
other end so positive message even the
biggest cloud provided Microsoft Azure
Amazon Google are using the same thing
so because as I said before the
direction is this there is no
alternative so this is the direction and
they have much better results but they
have much better results because they
have huge huge amount of days later they
don't have millions of date they have
billions and billions of data per day
so summary either you can define a limit
your problem otherwise you need a huge
amount of data to have better better
results and to conclude these are not my
requirements especially the fourth one
so we need fairness explain ability this
is an important point because most of
these deep-learning alchemists work but
we don't know why we don't know why and
DARPA open interesting project about the
explain ability why we want to know the
motivation if we want to apply this
algorithm in the society in the real we
we want to need the motivation why this
alchemist work this should be robust to
an evolving data set and even robusta to
adversarial attacks the fourth one is
scaring for all the technology people
that are around not for the lawyers
because they are trying to say the
organization for
Commerce and development we are trying
to say that organization individuals
that operate and deploy artificial
intelligence should be should be
accountable should be accountable when
should we become must I will go fishing
and sailing because this is dangerous I
mean I agree that the society the real
world want this accountability from us
but this will change the industry
because until now 50 or 60 years of
computer science of computer and
software industry has never never been
liable about the mistake we produce beta
testing products that are not product
you accept patching every week every
month this is not possible when
artificial integer when the software
will become an important part of this
already became a very important part of
the society of the Internet of Things
world accountability liability for the
computer industry by divino for for us
that want to apply this is an important
part thank you very much for your
okay thank you Michael for enlightening
us about problems relating machine
learning in security systems you have a
few time for few questions but before
panel discussion do we have any because
there is one questions there sir here in
the back I really appreciate your talk
I was just wondering as far as obstacles
- I'm back here so I'll stand up as far
as obstacles for improving our ability
to use machine learning algorithms did
you say that our ability to process
large quantities of data is the bigger
obstacle or ability to understand and
articulate to the machine learning
algorithm what it is that we're
providing as inputs no sorry I didn't
say that the impossibility to provide to
manage a huge amount of data is our
limit our limit is to have this huge
amount of data for training to
continuously have this amount of data
for training is I don't think that any I
mean the architectural part of the
machine part is the limit today I mean
the hardware is and the memories always
and always improving things with our
electronics colleagues it's not that the
probability problem is how you can get
this data and that you can manage
continuously changing because I mean as
we are working in an evolving model I
mean the chess are jewels the cat is the
cat the the text is the text but on the
other end I mean the the typical
approach that they have I use a 1
billions photo so billions of text and
then I can train the algorithms on this
on this set and then I can use the
the results for new tests that I didn't
see before I mean in this scenarios the
de algún is work but in our salad
our scenario is not that our scenario is
a continuous change in scenario so it's
not only to manage a huge amount of set
of data now but to manage a huge amount
of data now tomorrow next week and so on
and actually there aren't enough tools
that not yet I mean is a this is an open
it for us is a dream I mean any problem
before a researchers is the dream now
because we have problems to solve
please there are few questions in the
middle you need microphone
so I was curious about whether or not
anyone is actually attempting to develop
and use adversarial models in the real
world to attack machine learning systems
or when you think that might happen and
kind of what industries would be the
focal point for that okay do you want
the truth of the truth I don't know the
truth so is my opinion
the adversary attack I mean the attacker
now don't need not yet because I mean
even the best machine learning
algorithms and as I said before 99 is
not enough so they don't need but what I
can say if you use automatic attack
botnet they use automatic communication
standard communication we can in some
sense address the issue if there is a
human we are in the scene a competent
humans we are in the scene it wins I
mean as usually he wins
thanks please another question a bit
more about this principle of
accountability that's being developed
because from what I understand from what
you explained so they could hold the
person operating that algorithm
responsible but then that person doesn't
know how it's been developed so if I
understood what you were saying sorry no
no okay can you look amazing another
very sure when you were talking about AI
accountability there was something up
there about holding the person the
people developing deploying and
operating the AI systems yes would they
hold the person operating the AI system
responsible even if they hadn't
developed it so that person might not
know how the algorithms been developed
okay luckily this is just a proposal
just a proposal
but I mean the law system the society
wants this I mean there is a famous
example deep learning algorithm is walls
from dogs better than humans
but they didn't know why and after
months after months of research they
recognized that a machine didn't look at
the animal the machine looked at the
environment so an open environment the
boots is recognized as a world with high
probability in a domestic a city
environment today they didn't know the
machine learn by itself mean in some
sense this is real intelligence because
they didn't know at the beginning mud I
mean we cannot accept in the defense in
the society in the military space
something like this that work just war
it's not it's not enough but you just if
so I suggest ok there's another question
professor I particularly like your slide
13 sorry can we go back
among all the other it basically says
that we are looking for anomalies yeah
for us in particular we have an approach
that works much better which his face on
the data representation they the filter
ended up reprocessing we are talking
about forest algorithms algorithms based
on classification we find extremely
useful if we don't let the a neural
network run wild if we pre button the
information like you see in framework
like you see in Fourier transforms
gravel transforms forever to pattern
eyes input set you know in those cases
as I said before we don't get to ninety
percent we don't get to 98 percent but
we get to rates that are pretty robust
against change meaning that when we
change the dataset or we change the
adversary behavior the
she is still useful it doesn't go from
92 doesn't she do you agree with my last
comment
my suggestion combine multiple meters is
I I'm sorry I didn't present the last
claim by I completely agree with you and
I we cannot have just one one approach
we have to combine multiple fir I agree
perfectly this is the dead Iraq you can
take your seat and we will move into
panel discussion so let's let's take
first question for panel setting oh okay
okay
microphone is here
first you know thank you very much for
interesting talk and I do have a kind of
follow-up question actually it's not
you know question but rather than as a
statement you know again on this
thirteen slide and and the statement
that any detection of an anomaly may
lead to a malicious attack which is
pretty true but I would caution not to
generalize these principles because in
AI area in learning we actually for
example let's say emergent behavior of
complex systems the in principle the
emergent behavior leads to discovery to
new forms of species like in a world
like in evolution and they should be
considered like a positive feature
rather than something negative so yes
your statement is correct in the
specific domain but not to generalize in
other systems and processes if I can
generalize your comment it's true I mean
what we have to understand is not just a
model that is training and then a model
that is applied at a model that is
trained that is applied that is
continuously improved and so on and so
in in some sense the training part will
never hand because some emergent feature
can can be everyday answered even
something that you didn't think about or
some correlation that you didn't think
in advance I mean is some sense one of
the most challenging problem setting
that we have because you know different
data different attacks different system
because our systems change
and even without adversarial attacks is
already a really complex problem
this already is a complex problem then a
continuous improvement different model
the integration is the only way I mean
is easier to say than to implement do
you have topic for discussion yes please
I'd like to know just in general what
the panel thinks the impact of quantum
computing would have on their different
models yes and although no patent for
all three of you yeah I miss it quantum
computer and blockchain quantum computer
I don't I mean my colleagues want to
expect there are two quantum computing
it can be divided into different parts
one is quantum communications for
transmission that already worked it was
an interesting display experience from
China satellite to platform one is
whistlin or the other in China and so
quantum communication already wars
quantum computing is is a desire I mean
I mean the problem is still a problem we
are improving improving but we have not
only to improve the hardware part but
then we need a lot of software we have
to change completely the software so
it's not something that will be there in
few years this is on the other end our
community not me already are working on
on post quantum cryptography so the
academic research is already trying to
face the issue of tomorrow as far as I
know I don't know if you have more our
company is working on quantum
cryptography but for artificial
intelligence application I don't know
now it's not developed yet the hardware
and so on it's too early I see
okay another puppy here
thank you for your presentations and a
question for the for the panel it's an
open question in what way would you
think that machine learning would be
helpful in attribution of attack I know
I'm not sure I think for this test case
it's even much much harder to get the
datasets with which you could train such
a system so I don't see a
straightforward way to you earn a
promising way to use machine learning
there but maybe my colleagues have more
ideas emotions no sorry please no
attribution in general is very
complicated problem it's very very hard
to say
artificial intelligence depends on that
and if that is wrong you can produce
wrong attribution results it's dangerous
attribution is the problem all the
international community is based on this
fundamental and the the problem with
attribution is not only I mean we can
easily artifact the source I mean the
where attribution because there was some
comment in Islamic language come on
anybody can introduce some Russian
common source I mean it's not enough
it's not enough I think that these
models can help to circumvent the
problem mean something that should be in
this area because they use this tool but
then you need others other means I mean
you need other means that other other
approaches against is a combination is
any digital investigation is not
cannot be just digital not just based on
digital because in attack I mean I don't
think that there are any people now that
say they're build a completely new
malware a completely new botnet a new
button it is a combination of different
parts that are in the wild so the
attackers typically at the some software
combine had some masquerading some new
cryptography but most of the software is
already there is already there so can
you say that no it's not the environment
well you can say this I can tell you in
private there is a station here I don't
like polonium M
thank you do we have another topic no
then I will ask you a final question
with expected one sentence answer should
we be concerned about machine learning
in security systems in 5-10 years or are
we going in in some dangerous direction
the direction as I said that the
direction is this there is no the
problem is the the finish line and we
are not arrived on on the probably there
will not be a finish line I mean the
problem the society should decide which
is the autonomy that we want to give to
the machines I mean this is the real
question for a Anatoly for security how
much the machine can take the power in
games they want I mean in chess go poker
they win every time so they are better
than us in other context they are better
than us
Health System imagery connection they
are better than us in other open
environment where the decision is not
clear when we cannot apply a clear
optimization function because all the
machine learning is a actually data and
optimization and continuous optimization
if we don't tell the this optimization
file if we don't take the ground truth
we have a problem with the ground truth
we cannot compare the previous results
with another one it's difficult the
probably is not of the machine Lamy the
problem is is a is our problem that
decide to the odd source this decision
to a machine it's not a problem of the
machine the machine does whatever he can
but in some in some areas before quantum
computing that will open new issues and
they will open over a new solution we
are in the middle now there is an
interesting case as I know it is
Japanese so check that lose 20 millions
dollars because the algorithmic a
financial an algorithm enansal
investment made mistake it was to suit
the algorithm of the of the product so
it's something strange can you sue an
alchemist a it is related also to the
problem with assignment to liability I
mean it's a very interesting open
question that the society lawyers
politicals
and the technology we have to solve and
I mean I don't have the solution I don't
think that anybody here as the so this
is the solution we have to study I mean
if there is a positive effect of this
Congress is that we we can collaborate
we can discuss from different
different cultures and this I think that
is the real direction to discuss
together okay thank you roll on do you
have any concerns about future of
machine learning
I seen it depends on particular change
in some cases it's very good applicable
like image processing and some high risk
tasks maybe it's too dangerous because
we will not get hundred percent accuracy
okay Roland any final thoughts I think
we are at least in cybersecurity it's
not that we need to be worried about
what machine learning does it's more
that we need to be aware that machine
learning probably does not do everything
we want and it's always machine learning
more helps to fight against things that
we know or that happen in the past and
we have on the other hand skilled
attackers that do things that we do not
expect and that our machine learning
does not expect we cannot expect the
machine learning to defend us against
everything okay thank you let's give a
round of applause