good morning ladies and gentlemen we are
just about to start our last scheduled
press conference here at web site if
your advisor to welcome here mr. John
Liu Lu Jia eminent European person and
an terrorist expert of Council of Europe
from Strasbourg and mr. Sebastian for
Nico lecture of security studies and
international and european law at the
George Marshall European Center for
Security Studies and he as government
official he worked for several years in
the Federal Council area where he deals
with question related to security issues
parliamentary oversight and terrorism
gentlemen
thank you just some remarks and some
question about your problems or
financing terrorism which is maybe right
now with new attacks in Europe strands
and inverses crucial issue because it
was not possible of car to carry out
search operation to finance or certain
groups because my expectation that I
think we have more than 50 persons or no
oh all the group had not been Dementors
as a time and maybe between 15 maybe 100
people at a lot and so that's mean to
have to have resources or money and the
problem of financing is crucial is very
important to make a difference for me
according to my experience about what we
have you know in Syria and N and in the
call you know an anorak we have a lot of
money you know dash succeeded to have an
impressive amount of money several
billions of US dollars that's not seen
before but in fact you know the sense
operating outside you know the network's
implied involve in operations to you
know to detect you know the target to
organize you know the operations to have
safe house to have you know a munitions
rifle and so on that's a fine answer is
a small financing system and this
financing system is you know connect
comes from criminality the connection
between the terrorists and criminality
is not very new you know I've
experienced that before before and the
problem you know and all this money
comes not from some comes from South
Syria not really because it's very
difficult to transfer money they know
that you monitor by any systems are you
as a French users have the possibility
to connect and two monitors
the financial market is finish of the
banks so is a palimony you know on
rotary and and and there are many many
means for that you know the burglars you
know the fruits the credit card frauds
and specially right now something
they're quite new and very important is
the traffic the smuggling of cigarette
ebc trade of tobacco that's representing
very important about right now about 10
million 10 billion of euro per years you
know in Europe that's a lot of course
this money was not used only by that is
used by you know the criminal by the
black the black market but is the
important resources where was this
country feed product also is quite use
you have many meanings saying that that
so that's the reason why is very
difficult for us for the law enforcement
to judiciary intelligence to detect this
flow because the exchange is by cash and
don't you have no trace about that
that's a very big problem the other
reason why it is very important you know
to exchange information between zero
enforcement agency inside the country
and outside in order to detect them to
staunch this money because if you
succeed that we have a very good blood
we know to stop the terrorist operation
thank you very much good morning ladies
and gentlemen yesterday night night old
session was a very good opportunity not
only to visit what what you Jia Jia just
explained
organized crime terrorism nexus in the
narrow sense in a specific area but also
in the in a broader context if you wish
that the maser Angela de Marco level so
latest research shows we can talk about
a crime instability Nexus right whereas
in former times we fought like okay
organized crimes organized crime
terrorism is terrorism now with a fert
player the so-called shadow facilitator
or the fixers or the super fixers we
have a phenomenon which is much more
dangerous so it's about the proceeds of
crime the money she was was talking
about which is then going to enter in
may be legitimate business real estate
what what what have you and it has a
destabilizing effect in transition
countries in post-conflict countries
also in the Western Hemisphere and some
of the latest academic say this is
undermining the understanding of
sobriety or the westphalian state if you
if you wish and that of course will
probably hinder development look just
look at the figures were organized crime
is or crime and the Human Development
Index you will find it matches and this
danger we were able to discuss yesterday
night
thank you very much this is the space
for your questions
good morning Susanna Gabrielle from your
active my question would be whether
there are any indication that some of
the financing of terrorism in Europe
comes from the finances that the
smugglers of refugees are able to do
collect within the current refugee
crisis yes yes and no be careful we
could have some connections but for me
the connection is not the most important
the problem is manipulations that's very
crucial because it's not because we have
discovered some three or four peoples
who are involved you know in the Paris
attacks or Britain's as a matter of fact
that means that all the refugee refugee
is the flows of Asia is a main stream
you know to to conduct you know
terrorists in Europe's but but you know
the problems that that dash manipulate
these systems in orders to make you know
to make to promote the terror filling in
Europe that's a new tool of terrors and
so we should be very prudent of course
because because the manipulation is
democratic order is emphasized by the
media the media of course you know focus
about this problem and and and the goal
of that is to make you know it make you
know that to make a disturbed in inside
our society and try to oppose some you
know clan in our peoples in our society
in others to make you know a big disturb
right that's the goal you know to break
the consensus or social consensus you
know in our democratic order does it
also we should be very prudent about
that myanna that's a matter of fact that
use but in fact I think it's one one
person no more the problem is elsewhere
but the manipulation is much more
important is very dangerous
okay next question is the magic thank
you under my check daily pravda could
you please say a little bit more about
this next as you mentioned the organized
crime purism and start because yeah we
have this discussion at blob sick but
correct me if I am wrong but I don't
think this is like a really new
phenomenon so maybe it was evolving
somehow and maybe a little bit more
broadly I don't know I'm writing about
those issues in all 13 years and of
course we are always talking about the
financing terrorism and stopping finance
so if you can you say for example I
don't know from them from 9-11 what
happened what where are our successes
and and a little bit also about failure
thank you
huge pleasure will will will tell you
that the phenomenon is not new what we
believe in in a marshal center and we
have 700 students from the security
architecture from all over the world for
a year in our college so there is a
exchange also with practitioners from
from from out there is the understanding
maybe that the threat perception is is
new if the fish on this nexus for
instance there is diamond mining
somewhere in central Africa which is
probably not done in the legitimate
sense as we believe mining should should
be done in our part of the world then
how do you get it out from there you
need a shadow facilitator how do you get
it across oceans you need a shadow
facilitator and then the end user the
final destinations so there's there's a
sort of a hierarchy yeah but ultimately
this is this is all in flux and the
security architectures are now about to
understand it there are international
tools now on the table some are still in
the drafting process plus as mr. bouge
pointed out we need to cooperate more on
that we need to share information not
only state to state but also the
institutions inside the state maybe also
state public sector and private sector
many many many players ultimately how do
you fight a network of a network
and this is this is what we try to
achieve
ok now you agree now cooperation is
crucial right now you know where we are
facing a global threat that's a matter
of fact no but the response is too many
fragmented right now especially inside
of the country because the connections
sometimes is not sufficient between your
intelligence the police you know the ROI
enforcement says judiciary we have some
connection quite will be difficult and
so the response you know is not
responsive it's not you know we cut
waste time in response that's a very big
problem and the major problem for me is
Europe Europe you know is big problem as
you know because the cooperation is
globally good is not a problem no
political issue for that but in fact
practically speaking it's much more
complicated because it sort is a set of
sovereign state the premier sovereignty
as you know you know the prime of
security globally speaking is only of
the capitals of a member state not of
European Union's you know Europe all or
you resist adjustment to make
corporations they are not is not FBI
system you know of course and so the
prime of cooperation is crucial and yo
what is important for example that each
member state I have experiences in my
when I was in our dokie and I'm is on
you know perspective and experience in
thread in no specifics of the strength
the passage of the sweat in France was
not the same you know 10 years ago was
his pain for Spain was important it was
a there is open to the basque programs
UK was IRA remember that so it's very
difficult you know speaker is speaking
to have you know to have the same
intensity of a detection for two two or
three sweat you focus on one and you can
neglect users and so problem is you know
if you do that you end a mine in Rihanna
the global you know fight and
understanding your batteries because it
is I'm not this agenda yeah they use the
global you know the globality of
Europe's they move very quickly from one
state to others same solution can zone
and so from if you have not a global
understanding and reactions in real time
we can you know we can succeeded in the
future
okay thank you very much unfortunately
we are short of time so we have to
finish so I want to thank the gentleman
for being with us and thank you for
attention
the last scheduled press conference let
me thank you for your attention for
cooperation and thank you for your
interest about Bob sake and I wish you
safe journey back home
you