hi
about that life is mine home a fourth
grade and I like to talk and I really
like Consulate's 2014 is my first Def
Con for me I'm like everything security
jailbreaking buzzing sniffing and all
that other stuff capture the flag
what is it temporary flag is a game
where you try to compete against others
teams or individuals you try to get the
most points less importantly you try to
learn something you try to have fun
while doing it
flags are points from skinny simple
answer after Clinton's here's an example
what is the binary and for the fly to
answer can be the binary below 85 can
also be found or captured by complain as
complex task for example
you can be digging for a pcap files
packet capture you can be identifying
some logon credentials and you can log
into once I using this and logon
credentials and finally running SQL
injection against our base and tried to
obtain the black what makes a good
flight
I've been flagging it hard to guess its
unique within the game and it's supposed
to be long and random if it's not want
to lose too much can easily get it and
get points for it may 2016 is when
Facebook releases their capture the
flying framework as open-source it
supports both jeopardy 18 the Hillsdale
cps it's easy used mostly inexpensive
and it's excellent for schools teachers
and you can also use this for stuff
besides securities you want to tell
someone
another same maybe history maybe
something about our anything you can
install it using the readme file into
github repository
is a non vagrant install with virtualbox
wants 14 . go for my little box that i
use less makeup a parrot on as my host
system it's basically only really for
command to install the admin panel has
the ability to immense during the game
do announcements setup levels flying
aces control game time and you can
guarantee but most importantly change
the admin password about some global
thermonuclear war
I mean for him out here i have it
running so I lobbying to I prayed in our
admin account because the first time an
account password was too much here
begins configuration you can rip mystery
game you can login you can configure
login you can edit the game you can
control the meantime how long you want
to hear they can make announcements so
hello this later review when i login as
user here's the quiz level already have
set up i'll show you how to add one it's
very simple you can find me title you
can put it very well
you can put the quiz an actual question
you can select the country to be Auto
with children is a random country for
you and we're being sprayed it on the
game or you can also put a hit if you
like you can also bend ahead penalty
open it as 10 points your categories if
you have one topic you can group into
one category if it's too messy in tears
the flying it's kind of like the quizzes
titled your description the flag answer
points and bases are really 14 the help
sell cts really haven't gone team skills
yet you are countries that you can
enable if you would like you can
customize teams here walk is where
everything shows up we so let's begin
the game here we have it started now
let's log let's show you the game board
as well be hanged up already use the
Queen's flag business now i'll show you
what it looks like from of teams and
here's what it looks like as a user
was the binary
freeze
this is what it looks like let's show
you what it looks like when you get it
wrong you see that's what looks like we
get it we set up a quiz level or flags
the most important thing to do is make
sure you take yes
you actually make sure you have the
thing select as for me I always did
you have to make sure you turn on over
here a bunch of people forget that it's
on the most important thing to you
mostly everything you is has an on/off
button you have to make sure you got on
in order for people so here's what it
looks like when you register an account
on your main email teaming and passed so
when i get the announcement earlier i'm
putting you can see the announcements I
made right here if you would like to see
what song they're going to hear
currently amanat need this is at the
point right that is basically what
caption file looks likely set up if you
want to set up you have to go to get
help
probably here LLL tell you
calm / facebook /
here's all the files in it will tell you
how to install