hello everyone and welcome to the secure
developer if it's your first time
joining us our community that is to
educate and enable developers and
application security and today I am
joined by Travis McPhee hi Travis
hello before I heard let me Travis
quickly once and introduce myself so my
name is Sam - and I'm actually the
community manager yeah working behind
the scenes to make everything happen so
any questions and session ideas anything
like that and ping me a message on
Twitter slack email and I'm happy on to
them slack is actually the best place to
go and to interact with Travis today so
if you're not part of our community if
you hop on to be secured and join the
slack and join live sessions you can ask
your questions interact as well as if
you watched it watching the session post
recording and have questions pop them in
there and either Travis or one of our
community members can answer them for
you
the last thing so housekeeping is if
you're watching this on YouTube there is
a cog on the bottom right hand corner if
you turn your resolution up to maximum
it's actually the best way to do today's
session and the skill developer is
powered by sneak they aim to bring a
vendor-neutral community to share
knowledge and best practice so huge
thanks to them and but I think that's
enough for me so I'm gonna hand over to
Travis Travis welcome again thank you so
much
and I am going to briefly close my
browser like a pro good so welcome
everybody thank you so much for spending
the morning with me or the evening or
the afternoon wherever the case may be
today we're going to talk about at least
privileged in AWS as soon as I share my
slides cool so hello again I'm Travis
McGee if you feel so inclined you can
follow me on Twitter
I'll probably follow you back I'm on
LinkedIn but let's jump right into it so
I like
show this slide because the way that I
kind of think about you know depends in
depth and and in controls and stuff is
is it hopefully you've all seen one of
the obstacle course shows like the
ultimate beast master for American Ninja
Warrior this is ultimate beast master I
work for Netflix so I'm contractually
obligated to plug Netflix shows at any
open opportunity but basically the idea
is that you get these really strong
people and you know some of the
strongest people in the world they're
gymnasts they're rock climbers they're
all these amazing people and then you
build a super difficult obstacle course
and the idea is that the obstacle course
becomes so difficult that even these
super-strong people can't get their way
through and I kind of liken this in in
what we're doing in cybersecurity to the
attack chain and the cyber kill chain so
an attacker is trying to do something in
our environment something we don't want
them to do
maybe that steal our data maybe that's
take our site down do you face something
like that and our job so they're in in
this analogy they are the contestants
they are the people trying to get
through the obstacle course and we are
of course are the obstacle course
builders so we can layer these cool
controls on repo kit which I'll be
talking about today stream alert de
misto are alerting stack which I've
talked about and other points and then
of course some super confidential secret
sauce which we're never going to talk
about we layer these controls on and we
get hopefully into a state where even
the best attackers are going to try to
get through our obstacle course and are
going to get thrown off into the water
and disgraced at some point and that
that's kind of what we're trying to do
here we're trying to build this really
good obstacle course now of course this
is just one step we'll talk about others
but for today we're talking about lease
privilege and why don't we just it seems
so obvious everybody talks about it
let's just lease privilege hopefully
I'll convince you that it's not quite
that simple we'll give a little bit of
context about AWS and how this
specifically works here and then we'll
launch straight into you our approach
here at Netflix which leads well into
repo key at our open source tool for
doing this kind of work and
some next steps that we're taking and
that you might take if you're interested
as well so why don't we just leave llege
it seems pretty easy right it's been
around since 1975 if you had any formal
training in security or took classes in
school or you've been in security in the
industry you'll probably have heard of
this concept it's pretty simple it's
basically you just give the whoever is
using a system the minimum level of
access that they need to do it and this
was formalized in this paper the
protection of information and computer
systems by Saltzer and Schroder way back
when computers look like this and you
would think it's like okay this isn't
new like it's been around for you know
well over 40 years at this point why are
we just doing it so if I want to give
you access to a document I will only
give you like maybe read or edit access
on that one document I'm not going to
give you every single document that I
own right that's pretty obvious so given
all this it's been around forever it
makes sense you can articulate it to
your dad or somebody
everybody's got least privilege right
not even close it turns out that least
privilege is one of those things where
when you start reading about breaches
and things that went wrong in security
it's like lease privilege what it made
this better or at least privilege would
have stopped it and you wonder like okay
well these people care about it they're
very smart people working on this
problem why is it not happening a few
problems one of them is that you get
these permissions that are kind of like
frozen in time you know like like an
artifact the the reason this happens is
you typically do a review right you're
your own security team and you're
meeting with an application team or vice
versa and the application team says ok
we kind of think that we need this set
of permissions to get done and if the
application team ever ends up needing
more than that set of permissions you'll
definitely hear about that because they
they're blocked they need new
permissions to get their job done but
you don't really hear about that other
way where it's like oh actually we've
got more permissions that we need and so
you kind of get this
this fossilised set of permissions that
that you came to agreement in that one
time that you had a meeting with the
team 25 months ago or whatever you don't
want over provision permissions has
anybody ever I know I've never done this
for sure but has anybody ever been
working with a NIC system and just said
I don't know what permissions this file
needs I'm just gonna seven seven seven
and it'll probably work or you know I
don't know every time I pseudo blah blah
blah just it just sort of works out well
for me like this is this is over
provision and I understand why this
happens its permissions are pretty hard
it's difficult to wrap your mind around
if this isn't something that you do day
in and day out as part of your job
they're really hard to understand and
especially when you're working on a
problem you don't want to stop context
switch out of that and figure out
exactly what permissions you need so you
kind of like just just give it admin
just give it 777 just sudo this this
command and everything will work out and
then of course you'll go back and fix it
later but we're all busy that doesn't
happen as often as we'd like and then I
think in my personal opinion this is
probably the biggest reason that we have
over over permission or not least
privilege is because permission granting
the whole ceremony associated with it
sucks like you have you have this kind
of adversarial situation you really
shouldn't have it I mean everybody's
sort of on the same page which is that
security team application team everybody
wants the permissions for the app that
the app actually needs and yet the way
that they're approaching the problem is
subtly different enough such that it
becomes this kind of like adversarial
you know time-suck everybody's kind of
like oh I might need it down the road
just give me these permissions and the
whole process associated with it like
let's say that one of these meetings
took 10 minutes which i think is I think
it's generous I think they typically
take longer than this with the overhead
of going to a meeting and the number of
people that need to be in the room to
actually make a decision and you know we
live in a we live in a CIC Dee
constantly deploying you know a single
app might have five deploys a day and we
live in a micro service world where now
instead of one big monolith we've got
hundreds or thousands of many services
which are apps and they each need their
own permissions and so when you do the
numbers on this you figure out that the
the overhead to an organization of
having these kind of meetings quickly
just spirals out of control and so we
don't want all that I think this is a
really big reason why at least privilege
isn't done well is because everybody
just kind of bummed out on these
meetings and so because you have the
they don't permissions don't really get
smaller because everyone just leaves
them alone and doesn't really ever give
permissions back voluntarily and and the
meetings suck and all this you kind of
get this sort of gravity that pulls
policies larger over time and they just
sort of you know like this astronaut
here they just sort of like float off
into space which is exactly the opposite
of what we want this is not what salts
are in Schroeder we're thinking when
they define lease privilege in 1975 so
there needs to be a better way in a
physical world this all sort of just
happens it just makes sense it works out
for example if I move out of my
apartment it has never happened that my
landlord has forgotten to get my keys
back like this is just like yep of
course you no longer need the
permissions to this apartment and so
you're gonna give them up and similarly
if I stop working at Netflix 100% sure
my badge is not gonna work tomorrow like
it just happens nobody ever keeps those
privileges around for longer than needed
if I don't renew my passport on a
regular basis at some point I'm going to
show up at the airport
and it's not gonna work they're not
gonna let me out of the country they're
not gonna let me on the plane so these
are kind of all examples of a least
privileged approach that works in the
physical world but tends to break down
in the software world where these kind
of status changes nobody really pays
attention to you
and what I mean by status changes so we
had I'm moving out of my apartment right
that's a status change that's Travis no
longer has access to his apartment but
the software that we're developing is it
and actively maintained anymore or the
developers change positions or now it
does this whole new pile of things these
are also status changes and they aren't
tracked well in software and so while we
get the hey it's time to giving your
keys in the physical world we don't
really get this in software
and so I don't know about you but I'm
definitely you know I've been personally
aware of abandoned projects where there
were developers they were certainly
excited about working on it at the time
and then they've moved off there they
went to some other company they moved
under a different project and those
applications are still running today
these with the exact same permissions
that they were running before except for
now they're not getting patched nobody's
paying attention to them and these
represent big-time liability in an
organization especially as you consider
the sheer magnitude of number of
projects like this that a large
organization is likely to have so if you
have a really small environment you know
you're working on startup you're lucky
enough that you're a security person and
there are relatively small number of
developers and small number of apps then
you can probably just take care of this
yourself you'd say oK we've got a we are
apt changed we need new permissions or
app change we don't need these
permissions anymore here's the new
permissions the option have that kind of
stuff that seems reasonable for a really
small environment but I would argue that
that is not the reality that most of us
are dealing in which is these extremely
complicated you know I can mentioned
earlier system of interconnected micro
services that are doing multiple ships a
day or very large projects lots of
different things going on every company
that I've ever been a part of feels a
lot more like this metropolis than the
small house situation and so much so
that the manual approach of let me just
think about the permissions that the app
needs isn't gonna work here we go back
on track so let's talk about specifics
about the better approach here so this
will probably be recap for some of you
please bear with me we'll get on to the
fun stuff in a minute I promise but AWS
is the cloud
provider that Netflix uses and AWS
implements a really nice role based
access control system or our back if
you're a security nerd via the Identity
and Access Manager service so Identity
and Access Management is a AWS service
and it provides API api's that you can
call just like s3 and an AWS has other
well-known services and the whole
purpose of it is to implement role based
access control which was which is this
system where you can say Travis gains
access to his apartment basically and so
in AWS you have applications probably a
lot of them if you're the big
organization like we talked about and
those applications assume roles the
roles have policies attached to them and
each of those policies defines basically
what the role or application can do with
what other AWS services and resources so
let's uh let's use an example here to
make this a little bit more clear let's
say that we're going to implement a
cloud-based word processor right so
something like think like Google Docs or
something so what are we going to have
we have an application it's going to
read and write files delete files stuff
like that and it's going to if you were
doing this in Amazon world you'd
probably want an object store and the
object store would be s3 so here's what
a policy could look like for your word
processor so this is like this is first
cut and please look at the policy and
tell me what you think I put the little
newspaper emoji up here because I would
say that if you have this kind of policy
then you're probably going to end up in
the news at some point and not in a way
that you want people are gonna come
storming it on your door and saying why
is the word processor suck like why do
we get this breach basically what we're
doing here is we're saying the word
processor is essentially full admin on
your account which probably is not what
you want especially as you start
thinking about what else is running in
the account is the word processor the
only thing
okay well even if it is you probably
don't want if it gets compromised you
don't want the word processor to be able
to you
change your organization or turn on the
shield service which cost $36,000 a year
all kinds of other calls that you can
make with admin so I would argue and
hopefully you agree with me that this
policy is not good
okay let's refine it a little bit let's
say that instead of full admin we change
it to this which basically means that
your s3 admin hopefully the scream emoji
here conveys my my feelings about this I
still say this is not good and the
reason is because do you really need s3
admin do you need to be able to do
anything with any bucket if is there if
there's something else in the account
for example one thing that you could do
with s3 admin is you can make the
buckets public so every bucket the
bucket that your word processor is
dealing with is now on the Internet and
if you're paying attention to the news a
lot of companies have done this
accidentally or or just forgotten to
turn it back on so this is not good we
want to apply more restriction for this
and get that scream emoji to come to a
happier emoji all right now we're
getting somewhere
we've swapped s3 star for s3 specific
actions get object and put object which
is Amazon's version of read and write
and the problem that the the reason that
this is still not ideal for us is
because we're scoped to the star
resource which basically means that our
word processor can read and write
objects from any bucket in the account
and if you have code tenancy meaning
your word processor is sitting next to
other applications that you're
developing on such as maybe Google
sheets or something like this then if
the word processor gets compromised then
it can read and write documents from
Google sheets which breaks your your and
and ozzie models and is not something
you want so we're gonna swap that with
our deal state which is that this is
this is what we're trying to get to you
this is our Holy Grail
now we've got specific actions specific
services and the specific resource that
we need to do it for all right so this
is this is what we're shooting for so to
get there we're going to use D
the Amazon gives us in the form of
service action and resource usage and to
show how this works let's talk about
another example it is October now crown
is coming back soon I'm really excited
about it and of course you know like I
mentioned contractually obligated to
pitch all the Netflix shows so let's
talk about a really cool app that's
going to use some machine learning or
something like that and and put a crown
image on top of any person's face that
sounds pretty cool to me so we're gonna
implement that in AWS and we're
basically it's gonna be an app it does
some it's gonna access a bucket that
contains images of people's face and
it's going to write out new images that
contain the person's face with a crown
on it
and something that we're probably going
to need here is a queue and the queue is
going to tell us when new people's faces
come into the bucket and then we have
work to do so it Netflix the way that
this works is that every application
starts off through our deployment tool
which is called spinnaker and the
developers will come in and say I want a
new app so I'm the developer of this
cool crown app I come in I said I click
the button new app I say Travis's cool
crown app deploy and then it gives me a
role and that role has a base set of
permissions associated with it and it's
basically the same for everybody now
these permissions are things that we've
noticed over time the developers tend to
really need and so everybody gets the
same ones and it should cover you know
well above 95 percent of people's use of
cases out of the box and then once my
Crown app is deployed and working repo
kid in the process that I'm talking
about here we basically use these to
passively watch the application for 90
days and see which permissions are being
actively used now the reason we picked
90 days is two reasons actually at
Netflix we've got something called the
quarterly deprecation cycle and this
means that developers
are expected to redeploy their
application at least once a quarter and
so there are some permissions that may
be exercised only on instance start and
even those permissions we shall have we
should have observed once a quarter if
developers are adhering to this product
practice and also we just we think it's
a pretty reasonable amount of time to
let applications settle into steady
state you know ninety days is a while it
at the beginning when you have a new app
developers are iterating on it we're not
exactly sure what they're gonna need yet
but after after it quarters so we tend
to see that it sells down pretty well so
we're passively monitoring for the first
ninety days and then after that we're
gonna start doing stuff
so after 90 days we start taking away
unused permissions now I remember our
crown app is going to read and write
objects from s3 which is people's spaces
and modified people's spaces with the
crown image and it's going to receive
cue messages about when new work is
available for us but whatever these dots
were like we don't need the rest of that
crap so repo kid will actually take the
applications role it'll edit it to
remove the unused permissions and then
it'll save it back and and save a
version so in case we have to rollback
or anything and that's the way repo kid
works basically reads the role makes
these changes saves it back in the IAM
service and then saves a backup version
so let's say that the crown adds scope a
little bit right now we need to do
something new that we didn't have to do
before or you know one of those things
that we had removed we actually do end
up needing this is pretty easy instead
of that horrible like sit down
10-minute meeting 10 minutes at best I
mean we're talking like our meetings
hour and a half meetings we don't have
to do any of that anymore this is a
simple swing by my desk this is a simple
slack request
I need generally this class of thing and
then we can add it and we're not even
very worried about is this the exact
right set of permissions because we know
that repo kid is going to automatically
take us down to least privilege over
time so we don't have to spend all this
time thinking so much about it so in the
case of you know these things that were
removed it doesn't matter what they are
but a couple of them get put back and
that's not something the repo kid does
that's a manual process by us developers
or sorry us as the security team but
it's much simpler than that that picture
of the awful meeting that I showed
earlier and then when developers stop
using permissions at all like you know
like let's say that I move on and I'm
not doing the the crown application
anymore they get removed and so I'm like
hey I'm not I'm not doing this crown
thing it's abandoned like that picture
of the abandoned village I showed
earlier the whole thing the whole policy
gets zeroed out which is super cool
because those
unused you know forsaken applications
where the developers have all moved on
are completely powerless in our
environment after a quarter and that we
feel D risks us a lot so with all that
being said what do you think you want to
jump in you want to buy some repo Kid
figure out how this thing works well
you're on a webcast and you can't really
tell me now so I'm gonna go ahead so
let's let's dive into specifically the
mechanics of repo kid how it's doing the
updates the data sources that it uses
and all that stuff and in order to do
that we need to jump in a little bit
more back into the policy mechanics of I
am so this is a very simple statement it
allows the the role or the application
to list the contents of example bucket
and there's a few parts here that are
important the the effect which is
allowed there there are also deny base
statements but in the case of Netflix to
keep everything simple and to make it
easy to understand what permissions are
actually in scope or out of scope we
just use allow statements in all times
for the most part we have we have a few
denies but those are not those are an
exception rather than the normal case
and then the action so this is there we
go the action so this is s3 list bucket
which is you know you can think of it in
s3 object store like the ability to list
a directory right like what's in the
bucket what are in sub directories and
stuff like that and then the specific
resource that this is applying to so the
example bucket and so repo kin is going
to the the basic the basic daily flow of
it is that it operates you know for us
on a bunch of accounts but for each
account it jumps in there and it lists
all of the roles it key it maintains a
data store which is all of the roles it
knows about and their current state and
so it'll first list all the roles see
has anything changed with
and then write all that back to its
table and then on a daily basis it'll
figure out what role what permissions
are being actively exercised by this
role and what permissions does it have
and then it takes those two and combines
them to do a diff and based on the diff
like okay we have these 20 permissions
but only these ten are being used so
we're going to remove the other ten and
then it stores the these are the
permissions that can be removed in its
table and then periodically which for us
is once a week we go and we say schedule
a repo which means we let developers
know that unused permissions are going
to be taken away and then a week after
the repo schedule will actually go in
repo so to do the first part which is
the diff which permissions are being
used that we can take are not being used
we can take away we're gonna use three
data sources the first one this really
cute little aardvark in the in the
Netflix sweater is our proxy for access
advisor which is an Amazon service and
it tells us which services so an
application remember has permissions and
the permissions give it access to
services like s3 ec2 queues and access
advisor is great and then it says on a
service by service level for every
application what's being used and what
is not being used at all now when we
created aardvark access advisor was only
available in the UI but since then
amazon has made it available via an API
and the reason that we keep aardvark is
because it's useful to have a cache of
the data so repo can just for a little
context repo can for some of our large
accounts could take up to 45 minutes to
run and we want to complete the entire
repo period within the early part of our
daily operation but we don't want repo
kid making changes to roles after we all
go home and so we want to keep the
actual repo time window short and to do
this we want to have all of the access
advisor data and every other piece of
data that we need ready to go and so
that's what aardvark does for us it's
basically just a queue of access advisor
data
I'm sorry it's a cache of access advisor
data we also use cloud trails the cloud
trail
unlike access advisor which can only
tell us on a service level either yes
something is within the service is being
used or no nothing of the service is
being used cloud trail can give us
specific actions that are being used but
it doesn't work everywhere so there is
there's some caveats some actions are
not tracked at all in cloud trail so
like even with them a service did there
are just untracked actions and then data
plane operations generally are not
tracked as well so while we might have
well we might have like s3 create bucket
by default that'll show up and and s3
reads will not so the create bucket is
what's considered a control plane
operation and s3 get object is a data
plane operation and for s3 you can
actually turn on cloud trail for data
plate operations but for other services
you cannot so we have no way to see for
example in cloud trail when things are
being read from a sqs queue so that's
why it's useful to blend a few of these
data sources together is because access
advisor and aardvark can tell us part of
the story and cloud trail can tell us a
different part of the story and finally
another data source that we have is is
in our case s3 server access logs but
you can get the same thing with s3 cloud
trail and basically this is this gives
us the data plane visibility for
specifically for the s3 service so we're
gonna take these three data sources and
we're going to show how repo kid would
make changes based on what on on what
they say to a slightly more complicated
policy than the one we saw before so
we've got this policy and it's got its
got some ec2 which is Amazon's compute
service it's got some s3 actions and
it's got some sqs and some Q actions and
first up we can query access advisor and
see that the application is not actually
using any of the
to stuff at all so we can just
completely get rid of this entire Q
block which is pretty cool
we've already dropped our permissions
down significantly and then next up we
can use cloud trail to determine that
excuse me we can use cloud trails to
determine that some of the ec2 actions
specifically the ability to create a
volume is not being used and so we can
remove that as well and finally we can
use our s3 server access logs or s3
cloud trail whichever and determine that
the application is not actually using
all s3 buckets of course it's just using
maybe one or two in this case it's using
the bucket name my bucket name bucket so
by combining these three data feeds
together we can actually trim this
policy significantly beyond what any
individual data feed would allow us to
do so in Netflix the the way it is this
is working we've got this tool repo kid
it's updating the data it's using these
three data feeds and then applying back
what it thinks roles could keep and
remove and we update we use repo kit and
we update this data every single day and
we run it across all of our accounts and
then we have the accounts all of our
accounts split into two groups and their
I think they're actually internally just
called a and B and it doesn't really
matter like what they are we just don't
want to do you for a given stack we
don't want to do the test and prod at
the same time and so we have if we have
like our main tests and main prod main
tests will be an A and main prod will be
in B and then for our actual repoing and
scheduling we run on a tick-tock
schedule so maybe the you know on
Tuesday the first week of the month
we're going to schedule a and repo B and
then Tuesday the next week we'll do the
opposite of that well schedule the one
that we just repoed and will reap other
when we just schedule now scheduling
involves some hooks and hooks in my
opinion are one of the coolest parts of
repo kid they be we have an upstream
open source
but some of the business logic the repo
kids using is going to be a little
specific to organizations such as how do
we notify application owners and Netflix
this is all internal software tools that
we have API is that we can call to find
out who owns this role like what what
application does the role map to you and
then what team owns that application and
then just send them an email and let
them know what's happening so we have a
hook that we've written that does all
this and if you want to use repo kid and
you want out like for example notify
application owners or you want to use
your own data feed you can do all of
that via a hook and then anytime repo
kid makes changes it calls yet another
hook that posts a message to our
internal system and basically says hey
something has changed with this
environment that's how we do it in
Netflix I would very much love for
everybody on this webcast and all your
friends and everybody to be using repo
kit as well in fact if you want to use
it please we have a Gitter Channel I'm
very happy to get you started if you
have any questions about it but
basically what you're gonna want to do
is download and install aardvark and
repo kin update the data for your
environment for both of those tools and
then and then just run through a repo
kit see like what is it telling you
about your environment
do you have roles that are not used at
all that it can repo to zero do you have
some over privileged roles you can run
it in a non commit mode so if you want
to just see what it's gonna do you just
run a repo role give it the name of your
role and just don't pass the commit flag
and it'll actually tell you the changes
that it'll make ahead of time and then
you're probably going to need to write
your own automation Runner so if you
have more than one account you're gonna
want to set up like a cron thing that
loops through all your accounts and runs
on a periodic schedule whatever makes
sense for you in any hooks that you have
for your environment so for example the
cloud trail part that I talked about
earlier we use elasticsearch and the
hook for getting that data is something
that makes sense for our elasticsearch
cluster and doesn't make sense for the
commute
so you would probably want to write
whatever hook that you need for your to
get cloud trail in your environment and
please of course submit PRS for example
if you run through the update process
and decide that something's not clear or
one of the flags is not useful or is
unclear how to use it or you're confused
about getting started and you actually
do get unblocked and you figure out how
to do it please update the documentation
we love stuff like that we want to make
it really easy for everybody to get
involved in this project and there are a
few things that that people have been
asking for that I would love some help
on so at netflix we use in-line policies
for everything and I understand that
this is not this is not what every but
you know Amazon's a big complicated
beast people are doing different things
everybody's kind of cut permissions and
policies their own way so manage
policies is something that I know a lot
of people are using and I would love for
somebody to contribute this this and a
repo kid I'm happy to help with the
architecture or to point you in the
right direction I know a few people have
already expressed interest in doing this
so if you are interested happen to our
Gitter channel tell them that you want
to do this and I'm sure you'll have some
great people to work with um I think an
upstream plugin for cloud trail makes a
lot of sense this would probably be
Athena which is a you know a tool the
Amazon provides to query data from s3
buckets so you could just query the s3
bucket where cloud trail logs are
delivered and I think it probably makes
sense to put this in aardvark again if
this is something you're interested in
please let me know I'm happy to get you
started pointing in the right direction
and better testing coverage you know
right now we've got maybe 60% I think we
can do better so if you're interested in
the project and you want to just
understand how it works better I think
test coverage would be a great way to
start and with that I want to thank you
all so much for attending the webcast
and I will open it up for any questions
that you might have awesome thank you so
so much Travis it seems that not too
many questions have come in today
probably a lot of process and I like
that of the quarter to get started so we
can also direct those questions to you
as they come in a bit later but again
thank you so so much
we're getting involved lever the next
ethnic references to show you something
really looking forward to the crown
coming out so that's perfect thank you
but it can thank you so much hopefully
you're not and not the last time we have
you on one of our live sessions and for
anyone who enjoyed the session please
remember that we put it all on the
websites afterwards you can rewatch
share and show colleagues friends
anything like that for me secure
developer.com and we also run sessions
every two weeks so our next session will
be on the 24th of October and we're
talking about modern epic gotchas with
Heisler and he's the founder and hence
to you so it should be really really
good so if you enjoy that it must get
the ticket some websites but other than
that as I said please and share get
involved ask questions someone is typing
so there might be questions coming
you'll give him a second
but if not we will see everyone saying
thank you so much we will see you all
again soon so again thank you so much
everyone and thank you for having me