Oh
and hello and some you can hear me okay
yep all clear excellent and thanks
everyone for bearing with us well we had
a minor technical issue ads at the start
of the call and welcome everyone to the
latest edition of what's now known as my
devstack ops virtual session my district
box is a inclusive community that
educates and enables developers in
application security so coming up today
we have some belen from author who's
gonna be talking about authenticating
your single page apps using JSON web
tokens and before we dive into the
session just a quick intro about myself
for those of you meeting for the first
time so my name is Oliver Byrne and I'm
a community manager here at sleek so
working with my fellow humans and
hepburn on the community team and I'm
here to help
when the session smoothly hopefully with
no more technical issues and also to
coordinate any questions for Sam as they
come in and you can feel free to drop
any questions into our live session
Channel myself Sam Sam have been are in
that tunnel ready to pick up your
questions as we go on we'd love your
feedback as we go through you know so
during the session post session so we
can continue to improve the sessions
that we bring to you you can certainly
find us on twitter by searching for my
dev site so i'm giving us a follow and
you can also join our slack community if
you're listening to this they're at
their youtube or on our website and you
can find that link on my dev suck-ups io
I was like community is actually the
best place to interact with all my
speakers just to collect all of our post
session resources slides any links that
we share from our speakers we also have
lots of fellow community members so we
put on 2,000 members which is fantastic
and then once you join the community you
can orden you can join our future
sessions by joining the live sessions
Channel and asking any questions during
any of our future sessions once the
session is over
you can re-watch the session on our
website and CVN if you're listening to
this post session you can listen to a
website or directly to our youtube
channel and just let you know that my
dev sai baba's he brought to you by
sneak and our aim for this community is
to create a vending neutral space to
share knowledge and best practices
related to software security so that's
the intro we're here we are now I'm
going to hand it over to Sam Bell who's
going to introduce himself and take us
the rest so some over to you well let's
go let me quickly share my screen so you
can see the slides I prepared should be
all good to go
can you confirm it you can see my slides
yeah I can see your slides right perfect
so like like like I mentioned in the
introduction I'm going to be talking a
bit about JSON web tokens and how to use
them together with single page
applications because these kind of
applications we've been building for a
while but they post a certain set of
problems when you're dealing with
authentication and how to do how to deal
with them in a secure way um but let me
quickly introduce myself my name is Sam
Bell and I'm a developer advocate
engineer at alpha 0 you can have a read
of files here before that's perfectly
fine we're an identity service provider
which basically means that we try to
make it as easy as possible for anybody
to implement a secure authentication
flow so you can focus on building your
actual products I'm a Google developer
expert and I organize a few meetups one
in Belgium and also the identity
security meetup among them and if you
want to find me on the internet some
bigger is usually my username so what's
going to be what I'm going to be talking
about in this session today I'm going to
start off with some traditional
education or at least what I consider
some traditional authentication we're
going to have a look at tokens and try
and go to try to explain what they are
and lastly we'll go to have a look at
token-based authentication so
traditional authentication in the most
traditional scenario you have a user
who's using a browser to visit their web
sites and the browser is going to your
request to a pack and a server and any
time you use a clicks on a page the
process come to the request and refresh
the page and load that new page until
the user goes to a web page that has
protected for which he or she needs to
login so users going to enter their
credentials username password most of
the time and to the browser account
descends to the back end if you have a
user which is stood for these
credentials and their fellows then we're
just going to return the page and the
browser is going to render that page and
usually because we don't want the user
to login with every new page request
that we do we also send a session cookie
and basically this session cookies come
to be sent with every subsequent request
me go to a protected page or resource
just so that the user doesn't have to
login with every page like I mentioned
before so what are the difference
between a traditional web app like and
the one that just explains where all the
heavy lifting is on on the back end and
where we use a cookie based approach and
sick of based on vacations in your kind
of applications on the web which use all
of channel scripts often with these
frameworks like angular or reactive you
what all of you wants a traditional
architecture is usually the browser does
a rendering and the backend is all of
the logic this can be a surgeon API this
can be a bunch of api's but most of the
logic is happening on the API or on the
backends and the browser just render
stuff when it needs to render stuff and
while a single page architecture often
can have a bunch of different services
that do it a certain thing like giving
some data from an API some user related
data maybe handle some payments but the
browser's going to do a bit more than
just rendering content it's also going
to have a lot of logic in JavaScript in
the front end and we often have an
architecture something like this you
might have a mobile app a desktop app a
web app a whole different area of apps
and they all need to authenticate with a
sort of API or api's but as we've seen
in the example of the traditional web
app we use a cookie to remember if we're
locked in or not but cookies are
something that it's what is only used by
the web so it would be nice if we could
use a more or less similar way to
remember authentication state for mobile
desktop web whatever you whatever kind
of app you're using so what are some of
the problems with the traditional cookie
based approach cookies on like horse and
I assume anybody who's watching this
this session will agree with me nobody
likes course if you were into a course
problem the first thing you do is if I
really type in I have a course problem I
just read on Stack Overflow
well this is what your problem is just
like us cookies on my course a cookie
being issued by another origin cannot be
leased by a different origin also
cookies require States because inside of
these cookies most of the time we have a
session ID which is just a pointer to an
ID in a database which contains maybe
some data but if the cookie or if the
self if the session itself still tell
it's a date and end date and expiry
dates and this means that we need to
store this in our database my cookies on
phloem you cannot pass a cookie from one
back into another back here among API to
another API so you'll have to create
them up a bunch of cookies if you're
using multiple api's which can be
annoying for example if you want to do a
request to your main API but it needs
some authentication or some account data
like you're I don't know profile picture
you cannot just use a cookie generated
by the first one on the second so what's
the solution
maybe it's token-based authentication
we'll see in this in the session if we
can use second based authentication you
just solve some of these issues that
I've just explained but first what is a
cookie or what is a token I'm sorry to
me a token is a unique identifier
representing something as long as you
can take this token and get some meaning
out of it to me that's a valid token
there are a bunch of different kinds of
tokens maybe you've come across a nexus
token before an access token is usually
used with api's to prove that you've
access to do a certain action or to get
certain data from that API maybe you've
used an ID token before I mean an ID
token is usually used to handle identity
and related information when you log in
through the open ID connect framework
for example you can ask for an ID token
which will contain some more information
about the person that's just
authenticated maybe you've heard of
refresh tokens they're very powerful and
they cause a lot of problems especially
single page applications so we're going
to be talking about this a bit later but
basically what they allow you to do is
they allow you to request a new access
token if your previous access token has
expired and they're often in the form of
an opaque string in the form of a UUID
this means that
in itself this token doesn't have any
meaning but by looking up the the UUID
in your database you might get some
meaning like the expiry date but it
doesn't have to be just a string comes
to be something like XML if you're
working with the sewol these tokens
several tokens are always XML or it
could be a JSON web token and I
mentioned in the introduction this is
something that we're going to be focused
on focusing on today at all so you reuse
them as much as possible just because
you like him they're very powerful and
if you've never seen a JSON of talking
before this is a JSON web token and you
might see that this token is made up out
of three different parts the top part in
red the metal body in purple and the
bottom part in blue and they are
separated by the two dots in blank and
this is something specific or typical
imitation of tokens they will only
always contain these three parts with
the two dots to separate them so if you
look at the first one we see the web
part in red and this one is called the
Heather and what this is is basically
just a base64 encoded JSON object so if
you would decode this base64 we can get
something like this and the header image
is the web token we'll give you some
more information about the token itself
the type it suggests and I'm talking
obviously because we're working which is
about tokens but also which algorithm we
use to sign this token and we will see
what a signature is later but basically
it tells us already if you want to use
this token you have to know how to
handle this algorithm in this case a s 2
HS 2 5 6 then the second part and the
most beefier part the biggest part of a
JSON web token is the payload it's
always the middle part and again this is
some basics before encoded Chasen if you
want decode this you might see something
like this and what the payload is
basically it's a bunch of information
that is useful to the person or service
that is going to consume this token if
it's an ID token it will contain some
information about that entity if it's an
access token it contains information
about the API that is meant to use with
I mean it can contain a bunch of things
like subject which is often the user ID
some information about the user like a
given a family name an issue that dates
and also something very powerful it can
contain an expiry date so no need to
save this somewhere in the database
separately it just left open can contain
whether or not it has its expired inside
of the target inside of the payload so
by just looking at this expiry date and
the X part here at the bottom we can
already see if the token is still
balanced in terms of expiry dates and
there's a bunch of different claims you
can put in the payload the claim is just
a valid Chasen key value pair and the
first one I reserved claims these are
just key value pairs that have been
standardized by the JSON web token spec
things like subject issuer issue that
date and expiry dates there's a few
others but these are the most important
ones and they come from the Chasen lab
spec the second type you have is public
claims and these are not really
standardized by the JSON web token spec
but there is a whole list of public
claims published on the INR websites as
you can see here which contain a whole
bunch of claims which are often used
with API is just for API
interoperability so if you create an API
that issues Jason up tokens and I grade
one we can all call a given name a given
name instead of a first name just so you
know what to expect the same goes for
family name so people might call it the
last name but if we created all of them
all of detail of token issuing api's and
consuming api's are going to assume that
it's family name it makes it a bit more
easier and then the last name or the
last earth type of claims is private
claims and this is basically any type of
claim that is of use but that is useful
to you as long as it's valid Jason you
can put it in here keep in mind that
this is just a basic C 4 encoded JSON
object so I've never put something
privacy sensitive or something imported
in here like a credit card number
because everybody can just be coach
base64 like I said also try to keep your
payload as small as possible because
we're going to be sending this token
with each
Qwest that we're going to do in the
future or at least each request to it
protect endpoints so not smaller the
payload the smaller token is going to be
in the end then lastly the third part
the last part is going to be our
signature and what the signature
basically what it is it's basically you
take your header you take your payload
and you run into a signal to signing
algorithm there's a whole bunch of them
and this in stage in this instance we're
going to use hmm-hm x sha-256 or
whatever you pronounce that so you take
your header you take your payload and
you take your secret because this
assignment method works based on a
shared secrets your audits and in the
end you get a signature this means that
any time something changes in your
header or something changes in your
payloads your signature will also change
this means that we can verify HSN I'm
token because as soon as somebody tries
to tamper with the content of the
payload or the confident header the
signature will not match anymore and we
can know that somebody tried to do
something which we don't want them to do
usually you use a better key than your
super secret key something random so if
you try this out we have a JSON object
which is going to be our header we take
the basis for of that then we have a
payload with some basic data take the
bit take the basics for this and then
run both of these through a signing
algorithm that uses secret as the secret
and we just concatenate the three parts
we get a JSON web token so if we copy
this and go to Jason wrapped up in the
layout I'll talk about this later a bit
but basically this contains a debugger
that lets you debug just not tokens and
if you paste it in here you'll see that
we have our contents there's a space
missing here because I didn't look see
but you can see the contents I can also
see that the signature is enveloped
because we're assuming that our secret
is going to be your 2 5 256 bit key if
you just change this to secrets and
paste it in again our signature is
verified because we used secret as our
secret to sign its JSON web token
some real-world examples because talking
about tokens it's a bit abstract that we
want to see the tokens how we're going
to use them in the real world an access
token again these are the tokens that we
are usually used to access a protected
API resource or to do it a an action on
a protected API endpoints sorry we are
going to contain some information useful
to an API who issued D token for example
your authorization server which user
we're dealing with and which audience
which API scan consume this token if you
are working with an API that's not in
this audience array you might want to
recheck that token it shouldn't data
expiry dates and also the Scopes which
actions is this user allowed to do and
is it allowed to use this endpoint that
is trying to use at this moment so this
is all data concerning in the use of
api's and I think token will contain
some information about the identity of
the user as we said before it's going to
be issued so when a user is going to
authenticate so we can see some
information about the enemy like the
nickname a picture maybe and again user
ID audience whatever it should at date
and expiry days so we always include the
expiry dates just so we want to so we
can check every to talkin is still valid
and just love tokens are part of the
jose specification if you've never used
if you've never heard of this it's
basically a specification that specifies
a few frameworks or a few things that
are jason and that help you to education
and encryption on the web and it stands
for JSON object signing and encryption
so we've seen JSON web token there's
also a Chasen web King JSON signature
and jason encryption these are all
standards in this how is this standards
let's see what the question is what's
the best gesture way to use just map
token in a protected way against XSS and
CSRF this is a bit of a longer question
so going to charge you answer this one
at the end of the talk moving on
the Pope until now we've seen a
signature that is based on a secret
which is called asymmetrical algorithm
but you can also use a symmetrical
algorithms like the ones here at the
bottom they all rely on a private key to
create a signature and a public key to
verify the signature and if you want to
use one of these algorithms you want to
be able to share the public key so
people can verify these signatures based
on that public key we're going to use
adjust map key for this because that's
one of these things we have an auto belt
in the horsey specification and it might
look something like this it basically is
an array of public keys and it contains
some JSON which tells us all the
information we needs to work with this
public key if you're using the Open ID
specification they are often exposed in
this dot well-known slash open any
configuration if you look at it it might
look something like this so it contains
a bunch of public information about your
authorization server and one of them is
a checkable eks you arrive if you click
on it it's you can see that this is full
of public keys that is available to
validate the chase effectiveness that I
will be issuing so you can share this
with anybody that needs to notice since
it's a NASA medical algorithm you can
only validate keys with this public key
you cannot create a new key because you
need to private key for that and that
private key obviously we're going to
keep private
so don't well known /w I change wks for
Chase and is often the the place to find
these public keys so let's make a little
comparison on the right you have a
Belgian passports in four languages
because we like to make it a bit more
difficult but what it says is I'm a
password password issued by the kingdom
of Belgium and I'm from the European
Union and basically you can compare this
to the heatheravan JSON web token
because the passwords on the from it
says what it is and Heather OHS web
token also just mentions koala days I'm
a JSON web token and you can use this
algorithm to verify my signature if you
open the password you might see some
about myself my picture my name is her
name the expiry of the passport and the
same can be true for Jason of token if
you look inside the payload you might
find some information that's related to
the identity if it's a tiny token and as
well an expiry date then of course most
passports have some ways of determining
if it's a valid passport yes or no some
UV marks or some ID some fingerprints
stuff or whatever and the same is for a
JSON web token it has a signature that
lets you pollinate the token so he can
be sure that nobody tried to attempt to
change something in the payload or the
Heather so basically a chestnut token is
a passwords on the web so let's see one
in action so I have this little web app
here in front of me and it has two
buttons one to show you dog pictures and
every time I click on it I get a random
talk picture which is nice it also has
another button that will do the same for
cats but anybody who knows
the cat knows that cats are a bit
they're a bit more difficult to work
with them dogs so to show you get
pictures you need to be authenticated if
you click on the login button and you're
sending Kate with Google just because
it's easy
we know authenticated successfully and a
few things as have happens the first
thing we can see is that we now have my
username and my picture already
displayed on the right top sides this is
because when we are medicated and our
authentication was successful we issued
a tiny token which contains the
information about the identity of the
person that's authenticated successfully
and we can then use that ID token and
show the data inside of a token but we
didn't only issue an ID token we also
issued an access token so we can show
cat pictures so now with every quest -
or back-end or API for it get picture
we're going to send along the access
token as well if you look at this from
an API perspective we have in a very
simplified version we have an
authorization or authentication
endpoints and if we run this
oops I'm sorry I click to stop sharing
but instead of Lee so let's try that
again let me move this if you click this
and and username and password are
correct we will be issued a JSON web
token let's copy this for later if you
want to request in your dog picture we
just click on it and since the dog
picture endpoint is public we can just
request our pictures as many as we want
and then if you want to get a cat
picture we'll see that once we tried to
request it we get an error stating no
authorization token was found so we'll
have to send along is a very topical and
if I paste in the one we just requested
it should work and it does we can
request cat pictures but like I said
chestnut tokens they they already
contain some information inside of them
concerning the validity if they are
expired or not for example and they also
have this signature that determines if
somebody tried to tamper with them so if
he would copy an expired system I'm
talking to try to pass that one without
doing any extra requests as soon as we
try to use this one we're going to look
inside of a token and see that the JSON
web token it's not valid anymore because
the expiry date is in the past and the
same goes for HSN web token which of
which the signature doesn't match the
content of the payload and the Heather
so once we try to use one of those
tokens we can see that it's invalid
signature and we will not accept it as
well so without doing any extra requests
we were able to recheck tokens on based
on the expiry dates based on the
signature you could also reject them
based on scopes for example if your user
is not allowed to access certain
endpoints and some other things if you
want to know more chaste love token
denial which is the website I showed
earlier which contains his debugger it's
it's built and maintained by or zero
just as a disclaimer and we do not do
anything with them we don't send them to
a back-end it's all done on the front
end so you can safely paste your Jason
up Tommy
not some a pyramid scheme that tries to
steal your takis it also contains a
bunch of libraries in a lot of different
languages just so it can make your life
a bit easier working with Jason of
tokens you don't have to do all of my
validation logic yourself
there's also JSON web token handbook
it's it's an e-book which we reach the
roads and it goes very in-depth into
everything Jason map token if you really
want to know all the dirty secrets and
all the dirty details I suggest you read
this it's it's very interesting if you
want to know it all but this goes beyond
the basic usage of Jason web tokens so
are there some downsides to chase some
web tokens of course is a downside to
anything in validation of token is a bit
harder because interesting talking
contains all of the information inside
of it
it contains expiry date it contains
scopes or whatever as soon as you issue
a Jason up token it's out there it's
felt until the token becomes invalid so
if you want to revoke one becomes a bit
harder this is usually done with a
blacklist or whitelist so you're going
to check that like a whitelist first
before you're going to validate a token
which is a bit more annoying if you want
to do that also if you leave your secret
or your private keys that can be a
headache because it means that everybody
can just create address web tokens for
your API or services and we don't want
that that's why it's called secrets and
private keys able to keep them very
secure somewhere where we know that
they're safe and again don't put any
sensitive data NHSN I'm talking because
it's just a 64 and we can go to big sis
bay 64 encoded comm
or whatever website exists and paste it
in there and see what's in the JSON web
tokens so we've seen what it is a love
token is let's see how we can use them
with a token based approach and with
single based applications so again the
same examples in the beginning user
browser back-end API whatever you have
the user just requests pages until it
hits eight protect API endpoints and
it's going to try to authenticate with
its username password its credentials if
they match we're going to send back
and access token and instead of a cookie
which we saw the beginning we're going
to send back an access token stored
somewhere in memory and every time we
want to request it it protected API
endpoint after that we're going to send
along the access token to prove that we
have access to that API endpoints and
once we have access we can just just get
back all the data we need adjacent or in
JavaScript it's can look something like
this and the important part is that you
set the authorization header to bear and
the adjacent token just so your API can
find the token and see if it's valid for
that API or not and there's a few
frameworks that deal with token-based
authentication on the web the most
famous one is off and if you look at the
the definition of all it's all stupid or
is a protocol that allows the user to
grant limited access to their resources
and that's that's the most important
part of the specification that allows
you to grant limited access to the
resources which means that you can grant
access to certain parts of an API
instead of the whole parts instead of
the whole API and the other important
part of this is that it's used to grant
access but it's not used to authenticate
it's not used or it should not be used
to handle identity so for example if you
want to import gmail contacts into your
application you're going to use off to
access Gmail can I please get access to
the context of this user and can I
please just copy them to my application
but you're not going to request access
to Gmail itself or to the identity of
your gmail user just your complex in
this example and the other side is open
and it connects which by its definition
open and in connect was created as an
identity layer from off to point out so
if we take everything from off all the
everything that's specified and just add
an identity layer on top of that we have
open ID correct open ID Connect
weather and this you can use for example
log in with Google because when you log
in with Google you're going to ask some
information about the identity or
your Google user and not you're not
going to ask can I please copy all of
your contacts you just wanted some
identity related information you could
ask for more information like copying
the contacts as well open and you can I
can do that since it's just a layer on
top of earth so it has everything that
earth can do and then some if you look
at this in a any in an example I split
my authorization server from the rest of
my API just because it's easier to
explain like this so when a user wants
to login we sent the credential still
authorization server and if they're if
they're valid we send back the access
token and we can also send back an ID
token and if you really want to a
refresh token as well and we say from
somewhere in memory and every time we
want to do a request or API which is to
agree to a protected API endpoint we
come to send along the access token we
might use the ID token to show some
identity related information on our web
app and if the token is hard you get
your data back but I've mentioned before
a few times that we save them in memory
and I deliberately say in memory and not
somewhere and local storage or in index
DB or whatever because if you store them
somewhere persistently they become my
targets or become very vulnerable for
exercising tags and we don't want that
so if we start them somewhere in memory
this means that the user has to log in
with every visit because the tokens will
be gone as soon as the user refreshes
your page or if it goes away from your
web app and it comes back on our data
points it doesn't mean that the
beginning of the logon flow remains the
same as in the previous example we can't
or tokens back or access token or any
token and very maybe your refresh token
and together windows or authorization
server will also issue a session cookie
and then with each next visit we will
just send the session cookie first or
authorization server if the session
inside of that cookie is still valid the
authorization server will fetch we'll
return the token so he needs and we can
do the rest of her of her business that
we want to do with all of you tokens
we go to save this cookie or the
browsers go to save this cookie and as
soon as you bootstrap your single page
application you're going to send this to
your authorization server often in an
iframe in the background it's called a
silent request and if the session is
still valid in my cookie you get your
tokens which means that you fetch new
tokens with each refresher or with each
new visits which also means that you can
rotate your tokens that you can issue a
new tolerance which each with each new
visit which makes it a bit more secure
and you don't have to store your tokens
are persistently like local storage or
session storage or in xep
so they are less vulnerable for XSS
attacks and then you can use your tokens
this example use the earth implicit form
which is the most used or the floor for
single based applications but there's a
few things that are not so great about
this talk about this flow they have been
sufficient with a regular validation
they can be credentials by the referer
header they might expose your tokens or
your your access token in the browser
history and they might be favorable for
token injection most of these have been
solved by some workarounds like
insufficient to redirect your
invalidation you can enforce a strict
match between yet redirect your I
requested a trendline and one previously
gesture because usually when you want to
work with off or open ID connect your
come to which history clients which
lives on a certain your I so only
clients from that URI can fetch tokens
or can request new tokens potential
leakage can be solved by your fur policy
Heather and the broader history leaking
you're talking about history can also be
solved most at a time by use any form
post response modes that's not always
possible single page applications but it
might be you might be able to solve it
with it but because of these
vulnerabilities the IETF which is the
internet Engineering Task Force
published a new best practices document
stating that you to try to avoid the
implicit form and go to a new flow
called the other authorization code with
proof key for code exchange pixie very
short flow which
a bit more complicated but Seoul's most
or all of these issues that the implicit
flow has if you want to read more about
the whys of why the IDF advises to use a
pixie flow you can find it in this URL
or at this blog post that we wrote which
explains what's wrong with your business
flow in a very readable way so if you
look at the pixie flow for a minute or
example the setup is still the same
River browser we have our two API is one
for authorization and authentication and
the other one for just all the rather
regular other stuff but when we send or
where we redirect to authorization
server to enter the user credentials
username and password we're not only
going to do the redirect and that user
enter the credentials on the page we're
also going to send a code challenge to
that page and once the user has entered
their credentials it's going to send us
back a code which we then can use to
create a code verifier and we send the
code back with the code verify that your
authorization server so together with
this first code challenge this code and
the code or verifier of our
authorization server can be sure that it
was the same client that initiated the
request that is going to receive the
tokens in the ends so a little note
about access tokens as JSON web tokens
or often open ID connect do not specify
what format an access token should be
they do not have to be just web targets
they can be anything a lot of people
just use opaque UID strings as access
tokens and that's perfectly fine
there is however an int after I have to
standardize the way you can use Jason
app Toby's as access tokens and if you
would look at that it would look a bit
similar like the ones I showed before
type will be excess token bus Jason I'm
talking and it basically tries to
standardize all of the contents inside
of the payload so if you want to use
just web tokens as an access token it
might be good to look at the standards
or just draft or standards because it
might become
in the future if however you're working
with ID tokens they're always going to
be HSN app token because they open and
you can expect specifies that I think
token is going to be HSN app token
mainly because it contains some
information about yet entities so we
want to have a form of token that can
contains a payload like a JSON web token
and then a note about refresh tokens and
single page applications in a refresh
token allows you to request a new access
token if your access token is expired
and this is something very powerful but
because single page applications have a
lot of logic on the front end they
become a bit more vulnerable to attacks
XSS attacks and whatever so if it
refresh token would get stolen
that would be dramatic and the chances
of them getting stolen are a bit higher
with single page applications compared
to other kinds of applications so if you
want to use refresh tokens in the
front-end you should try to avoid it
unless a system of refresh token
rotation or sender constrains is in
place and what this means is unless you
rotate your refresh tokens every time
they use you use your refresh hope you
come to issue a new token or maybe you
can do this also on a time-based
approach or if you can with sender
constraint which is something
theoretically possible but there's no
real way of doing this yet some people
are thinking about how to do this and
this means that you can tie a token to a
sender and a receiver to the sender
mostly that's not really possible yet
refresh token rotation is possible but
my advice would be to avoid using
refresh tokens in the front end and use
a way like this silent request I showed
earlier to fetch new tokens on every
refresh or every new revisits so this is
a proof of purchase all for course you
can wonder yourself if you think this
disappered solves for course and my my
answer to that question would be yes
because a token is not issued based on a
common origin a token that's been issued
by a certain server can be used by
another server other or
other domain as long as the other party
also knows how to validate that token so
if it has access to the public key or
the shared secrets it can validate the
signature and can look inside of the
token and determine if it's still valid
the same thing goes for a flow you can
pass along targets from one server to
the other is this usually not done
you're usually going to exchange it with
token endpoints for a new token but in
theory you can just pass among tokens
from a PRT API as long as all of your
api's know how to validate that token
and this is a part of keeping States
interior does solve that problem because
they just have token contains all the
information you need about you need to
verify the token but if you want to do
some more things like keeping a
blacklist or whitelist of invalidated
tokens or if you want to do the silent
approach for which you're going to issue
a session cookie anyway you might have
to keep in a state after all so let's
summarize
using session cookies is hard to think
of mesh applications mostly because we
work with different origins we often
have multiple API endpoints you might
have some external API eyes as well and
this gives us some course issues for
issues and we might have to keep some
states which we've seen just now that
you might also have to do wastage of
tokens but anyway it's a bit harder
stateless authentication is possible if
you're not doing it like there's a
whitelist or the silence requests
approach and Jason web tokens consists
out of three parts the header which
contains some information about the
token itself the payload which contains
all of the other information that your
API or service is going to need to in
order to work with this token and the
signature which lets you verify the
content of that header and that payload
if you wanna know more Jason up to
condole IO the blog post I mentioned
before my new blog is full of other
interesting material as well if you want
to find these slides again I chase
enough tokens on some big enough tech
but there will be this link will also be
shared later
that being said thank you
and if you have any questions I will try
to answer them and there was one before
what's the best suggested way to use
JSON web tokens in a protected way
against XSS and CSRF attacks so the
answer to that is already mentioned in
my session I think don't store them
somewhere persistently this will protect
you against XSS because you will not be
able to steal them as easily as you are
when they're stored on local storage or
whatever and CSRF is not really related
to tokens so that's not really something
I can answer with like an excerpt me are
there any other questions so thankful
awesome it was a great session very very
useful hope everyone enjoyed it and if
anyone does have any question you can
feel free to post them into these live
sessions channel now otherwise we can
claim that after the session and just
let everybody know who is listening
along either by the website on YouTube
or listening to the recording after the
links that you've seen during the
session today we will share into our
slack community so the best way to
access them is to become a member if
you're already not part of the community
and as we come towards the end of the
session I just want to say some huge
thanks to you for taking us through
today and we hope it won't be the last
time that you join us for a live session
we'll see you again hopefully and to
everyone listening and just to let you
know that we have one more virtual
session lined up for this year and as we
say hi to the sounds cat that we can see
making a guest appearance on screen
which she surveys also and we have one
more session which is on the 19th of
December and I'll actually be a panel
discussion on practical dev so folks we
have a great line of people on our panel
so you can check out our website my dev
suck-ups diode for all the details on
who be part of that particular session
and in the meantime Sam thanks once
again for joining us today if everyone
if you enjoyed this session if you know
do you think you would benefit from
listening want a please share the
recording motion that works the
recording will be up on the website
and just to show a while and with that
said we can we can close the session
today so thanks again sound thanks
everyone who's listening for your time I
will see you again next time
thanks everyone