and rely hi everyone we welcome to the
secure developer for those who don't
know we're an inclusive community that
hopes to educate and enable developers
and application security and the session
will be a panel discussion on the state
of open source security moderated by
southern maple and before we get started
I just wants to quickly introduce myself
so I'm Sam and I'm the community manager
here at sneaked and hope you the person
working behind the scenes to make this
all happen I really hope you enjoy to
today's session and if you've got any
feedback please and if you're not signed
up to the slack channels that is the
best way to facilitate questions for
today got any questions and you're not
on the slack just pop on to the secure
developer comm and the top right hand
corner you'll see join and we'll give
you all the information on joining and
slack and if you can join the live
sessions and channel you can answer
questions in there and we'll get them
over to Simon for today the other thing
to do is in your bottom right hand
corner you'll see a little cog if you
can at the resolution to maximum it'll
be the best way to view today's session
and I think that's it for me would love
you to share so you can find uh some
toilet atmosphere div or a sink on the
web side and the session will be posted
on the web side after today I think
that's enough for me I'm gonna hand over
to Simon to get a people ready thank you
very much Sam and yeah please do click
that code because if you do not kick
that cog then you will not see L'Orange
hat in full HD so we'll come to it we'll
come to that in just a second so yeah
first of all the state of open source
security is a report which really came
from a number of different sources we
will talk about in just a second I'm
sorry maple let's talk a little bit
about who we have on the panel first I'm
sorry maple I'll just be moderating and
facilitating this this chat as Sam
mentioned in the in the live session
chat on slack there you can post all
your questions and I'll put that to the
panel we also have a number of questions
that I can kick off with please do also
make sure you have the the report in
front of us this beautiful handcrafted
report that was that was released only a
couple of weeks ago whole bunch of
lovely graphs and interesting
information in there
so download that report as well and
we'll try and do it we'll try and
mention the page number so you know you
can read along with us as we go so
whoever else here snick as well and I
helped with the report a little bit but
the vast majority of this report was
done by Iran so let me introduce their
aunt are around $2 a developer advocates
Nick please tell us a little bit banks
after around so yeah I joined sneak a
couple of months ago been really happy
with the right so far and the report has
been immensely insightful on building
that so so thank you Simon for all the
help with that as well just a bit of
background for me I've been doing a lot
of security around the node and carrot
foundation true true the node foundation
itself actually and then I would echo
system to being also advocated for OS
true what through the node project which
can work on contribute to helping raise
awareness on that project and have
doubled and right Oh Jay security so
kind of been doing a security for the
last couple of years a little bit more
Intel fade and I was done before awesome
Thank You neuron and welcome to the
session also we have Tokyo who is the
product marketing manager and very very
knowledgeable about security as well on
the Google cloud platform so and welcome
tell us a little bit about yourself yeah
absolutely thank you for having me
I like Simon said I'm on the trust and
security product team at Google cloud
platform but I specifically focus on
container security prior to Google I
have worked for Fears at the OpenStack
foundation on staff there and I've
managed the cotta containers project and
was on the release management team for
the OpenStack project which if you're
not familiar it's an open source cloud
infrastructure and one of the larger
open source projects in the world so
that's a little bit about me listen
thank you
and finally bit my no means least we
have Josh Grossman who is team leader
and senior application security
consultant COMSEC and an O wasp Israel
board member so welcome Josh tell us
get started yes like like I said my name
is Josh Grossman workers and application
security consultant be doing up several
years now that means my day job is
generally going in breaking clients
applications and then helping them to
fix them afterwards but I also spend a
fair amount of time
advising generally on secure application
architecture and secure development as
well to sort more earlier stage sort of
the shifting left started style like I
say I'm a member of the OSP our board
and I'm one of the organizers of the OS
global outset Tel Aviv conference which
is coming up at the end of May over here
in sunny as well that should be great
fun yeah and we're working with one more
trip more information about not say just
to put you on the spot so the I think
actually get 1/2 sec you I think that
actually read a conference website am I
right yes it does it's not so simple
chat as well I do like the abstract
conferences so that's definitely one
that's there people's would look up yeah
so without further ado let's let's first
jump in and LaRon is the author of group
what are you give us a quick overview
about some of the highlights some of the
things that really stood out for you
from the statements or security report
sure what report is that Jay gamer cool
I thought the generally okay all right
so yeah I think you kind of tried to
give an intro on that and I think it's
important to also highlight that what I
really like about this report is that we
managed to to bring in like several
perspectives you know open source
security one of them being like the
human side of it through kind of having
a survey and asking Mainers and
developers how do they you know taking
security what kind of stuff do they do
around it etc and was the the data side
of it which is also kind of built like
around several layers so it's a
application security and then you know
OS library security and that's kind
reflected into docker which was an
interesting piece of information that we
found out through building it so so some
key takeaways I think are you know if we
take a look at the amount of you know
situation vulnerabilities that got is
closed we're seeing that you know around
you know other guys put that into a time
line so the number almost doubled over
the last two years just from plication
from your abilities big is closed and if
you take a look at you know the same
graph the same kind of period graph over
time line for system libraries
vulnerabilities you would see the same
trend right so we're seeing
vulnerabilities kind of jumping in in
that sense as well and that gave us
insight into finding out that when we
looked into talker mo 10 most popular
that are proven just around the duck
Rahad websites just counting them we
find out that you know each and every
one of them had the three story
vulnerabilities found for the for each
of those and I'm not sure like a lot of
people really understood the the you
know the impact of that and when we even
dive into a little bit deeper deeper in
do you know what kind of vulnerability
stored Osorio well you found a
vulnerability what can you do about it
so this is a piece of data that we found
out from sneaked theta which is also
kind of insightful around just figuring
out that the fact of out of all the
scanned dr. images that we found you
know you could 44% of out of all of
those you could just fix them by a
retreat you know lower the amount of
vulnerabilities found in them just by
updating your base image so just moving
from you know I don't want you to win to
slim or something like that we just
lower the amount of vulnerabilities you
know just 20% of of those doctor images
if you just rebuild them you know just
get even you're on the same image that
but those image tags get built all the
time so if you would just rebuild it
more often you know when you would not
have some kind of longleaf docker
container out there you would get a lot
of benefit out of lowering your
vulnerabilities
so we got into I think this very
insightful kind of pieces of information
and I think some other really key
takeaways were from the human side of
you know how people take security so
what the thing we noticed is you know
maintainer is have good intent or into
being you know security aware so for
example when we ask the velop or you
know how do they feel about owning the
open-source security of what they built
right your application and stuff like
that so 81% of them you know one to own
security and I think that's that's an
amazing number very positively impacting
the fact that I think you know all of
the work that everyone here on this
panel are involved in is kind of taking
shape and you know the awareness and
engagement is out there and it's working
when we ask them about you know taking
the responsibility of their docker
images which is I think in and not not a
less astonishing number is 68 percent of
them feel that they should should own
that as well which is even more
insightful in terms of showing how
DevOps is really you know working in
terms of the developer teams and stuff
like that a little bit to contrast that
is while I think Mainers and developers
have those good intentions of you know
owning security we're saying still that
37% of them are not implementing any
kind of security testing under sea ice
in Drupal systems
half of them are not implementing any
kind of docker image security testing so
so there's like a bit of you know juries
is like a the good and bad into this
there's a good intent in in in being
there and taking ownership but I think
we still we still need a lot of tooling
and culture and you know helping
developers and maintain is kind of
embraced security a lot more into what
they do into their streamlined workflows
and stuff like that interesting in it it
sounds so much it sounds so much more
believable when I want to Jedi Master as
well so you know it's pretty interesting
takeaways there and and and some barrier
and stats which are both from from what
I understand from from a survey that was
that was given as well as data which has
been mine so data that they existence
out today as well so let's take that
let's take a deeper dive into some of
those and so so let's start with let's
start with Josh one thing key takeaways
there which which which Lauren mentioned
was that we've seen an 88 percent
increase in in the number of open source
sorry the number of vulnerabilities
application library vulnerabilities over
just in two years we've always done
within a couple of years what about what
do you think the main drivers are of
this is it the open source growth is it
is it the more of a focus on security
what is what is your kind of view and
maybe even some of the some of the
insights that we eating maybe grab from
a wasp as law yeah I think it make a
couple of very good points down I mean
certain first of all the growth in the
exponential growth a growth of how many
libraries there are they're available
how many organizations are now taking
advantage of these libraries and I think
also the increased awareness ultimately
we're seeing an increase in how many
Veronese has been discovered that
doesn't necessarily mean an increase in
how many vulnerabilities are actually
there to begin with so I think in some
ways that's a good sign that the
vulnerabilities are being found at the
same time the holes of open source
library system does bring very
significant challenges because of this I
mean ultimately though there are
vulnerabilities caused by yeah I suppose
scope coding errors but also very
concerning is the sort of the the
deliberate supply chain poisoning by
either a malicious developer is
inserting something not not desirable
into a library then gets put into a
large piece of software alternatively a
developer's account is getting taken
over and then that malicious code has
been being put in so I think it's
certainly a growing a growing problem
and definitely seeing as well that
developers are aware of this issue and
they are trying to find ways to deal
with it I think that I hope that slowly
developers will start to have a better
understanding of what libraries are
actually using where the
libraries are actually coming from I do
I do even wonder where that we're gonna
start singing move towards some sort of
trusted registries we're on right now
there tend to be a few very very large
but completely open registries I wonder
whether companies will start looking
into okay can I get a a trusted registry
where it doesn't have everything but I
know that whatever's in there I can rely
on that someone has looked at it private
crafted registry Lord registry that just
has greater governance around it so I
want my thought is that if a company is
big enough I guess it can stand up its
own private trusted registry that
obviously requires a company of a
certain size alternative it may be a
third party it says okay look we're
gonna take how we're going to stand up
our registry I'm gonna allow other
companies to use it and we offer certain
guarantees or certain assurance over
this registry that companies can then
feel a little bit more comfortable than
just sort of doing NPM install and
hoping for the best I guess which is
interesting on the contrast say NPM may
even actually because of course you know
when we think about them you know
malicious packages we see we see them
more on the NPM registries than that
than the maiden registries right so and
do you think do you think the solutions
this exists on the registry side or do
you think is more on the applique on the
on the developers side that's a great
question um yeah I think one of the
biggest things to define but we're
seeing an increase in open-source growth
in general and kind of a normalization
of it is that we need to encourage
people to be informed consumers you know
everyone is going to have a slightly
different trust model security profile a
different approach to whether that means
I need to host my own private registry
or I need to establish a trusted
registry I think the thing I saw your
the 88 percent for example and I I think
it's worth emphasizing that you know
there there can be vulnerabilities in
both open source and proprietary
software and we shouldn't be afraid of
these these big numbers they can mean a
lot of things Josh I think you just hit
it on the nose with disclosure is not
the same as existence but I think you
know as people bring in open source you
care you have to remember you can't just
get clone and walk away you need to know
we're in this community that do they be
disclosed vulnerabilities where do I
need to be to make sure when a patch
comes
I'm getting it you know what finding
those communication lines I think that's
something that's really important as
people journey into the open source
world mm-hmm dad there's an interesting
insight on that would you like to do
known vulnerabilities in you know what's
kind of unknown and I think we kind of
found something you know kind of related
to that in the report which is we
retract a couple of very high you know
high profile packages on NPM and the
security disclosures that work for them
and you know we found that security
vulnerability actually existed in the
code you know for like almost two two
and a half years until it was until it
was disclosed you know found and fixed
and everything and it was like the
median time for it and you know the
worst time was like almost six years the
quickest time was you know almost 20
years so it's kind of relating to to
what you know Josh and I are saying you
know there's these are only the known
vulnerabilities
it doesn't mean you know there's so many
stuff that we probably don't know yet
and you know we'll get discovered and
just just like a point on unperfect or a
closed source stuff like that is I was
at a college actually discussing you
know it seems like from the
vulnerability which students for a cyber
uh major degree and you know one of them
was was asking me do we do we know you
know how do we feel about open source in
terms of security versus closed source
meaning you know tech kind of I think
taking a look at what every Kremlin said
about you know Linux and stuff like that
you know given enough eyeballs all bugs
are shallow so you know would would we
would we assume you know I think that
kind of we assume that as we use open
source software because it's just outer
and people are seeing it you know more
people are saying it we would we would
find those security vulnerabilities
maybe much quicker but I'm not really
sure you know I don't think we have
exact numbers of that or research on
that specific know closed versus open
source security I know I just just kind
of
mocking the discussion around this if
you want to share and I think I think in
terms of the the open versus closed
source I think that I think that the
many eyes assumes that the many eyes are
actually looking and I think that's
definitely see I mean look at the it's
not not not directly later but if you
look at something open SSL bugs or
something over there for many many many
years and that was always open source
but just no one was looking at a
particular point exactly
and but at the same time certainly close
source just means you don't necessary
know about it but we do know that
example look at Dobby or Java in a
software that isn't really thought of as
open source but you see update after
update after update for security
beaucoup de bellas artes security bugs
so certainly no less for a problem I
guess the first time for the open source
is possible to say it I think something
interesting that the an mentioned about
finding out about the findings and
finding out about vulnerabilities
I think one that wants to just it from
the report that jumped out at me was I
think a quarter of 27% of of the users
said they just wouldn't find out about
vulnerabilities they didn't have a way
they find out about fun abilities and I
think 17% of maintainer x' as well so
given that I suppose I've mind my
assumption is that people are filling
out this pinning outlet surveys for this
would have been relatively security
minded because I suppose they're
engaging with a survey from a scooter
company I felt those those percentages
were were slightly alarmingly high they
had sort of no way they felt like they'd
find out about our abilities meeting it
the companies died so I'm you know
obviously do you have a lot of
experience chronic on the product side
product managers that kind of area
already knowing about these these known
vulnerabilities that exist if you've
more focus on the open source kind of
site knowing about these run abilities
what about the challenges or awareness
of among the company and among the team
in terms of dealing with archiving
triaging any kind of application
security issues as part of you know the
the ownership and in the delivery of a
library or project or an application how
do you how do you see that bounce yeah
actually we just hosted the container
security summit here at Google a couple
weeks ago and iam cold water was our
closing keynote and her talk probably
heard the breadth of her talks is one of
her more less technical ones but it was
so impactful because her whole point was
that the best security tool you have is
communication with your security teams
and you know she's kind of the put it
half on the security people were a
little cranky we dress it all black and
it scares off people who are in product
people are you know does that you really
need to have those lines of
communication that needs to be your best
friend essentially because you're a
patched comes in when you know
disclosure comes in those are the people
who are probably seeing it first and
that's how you're gonna find out that
information is having that line stretch
of those security teams I think Laureen
you're mentioning about those shift less
that's or maybe Josh was and I think
that's something we should definitely
dive into the difference between I think
sometimes people in shifting left they
are using responsibility on the
developer interchangeably with moving
security checks earlier in your
development lifecycle I think those are
two very different things and I think we
have to be fair to our developers about
expectations on you know am I asking you
to be an expert in both my application
and security that's a lot to put on on
one team or am I just moving my checks
earlier so I put those security guard
rails in place and I think I just took
your question all over the place this is
really interesting particularly you know
you mentioned communication which is
incredibly important but it's equally
the hot one of the hottest things right
I mean we can we can add whatever tool
and we can add whatever processes you
want and things like that you know get
followed but when it's literally one
person and on you know maybe a few
meters away from another person that
sitting out an office you know their
desks getting getting people eaten that
close to communicate is hard it's it's
it's not an easy thing and I guess this
is why this is where the DevOps
movements the dev Cyclops movements
we're trying to engage people from
different silos and getting them to talk
is is really key to fixing this problem
absolutely I mean it's I think for ever
you know the relationship between
security and devs the security people
who say no
they tell the developers please stop
doing that don't do that and we have to
kind of change the understanding in the
conversation to be no I'm telling you
not to do this you know for the benefit
of this whole team the school
organization oh sorry
Josh I was gonna say I suppose I thought
following on from that the idea really
is that these security people coming in
saying yes you can do that but let's try
and find a way of making that more
secure process or like it you know I can
says is very much about not being
Department of no and about Department of
yes but let's still have a conversation
about this again sorts of circles back
to communication point if I'm on why
don't you pull em on from the previous
discussion which is actually pretty
interesting as well so we'll go back to
that one and then one about this current
one so when we talked about the
differences in open source a closed
source is is there a downside of using
open source software because once one
ability is known your open source
software there are obviously targets all
around that are still using software
versions with known vulnerabilities in
other targets bigger as a result well I
think this and sorry I'll maybe I'll
start and Josh I'm sure you have heaps
of opinions on this one as well um I
think this goes to the importance of
knowing where there's communication
channels are I think there's not a lot
of general understanding about how the
open source disclosure and patching
process works and so for example if you
use a distro those distributions are on
an embargoed list to give that patch
early so you know if you're consuming
something from industry you kind of have
this shared responsibility model and
it's it is on the user to understand is
my district patching me do I need to be
responsible for the patch and that gets
to being on those lists understanding
where those announcements come through
but you have you have some time to patch
right away but then if you let something
go and you sit on it yes you do become I
think that's one of the quickest things
that you know talkers can look for is oh
is there the Seavey's been out for a
long time it's a previs core something
you know that I can really get to I'm
gonna go straight there it's it's kind
of an easy target so that 27 percent in
the report
who are not getting information about
vulnerabilities go go get on those
security right away is it reasonable to
jump on that many security burnable to
kind of make this because you know we
see people with hundreds and hundreds
and hundreds of trying to tears and
direct dependencies can we rely just on
that you know I think actually that's
the joy of this ecosystem that's come up
around like snick is that there are a
lot you know if I'm pulling in heaps of
tools that and they all have open-source
announce list that is a lot to manage
but we have this whole ecosystem like
some tools like slick that are putting
it in one place for you you also have
things like Claire you know it's a CDE
essentially a database of what's coming
in through CDs so people can use that to
scan against so there's a lot of tools
to help you out you don't have to feel
like I'm scanning through you know new
email announce list every single day
okay cool and one flock question as well
around this is actually a DM that came
in so Josh will talk we're talking about
we're talking about you know the
differences in communicate the hard the
hard part of you know people
communicating but communication being
such an important thing when we have one
we have separate communication oh sorry
separate security teams obviously that's
an extra level of communication not just
within developers and we try to
encourage say three times a day multiple
times a day it's the flavor of the month
all right how many times can you to play
deploy a week or a day is having a
separate security team still valid or is
this just making the problem hard of
course I think there's always gonna be a
need for the security specialists or
looking at the living and breathing that
man definitely security is yes this
whole this whole industry there's a lot
going on all the time it's on the sign
it's very difficult to just keep track
of solve it as a site as a sidenote but
at the same time I think it's very
important to yeah firstly have the
communication with the develop teams
have the close wish that the development
team is an ideally sort of identify who
on development teams is more security
minded and maybe able to act as liaison
or as an ambassador for security within
within the software group itself I've
seen examples where
the security people are I thought
there's a skilled full-time security
person but he reports to the manager of
the our of the development team you'll
sit in a separate security office or
security harmony sits within the
development team alongside developers
beings a dedicated security person other
another model is to have a security
essential security body but each person
has responsibility for a few products
and they will therefore be the contact
for those different products so I think
it's again it's about how that
communication happens and about how you
identify who are the people who can
really help so I was doing as as a sir
commenting to internally at a company
and identified that you know obviously
QA was gonna be a big big part of this
because if we want people to find bugs
such as security bugs and QA to the
place to start I've talked to the head
of QA and I made sure I make time to
speak to him and sort of talk to him
about what I was planning on what I was
thinking about and you know how I could
help him if do security testing without
making his job life more difficult and
along the way so yeah I've got this guy
on my team who really likes automated
testing is also really interested in
security as well so I think there's
definitely the need for the security
specialist but they can't exist in an
ivory tower completely separately they
have to have that it dart line into
development teams as well I think this
ties into kind of the whole cube left
kind of think right because it's like if
you think of security
it's a cross-cutting concerns up the
patient's right it just like performance
and accessibility and stuff like that
and it's kind of you know it's one of
those things maybe one of maybe a more
important thing you know depending on an
opinions but each one of those things
were like he's like an said before
you're not gonna you know you're not
gonna get developers to be you know the
ultimate security expert as well as
developers I mean if you have that from
the team it's amazing but that's
probably not gonna be you know what
starts around everyone but still just
having this awareness I think this is
kind of what a shift left is all about
from security as well it's kind of
getting the awareness out so even if you
have you know some kind of tooling you
know it's gonna go
just you know that's at some point still
and there are other aspects of it right
like code reviews is something that you
generally don't need tooling for or you
know it could help but you it's enough
to just have the awareness of it so just
watching a code review between two
developers you know talking about
something and you know it's not just a
functional kind of bug discussion it's
also where well maybe this is something
that's gonna get user input and you know
could that be malicious should we trust
it should we not what should we do about
it there's a lot about awareness I think
that goes in there
that is as far as I see it the moment
that developers are asking those
questions that's for me it's like 50%
win because at that point I know that
they're gonna be pretty much aware for
it they're gonna be very much committed
to it and they want to be secure they
want to you know they want to have you
know these kind of ownership and and you
know it's not gonna say that they're
gonna own the tools and connect
everything it's a try and be the
security expert for it but it's a very
long way I think from from the from the
cannot being aware of it at all not
taking any kind of ownership for it so I
was really surprised by that 81% say the
responsibility on developers I thought
that was astonishingly high I just
assumed it'd been a lot of fun no DevOps
people or vote managers or something who
felt like okay I'll just put it on the
developers I thought that was really I
think they were talked about shift left
it's not something you're thinking maybe
that it's more about spreading left
rather than shifting that because we
want security every stage not just at a
particular stage you know ultimately I
said 81% figure is very strange I think
that if security isn't everyone's job
but it doesn't need to be able to I need
to have some responsibility for it and
they need to have some sort of awareness
of it and that will come from the
architect from the developers from the
QA from the DevOps people that come all
the way all the way through the chain
and I think it's immune maybe the
concept of shifting left is about saying
okay well this is now a concern at every
stage of the process and therefore what
everyone needs to be thinking about it
and if the developer says oh I've got
the security bug they need to do to deal
with or
I've got this particular problem where I
need a security architect to look at
this feature because it's quite
dangerous then once we know that okay
security is now covering every stage of
the lifecycle developers more like to
have that by intercept to get permission
see yes you can now go and spend two
days working on this or you can engage a
security architect to look at this so I
think that's really sort of where we're
shift left has to has to County to
spread it across the entire process and
I think Josh you were talking about the
from security that answers not know but
it's yes and and I think we have to
encourage our developers to look at
their security tools the same way so for
example like on Google cloud we have
this tool called binary relation and
it's essentially deploy time gating you
know based on parameters that your
organization has decided for you so for
some reason by an auth where you say
nope you can't do that it's it should be
looked at as you know for the developer
this is a flag this is a good morning
this is not frustration this is not know
this is something is up and I need to I
need to take a look you know I think
kind of I see a lot when you look at
what is the the one of the second most
searched things when you search for SEO
Linux is how do I turn selinux off
[Laughter]
people are not looking for oh this is a
warning I should be saying what's up
it's how do I get rid of this as quickly
as well so I think I need to have the
same open mindset to tools whether it's
you know results I'm seeing and scanning
or something to like been off these are
our friends this tooling is our friend
and the number the number the 81% that
we mentioned that shift that so that
that number is - a multi multiple choice
question and that people chose
developers more than any other answer
put together which was which was really
interesting so from from the shift left
point of view I mean Lorraine you're a
developer you're right you know you're
an application developer you also write
note what when we think about when we
think about shifting left are we
actually just pushing too much onto a
developer how much more kind of
developer take their doing I remember
when I started it was people worked and
development people works and tests big
work operations people works and
security right now developers are doing
more and more unit tests more more
functional tests more
the you know operations and chatting
encode instructress code now doing more
and more security let is it stock will
be putting too much on to developers
where's the break for the developer
right so uh so someone when you do know
it's very easy so as opposed to Java for
example you know it gives you a lot of
spare time to do performance and those
things alright cool so I think it's so
it's a good question right because you
keep it outside exactly about all these
other cutting concerns and all the
examples that you gave and I think in
general the idea is that we're also
having a lot of awareness around it but
then tooling that helps us and and you
know it's there's AI think developers
want to do the right thing and build it
the right way and you know this goes a
long way into giving them educating them
into how to do things so if you would
put if you would give developers you
know this is a secure coding guidelines
no I think they would want to follow it
and not say you know I don't have time
to do this and I think that as we are
going into delivering in a very very
fast way and you know delivering value
to our customers and delivering products
very fast which is important you know to
the business or you know whatever
basically you're doing on it's also
important to not let go of quality and
all it is not just testing is it's also
security it's also other aspect of the
apps so it's I don't think it's
something that you know is requiring a
lot too much of them I think it's
requiring their attention in general for
developers to do it because like I think
like and Josh said before we're gonna
have security teams there are we're
gonna have security experts that we can
consult with and you know just like you
have an architect for general you know
software design you would have that for
for for security and maybe for some
organization for performance that would
be tech leads for security so I don't
think you know everyone on the team has
to be you know 120 percent knowledgeable
on security aspects but usually you do
have those tech leads on you know
development teams one is a very you know
you know UI tech lead
reinterred so he would know a lot about
performance optimization and stuff like
that you know someone else might be a
security tech laid around you know for
that whole team and he could be someone
who would mentor other other team
members and you know be involved in code
reviews so I think it's kind of a shared
effort throughout developed for timpz
and i think it's it's an amazing kind of
incubation part where you know also team
members you know or tech ladies and
seniors and juniors kind of mentor each
other you know incur that knowledge so I
think that'sthat's pretty reasonable
asks and it's a great there's a great
point has just been made in in a live
session from Mark Stevenson so please
don't comment or questions do you jump
into the live session mark says that's
interesting but if you're a small
company the developer has to wear many
hats right and maybe there isn't a
dedicated security team plus to add to
that question I would say you're often
with the smaller companies more likely
to release more often perhaps you know
then some of the bigger companies that
are maybe more traditional in terms of
that their deployment flow any from the
panel anyone one I want to add into that
I would say I think that's where you're
probably leaning on some of your
automated security tooling heavier than
in other places you know you're yeah
we've refreshed um you know even putting
in scanners I'm putting in gaining tools
like the not that I was talking about
you know if you know if you don't have
many actual hands you have to kind of
have those automated hands I'm staying
with you there's a product that you work
on cool I may say this wrong is it cater
or Carter cutter
of course I was just hoping it yeah
that's right so the cards containers
project give us a little bit about what
that is and how and how that helps
people find you know understand about
their new security issues as early as
possible
and also week so do you get if you win
Decatur the cut out well I'll explain
kind of containers and maybe I confused
you with some of the other tooling we
have so kind of containers is an open
source project it was started by Intel
and hi
4sh typers has started about in China
until had clear containers and they were
both kind of looking at virtualized
containers so how can I add a second
layer of isolation you know I think the
mistake from technically my titles and
marketing so marketer here the mistake
container world is made is was using all
those images of shipping containers and
really telling people that you know
containers really contain everything's
fine I think we may be oversold a little
bit what that containment really means
and so there's a big movement and
contain the container security world
around isolation so how can I have
defense and depth how can I have more
than just relying on my namespaces and
see groups to isolate those workloads
socata containers is essentially putting
a lightweight VM around your container
through their own runtime that they have
and so it's OCI compliant runtime and
that micro VM approach is one thing you
see like AWS firecracker kind of come
out with that my chromium approach
there's another open-source project out
of Google called G visor and rather than
going in micro VM they're looking at how
can I support kind of low i/o but highly
scaled applications who maybe don't need
that micro VM approach and so but
they're actually do they have a user
space kernel that's got kind of sets a
set suite of syscalls that a can and
can't have and so that's why you can
have kind of that rapid performance but
get a second layer of isolation so
there's a lot happening that space
there's also Noblet containers so a lot
a lot of people experimenting in the
open source world with isolation right
now and so in terms of the from the
open-source maintainer point of view one
of the biggest wins for an open source
maintained if you're using these I think
for a maintainer it's really they're
much more end-user products so you know
if you are a maintainer you could be
running your applications in them
you know looking at them if I want to
secure my projects that I'm posting
somewhere but they're much more end-user
results okay oh cool and when we talk
about other containers would be the
report found Leron that the top 10 most
popular docker images containing at
least 30 vulnerabilities and
and no it was the clear winner on that
one there are what we're that surprising
to you with is this is this in this kind
of like something that people tend not
to realize when they're using containers
what what's the what's the story with
this yeah I think it's uh yes so it had
a considerably large amount of
vulnerabilities inside something like
580 it's not the number right as opposed
to the others
so I actually think that we fixed that
on the node Foundation side and using
now a different image at least there's a
whole discussion around that on the
issue queue but even regard the girlís
said I think there's a lot of
misconception or you know just maybe
lack of knowledge where people might be
doing I know what's you know for myself
before I went into snake it was a you
know developer and a team leader and you
know my team also had maintained to run
docker file and stuff like that and we
used to do you know from you know node :
10 etc and you know the classic examples
were building on you know our app on
foundation of some some kind of a waste
or or distribution but we didn't you
know didn't even had this you know kind
of this awareness into what we are
bringing in with ourselves and I think
that this is something that we we talk a
lot in terms of video stuck over for the
stock overflow problem where people go
in they you know they copy paste you
know from node N or some other kind of
vulnerable code and you know it works
but there's there's no you know deeper
understanding into what what exactly is
it doing or you know what exactly are
the risk of doing something that way so
I think it's easy for for teams to make
those kind of mistakes as they think
like that the deeper knowledge into into
what goes into that I think maybe an
wants to the jump on it says I think
she's nodding in yeah I think what's at
2000 17 or 18 kind of this you know this
crypto mining docker images that we saw
um you know I think there's this
assumption all most people are too too
trusting sometimes of I pulled this from
docker hub it must be fine it must be ok
and I think you have to you know as an
organization kind of established a
definition of trust of whose images are
we going to trust you can kind of have
your own rules of I I trust things from
Netflix I trust things from Google I'd
you know things certain developers that
I know through the community having
those definitions of trust versus I
pulled this because it was from user
abc123 sounds good and then once you you
know after you that where are you what
are the sets of checks that you're gonna
put in place to establish that trust are
you gonna do scanning are you you know
what are you having to make sure that
the play time also this image wasn't
tampered with between the time you
pulled it in the play time and so I
think that's one of the big things
around the growth of open-source is that
you get a lot more contributions but you
need to start looking at where are they
coming from and what are they and do I
trust them and with docker images in
particular I know
Dirk kondal from VMware he's the head of
open-source there
he's really been pushing the turn
project because one of the other things
is that images can pull other images
that can pull other images so you can
kind of have a chain both from a
licensing perspective but also a
potentially vulnerability perspective
and so it Bob Lowe yeah and in terms of
whether fix where the fix should exist
that is at the maintain is that that
should be more careful about which you
know whose other containers they pull in
or other layers that they put in is it
the user that needs to be careful about
you know who they who they win and which
images they say you mentioned about that
the publisher for example which is a
little bit easier perhaps on docker than
it is maybe something like you're
looking for a package on an application
repository or something like that where
is that whether the fixes lie or is it
kind of across from multiple places and
we need in some ways it is across
multiple places we often end of do our
best effort but I think at the end of
the day for this one it does sit in back
to that shift left in the developer and
putting the security checks in place of
you know if you're gonna pull something
in you need to have a process to
establish how why you did that in a high
trust it I really like this going into
this
supply chain attacks go ahead Josh
because I think we have a lot of stuff
to say and it's yeah I wasn't gonna
carry on supply chain attacks because I
think it's it's it's it's a really
interesting problem is very difficult
problem I mean in terms of whose
responsibility is it I think like Anne
says it has to come back to develop an
organization you can't necessarily rely
that someone upstream is gonna worry
about this I mean look it was at the
events tree an example exactly it was
because it was a sub library of a sub
library or something where the
maintainer just sort of got bored and
maintaining it someone else in mo can I
take over maintenance of this packages
like oh yeah sure I can border this
anymore
transfer to transferred over ownership
of the package and then suddenly when it
was discovered he something got a lot of
heating inside look I'm not being paid
for this this is my hobby I got bored of
this this guy have been doing you had
been submitting patches whatever to this
library so didn't see a problem in
transferring over ownership to him yeah
and you can say oh it was irresponsible
to transfer though ownership but again
what what no the guy wasn't being paid
to do this it wasn't I didn't have any
sort contract there was no sort of
guarantees years offering he was just
one guys up committing code to github
and into into the registry so it's going
to come back to ultimately organizations
that using this code have to sort of be
a buyer buyer beware approach or suppose
a download everywhere approach wait wait
it's actually coming from where where's
it started I love that story because I
think like you just break it out there's
a lot of open source sauce into this
right this is kind of the stuff that
open source is built from the idea of
accepting contributions you know
mentoring other people to own your
project and you know help you contribute
so you know they are very empowered to
take some project and you know while you
are maybe continuing your journey with
something else and this story like sheds
a lot of light in to know how open
source is both amazing but also you know
has its kind of down fold with stuff
like you know social engineering in this
kind of way it's it's an interesting
story you know or problem space to
figure out as you know you there's no
like one person to blame
how this happened right there's multiple
ways both developers you know consuming
a library should they have had some kind
of pooling or some kind of policies to
vet their packages before they upgrade
before the install or whatever should
the registry have noted this kind of
ownership change and you know maybe had
alerted or you know had required someone
to to use like a assembler major change
just to reflect the fact that you know
something has changed there's a lot of
interesting talks around it I can share
from the node foundation side is there's
actually a funny story around it there's
been a so the net foundation is built
around different working room features
like a top level technical steering
committee community committee different
working groups all togethers and one of
the things is there's a working group
called package maintenance which has
existed for actually quite a while
before the event stream story and it was
really about about this how would how do
we make open-source
you know maintainable right successful
because you can't expect people to be
you know as they volunteer you know I
think the majority of open-source is you
know volunteer based and you can't
expect people to be committed to that
you know 24/7 etc so when they want to
move on you know with other projects how
do we make it sustainable so that the
project is kept alive a really good
example of that or you know at least a
very pure example of that is we had an
NPM also the story of left fad and you
know an maintainer that got you know I
would say it very easily upset with how
things were done and he just pulled a
lot of his code which actually broke so
many systems around the ecosystem
because everything was kind of not
everything but so many projects were
depended on it and so how do we make
that sustainable how do we make that
work how do we do that and the event
stream was a catalyst to bringing the
package maintenance working group back
to life and there's a lot of if you
would go if this is of interest anyone
who's listening there's a lot of really
good
yes and processes and policies that are
now being put into use for the node
foundation so at the very least we can
be you know very hopeful for things too
I know we've solved but better working
in the future I think it's worth the
reminding our listeners that open-source
maintainer czar only human you know I we
put up a lot of nice polish around our
projects but to the end of the day we're
only human and things like turnover and
burnout happened just as they would you
know inside employees in an organization
and so I think is you're a consuming
open source you have to keep continually
asking yourself can I contribute back
and maybe the answer is not right now
but then the next day might be yes I can
offer that community X I can offer them
why it's sort of that's that's what
makes this whole process work no very
much so I think that people see in
essence or scissors there it's free I
think is use it I think they're
necessary realized okay maybe there's no
monetary cost involved in that directly
that may there's a time investment or
maybe you want to be volunteering some
time back to actually give back to that
I think that if it's seen as a purely
take-take-take process where people just
use open source materials then you end
up in a situation where they suddenly
have some sort feel some sort of
entitlement say okay why isn't it's
working you need to go fix this now all
this is my hobby I do some on Sundays
when I've got my day off I mean except
I'm on the board of OS when we sort of
see similar issues now Hawass there's an
organization that's dedicated to
producing free application security
resources for for anyone to use and it's
been around for must become around for
17 18 years now something like that and
people just sort of assumed that it's
this big
maddening massive audience the best
example I seen of that was last laugh no
the year before 2017 when the latest
version of OS top 10 risks came out so
the 2017 version of the top 10 web
security risks came out and a lot of
people got very angry because they said
okay well this item on this new item on
list is just the the main take the
maintainer the project trying to sell
their product and there was a big big
Brown set and of the support leaders end
up standing down but one of the things I
said looked yeah this project this our
top ten project that's reference in
regulatory standards and all sorts of
things that's been around for so long
the worldly speaking is two guys
volunteering their time sitting down
gathering data together and coming up
with how they see it and just so happen
the two guys who are working on it both
worked at a company in a particular
space and therefore naturally their
point of view is shaped by where they
were working and you know the people saw
that OS top-10 as this massive
monolithic standard that had to have
complete integrity and be completely
pure of it only thing as two guys were
just giving their time to do it and then
afterwards they change they were the
maintainer zwerling and there were four
leaders and they made a very very open
process perfectly and github gathered
data from all sorts of sources and even
after they released their bought work
people still came back said okay why is
this like this why is it like that and
they just came back said look this is
been in github for six months be open
for common you could have open issues
people opened issues people open
comments there's no point coming right
now and saying well why is this like
this you could have said this two months
ago I did an issue and something might
have happened so it's very much about I
think maybe shifting your mindset here
saying okay we have all these open free
resources but there's a there's a
responsibility that comes with that of
giving back to that as well and staying
on this point as well I'd love to I'd
love to
we have about ten minutes left I would
love to finish with some some actionable
recommendations and suggestions for the
debate for developers and others to to
better take away and actually improve
their day to day that they'd say general
security practices now now Josh you
mentioned I was is you know a great
resource for education for developers in
general what what specifically you're
we've talked about the OWASP top 10
exactly the previous session which was
Jim Monaco which do many are very
actively with with a big knife and some
spray and if we have water session again
but Brian still shaking about that he
was still giving Brian some counseling
about that session but what the clad
things in what are the top things in in
you know
but you would recommend people people
you know read and also in general what
if you could give like a few piece of
advice to people to developers
what would you say they should do um
OS perspective like I said the top 10
risks I suppose the most the most
popular well-known project and that's
something that's been around for
probably almost as long as OS but being
around and the idea behind that Dogma is
to raise awareness it's about saying you
know here the top 10 things are gonna
give you a bad day we're not necessarily
meanest olia developers were just a
meanness is general awareness at all
levels in disease or seen as more
management level doctrine and then the
the document that Jim was talking about
last week was the top 10 for active
controls which is sort of response to
the OS top 10 in some ways it's saying
look there's a top-10 risk see the
things that are going to ruin your day
but let's think about how we empower
developers slightly more and give them a
slightly more positive way of thinking
about - not saying it is the bad things
are gonna happen they're gonna say okay
these are the good things you should be
doing so the product of controls is sort
of a nice starting point of 10 areas
that developers might well be thinking
about from a security perspective and
then if we sort of get more in depth
than that there's the application
security verification standard which is
another document that is very very
detailed and sort of goes into self
line-by-line controls that developers
should be thinking about when building
into their applications we recently
recently released version 4 of the
document ASVs I was involved in that as
well the other thing that OS does is it
has the actual product products you can
play with has various fun of all
applications so I think Leon mentioned
earlier note goat if I'm not mistaken
which is a application written nodejs
with a lot of known vulnerabilities
another one which is also written in
node.js by for instance but it's very
very very advanced is the OS juice shop
which is a very realistic it's of
e-commerce start application where you
can buy juice but it's also got a very
large number of different
vulnerabilities so that's something that
anyone can download set up in da
container set up in Heroku or something
like that and start I find
vulnerabilities
practice their skills in thereit's and
they might xs/s they can start trying to
exploit XSS and this in this application
or for other different other different
vulnerabilities in their vote about so
you know there are lots of different
resources that OS boffer generally
they'll also be local chapters all
around the world we've got one here in
Israel I know in the UK there are lots
of different cities have London Bristol
Cambridge Newcastle all sorts of
different around the country that meets
at least once every three months I think
and not have speakers talking about
different topics around the security
application and Security's there's also
you know Rica places to meet other
people who have an interest in security
than necessarily working security
now overall OS tends to aim more at the
developers it's not designed to be a
hardcore security let's go and break in
hack stuff it's more of okay how can we
fix this yes certainly if we look at the
OS conferences for example there the
lineup for OS conferences a very much
developer focused very much okay here's
how we fix this particular problem
here's an idea of how you can go back to
organisations and do this let's say see
the sort of here's how we broke this
thing completely away here's how we took
this webcam and shredded it yeah it's
very much ok here's how we try and solve
this problem and the global conferences
as well have training courses attached
to them so we've got the global
conference car in tel-aviv like I said
at the end of May
and that's three days of training most
of which are aimed at developers or
people working in R&D teams and after
that the two days of the conference
itself you know that training very much
designed to cover all sorts different
topics as training for developers who
may be new to security training for
security professionals gonna get a
little bit more experience than one of
the more advanced web hacking techniques
there's a training course about dev set
cops have them integrates
security tools into the continuous
integration communes delivery pipeline
of course about containers you know
sorts different topics that focused
around application security and product
security and the training courses do do
cost
because we've got trainers flying over
to give their time to that but you know
really the global conferences and the
training training courses hatch to
really only things that with our stood
directly cost money you can be a member
and it costs not very much about a year
there's really the whole wealth of
different information there so I'd say
you have to vote the people interested
in game getting more involved without
try and find out about your local
chapter try and find out who's involved
locally and get new people and a
different point in the right direction
or age around the education of
developers there's key fever and
anything you know yeah I would say from
the Container Security site I would be
remiss not to mention that we have a
series called exploring container
security on the GCP blog and it's not
just google kubernetes engine specific
it's you know broader about the the
space and I think if people just have
the mindset if I'm gonna make an effort
to kind of be this informed consumer
that we were talking about with making
sure I'm receiving information about
patches with regards to containers you
know reading up on what's gonna work for
my organization what's gonna work for
our context sure I think if you just
start with the mindset of string
containers may not necessarily be the
most secure option for me you're in a
good spot if you're at least considering
that beyond that you know a lot of the
container security work revolves around
either OCI or the kubernetes communities
there's lots of other orchestration
tools but kubernetes kind of is the I
say it's the whirlwind of the hub you
know so if you start hanging out around
the kubernetes security channels and
community you'll start getting some
answers there you know in general for
both open-source maintainer is looking
for more security expertise as well as
consumers the communities are friendly
and where people particularly in
security really wanna help and share
information so if you just reach out on
you know IRC or slack or wherever the
community hangs out and just ask I want
help that's you will find an answer okay
thank you and under on why don't you
wait you finished just awfully wrong
with didn't ye recently wrote docker
chichi write up some security tips in
there
or at least what's coming from say yes
so we so I wrote a couple of those
tickets one of them is that docker
images security with the help of
over a week of running from saluto and
also an NPM security best practices as
well with with one picado his
decrementing / - EO and both of them are
really around you know you're using
these tools you're using you know
building better images you're using and
gambelli
but there are some really good security
practices that you should follow so so
you know just look up for those will
probably mention them later in the
channel just to give you some some
resources and I also wanted to give I
think Josh and and did a great job at
giving several perspectives of how to
kind of get started with security I want
to give that developer a side of it
which is I would say what worked for me
at least as a team lead for previous
companies I've worked at is if you have
if you can have one of the team members
out of the hole you know R&D developers
teams assuming that you know a large
enough world to work on having you know
empowering one of them a place to be a
security champion to be someone who
would advocate for security there's
really a long way it's a great plan to
you know get the organization around you
know security practices so you know it's
both empowerment you know you win you
mean all of it it's empowerment for
engineers as well as security you know
knowledge into the team and bringing
that in so I'm happy also to help with
that if anyone has any questions on how
to make that work thank you very much
and further I'm watching if you if you
wanted to take a look at the state open
source code report and much more depth
there's about 50 or 60 pages you could
it's linked in the in the live session
chat on slack if you're not on slack
please do join slack and enjoying that
click that link if you don't have the
RAM to start slack then you can go to us
click the i/o
forward slash security and have a free
undated I'm great at keeping it clear
for you as well so yeah it just needs me
to say a massive thank you and Josh and
Lauren for joining us today and back
over to you sir thanks Simon and Yoda a
cadet from from
thank you so much to the panelists as
well as you Simon for such a great
discussion I really enjoyed it
I said that's all we've got time for
today if you do have any more questions
please pop it on the slack and I'll try
to get those answered for you and I hope
you will have the panelists on and on a
future session on the security there's
not the last time we see them and but if
you did enjoy that I want to rewatch or
anything it will be on the website in a
couple minutes you give me a couple
minutes and the session with Jimena Koh
on the Olaf top temperature controls is
there as well so if you haven't watched
that already check it out and our next
session will be in two weeks time it'll
be why can't we build secure software
with Tonya Janko on the 28th of March
and so sign up for that and we'll be
sending Wilson
you should everyone should sign up -
that thing is awesome and yeah if you
enjoyed it please share with your
colleagues or your friends I hope you
there are your friends and your
colleagues and hopefully we'll see you
again soon and another mention is
obviously the secure developer is
brought to you by sneak our a mr. native
in the neutral space to share knowledge
and best practice dr. M security and so
if you'd like to get involved but I got
pleasing you know and that's that so
thank you very much thank you
thanks so much it's pretty great thanks
everyone