great I think we live hi everyone and
welcome to my dev shake ups if you're
the you camp for the first time we're an
inclusive community that aims to educate
San enable developers and application
security and today I'm joined by the
lovely Liz rice who is the VP of open
source engineering and container
security specialist at aqua security so
Highness hello thank you very much Sam
and hi everyone
same thing so and Liz will be talking
about vulnerability scanning and
container images but before we get
started with that just want to introduce
myself anyone that doesn't know me my
name is Sam and I'm the community
manager care and I also be on the slack
channel if anyone's a member of that
feeding questions across Tiller's so
please keep your your in your questions
and then we get the concert and anything
you'd like to see in terms of sessions
please feel free to tweet me dear me on
on slack or email me those communities
definitely for you I know most of us are
currently on house arrest somewhere in
the world link so a bit more time on my
hands so please let me know if there's
something you'd like to see in the next
few weeks and selects actually the best
place to interact today so if you're not
a member if you pop on to my grave sick
ops or IO you can find the link there
join the slack and we're currently all
chatting on the live sessions channel
and you can also pop on that website to
find all our previous sessions rewatch
Liz the session today and obviously find
all the contact details for us my
district offices actually am supported
and brought to you by sneaked their aim
is to create a vendor-neutral community
and to share knowledge a best practice
so a huge thanks to them but that's
enough for me I'm gonna hand over to Lou
Solon's thank you so much again for
being here thank you so much and hi
everyone from your homes around the
world I'm just gonna try and share my
slides this works a second ago when we
did a tech check so I think that looks
like it's good yeah yeah your love life
excellent
yes so as Sam said and thank you very
much Sam for the intro and if you do
have any questions do you throw them
into that snack Channel I really like
interactive sessions event
love you questions as we go along it's
great yes so my name is Miss Rice I work
with a company called aqua security
where we help enterprises we have a
platform for securing their cloud native
deployments and one of the really
important parts about securing your
containerized or cloud native deployment
is to make sure you're not running
containers that contain known
vulnerabilities so that's really what
I'm going to concentrate on today I'm
gonna talk a bit about what a
vulnerability czar and a bit about how
abilities scanners work and why they're
so important and what I hope is that by
the end of today's session you'll all be
if you don't already have it you will be
adding image scanning into your CI CD
pipelines into your workflows because
it's pretty easy to add and you get a
big security benefit out of it all right
so did I skip ok ok so what am I talking
about when I talk about vulnerabilities
this is all about floors bugs some kind
of issue within the code that an
attacker can exploit and cause something
bad to happen potentially inside your
system you have heard of some of these
vulnerabilities some of the really
really critical ones get so kind of
famous they get their own logos so
things like meltdown shellshock
heartbleed and dirty cow you've probably
heard of them if you've you know had any
kind of involvement in software security
but these are really just you know the
tip of the iceberg these are the kind of
bayon face and justin bieber's of the
vulnerability world there are thousands
of less well-known
and probably less critical
vulnerabilities that get discovered
every year every one of these
vulnerabilities gets given an identifier
called a CVA
so CVE stands for common vulnerabilities
and exposures and see we have this
lovely logo that I think 1994 is called
and asked for it back but it's still
that's the logo and so when the
researcher finds a vulnerability in a
piece of software they basically
register that vulnerability and it gets
this unique identifier and information
about that vulnerability stored in a
list called the national vulnerability
database so you might hear the term CVE
and NVD in the context of software
vulnerabilities and the NVD lists has an
entry for each of these vulnerabilities
each of these CVS and the entry will
tell you basically what is this this
exploit what was it all about and what
software packages does it affect so
here's an example of a sort of extract
for this is for the heartbleed
vulnerability and it's telling us that
this particular vulnerability will
affect you if you're using the open ssl
package and all of these different
versions basically 1:01 all the way
through to a 1 0 a 2 B 2 1 so all of
those versions were affected if you're
running with this version of open SSL
you are in some danger because you've
got this heartbleed exploit and an
attacker could potentially take upon an
advantage of that vulnerability in your
system so we use vulnerability scanners
to try to establish whether or not these
vulnerabilities exist in in our system
so that we can do something about it we
can we can address those vulnerabilities
there are lots of different types of
vulnerability scanners and that term
includes things like port scanning but
really what I'm gonna talk about today
I'm just gonna focus on looking for
known vulnerabilities once a CBE
identifiers in
software packages installed in container
images
I said known vulnerabilities and those
are the ones that have these CV
identifiers assigned to them of course
there could also be unknown
vulnerabilities by which that you know
they haven't been published there is no
CVE maybe those are flaws in your own
application code as a an enterprise
operating application code you could
have your own unique set of software
bugs in your unique software and maybe
those flaws could be taken advantage of
by an attacker those are essentially
unknown to any vulnerability scanner so
the scanners that I'm talking about
today it's no one's we're really
interested in but of course the known
ones are the ones that attackers know
about - so they're the ones that squits
you know on the Internet are constantly
trying to take advantage of so these
known vulnerabilities it's basically you
can have a scanner that will identify
whether or not you're running with these
packages that contain known
vulnerabilities there are also tools for
looking for these unknown
vulnerabilities so things like fuzzers
Oh what tools here they're they're
designed to look for these unknown
vulnerabilities or to attempt to do the
kind of things that maybe might be
permitted because of an unknown
vulnerability the known ones are
specifically looking for known
vulnerable packages there's a handful of
different ones I've listed there this
there are many more vulnerability
scanners out there I'll talk a bit about
the kind of things you might want to
look for in in different vulnerability
scanners some of them are open source
some of them are commercial that the
choice is yours
so really what we're doing when we have
a container image that we want to scan
imagine that image
stored in its image registry I'm going
to extract that image and run it in a
deployment somewhere and it would be a
very good idea that if that image has us
has a vulnerability in it before we
deploy it we want to be able to check
for that and stop it from running we
also want to know that if a new
vulnerability gets uncovered because
phoner abilities can be found new
vulnerabilities might be identified in
existing code then we need to know which
of our running containers have that
vulnerability so we might have already
deployed that container it's already
we've got containers running with that
vulnerability we need to be able to
identify those stop them and replace
them with a new version of the image it
doesn't have that vulnerability so we
would typically want to have a scanning
step every time we get in an image out
the registry just make sure that it's or
at least on a regular basis make sure
that that image does not have known
vulnerabilities if we find one we need
to replace that container with a version
that doesn't have that issue so this
vulnerability scanning step it's going
to look inside the container image find
out which software packages are
contained in that image so packages like
open SSL look at the version of that
package check whether or not that
version of that package has a name
vulnerability and if it does it will
report that vulnerability and that
sounds super easy right because we've
got a vulnerability database we can look
inside the container image for these
packages we should just be able to
compare the two so why is this a big
deal why is this hard we'll talk about
that it all comes down to the fact that
there are different distributions that
handle different software packages in
different ways so for most of us we're
talking about Linux containers windows
containers is
thing but for most of us were really
talking about images based on Linux and
those images can use different
distributions of Linux so the Linux
kernel is one thing there are different
versions of it but it's essentially one
product that gets released but there are
lots of different distributions built on
top of that kernel so lots of us you
know will have come across these
different versions like Ubuntu or Suzy
Linux or maybe Amazon Linux if you're
using the Amazon ec2 machines there are
many different I don't know how many
probably dozens of different
distributions of Linux out there and
they they have these different
components that they bring together and
they also have different philosophies
about how they manage the distribution
and that affects the way that
vulnerabilities get found so for example
and here's a selection of a few
different Linux distributions they have
different gooeys they might have
different default shells installed
importantly for us they have different
default package managers the package
manager makes a difference to how we
handle these vulnerabilities because
we're looking for vulnerabilities in
software packages installed by these
package managers so doesn't really
matter what all the individual details
in this table are the point is that they
distribute different components and
particularly in that last line we talked
about the release model they have
different philosophies about how
frequently they all do updates whether
or not they do package updates
frequently or wait for us a major
release app on a known schedule every
three months or every six months and
these container images that we have
could be based on different
provisions you know so EU a lot of us
might be running on a host machine that
runs one or a set of host machines that
run one distribution of Linux but the
container images could be running
different distributions alpine is a
great example is that relatively
stripped-down distribution so a lot of
container images are based on alpine the
packages that are installed into those
container images are probably using
Alpine package management called apk and
they will follow those apk distributions
of packages and those are handled quite
differently from the way that let us say
Debian handles packages and updates to
packages so let's drill down a little
bit more into these different approaches
to handling software packages let's say
there is some software package that were
interested in maybe we could be talking
about open SSL that I had in my example
before or we could be talking about
essentially any package that you might
install with a package manager and those
packages they probably come from some
source code written by some developers
who may have no particular relationship
with a particular Linux distribution
those developers create a binary
distribution they work on that code and
they release that code but there's often
going to be a version of those packages
developed for different Linux
distributions I'm just noticed that for
some reason my arrow has an arrow that
has shifted up on this slide so should
be an area between compiled and packaged
and package repository so the
distribution maintainer x' will take
that source code now they might take the
binary distribution but oftentimes
they'll take the source code compile it
themselves package it up in the
particular package management for their
for their distribution and they'll store
it in a repository so these different
distributions have their own different
package repositories and they may do
different things they may take different
choices as they build those packages and
put them in their different package
repositories so for example a
distribution the distribution maintainer
might decide to enable or disable
particular features in the package they
might decide that they're going to link
with those packages based on certain
releases of underlying dependency
libraries they might repackage these
packages all together and then we get
into the things that are really
important to us from our vulnerability
perspective which is how they handle
patches and bug fixes so the upstream
developers are making changes and fixes
to their software and some set of those
changes and fixes will be to fix
software vulnerabilities so if a
researcher finds a vulnerability they
disclose it to the developers and the
developers create a fix to to patch that
that vulnerability so basically render
that vulnerability non-existent so
somewhere there's a code change or a set
of code changes in some software that
needs to be built into that package just
to remove the vulnerability the
distribution already has a package with
the vulnerability and now they have to
decide how they're going to handle that
fix and for example are they going to
cherry-pick just that fix are they going
to take a new release of that package
and that's kind of up to the
distribution maintainer x' to decide how
they're going to handle that and I just
saw a really great question coming in
I've got the the slack in front of me
and I just saw the question saying is
there
a website that announces the new
vulnerabilities and their severity so I
will show in shortly about how there are
distribution specific websites or
sources and there are also there is the
MVD so that NVD website which has
updates every time there are new
vulnerabilities
sometimes the nvd and the distributions
don't even agree on what the severity is
so that's interesting so depending on
which distribution you're using the
updated version of the package you get
with a fix for a vulnerability might be
it might be a whole new release or it
might be a patch and different
distributions might create different
patches to address the same
vulnerability so for example taking
Debian they very much focus on stability
they release infrequently and they try
to take the minimal amount of change for
required to to patch security issues so
that as a general philosophy they they
were rarely if ever update a package to
its latest version its latest operating
version to address a vulnerability they
would rather just apply the patch
cherry-pick the patch for that
particular issue and they might need to
do some back porting to apply that fix
to older versions that they're still
supporting
so you need to know whether or not your
package has that patch in order to know
whether it's got that vulnerability
we'll take an example here this is
doesn't really matter what the
vulnerability is here but oh I've gone
skip to trot forward by moving my mouse
all right there we go
and so this particular vulnerability in
a varnish HTTP cache package and it
exists according to the NVD it exists in
all the versions between I think it's
actually the enemy will tell us it was
between $4 0.0 and 5.2 so actually
there's conflicting information on that
slide so I'm I'm doubting myself now but
one of those things is true I live
between 4.1 and 5.2 or 4.0 and 5.2 okay
so that's what the NVD says that's the
essentially based on the upstream
version of the package and now let's
look at what Debian say about the same
issue so this is the what they would say
the it's the Debian security advisory
about this particular and vulnerability
so the question that came up earlier
about the website that announces these
new vulnerabilities this is the
distribution specific website for Debian
what's an extract from and what it's
saying is for the versions of the
varnish package that Debian we're
maintaining at the point that I took
this screenshot they apply patches to
each of those versions so 3.0.2 4.0.2
and v dot 0 dot 0 and you would have
expected from the information on the
previous slide that v dot 0 dot 0 would
be a vulnerable
if all you looked at was the NVD
information and you looked at that
package version number you'd probably
think it was vulnerable you have to have
come and looked at this distribution
information so know that I know if
you've got this patch it's okay this is
a fixed version so the scanner your
vulnerability scanner would need to be
looking at this information source as
well as the NVD if it was scanning a
Debian image
another example is Alpine here so and
I'm getting I'm gonna have to try and
move my mouse to something is obscuring
my screen and they need to okay
apologies for the baton and there we go
right so this particular release of the
busybox package in Alpine there's a few
high severity and medium severity ulnar
abilities in that particular release
1.20 7.2 if you look at the this is the
kind of build record that the contents
of what the Alpine distribution put into
busybox 1.20 7.2 and it actually has
these patches for the known
vulnerabilities applied so for example
the first on that list is CDE twenty
seventeen sixteen five four four if I go
back and look at the previous one that's
the top one in my list so this
vulnerability exists in the base image
for one door 27.2 but the Alpine
maintainer applied a patch in order to
fix that particular vulnerability and
the other two on that previous list what
we can also see from this alpine record
of what went into their busybox package
is another set of patches that for
whatever reason from probably very good
reasons that our point maintained is
made to that particular package they
could be great they can be perfect
patches they can be flawless but there's
there's no way of knowing and there's no
because those patches are not known to
nvd there's no way for the nvd record to
reflect any vulnerabilities that might
be in that patch you'd have to rely on
the Alpine maintainer sharing
information about any vulnerabilities in
that kind of Alpine specific set of
patches and of course these records are
happening for all the thousands of
different packages that exist you know
in the world and all the different
variant variations of those packages for
different distributions there's a lot of
information out there required to do
vulnerability scanning and I've just
been talking about these package moment
these packages that get installed by a
system package manager like a PT or a PK
you're young there are specific to the
Linux distribution and for a lot of
container image scanners that's that's
all they'll scan for and that's a lot
but this is where the majority of
serious software vulnerabilities come
through these operating system packages
there are two other places in which
software can get sort of installed into
your into your container or onto a
server comes of that language specific
or application package managers so for
example for node if you're writing in
node E might be installing dependencies
with NPM if you're writing in Python you
might be installing dependencies using
pet and there can be software
vulnerabilities in
in those dependencies as well any
software could have an exploitable flaw
in it
theoretically so some image scanners
will also look at security advisories
related to these application packages
the programming language specific
packages the third set of ways that
software can get into your container is
what I've called herself installation so
some other manual way of getting
software into you into a container into
container image or into a server for
example manually copying files or
running make those things much harder to
scan certainly won't come under the
class of known vulnerabilities but when
we talk about container image scanners
generally speaking they will cover item
one here's their system packages and
sometimes they will also cover
application packages such as I didn't
see here all right so I think I've we'll
talk a little bit more about scanners so
what are we looking for in a scanner go
ahead of myself I thought it was going
to show you some actual scan results
there and when you're picking an image
scanner there are many of them out there
and as I said before some of them I can
saw some of them are commercial and I
wanted to just kind of run through some
of the things that you want to look for
in an image scanner
kind of an obvious thing is that you
wanted to detect a vulnerability x' and
depending on which linux distributions
you're using and which programming
languages you're using you want to make
sure you've got support for those in the
image scanner that you're using if your
scanner doesn't look at let's take
debian as an example if you're using
Debian based container images you need
to make sure your scanner supports that
I think they all do but maybe if you'll
be using something a bit
esoteric check that your scanner
supports all the base images that you're
using you also want to look for high
accuracy so one of the complaints that
people make about vulnerability scanning
is that because you get you've got lots
and lots of images and there are lots
and lots of packages in those images and
there are lots of potential
vulnerabilities in all of those packages
you can end up with a giant set of
results and it can be hard to manage it
could be hard to understand whether some
of those are false positives it can be a
bit of a flood of information so you
really want to have accurate scanning
make sure that it is pulling data from
the from the relevant security
advisories sometimes upstream software
vendors will also have security
advisories there are lots of different
sources and generally speaking the more
sources the more accurate and the less
likely you are to have these false
positives you might also want to be
looking for automating this pros walk
you I hope you will be looking to
automate this process so you want tools
that you can embed that integrate with
the other systems other parts of the
system you're using so for example
whatever CI CD pipeline you're using you
might want to scan the images in your
image registry automatically and the
different scanners will have different
integrations with different tools a
couple of things I wanted to just
highlight here when you're running a CI
see deep pipeline something like Travis
for example as a general rule you get a
new instance of probably a container
possibly a virtual machine probably a
container to run your your build and
your tests within and you get that new
instance ever
every time some of them support caching
others don't
a lot of scanners have some kind of
vulnerability database information that
they will download so you're either
going to download a database locally or
you're going to check a database in some
kind of client-server model because
you've got to check against all that
data about all those vulnerabilities if
it's a local database if the database is
pulled locally you want that database to
be small because otherwise every time
you run cic deep pipeline if it doesn't
have caching it's got to pull that whole
database again so some tools will have
like an optimized version of the
database so that you can somebody's
faster download basically in CI CD some
pipelines do have the ability to cache
some information so you can keep that
that database
cached but updated another interesting
point is whether your scanner relies on
having something like docker present to
pull the image for you or whether it can
pull the image by itself this is kind of
a almost a sort of preference thing
really it's quite nice to have a scanner
that you can run stand alone without a
dependency on other on having docker
installed or having other tools like
scope you installed and having tools
that are easy to install and use I think
we'd all rather to use tools that are
easy to install and use and then the
last set of things is additional
features and now some of these things so
for example malware the feeds that the
data feeds that a scan would use to
identify malware I think that the most
if not all are commercial so you're
unlikely to see malware scanning in many
free to use tools because
somebody's gotta pay for that datasource
other functionality that you might see
in some scanners is the ability to scan
for sensitive data like passwords and
tokens or the ability to scan windows
containers as well as Linux containers
and I just saw another a couple of
actually big questions here which is
basically how can you check these these
things these characteristics of
different scanners and I think one is
like read the documentation if you know
that you're using particular programming
languages or particular Linux
distributions you know have been looking
the documentation for support for those
scanners some scanners will publish what
different sources they're using or what
distributions they support and another
great question is is it worthwhile using
multiple scanners really great question
because at one level yes because you're
going to be more likely to identify
vulnerabilities you're less likely it's
always possible that she's kind of
walnuts and vulnerabilities the downside
is you're gonna have to figure out which
set of results is correct and correct
turns out to be really hard like when I
first started in software I thought that
you know software things were generally
you know they worked or they didn't work
things are fixed on they're broken
turns out there's a whole gray area with
vulnerabilities so for example the MPD
may say that a particular vulnerability
a particular vulnerability is high
severity classified it that way and a
particular distribution might say
because of some mitigating factor
because of some other characteristic of
their system it's not so severe on their
platform so are you'd think as a general
rule I would tend to say the
distribution is probably correct that
you know they take these things
seriously they want to have the correct
assessment of vulnerabilities but
you know philosophically what do I take
the most severe result or do I take the
distribution results it's it's kind of a
philosophical choice you do also get
this knowledge of which version got the
patch applied and so some sometimes the
version numbering is not as consistent
as you would hope so
sometimes packages get released you know
not in semantic version order
incorrectly and then you have this
problem of whether or not a version is
vulnerable or not and you can't
necessarily just do a sort of
mathematical check on the version number
and using multiple scanners I think I
would hope that most scanners if they
are pulling from the correct sources
would be would be pretty accurate pretty
they would pretty much agree on the
really important like critical high
severity vulnerabilities it would be an
interesting test to compare the team oh
one of the interesting some anecdote I
suppose about these different sources
Alpine the Alpine Linux distribution a
few months ago changed the way their
publishing their security advisories and
hmm I know because I my company works
produces this open-source tool called
trivy you know we updated it to use the
new source but we know that there are
some other scanners who have not updated
to use the new source yet and so their
data is you know now several months out
of date so it's kind of a an interesting
test I would definitely say try testing
for some more recent vulnerabilities and
see whether you get the right results
I'll come back to that question later
actually I think there's one last
question come up okay so I wanted to do
a quick demo I'm actually just going to
use the screenshot just to sort of save
a bit of time here so trivy which I just
mentioned and this is the open source
tool that that I my team and I work on
called trivy and we do try to make it
really easy to install and use so you
can install it using things like
homebrew if you want to put it on your
Mac we have installations for a lot of
the major package managers so you can
just install it from using yeah more apt
whatever your package manager of choice
is and basically you just run trivy and
the name of your image and that's all
you need to do some scanners will
require you to install a variety of
different components we try to make it
as simple as possible and this is an
example of some results so here I
actually took this earlier as you can
see earlier today you can see from the
timestamp
I ran shipping it against an old version
of Alpine that I knew even in that base
image it has some known vulnerabilities
in some of the packages installed and
you can see the kind of information
you're looking for from a scanner so
first of all how many issues there are
and what severity they are so you might
choose to have a very simple rule that
says if this has any high severity or
critical vulnerabilities I don't want to
deploy it or you might have more
sophisticated rules that say well in
general I don't want to deploy any high
severity vulnerabilities but perhaps
I've got like some white listed ones
that I know I'm gonna have to live with
for some period of time but generally
speaking as a rule of thumb not
deploying any high or critical severity
vulnerabilities would be
really good to baseline policy so if he
saw a result like this you would not
want to deploy this image and you would
not want to deploy an image based on
this version of Alpine and other thing
to point out is it's showing you what
version is installed into this image and
it showing you what version needs to be
installed in order to get the while to
remove the vulnerability running the
same thing over Alpine latest now I left
in this warning so scanning using the
latest tag is a little bit you know I
wouldn't necessarily recommend it
because it's a little bit of a detour
but that latest tag changes right every
time you rebuild a new version the image
and push it and make it the latest
version it means that somebody else is
what you can't rely on Alpine latest
meaning a particular version of Alpine
and in the context of a scanner if we're
caching the results which we do in the
case of tribbey
if you catch those results for some
amount of time it doesn't necessarily
know that the tag has changed so if I
were to rerun that trivial pine latest
command it go up his the results I had
from before without necessarily knowing
that the the latest version was actually
a different might have been changed in
the meantime but the good news here is
that in this latest version three dollar
and all three of today there are no
vulnerabilities which is pretty awesome
so I wanted to just wrap up a little bit
by talking a bit about incorporating the
scanning into your pipelines into your
workflows I mean this is there circles
right you want to automate this
don't want to be running it day in day
out on your command line that would be
really dull so you can do that you can
be running these scans on your developer
laptop
do you want to be incorporating this
into your automated build into your CI
process somehow and you might for
example fail the build if you find a
high severity vulnerability so that the
developer can straightaway update the
versions of they're using in the build
so that rebuild it with up-to-date
patched versions of all the packages you
might also want to regularly scan the
images that exist in your image registry
and this comes back to what I mentioned
before about researchers finding new
vulnerabilities in existing code so your
images sitting in your registry
completely unchanged maybe haven't maybe
some of those images haven't changed for
weeks or months software hasn't changed
but our knowledge of vulnerabilities has
changed so you might now find new
vulnerabilities when you rescan
so having scanned it might for example
want to scan on a regular basis you
might also want to scan as you pull any
accounts with the registry I mentioned
this earlier on and make sure that you
don't admit images if they have high
severity vulnerabilities or you could
have more sophisticated admission
control rules that look at exactly
what's what's in the report okay so if
you want to incorporate something like
trivy into CI CD pipeline it's it's
pretty trivial
it's called trivially it's trivial one
of the things that we may be a little
gotcha is that you have to specify want
to fail the CI pipeline based on its
the severity and abilities you can use
this batch - exit code parameter so the
basic saying for example in the first
example if you find a high severity or
critical severity vulnerability use the
exit code 1 and in general and non zero
exit code would fail a CI tool and
there's a couple of other options that
we recommend to basically not show
progress bar if it's downloading the the
database it would normally show a
progress bar but that would be pointless
in the CI a automated system and to
automatically refresh the database so
just a few examples to show that it's a
simple thing to add something like trivy
into your pipeline and you know this
kind of stack would also be true for
other kinds of scanners a some scanners
are more complex and require additional
components other scanners are also kind
of single line commands that you could
integrate should you want to okay say I
know there's a couple of questions but I
thought I just sort of finished up by
saying if you take anything away from
this talk I would like to encourage you
to scan your images because if you are
running with those high severity
vulnerabilities somebody will find them
if you know if you're running it on an
internet-connected application someone
will exploit them if they're high or
critical sororities and it's easy to
incorporate this into your CI CD
pipeline if there's one thing you do to
secure your container deployment well I
mean you know aside from doing things
like not I don't know putting your admin
dashboard on on the internet or
something but in general this is really
easy to do it's a huge bang per buck for
container s deployment so I've really
encourage you to add a scanner into your
pipeline okay I think there were also a
couple of questions and I'm slightly
lost tracks they sound maybe you can
help me
find which questions perfect of course I
can well um we had one actually specific
to trivia about databases and which ones
you guys were scanning but let me also
make sure that we don't leave out so we
had someone asking about how
vulnerability scanners help in scanning
third-party libraries which are not part
of the base docker image right yes and I
may have because I used an Alpine base
image that may have been slightly
confusing so yeah in a container image
you have you start with the base image
and you can think of it as a layer and
then your docker file as you as you
build the image based on a docker file
each instruction in that docker file
adds a new layer so your container image
actually comes delivered to you when you
when you pull it out of the registry it
has these separate layers and then they
get unpacked and merged into the image
that you actually run say it's some
really interesting things happening so
first of all you can think about do you
just scan the combined image the thing
that you're gonna run when you unpack
that image that's the set of software
you're gonna run or do you also want to
scan the individual layers one of the
reasons why that's quite interesting is
because one layer can add a
vulnerability and another subsequent
layer can take it away again and so for
example you could have a layer that runs
let's say app get install some image and
maybe that sorry some package and maybe
that package has a vulnerability in it
you'd have a another command later that
does a get install right get update to
install a newer version of the same
package so the result is an image that
doesn't have that vulnerability but if
you look at the individual layers it
does
you might want to you might want to
remove those older layers kind of partly
out of just being on the safe side and
partly because well particularly if we
were thinking about things like
sensitive data things like passwords
although they're not in the container
image as it gets run you could inspect
those individual layers and find that
sensitive data okay I hope that so and
how the vulnerability is kind of helping
scanning third libraries which aren't
part of a stalker image I think they
should all be looking at either all the
individual layers or the overall sort of
unpacked version of of those all the
layers and what they'll do is they will
essentially you've got a file system and
it will look to see what the package
manager in that file system says is
installed what packages are installed
typically sounds good I think all the
other questions that came through you
kind of either answered or alluded to in
your actual session so I think that is a
rapid end if anyone does have any
further questions please feel free to
obviously jump into the slack community
and liz is a member there and she'll be
able to answer questions and obviously
we have abundance of knowledge within
that community and so if this is not
available there's obviously a lot of
people to join the discussion and NSS so
if you're watching this post live
session and your questions can always be
answered in there and kind of living
breathing content but again thank you so
much those really excited to have you on
the show and our first sort of a few
people asked me if I've been affixed
well I've always been virtual so it
works really well and but I hope
everyone has enjoyed that and again
it'll be live on the website in a few
minutes and as well as on YouTube and
our next session if not soon will be on
the 2nd of April really looking forward
to that one and but again if you enjoyed
it please
tell your friends your families you know
wasn't real pets enjoyed it too and
again thank you so much less but that is
a wrap thank you having me and bye
everyone stay safe