we're live
we're live all right all right
welcome everyone to cactus con 9 2021.
we're extremely excited to be able to
present cactus con to you virtually for
the first time ever
the overall crew has been out this for
over 10 years now we took
somewhat of a hiatus in 2020 simply
because our last event was in
december by 2019 we wanted to move to
earlier in the year
and it just wouldn't have made a ton of
sense to do december and then february
so i know many of us wish we could have
just outright skipped 2020 ourselves but
our conference at least was able to do
so and we're back
and better than ever we have some great
talks lined up we have a whole bunch of
giveaways we have some fantastic
prizes that have been provided by many
of our sponsors
overall i'm just really really excited
so hey i'm ryan
i'm the lead organizer this year taking
over from
andrew wilson who helped run the
conference the entire time original
founding member
and i'm here with
hey i'm alex i'm the uh i guess discord
admin and bot builder
for uh for cacticon and happy to be here
ryan you're gonna have to introduce me
come on man
you want your own introduction nah
absolutely not i'm too good for that
all right well i'll throw it on the uh
we have an upcoming about the uh
staff slide i'll just do it there with
you we have a whole bunch of staff
members
who don't necessarily like the spotlight
and you've got ryan
who just loves the spotlight so
all film is needed oh look who it is
hey there is andrew say hi
hey sorry i was actually listening to
the stream on the other thing that's
where we're getting the double
surger comps piece so i thought i'd jump
in and say hello
uh thank you all for joining and really
excited to be able to participate
uh for me this is a big deal you know as
ryan mentioned it's the first time i'm
not the lead organizer
i will say i am so really super
impressed with the team and what they
were able to accomplish this year
and uh just happy to be a part of it
i'll be sort of lurking around
on channels throughout the day so if you
want to catch up with me
i'll be i'll be hanging around
specifically in the cabana room that was
made for
for me it's the only time anyone's ever
given me a cabana after
years of waiting so if
you want to catch up and talk a little
bit more about the history uh you know
i'll be around but i'm
super excited for this year and i'm glad
to be able to participate and join with
y'all
right you're muted
yep right off course i'm on youtube
we've been doing conference calls the
entire year 2020 and i'm still talking
on mute
you all knew i was going to do it
everybody knows me was like yup yup
that's about right
we're extremely happy to have you here
andrew because
uh unbeknownst to you but now known to
you we were about to talk about the
lady of caccus con do you want to do you
want to be on the spot you want to go
for it
the legacy of cactus con is that the
history of cactus con where did we come
from
oh yeah so uh absolutely um
cagus con is interesting we started uh
cactus khan
literally after an oauth meeting in town
i think we were actually in scottsdale
and a bunch of us went out sort of bar
crawling afterwards and had a long
conversation about like
the phoenix community is huge and we
have a ton of people out here
like why do we have to wait for defcon
or why do we have to wait for all these
other conferences to happen like
do we have enough momentum to
potentially do something
ourselves and so i think there was about
eight of us originally who got together
and said look you know what would it
take to do a very bootstrap thing and so
we
looked at a bunch of venues and actually
ended up settling on
dave and buster's here in town which
turns out to have like an amazing
conference room deal that was relatively
affordable in fact we
floated the entire conference year one
between the eight of us
right we just said look let's let's do
it let's see what we can get out there
let's see if we can get sponsors
um we did we had a couple of sponsors
step up and jump in i think that year
godaddy helped out and a couple of other
local firms
uh stack and lou now bishop fox has
actually been involved really from the
beginning
uh securiosus was one of our original
sponsors and they
they helped us out for a season and so
we sort of grew it out from there
the idea behind it has always been we
just want
to create something with high quality
talks that are
freely available to anybody in the
community who wants to attend
we want it to be vendor neutral so you
don't show up and go oh my gosh like
this is vendor con i mean i've been
places where you walk in
and you have to pass through the hall of
vendors before you're even allowed to
like get to the conference you know
uh and then we wanted we wanted
something
that could kind of grow as a community
and
and and have some of the best talks out
there right and then to think
in the time we've done this we've had
some amazing keynotes right we've had
uh dave kennedy and others um come in
we've had
lost come in we've had uh caesar from
ghetto hackers we've had
major leads from microsoft come we've
we've been able to grow this out year
over year
and we get better and better keynotes
and better and better speakers uh out
here joining us
uh and so i'm again super that's that's
really the history in a nutshell we've
started i think the first year we had
people show up and uh 20 of them were us
you know
and then and then now we're we're really
sort of grown and expanded
year-over-year it's just been really
impressive to be a part of so
so that's it awesome thank you andrew
appreciate that
yeah it comes much better from the
person who ran the con
for the first eight year and the new guy
i really appreciate you being able to
pop in and do that that's awesome
um just a shout out to the b-sides crew
in general you know
starting as a b-sides event we had their
support to transition
to our own cactus con and uh what was it
was it last year or the year before was
last year
where we had them come in and do our
keynote um
it was last year yeah last year yeah the
years were already starting to blend for
me i don't know about everyone else out
there
but i mean it was last cactus con it
wasn't necessarily last year
there we go that's probably it right
there
all right so check it out we're going to
take a look here and
peek behind the curtain a little bit
somewhat i mean we still have folks who
like to use
avatars skyler rather than
their actual likeness but i want to
introduce people to the team
behind the conference because this
conference could not happen without an
entire
team or organization committee of people
so we have a board for cactus khan
on the board we have skyler jessica and
well andrew kazushi over there so skyler
has been
an awesome person to assist for example
myself
coming in as a new member he helps every
year with doing awesome stuff like the
badge
work working with the hardware hacking
village folks and making sure that
on that side of things that everything
is on the up and up on the art side of
things i think we've had an amazing
art game over the years i mean i'm
wearing right now a cactus con eight
shirt and i honestly still get you know
people were like oh that's a cool shirt
and i'm like
i know whenever i wear it in public like
just awesome stuff from skyler over the
years thank you man for all the help
all the things that you've done jessica
has been with the conference for
i don't know how many years now um i
actually heard about
cactus khan originally because of
jessica
and i'm in the position where i am now
with the organization
because of jessica she has just been a
fantastic advocate
she helps out with many different
conferences some of the b-sides
conferences like b-side san francisco i
met her there back in 2000
13 or something ridiculous like that
she does all kinds of great stuff for us
she runs our call for papers board
um quick shout out by the way the call
for papers board we have some folks
whose name might not otherwise show up
in the conference so
jamie winterton from asu hi we love you
and then we've got cheerio hi how you
doing we appreciate your assistance
over the past couple years on our cfp
board uh we have some internal folks who
are also on the board
uh but overall jessica just thank you
for what you do we really appreciate it
and
uh and also a note here the mask that
you see on this slide
this is not specifically a coveted mask
this was taken
well before a coven so this is just her
doing her thing and then we've got
kazushi we've got andrew who has already
introduced himself
and uh gave us the awesome lowdown on
conference from years past
so thank you to the board and then we've
got
some a new challenger arrives me mr
loudmouth mr
i think i'm a funny guy and i'll be
playing the mc
of the event this year i'll be
introducing the keynotes doing an
opening and closing you'll see more of
me um i've been
presenting for uh five years in a row
now for cactus con my first cactus con
event
the first thing i did was go to a
workshop i attended a workshop put on by
joe jurum so shout out to joe out there
and i was immediately in love
this was back in 2013 or 14. i think it
was 2014
cactus con yeah number three yeah so i
just had an absolute blast and over the
years i just i've like just
sunk in and couldn't let go so i'm
extremely excited to now be part
of the conference it's just it's you
know that's a dream come true okay
though i
just i love it um and then we've got
mike
so we've got mike and matt the hoffman
brothers
so mike who we see maybe here with us
today he's been helping out
for five years um he's been helping a
whole lot
with day of activities and helping to
wrangle and make things
actually happen this year both the
hoffman brothers but mike
also has been working with the discord
server getting the channels set up
working with our discord admin whose
name is coming up very shortly and is
also on our screen now
and just making darn sure that
everything flows properly people are
able to check in
everything was set up for the server to
be inundated with folks
mike thank you so much for all the stuff
that you do and we've got matt
the other hop well not the other another
hoffman it's basically a hoffman con at
this point
so we've got matt aka alpha he's been
helping out with volunteer coordination
and
quite honestly again the two brothers is
really helping out with day of
activities
when we have a physical conference
obviously it's a lot different we have
all kinds of
you know hullabaloo day of and
everyone's running around and there's
directing needs to occur
it was a lot different it was a big
transition for both of them
for all of us really of course but
especially for them
uh you know they're not currying around
projectors and making sure that cables
aren't you know
causing tripping hazards and stuff it's
just a you know it's a virtual
environment now
so uh helping out with all the
volunteers we've got what almost upwards
of 40 volunteers this year
right around there got a bunch of
moderators we have team leads assigned
all because of the
assistance from our crew and uh just
matt thank you very much for what you do
and then we have another newcomer to the
mix we've got zoom in on you
yeah we've got alex who's actually here
with us
red wedge you want to introduce yourself
sir
no no i will yeah uh i think i already
did at the beginning but yeah i'm alex
like
like you said i've been coming to cactus
con for four or five years and
volunteering the last few years and
and this year um got roped into
doing a lot of discord stuff because
i've discord bot building experience so
uh
yeah if the bot breaks uh you can
probably blame ryan and definitely not
me
awesome thank you sir and then not on
stream here but
nick has been helping us for many years
now
zoom in on his on his mug there with our
art
whether it's partially doing the design
or whether it's just running the full
actual exhibit if you will it's almost
like you walk into a physical cactus con
and it's like an art display it's like
an exhibit you know we had like vinyl on
the windows we had large stands here i
mean it's just been
awesome now this year obviously
different again because we don't
necessarily have artwork to you know put
around a venue
but a lot of the artwork that you see
throughout the con a lot of the digital
graphic items that you're gonna see and
be provided
uh is handiwork of nick in fact what
we're looking at right now is
technically
let me go back to the front here is our
digital event brochure
it's not yet been released but very
shortly will and this is handiwork of
nick
so nick thank you for all that you do
and what you have done throughout the
years
and that takes us to our partners and
sponsors we obviously couldn't throw
a conference we couldn't hold this thing
without our partners and sponsors
this year again it's very different in
former years years past we've had you
know table set up and we've tried to
funnel people to our our sponsors be
like hey
yeah all this what we're doing now is a
little different
in the digital venue but i want to go
ahead and transition over
and take a look at our website
on the cactuscon.com website we've got a
sponsor section so i'm literally just
going to click on the sponsor section
and just show you here we have a couple
different tiers this year
so one of our tiers is our partner tier
and in the partner tier returning for
i don't know half of six seven the whole
time andrew were they day one
partner bishop fox yeah technically
vision fox has been a day one partner
when they were
stacking lou they've sort of grown year
over year
and i'll i'll say something else kind of
specific about partners is that we were
very careful
in that word because you see in that
group
are not just people who contribute
financially to
the conference historically the people
who are in that partner tier
and folks who've stepped up to help run
it so like paypal
a lot of people volunteer and help
actually run the conference
early warning for a season some of their
main people and directors actually
sat in the registration booth with us
and helped run registration
and so what you see is kind of an
investment in the in the conference that
is
you know beyond this idea of hey here's
some money go go
like do stuff with it they've actually
joined in and helped us do things early
warning ran
a ctf actually at one point and paypal
has a lot of people who've supported
different ctfs and such so like this
partner tier is like a big deal for us
not just in sort of that idea of a title
but it really represents our
relationship
to them and that it's not it's not just
this transactional thing but it's
an investment that they bring to the
conference so
it's awesome it's really great to see
all these these folks i mean
uh bishop vox has been from the
beginning early warning in paypal
kind of in lockstep early warning i
think just a little bit ahead of paypal
and then
this is the first year uh blackberry has
joined us as a partner
you know but obviously they they
produced you
for us so i don't know if that counts uh
you know but
yeah it's anyways this is more than just
than than something like hey here's some
money so
yes i appreciate i appreciate that that
uh
that earnest thanks to the partners
um you know early warning uh i
the zell folks last year it was like an
army like literally like an army
i had some people come up and just ask
me like hey what's up what's up with the
zell like why are they why are they all
here
like why are there so many of them here
i was like because they know what
they're doing
it was it was awesome i'm colorblind i
was it the blue shirts i don't know what
color it was i just remember it was
flooded
the whole scene it was great um paypal
you know been around for so many years
now i remember my first
uh cactus con badge which was up on the
wall there i got the whole series
and i was like oh look paypal's here
like that's cool you know i grew up
using paypal
i made a living on oh snap look who just
joined us
i made a living on paypal for for many
years selling stuff on ebay and it was
like paypal paypal it was
great it was part of my life and all of
a sudden i was like oh look we're
working with them like that's
cool and then of course i actually work
for blackberry so blackberry security
services
is where i work as an instant response
consultant to have
us to have our team come on as a partner
phenomenal
love it we just had a guest pop into the
stream i'm not sure if she wants to say
hello
but if she does go for it
in our sponsor tier this year we have
axon axon returns they have been with us
now for a couple of years
for anyone who recalls formerly taser
company
uh make a bunch of body cams for uh
law enforcement um i did a ride along
with lieutenant from the glendale
pd out that's local by the way for folks
who are not from phoenix
and i got to play with the wall of axon
chargers it's just a massive wall of
body cam chargers and it was
freaking cool so um last conference you
just constantly heard tasers going up
because they were showing off their
equipment i was waiting for some dum-dum
to be like does it hurt
luckily that didn't happen but it's
really cool
if you go work for them you get to play
with tasers all the time
can confirm because i used to work for
them so they have a bunch of jobs go
check them out
great place to work yeah cool
and our supporters here this year we
have a couple
groups including a local group that's
near and dear to my heart new genesis
solution
that's andy jordan's company andy i hope
you're watching right now man what's up
thank you for supporting us man
andy and i have known each other for how
many years now we've been back and forth
um they are here they're hanging out uh
to
just interact with the group if you need
some consulting services check them out
digital shadows i'm not sure how many
folks out there are
interested in the general osint game and
being able to
uh obtain the information a lot of
others or not
digital shadows is a pretty darn cool
group and i'm very glad they can
jump in and be uh part of the team this
year so thank you very much for that
we also have hack the box hack the box
is actually
started out as an in-kind supporter
and they were going to provide to our
ctf
attendees a whole bunch of fun stuff
they decided you know what we're also
going to be a supporter so we're going
to financially fiscally support the
conference so thank you so much to hack
the box
as a note we're going to get to the
in-kind
sponsors right now but hack the box is
in kind giving away the following
five times 500 academy cubes
five times annual vip plus
passes and five one month prolab of your
choice passes those will be given away
during the capture the flag event
and i will let barrett kind of give the
breakdown that's pwneip by the way for
folks in the server
give away how he's going to be
facilitating that there's a survey
involved and they've got it all planned
out and i'm i'm excited for that too
for our in-kind sponsors we have don
sans
is up in the mix i am actually a sans
instructor
and i have been obsessed with sans for
many years now and
they are giving away what a free course
so when i say a free course i mean it is
a free course voucher
it is going to be valid for any course
that you want to take whether that
course be a v
live which is a live with an instructor
like actually scheduled out
whether it's an on-demand or whether
some month year or
ticket or whatever we go back to
in-person training in the local venues
at least
it'll be applicable to that we will be
doing that giveaway during
our closing ceremony so if you want to
get in on the
free sans course come to our closing
ceremony which by the way will be
tomorrow at uh
6 p.m right folks 6 p.m mountain
standard time
utc minus 7 for those around the world
gmt-7 we also have
offensive security as an in-kind sponsor
and offensive security is also giving
away
all kinds of fun stuff during the ctf
so they are going to be giving away ah
oscp
vouchers and we're talking about the
entire lab access in addition to the
exam
there are many folks out there who are
at this crossroads of
do i want to go to the blue team or do i
want to go to the red team do i want to
go right down the middle and be purple
like what am i going to do
and offensive security really for you
know the oscp certification
is very important for anyone to truly
understand you know
what's going on when people break in or
how to break in all the above
those will also be available in our ctf
during our ctf
by the way the ctf prize is being
provided by
offensive security and hack the box they
are participatory
so they are not going to be given out to
a first
second or third place finisher by design
we've decided that we're going to base
it on
participation so folks who are able to
jump into the mix folks who are doing
the work folks who are helping other
folks
perhaps you know um whatever we're
whenever we see someone who's going
above and beyond
that is how pon is going to make his
decisions as to
where those go we also have no starch
press
as an in-kind sponsor this year very
very grateful to have them
i don't know how many of you have a
bookshelf like me where you've got
a whole bunch of no starch press books
and i mean i may not have read them all
but i have them i absolutely love them
i'm obsessed with them going back to a
practical network monitoring i mean just
over the years no starch has been a
great resource
uh i'm a hardcore and malware analyst
fella and uh
there's a particular text the pma that
no starts put out years ago that i still
point people to
they have provided to us eight 20
vouchers that we will be giving out so
20 discount code
voucher and they have also mailed over
to myself
four physical books that we will be
giving out so we'll just be shipping
those suckers on out to folks
and as far as the giveaways and such are
concerned we have
a lineup of things that we will be
giving away throughout the conference
more on that coming up
also a huge shout out to our community
sponsors
this year it has just gone above and
beyond like i
personally i'm floored and all of us
were on a call last night we were like
what
what that's awesome a community sponsor
is someone from the community who simply
wanted to click the button
add a dollar value and just provide
fiscally to
our organization to help us do what we
do
and i just couldn't be more happy
to see that we have so many of them this
year i believe the current count was 66
as of you know like one in the morning i
didn't check
this morning you know when i woke up
after my four hours of sleep
but we have on the website an update of
the names at least from when i checked
it
right past midnight and uh you know
some folks like you see familiar names
catatonic prime
we we miss you man we love you he
sponsored our jiu jitsu our brazilian
jiu jitsu event last year
uh absolutely great dude so i love
seeing his name at the top there
we will be able to get together and roll
again very soon
um you can tap me a million times again
whatever
so all the names that you see here in
the community sponsor
list please just note that these people
have just gone
above and beyond they didn't just sign
up for a free ticket they were like here
i want to financially support the
conference and we are just
ever so grateful to have them on board
thank you thank you
thank you
all right i also want to talk about a
couple different things before we get to
the
platform we have a virtual swag bag that
we've done this year so let me
transition over to this bad boy
the virtual swag bag is a zip file that
is available
at cactuscon.com
cc9 swag you should have received the
link when you first joined our server
alex set that up for you
it is a zip file hosted on google drive
if you're
hesitant to open any of the files
contained within we included a hashes
file
md5 sha-1 shot 256 of all the various
files i can guarantee you that they are
all clean
most of these are pdfs and you're
wondering was there javascript in there
no no we're good to go so in the virtual
swag bag
we allowed the partner level and the
sponsor level to participate
and yes if anyone's wondering we had
four sponsor roles the three financial
being labeled
partner sponsor and supporter
it was my wonderful idea to name the
middle tier
sponsor so they are a sponsor sponsor
yeah good job ryan everyone else
approved it though so i mean we all kind
of
yeah so anywho we have from bishop fox
we've got a whole bunch of cool
backgrounds wallpaper for your computer
so this is just digital wallpaper you
can
throw up i love the 8-bit one i'm a
retro guy i've got some retro consoles
back there in view
hopefully trying to show them off so
really cool stuff if you're interested
in setting these bad boys just grab the
virtual swag bag they're in there
from blackberry we've got a couple
different product sheets for
our stuff so we've got like optics and
protect and we have the overall
cyber suite so these are our data data
sheets and our solution briefs
they've provided we slash they provided
a
threat until report called decade of the
rats i think that's a phenomenal report
check that out
a general leaflet on who is blackberry
and then of course
a one-page flyer for hiring purposes
and axon has provided a coupon code for
everyone to use oh
watch out so if you want to go get
yourself some axon
products as in if you want to go and
have fun with your friends and oh never
mind don't tase your friends
but also i have a link here for careers
their ethics board products and their
infosec department
and then your 15 discount code so go
check that out actus con is not
responsible if you get tased
correct and then we've got from no
starch press we have a 30
discount code that has been provided
cool little one page pdf to include in
our swag bag
i'll just show you here the discount
code is cactus 30
for 30 off at no storagepress.com
all right also in the swag bag we have
digital badges this year
how this came to be alex and the rest of
the crew were sitting in the ask
cactus con channel in our cactus con
community discord server
and someone randomly asked hey are we
going to have digital badges that we can
print out
and some of us were like we had that
idea and and just didn't do it and
was it even 10 minutes later perhaps
probably yeah five or six minutes yeah
yeah it was just like oh here you go
like this like yeah yeah just like that
yeah
so not only do we have for example
attendee
badges but we have staff we have
volunteer we have
speaker a couple others right i think so
so everyone should have your
your little digital badge it would be
really cool if we could see some folks
actually print these out
and maybe even like you know throw your
little hole punch in there and throw
them around your neck and i don't know
take a picture go on the video for
our after party something i think that'd
be pretty rad to see
so that's available in the swag bag also
and then we have an agenda so a quick
shout out to
grace from pulse dive reached out and
said hey do you have a dynamic agenda
and i said
now we didn't get one done she went and
did it for us
so thank you very very much appreciate
that so the digital agenda if you will
the pdf has all these fun clickable
links
so that we don't necessarily have to
just go to the website every time we
want something if you want just load up
your pdf
you can track the schedule click on
things that you want to click on
we have a link to our community discord
which is separate
from the event by the way and then we
have our twitter
the online schedule and of course then
we have page two of this little sucker
that shows our stuff for saturday so
there you go that's also available in
the digital swag bag
all right our virtual events our virtual
platform this year we've got obviously
the website
cactuscon.com so if you go to the
website we have some information
available for you we've got our general
about section
we have a cactus con 9 specific overview
page
which includes a link to our community
discord server
some updates that we had along the way
and then of course links to the sponsors
that we were just looking at
and we also have the online schedule
here under toxin workshops so if you go
here
you can see that we have the various
items provided to you
we also have the online schedule here so
there's our schedule starting with the
opening which is where we are right now
and then moving into our first keynote
shortly
shortly from now there's also a link
here to our store which i'd like to
mention to everyone now this is
something
that skyler really really pushed
and made happen when i came into the
group i
i have an affinity for the hitchhiker's
guide to the galaxy
and i was trying not to push my agenda
while trying to push my agenda
i was like come on i want to use it for
a theme come on
and skyler the uh is always been the
head of the art and
you know his the view the the way that
we're displayed to the public is is big
for him and he was okay with it and he
put together
with our artists nick and travis and
some others just
you know some amazing art and we were
able to open up a store
this year on threadless.com which
apparently i didn't make as an actual
link that would have been too easy
so uh let's just go take a look now
i think skyler is in here in the in the
stream too
oh good skyler if you want to say hi or
if you want to talk about the store
if you want to be on the spot you're
doing a great job just go for it
all right so in the threadless store
that skyler and our artists so
tirelessly put together we have
a lot more than we would normally be
able to provide as a conference
simply because in years past we've had
the merchandise up front
we purchase it we have it printed we
have it shipped you come to the
conference we have posters
we have t-shirts some other things but
we have to you know
front that cost in this case we were
able to upload all the art and we were
able to
provide things that otherwise we
wouldn't have been a stockpile
so we have a bunch of different really
cool art
so we took our hacktar which is our
ongoing uh
from kind of cactuar if you will um and
melded with the hacking
theme which has been our mascot for the
entire time right since year one
officially or is that started year two
or three andrew
the hacked r was year two and beyond
you're telling started the first year
our um theme was
f snow so if you go to uat
there was a guy named frank snow or fred
snow and he had a lice
like a custom vanity plate that said um
f snow on it for his parking spot
and that became our logo for the b-sides
phoenix and when we
transitioned to cactus con right off the
bat we created
uh the hectare and everything kind of
moved from there so
awesome i love it so we've basically
done the design we've taken the
hitchhiker's guide to the galaxy
marvin the robot the depressed eeyore
like robot
and we've uh hectorized him so we've got
a bunch of cool art here we've got the
little green guy
hanging out we've got some fun 8-bit
looking dolphin world stuff for anyone
who hasn't
uh read the books seen one of the movies
listen to the many bbc radio plays of
hitchhiker's guide to the galaxy
this particular art may seem a bit
confusing
but for others oh there he is there's
our hacktariak yeah
the physical plush i love it so we have
a new design also for a logo
cactus con logo going on here so these
were all put together and you can get
in the store you can get t-shirts you
can get tank tops
pull over hoodies zip up hoodies so we
didn't have to choose between them we
could offer both
they have like a terry of fleece and by
the way the fleece is super soft
and for women's stuff we have uh the
same things we also have v-necks
so check out the general uh i guess
upper body where upper torso wear if you
will
and then we were able to also do some
kid stuff so t-shirts and a little
pullover hoodie for the little farts huh
that's kind of cool
and then here's where it really starts
just opening wide up under home
for example we've got mounted aluminum
prints and acrylic prints we were able
to do blankets
and hey check this out this is this is
real this is not a rick roll by the way
it's an actual shower curtain
it's fantastic i want to get this and
replace my white shower curtain with it
i don't know if i can see him every day
while trying to get in the shower and
give me that look
i'm right as soon as you drop trout and
he's like
oh man we've got tapestries and throw
pillows and all kinds of cool stuff
accessories wise we have face masks i'll
check it out
we're going to be using these for how
many months to come now so we've got a
don't panic face
mask for example just really cool stuff
in the store we've got notebooks and of
course
what would a hitchhiker's guide themed
anything be
without towels we will actually be
giving away towels throughout the
conference so the towel of your choice
you'll get to choose which towel you
want
and then we'll just get your shipping
address and ship it on over to you
our first giveaway is actually going to
be initiated very very shortly here as
soon as i
toss the command into the bot so
throughout the conference you'll see
various giveaways some of them will have
an item value
if it doesn't have an item value as in
if it doesn't say
x available or three or five or whatever
available that means there's one
available for that particular giveaway
just a heads up
so go get your cactus con swag
get your schwein and that will
transition over to
discord so for discord i'm actually
going to throw it over to
alex to discuss what he and
the the rest of the hoffman crew have
set up for us
so alex do you want to share your screen
you want to go online what's your
preference
you go ahead and share i don't want to
deal with the confusion of trying to
figure that part out right now
all right cool so let me transition and
let me we're gonna have some weird
inception thing going on yeah probably
because
it's i don't think i can hide this
little sucker
all right um so uh brian was just
talking about giveaways i want to touch
on that real quick there's a giveaways
channel
that he's pointing at right now um
whenever a giveaway is kicked off by
either
cactuscon itself or a sponsor a notice
will be posted in there
and it'll tell you either thumbs up
react to the post or if it's one of our
sponsors kicking it off it'll direct you
to go to their channel
and thumbs up react to the post all you
have to do to enter a giveaway is just
the thumbs up react to the post
um one heads up i do need to point out
if you enter a giveaway that is
uh kicked off by one of our sponsors uh
that is
similar to how you would have your badge
scanned in a real live
like trade show it will give your
personal information it's your first
name last name and email address
to that sponsor so if that's a concern
that is only applicable for the
sponsored giveaways the ones that are
have the cactus con logo on them uh that
is not the case
um so yeah giveaways are easy just
thumbs up react and then we pick a
winner when we pick a winner and it's
all automated and random
um the announcements channel is going to
uh keep you updated on what talks are
coming you'll get a 15 minute
five minute and one minute warning for
the talks with the link and if you're
here listening to me then you probably
already know that because you saw the
link
if you need any help and support you can
go to the help support channel
open a trouble ticket uh exclamation
mark reg will open up with registration
team
mod will open with the moderators and
tech if you have problems with the bot
that will call me directly and
hopefully nothing's broken if you are
not comfortable posting here you need to
talk to a moderator
uh privately you can just dm the
exclamation mark mod command
to hectare and it'll open up a private
chat with a moderator uh so if you need
to report something you wish to do it
anonymously you can do that that way
um we have a number of other channels um
with information in them up top uh chill
out channels are exactly for that
they're for
chilling out hang out talk about
whatever
in the talks discussion category this is
where we expect you to do while you're
watching a talk if you want to have a
conversation about what you're seeing on
the youtube link
this is the place for it um if you want
to ask a question to the presenter
because
all of our presentations after they go
live on youtube
will be followed by a live q a um
just ask the question the talks q a
channel and the presenters will be able
to see it in the mc during the live
talks
uh after a talk is completed if you
still wish to continue conversation on
the talk
step out of the hallway just like we
would ask you to in a real life con so
the hallway is there for you to talk
about
previous talks or or whatever just
continue the conversation
uh moving on down what else we got
uh workshops are uh and i apologize
again anybody who didn't get a ticket
but
they filled up super quickly um
information about the workshops before
they kick off will be in the workshops
general discussion
uh and the channel should allow you if
you had a workshop ticket
to access those channels if not open up
a help ticket with the registration team
and they'll get you hooked up for that
ctf channels look for announcements on
the ctf and then general discussion
and there's a channel called ctf players
only that if you
sign in with a ctf ticket with the bot
you should have access to it
uh just a reminder going back one step
if you have multiple tickets
um for ctf or workshops send them all to
hectare one at a time and i'll make sure
you have the right roles if you haven't
done that already
um chat villages these are uh
we're not doing any um like traditional
villages but we wanted to have a place
where you can talk about specific topics
um hiring jobs if you're looking for a
job or you
have a job to post feel free to post it
in there there's channels for
hardware hacking lock picking radio
frequency tech learning
we've got a sponsors channel that is for
all of our sponsors at tiers that don't
have specific channels for each of them
uh you're welcome to reach out and talk
to sponsors here and then we have a
channel dedicated to the eff
so let me jump in real quick the eff is
here with us we have an eff
presence not only is our keynote speaker
coming up in
about 20 minutes going to discuss the
eff
talk about them for anyone who may not
be familiar yet
and i'd be surprised but if you're not
you're definitely going to want to see
her keynote
the electronic frontier foundation is i
we all
believe is a critical organization to
protecting the privacy and security
of all of us um everyone not just those
of us in the infosec if you will
community so we're very very happy and
we're very glad to have them on board
if you have any questions for them pop
in the eff channel
and uh yeah thank you for for being
involved folks
there's uh after that we've got some
extra voice channels think of these as
just little extra rooms if you are
you know want to just have a little
conversation with somebody those are
free to use rooms
uh for whatever you want those breakout
rooms um and then our partners
and sponsors all have partner sponsor
chairs all have their own individual
rooms
um you're welcome to interact with them
and chat with them there and that's
where they will be
kicking off the giveaways for you to
thumbs up react um
so jumping into the the partners and the
our sponsor exxon i just want everyone
to know
that they have these public chats they
have their own little backstage which
you wouldn't normally see
and we would really appreciate folks to
pop into these channels and to say hello
to them
again this conference couldn't be
without our
various sponsors so the partner level
and the
sponsor the mid-tier level that i so
wonderfully named
they have their own chats we'd love
people to funnel in there they have
upwards of uh four official
representatives each
some of them have a couple some have far
more than that
uh but you'll see them actually labeled
four or five of them
so you know go in and say hello when
they're doing you go into the channel
and i just want to reiterate alex has
already stated it but it's very
important that i make this
adamantly clear when a giveaway is
facilitated by us by cactus con
you can submit and your information is
not necessarily going anywhere
when a giveaway is facilitated by one of
the sponsors you will know
because their logo will be at the top
right hand side and it will say so and
so is sponsoring this giveaway right
if you see that when you put that thumbs
up you are agreeing to have
your first name last name and email
address as registered with
eventbrite provided to them it's the
exact same as having your badge scanned
when you go up to say a vendor booth at
you know one of those types of
conferences so i just want to make
very very clear that everyone's aware of
that and that that's
how that works all right back to you
i think that's about it for discord um
as far as uh
the overview if we want to talk turn it
over and talk about some moderation
stuff and
and rules turn it back over you
awesome thank you very much really
appreciate that
we have a rules channel up in the
general cactus con 2021
section and our rules we have a code of
conduct it is
basically it boils down to hey don't be
a fart okay please don't be a fart
if you are being a fart you will be put
in time out
well literally we have a room a channel
that most people will not see
in fact you should never see it or even
know that it exists outside of me
talking about it right now
if you're put in time out you will only
be able to communicate in that channel
and our staff members will ask you
politely to stop being a dick
so if we have an issue with
any community members then we have
plenty of volunteers
and moderators to take care of it our
code of conduct
is essentially anti-harassment we have
exhibitors and sponsors
and we don't want them to be barraged by
negativity they're a big part of this
conference so
for example let's just say a given
sponsor
you're like oh i don't like that product
can you just keep spamming this
product's crap and trash i'm very very
like that's just it's just not
appropriate
so um and plus we love all of our
sponsors and all of their products
so people people hey hey there's other
people in this
this discord server okay people don't
want to
come to a conference like this and have
a negative experience
so pretty much any general negativity
where you want you don't feel safe or
you feel as though your
experience is being marred if that
happens please do report that either in
the help and support or directly to
hacktar
if you go to hachtar it's completely
anonymous and you will not
you know have to worry about anyone
knowing or whatever you get the idea
also privacy and operations security
this is an online conference
we had a press member reach out to us
and say hey are you doing a a badge or a
role
a ticket type specifically for press we
decided
we did not want to go that route and as
such
we figured that one of the things we
would do is just simply add
the privacy and opsec note to our rules
so take a look at these bad boys posted
by matt these
are it's just a heads up letting you
know look whatever you type in here
if you're in a public chat room you're
in a public chat room
so act accordingly all right loose lips
sink ships be careful of what you say
try not to divulge any secret private
information
all righty so for giveaways
let me take a look at my list here of
the various giveaways
a quick shout out to some of the folks
who participated
uh in providing stuff for us to give
away i mean we've got all kinds of
really cool stuff
so we've got some cactus con merchandise
we have some items from cactus con eight
from december 2019 we have a couple of
hardware badges left over and we have
some posters left over
we're going to be giving those away we
have our nose no starch press
vouchers the 20 vouchers and awesome
shout out to
ted demopolis for anyone uh not familiar
with ted how dare you
he is a fellow sans instructor and he
has an awesome book called the infosec
rockstar he has provided eight signed
copies of his book in fact i have them
right down here
as i yelled right in my microphone sorry
about that but we have right here
signed copies of his book see a little
signature hopefully it
focuses for you so we have a bunch of
these to give away we will be giving
these away
we have uh one of my co-workers actually
chapin bryce hi chapin hopefully you're
watching right now
he is an author and he has written two
different textbooks
on uh basically dealing with python in
the forensics realm
they are awesome if you are a developer
and you're in the
in this realm at all if you're here and
you're a developer definitely be
interested in that and if you're not a
developer
you'll definitely be interested to get a
feel for what goes on behind the scenes
of the automation of many of the tools
upon which you rely we also have
some other fun books from no starch
press they've provided for example
beyond the basic stuff with python
they've also provided real world python
and two copies of practical
vulnerability management
those will be given away throughout the
conference i also have i've had this
sitting around and i was you know i was
like you know what someone's gonna enjoy
this
and it probably won't focus very well
here but it is a
jack the defcon jack soldering kit uh
we were like we don't want to give away
another conference of stuff that's weird
but it's a really fun soldering kit and
i couldn't help myself
and we're gonna couple that with a ble
key and it's not really much to see here
but if you look this up
it's a uh fun little device to mess
around with bluetooth
i will initiate the first yes stream
crash
yeah we lost the stream
well oh it's back i hear you again you
get back
yeah is it back we're back up
we're back hi also we have giveaways
from uh ex-logic
and his books as well yes we do
so xlogix his book is
right on my list what are we giving it
away
ryan really andrew do you want to give a
quick shout out since he's been such a
pivotal part of the conference for so
many years
yeah so uh one of their original
presenters from
besides phoenix uh and in competition
with joe garone garona's the
single most presenter of all things
cactus con b-sides etc
has actually written a book so reached
out to him and got a couple copies of
the book
autographed here to do for giveaways so
really excited to be able to share that
since he was such a big part of
kind of helping us grow in fact with
with ex-logic it was actually
i sort of begged him last minute we had
a person drop out
like for sickness reasons and he just
showed up and gave a talk like randomly
uh and his talks have always been i'm
from my opinion like really
amazing in the sense that they're kind
of like this cool obscure
like low level uh crypt not crypto free
um
observation type of hide it
steganography things
always very interesting talks so i'm
really excited to be able to pass that
along and
share that out this year so
awesome thank you andrew yes his book
the complete
boot rogue strategy guide boot rogue is
essentially again
fit into a boot sector and the tech
behind it and the way that it was
designed is just phenomenal
um i thought that i was like oh yeah i'm
a reverse engineer oh yeah i i teach
malware analysis i i know i know
assembly and then i saw some of his
talks and have just uh
been in scenes his work i'm like oh okay
oh that's how that's done so really
excited we have five of those by the way
to give away
all right so uh our capture the flag
event
has i think almost 1500 people
registered at this point
all kinds of awesome stuff going on with
that so let me actually get out of this
inception screen for you
just go back to the welcome there all
right
workshops are all full as we already
mentioned so
say too much more about them i do just
want to give some love to the folks who
are putting on the workshops thank you
so much
for doing that for us i really really
really appreciate that
and the last thing really before we kick
off our first giveaway
is to talk about the after party
actually
i want to talk quickly about youtube and
explain how all that's going to work as
well if you got a sec go for it
you're up yep so if you're watching the
stream now you've probably already seen
it but all of our talks are gonna be on
youtube the link will be posted by the
bot
uh after each talk at the end of the
talk it's gonna be using uh
youtube premier mode which means it'll
go live at the scheduled time
and you'll be able to watch it alongside
everybody else once the talk ends
there'll be a big pop-up on the screen
that says click here for the live q a
it'll take you to another youtube link
which will be the live q
a with ryan and the presenter so just
check out for that there will be
a notification in the talks channel a
live q a is about to begin
uh but in general the best way to find
the live q a is just watch the talks and
click the link at the end
awesome thank you
so i think i'm going to go ahead and
kick off the first giveaway here just so
that i
see it before we end it we have our
keynote coming up very shortly
let's do a giveaway so throughout the
conference we basically have the
giveaways
to the talk schedule so
during the q and a's which i will be
facilitating with the presenter or
presenters
what we're going to be doing is when we
start the q a
we are going to announce who won the
last prize
and then we're going to announce the
next prize being opened
we will initiate it and then do the q a
session so each q a will also be a fun
little
time where we can talk about prizes and
what's being given away
so i've got my first little command here
for a giveaway
and um i'm trying to find the right chat
to give it away here
[Music]
let's see can i use this guy let's find
out
oh i'll just ask alex where's the best
place to initiate it
the staff room did that not work of
course it didn't
do over
well we will be kicking off the giveaway
shortly
[Music]
i was like i mean we're gonna do it in
five minutes
yeah yeah what are you talking about
yeah
all right the after party last thing and
then we will uh close up here the after
party is actually going to be
facilitated
in our cactus con community server
so just one quick note about that and
then we will get at
the rest of the conference uh going we
have
a cactus con community server
at night about oh half an hour an hour
whatever we decide
the actual event server that we're all
in now the one that you see on your
screen now
this guy that says cactus con 9 on it
this will be locked down
you will not be able to chat in here we
would like people to go over to our
community server
and the community server is where you
can go and
essentially just be a part of the open
that's a weird image
of the overall cactus con community so
we wanted this to be up
and available year round we wanted to
have a place where people could come in
and just you know say hi and just hang
out with with everyone else
so we've got all kinds of stuff tech to
discuss
hobby chats um other chats all kinds of
fun things right now
it is closed because we want people in
our event server
but at night it will be open and we will
have the after party in here i just
realized we never officially set a time
i guess what 8 pm sounds about right
so the quote unquote after party we
thought about doing a full vr thing all
kinds of great ideas
and it just came down to you know what
we're going to do we're going to have a
chat room
and we're going to have multiple video
and audio rooms and we're just going to
have people pop in
and just say hello and just be yourself
be you because that's really what a
community
is all about so the after party will be
kicking off we'll say around
8 p.m mountain standard or utc minus 7
tonight
so look forward to that i'm about to
kick off the first giveaway as soon as
we retool our
we're going to kick off now and get out
of your hair our keynote is coming up in
less than five minutes
so once again my name is ryan everyone
here from the cactus con crew is really
excited to have you here
for cactus con 9 our first virtual
event so thank you everyone
you