12 11 10.
are you doing big stream
yep
hey folks ryan here alongside as you can
see on your screen
the whole bunch of the cactus con crew
this is our closing ceremonies we are
now concluding cactus con 9.
i am just absolutely ecstatic about how
well things went this weekend it
couldn't have asked for a better show
the transition from in person to virtual
is it's hard to put it into words it is
a completely
different animal so we have some
absolutely wonderful people on our staff
we have some great people on the team
and they
everyone just helped out and it ended up
just being freaking awesome
so i'm gonna go ahead and share out a
little slide deck normally for our
closings we don't do an official slide
deck it's just more we kind of speak to
it
but i wanted to switch it up a little
bit i didn't even have a slide deck up
until
i don't know what was it half an hour
ago and our wizard
red wedge x once again was like here you
go and just gave me one so
let's get to it all right uh fellas let
me know are we sure not the
screen are we good yep all right
that's a wrap so we have a free sans
course
to give away i'm gonna go ahead and
initiate that right now
so if you want to get in on the sans
course
giveaway what you want to do is
you want to go into the announcements
room and you want to or
the giveaway room excuse me and you want
to just throw a little thumbs up if
you've been following along with a
conference
you know what to do
boom and there it is so we will choose a
winner at the end
of these closing ceremonies i have no
idea how long they're going to take
we'll find out
so we had a couple mishaps along the way
and i just wanted to kind of point them
out for anyone thinking of running a
virtual conference or just to show that
hey it may have looked like
everything worked out absolutely
flawlessly but of course you're going to
have little you know flubs here and
there
uh our stream went mostly well and i was
very excited to see that
we had a dip and i believe it was either
our first or our second
q a session our live session the stream
just kind of went away for like a minute
or
maybe two it wasn't that long and it
just came right back we're like okay
cool we had uh some random giveaway bot
issues
uh our red wedge put in so
much time and effort to our discord bots
uh that was the one bot that was
actually functioning and just
behaving the entire time and then it
just decided on day two like
i'm bored i don't want to give us you
know a little bit of a
little bit of a headache if you will but
got it back working
everything's working fine now our cloud
vendors stole
our gpu oh yeah our streaming box was
working just fine and then all of a
sudden the gpu decided to die
and when we tried to migrate over to a
different box a gpu was not available so
it just kind of we've been rendering on
software the entire time but it's been
working just fine
so no biggie there and um alex i'm going
to put you on the spot
red wedge if you want to talk about the
reg bot issues i don't want to steal
your thunder i think it's such a
fun thing to discuss yeah we had when we
opened the con server the night before
kind of like a soft opening um the
registration bot just completely crashed
uh didn't work at
all and people were just streaming in it
had no way to check into the con
so for a good hour and a half i was
running the entire con for my laptop on
wi-fi on my desk
and shockingly it completely held up but
it was a little nerve-wracking watching
everyone come in with absolutely no way
i've literally had sleepless nights
about this registration bot
at one point he held up his laptop and
you can hear the fans just you know
going crazy it was a it was a good time
but it worked out
and uh we're all the better for it
so i'd like to do a quick meet the staff
thing once again we did one in the
opening
and by the way we do have a brochure
that is available
so folks can go check out that brochure
i'm going to just navigate over to it
myself so you can
ignore my typing for a second here um
our artist we have uh two artists two
primary artists this year we had both
uh nick and we had travis who helped us
out uh we'll have general thanks later
but i'm just jumping the gun now
and uh nick was able to put together
this great brochure for us
so i'm gonna pull it up real quick right
about
now and pop it on the screen
and i'd like everyone who wants to kind
of follow along if you will to go check
it out so it's just
uh cc9 slash
excuse me cactuscon.com cc9 brochure or
just slash brochure we'll also bring it
up so in the digital event brochure
we have some information about the
people behind the scenes
so you know if for anyone following
along this week obviously you saw a
whole lot of me you saw a whole lot of
ryan because
i was in all of the q and a's and oh
god did i love doing that but this
conference isn't just about
one or two or three people it's about an
entire team so we have a board
actually and on the board we have skyler
jessica or jess
and then we have kazushi or andrew who
just gave a talk two talks ago
so just a shout out to them for all the
things that they do
um if any of them want to unmute and
start rambling away
i'm all for it but i know a lot of times
the team just like ah
you'd be that you'd be the mouth runner
so skylar does a
absolutely great job with the hardware
badge stuff facilitating that and
working with the folks who do those in
previous years
he also helps out a whole lot with
general organization for all of our art
stuff
and just did a great job this year the
store we had on threadless
it i love it i got all kinds of stuff in
the store we'll be talking about the
store
shortly here during the closing and i'll
show off some of the cool things we have
there and it was all made possible by
our two artists and skyler and jess i
we just had our last talk was like oh i
learned about cactus con because of jess
i'm pretty sure i did too um i think i
had a conversation with her actually in
san francisco
at one point and i was you know not at
home and realized that there's a con at
home like what
so jess has been great she's uh this
year
big time helping with all the speakers
and wrangling the speakers and
facilitating and overall management uh
managing
the call for papers process so we really
appreciate that
she also has helped out a lot with uh
social media type of stuff
uh in the past and this year so just
very very grateful to have her on the
board
and then of course we have andrew who if
anyone was in the q a you saw that you
know andrew was on
the board for uh i mean on onboard if
you will
since day one and this was part of his
original idea
to make this all happen so you know a
huge thank you to them let me take a
look here
how many of them are on camera right now
all three of them
ah of course the internet monitors the
video on skyler's hiding from us that's
all right
so anyways thank you all very much we
also have other people who are not
officially on the board if you will
you've got uh mr runs his mouth a lot
that'd be me over here
and then you've got mike mike was
excuse me i have fond memories of the
closings for cactus con
and for some reason i just this one
event loops in my head
all the time and it's mike sitting on
stage while andrew was talking
and just kind of kicking his feet around
looking at the audience and i don't know
why i always
flash back to that uh but mike has been
extremely extremely helpful
he and his brother matt who's just the
right over here
have been pivotal for day of operations
primarily like really big for day of
you know making sure that speakers are
going to the right places making sure
the projectors are in the right places
making sure the rooms are
set up as they're supposed to be all of
that the transition to
a digital to a virtual space was very
different
for us our home this year our venue was
discord
so the two of them helped a whole lot
with discord setting up all the rooms
making sure all the permissions were
correct
on the day of today and yesterday they
were also they went right back to their
old roles really and just did a great
job of making sure speakers knew where
to go
and telling me like hey stupid you
forgot to do this i was okay
i got it done like it was just great uh
matt thank you thank you very much
uh we also have volunteer coordination
under their umbrella
we had how many total volunteers 37
almost 40-ish volunteers uh this year
yeah we had 37 and uh i think only like
can't or like actually showed up but we
had uh i think we had over 80
people who submitted a form to be a
volunteer but
obviously we didn't need quite that many
for the virtual then
but appreciate everybody who offers
their time to us
yes well matt thank you very much for
helping run that i saw matt
i'm the spreadsheet king so i had a
spreadsheet of depth with you know like
what 20 something tabs for everyone's
tasks but he had his own spreadsheet
just for
organization of the various crews and
committees that would be you know make
up the volunteer staff
and appointing team leads and i saw how
that was operating it was like oh
he's been doing this a while like okay
they're very cool very cool that was
awesome to see
and then i love this picture of him over
here
we've got alex who also goes by red
wedge x
we're we're gonna call him the overall
potential master of this online event
not just the discord
master because alex did so
so much for us and this is his first
year um
specifically on the staff last year and
i believe the year before
right he was a volunteer and i actually
was running my mouth as usual and some
slack group or i don't know somewhere i
think it was actually in
one of the previous cactus con slacks
and i was asking like who knows a good
discord developer because we're gonna
need one for you know
the conference that we just did and alex
was the first person to respond to me
and we set up a meeting and within 10
minutes maybe
i was like holy crap this is our guy and
as everyone could see
with the registration about the giveaway
bought our hacktar our moderation bot
all the above
it was absolutely the right way to go so
thank you alex
i can't thank you enough for how awesome
this event was because of your work
and then we've got nick nick is has been
an artist for us for i don't know how
many years now quite a few actually
um at first was you know a lot of a lot
of time donation
uh involved over the years too uh just
helping us out getting stuff done
and the in person at the former cactus
cons events
there we've had art all over the place
like literally all over the place you
know on the windows and vinyl stickers
and
huge huge things you know like multi 10
20 feet by something whatever
and uh he's organized a whole lot of
that so just thank you very much
hopefully you see this at some point we
really appreciate
all the stuff that you've done for us
over the years and this year of course
and heck we're looking at a digital
brochure that you made
so thank you very much nick it is
much appreciated all right and i'm gonna
actually transition on back to this
little guy right here
and give some additional thanks to folks
who helped make the event what it was
thank you thank you thank you thank you
to our two keynote speakers
eva galperin and april wright both of
your keynotes were freaking
awesome i believe i personally saw the
most
interactivity and interaction throughout
the entire conference
during both of your keynotes it was just
uh just amazing
on eva's side we've been trying to get
the eff involved with cactus con
for quite a while and then as we reached
out to eva it just became so freaking
easy she was like yeah
i'll do that i was like oh yay awesome
uh
so thank you very much for your talk and
also for the eff by the way
for being involved with us and being
available for people to you know to go
to
for april i don't know how many times
i've i've snuck my way into like the
cool a cool kids you know group and
she's either standing right there or
she's already in the slack and i
you know just watching her work for so
long now and having her keynote
is just it's extremely extremely
applicable
and i love it if anyone didn't see
either of those keynotes
please make sure you go back and check
those suckers out all of our talks
and all of our q and a's and this talk
now you know what we're doing now the
closing
it's all on or going to be on youtube
and you can find the link
at just simply cactuscon.com youtube
i'm going to set that link up i actually
didn't set it up so as soon as someone
else starts talking i'll make it live
otherwise for right now just go to
youtube and type in cactus con you'll
find our account
speakers thank you speakers you wouldn't
have much of a con without speakers
right
so we had a whole bunch of submissions
to our cfp that jess helped run as she's
done for years
i think we had over 45 right i think and
uh we decided we made the decision to go
with
one track we wanted to just have one
track and we didn't want to release all
the videos at once and have people just
kind of randomly go to the talks we
rather chose to go with the hey we're
going to do a premiere mode right they
were all pre-recorded
but we want it to feel like it's
actually on schedule and do live
q and a's after so out of all those
talks we whittled it down
to just 14 and personally i think
it worked out really well i i loved all
of our extremely happy that all the
speakers
were able to be here with us also for q
a
thank you speakers there's no con
without speakers it's the entire purpose
that you know without speakers
also the folks who ran our workshops we
had four different workshops
we understand by the way we know we are
fully cognizant of the fact
that not enough people felt they got
into the workshops
um on one hand at uh cactus cons in
person or
any conference really workshops are
often the most limited
thing for me i i totally feel all of the
people who are like
i didn't get in the workshop like that
sucks i'm the same damn way when i go to
a conference i typically spend the whole
damn time
either talking to people in the hallways
or in workshops
so one of the things we're going to try
to to work on for next year if we have
however much of an element of a virtual
conference is dealing with that
and trying to make them as big as
possible while keeping the
folks running them comfortable but the
workshops went
really really well so thank you so much
to the folks who ran
your workshops for us that was awesome
and all of the talks are in the digital
brochure by the way so let me just pop
back over that little sucker
so if we go over to the digital brochure
i'm just going to skip past those
we've got here our keynotes
and then we've got our workshops so
thank you to sam bone and
elizabeth biddlecom i'll stop the last
name sam and elizabeth
i've known sam fernando how many years
now hell i profess my love for him
every every chance i get i have a video
on youtube me talking about how great
his website is
sam i love you we all love you thank you
so much for being a part of cactus con
uh thank you to christy for the analysis
101 and 102 for the incident responder
i think it's critical that we have these
types of workshops
more and more of them at conferences or
at other venues just like this we're
even throwing around
ideas of doing potentially
we're not committing anything but
potentially looking at you know
between or at some point a conference
that's sole focus
is essentially workshops because of how
important they are
and this type of introductory like look
you're just gonna jump into it you're
gonna get your feet wet you're gonna do
it hands-on that is exactly
what we all want uh gavin thank you very
much for your machine learning
workshop that was a really cool one um i
personally i'm huge on machine learning
in the general ai
it's that's what i do you know work for
a company and
it's just great to have that in your
talk of course too and then
george i mean purple teaming is i i just
from the first time at last company that
we did your last job
we did a purple team versus just a red
team it was like
the heavens you know the clouds parted
and the heavens sang down i was like
this is this is the way
right this is the way to do this this is
how we do this so providing that
workshop for our attendees
freaking awesome thank you so much
all right i'm not gonna have time to go
through all the talks but i'm just gonna
say that we do have all the talks
did see i'll just keep paging down
randomly through
here they are in the digital brochure so
please
check those out and reach out to any
speakers ask them questions bug them
constantly you know
let them know that they are loved our
partners
all of our sponsors all of our sponsors
a conference
would be purposeless without speakers it
would not be possible without sponsors
um not having any type of money to do
anything
that's not going to work very well you
know cactus con is we are officially a
501c3 organization
so we're not in this for profit we're in
this for the community
and that's why for example we have a
discord community server it's called
cactus con
community facilitating all that does
require
money essentially right so we're not
trying to line our pockets but we need
money coming in this year our partners
bishop
fox blackberry early warning and paypal
thank you so much for being a partner at
that tier and at that level it's a
pretty decent
it's a decent amount of money to provide
to a group like ours
for getting into a conference that
really there haven't been that many
for you to judge what you're going to
get for your money right what you're
going to get for that
as andrew has said in the past in fact
he said it so well in our opening i
don't know if he was unmuted say it
himself but our partners
are not just sponsors they are literally
partners they're they go above and
beyond they do
things and they apply themselves oh
andrew you're unmuted go
yeah uh no our partner here actually
came about
because he had so many different
sponsors or
step up and actually contribute so much
more
beyond this idea of uh just giving us
money right so early warning
spent a lot of time in the early days
helping us with
um registration as an example they
helped run the registration booths with
jessica
and then we've had bishop fox involved
from the beginning when
even when it was stack and lieu and you
know they've helped us with
they helped us with the ctfs and several
art pieces and some of the marketing
such so
we've done a really we created this
because of their involvement in the
conference
and our ability to continue to up level
and and make this what
what ultimately we want is something
that benefits the whole community
including
the the companies and the people who are
looking for work here in town so
it's been it's been phenomenal to see
this many people step up paypal
more recently and then uh blackberry
this is the first year
uh they've they've joined at this level
but you know obviously they gave us
they gave us time for you so so there's
that
yes very cool thank you andrew
our sponsors we had one sponsor tier and
yes yes
it was my personal decision to have
three tiers this year and to name the
middle tier
sponsor awesome good job ryan that was
more than confusing that's okay so axon
thank you very much for being a return
sponsor of cactus con i did miss not
hearing the tasers
constantly going off like we have in
meat space where you're like and people
go
getting excited by your tasers so thank
you thank you thank you very much and by
the way folks
don't forget our digital swag bag which
does include a 15
discount code for axon the swag bag is
at cactuscon.com
cc9 swag and that's the zip file and
there's a bunch of pdfs in there
one of theirs is that little guy right
there and then we have our supporters
uh new genesis solutions starting with
you andy hi i'd like to say your name
we've been buddies for a while now and i
reached out and he's only started his
company but maybe two years officially
right and uh
i was like you want to sponsor you want
to give us money get money to give yet
you're a pretty new company how's it
going well he's doing pretty darn well
so he was able to to throw us a
sponsorship our way and we really
appreciate you man
and then the digital shadows crew i
personally i'm just huge
on what digital shadows their realm
they deal with uh really big into threat
intel and really big into
groups that dedicate themselves to that
so having one of them on board uh
thank you heck yeah hack the box hack
the box
originally started as an in-kind sponsor
and uh
uh i guess i should call him pwn eip as
opposed to real name i don't know if he
loves me say his real name
a fellow who ran our ctf actually
brought in hacked the box and when he
contacted me
said hey do you need a ctf and we
actually had one
previously lined up and it turns out it
just wasn't going to work out and i had
just found out
basically it the day before so pone
reaches out to me and he's like you do
you need a ctf
yeah yeah we do we really do need a ctf
and then he also was like oh i can get a
bunch of giveaways is that cool i'm like
yeah
that's perfectly fine so hack the box
gave away a whole bunch of great stuff
and i will actually let
their crew discuss that when we get to
that slide
but they also went forward and was like
oh you want you want some money too
we'll be a supporter too if that's cool
and i said yeah that's cool
so thank you very much to them really
appreciate that
our in-kind sponsors provided some
really cool freaking giveaways
we have sans and by the way they
originally came in
and the offer to be an in-kind sponsor
was a free sans course which by the way
those are
that is um that's a really good giveaway
i don't want to throw at dollar amounts
but if you go look at the sands website
and see what does it cost to register
for the class we're giving away free
shortly at the end toward the end of
this closing right now
that was awesome and then randomly today
they
pinged me and said hey um is it okay if
we give away
four months of continuous net wars and i
was like
yeah it is that was awesome to have that
giveaway too
thank you offensive security i mean it's
really hard to discuss
training of any sort without mentioning
sans or offensive security they're
they're two of
the best at what they do and offensive
security was also brought in by pon pony
ip
uh he was just randomly asked me do you
want some oscp vouchers to give away is
that cool and
i was like please yes that's fantastic i
wouldn't have even thought to ask them
to give those away so that was
really really cool of them to jump in
thank you folks
no starch press i have some of your
books right here i got your shipment
today
thank you for sending out the physical
books we gave out
was it four physical books we gave out
uh
eight actually six so far we have two
more which we're going to give out at
the after party tonight
but we had six different 20 vouchers and
i almost forgot there's a 30 coupon code
cactus 30 the word cactus the number 30.
squish them together and that is a
coupon code for 30
off anywhere on the no starch press
website they also have a pdf
in the virtual swag bag that contains
the code that i just
mentioned so no starch thank you so much
there were so many opportunities
throughout the conference to bring you
up and to talk about you
and just really appreciate it i think
many of us have our shelves lined with
your stuff
let's talk about registration right we
really didn't know
what was in store in terms of numbers in
terms of actual attendance which is
technically the very next slide
um what we ended up with is far more
far more than i personally could have
ever expected
so we have registration counts we used
eventbrite this year a little shout out
to eventbrite
um just we use their system and have for
years now jess has been running that for
us thank you for that again by the way
and general admission wise we had 3162
which is pretty damn cool um i don't
believe we actually had that number of
people
show up to the conference uh and i know
that because
it's on the next slide but it's still
really cool to see such a big number of
people who
at some point showed you know interest
to come over and hang out with us
community sponsors
was ridiculous this year we had 67
community sponsors a community sponsor
by the way
is simply just a donation look it's even
listed literally i just say donation
format
it's simply people who just wanted to
give to the conference we're not talking
about
our corporate sponsors that we have
listed here on the left hand side of the
screen we're talking about
individual people who just decided to
quote unquote open their wallet
their digital wallets and say here you
go i like what you do i want to help out
67 of them and we received over 5700
so over 5 700 from the community
and that is freaking awesome so
extremely excited to
to have that uh have that money thank
you
thank you thank you for the money uh by
the way if anyone has been wondering
like you know what is cactus con doing
with the money that they received
right how much did you make and how much
did you spend
i'll be going over that but for the most
part it was so that we could fill
our money gun and so that we could thank
you we're all gonna go celebrate
later on
that's where all the sponsor money went
wee and uh
yeah anywho my kid had a money gun we
had to incorporate it
if you're wondering those were all real
hundreds we had a soul do you want to
know what the best part is
the best part is no one can see you to
have done that because of the way uh
discord scrolled down you're not even on
screen
oh that's horrible we all just heard you
shoot a money gun i assume
that was a money gun it rained
it rained everyone maybe i'll have to do
it i
i fixed it do it again now they can see
there
it was even full of real hundreds uh we
had a solar installation and they give
you some cash back which of course just
goes right to our bills it's not like
it's funny money but for right now it
was but no one saw it
damn it you should have told me now i'm
sad
now i'm sad you'll have to reload it and
do it for the opening ceremonies of
cactus content
damn right cactuscon 9ctf
this registration number was zany 1576
registrations for the ctf the ctf that
by the way
just came to us pone who by the way
works for bishop fox one of our partners
a good example of why they're they've
been a partner
right for so many years just like hey
let me help drive some people to your
con and just
number blew up awesome and we had a
bunch of folks we had 33 different
contacts or i should say points of
contact from our various sponsors
38 official volunteer registrations
23 overall presenter check-ins including
keynotes and workshops and such
and then our workshops were pretty much
full up the
entire time uh so that was awesome in
fact sam's workshop violent python ended
up
just busting at the seams and he said
you know what i'm going to twitch and he
just wanted to use his live stream
that was like whatever and whoever wants
to come could just show up i was like
that's such a sam thing to do
that was great i love it let's talk
about discord
we can't talk about discord without
again talking about
this fella alex red wedge x he put in so
much work
for this um bot dev setting permissions
all the things uh now don't mike and
matt
both helped out with discord too but
alex put together all of our bots
all kinds of work went into that love
attendees now that was different from
the 1814
who entered the server so 1814
showed up if you will but there was a
registration bot
that required your eventbrite
information in order to get into the
server
so somehow uh 350 or so just never got
past that
i don't know if they just showed up and
gave up and whatever we had a great help
ticket system so it's not like they
they just couldn't do it i guess they
just gave up but
almost 1500 people and andrew if i'm
correct here
our check-in for people in person
people in person people real people
showing up to cactus con
9 in december 2019 was right around that
same number was it not just shy of 1500
people
yeah i think we have basically met the
exact amount
that we hit last year so we're right on
par with what we did the last time we
hosted this event which is
is really exciting and the 1800 folks as
sort of entering and registering to get
into the conference
larger than any event we've held so far
so
right really really cool to see that we
had 1355
messages sent in discord 13 that says 13
000. excuse me i'll learn to read
thirteen thousand
five hundred and fifty five that is a
lot of communicating and communication
going on in our server
we had 79 help tickets one of the things
that we had was a bot that
facilitated help tickets so the
registration team the technical team
and the was it moderation
also yeah all three of those people were
able to open tickets
and i watched as the tickets popped open
because i was
included in those group as being a core
staff member role and discord
and people our volunteers just jumped
right on them it was
awesome we also had someone i don't want
to
divulge too much about the general the
specific details but we had
a cactus con 9 attendee reach out
via one of those help tickets and tell
us something
that was potentially very very important
and give us a heads up about something
and we ended up
providing that person uh by the way it
was blitz thanks blitz
uh we're sending a free t-shirt for for
that
uh reaching out and letting us know and
not just you know assuming that we knew
about it or whatever
so um i love the help ticket system
we had 23 different giveaways
23 different giveaways so i'm just going
to read out a list of some of the items
that we gave away
during the conference i'm going to
scroll to my the top of my
spreadsheet here we gave away two cactus
con nine towels
uh a total soon of uh eight no starch
press twenty dollar vouchers
another towel we gave away eight copies
of ted demopolis's
infosec rockstar the physical signed
book thank you ted by the way if you do
get around to watching this
that was really really cool that you
sent that out um
by the way sans being an in-kind sponsor
and
george who did a talk and a workshop is
an instructor for sans i'm also an
instructor for sans
and it was really really cool being able
to have ted
another sans instructor you know reach
out and say hey
i'll give you stuff for a giveaway and
then sign the books and ship them out
freaking cool we also had two different
textbooks from
chapin bryce that is a co-worker of mine
at
blackberry blackberry security services
incident response we both worked
together and
he gave out two copies of his digital
book we had a
bishop fox moleskin notebook we gave out
five total copies of the complete boot
rogue strategy guy that's
eric's book uh digital shadows
oh i almost forgot how dare i gave out a
amazon gift card freaking cool
and there was even more than that and
i'm just gonna digress
i got most of the big items there so
really cool to see all those giveaways
and we have one more giveaway to do
today and two more tonight
seven sample tickets were sent to our
bot when you go
into the server for the first time when
you enter you receive a note
saying i need your eventbrite
information here's exactly where it is
and what it looks like
well were someone to actually take that
exact example
and try to feed that to the bot in other
words trying to use the example
as the entry data we logged that and we
had seven of those that occurred we just
thought that was a cute little number to
provide
along with the fact that we had six
different links that were sent to the
bot so people trying to get the bot to
access links
and just be silly apparently hopefully
not too malicious
four of them have any
four of them or rick rolls nice
four of six were rick rolls that's
fantastic
uh as far as development went on the uh
the bot
stuff we had eight different vms in use
throughout the conference
four distinctive bot applications one
web app
and one lambda function which gives you
a heads up on what platform we use
and over or i guess specifically 2 656
lines of python which were written by
alex
in order to facilitate the whole damn
conference on discord
so um i think this worked really really
well we've also decided
well i don't know if we either or i just
did we would like to use
and have an online presence at the next
cactus con
even if we're not quote unquote a
digital or virtual conference
and please don't forget we have a
community server it's where our after
party tonight is going to be
from 8 p.m mountain time utc minus 7
as we've been using the whole conference
8 pm is our after party it's in our
community server
and just in general it's going to be a
year-round place where we want people to
congregate and hang out
that's at cactuscon.com discord and
you'll receive an invite if for whatever
reason you're not there yet
all right so i'd like to give out a
special thanks
and people aren't aware that i'm doing
this
um is it possible to pop back to
me as opposed to my screen yeah
it sure is i got it
okay
you're good are you good all right it
was uh
besides las vegas 2016. i was uh
surprised mid talk uh genevieve
uh who is an absolute badass used to
run b-sides las vegas and uh she
surprised me during my talk in fact it
was so abrupt i thought my talk was
getting shut down because the woman who
runs the entire show
was like excuse me ryan ryan and i was
like oh
like what did i do and she
presented me with something and
it has been a it has been a huge
motivating factor
essentially in a lot of what i do as far
as networking
the minor details that people pay and
the the appreciation and thanks
it's just it's just been a very big
thing for me so i invited her to come
check this out i hope she's watching now
and if you are
i never forgot that moment and so we put
together
my wife by the way had this idea she
said isn't that that thing i don't want
to give it away just yet isn't don't you
absolutely love that i'm like yeah it's
like do you want to do you want to do
that and i was like
i do so i i didn't tell the crew about
this yet
but uh we are giving away and i don't
even want to get my fingerprints on it
a cactus con 9 mvp
chalice so i lied i'll get my
fingerprints on it this chalice was
created my wife asked me if i wanted to
do this for someone and i
nearly died thing is that was three days
ago so i was like there's no way
that we're going to be able to get this
engraved and we did so i'd like to
present
the envy board to mr redwedgex to alex
[Laughter]
congrats thank you thank you alex
we absolutely could not have done this
without all the hard work that you put
in
and we are really excited
i mean we're really i lost my words
there oh
we're really really happy that you were
on the team so thanks man and next year
in real life we're all getting trashed
from that cup
damn right i have mine i have mine from
genevieve
go around here i have my golden chalice
that i received from b-side so you and i
gotta just tink
tink tink all night long heck yeah
okay um we are going to now move over to
discuss the ctf so uh i actually there's
my slide
i have no slide in fact you probably
away from me which is fine
yeah i don't see your stream anymore so
yeah that's good i actually killed it i
forgot
so if we could have our ctf folks uh
throw video on unmute can we get them on
i see you all right go for it do you see
my slide
yep you're up awesome all right huge
shout out uh
we just want to say thanks to cactus con
for you know uh let us come out here i
know
uh a lot of work with barry good friend
of his
uh appreciate kind of all the networking
connections get out here
big thanks to hack the box and offensive
security hack the box was able to give
us
some academy cubes some annual vip
subscriptions
some pro labs oscp gave us or sorry
offensive security give us some oscp
vouchers
it's a huge shout out to them thanks a
lot
if you look at the uh top scorers that
we have here code named tim
and pioneer both tied for first place at
1906 points
uh they're just kind of slugging it out
uh the entire time
so it's really great to kind of watch
them go spitfire jog
and ox doge uh huge
huge competition kind of set the pace
you know early on
so huge shout out to them uh we had 18
prizes total that were able to kind of
give away to a lot of the random folks
out there so
i think you know it's great great
opportunity for everyone to kind of get
involved we had a total of
635 players uh actually play and submit
flags
uh there's 13 000 flag submissions
so just a lot of activity on the board a
lot of people going back and forth
uh and then a big shout out to the rest
of the ctf team
uh both pony ip waldo
kyle ray haan system dumb juicy k bob
dole
uh all the hard work kind of behind the
scenes doing their qa
hosting everything so big shout out
thanks again for letting us come out
and uh we really enjoyed it had a had a
blast uh
hanging out on the discord you know
there's a lot of community a lot of the
players kind of helping each other
a lot of fun kind of going back and
forth a lot of memes getting posted so
we had a blast uh i you know love to do
it again next year
awesome thank you thank you thank you i
appreciate that
thank you for helping out also um
like i said i just randomly received it
not randomly but i received education
that from the previous group they were
like hey you know what we're not going
to be able to make it we were
just about to announce it and i was like
no
damn it and we didn't think it was
anywhere near enough time to get
something together
and all of a sudden here comes your guy
like do you want to do you need
like yeah i really do like that's
awesome dude so yeah all right we can
come through for you
heck yeah cool
all right uh the next thing i want to do
is actually transition
uh do we have skyler on audio to discuss
the cactus con
kids ctf
skyler
he's so pissed right now he's like damn
it ryan
he's running back to his computer all
right
that's cool i can go over it
and if you can hear me sir just
interrupt me i'm going to go ahead
and switch back on my screen sharing so
if we could
switch back to that i've got to go
now
okay so some folks may not be aware of
the fact
that cactus con for many or a couple
years now in fact
andrew can you throw out a number of
years i don't cactus con kids
that it's been a thing oops
uh two years i think we we did it for
two years and this is the third year we
have kids stuff
okay cool so for two years cactus khan
had a a sub event if you will a holy
separate event entitled cactus con kids
that had a i believe
and you can correct me andrew if you
need to over 250 something odd kids
showed up last year or 2019.
um i think that sounds about right we've
restricted we restricted it to a hundred
people i think the first year
and we got that and then we ran it the
second year at like two to fifty and i
think that sounds about right
cool cactus con kids obviously caters to
the kiddos right and the idea was to
provide like for example here's the oh
i was gonna say here's the old agenda
and the doors closed
uh but it caters to the kiddos and the
idea is just to give them a place to
learn grow
and hack and you can see here they're
being shown some lock picking
cactus con kids itself is amazing
i was floored last year they had i don't
remember how many five
six different stations uh lock picking
and
all kinds of soldering station all kinds
of fun stuff
and then the culmination of going
through those stations was going into an
escape room
where you had to then implement the
newly learned skills in order to get the
hell out of the room
i thought it was phenomenal um kevin
helped out with that and he runs cactus
con i should give him a little shout out
by the way hi
this year we were not able to
incorporate overall
cactus con kids uh a couple of a couple
of big
red flags one of them generally discord
you simply are not allowed to
you know officially and you're like my
kids are on discord
you're not allowed to be on discord if
you're under 13 years old it's part of
their
end-user license agreement so there's
certain things like that we're like well
so we are however happy to announce and
it is in
our digital brochure that ctf
for kids sponsored by cactus con kids is
going to be kicking off
the following weekend from this weekend
so a week from now
you can go find it now at ctf.cactus
there are going to be a bunch of
challenges for the kiddos to go through
and i think it could be really really
cool for any folks out there
whether it's your own children or
whether it's friends and families or
your neighbors just go
and knock on your neighbor's door and
talk to their kids that's a horrible
joke
hey you want to do a challenge um the
link itself in the pdf
sorry that was i'm sorry don't do that
don't knock in your neighbor's doors and
talk to your kids
i'm gonna hear about that later uh so
the link itself is actually broken if
you click
on the link here you'll see that it
actually throws in some extra values um
so that's kind of challenge number one
is to get to the link but
visually the link is is actually correct
totally on purpose go ahead and check
out
what's that so that was totally on
purpose
yeah oh 100 yeah so go
check that out um hopefully folks can
find that very useful
and and get some kiddos involved i think
that would be really really cool
so we're just about done here we've got
financial details next year and then our
our giveaway and then we're pretty much
done so i do want to go over some
financial details with folks
and i am actually going to literally
just make the slide
while we sit here and look at it because
you know what i didn't get it done in
time
i wasn't trying to do yes don't forget
about our sponsor videos
oh let's run them now are we able to
switch over to obs and rock'em
yeah i can do that okay let me go over
the as soon as we hit the finances
because i have one more thanks for them
anyway so thank you
all right now again we're a non-profit
organization
uh and we our goal is to
be here for the community and our goal
is to be able to provide
uh the service really of of cactus con
none of us
are paid for example um if i say
anything along
the lines of the profit i don't actually
mean profit because
everything goes right back into the
product right so
we have some numbers for you we like to
we believe in and because we're a 501c3
we don't just believe in but we have to
adhere to
you know full transparency so this year
from general sponsorship corporate
sponsorship if you will
we brought in 26 000 we also brought in
5.7 technically 5727
from community sponsors and remember
that that's just people just
giving us 100 250 you know bucks
themselves 67 of those people
provided that our store the cactus con
9 store brought in 1 190
which is pretty darn cool there's not a
there's not a steep
profit on that it's not a huge profit
per item so that just goes to show how
many
things were primo purchased and uh
that's awesome okay door's still
oh that's really cool yes
yes the store is still up and i actually
have a thing to go over um that's i
forgot to talk about the store that's
that's next i lied store
all right normally we do our closings we
just walk up to the podium and start
talking so i tried to do a powerpoint
and i almost had it finished
almost so money-wise um
we had expenses of course operating
expenses one of our expenses
was 1 100 for
taxes and accounting so we have to pay
for our taxes to be done
essentially in accounting and we had 4k
that was already paid toward the venue
now you might be wondering like what
venue
we ran on discord and it was technically
free discord itself
was free so what are you talking about
well we have a physical venue that we
were in a three-year contract with
and they were actually really cool and
i'll even say it's the mesa community
center it's where we had our last
conference
it was a three-year contract and we were
unable to meet this year because
we would not all want to hang out right
now and exchange covet together
um and in meet space if you will so we
had money down and they were cool enough
to not make it weird
and uh basically just allowed us to just
push that money
to next year so that that was already in
there
the 4k was already in there and there's
a couple other bills that are due coming
up for our our next venue
payment if you will so on top of that we
also had
okay cool discord was not very expensive
at all
uh just basically free um however the
bots that ran
on discord are in a cloud-based provider
i'll just call it cloud for right now
and that cloud-based provider actually
and i'm going to give a huge hint as to
who it is right now they provide an
initial upfront 300
credit when you sign up so we signed up
and out of that 300
credit uh alex i believe you said we
were at 220 230ish
dollars so this morning yeah um yeah so
probably by the end of the conference
we're just going to hit that 300
so essentially that was also free
right we did pay some money towards
discord though i don't know if you
forgot about that
i did forget about that we paid 125
dollars to discord because i am a filthy
liar
sorry about that so in discord land we
actually
too hold on what's it called uh nitro
boost the server up to what's known as
level two it took 15 boosts and and
normally that would be
uh well if it was normally we had a
slight discount because of
a previous membership and it was around
125 bucks to do that
thank you for reminding me about that
that is not in my notes i'm a bad person
um we had a lot of things that we didn't
necessarily
have to pay for this year and
that's awesome because for many years
now folks
on the staff uh on the board for that
matter
have fronted from their own personal
bank accounts and
well credit cards more more likely than
not um a bunch of money
for keeping cactus con going so this is
going to be
i don't know if it's the first
officially um android if you want to
jump in there and
correct me but it's one of the first
years where we did not
have to actually
spend money ourselves so other
expenses that we had for example was
there a
venue that was from 2019
so good example of what i'm talking
about it up here it's like oh
you got a whole bunch of profit for a
virtual conference where'd it all go
well we owed a bunch of myself
right so there's that um the venue fees
for the upcoming years were actually not
100 sure on especially this
contract next year so i couldn't put a
dollar amount on here
but it looks like based on what we
brought in
right and if you ballpark right this
value it looks like
33 34 000. we're probably not going to
have to pay
anything for at least for the venue for
now the trick comes into when you then
discuss
other fees and things that we normally
have to pay for
for an in-person conference so since i'm
just sharing my screen i will go ahead
and literally just
just cut that and start going again we
saved on the following
art we did not have to line walls with
art because
we're all at home so we didn't have to
pay for a ton
of art to be created now one of the
things i did forget by the way
put on here was that our expenses for
our artists
was one thousand two hundred dollars so
that's another expense to throw on there
but we didn't have to pay for all of the
art to be printed out
so we avoided that expense this year now
we have that coming up next year still
another thing that we didn't necessarily
have to pay for this year i guess that's
wrong we did pay for the video we just
pushed
some of that to last year and then we
paid for the previous year that we still
had it you know we owed a decent amount
on
but at the very least we didn't
necessarily have to you know put the
money towards that at least we have some
of that funneled into next year
another thing is uh just food and
concessions
we didn't have to pay for food or
concessions because everyone just went
to their own refrigerator
essentially um we didn't have to pay for
badges we did not do hardware badges
this year it was just going to be too
much of a pain
in the butt basically so we didn't have
to worry about all the sourcing
skyler by the way typically from the
board typically deals with all that and
we were able to
essentially avoid that this year we do
have something special
planned there is something uh in the
works that
certain folks may or may not receive but
as far as we're all concerned right now
there was zero cost to any of that and
whatever i'm talking about doesn't exist
so we were also we didn't have to
pre-purchase
merchandise rather we had our threadless
store which i'm gonna
talk to talk about right after this and
because of that store
we were able to allow on-demand
purchasing and dust printing for stuff
and because of that
we didn't have to bulk purchase x number
of shirts
and keep in mind even just when you're
selling shirts at a conference
you don't buy 500 shirts you buy x
number of a hundred in every size and in
every model if you will right men's and
women's and children
that adds up the badges
the pre-purchasing merchandise and oops
excuse me and the art those are massive
expenditures
for us and we were able to avoid that
this year now we're not going to be able
to avoid it completely next year
but it's something that allowed us this
was essentially a recovery year
for us so while certain organizations
were losing money
cactus con going virtual allowed us to
get out of the red
and be into a good place now what are
these things going to cost for us
next year we really have no idea we're
not sure what to expect
um badges aren't even designed yet of
course but i mean just parts wise like
what's
i don't know um but we also were able to
avoid um spending money on gas to drive
places because we just we all just hung
out here together
so easy enough overall we
are finally out of the red we are
extremely
appreciative of all of the folks
who uh donated to cactus con and we will
have
very specific information once we know
exactly what all of our venue fees are
going to be
for next year but it looks like we're
not necessarily going to be in
a place where we have to spend our own
money
then to even just reserve that we're
we're good we're fine
and that's an awesome feeling so let me
just zero for a second sorry i want to
clarify we
we're not really ever been in the red
right cash flow
works a little different right in the
sense that you have earnings from one
that go into the other
and one of the things that's happened to
your point before and i'll i'll sort of
simplify it is that
when we make reservations for a physical
venue
especially because we wanted to move it
to the beginning of each year we have to
get reservations
over multiple years and we have to put
deposits into it
which in the past we didn't necessarily
pay for right
we collected money exclusively and
solely for the purpose of investing into
each year
and the moment that we started planning
multiple years out in advance of course
it meant we needed more money so there's
always
this sort of lag where there might have
been some deposits that were due from
one season to the next but
never been in the red let's be clear
about that we've been able to pay all of
our bills and we've been actually
you know ahead of that game because we
are
doing everything virtual this year we're
actually in a much better position
to sort of prepay for some of the things
in the past
to your point which is like if we want
to have t-shirts
at the venue we have to buy them all
before and then we can sell them there
and so there's sort of that lag that
happens with it because this is all
virtual and because you could just order
it online et cetera
there's no reason for us to have
pre-purchased some of those things
because
it wouldn't have changed the experience
so um the long and short of it is we've
done
you know i think very well with stuff
and we're actually really well
positioned
to come into 2022 to do what we wanted
to do
uh you know in person hopefully right as
we get closer to that
it just means we get to do more right
think um you know better badges or more
investment in other activities
we also look at ways to give this money
back out too
and so there's continued discussion of
how that money can be leveraged for
things like
supporting cactus con kids or other
activities and such so
um anyways we're very excited about
where that's going and excited that uh
you know this thing worked out as well
as we were able to collect this year
as it puts us in a better position for
the next year and the year prior next
after that so
awesome thank you andrew yeah i andrew's
like whoa whoa
[Laughter]
the new guy sorry about that
okay um one more thing before we give
away that sans course
and make our way over to the community
server to just fart around and have a
fun night
arches and sponsor videos
i want to show the store i'm going to
show the store first so the sponsor
videos are right for the giveaway that
was the design so the store
is still open there are a lot of really
cool things available at the store
please go check them out
if we could go ahead and cut to just my
video
i want to show some things off we'll
show our sponsor videos
once again final thanks to the sponsors
and then give away that course and get
the hell out of here
you're good just on video good good all
right thank you
so our store we have all kinds of
awesome stuff we got uh for example our
premium face masks
i got mine today don't panic you gotta
love that
for folks who like stickers especially
for laptops and such we have
all kinds of really cool stickers so
we've got a bunch of our different logos
you can get a sticker of that bad boy
let's see what else that i have around
here i received
a ball i got my little button uh a
little cactus guy a little hectare
button right there stick that on a
backpack or whatever and i want to show
this off just because i'm obsessed with
it
i think this is the bee's knees if you
will check this bad boy oh
okay they're digital prints that they
provide they'll put them on
aluminum or acrylic this one happens to
be the aluminum one
and you can see it's extremely
reflective but it is
badass and it's really made really
really well
the mounting over here i just awesome so
check out the store
uh and of course we have shower curtains
don't forget that
all right so our store store's gonna
remain open let's go ahead and
transition
and go ahead and take a look at our
sponsor videos we're about to give away
the sans course and call it a day
but first we have a word from our
sponsors and while it's being queued up
once again thank you thank you thank you
to all of our sponsors
so
[Music]
wow what a fantastic couple of days
filled with awesome keynotes and
presentations
i'm pat flynn head of recruiting for
bishop fox the largest privately held
professional services firm focused on
offensive security testing
congratulations to the cactus con
organizers for all of their hard work
and putting together a very successful
conference
it's been great meeting many of you in
our discord channel and if you did get a
chance to drop in we'll be hanging out
there for a bit longer
most of all we look forward to seeing
everyone in person in the valley of the
sun for cactus content
it's back to us now let's all go to
cobra wasn't there one more video we had
to watch
oh yeah you're right hold on i think i
got one little special thing here for
you ryan
oh yum yum yum yum yum yum yum yum yum
[Music]
meow mix comes in two varieties original
and seafood mills
a medley of mackerel tuna and crunchy
centers bursting with seafood flavor
meow mix tastes so good cats ask for it
by name
meow and while i was trying to record an
intro
uh i decided to go on a meow outfit
and someone turned her into that good
times
all right so we're going to give away
our sans course thanks again sans
for providing this course for giveaway
we're going to choose the lucky winner
right now
boom and the winner is divius dvi
the vias are you here are you able to
say something and
so you're able to pop something into the
chill out cabana or something so that we
know that you're uh you're around
it might be a minute i think we have a
20 second delay i think we're on on that
kind of delay
yeah it's a little bit that's right
nope they know now
that person appears to be offline
ah they are offline oh well i was hoping
they'd be like yeah
well nope nope there they are oh he's
back
there you go yep yes
what wow all right cool
well folks that's pretty much it that's
the end of cactus con 9 we took over an
hour
closing i really really can't say more
thanks to the crew and of course red
wedge
alex uh my wife was able to get this
done in less than three days and it's
freaking awesome shout out to my wife
melanie hi i like you
so this will be headed your way
uh we're about an hour away from each
other so i'll probably just ship it out
to you buddy
but sounds good everyone the whole crew
thank you thank you thank you
we have our after party tonight
scheduled for scheduled whatever we're
all just going to act like fools in the
community server that's what we're doing
so
just go over there uh 8 pm officially is
the start time
it's uh just us hanging out with our
video and chat on and act in the fools
so
thank you everyone that's the end of the
show