hey everyone alex here to introduce our
next presenter
dr anker choudry who works as a cyber
security
engineer for lincoln heritage life
insurance company he has worked for
bishop fox and blackberry limited
security teams in the past
and his talk today is entitled can
artificial intelligence detect advanced
persistent threats
make sure to stay tuned after the talk
for a live q a just go ahead and click
the link on your screen
hello all my name is ankur chadri uh
this is my presentation
on the topic can artificial intelligence
detect advanced persistent threats
so during next 45 minutes
or so we will explore the question can
ai in its current stage detect uh
sophisticated attacks like
advanced persistent threat
so a little bit about myself i received
my doctorate from arizona state
university
last year and i am currently working as
a senior cyber security engineer at
lincoln heritage
i have been quite active in both
academia and industry side of cyber
security
i co-founded devil sec which is a
hacking club
at asu so if you do have time please
check it out
in past i've worked for companies like
bishop fox
blackberry very public services and csc
private limited
bishop fox and blackberry are
sponsors of this conference so
that's a happy coincidence and this is
my contact
information if you want to reach out to
me after
the talk so this is the
agenda that i have in mind so we'll
explore like why do we want to use ai in
cyber security and in particular why
at this point in time it is relevant
the next question i'll answer is what is
advanced persistent threat
we will also look at the cases which
are not apts
we will consider some apt stages
and case studies to better understand
the
past apt attacks
then we will dive into the motivation
of this data set for advanced persistent
thread that we
created to benchmark the ai models
we will see how the
state-of-the-art ai models behave on
this
apt data set then we will see the
experimental results and finally i'll
conclude the talk
with some discussion for the future
so ai is intelligent way of
analyzing an environment by an agent and
then updating its model
of the world and taking better actions
so this is the diagram that you will see
in
most of the ai frameworks
and the agent in this case is
trying to maximize his chances of
achieving the desired goal
so why it makes sense to use ai in cyber
security
ai mimics the cognitive function of
human brain
very closely so we are trying to use ai
models
in many cases to mimic the stealthy
attacks and
identify and detect some of the
methods that are used by modern
attackers
also it can be used in cases of
proactive cyber security where
we are trying to deceive the attacker
and we are trying to play some kind of
intelligent game with the adversary so
honey pots
are one of the techniques that is used
and there is research in the field of
cyber deception where the defender is
trying to
identify the best response to the
attackers
attack methods so this is one example of
how we can
actively deceive adversary
and why does it make sense to use ai
these
at this point in time so it's estimated
if you look at this graph
that in 2021 there will be 25 billion
iot devices
and the spending on cyber security will
be around 1 trillion dollars
there will be a shortage in cyber
security workforce by 3.5 millions
and already 65 percent of the
organizations are reporting that
they have shortage of cyber security
staff and those organizations which do
have
enough personnels in the cyber security
department
they think that
professionals are not trained enough to
deal with the modern threats
so to manage this kind of complexity and
this kind of
workload ai becomes very very important
so next we will see how the national
institute of standards and technology
defines
advanced persistent threats so these are
little bit different from
our traditional attacks in the sense
that attacker
pursues his objective repeatedly over a
extended period of
time and if you have defense mechanisms
in place like
your intrusion detection system or
modern
distributed firewall the adversary is
able to identify those
defense mechanisms and adapt to them so
if you have say endpoint detection
system
the attacker can wait out the scanning
cycle of
that particular security product
even if you are able to detect their
current attack kill chain they have
alternate means by which
they can maintain desired level of
persistence to achieve
their goal so let's
break down each component of apt so what
does
advance means it means that these are
not
your everyday script kiddies they are
well funded organization
so if you look at some of the apt groups
like apt 28
or apd41 they are funded on
a national scale so they are
basically really out there to get you
they use
some of the attack tools and attack
factors
which you will not find on
your traditional set of tools and
techniques
and because it's at a scale
of uh nation state they
are often trying to attack a high value
target for example
one of the apt attacks carried out
against
sony was sponsored by north korea
the next component is persistent so as
we
mentioned in the definition provided by
nist that
they are motivated and they can gain
back
any connection attempts to their
malicious software on your internal
network
even if you disconnect it the first time
they follow a evasive technique which
basically tries to evade any kind of
detection
system you have in place so it's
a slow and low approach
and it is called threat because it leads
to
the disclosure of sensitive information
for example
the data leaked
about the health care information or
credit card of a company can
be a significant damage the latest
attack that we observed was
the attack on solar winds and it was a
huge hit to their pr it can obviously
lead to disruption of normal
operations in an organization
and needless to say it's a big loss of
reputation
and because these attacks use this kind
of evasive mechanisms
the simple signature based detection
mechanisms
used by modern ideas or firewalls
they are not enough to
detect the series of events mounted by
apt attackers
and this table shows that it has
impacted
almost all important sectors automotive
communication energy banking
so it is very important that we
understand the motivation behind these
attacks and develop
sophisticated means by which we can
detect and block
these attacks so this
is one of the ways of representing
various
stages of an apt attack and this was
something that we came up
in our survey on advanced persistent
threats
technique solution and challenges in
ieee communication
surveys and tutorials so we came up with
this attack
tree which represents the different sub
goals of apt starting from
stage one where the attacker performs
reconnaissance
gains initial foothold into the target
organization
learns which systems are critical
basically
it is termed as lateral movement then
perform some detrimental activity on
one high value target and achieve their
desired objective
and it is often followed by the
post exploitation activities which
include deletion of logs and
removal of any footprints that can help
the defender
organization trace steps of the attacker
so if we look at these phases one by one
during the
reconnaissance phase the goal of the
attacker is to
gather as much information about the
target organization
identify the websites frequented by the
employees
their social media account what sort of
habits they are into for example if
there is someone
who is into fitness it makes sense for
the
apg team to send a
spam email to that person with some
offer on
some fitness string and this information
can
help the attacker move to the second
stage which is establishing foothold in
the network
so during the second stage the attackers
basically compromise some known
vulnerability
or unknown vulnerability that they
observed from dark web or deep web
forums
they can also use business emails to
send
spam emails with malicious documents
and this helps them gain initial entry
into
one of the end systems
or one of the edge devices or endpoints
of the organization
and this leads them into the third stage
which is basically moving slow and low
evading detection basically moving
literally in the organization
and identifying some
critical systems uh using this lateral
movement
so using this lateral movement the
malware can spread
into neighboring machines some critical
active directory systems some of the
tools that have been observed include
windows command execution mimiket's
windows
local security authority and the
attacker tries to
identify some important nodes in the
system for example a very
critical ftp server or a database server
which has the relevant information
so after the attacker has identified
this information they
try to exfiltrate it to one of the
command and control center
that they own they can have
google drives or ftp servers
and this step has to be carried in
a manner
that creates detection by the intrusion
detection and prevention systems
so often they can exfiltrate this
traffic
over dns or basically
they can use the
batching of the data basically
distribute the data
into small chunks which basically
fly low under the radar of the detection
mechanism that has been
employed by the target organization
and it often is a important activity
carried
out over a long period of time
so like the sony hack that happened
the duration was around 140 days
or so so you can imagine that
any detection mechanism which is
trying to identify these patterns it's
difficult for them to
correlate the time series of these
malicious activities
the last stage is that attacker uses
some mechanisms to
ensure that even if they are detected
and blocked
by the target organization they can
gain back that persistence
and they should ensure that they are
covering their tracks
to prevent any kind of forensic analysis
basically deleting logs if there are
dropper files by a particular malware
the goal is to delete those dropper
files those dynamic link libraries
and we will see an example of
this nature where we will observe all
these activities
uh coming into play
so let's talk about one of the major
reaches that happened
on one of the credit bureaus
in 2017 and it was claimed to be an apt
attack so
equifax was one of the largest breach
and it compromised the data of 143
million people
and attackers basically exploited a
unpatched vulnerability
that had a high severity score
cbss core which is known as common
vulnerability scoring system
uh for rating the risk associated with
different vulnerabilities so it was a
high severity vulnerability and
that compromised the account of
143 million people so think about
this for a second is this napt attack
so if the answer is no you are right
uh this was one of the targeted attacks
and
the attackers basically exploited a
known vulnerability which was unpatched
they compromised the portal website
which had apache strut software and this
web server
allowed them to gain access to database
server
and eventually exfiltrate the data to
their command and control center so
a lot of times companies try to
shift the blame claiming that something
that happened is an apt attack but
in this particular case this was not an
apd attack
so if we try to differentiate between
traditional attacks and apt attacks the
summary is that apt attacks are carried
out by highly sophisticated
organizations they are well funded their
target is very specific for example sony
or equifax
or any kind of nuclear facility in
ukraine there was a compromise
of the nuclear facility of iran
known as tuxnet so their target is very
specific
and their purpose is either to gain
competitive advantage or
gain a strategic benefit over the target
and their approach is
not the approach of a
standalone hacker where the idea is to
just
show off something or use a smash and
grab approach to
basically show off to your friends or
basically compromise one
particular component of organization
the attackers use a very slow and low
approach
they adapt to the defense mechanisms in
place
and the activities itself carried out
over a very
long duration of time so let's look at
the
case studies of hydreck which was
apt exploit against the
google which targeted our zero-day
vulnerability uh
and later the cv he was assigned
to this vulnerability the attackers were
able to successfully establish foothold
in several organizations using this
exploit
so this attack was carried
out by using social engineering tricks
and enticing
users to click on some
links and the zero-day vulnerabilities
with
these cv ids had some
javascript running at back back end
which was
basically obfuscated and hided the real
intention of the attacker
the exploit targeted object handling
flow in the html of internet explorer so
internet explorer was trying to access
one of the
deleted element and the element was
itself incorrectly analyzed
so when later this code was reverse
engineered
the security team observed that binary
shell code
so basically if you perform a xor
operation
using a particular key on the
payload you identify that the decoded
instruction
points to installer executable
which is the shell code of hydraulic
installer
so what this hydra
exploit does to maintain exp
access is ensure that it uses a dropper
file which generates a
random service and it drops a component
dynamic link library from its resource
at a particular location and it
adds this to one of the registry entries
to
maintain persistence
it goes on and creates a service with
some characteristics which allows it
access
which allows it to automatically start
in case it is shut down
and this dynamic link library is a
component is executed under the context
of generic
host process servicehost.exe
once the hydrec is done with
the exploit it deletes its traces by
proving
the hydra dropper file from the list of
registries
so the below registry entry which we saw
was used to maintain access
is deleted and the dropper component
creates a batch file which eventually
deletes the
hydraulic dropper file
let's have a look at another example of
apt attack
which was the target breach that
happened so
in this case the one of the vendor pc
was infected with malware and the
attackers
compromised its credential in step one
they used the compromise credentials to
connect to the main system
one of the vendor application server
so this shows that reconnaissance and
foothold establishment
involved exploiting
the vendor pc and using
it to connect to the main system of the
target network
because this vendor application was
trusted
the detection mechanism
in a target organization did not detect
uh any or did not point to any
lateral movement that was going to
happen
so the attackers used this stolen token
to create a fake admin account and
propagated attack on the internal
network
they went on and connected to some of
the pcs
with the fake admin credentials
so this shows that lateral movement
happened
in step 3 of this exploit
they infected the internal systems on
the target organization
and installed malware on some critical
systems
with the goal of exfiltrating data out
of the target organization
and eventually they used ftp as a
mechanism to send the
stolen data over network share to their
remote
command and control center so this shows
you that there are
uh four or five stages in an apt attack
so there is also post exfiltration
and deletion of logs which is part of
apt attack but
in our research it's not very important
because it does
not add further value to our machine
learning models
that we will discuss as part of this
research
but these four stages will be
important and will refer to them
throughout the
next phase of this talk
so we have seen previously in like a few
last few slides that apt attacks are
very difficult
to detect so another reason
we went on and created this
data set for apt detection dapt 2020 was
that
we wanted to benchmark if the current ai
models are good enough to detect apt
attacks
and the data sets that these a model
screen on to
claim that they are getting 90 detection
accuracy or 100
detection accuracy are those data sets
themselves are good enough
and as a
snapshot of what we are going to see
next is that existing data sets
fail to model all phases of apt attacks
and they don't cover all the attack
vectors of the apt attack so
we tried to provide coverage of both
of these when we generated this
apt data set
so we created a system where we had the
gateway router
providing access to a public virtual
machine which had
some vulnerable softwares for example
mutiladi or dam vulnerable
web application bad store
metaexploitable
and the red team was asked to
first compromise the service on the
public
machine then move on to the private
virtual machine which was hosted on the
internal private network
and after compromising the private
virtual machine
basically exploiting these services like
samba web application
or wordpress
their goal was to exfiltrate the data to
their command and control
center using any mechanism like secured
copy
or sftp or
using a client to exfiltrate data to the
google drive they created
we used elasticsearch log stash and
kibana
basically elk stack to
record the host log information
and network packet capture
which helped us record the
network and host activity of
the red team during the duration of
this data set creation
so you can see different networks the
file bit which is a component of elk
or basically agent of elk which helps
collect
this logs is on a api network
and the private network connects
the public vm private vm and log server
and the red team was using
the exposed service on the public
network
to access the public vm first
and then eventually leading up to the
goal of private vm
and exfiltrating the data so what we did
was we
broke up the apt
attack across multiple days so
during day one we asked a
group of students to perform
the normal activities on these services
that were exposed on public network
so they did bring get post requests they
pulled
web pages they used
curl to
test some of the links on these
vulnerable services they uploaded the
files
downloaded the files so this was done to
baseline how the normal
behavior of the users looks like
during the second day the red team
performed reconnaissance
using different tools and techniques
such as work suite or they use account
discovery techniques
or sql map the idea was to cover
as many ttps as possible
once they had the reconnaissance
information the
next stage was foothold establishment
where the red team basically used things
like php reversal
or net cat or sql injection to
exploit the vulnerabilities on the
public vm that we can see in the
top left of this figure
and the idea was to gain root access
or gain some kind of persistence on the
public
vm of the network so
during next day they use lateral
movement to
target the services on the private vm
like sum up or dns so these were little
bit difficult to target
compared to the services on the public
virtual machine
so they performed nmap scan they
exploited some
authentication and
used uh authentication vulnerabilities
and used some scripts to target
the vulnerabilities on this private
network
and on day five they used uh tools and
techniques like
google drive client to exfiltrate the
data
or using ftp to
exfiltrate the data to their ftp server
or simple tools like w put or
scp so as you can see that we
did all the individual activities during
these different days to ensure that
we can observe each individual activity
of
the apt attack that we
defined during the
example of this target hack
so that was the motivation uh to perform
them on
different days another key
thing was that we carried out a lot of
normal
activities during that these days and
large percentage of traffic was normal
activity so
this was done to ensure that the
percentage of attack traffic remained
very low compared to the normal traffic
so we had the student team
doing the normal activity during all
these days
and the red team trying to do
these attack steps and trying to blend
in
to the normal traffic
so when we compared the data set that we
created dapd 2020
with other data sets we observe that
most
data sets they perform only
first three phases of apt attack like
cic ids was a well-known data set that
performed just a normal traffic
reconnaissance and foothold
establishment
similarly other data sets that are
popularly used to
benchmark machine learning models they
were missing the lateral movement and
data exfiltration which was
carried out in our data set so this was
to provide
completion of all phases of apt attack
so next i'll discuss the machine
learning models
so the idea was to use semi supervised
machine learning models
and by developing a baseline of normal
behavior
any deviation from this baseline
behavior was indicative of
the anomaly and semi supervised
approaches
are prevalent in anomaly detection
research where the idea is to make
distinction between normal and anomalous
traffic
when the large percentage of traffic is
normal and only small percentage of
traffic is anomalous so
semi-supervised models uh perform
well in those scenarios
so one class support vector machine
are known to be particularly effective
in scenarios when
there is a large percentage of normal
traffic and small fraction of anomalous
data
so the idea is to train the model on
labeled example
of class with more data and any
deviations from that
are anomalous the
stacked auto encoders are specific type
of feed forward neural network
that find the compact latent space
representation of
input which can be later leveraged for
reconstruction
so auto encoders have hidden layer and
there is basically compression
operations that occurs between the input
and hidden layer
and they use the notion of
reconstruction
between the hidden layer and output
layer
so the compression function in the stack
auto encoder
is followed by reconstruction
and this is done with a deep neural
network
as opposed to a single non-linear layer
in
other neural network other
neural network frameworks
the output of stack auto encoder is then
forced uh to basically mimic the input
and the loss function seeks to minimize
the distance between the original input
and reconstruction
output so what we do is we first train
the stackout encoder on normal traffic
followed by testing it on both normal
and anomalous data
the expectation is that although stack
auto encoder can correctly
reconstruct the normal data it fails to
do so effectively
for a normal abnormal data so
basically the data with high
reconstruction error can be flagged as
anomalous but staccato encoder is
limited in the sense that they are
not capable of detecting contextual
anomalies
which are significant in
advance persistent threats so basically
we use
long term short memory stack auto
encoder to
use this time series correlation between
different phases of apt attack
this is because the input layer of stack
auto encoder only accept a single
network packet as input and stackover
encoder that uses lstm cells
instead use hidden layers
as the lstm cells instead of like a
single neuron which is in case of a
stack order encoder
so this helps in the use of basic cell
as
lstm helps in successful time series
analysis
and this modified stackover encoder is
known as lstm stack autoencoder
so this compresses the network traffic
packets in
multiple time series steps and then
basically reconstructs
those so this is the information
on data that we collected we collected
network traffic data
which compromised which comprised of
syslogs dns logs
access and authentication logs the logs
of
sql servers and
we used pcap files and we
basically extracted 84 features
from the network traffic data such as
floor
duration the total forward packet trade
the total backward packet rate
the inter arrival time between two flows
so we used different measurement metrics
so first one was
a precision recall curve the precision
is two positive
divided by uh total data basically the
true positive and false positive the
recall
is true positive divided by 2 positive
plus false negative
and the reason we used pr curve
is because the attack representation is
often
very small fraction of the total data so
it will be around maybe two percent of
the total data set
the roc area under curve
receiver optimize optimized
characteristics
receiver operating characteristic
basically uses the false positive rate
in comparison
to precision used in pr curves or
precision recall curve
the issue is that false positive rate is
less sensitive to changes
if the number of false positives
are very high so basically
normal traffic's being classified as
attacks is one case of false positive
whereas the precision looks only at the
class of positive samples which
in our case is basically anomalies
so it provides a better matrix when
particular class is uh severally
underrepresented
in our case the apt attack phases
so performance of algorithm on different
data sets
using accuracy or roc curve
can also become a little bit misleading
in the context
because they have different
percentage or degrees of anomalies so
one observation was that
the attack traffic in cic ids
is 22 whereas in the
case of unb 2015
the attack traffic uh was around 14
so we use another parameter basically
confidence value p after normalizing the
reconstruction error across
the test sample between 0 and 1
and when the reconstruction error is
large the value of
p is close to 1. thus p indicates the
confidence with which the model predicts
input as anomaly
so to plot the pr curve we first set
a threshold value we then use the
test input and find how the
value of this confidence interval is
compared to this threshold
if it is above the threshold we classify
it as
anomaly and if it is lower than
threshold it is normal
so i ideal classifier should be able to
predict the
test label of each input with
complete confidence so if there is an
anomaly and the classifier is doing well
the value
of this confidence
value p should be 1 for the normal
traffic and it should be
for the anomalous traffic the value of p
should be 1
while for the normal traffic it should
be predicted as zero
and we also used a baseline no skill
classifier that
outputs a value of the confidence
interval
one in all cases of input data
and it is shown in the plots that follow
using dotted lines
the abundance of attack data in one
phase helps the accuracy of
overall anomaly detection system which
may be
highly realized unreliable in some other
context
so that is the reasoning behind
these metrics that we used
so we observed uh how these different
ai algorithms stack auto encoder lstm
and lstm
stack photo encoder and svm perform
so stackover encoder performs uh
satisfactorily
in two settings that is detecting a
reconnaissance attack on cic ids 2018
and detecting a foothold establishment
on our data set if you
look at the bottom right
in case of reconnaissance the anomaly
detection
[Music]
performed by stackout encoder works well
only
for cic ids 2018
and
for this case the no skill classifier
has a precision value 0.23
corresponding to the
anomalies and the no skill classifier is
far better compared to other data sets
with the far better than any of the
other data sets with the high precision
value of 0.87 for some threshold
in case of foothold establishment phase
stackout encoder behaves very
unsatisfactorily and it is as bad as
no skill classifier and the
lateral movement and detects filtration
were not in
some of the other data sets and on dapt
stack auto encoder performed very badly
for these two stages
in case of lstm stack auto encoder there
was
a significant improvement in
reconnaissance phase the
performance or maximum precision value
increased to about 0.9
this is to an extent an indication that
there exists
some contextual information
particularly in case of cic ids 2018
that
is detected by lstm stack encoder
for the foothold establishment the
performance is
as bad as a no skill classifier for lstm
stack auto encoder and it is
bad for other data sets as well
the performance of the lstm stack auto
encoder on or data set because no other
data set had lateral movement
ended exfiltration was much worse
compared to
stack auto encoder
so lastly in case of support vector
machine
in reconnaissance phase the learning
classifier performs as bad as
no skill classifier for all data set
except cic ids 2018
that you see in the red line
and it's performed quite well compared
to their previous data set cicidas
2017 and unb 2015.
it essentially implies that like for cic
ids 2018
there were a lot more reconnaissance
attempts compared to other data sets
the foothold establishment phase
is one case where support vector machine
performed well on
our data set dapt
2020 compared to
other data sets
for most of the other data sets
it's as bad as the no scale classifier
and
for the lateral movement and data
exfiltration
support vector machine performed very
poorly on our dataset
so next we did some observation of
different phases of apt attack
uh reconnaissance foothold establishment
lateral movement and exfiltration
using uh the
receiver operating characteristic
so area under curve area under curve roc
and
area under curve pr
so these roc curves uh represent that
true positive against
false positive and the graphical uh
or the table illustrates the diagnostic
ability of
the binary classifier for varying
degree of threshold so aucpr summarizes
the curves
precision against recall and auc roc is
the value
so auc roc value when it is close to 1
it
implies that it's good performance
whereas if it is close to 0.5
it means it's making uh the classifier
is making
random guess auc roc is good for
interoperability however if anomaly
detection mechanism is
sensitive to performance on the positive
class
as opposed to negative class aucpr is
a good metric for anomaly detection
so we can see that for reconnaissance
the aucroc is
detected very well by stack auto encoder
on all data sets uh the stack
autoencoder lstm
does well on the cic ids 2017
compared to other data sets but it's not
a regular pattern
the aucpr values were consistently low
on
all data set in the
foothold establishment phase stack auto
encoder showed
better performance compared to other ai
models
particularly in case of dapt 2020
where the value was 0.846
for the foothold establishment auc
roc
in case of lateral movement
and data exfiltration
the or ai models are
consistently performed up badly
so they achieved low value for all
unsupervised learning algorithms
and it shows that attack factors
employed
in our data sets were highly stealthy
and the
ai models were not able to detect them
accurately
so in conclusion the reliable detection
of apt attacks
is a very challenging task so we
did our best to generate a data set
dapd 2020 which covers all the phases of
an apt attack
we showed using state-of-the-art
semi-supervised machine learning models
that these attacks are very stealthy and
these models do not show a consistent
detection
of all phases of apt attack on these
data sets
so we need to develop some better ai
models
for apt detection so if you
want to have a look at the data set it
is hosted at
this location and with that
i will conclude my talk and uh
i can answer any questions
thank you
you