i'm russ
and i'm part of the cactus con
registration team
it's my pleasure to introduce our next
speaker today hypoxic owner and operator
mark kirschenbaum
mark's talk today is entitled extracting
a bootloader's
aes key via power analysis side channel
attack
at the end of the talk there'll be a
live q a with mark all you need to do to
join in is have your questions ready
well all right welcome to my talk on
power analysis side channel attacks
my name is mark christenbaum a lot of
people call me trunk in the industry so
feel free to use that
we're going to talk a little bit about
how i was able to
break into the security enclave on a
gopro hero5
and extract its builders keys so i hope
you enjoy this
talk a little bit about my background
i uh own and operate a company called
hypoxic
and we make a camera of equipment
basically for extreme sports
so let's say i'm jumping out of an
airplane and i want to capture image of
you know my girlfriend
who's in the bottom right hand corner
here uh while i'm flying i'm using my
hands i have
i have to look at her i'm using my face
and so i can't be holding a camera while
i'm doing that
so we make a bunch of the accessories
that mount on our helmets and enable us
to capture these image or capture the
video
and make sure that we do it reliably
so in order to do that over the years
i've
had to reverse engineer a bunch of
cameras a bunch of embedded systems
to make them work the way i want them to
i think like all of us i really love to
take things apart
and maybe in the past 10 years i've
actually learned how to put them back
together
so full disclosure i used to work for a
my controller company i no longer work
for them and
that was something like 11 years ago but
just in case people
put two together this uh talk has
nothing to do about them i look forward
to answering
the question why i'm doing a side
channel power analysis attack why i
chose to go about it this way
a little bit of the power analysis
behind a side channel attack
and then obviously how to implement this
in the real world because that's where
you really take the pen to the paper
give you some advice
on implementing this in your own target
and hopefully at the end of the day give
answer any questions you have
on the discord server
okay side channel attacks are really
really neat i find them they're
the culmination of like everything
you've ever learned in school
uh it bridges statistics analog
electronics digital electronics and with
cryptography and
it's it's pretty complex because now
many of us are good at all those tasks
or aspects
and so it it's a really kind of a neat
concept to learn
and to work through yourself today my
goal is to
pretty much simplify all this and give
you an overview
so at the end you could you know work
through one yourself and learn it
i'll start off with this question what
does a inkjet printer and a gopro have
in common
as most of us know that when we go out
to buying jet cartridges
there's some kind of a technological
prevention measure
that is put into the actual
cartridge itself that prevents a third
party from making these cartridges
likewise gopro has introduced with the
gopro hero 5 on one of these tpms
that prevented us from making a third
party you know accessories for the
cameras
so obviously as a little bit of a
reverse engineer and hacker
i wanted to figure out how to circumvent
these measures
well how do we circumvent this tpm
now the the easy way is just to find the
security enclave and break into it and
dump the keys and then from there we're
going to do something and we're going to
profit
well that sounds like really easy in
theory but it's really pain in the butt
to do it
in the real world obviously these
security enclaves they're the first word
is security
and there is a lot of security trying to
prevent people from dumping these fees
so that's our whole goal today
our goal at the end of the day is to
basically dump the security on caves
contents and hopefully reveal the keys
that are used to
to do this tpm we found out after taking
apart the the camera that is based upon
a microchip
samd 21 that used to be atmel so i use
those names interchangeably
the part is uh very small it's 2.8
millimeters by 2.5 millimeters
and you could actually see it on the
bottom here that you could
you could see like the dye that's that's
uh through the
the actual wl csp
encasing here it's a pga part that gets
flipped around and gets soldered on the
board and the back side looks like that
black spot there
attack surface wise it really had a
small attack surface it had
only two i scored c buses no and then
what's called an sdq
which is a bus one wire protocol to talk
to
batteries to to gauge their their health
it has no uart and no usb
so and and let's see like we're going to
attack this let's attack this as a
as a hacker or you know as a company
doing some
security research on it and all the
times
this is the flow that many of us will go
through uh
we'll look at the update we'll see how
it updates and unfortunately we found
out that it's encrypted
so a little bit of a failure there
then it will go through like the
interface see maybe there's a debug
command that they left into
a lot of times people will left a lot of
times engineers will leave
you know debug commands on the earlier
versions before they realize like oh
shoot i shouldn't have done that so it's
very easy to exploit those type of
things
uh moving on
a lot of times nowadays we'll write
fuzzers which basically just tries a
whole bunch of different combinations
and see if we can't make this crash
and if we make it crash then we know
that we've hit something that we weren't
supposed to hit
and you know kind of iterate through
that and try to find a method of
extracting the the firmware out of these
devices
uh continuing on when that failed you we
learned how the updates occurred okay
it's encrypted
how is encrypted now there's ways of
looking through that and seeing
what kind of encryption it's using and
perhaps working through
some development nodes or app notes that
companies
push out and figure out you know maybe
they use the
the default password type of thing and
try to decrypt it all that way
and of course that didn't work for our
our solution here
and then we go even further we we take
apart the board and we'll we'll see if
like the software debug port is unlocked
they didn't send a
code protect key or bin or whatever they
call the particular part
calls it or maybe there's a debug uart
that was left
unlocked or maybe there's some kind of
jtag exploit
uh that is less vulnerable
and then finally you know and similarly
we would research some vulnerabilities
that the host ic has
or the host microcontroller has and
there's there's a paratha of these out
there
where companies have messed up their
code protection schemes and we're easily
able to
defeat those so that's kind of the uh
the where i was at uh and then
more or less was like you know what this
is taking too long and i don't really
need to do this
and i put it back and nonetheless i
failed it and
so i put this off to the side
and then well then covet hit and i was
home a lot more than i expected to be
like a lot of us
and i was like man i saw this board on
the side of my desk that's been
collecting dust and like
i've always wanted to be able to extract
these keys let's uh let's learn
something
with all this extra time and uh let's
let's learn how
to implement side channel attacks now
there's a lot of sideshow
attacks out there there's timing attacks
uh which i think a lot of people are
familiar with there's vulture voltage
glitching attacks which is basically
you know hitting the part on the head by
uh bringing the voltage level down
really quick and a little spike and
basically the the part just skips
it skips a beat uh that didn't work on
that ml sam d21
so then we had you know we could do a
electromagnetic fault injection
which is basically um just being
bringing a giant emp pole so you can
think of and that
makes the parts uh you know skip a beat
also
the only problem about that is it's
fairly expensive the tools
cost about thirty eight hundred dollars
to to to do
uh electromagnetic fault injections or
emf by
side channel attacks so that was like
off the table
but what was on the table was a power
analysis attack
and that's uh what we ended up doing and
was
able to figure out the the keys by this
this particular attack what is a power
analysis side channel attack
basically all it is is we're going to be
extracting the the key
by monitoring the power we're using
during decryption
it seems pretty far-fetched but in
actuality it works
um a lot of people immediately are like
there's so much stuff going on in these
microcontrollers
at once and there is no way that we're
going to be able to extract at a certain
time
the the power used and know what the key
is from that and you know
it's it's fiction there's no way but uh
honestly i've done this myself and it
does work
and i'll show you how this works in
order to show you that uh the flow that
i'm going to be following is i want to
give you a little bit
about a aes and more specifically what
parts of it we need to know for
a side channel attack um i'll explain
hemming weight
give you a little bit about the circuit
analysis that we're going to need to
know to
implement this and how the park
works on the inside the market
controllers actually work with
information
and at the end i will give you how i
implemented this attack in the real
world
here's my aes refresher for you all if
we uh start here we work for mario it's
so easy like here you got it okay and
we're done
uh no no really this is uh this is not
my refresher
but uh aes is quite uh it's simple in
concept
i think a lot of people put a little bit
too much a math background
when they're teaching it and uh i'm
going to try to simplify it for you guys
let's simplify the aes decryption method
we're going to start with some encrypted
data and then uh that encrypted data
it's it's gonna we're gonna be working
on 16 byte blocks at a time
okay so on each byte
we're going to uh one byte at a time
we're going to add this round key
which all that is doing is we're going
to take our key and we're going to zoro
that
with uh the encrypted data so each byte
at a time
16 bytes in this round key and 16 bytes
of data
we're going to absorb that um each
each location with the the corresponding
location
of encrypted data okay that's going to
uh result in a ray
of 16 bytes and in that ray we're just
going to shift things around
in this inverse shift rounds key we're
not doing any changing to the numbers
we're just going to
you know shift around its location in
that array from there
we're going to take the the data and
we'll talk a little bit more about this
and we're going to you know look up the
data in that array and substitute it
with
a different value from a lookup table
the lookup table is just 256 bytes long
and so each value each byte value has a
corresponding result of in this what's
called an inverse
s by box lookup table
again we're going to continue this flow
we're going to add another round key to
it
uh and then we're going to inverse do a
process called inverse mixed columns and
we're going to be doing this
9 times on the 10th time we're going to
spit it out and we're going to have
decrypted data
so this is what it looks like for aes
128. i'm going to rinse and repeat it
for 10 times
oh the next thing we're going to talk
about is the key schedule
let's say i have a key of all zeros okay
it's 16 bytes key of all zeros
and we're talking about aes 128 so we're
going to have 10 rounds here
okay in order to calculate the key
schedule
we're going to do some post-processing
to this key the first
round the key is going to be itself okay
the second round it's you know slightly
different
and as we follow through all these
rounds until round 10
we're going to have the corresponding
what we call the round 10
key schedule and we can see here this is
a
b4 ef 5b cb blah blah blah blah blah
blah doesn't matter
so that's the round 10 key schedule
okay so that s box let's just really
touch base with that uh we found key
schedule
let's say our our output of everything
was uh let's say
b4 right so b four would be the c6 here
that's what that's all this s box
inverse s box is
it's a lookup table super c super easy
okay so aes for uh side channel text is
very easy
we're going to start with our our um
we'll start with the round key okay
let's let's all just do this at a byte
at a time
uh byte zero we have round key uh of
zero which was b4 let's say
was it bf bf uh yeah before
okay and we're gonna take input somehow
in the system we're going to
we're going to put input into it okay
we're going to absorb that data
and then we're going to have an output
of that zor we're going to shove that
into this
gives it as the index to the to the
s box the inverse s box and then we're
gonna get some result out
a lot of people that uh that know aes
are like hey trunk you're
kind of missing a step aren't you yes
uh this little guy right here this
inverse shift rounds
for side channel attacks we don't really
care we really don't care
um and i'll show you why in a little bit
but
because we're dealing with the
correlation of the data
we don't really care in where in time
this happens we just
you know care that it happens so we
preclude this or we we ignore this step
in aes
when we're doing our our side channel
attack so don't worry about that little
guy there
now that we're all aes experts let's
dive into the power analysis part of the
attack
uh first let's let's take a look at what
we're actually working on
this is the microchip sam d21 and this
is basically the block diagram of the
whole system
we're going to be focusing more or less
on this top area here
the cortex m0 plus is actually about new
architecture so it's got a shared high
speed data bus
and we'll see this as you know the data
from know ram is going to cross
across go across this high speed data
bus the data from
flash internal flash or they call it nvm
likewise it's going to go across this
bus so there's some kind of
caching in this cortex m0 they don't
really break it out here
in this diagram there's also going to be
the registers like r0 through whatever
and more or less what we
our concern is every time we read or
write
from this bus
you know obviously there's going to be
some power that's necessary to do that
now the basis of power analysis is when
we do that read or write
the power required is going to be
proportional to the data or reader
writing on the bus
um pretty nifty stuff so let's say for
instance i'm going to be
writing into the sram i'm going to write
like all these
okay that's going to use a certain
amount of power to do that
now if i go ahead and i write all zeros
there it's going to be using a different
amount of power
okay likewise with uh reads and writes
and also similarly similarly when i'm
reading writing into ran
uh the registers is going to be the same
way that it's going to take a certain
amount of power
so the power analysis basis uh
is is that it's just that the power is
gonna
that is needed to do loaded source is
going to be proportional to the data
itself
now when you start hearing about power
analysis you'll start hearing terms
called dpa and cpa
that's just really names for the math
used to extract
what the original data is that's going
across these buses
for instance dpa is called differential
power analysis
you can read up on that on your own if
you want to and then cpa
is uh it's going to be extracting these
secrets using correlational
power analysis and that's what we're
going to continue to focus on today
in order to explain correlation power
analysis we have to introduce a concept
called hamming weight
heaving weight is pretty easy to explain
and
generally it's just by example for
instance if we have
the value dd all we do is we buss this
out into binary
and now we have 1 1 0 1 1
1 0 1. now for hearing weight all we're
doing is counting how many ones there
are
one two three four five six
so hemming weight of dd is six
likewise if we have a hex value of zero
the hem and weight of it is just going
to be zero because there's no ones in
this
okay so all we're doing now is we take
out you know all values that a byte
could be from zero to 255
and determine the hemming weight of it
and we'll get uh
basically nine layers of uh hamming
weights where
uh that a number can have
so like we said earlier during a store
the power consumed it's going to
coincide to the data itself
we use the example a a versus 0 0.
the power consumed at that point is
going to be for an aaa
is going to be different than the 0 0.
and
if we're going to if we want to we can
probe
right at this this particular time right
after the inverse uh substitution by
occurs and we can come up with like
some power usage at this particular time
we're gonna take that power usage and
then we're going to convert it into
one of nine hanging weight buckets
okay and this is going to tell us a
little bit about this information
now we have some quantifiable
information about the data
that came out of this substitution byte
block
so what do we do with all this well what
we're going to do is we're going to make
a lot of gases
check this out uh obviously we just
talked about the hamming weight
coming out of this okay so we know
something about the signal we know
something about the output
uh we also know the input and why do we
know the input
look the manufacturer is going to have
to
push and update to you that means that
you're going to be able to
somehow push this update to into the
victim
so we're going to be in control of this
input here
we don't know and we're looking for this
the round 10 key let's say
byte zero so we know the input we can
guess
this is only 256 guesses here okay we
can guess this value
we know the input we go and zord we look
it up in the xbox inverse xbox
we come with an output we convert that
to hemming weight
and then we see if that hamming weight
with the hemingway we
we've actually got if they correlate
if they actually work um if so
plus one for this if not then you know
we ignore it
that's really neat and all but how do we
automate this
well in order to show you how we
automate this i first want to show you
what we're working on
uh to the left here is is basically our
power trace we grab a pointer
so this is our power trace of probably
about 50 power traces they're all
stacked on top of each other
but what you can make out is you make
out the 16 inverse substitution by
blocks here there's 16 of these little
pulses all along
if we start zooming in you'll start
seeing signals like this
we'll zoom in a little bit more and then
you'll end up with a signal like so
and uh you'll notice how there's these
like
striations i would say of of the power
being used
during a you know one of these
encryption process during the the output
to the inverse
s box function and the reason why i
zoomed on here is because this is
actually
a real world example of you know the
kind of
differential that you'll get there now
that's where the two
different types of side channel power
analysis goes is how to process this
change
we're working on the correlation method
so
there's really a thing called a pearson
correlation coefficient which will allow
us to
basically figure out what the value is
by you know how the data correlates with
each other
and luckily for us is the software will
do it for us
and uh at the end of the day all we're
going to be doing is we're going to be
throwing
you know this power trace into the
software we're going to say what kind of
linguist model we have
and it's going to help us come up with
you know the the the end up keys
i've talked a lot about correlation
without actually giving an explanation
of what it is
correlation is fairly simple it's
basically the relationship
it just says that an input has a
relationship to the output
so if we put a number into this system
if it correlates that means the input
has some kind of relationship to its
output so if we have a correlation of 0
that means the input has no correlation
to the output it has no relationship to
the output
so basically it has you know that number
has nothing to do with the the output uh
as we go in correlation
all the way up to one or negative one uh
today we'll just be taking the absolute
value so it's basically going to go from
zero to one
as we grow in correlation you can see
how
our you know blob of data or you know
becomes our scatter plot here just
becomes more and more like a line
obviously in a real world system we're
never going to have a
pure core well in a real world power
side channel analysis attack
we're not going to have a pure one
correlation it's always going to be
you know there's something else that's
going to happen there's going to be a
bad
sample so we're going to get a
correlation of like you know 0.6 or
something like that which is pretty good
but what ends up happening is you'll
have all the other numbers
having a correlation of let's say 0.2
okay so you have one number that has a
very high correlation
and all the rest of the numbers have a
very low correlation and that's going to
allow us to figure out what our
original key is
so the nice thing is that we have tools
that
are going to be able to process all of
our power traces for us
so this is what it's going to look like
we're going to put our power trace into
this tool we're going to start running
it
and we're going to tell it what kind of
leakage model we want
and pretty much you're going to start
seeing these number pop up now this
happened really quick on
on this particular the part where we're
able to do
very minor amounts of or small amounts
of you know traces and gleam out
eventually what this key is going to be
so you'll see here like we have on byte
zero
we have a key of ea and with the high
this is the uh correlation coefficient
here this point six six two
it's getting nearing one and the next
closest one is
this point three nine four uh you'll
notice that this .394.39
these are all very similar um which
means that this one is to a high degree
of certainty
most likely our byte zero key and if we
go down this row it's going to be like
the same for all of them where
for a high degree of certainty this is
our key
so believe it or not here with in 150
traces
we were able to figure out um the key
from this leakage model which would be
ea 7979
20 blah blah blah and this is the key
the round tense key
you may be asking yourself like how many
like it sounds like a ton of data that
i'm processing through and it is
but luckily our computers are fast so
let's say that we're going to take a
power sample or the power trace that we
just saw
each power trace let's say has 5 000
points in time
now and each point we're going to have
to make 256 guesses
and then we're going to be doing the 16
bytes in aes 128
let's say we are doing like that last
one was only 200 samples but let's
bring it up to like 5 000 samples so if
we do the math there
we're only ending up with one 102
billion
uh basically mathematical competitions
we're going to have to do
in my laptop that took like no time at
all like less than 20 minutes i think
for cracking the
the gopro once i figured out what you
know the process and did all this stuff
going out and that's definitely a lot
smaller than this to the 128th
so yeah we found around 10 keys this is
awesome
and like i said uh two seconds ago it's
invertible so we we found around 10 keys
we're going to invert that to
round zeroes keys from there we're going
to take the update
and we're going to decrypt that from
there i'm going to reverse engineer the
firmware
patch it to allow myself to read out the
the software
read out the tpm keys and
i don't know and hopefully profit yay
wow nice theory bro how how are we going
to implement this
and so that's what i'm going to talk
about next i'm going to talk about the
tools that i used
uh how we input our own data into the
system how do we capture the power trace
what tools we use for that how fast we
need to capture it
and then how do we synchronize it so all
these buckets are in the same spot
and then of course how do we process
this information
once we capture it so if you're planning
on doing any type of side channel attack
you really need to get one of these uh
chip whisperers
the top one here is i think about 60
bucks the bottom one's 260 bucks
and it basically comes with this whole
ecosystem on how to learn
side channel attacks and how to perform
them on your own this is the platform
the one on the bottom the chip whisperer
light
is the platform i use to carry out this
attack on the gopro
it's basically 105 million samples per
second oscilloscope has triggers
it has a clock generator you could throw
in as the input clock into your target
and a serial port as well as a way of
doing some voltage
glitching attacks it's amazing ecosystem
and also it has like
you know all these tutorials on various
attacks uh colin often he i think he did
his phd
using this tool and then ended up
selling it and now he does all these
these training things so if you're
you're in interested in getting trained
up on this uh he has a bunch of courses
and stuff like that
and i highly recommend it i i'm not
sponsored by them but they did send me a
care package after my talk
because i think they were a little bit
taken back by the little board that i
made by the target so you ended up
sending me one of these uh ufo boards
which i'm
definitely very appreciative of so that
again this is the tool that i'm going to
be using for all this and the ecosystem
that i'm going to be using to run this
exploit
knowing the eye system since we're going
to be doing a power analysis side
channel attack
we now need to figure out how to push
data into this
the part so it it will decrypt it or
attempt to decrypt this data
so in the case the gopro what i ended up
doing was i ended up sniffing the
i square c protocol to during the update
i found that it was requiring 144 bytes
at per time
there was a flag at the start that
basically reset the whole process which
helped me out a lot
and this is all done during the
reconstant stage i then found out that
it would be easier
to basically hack this part if i took
the part out of the gopro system itself
there was a lot of other stuff going on
in that system a lot of switch mode
power
supplies and stuff that would make my
life a little bit harder
so i found it's easier to to actually
just pull that part off
make my own circuit board and then
resolder it back onto it
this allowed me to recreate the protocol
and recreate basically make a fake
update process where i'm throwing at
these 144 bytes at a time
and was able to start the first
decryption process
which we would end up sniffing and
creating a power
trace from that from that process
we ended up building up a converter to
help us with the
basics glue logic between the chip
whisperer and our target
this knew the whole update process it
basically converted the 16 bytes the
chip whisperer was sending
us the 16 fake bytes it was sending us
to decrypt
and it and it put it into that whole
protocol that the gopro was
was wanting for an update
blob so basically it was uh asking for
144 bytes
we would expand it to from 16 bytes 144
bytes
add on the headers and send it to the
the gopro the target the victim to start
the
the update process and decrypt this data
what was really nice about this is it
allowed us also to put a
very well timed trigger and throw a
trigger out to our chip whisperer and to
our oscilloscope to capture the power
trace
so if your protocol is not necessary
expect if your
victim is not necessarily expecting
serial data
making a converter like this out of
arduino or whatnot is
something i would highly recommend doing
so how do we measure power
how do we create one of these power
traces well it's pretty easy over
we have a we look at the power that's
going to the system in this case it's
going to be 3.3 volts
and after the bulk cap or whatever
capacitors they have
out there the bypass capacitors we
cut the trace and we're going to add
what's called a shunt resistor to it in
this case it's 10 ohms
and after that we're going to add a
voltage probe this voltage probe and i'm
not going to bore you with the math
but it basically is going to allow us to
to measure the
voltage drop across that resistor and
from there we're going to be able to
figure out the current
and current and power we're going to be
using interchangeably here for
for this discussion so this voltage
probe here is more or less going to be
directly proportional to how much power
the system uses
the measurement here it's going to be
directly proportional to
the power that the the system is using
now if we want to do this over time
if we want for each timer each instance
each instance in t we want to measure
the
the power being used all we do is we use
an oscilloscope
and that will measure um you know at
every acquisition point it's going to
measure what that
that voltage drop is and and therefore
measure
basically the the power curve of the
system
let's see uh what ends up happening in
the real world though
in the real world these microcontrollers
now have a lot of inputs
a lot of power inputs they have i o
power inputs they have
ones for their analog they have you know
basically
a power input for each subsystem
specifically they admiral sam d21 had a
power
what's called a internal voltage
regulator for their
vdd core okay so in order to measure how
much
current or power the the core is using i
had to come up with a solution
and that's where what we did here is we
over drove that vd core to like 1.5
volts
and that shut it down effectively shut
it down and then it was
sourcing the power from this out
external
input now you may be asking yourself
self
you know that's way you know i'm gonna
blow it apart
yeah if it's like very hot out or you
know you're using this in a very
heated temperature you might you know
definitely stress the part but we're not
using it for very long at that
voltage range so it'll be fine so
anyways if i continue on
i i just did the same thing here we
ended up using a little bit bigger shot
resistor
okay and that allowed us to have a
little bit
higher gain of the uh the voltage drop
across it
and also because we wanted a very clean
signal we used what's called a
differential probe
which just basically does the math for
you the difference between the
the vultures on this side versus the
vultures on this side and that gave us a
very clean signal
for the power trace that we're requiring
to run this x point
okay so now we have the power trace uh
but one of the things we got to figure
out is how fast do we have to capture
this
power trace how fast do we have to
basically measure the currents we're
going to be measuring the current at a
certain beat
and we need to figure out what that
beats going to be
the chip whisperer is awesome and one of
the things it does is it
generally outputs a clock okay and what
you'll do is you'll feed that clock into
the system
into your your victim as its input clock
and what that allows us to do is allows
us to capture
right at the very point that the
instruction is getting
operated on are getting executed so that
makes it
this exploit so much easier because we
know exactly when that
instruction is going to be operated on
we can measure the current at that
at that point in time and we really
are it makes their lives so much easier
unfortunately for us
what our target had is what's called an
internal oscillator it had its clock
inside of itself
so there's ways that you could sniff
that internal clock from like
the emf radiation and recreate that
clock
or you could do what we did and we just
over sampled it so we over sampled it
past the 105 million samples per second
bandwidth that the chip whisperer had
and in order to do this
we ended up using
our trusty oscilloscope and we just
basically took the differential probe
dropped it right into our oscilloscope
had the chip whisperer go to its
triggers so trigger the oscilloscope
when it was capturing and you know
basically bypass the whole
oscilloscope portion of the chip resper
once the data was collected
in the oscilloscope we wrote a python
script on our computer to
basically suck in that power trace and
we sucked it right into like the chip
whisperer software
so all together now like man this is
you're talking a lot of hardware
but uh you know how does this all work
so
let's start with what's going on we have
the chip whisperer ecosystem running on
our computer
and this is running through python it's
a
juniper uh basic notebook that we're
running
this is talking to the chip whisperer
and sending it 16 bytes of data
this data goes over serial and then the
serial to i square c host is converting
this data
from you know 16 bytes to the basically
the protocol
that the victim is expecting for an
update
it's sending it to the victim and at the
same time it's sending a trigger
to my oscilloscope to start capturing
the uh the power trace okay once that
capture is completed it uploads it to
ethernet
and then this is my whole acquisition of
chain that was used to capture all these
you know thousands of thousands of power
traces in order to do
power analysis side gel attack
so you can see like kind of the whole
setup here's the chip whisperer
you know talking to the computer over
this is uh
you know basically from here it was
serial to my i square c to serial hills
i scored c over to my victim okay my
victim is getting the power is getting
sniffed basically or monitored through
my differential probe this is going to
the oscilloscope
uh which is getting triggered from here
and there the trigger line from my
square sees her serial host is going
there so that's the same line so
basically technically
color spaghetti at this point now that
we're capturing all these traces
how do we synchronize the traces amongst
one of one another
uh generally if you were you had an
external clock
you would make it really easy to to
synchronize that data and the chip
whisperer does a good job of
synchronizing that data for
for you since we have an internal clock
and we're over sampling
how do we make sure that all these power
traces are
on top of one another because at the end
of the day we basically need
that bucket to be in the same spot for
each power trace
well thankfully there's a solution well
the solution is math
and basically we're going to use a
filter called a sum of absolute
differences
and that's going to allow us to align
our traces if we look below here i have
basically
uh two well i have a portion of a bunch
of power traces
and i have two little distinctive like
waveforms here that happens on every
power trace
and what i would do is i'll end up going
and running this filter this add filter
on it and do a course alignment
and it brings it fairly close and then
i'll run it through one more time
and do another fine alignment you know
on this rising edge
so this will allow me to to get them you
know squared up
so that when i run it through the the
linkage model that it will
end up finding the keys for me
now we need to process all these power
traces and to do this we're using
something that's included in
chip whisperers ecosystem it's these
juniper notebooks
they basically have a bunch of tutorials
on how to implement
side channel attacks on your own the one
i used was i think a 256-bit
bootloader decryption method that he
came up with
and i just basically extracted out the
pieces i need
it's all python based so you can write
your own code and that allowed me to
basically interface to my victim or my
serial to i squared c converter that i
that i built and allow me to send
the random data and capture the traces
from my oscilloscope right into this
juniper notebook
at this time i'm basically going to be
saving these traces
with the data that i sent the victim
okay so now i have a
basically a plot a bunch of numbers of
of what the power is at a certain time
and i have the keys that the the fake
encrypted data
that i sent to the target and this will
this is something that i'll you know
will end up processing uh after i have
that that chunker the blob of data for
you know each power trace i'm going to
align all the power traces with the
sad filter like i said uh in the last
slide
and then i'm going to basically send it
into this inverse sbox leakage model
and have it process all this data from
there we're going to be
extracting the round tens keys
if you're going to attack a target like
this like let's say the sam d21 or any
other target that's
you know you have my controller that you
you know obviously you're trying to
extract the keys
is to create a mock-up we know what kind
of uh
encryption algorithm they're they're
most likely using we know
what the isrc protocol the protocol they
are using to talk to it
we'll figure out stuff like that they're
using internal clocks
and we're able to basically remake the
system
okay we know everything but the keys at
this point so
i would write some code program it on
the part and then
try to adjust my do power traces on it
just like attack this part
[Music]
and maximize or optimize your your power
trace
optimize you know how many points i need
to find
my voltage levels like everything all
the inputs of the systems like
my resistance their value how fast i
need to capture data
how many points i need to capture and
really learn
how this target reacts
and that was invaluable with for me to
end up extracting the
the key i spent more time i think on
this and getting this all cleaned up and
right and then once i just popped the
chip in
it was very easy to extract the actual
key itself
so i highly recommend this when we're
running these attacks there's some times
when
we don't can't extract a key for for
whatever reason like the
the certain key bite won't be
extractable
well luckily that now only becomes uh
you know 256 problems i have to solve
right uh that byte is only 256
uh possible numbers that it could be
and we just brute force that we just pop
the number into the round
10 key work our way backwards to find
around zero key
uh throw in the gopros update decrypt it
and then throw it in an entropy kind of
uh post processor
to see how the data looks if the data
has
you know a very high low entropy we know
we just decrypted it
the other thing i haven't really
mentioned throughout all this is the uh
the chaining mode and for decryption it
really doesn't matter
um i mean of course it matters but to
actually figure out the key
it doesn't really matter if we look at
the bottom right hand corner here we
have
you know obviously our our encrypted
data
we're going to go through our box cipher
with the key and then once that comes
out the first 16 bytes
at that point we zore in the
initialization
vector so the id for decryption only
matters for the first 16 bytes
and if you know luckily we had the iv of
zero so it didn't really
affect us too it was very easy we didn't
really have to do anything
but if you have an iv of anything else
you can go ahead and do a little bit of
side channel attack there
and there's a ways around that and for
most of these
you know let's say for the cortex or any
of these parts a lot of times it's just
a interrupt table
and we could figure that out on our own
so it's not as bad as it sounds that
initialization vector
and uh pretty easy to circumvent
honestly i could have done a lot of
things better during my attack
uh one thing that i didn't really care
for was how small i made the
the the target board the victim board is
you know very small like
yeah big uh i should have used
you know one of the new aes ufo boards
or at least made it bigger
i i get so used to making everything so
small i use
the smallest disaster values i have all
four twos
and uh that really made it a lot harder
to to
to run this attack so definitely make it
bigger
um emf i would have done this a lot
faster
and that's kind of like the way of the
future i think a lot of people are not
doing uh
power analysis side channel attacks as
much anymore because these emf eyes
or even laser tags are really powerful
and really quick
again start small make your mock-up uh
learn all the samples on the the new ae
juniper
chip whisper you know ecosystem like run
through all that stuff so you really
understand it and like i said you know
create your own mock-up there
and obviously like any of the stuff you
just need to do it you just need to run
with it and
try it out yourself and see how it works
at the other day just make sure that
you're not going down a rabbit hole
that's pretty much what this whole thing
was
i mean i'm grateful that i spent the
time to learn how to do a side channel
attack
on a target such like this but at the
end of the day i really didn't need to
do it
i mean i spent a lot of times figuring
out how to do it but
you know make sure you're not going down
a rabbit hole with this kind of stuff
make sure that there's not easy ways of
doing it
or you know ways to circumvent that
because it's very easy to get to go down
that with a side channel attacks
where to go to the next if you're really
interested in doing your own side
channel attack
i would highly recommend these uh these
videos or
articles i have a really good article on
my website
uh under my blogs on you know
this whole attack goes a little bit more
into detail
if you're a little confused about aes
still and want to learn a little bit
more this computer file
video did a great job of of explaining
it
and of course for side channel attacks i
would definitely just check out nuai
they have some really good resources on
learning how to do side channel attacks
and this video in particular was
instrumental in teaching me
how side channel attacks work and what's
the premise behind it
so highly recommend that well thank you
for sitting through my talk
i i hope you learned a little bit if you
want to get in contact with me uh
feel free to follow me on twitter it's
at get hypoxic
uh on instagram i have a bunch of my
photographs and some video
that's at get hypoxic also and
likewise if you want to read some of my
blogs feel free to
check out gethypoxide.com where i have
all my technical blogs and whatnots
well thank you again and if you're
listening to this live i will be
answering questions on discord in a
little bit
bye now
you