russ heir from the reg team
our next talk today comes from senior
consultant and researcher
speaker and blogger gavin klondike
gavin's talk is titled hacking with
skynet
how ai is empowering adversaries
at the end of the talk a link will be
displayed so that you can join in
on a live q a session with gavin all you
need to do is
click the link and you'll be taken over
to the live q a channel
so without further delay gavin over to
you
hello cactus con and welcome to hacking
with skynet
how ai is empowering adversaries
now before we get started i want to
share with you something that
may be a little scary but really hits on
what we're going to be talking about
today
late last november there was a top
iranian nuclear scientist that was
assassinated
by what some have called an ai powered
gun now there's conflicting reports as
to what exactly happened
but this isn't too far outside the realm
of possibility
there's already tutorials online on how
to create an autonomous century turret
and that uses lidar for object detection
but what if we add a little bit more
brains into the mix
what if we added in some facial
recognition or
deep learning object detection tracking
like
yolo or you only look once now we're
starting to get somewhere
anyways that's your bottom line up front
what we're going to be talking about
today and why this presentation is
called
hacking with skynet my name is gavin
i am known online as gt klondike i am a
security researcher
and ai village officer and a senior
security consultant
i also run a passion project called
netsec explain where i explain
advanced level computer and network
security topics in an easy to understand
way
so for the uninitiated uh you've
probably heard machine learning
artificial intelligence and deep
learning used interchangeably
but there's a difference and we'll go
over that
so artificial intelligence is a big
umbrella term
that covers not only machine learning
but other types of artificial
intelligence like
rule-based artificial intelligence and
traditional
or classical object recognition
underneath that umbrella we have machine
learning
now machine learning uses statistics and
data to come
to inferences or decisions based on the
data
so the algorithms will stay the same but
the data is what
allows the machine to make the decisions
that it's making
and then as a subset of machine learning
we have deep learning
this is where we have deep neural
networks
so think of this presentation as being
really to
smaller talks so in the first section
we're going to be talking about
offensive ai tools what's out there
what's possible and what exists today
and then in the second part we're going
to talk about adversarial machine
learning this is
hacking or attacking machine learning
algorithms and machine learning based
software so why is that important
well there's no question we've already
seen the effects of machine learning in
the security industry
we see how it can help us with log
detection anomaly detection
and sifting through massive amounts of
data
it's very valuable but there's another
side to this coin
how is this allowing attackers to
improve their own capabilities
so let's jump into it by talking about
offensive ai tools
so why do we even want offensive ai
tools well
what this is going to allow us to do is
explore the target attack surface
very quickly especially in today's day
and age where we have a lot of iot
devices we have
billions with a b lines of code on
millions of devices
stamped into a chip and sent across the
world
i can't even wrap my head around the
idea of billions of lines of code
let alone the potential vulnerabilities
that could be associated with that
so how can we operate at a speed and
scale
that will allow us to handle this with
our current workforce
and that's exactly what offensive tools
will allow us to do it'll allow us to
automate some of the penetration testing
and vulnerability assessments
but it also allows adversaries the bad
guys
to attack us in many different and
unthought of ways
so this is going to allow us to move at
a speed and scale
that we have not been able to do before
and it's going to allow us to
automate our manual analysis plus the
added caveat
where we're going to be able to uncover
some hidden blind spots in our defensive
tools and software
and so can they so how realistic is this
well in 2016 darpa initiated the cyber
grand
challenge where it pitted teams of
researchers against each other
in a fully ai or autonomous
capture the flag challenge so as part of
this challenge
the ai or the automated applications and
systems that they built
had to perform its own vulnerability
discovery exploitation
post exploitation or patching and
data theft it would then take the
exploits that it found in its own
systems and launch them against other
systems
automatically everything was air-gapped
and the only people the only humans
on that side of the fence were the
referees
so it was absolutely crazy and if you
haven't i
highly recommend that you check it out
because some of the results
were insane for example one of the
researchers or one of the
the ai units actually found
vulnerabilities in a challenge that the
author
didn't initially intend to have in there
but another one identified
and patched that same vulnerability so
this really gave us a glimpse on the
world stage of
what ai can do and how it can be applied
into the security
sphere
so some applications of offensive ai
unfortunately i'm not going to be able
to get into all of them
but i'm going to be doing a whirlwind
tour to kind of show you what's out
there
and what advancements are being made
today so
right now applications of offensive ai
we have social engineering
we already know that we can use ai to
perform
defensive detection but what if we're a
malware researcher or a malware engineer
and we want to identify whether or not
something is in a sandbox
so how can we find ways to bypass
intrusion detection systems
and even antivirus systems and evade
those or shut down
if we detect that we're located on one
of them
we can use or adversaries can use
artificial intelligence in order to
evaluate data leaks so
massive password dumps or credential
dumps in order to see who's connected to
what
and how things are related uh automated
network exploitation both internal
network exploitation and
external network exploitation and then
automated software exploitation
so this will take fuzzing to a whole new
level develop
new and interesting exploits and proof
of concepts
so let's start off talking about
social engineering and applications for
that so the first one i want to bring up
is stylegan stylegan is a project by
nvidia and what it allows
us to do is create ai generated
human faces that look realistic
so how do we apply this to social
engineering social engineering
uh usually what you'll have is a persona
and so this will be for the social
engineering contest
and this will be for red teams you'll
develop a persona somebody that seems
plausible
usually this comes with a name and a
face
traditionally what people would do is
they'll go to the 10th page of google or
they'll look up a stock photo
grab that and post that as a profile
picture
and so i as a 32 year old male can
impersonate
becky a 20-something female who's
looking at getting started in the
industry
and then i can perform my social
engineering tasks from there i can send
emails to everybody in hr accounting
sales
whatever in order to gather more
information
from a company but a clever security
researcher
or network defender will be able to see
that image
if it doesn't pass the sniff test
they'll grab it reverse image search
and they'll find that exact same person
as i don't know
catherine in new york new york as
a image that i had stolen so
things are going to match up and
immediately flagged as
false but why steal somebody's identity
when i can create a whole new identity
style again will let me generate a
profile picture and there's other tools
out there that'll let me generate social
media content
long form blog posts and even my own
voice
now before i show you the voice part i
kind of want to show you uh
some interesting things about the way
that stylegan is generated and some
things that you can use
to identify and see if somebody has
already done this
so if you notice that all of the images
they're all looking straight
uh another thing that you might notice
and this isn't true for all images but
you'll see artifacts happening in the
background the background is really
blurry but if you see things that are
supposed to be vertical or in a straight
line like
trees or fence posts you can kind of see
some distortion or artifacts
an easier way to demonstrate this is
with ai-generated cats
so all the images here are also
generated by stylegan
of cat pictures and you can see the
level of detail that they have in the
fur and the whiskers
but artifacts do happen their paws
aren't rendered properly
and you can even see some weird like wtf
stuff
going on over here
so let's talk about voice what if it's
not enough for me to
communicate over chat and somebody wants
to actually conduct an interview
or get on the phone with me how can i
impersonate
becky well i can use a friend of mine
or i can use a synthetic voice that will
be able to
put in the right suggestions that i need
in order to
ask the questions of part of my social
engineering campaign
and get those trophies so i'm going to
show you a couple
voice clips from lyra bird and tacotron
lyrebird
is a a real organization
and it's pitched as a reverse
transcription service
so you type in whatever it is you want
to say and then you send it off to
lyrebird
and they will give you a human
synthesized voice saying those things
and then tacotron is a google project
google project
that does a similar thing so let's go
ahead
check out the original voice and these
first two are from lyrebird
in another moment down went alice after
it never once did she consider how in
the world she was to get out again
awesome and so the synthetic voice based
off of
that sample image or that sample clip
oops my voice might be generated by a
computer
but i think it sounds pretty human i
don't know exactly how they made it but
i'm really impressed
very nice so
what we can do is type up a script or
type up a series of scripts
and will react to question answer
segments
and then use that for social engineering
but you notice that it sounds a little
synthetic or it just sounds a little off
you can explain that away as saying uh
it's just part of a bad connection or
i'm using wi-fi calling or something of
that nature
so the last one that i want to show you
here is tacotron and there's been a lot
of advancements since i originally
pulled this audio clip but this one what
i want you to do is while you're
listening to it
listen to the breaths and species
normally in human speech we'll have
where there's a comma or a period
a breath or a space something that kind
of fills in that gap
another thing and this isn't part of
this research is they'll introduce
filler words like um and uh so and and
so anyways take a listen to this clip
listen for the breaths
only the photograph really showed how
much time had passed 10 years ago
there had been lots of pictures of what
looked like a large pink beach ball
wearing different colored bonnets
but dudley dursley was no longer a baby
and now the photograph showed a large
blonde boy riding his first bicycle
on a carousel at the fair playing a
computer game with his father being
hugged and kissed by his mother
by his mother
[Music]
and these are technologies that are
advancing all the time
so soon we might have to keep an eye out
for
synthetically generated voice that is
trying to social engineer
our organizations or us as individuals
so let's move on next we have sandbox
detection
so for malware if you're a malware
engineer
what you want to do is try and avoid
sandbox detection
as long as possible the reason is
because
antivirus companies such as norton
kaspersky mcafee what have you
they try and grab malware samples or
potential malware samples they throw
them
in a special environment and then they
just
let them run and see what they do so as
a malware engineer
i want my malware to go undetected for
as long as possible
which means that i need to find a way to
get past
this sandbox or this this phase of
analysis that they perform
so i'm going to perform sandbox
detection and implement that into my
alpha
into my malware so the way that sandbox
detection some of the researchers over
at silent break security
what they did was they identified what
is something
that will identify or what what are some
uh processes
that we'll see inside of a legitimate
operating system that is being used by a
user
and processes that are just in there by
default on
some of the well-known sandboxes like
fireeye and cuckoo
what they were able to do is use process
lists user count
and other types of information on the
host operating system
as data points and they said based on
those data points that we've identified
we're going to set a threshold and based
on that threshold we're going to
determine whether or not we're in a
sandbox or
on a legitimate user a legitimate user
system
if we're on a legitimate user system go
ahead execute no problem
if we have identified that we're on a
sandbox then shut down delete itself
and it can't be analyzed so for this
uh every ai or machine learning
algorithm
you need to set a threshold so it gives
you a certain confidence level based on
the data points that you give and then
you set a certain threshold
so in this case we have hosts a c and f
that were determined to be part of a
sandbox and that's because they didn't
reach this threshold of 168
which is the host average score so if
you didn't reach the host average score
then i'm going to consider you a sandbox
and just shut down
so the next part that i want to talk
about is automatic
network exploitation and these are some
tools that were released a couple years
ago that are still being updated today
uh deep exploit and goython they work
very similar but they automate the
network intro
uh the network penetration testing
process
so where they'll start is they'll begin
with an nmap scan
or a series of analyzers so maybe a nesa
scan or openvas or something of that
nature
and then they'll follow it up with
identifying certain ports
so if port 80 is open or 443 then we're
going to perform web crawling using
scrappy
based on the information that we pulled
from the nmap scan
nessus and scrappy we're going to be
able to identify and enumerate the type
of service
that's running on the system so are they
running apache
nginx are they running jboss
are they running jenkins things like
that
then they're going to port it over to
metasploit and see what existing
metasploit modules there are and
try and kick off the types of metasploit
modules that'll target that specific
type of system
they'll run through the gamut see what
connects back and then they'll be able
to print out a nice report
that will tell you what was exploitable
what was found
and what was actually exploited
my favorite one in the network intrusion
or the network penetration testing
section
is this application called death star
now death star is one of my favorites
just because of the way that it works
it seems like it's just a bunch of if
statements but it's a lot more
complicated than that
so here we start off saying uh going
from a regular
domain user account to try and escalate
up to domain admin
and we already see attack graphs like
this kind of being generated by tools
like bloodhound
but this one's a little unique so it
starts off in a start state and says
okay do i already have domain admin
credentials or do i already have
a domain admin user it goes down one
track if we have the user it goes down
another track if we have the user
and the credentials and then it ends uh
if not then we're just going to go ahead
and start the next loop
and we go down this middle spine column
if you will so it says okay let's spawn
a new agent
now do we know where the domain
controllers are yes all right let's
enumerate the domain controllers
so we're going to use get net domain
controller
get net group member invoke user hunter
and try and identify all the paths that
we can to get to a
domain admin now
i should have said this earlier but this
is built on powershell empire
3 and so some of these things may work
may not work i know powershell empire
kind of has some
criticisms against it but uh besides
that the idea
is still there eventually it'll go down
it'll find domain admin or it'll find a
new windows system and it'll say hey
let's enumerate the processes on the
system and then let's identify the
operating system
are we running windows 7 yeah let's run
mimikatz on it are we running windows 8
windows 10
let's try other exploitation techniques
and then if there's
other users on the system that we don't
already have in our list
let's add it to our list and try the
whole process again
so this is very cool and i'm excited to
see
where this will go but we might see
some adversaries or even apts
start to use this kind of automation in
some of their tools in order to traverse
through the network
secretly and quickly so be on the
lookout
anyways that's all i have for the
offensive ai tools portion but i don't
want to leave you empty-handed on here
if you want to develop your own
offensive ai tools
here's my recommendations first start
with a pipeline
so something that is repeatable and
automated
or wrote so for example you'll start
with an nmap scan
okay cool with an nmap scan what can we
do with this oh well i see port 80 or
let me go ahead and perform some
analysis on that
we saw with goythan and deep exploit
that they're using
scrappy and so we can also use gobuster
dirtbuster something of that nature and
then we can enumerate
all the different directories we can use
aquatone to grab screenshots
so now we have a lot of information
about this potential web application
we can continue further down our
analysis we can try identify a login
page
try and log in as a potential user or as
a
using a password list and
so this is the the way that you develop
the framework for building ai tools
you just take a process that you do
repeatedly build a pipeline out of it
and then turn that into data to be
passed on to the next process
and or the next pipeline
so the next thing that i want to talk
about is adversarial
machine learning adversarial machine
learning is actually
attacking the ai algorithms
and this is specifically machine
learning
so there are really four primary ways to
attack a machine learning model
first is to look at the model robustness
which isn't really attacking the model
itself so much as attacking the software
around the model
all of machine learning as advanced as
it may sound
it's just software and it's vulnerable
to the exact same software
vulnerabilities that we see day in
and day out uh the three others we have
model evasion so how can we develop some
sort of
adversarial example that'll bypass the
model so if the model has intrusion
detection or something of that nature
how can we actually use the intrusion
detection built into that model to
bypass it
and be considered benign model poisoning
is how do we actually influence the way
that the model
learns in order to build
new adversarial examples without being
detected or to just completely tear down
the model
and uh ruin it and then we have data
leakage so
maybe we have access to the model in
some way shape or form
and then we can ask it targeted
questions in order to leak data and
information
that the model was trained on so this
can be really dangerous
for top secret information or hipaa
information right phi data so if a model
is trained on phi data
and it's vulnerable to data leakage then
we
as adversaries can just extract that phi
data out of the model
it's very hard to do but definitely a
thing
so the first thing i want to talk about
is model robustness and
sometimes the software is just broken
if it's not a robust model it's not a
good model and that is true
absolutely true for machine learning
so a really good example would be
self-driving cars
self-driving cars you'll see all these
cool hacks that are happening
security researcher will find them
they'll submit them off to
toyota or jeep or whatever company and
then the company will come back and say
oh
that's not a security problem why not
what happened
like i was able to influence your
self-driving car
well this is where we talk about model
robustness uh
the model needs to be able to exist in
its environment
without having problems that's way
before we get to the security section
where the model can exist in its
environment but we
as adversaries can try and influence it
or attack it and make it to do something
that it wasn't expecting to do
so in this example actually one of my
favorite examples is
called the summoning circle attack where
somebody can just paint
what seem like road lines out of salt
onto
a road or concrete or asphalt
and uh as soon as a self-driving car
goes into it it gets stuck
because it knows that it's not legally
allowed to cross
that that intersection or that street
but it also can't back up it can't go
off to the side so it gets very confused
and has no idea what it's supposed to do
another example of failed model
robustness with
self-driving cars is a team of
researchers working on tesla
was actually able to get a tesla car to
switch lanes
into potentially oncoming traffic now
the reason why this isn't really a
security concern
is because what they were able to do is
just put little lidar stickers
on the asphalt and so they just did the
wiley coyote version of drawing
lane lines over into the oncoming
traffic so
not really a security concern more they
just need to work on their model
for their self-driving car let's move on
so this is where we start getting into
the actual adversarial approach
right so when you're going to attack or
when somebody is going to attack
a machine learning model you have either
a white box
or a black box the white box is fairly
self-explanatory
uh white box here we have the source
code or the data that the model was
originally trained on we have the way
that the model was created
and so we can just do a code review and
we can rebuild the model and we can
try and find little uh points in that
model
that are vulnerable the black box model
is a little bit more complicated instead
of
trying to attack it like a web
application from a black box perspective
what we try to do is ask the model a
series of questions right
millions and millions of questions so
that we can get as many data points as
we can to train our own
surrogate model now if you're familiar
with cryptography and some of the
the crypto games that are done there uh
we can use that surrogate model to act
as an
oracle where we can try and attack the
oracle
and whatever works on the oracle should
work on the original model
this is because of a phenomenon known as
attack transferability
the phenomenon that's been identified is
if
an attack works on one specific model
then it'll work
on many other types of models it doesn't
even have to be made with the same
algorithm or the same data
it's the same type it's the same type of
features
that really kind of messes with the
model
and we'll see why this is important a
little later on
so before we can begin attacking an ai
model
first or a machine learning model first
we need to understand what is a
realistic
attack surface now i'm sure that you've
seen
image of a panda you manipulate some
pixels
and then it identifies it as a bird
that's not really realistic because the
only way that you can
attack that panda image and modify the
pixels is if you have some sort of
physical access to the model itself
and at that point why modify pixels in a
really convoluted way when you can just
change them so it is a picture of a bird
it's a little weird so here's the
generic machine learning model and the
process that it goes through
and then as an example so that it makes
a lot more sense to
those who aren't familiar with machine
learning i have a network intrusion
detection system
built on machine learning to kind of
illustrate what different points
what means what at different points so
here we have a physical object which is
the observed event
so this could be a road sign this could
be an image of a road sign i should say
this should be
distance to an object in our network
intrusion detection system we have the
attack
traffic itself then what we're going to
do is digitize
that information and we're going to
transform it into something that the
model can use
so we're going to take that image we're
going to transform it into bytes or
we're going to take that attack traffic
and we're going to transform it into a
pcap using
tcp dump or t-sharp or something of that
nature
and then we can take that pull the
features out of it
and put it into our machine learning
model now
our machine learning model is kind of a
box in and of itself it takes input
features
and it provides an output so that output
is always going to be
some sort of score or some sort of scale
and so in this case we're going to have
our packet metadata
and then it's going to output our attack
probability what is the probability that
what we're looking at right now is a
network attack
and then at that point it goes on to the
rest of the software
that makes a decision it says okay if
you reach this threshold
anything above it is attack traffic
anything below it
is benign and that's just a binary
classifier a one or a two
there are many other types of
classifiers for example object detection
i know imagenet can detect i believe
it's 200 different types of images is it
a dog is it a cat is it a plane is it a
train
uh that's all based on this decision
piece so let's see how this works in
practice
first we're going to talk about model
evasion in model evasion uh
or i should explain this diagram first
we have a massive amount of theoretical
space this is all the
possible objects in the world but we
can't
look at all the possible objects in the
world so what we do is we collect as
much data as we can
and this is our training and testing
data
so we have all the data that we have
it's clean it's labeled
it's clear and so we split it up usually
it's 80 20 or
70 30 where the model is trained on
80 or 70 of the data and then it's
tested on
that 20 or 30 that's left over so the
reason we do this
is the same reason uh the same way
actually that we teach students in
elementary school right we teach them as
much as we can
on different mathematical principles and
we use many different examples of what
math looks like
and then we test them to see if they
actually understand what's going on
so here's where we get into our
adversarial space adversarial space is
where we as attackers
are actually able to try and hide and
blend in
so this is outside of their training and
testing data but we need to have some
sort of knowledge of what they used
in order to perform some sort of
malicious action
so for model evasion our adversarial
space is also kind of
technically part of our testing space
where
we try to hide in the blind spots so we
try and make the things that it's
looking at
as benign but the things that it's not
as uh malicious that'll get through
so a perfect example of this would be a
naive bayesian
spam filter and if you want more
information on how
a spam filter like this works or how the
machine learning process
works take a look at my workshop that's
going on later today
so how do we defeat a naive bayesian
spam filter just any
uh regular machine learning spam filter
well here we have an email that it flags
on certain keywords so the probability
of a regular email having the word
viagra is pretty low but the probability
that a spam email has viagra is pretty
high
and so it looks at all the words it
scores all those words and says okay
here's a bundle
of potentially bad words here's a bundle
of potentially good words
if we add them all together then we can
see where we fit
on this little scale so in this case
here's an email
that the spam filter is 99 sure
is spam so it throws it out how can we
evade it
well one clever way of doing this is
looking at the way that emails are
constructed
emails are typically html files
now a typical spam filter or a
regular spam filter and this is exactly
what they used to use back in the day
only looks at the keywords it can't
determine whether or not it's a word
that's being shown to the user
so what we can do is go to wikipedia
grab
the entire article for a horse and
put that in as a html comment
so to the user's perspective it doesn't
see any difference in the spam email or
in the regular
email but from a machine learning
perspective it takes
all of the words from that wikipedia
article into account
and it says hey you have a lot more good
boy points than bad boy points
you get to go right on through so that's
an example of model evasion in action
let's see what more we can do with it
so the researchers over at skylight
saber actually did something very
similar
with the silent antivirus and this
wonderful article i highly recommend
checking out called
silent i kill you where what they were
able to do is
identify different features that
the the the silence antivirus was able
to look
at and perform on they did a little bit
of reverse engineering and they found
that there are certain uh applications
that are white listed inside of silence
so in this case they looked at online
video games
so online video games they found certain
things were whitelisted
so they just grabbed as many as they
could and
put those into their antivirus or into
their malware samples
so here we can see the score before
making the change
and the scores after making the change
so
the one that uh the one that entertains
me the most is actually the zeus
malware where it is at negative 997
one of the worst malware that it was
able to identify
and then after padding it with a whole
bunch of good boy points
it now became 997 positive which is one
of the best
examples that cy lance was able to
identify
so now that they're actually able to
disclose
what what game it was it actually turns
out it was rocket league
so they took words or features sets
from rocket league and put them into
their malware samples
but they also tried other games like
fortnite league of legends
so how do we prevent model evasion well
there's a few different ways
what we can do is actually perform
adversarial training
so the idea is that we know we're going
to come across
people who are going to try and
manipulate our model
so what if we put those kinds of
manipulations in our training set
so that we can identify them this kind
of runs on the same principle
as what is called chaos engineering or
engineering chaos
which is hey we know that we have a
network our server is going to go down
at some point where something's going to
happen hard drive is going to die
power's going to go out how do we
account for that
so engineering chaos what they'll do is
they'll have
a cso or somebody of that nature walk
into the data center and just start
unplugging servers
right we know that there's a data we
know that there's going to be an outage
at some point
how do we handle that how do we protect
against it so if you go in start
unplugging servers then what you're
going to do is start to develop
processes and policies
around those potential out those
potential outages
so it's not a matter of if it's a matter
of when and
you know what types of things are going
to happen
so you begin to train your model on
adversarial examples or you begin to
train your data center or your processes
on malicious insider or power outages
and
other unexpected things another way to
prevent model evasion is what's called
defensive
distillation so defensive distillation
is just really a fancy term
of smoothing a curve
so in this case instead of
the model looking at the email right the
email example that we had
instead of looking at the email and
saying okay there's a bunch of bad point
points bad boy points
oh here's a bunch of good boy points and
it goes straight down what it does is it
smooths the curve so it can't do
a radical change so that
isn't entirely foolproof but it
definitely helps make the model a lot
more resilient
against adversarial examples and then
the last one
is called uh monotonic classification
monotonic
also another fancy term for the graph
only grows in one direction
so in this case we see a non-monotonic
example
where it'll dip down below the decision
boundary it'll dip back up as soon as it
sees
all of the the words in the article for
a horse
and then in the monotonic example we see
that it only goes in one direction
it starts accumulating bad boy points
and once it hits a certain threshold
it doesn't matter what you do jesus
won't save you you're bad
so those are some evasion defenses
next we have model poisoning this is
where
an adversary is actually able to
influence the model itself
now this is really unique because it
almost exclusively
works on what are called online learners
machine learning models stop learning as
soon as they're done being trained
to work on that engineers have developed
online models where they will classify
images or data points objects data
objects
uh as benign malicious or whatever
different classes they have and then
they'll use the data
from the stuff that it had classified to
retrain
itself so a really good example of this
would be
network intrusion detection where it
needs to learn how your network operates
what is baseline what is stuff that's
normally seen so for example in company
a
telnet might be something normal it's
probably something the security team
doesn't like
and they want to get rid of but for the
time being it's normal
but in company b telnet traffic is
immediately a red flag
because it's all clear text so for an
online learner
what we want to do is add adversarial
examples into the adversarial space and
then move that information
into the training space so the model is
slowly moving the line
to what is acceptable
so a couple examples of model poisoning
would be
the microsoft tay ai tai if you're not
familiar
was a microsoft twitter chat bot and i
use
was because people over at 4chan
decided that they wanted to try and take
it down
tai was pitched as a twitter bot that
will learn from conversations that it
has with people
and it becomes more intelligent over
time so the people over at 4chan we're
trying to decide
what's the worst that we can do
it took only about 16 hours before
microsoft permanently shut it down
which is terrifying because imagine how
many engineers how many
uh software developers were behind this
in order to develop the system
that is now just permanently shut down
so the way they were able to do that was
just uh treat it
with some conversation pieces and it
would learn over time
what was acceptable and what was not so
it only took about 16 hours before it
started saying things like
hitler did nothing wrong or
other racial slurs another form
is a jacobian map saliency attack or
jmsa and this is where we kind of modify
certain pixels so it's very technical
and academic and not something that i
would really consider realistic
uh in a real world setting but
definitely something to be aware of
so in this example we have a seven eight
kilometer per hour sign
change some pixels and then it drops
down to 30 kilometers per hour
so we may be able to influence a
self-driving car
by being able to change some of this
stuff
but remember what i said it's almost
exclusively
for online learners and self-driving
cars don't really do
online learning that much so just some
examples to be aware of
so how do we prevent model poisoning
well
there's a few different ways we can
train the model
for uh longer periods of time or have
longer periods of time between the
trainings
so what that'll do is allow the model to
accumulate a lot more examples
that it can be used to train the next
version of that model
so it makes it a lot harder for the
adversaries to influence enough of the
data
for it to be statistically significant
another way that we can do is analyzing
longer periods of data
it's kind of the same thing and then we
can just minimize the impact of
adversarial training examples
by incorporating our own adversarial
training examples or
limiting what the adversaries are able
to get through or
what data points that the model
collected
how many of those actually go into
retraining the model
so the last one we have here is data
leakage
data leakage i mentioned earlier can be
really devastating if you're creating a
top secret model or if you're
creating a model that is built on
personal health care data or phi or
hipaa compliant data
also privacy especially if you're
concerned with gdpr
so the idea here is models being trained
if they are what's called overfit will
store some of the information or it'll
memorize some of the information
so in this example the headlines were
saying oh my god this google ai
it memorized the test and so it was able
to cheat
that's not really true this is a really
well known phenomenon called overfitting
overfitting is just the ai model
memorizes certain things instead of uh
generalizing so if two plus two is two
or
if two plus two is four every single
time and then you say okay well what's
one
eight plus five it'll say four because
it only memorized
certain answers it's a really poorly
performing model and part of a whole
other problem
but overfit models do go into production
sometimes
so usually we'll see this when models
are too good to be true
because it memorized the answers that it
needs to memorize
which means that it will usually perform
really badly when it's given a question
that it hasn't seen before
it could leak private or proprietary
data and then it could also allow
model theft by competitors as i was
saying with the
black box testing paradigm where you
take a model
you ask it a series of questions and
then you create your own surrogate model
it's not technically stealing but
it's a nearly identical model and so
that's stolen proprietary data
so one more thing i want to leave you
with is a
conversation around adversarial stickers
so adversarial stickers they look like
melted crayons in my opinion but they
were all the rage especially when
uh some of this research first came out
where uh headlines really grabbed on to
the idea of putting adversarial stickers
next to things
maybe you can put something on a stop
sign and it looks like a
guild sign or a crosswalk or a speed up
to 100 miles an hour sign
that's not really the case so
adversarial stickers
they look cool but they suffer from a
very
critical problem and that problem is
attack transferability
they're not transferable so if you had
two models that operated
nearly identically right so in this case
we have
an image classifier that can identify
bananas and other images
you can have one model that you create
an adversarial sticker for
put it next to a banana it thinks it's a
toaster the other model if you use that
same adversarial sticker
it may not trap it may not pick it up it
may not consider that a toaster it may
still consider it a banana with a really
weird thing next to it
so adversarial stickers they look cool
but
not realistic in a lot of ways
if you want more information on this i
highly recommend checking out the defcon
2018 talk by sven it's 30 minutes he
talks about adversarial stickers and the
problems with them
then i also recommend defcon 2019 by
rich haring
talking about defeating facial
recognition algorithms
so both of them kind of talk about this
attack transferability problem
and why even though it looks cool it's
not realistic
so to recap how has ai empower
adversaries or how will advancements in
ai empower adversaries
well it's going to let them operate at
the same speed and scale as machines
so now we're going to have ai defense
tools against ai attack tools
at some point in the near future and
this is also the very beginning of what
ai can bring
so you remember back to the 80s and 90s
where
anti-virus systems intrusion detections
they were all
basic scripts or very large but still
basic scripts
and now they've both turned into
multi-billion dollar industries
so i see ai and security being able to
do the same thing
for both the attackers and the defenders
and i think that we're on the very edge
of where this transition will start
we're also already starting to see some
of these adversarial attacks against
real world models
for example the self-driving cars that i
showed earlier
those are real world models that
researchers were able to
get to kind of trap themselves
the adversarial sticker that is a real
model but it's not something that can
work in the real world against other
models
because of attack transferability we saw
silence how silence could be bypassed
we saw how spam filters could be
bypassed so a lot of this is what we're
starting to see with researchers
and some of these are what we're
starting to see in the wild
anyways that's all i have for you guys
today if you
didn't have a chance to ask questions in
the discord server here's my contact
information
if you think of something later on go
ahead reach out to me
and of course check out my youtube video
net tech explained
and my slides are up on slideshare.net
so the slides unfortunately i wasn't
able to cover everything
but of the things that i wasn't able to
cover i have up there on the slides and
of course you can reach out to me and we
can talk about them
anyways thank you for your time and
attention and have a good day
you