well hello again cactus con
ryan with the cactus con crew here with
you once again
and i have the distinguished honor from
playing the mc to cactus con 9
of introducing our keynote speakers
we're about to introduce our keynote
speaker for day one but first
we're going to hear from some of our
partner level sponsors
please note that without our sponsors
this conference simply just
would not be possible so let's all take
a listen and see what they have to say
[Music]
hi this is pat flynn head of recruiting
with bishop fox
we're proud to sponsor this year's
cactus gun and hope you're enjoying the
presentations
even though this year's experience is
different it's still one of the best
cactus con conferences we've ever had
enjoy the rest of your day and we look
forward to meeting you in our discord
channel
all right and we are back
it pleasures me to be able to introduce
to you
our keynote speaker for day one of
cactus con 9
eva galbrain eva has worked with the
electronic frontier foundation or eff
since 2007. during her tenure with the
eff
eva has focused primarily on protecting
helping to protect the privacy and the
security
of those in underserved populations
those who simply
normally wouldn't realize they can be
afforded those protections
her work in this realm is more than
commendable and we
are very excited to have her with us
today enough of me it's time to listen
to eva
and see what she has to say to us so
we move now to eva's keynote speech
entitled
how to build a threat lab
hi there my name is eva galperin and i
am the director of cyber security at the
electronic frontier foundation
i am here to talk to you a little bit
about how to build a snowman
i mean a threat lab uh welcome everybody
to cactus con the play along at home
edition
uh as you can see we are currently at
the eff
office slash my apartment and
out of deference to to tradition i am
wearing a gown but because these are
quarantine times
i am also wearing fuzzy slippers so
uh enough about my sartorial choices
let's uh let's talk fat labs
so usually around this time i ask
everybody to raise their hand if they
know
what eff is and in this case
that will not be happening so i'm just
going to assume that some people raise
their hands that some people aren't
entirely sure what eff is
that some people assume that we are a
t-shirt and sticker company
especially if you have been to a
conference where eff has a heavy
presence and
everybody is wearing eff t-shirts and no
one will explain to you
what they mean if you go to defcon
in las vegas you will see that eff is
essentially
the closest thing that hackers have to
a to a religious organization um
but uh we we have actual goals we are
we're a real thing and we do things
other than
making uh clever t-shirts and stickers
uh we are a digital civil liberties
organization
and our goal is to make sure that when
you go online your rights come with you
eff has been around since 1990.
uh i have not i was not there in 1990
i've been working at eff since
2007 which was a long enough time ago
and from the very beginning
eff was an organization that was
envisioned as a way of speaking
tech to power uh even back in 1990 when
the internet existed but the web was
sort of in its
nascent state we had a couple
of incidents that that led our founders
to believe that the government was not
very good at understanding the internet
uh where
data was going and how data was going
there and as our lives
have become increasingly digital that
there
was a risk that we would lose
our our rights to to privacy
and to security our right to
own the things that we buy and tinker
with them
our right uh to speak freely and to
speak
anonymously and to be able to
communicate with one another
in uh in a way that is safe and
that is safe specifically
from government eavesdropping
furthermore we understood that this
wasn't just going to be the u.s
government that was a problem a lot of
the time
if you're talking about digital civil
liberties and you're
okay with the u.s government having
certain powers
in order to spy on bad guys or
pedophiles or terrorists or pedophile
terrorists which i understand are a very
serious problem
you might not be okay with uh
the chinese government using the same
powers on
uh the residents of xinjiang uh
or uh you might not be okay
with the ethiopian government using
those powers
and that technology to spy on dissidents
who are living in washington dc
or the russian government using it to
spy
on supporters of alexei navalny or
any of uh putin's other uh
sort of political opponents you might
not be okay
with the uae or saudi arabia having
these powers
with countries with extremely bad human
rights records
that use these powers in order to
identify people
prevent them from speaking and sometimes
as in the case of our
research in syria you will see that they
that they use these powers to find
dissidents
and bring them to torture centers and
kill them so there is a very
strong link between the things that we
do online and the things that happen to
us
in the real world i in fact there was a
a documentary that came out several
years ago about the pirate bay and i
think it was peter soon
who got up in front of a court and said
that he was really offended by the term
irl
by the the notion that there is a
separation between the things that
happen
online and the things that happen in
real life
and increasingly our digital life is
our real life and as a result uh
eff's issues have really moved from the
periphery
from being a bunch of what the british
call boffins
from being you know tech nerds who get
stuff stuffed into lockers
to being at the at the center of
everyone's lives
um most people uh have
some sort of access to technology and
some sort of
experience with technology every day
we have cell phones we are carrying
tracking devices around in our pockets
we post to social media
where a a company controls the platform
and decides who can and cannot speak
largely according to its own terms of
service
we have you know
services and and consumer goods
advertised
to us at all times sometimes
in especially insidious ways
that that we are not aware of and uh
eff is there to make sure that
your right
to privacy to security to free speech to
anonymity
to tinker with the stuff that you bought
to
be creative still exists
and it's really under threat uh it is
increasingly under threat
with uh with every passing year so we
found that our issues have really moved
from the periphery
uh to the center of everyone's lives
so i am going to talk a little bit about
the
the three ways in which eff usually
uh approaches these issues so
when all you have is a hammer every
problem looks like a nail
so eff has a sort of diverse
toolbox for dealing with digital civil
liberties issues because
different problems require different
approaches so we
have people who work for us who are
lawyers and we do what is called impact
litigation
usually at this point i would also reach
out and
ask the audience who here knows what
impact litigation is
and some people would raise their hands
and some people would not raise their
hands and then i would try to
explain impact litigation relatively
quickly
most people are familiar with the
american civil liberties union or the
aclu
the aclu does impact litigation in the
sense that they take on
cases that they think are going to
create good precedent
or that are going to allow them to
strike down
bad precedent and one of the reasons for
that
is to create an environment in which
we have greater legal protections and to
sort of push
the the borders of civil liberties out
rather than having them
shrink and this means that we have
lawyers and that they have lawyers that
take on cases
but that we take on cases that uh
where we're not merely representing our
client
but we think that the outcome of this
case is going
to have an impact beyond that client
that is going to have an impact on a
large number of people
that it's going to impact the way that
judges decide future cases
the way that legislation is drafted in
the future
and the conversation around a particular
issue
so that those are often the reasons that
we get involved
um when i go to hacker conferences it's
really common
for people to think of eff as sort of
hacker lawyers in in the sense that if
you have questions about your security
research
or if you get into trouble doing your
security research or
doing responsible disclosure often uh
efs lawyers are the people that you will
call
we don't often end up directly
representing security researchers but we
advise them
really often uh and to that effect we
have
a program called coders rights
and you can contact info at eff.org
and they will put you through to the
coders rights attorneys
and if you have questions about how to
go about your research in a way that
will keep you from getting sued
how to release your research in a way
that will
keep you from getting sued uh and also
what to do
when the target of your research uh or
a platform on which you are releasing
your research or something
associated with your research uh
starts threatening you legally so
there are a lot of things that we do
along those lines so we have this uh
this sort of
floor of uh
very angry and talented
uh attack lawyers i'm very excited about
them
uh they have done things like uh sue the
u.s government a lot um specifically
eff is probably best known around the
time
that i came work to work for them for
having
sued the nsa
over its warrantless wiretapping program
first
we sued at t because we did not have the
standing to sue
the nsa and then apparently
one of the motivations for edward
snowden's
leaks uh was that he wanted to help
our uh our lawsuit and the very first
document that was
uh that was released in the snowden
leaks was actually a document that
supported
our lawsuit uh against the against at t
and that made it possible for us to go
on
and sue the nsa for spying on everybody
we argued that the
that mass surveillance is a violation
of americans fourth amendment rights and
outside of the lawsuit in sort of a
broader sense
eff argues that mass surveillance
is a violation of everyone's rights
it is a violation of fundamental human
rights
i and uh to that end we have an
international department
uh eff's international team is uh
one of our you know most most wonderful
sort of growing sectors and one of the
reasons for that is because eff
started out as a primarily us-based
organization and for a very long time we
were thought of
as you know sort of those crazy
americans on the west
coast uh or sometimes those crazy
americans in dc or boston
but always people who are concerned with
american law with american companies
and who believed that the way
to really change the internet uh was to
influence american law and american
companies because so much of the
the internet lives here that's not true
anymore
uh and in fact that has not been true in
many years and that was one of the
reasons why we created our
our international team so uh eff
has an international team that uh
travels all over the world not right now
obviously but under under better
circumstances
they travel all over the world they're
concerned with policy
in uh the world outside of the united
states
especially in latin america for a very
long time
i was a sort of eff specialist in
eastern europe
and the post-soviet states we're very
interested
in the surveillance state
that has been forming in china in the
surveillance state that has been forming
in russia
in surveillance states and
sort of creepy behavior among countries
that are normally
thought to be u.s allies and therefore
don't get as much attention
places like saudi arabia and ethiopia
uh and of course uh places that are
thought to be you know
the west and therefore somehow above
criticism
of their human rights records so we
also are are looking at places like
canada
and looking at policies in the eu and
especially
uh eu member states uh and
and now the uk since it's no longer part
of the eu
and has some of the most alarming first
amendment law the
first event free speech law that that i
have
ever seen so we have uh we have this
international team
in addition to an international team we
have a team
of rabid attack activists uh people
whose job it is
to get people on the ground uh to get
people excited about the work that we're
doing sometimes
the answer to a problem is not to file a
lawsuit
sometimes uh people have to get out and
march
sometimes people need to file a uh
you know to send an angry letter
sometimes
people need to sign a petition sometimes
it's necessary
for people to do something to their
devices or to
contact a company or a platform
they're using to explain to them that
their users will have
no more of this behavior sometimes
a revolt among the engineers is
the is the best way to go and this is
the kind of outreach that i love doing
more than anything else
because companies are not monoliths
corporations are not monoliths they are
made up of people
and the people who go to cactus con are
those people
the information security uh sort of
community is made up of those people
and we decide what our companies do uh
if you take a look at recent behaviors
by
by google and amazon uh
and um and apple
you will see that the times when they
have really
made concessions to human rights
to sort of doing the right thing it has
largely been as the result of
a revolt among their engineers
one of the arguments that i hear really
often about not speaking up
in your job is that tech is not
political and that's simply not true
everything is political everything that
you do is political
and as an information security
practitioner your work
is especially political i mean i
i'm not a person who brings up the you
know world war ii or nazis or the
holocaust
flippantly but
not everybody who lived in germany
during world war ii was a nazi but
somebody still had to you know build the
machines
and if you refused to build the machines
and you refused to build the software
some of which was built
in the united states by ibm then
the work will not get done it is not as
if some other
engineer will rise up to take your place
uh
one of the things that i really want to
see engineers do
both now and in the future and some of
the best work that we're capable of
is changing the norms around what is
acceptable
and finally we have our tech team
and this is the the team that i am a
member of
uh sometimes the answer to
what what are you going to do about this
about this great ill
on the internet is actually to build an
app
uh or a web extension
or to explain how encryption works to
members of congress
or to give privacy and security advice
to people
all around the world uh or to sit down
with companies and talk to them about
how
they can provide greater privacy and
security
against authoritarian governments
or companies that are you know screen
scraping
or anything else that they they might be
concerned about and also to bring up new
concerns
uh like how they can serve
broader communities one of the big
problems that we have
in uh sort of in information security
and
you know in in tech in general is that
we
build platforms and we build tools for
people like ourselves
uh and the majority of people who work
in information security
are sort of white and middle class and
living in what is euphemistically
referred to as the west
but i mostly think of as santa clara
california
and that leads to products
that work really well for you know kind
of
middle class straight cis men who live
in santa clara california
but the world is bigger than that and
other people have
other kinds of problems and if we think
of their problems as edge cases
as things that happen um you know as as
exceptions rather than the rule we build
products that simply do not work for
them and that let them down
in really frightening ways that often
have
a direct effect on
their everyday lives so that's one of
the reasons why the tech team is so
important
um a few of the the tech team projects
that you might be familiar with
uh include https everywhere
a very long time ago i think five maybe
even six years ago at the dawn of time
dinosaurs roamed the earth and most of
the web was unencrypted
i and so eff built a
web extension that made sure that if a
website
was capable of using https
that it would serve its contents over
https
by default um since then thanks to
another one of our
uh projects cert bot uh the web
is largely encrypted in transit
something like 80
of all internet traffic is now served
over https
and i'm really excited about that
because i remember a time when it was
trivial
for authoritarian governments and indeed
unauthoritarian governments
to see what we were doing online and
they spent a lot of time you know man in
the middling traffic
to email or to your various various
social media platforms
um one of the other things that our tech
team has really
uh championed is certificate
transparency
because obviously once the governments
were no longer able to just man in the
middle traffic
by by controlling the telcos
they started man in the middling
certificates they started issuing safe
uh
fake certificates uh in order to
decrypt the ssh traffic and thanks to
certificate uh transparency that would
be
visible almost immediately after it
happens
and people can simply stop trusting
uh the certificate probably the most um
noteworthy case of uh of that happening
was
uh with a european company called uh
diginotar
uh and i think it was belgium
so we have uh we have our tech team and
then
within the tech team we have a tiny
group of commandos uh there's there's
five of us
and uh and we are called the threat lab
uh in threat lab was founded
about three years ago
by me and my colleagues
i and the reason why we founded threat
lab
was that we had found ourselves doing a
lot
of security research which was not
unusual for eff
but the security research that we chose
to do
was uh mostly about internet censorship
and that led us to do work on
on apts so i spent several years
studying the behavior and writing
reports about the behavior
of various advanced persistent threat
actors
which is you know just our fancy way
usually of saying governments
um i wrote reports about
uh threat actors in vietnam
i in kazakhstan in lebanon
uh and and syria uh
as i mentioned before a lot of these a
lot of these things
resulted in you know real physical harm
to people which was one of the reasons
that i concentrated on it
and at the time the information security
world was not really interested
in malware that was targeting
journalists
or activists or lawyers
or you know other kinds of dissidents
they were not interested in
the um in the malware that was targeting
people who spoke truth to power
and the reason for that was because
activists and journalists and and
dissidents of all kinds
have no money it is a really big deal to
write reports
about threats to enterprises especially
if you are doing it in order to prove
how useful you are
to enterprises so that you can sell
enterprise software
and this is one of the reasons why
nobody cared if if somebody was
targeting syrians
and sending them off to to camps to be
tortured
nobody cared if the ethiopian government
was spying
on ethiopian uh you know
exiles living in washington dc uh
no one spent a lot of time worrying
about what was happening
to uh you know
lebanese journalists or activists
because it there was no money in it
uh not only was there no money in it but
the
uh the malware that was targeting them
was not very sophisticated
uh when you see infosec companies at
least
at the time uh write reports about eight
pts
they started with apt-1 they started
with china
they started with china trying
or succeeding at uh compromising
the the new york times there was a lot
of interest
in chinese hacking against google there
was a lot of interest in you know sort
of uh
in russian apts all of the sudden uh
somewhere around 2016 for some reason
uh and now if you go out into a room of
non-infosec people
there are actually people who know what
you know
cozy bear and fancy bear are who
will not just look at you blankly when
you say apt
28 or apt-29 i mean they're not gonna
know what apt32 is but
you know this is this is the an example
of how much
uh this this language has entered the
kind of
normal person lexicon um but
when we were first doing this work that
simply wasn't the case
uh people did work on you know
north korea uh and uh sort of other
non-big five actors occasionally uh
israel
but the reason that they did that work
was to show off their chops
uh because these were you know sort of
the
best most sophisticated most you know
kind of prolific
actors in the uh in the field a security
company could prove that they were good
simply by saying listen i i found
five eyes i have you know here is regin
the software which is being used uh to
you know the malware which is being used
by uh
gchq which is uh the british
uh sort of spy agency
here is the malware which is being used
by the cia or the nsa
or again the fsb
or svu uh that is a
that is a flex as the kids say
uh whereas the sort of stuff that i was
looking at was actually very simple
and it was very rarely
using odays it was often using
you know straight up fishing the most
the most
basic and and boring stuff in the
universe
but it was effective and it was having a
real effect
on the uh on the lives of
uh of people in uh in authoritarian
countries
and often people who had fled
authoritarian countries who were still
trying to communicate with the people
in uh in those countries who are trying
to do work
or speak up to to power in some way
so we had we had this kind of work and
we we needed a place to put it
uh then we also got interested
in uh sort of other
types of uh of targets
uh for example and other types of
technologies for example my
uh colleague cooper quinton
along with another researcher from from
google
worked on a project in which he
described the ways in which
the police were using
cell site simulators or mz catchers
and at the time there had been a lot of
research done
on uh sort of the the older version of
mz catchers
but there wasn't a lot being done on the
kind of next generation and the kind of
technology that was being
that was being used at the time uh
stingrays uh
for example were out of fashion uh and
we uh believed that hail storms were
sort of the new hotness
so we spent a bunch of time uh studying
how they worked and uh our cell site
simulator
uh sort of project
for uh for finding them uh based on sort
of
aberrant behavior um you know in the
i is is available on github in fact all
of the software that we write
is open source we take contributions
from everybody
anybody can fork we're always very very
excited about it
so if you are looking for a way to get
involved
with eff or its projects i strongly
recommend taking a look at our github
and making some
contributions if you feel that you are
not yet ready for prime time
and you are afraid of the judging eyes
of
eff staff it's also good to look at the
code simply to
learn how to do this stuff in the first
place uh
eff is really deeply opposed to the
notion of gatekeeping
if we don't inspire uh new software
engineers and we don't
inspire new security researchers then
then there will not
be a new generation of people to do this
stuff
if we climb up and we just pull up the
ladder behind us
uh then then no one will come and we
will be standing
at the top of whatever it is that ladder
was allowing us to climb to wondering
why it is so empty
uh so i really strongly encourage you
to to take a look at our github um
so where were we uh we were on
mzcatchers so we spent some time talking
talking about that we published a uh a
paper
on on how those mz catchers and cell
site simulators work
uh called gotta catch em all because we
love pokemon
and we also worked on some other
projects
probably about last year people became
for some strange reason
uh very interested in the kind of
technologies that police had access to
in order to spy on activists inside of
the united states
and specifically the kind of
technologies that they were using to spy
on on protests and on protest movements
it turns out that you can file freedom
of information requests
and find out a lot of information about
the kind of stuff that
that various local police departments
are buying
and so uh my colleague dave moss
organized large groups of volunteers
mostly college students to go ahead and
look
into the to look into these purchases
and we mapped them out we mapped out the
different kinds of technologies and we
mapped them out
all over the state and this particular
project
is called the atlas of surveillance one
of the places that we really emphasized
because threat lab is so focused on
sort of centering the needs of
vulnerable populations
was the border the u.s border with
mexico and so we went
we went down to the border and we spent
a lot of time looking into the
technology which is being used
there because technology is being
disproportionately
uh used there and it is
disproportionately being used
to uh to target people of color to
target
uh immigrants to target uh refugees
and uh we're especially concerned about
that so
knowing what kind of technology is there
is very important um
it's also the first step uh to allowing
people to protect themselves from this
sort of technology
to protesting the use of these
technologies
in your sort of immediate vicinity
uh one of the the most interesting
bits of activism the eff has has done
recently
has been a campaign against the
government use
of a face surveillance technologies
and our suggestion is simply that face
technology
face surveillance technologies and face
identification technologies
because they are so bad at what they do
and are are so biased towards
misidentifying uh people of color
that governments should not be using
them and specifically local governments
should not be using them and so
we worked with a lot of grassroots
organizations and have helped
to sort of create these bans
on uh on the use of facial recognition
technology
by uh by police and by governments in
in san francisco in oakland in
uh in cities in massachusetts and this
sort of thing is you know kind of
kind of spreading throughout the country
which i'm very excited about
um and finally there's there's the work
that i'm
usually known best for uh which was so
while i was doing all of this apt work
uh i uh was working with another
security researcher
who turned out to be a serial rapist
and i uh was really
really mad and so one of the things that
i did
after i was i i read about it and i
read an interview with one of his
uh sort of survivors slash victims and
she was really scared one of the the
things that really touched me about this
interview
was that she was worried that he was
going to
hack her devices that he was going to
install you know stalker wear
on her phone or on her computer and
apparently he had threatened to do so
and so i tweeted that if there was a
woman who had been sexually assaulted by
a hacker and was worried about the state
of her devices
that she could contact me and that i
would make sure that she got you know
sort of the
the forensics examination that she
needed
uh for her device and this tweet blew up
and in fact i still uh
this week i have been getting somewhere
between
six and a dozen requests a day
which is a little bit exhausting but one
of the things that i discovered was that
most of the time it's not stalkerware
most of the time people really just need
to lock down
lock down their accounts they need to be
able to change their passwords and
generally i found
that the problem was much bigger
than than just stalker ware that it was
that our real problem was a belief
in the information security field that
somehow spying on devices that belong to
your spouse or that belong to an ex
or that belong to one of your partners
in order to discover whether or not
they're cheating or to maintain some
sort of control
over them because you don't trust them
is somehow okay
and it's not so i've been
spending a lot of time working on
changing that norm
and also encouraging av companies to
treat
stalkerware as malware as potentially
unwanted
programs on people's devices i
also go around talking to companies
about
the domestic abuse use case
uh in the same way that we spent a lot
of time
trying to convince people that that
journalists matter
and that their safety is not an edge
case
and that activists matter and their
safety is not an edge case
women matter and their safety is not an
edge case uh
survivors of domestic abuse also matter
and their safety is not an edge case
so i have gone around trying to to talk
to companies
about how they can kind of domestic
abuse proof
uh their products and one of the big
problems that we have
in security is that we assume that
having uh the password combined with
physical access to the device
equals legitimate access to the device
and
in the domestic abuse case that is
frequently not the case so we need to
look
at other ways of establishing legitimate
legitimate access and being able to lock
uh
lock a user out because one of the the
most interesting things about the
domestic abuse case
is that it is not about simply not
trusting
someone often a a domestic abuser is not
somebody who shows up on day one and
says hi i'm going to control every move
that you make and i'm going to have
access to all of your devices
they show up looking nice they show up
being polite
they show up being you know the best
thing that ever happened to you
and the abuse very slowly creeps in and
so you're moving from a person
that you trust very much and that you
love very much to a person that you need
to lock
out of your life asap i and so i've gone
around to companies and
talked to them about uh the the things
that they can do to do that
one of the big mandates that i have for
companies is
i tell them that you need to make it
very uh easy for people to see who has
access to their data
and you need to make it very easy for uh
for a user
to lock a person out to move them
from trusted to uh to a state of
untrusted so i think that that's
especially important
so let's talk a little bit about what
you can do because
uh a lot of a lot of this talk was
really supposed to be focused on
how you build a threat lab eff's threat
lab is
really not the only organization of its
kind
i don't know if you are familiar with
the work of citizen lab
in toronto but they predate us by many
years and they're sort of the
the og of doing this kind of this kind
of research
uh paired with advocacy there's uh
lucy parsons labs which is
is also quite fabulous consumer reports
has opened up a lab and they put out a
report
just today in which they
compared various uh kind of opt-out
services
that that take advantage of california's
new privacy laws that allow you to
opt out of data collection uh and and
their report is really great
uh amnesty international uh puts out
reports
about the malware which targets the
sort of activists and journalists that
they work with
uh and again um citizen lab
has done years and years of great work
uh highlighting
the way that uh the the sort of makers
of these technologies
uh are often uh not people in
authoritarian regimes
but uh you know information
security workers like you and me who
work
in so-called western countries that
frequently this technology is built
in uh in places like
italy and germany and
israel which is the home of sort of the
the notorious nso group
um so this is one of the places where
uh people like you and me can make an
enormous difference
simply by uh changing the norm so that
working for these companies
is not okay so the you know building the
panopticon
is uh is not okay and we should not be
doing it
so hopefully at this point i've gotten
everybody all fired up
and uh they are trying to figure out
what kind of research
they can do in order to help
to help their their community and the
good news is
that everybody has a community that they
know
everybody is from somewhere for example
you might look into the
security and privacy concerns of
uh of your family of uh your
you know parents or grandparents and
just generally the elderly population
who are really being left out in the
cold during this quarantine
you might look at the security concerns
of students
and student privacy right now especially
now that
most learning takes place online and eff
has done some really interesting work
in student privacy especially on the
kind of proctoring software which is
very invasive
that that children have been required to
put on their devices
and we're very worried about that
so you can do work on student software
you can do work
on the concerns of your
immediate community of your school of
your church
temple or coven depending uh
and there is work for everyone to do
one of the most important things that i
would really like people
to to take away from this talk is that
you don't need permission to become a
security researcher there is no fairy
that comes around and sprinkles glitter
on you
and tells you you have now been blessed
by cactus con
or defcon or rsa
or anything like that and now now my
friend you are a security researcher
the best way to do it is not to wait for
permission uh
though consulting with with an attorney
in advance is a very good idea before
publication or before doing your work
including our coders rights project but
the most important thing is to
find a community that you care about and
ask them what their concerns are find
out the ways in which they are being
underserved the ways in which they're
being taken advantage of the ways in
which
ordinary platforms and uh and
internet connected devices and phones
and computers
are failing them i and start
looking into that and just go ahead and
publish
go ahead and publish and i swear i will
i will make sure that people read it i
am especially interested in this work
one of the things that i'm really proud
of uh
with my with my soccerware work is that
it has
inspired a number of academics to go out
and
build their you know sort of phd theses
around uh around doing research into
the domestic abuse case uh and into ways
that
uh iot devices are being used in
domestic abuse
and ways in which malware is being
categorized
and ways in which uh you know this this
tracking is taking place
and i think that that is really
important work uh that just about
everybody here can do
so i i hope that this has been helpful
and
i would like to see every last one of
you go out
and build a threat lab
you