well hello hello again folks
ryan once again with the cactus con crew
i'm here with red hat august and
the fish 7. i don't know if he actually
pronounces it do you pronounce it that
way i'm now i'm going to because i just
made that joke up there
i like that thank you fellas for being
with us today
and thank you of course for your talk um
we'll get into that moment
momentarily first up some prize stuff
some giveaway stuff we had
some winners just announced so
we've got uh downgrade and
nabon nitis the botanists i should have
practiced that before and danger noodle
nice uh congratulations we will
be in contact shortly whatever shortly
it actually is
and let's go ahead and give out some
additional prizes in the
last round um i did not give out enough
of the vouchers so we're just gonna do
that
right now live on the air
and boom there we go so um
we've got gizmo clutchbot and hdz
with 20 dollar vouchers for no starch
press
again thank you to no starch press as an
in-kind sponsor
heck yeah we really appreciate that
those ted demopolis books
uh they are signed they will be going
out to you folks who won them so again
just you know we'll be in contact
all right so before we get going here
with the questions uh
red hat august i believe you have
something you wanted to add
yes so i just wanted to let everybody
know i kind of made a little bit of a
nooblet mistake in the video
uh i put vagrant remove and that's it
it's the command would actually be
vagrant box remove and then you have to
specify the box
so i don't want people who are using
this uh to end up like
you know filling up their hard drive
when they're trying to remove it or
freaking out when that command doesn't
work
uh we'll put it in the readme just for
clarification but again i made a mistake
wanted to come forward with that and
clarify what it's supposed to be
so just stay tuned for the readme on
that
awesome thank you for that uh little
note here
i i thought it was you know just
absolutely fantastic project
and talk concerning the project i
personally am not a red teamer at all i
mean i've already mentioned this in a
couple qas before all right we get it
dude you're a blue team
shut up but the thing is is that i
love trying to pretend like i'm a red
teamer and every once in a while you
know i still go back to like
metasploitable too you know
from like 2000 and no i don't know what
year that came out
you know um i keep popping pro ft ftpd
and thinking i'm awesome
so having this easy method to just
spin up boxes is awesome i love the use
of vagrant to bring stuff up and bring
it down when needed
there's a group westmech hopefully
there's some westmeckers out there
watching right now the western
maricopa education group um they do some
great training for folks
on the uh well the west side of the
valley hence the name
some extension training some adult
training and a lot of concurrent
enrollment for high schoolers
they were teaching vagrant to their uh
you know 16 to 18 range i believe kiddos
back like even four or five years ago i
remember going over there the first time
and the the kids were like you know they
got up and and
bringing boxes up and down and i'm like
i work with people who don't
who don't know how to do that so yeah i
just i i love
i love that inclusion great great job
overall
so we have a couple questions for you
one and it's been answered but we're
going to go ahead and ask it and make
sure everyone
is aware is essentially is the project
is it available is it open is it public
and
essentially where can i find it yeah
absolutely uh
so as the video had it you would just go
to my github
and uh phone hub underscore vagrant you
would want to clone that in
as i put in the video um you'd have to
install
virtualbox virtualbox extension pack and
fragrant
i do encourage you install git too
because i'm just a command line junkie
uh so you clone it in and you go into
the directory and you do vagrant up
it is free as in um you know free beer
which is great such as vonhub has always
been since 2004.
everybody has access to these machines
always has
ever since its creation you know hence
got milk's point of putting it out in
the world
uh however through my experience of
starting out
remembering what that was like i just
wanted to make it a little bit more
accessible as in setting up the machines
because some of them you can kind of
have issues with getting them to work
so i'm trying to get all that done up
front so again you just have to run the
command and everything
is good and you also don't have to worry
about oh i need to go get vmware
versus virtualbox or you know hyper-v or
what what have you
right so yep it's free just hit the
github
i like it i like it and
another question for you here and this
question
we talked about it offline we'll see
where we go with this is there any way
to set up
and then essentially to remote in such
as in a classroom
setting so a shared infrastructure if
you will
right so um to address this question the
way that i designed the project
is really to be on the host itself right
i the intent was somebody's gonna be
going in their own computer
and i made that internal network a
requirement for virtualbox that means
there's no internet access from both
your attacker host
and uh the virtual machine you know just
in case somebody's a little bit nervous
about pulling in an exploitable
machine there might be something on it
they're worried about that it's
literally going to
lock it down so it doesn't even have
access to the host
however with that being said if you
wanted to change the network of the
vulnerable machine to maybe bridged and
you had it as an
internal setup for your classroom you
pull them all into a central server
that's how i do it in my class right
however that does mean that you would
need a some type of access maybe a vpn
to get into the classroom to be able to
hit those machines on that server
so it is definitely possible but it will
take a little bit more manipulation
and um you know finesse on your part
depending on how your network is set up
how you wanted to deliver it
uh whoever asked that question feel free
to hit me up on twitter
you know and we can we can kind of
clarify that out uh of course doing the
whole vpn thing i'm going to leave that
out of scope for me that would be for
you to figure out but if everybody's in
the same classroom and you have like a
bunch of
uh student computers who are accessing
it that's how i do it um
so i i could make that shift really
really quick
awesome thank you thank you i don't see
any
questions immediately in the chat right
now anything that either you fellows
would like to
share with the group any you know
commentary what you
what you got you're on the spot all
right yeah sure one
one thing that i want to do is i want to
give a shout out to dion zeller
i you know something in the github that
i want to make clear is i have a folder
called other
right he's the only machine that i have
in there so far uh
but his uh server yoblog was one of the
very first servers that i ever hacked
into and what i learned from
so i highly recommend that go check it
out you're going to learn about lfi
you're going to learn
you know how to get into servers you're
going to learn a little bit about
database
exfiltration and whatnot a really cool
machine go into other
check out yo blog it's outside of
vulnerhub uh and then another thing is
if there are any
exploit machine developers out there
that want to give me
uh you know the machine to throw into
the project reach out
you know i'll throw you in the other if
you're not on vuln hub
uh so we can grow this thing and really
make it again accessible for
our newbies who you know we're gonna try
to level up right
absolutely fantastic uh a note about
that box
the yo blog i see here in the
description on github
this machine was used in the cactus con
uh root box competition in 2016.
that's right put on by early warning
yeah early warning by the way who's one
of our
partner sponsors and has a chat room
that you should go check out
very cool thank you thank you all right
well
if there's anything else you want to
throw in now's the time to do it
otherwise we'll go ahead and wrap it up
and um yeah thank you both
very very much again awesome awesome
project
uh i was going to ask about how you're
going to maintain uh to avoid
stale boxes and then realize that you
don't need to i mean you can essentially
you know i'm still with metasploitable 2
like i said so
and it's it's huge there's a last time i
checked
um because the last time they were
updated was december 15th of 2020
uh there were 624 in all i have on vol
hub
209 of them finished uploaded ready to
go i'm working from the newest one and
going to the oldest ones
uh i gotta you know i'm hoping to talk
with got milk later on to see kind of
what the future of on hub is if it's
going to keep going if my project has a
definitive close date
but like i said if there's people who
are making uh exploitable
machines that are outside of vuln hub
and you want to keep adding to the flow
just hit me up and
and we'll get it up there you know
awesome and i have to ask you before we
leave here i see that you have a whole
bunch of
rubik's cubes behind you do you have do
you have one of the connected cubes
one of the no no no
i got the uh the go cube um and then i
connected when rubik's actually you know
got into it
and they're pretty nifty especially for
someone who is horrible at them so i
assume you're probably better given
i don't know man i don't know i like
puzzles they're fun to fiddle with but
you know there's always someone better
[Laughter]
all right well redhead august and the 7.
thank you very very much for your talk
and for that project it's
really a great project everyone go check
it out on github
and there we go i'm going to go ahead
and kick off the
next giveaway the next giveaway coming
up
is learning python for forensics
leverage the power of python and
forensic investigations
this is a digital book by chapin bryce
he's a co-worker of mine he works also
on our team blackberry security services
ir
blackberry of course is a partner of
ours they have a chat room go check them
out
i'm going to initiate that little sucker
right now
and there we go so everyone go ahead and
put in for that this is officially
our lunch half hour if you will so we
have our next talk starting in about 28
minutes
and we'll see you all then all right
thanks everybody
thank you bye