I saw the submission come through I
started geeking out and asking everybody
who is this county so I'm looking
forward to the stock so a little bit of
a quick story when I so submitted here i
thought that i was submitting to a town
that's about to annette hours from DC
Jefferson's house and it yeah so I
showed my my my girlfriend you know hey
I got accepted here and she's like
that's kind of a long drive I was like
oh what no no yes Charlotte which is not
sure what's built so so that's kind of
how I got here when I'm super excited to
be a Jame so so today we are going to
talk a little bit about
okay so today we are we are going to
talk about LTE security um there is a
much longer date our class I have
developed up about GSM UMTS and LTE and
LTE but this is basically a small and
quick dirty intro to LTE networks and
LTE security and we are really going to
look at it from a standards-based
perspective you see a lot of different
security claims about about LTE and
there was one that was really really
bothering me and that was the this whole
notion
and to end LTE security people were
basically saying that you know LTE is is
is encrypted from start to imagine so I
want to show some of the standards later
and show why that's probably not true
and you can make your own judgments but
I'm just showing you these the standards
and basically providing some evidence
about my security claims so we are we
are going to talk about different so
there are standards and importance other
concepts LTE network architectures the
security architecture and then I'll
provide some stuff for some further so
further reading so I have Josh Franklin
from DC 27 a totally 63 so yeah I do i
do work at a nest I I focus in public
safety networks mobile security hardware
roots of trust and electronic voting so
so what is LT LT LTE that is the long
term evolution that is the fourth I
could say for its 4G whatever whatever
that means it's basically be deployed
worldwide it's really really nice that
we're starting to have it a nice
worldwide send their standard before
it's kind of fractured you have gsm cdma
you're really really focusing on one us
sort of having our own little fight
without one and then we had whatever
Japan was doing
yeah so uh a LTE super super cool it's
probably here to stay for a long time so
it's it's definitely worth your time in
picking up some LTE knowledge here LTE
is is basically always evolving there's
a standards group called 3gpp that that
actually develops these of standards and
they drop of new releases which is
basically we have you know 400 documents
and worship stop adding the stop stop
editing them now and that's called a of
fries or a release and so LTE release 12
is actually coming on in December 2014
but you know there's going to be you
know lte-advanced and then what does it
LTE be as what I hear three of three
to basically every new drop as
standards 3gpp is the standards body
that is that is actually developing
these standards the same standards
bonded both gsm and UMTS caesar come
completely open and viewable standards
it's not like it's not like I saw where
you have pain or forty five francs your
Swiss francs to look at mobile or
whatever it is 3gpp is actually made of
six different standards development
organizations that are basically from
different parts of the whole world you
see erith there Addis is the North
America's you see XE here also and
that's Europe's and Etsy does a lot of
the crypto standards so a lot of the the
base of the coin
there are other organ of organizations
3gpp2 which is the most confusing in the
whole world develops cma and their hold
their whole why and there's also the OBO
MX form which day Belvoir max 3gpp2 just
at a quick note was developing a cdma
variant
4G and it was called UMB and thankfully
they ate a stock and so America's all
moving towards the same technology there
ain't no long on it on bottle of this
3gpp has technical reports which kind of
more like book reports and you know
analyses and then there's there's actual
technical specifications which are
requirements documents you'll probably
have to read both cellar standards use
lots of jargon and and abbreviations
frequently nested acronyms are common
and this is one of the fun things I have
found a 3 a 3 depth nested acronym I was
you know I'm really really curious if
anyone else has seen any you know
anything that goes further so for
instance G ran stands for GPRS evolution
radio access network and GPRS stands for
like a general packet after i forget
what GPRS technically stands for so i've
seen four of those though and so you
know let me know if you find anything
deeper open challenge open challenge so
packets and circuits previously any
voice tect like basically any voice
technology was basically using a circuit
fork for communication which is
basically fixed fixed bandwidth you know
guaranteed bandwidth and you know that
that actually happened with the PSTN and
and it happened with gsm and and um TS
and so basically if you wanted data you
had to have distinct data networks and
so you had a gsm talking sorry a gsm
voice traffic going to the core network
and then you had a distinct GPRS packet
switched Network that had to converge on
the core network and so LTE is really
really different their LTE is completely
packet-based which is really really
interesting it there is volte which is
voice over LTE sorry voice over LTE
which is another that's the third that's
a third level nesib acronym right anyway
so so a VoIP is but is but one way of
doing voiceover over LTE there are a
bunch of others right now if you do make
a call on LT on LTE you are most likely
falling falling back to either CD cdma
gsm or um TS so it's not actually
implemented nationwide yet so the big
lesson here is LTE is completely
ip-based which actually means that a
once you like you can do a lot more with
with LTE networks now but it like now
that all the the different offensive
tools you know are all tcp/ip you know
you know packet based basically whereas
it's very very different in the past the
cellular standards this is how I think
of it you have 3gpp circuit-switched
which you see the the the gsm 2g tech
and you see the the UMTS 3g tech there
in that one column you have the 3gpp
packet-switched which is GPRS EDGE HSPA
family there's up there's a bunch of
those and then LTE 3gpp2 has cdma 12
thousand evdo the now dead um B&Y faxes
wife XY max is quickly dying and because
basically sprint invested heavily in
that upfront and they are now
transitioning to to LTE these are the
primary documents that you should
basically be aware of and i would just
recommend reading the first three if
you're interested it's not too difficult
that's probably 200 pages you know you
probably read longer books and 9th grade
right yeah yeah so these are you know
this is just a quick little collection
here we're going to zoom in here and
mostly we're going to be discussing 33
dot 401 and that is the specific version
that i use for this presentation this is
the primary LTE security architecture
document and you can for the most part
read the first 20 pages without much
difficulty and that's
where the most important portion is so
you know give it a quick look it's
really confusing to to to download these
standards FYI they're going to be
downloaded in a's a zip file and that's
the only way answer then double click on
that and then open it up it's super
awful so just FYI with some instructions
so here's the big picture in case you
you like really haven't looked at
cellular networks before so mobile
devices connect to a base station which
is those giant and and and antennas in
the sky which connects to a core network
which is basically run by verizon AT&T
sprint which then you know connects to
the internet or or other cellular
networks or or the the public switched
telephone network the portion between
just the base stations is called the
radio access network the iran and you're
going to see that term kind of be
evolved there is a G ran a you Tran and
EU Tran and so r and you know just just
just be be aware of that that is a a
collection of basically base stations as
we said base stations are permanent
cellular sites often times they are
disguised which is kind of funny when
you find one of one of those they
sometimes look like rocks or like they
like put trees around them so you don't
really know that they're there sometimes
they can you know run off of gas like
gasoline if they're like like way high
up in the the the mountains it's just
you know interesting when you when you
come across one next time you do take
you know take a look and just you know
look at the different types of locks and
just be aware so base stations sometimes
co-locate different carriers on the same
base station so you might have 80 AT&T
buying time from Sprint or a buying time
or space from
of verizon so a base station doesn't
necessarily have to be just one one
company and base stations are often well
base stations are connected back to the
the core network via a link called the
backhaul kind of pointed to it there and
that backhaul interface sometimes is a
fiber sometimes it's satellite sometimes
it's microwave it all depends on what
sorry most definitely t1 yep it's it's
basically however we can get the
information from the base station back
to the core network mobile devices your
your typical mobile device and whenever
someone talks about mobile devices they
want to take out there a phone and show
you right and I really want to right now
for some reason I know you all know what
a freaking phone looks like so my my
mobile device has anywhere from like
four to six different radios in it you
know Wi-Fi GPS Bluetooth you know
possibly a bunch of different cellular
radios and so just just kind of be be
aware of that um in in LTE terms bless
you a phone is called a ue a user
equipment and this this user equipment
has a a UIC see which is often thought
of as a semi am a sim card this this
this a UICC is actually running an
application on top of it called the the
the the you sim and so that's just sort
of a big difference from a couple years
back sim and um are kind of used
interchangeably but they are very very
different nowadays subscriber identity
MC you've probably heard this when
you're basically hearing about stingrays
or you know MC catchers MC is basically
you're on the cellular network it is
your personal identity it defines who
you are it is a 15 digit number
stored on the the sim card or you sim
card whatever it consists of three of
values mcc MNC msi n we'll take a look
at that in a moment a lot of times
carriers try not to send the mcs over
the over the air if they don't if they
don't have to and so they'll use a
temporary identity called a guti I don't
know if that's how it's said that's how
I say it in my head a globally unique
uuue identity or a Tim see again I'm not
sure if that's how it's said temporary
mobile subscriber identity and these are
all different from your actual phone
number right your actual msisdn this is
what an AMC looks like and how its kind
of broken up it's just interesting to
note that a Europe may use a two digit
value for the second thing there for the
the second range yeah this is what the
you know just this is what all the fuss
is about hum but I have anyway so ue
identity your actual phone has its own
identity called the actual imei the
International Mobile Equipment Identity
it is a 16-digit number you can actually
look at it right now by doing pound hash
06 hash on your phone and it'll it'll
probably pop right up for our our sorry
sorry star hash 06 hash my bad don't
want to confuse our British friends and
the actual imei is often used most often
used to to blacklist phones from a
cellular network so so if someone steals
your phone they can blacklist AT&T can
can can blacklist that phone from
getting on their network it is um it is
illegal to change a phone's IMEI and
many in many countries for that reason I
don't know about our country you sim
cards these are basically and if if what
if what I read is true this is the
single most popular smart card and the
whole were
old / 7 over 7 billion in circulation
they actually store cryptographic keys I
mean that's their primary duty here
right is they are long-term
cryptographic key storage in a secure
area they do house a processor that
actually runs an operating system and
and on on top of this operating system
there is a stripped stripped-down mobile
mobile version of the the Java Virtual
Machine that is used and and and and it
can actually run apps like you can run
games off your s ehre your sim card
which is kind of cool and will totally
not be misused by anyone ever yeah and
like we were sent here sims are
deprecated the modern term is used sim
so you may remember cdma did so
basically a verizon used a soft sim they
have now basically you know made this
huge change in their a network and they
are now using a you know hard Sims now
and Sprint is changing from my mac
stealthy already went over that here's
what the sim card looks like there are a
bunch of different types right um we're
really just removing plastic for them
for the most part here in this picture
the the the yeah remove plastic I don't
know what that means um so the actual
metal part is more or less the same the
contacts are a little bit different oh I
Sims if you if you roll in Android you
are probably using a micro sim if you
roll and iPhone you're probably using a
nano-sim makes it real hard to go back
and forth so LTE networking here's
here's what we're really here for
remember it's a 4G data and voice tech
technology it's basically split into
three different portions any LTE network
the actual radio network which is called
the ve yu Tran I don't want to try and
go for that giant acronym the actual
core network the the evolved packet core
and the the
the IP multi multimedia subsystem we're
not going to talk about the IMS because
it's kind of confusing and we don't have
enough time here and if anyone has any
questions you know stop me let me know
so we're we are really going to focus on
the interaction between the the actual
phone and a base station I know this
looks awful and horrible let's talk
about it for a moment and then we'll go
into a nice pretty picture I promise
okay so the actual ue is the LTE device
in LTE parlance base stations are called
evolved node bees which is an awful name
so i know'd bees or eaten bees you will
see it written three or four different
different ways just just just know
anything with a be on the end it's
probably a base station that's just you
know so the the mobility management
entity Mme this is a really important
box on the core network it is it is a
server that is um that is basically
doing all of the authentication
functions and all of the Kindle like all
the different control signaling allowing
you on the the network saying you know
you can go here can't go there the
serving the serving gateway is the it's
it's basically the main route that user
data passes through it's just it's just
another server on the network it does do
handoff between other 3gpp networks and
so if you're going from AT&T LTE to
verizon LTE then if if there was a
handoff that had to be done because
you're going down a highway at 60 miles
an hour and you have to switch from this
from this base station to this base
station then that actual handoff would
would occur at the SD as the serving
gateway the the packet gateway the p
gateway allocates IP addresses and so
yeah all your phones have have nice IP
addresses now that none now that you're
on LTE the p gateway does handoff
between LTE oh sorry between 3gpp
networks and non 3gpp network
so if you were trimmed like if you were
handing off from AT&T LTE to verizon
cdma then that actual handoff would
occur from from the P gateway the home
subscriber server and the authentication
center the difference between these are
very minut I don't even talk about it I
just kind of mentioned them in the same
thing they actually reside on the the
enemy and they they actually hold your
long term cryptographic key k well we'll
get into that and the actual MC and then
I ms which is kind of confusing we're
not going to talk about that so here you
can see we have the the phone and
through some awesome lightning bolt
graphic there it goes to the the base
station from the the base station
control signaling is routed from the
base station to the enemy and as like
this is where all your all your
authentication information is stored at
and the serving gateway is where all
your user data is is put through and so
from here we would go out to the
internet or the the PSTN and this is
just a really basic LTE network was not
really mini you know there's not much to
know here which is which is nice right
so for communication between the phone
and the and the and the e node B and
then the core there are there are
cellular specific protocols as you might
as you might as you might imagine it
it's it's a cellular version of tcp/ip
right and in reality tcp/ip actually is
no runs on on top of all of all of this
which is which is which is nice um so
we're going to we're going to take a
look at some of these protocols here
let's zoom in on the far left side so
LTE uses different communica munications
planes prime primarily you should just
think of three you have a communica
munications plane for user data my phone
to the base station to the court to the
core to the core network that could be
voice or whatever you're looking at
there is control
signaling between your phone and the
base station right because the base
station has to know where your your
phone is it has they get tracking area
updates it has to you know do all that
authentication it has to say hey you're
being a little bit loud simmer down
right um and you know there's actual
control signaling for that and then
there has to be control signaling from
your phone to the core network and so
there's that's basically three distinct
planes here cool uh so we're going to
look at for a moment these three bottom
these three bottom ones so our RC
basically provides control signaling
between the phone and the e node B the
PDC p protocol packet data convergence
protocol does encryption and and it
actually gets like a it basically takes
all these the signaling above it and
then encapsulate sand then frankly just
you know encrypts it or or or integrity
protects it the the the RLC it actually
readies readies packets to be
transferred over the air interface and
then the actual Mac layer does
multiplexing and quality of service and
then physical you actually have you know
electronic bless you electronic
transmissions you know gallivanting over
the airwaves so here are the control
protocols and and and a lot of these
protocols are sort of repeated here and
that's and that's fine it's just how the
standards documents explain it so you
have the the control protocols which is
an ass security which is the which is a
non access stratum super confusing name
it connects you're like this is that a
control signaling plane from your phone
back to the core network and then you
see our RC there which is control
signaling from your phone to the actual
base station and then simply simplified
much more is where is what your your
data would would traverses
these four protocols here interfaces
that nice diagram that we had earlier
every single thing like every single
interface every single connection
between between a server or a network
component has its own unique identifier
basically and here are the main ones
that I want you to know for LTE so in
requirements will say things like the
actual yeah it'll say the x2 interface
which is between between two base
stations the x2 interface has to you
know has to have this much encryption or
you know has to be protected by these by
these means and so what you really need
to pay attention to is what's going to
confuse you is the is the s-1 interface
has to has two separate interfaces I
don't want it they just didn't call them
two different s 1 and s 2 so the actual
s 1 mm II is the the control plane
signaling interface and then the s1 you
is the user plane inner is the user
plane information in an interface
security what we're all here for so
there are a couple of different security
mechanisms in use here the actual um
token right the actual hardware token
authentication and key agreement which
is how your phone gets gets
authenticated onto the the the network
and that's really what what what a lot
of um a lot of people that say black hat
and DEF CON have been you know breaking
over over years passed and then we have
crypto LTE you know has its own like
basically has its own encryption and
integrity cryptographic algorithms so
we're gonna talk a little bit about that
high level threats to LTE there is a
document and it's one of those TRS and
you should probably go take a look at it
and just just sort of talks about stuff
we are worried about it was the the LTE
designers and so these are some of the
things here right tracking tracking
identity physical physical attacks on
base stations manipulating country
plain or user plane data threats to like
basically how there are like downgrade
attacks in SSL there are you know
downgrade attacks exist in cellular
networks as well Tino push you into
using a week or cipher and then you know
jamming it is you know an open an open
interface and so on it's interesting to
note that jamming is not within the
threat model of LTE and you can you can
basically acquire jammers for like 40 40
bucks on ebay from you know they'll have
some Russian characters on the packages
but uh yeah so it's just interesting to
know that they are not trying to prove
protect against this and mentally it's a
really hard hard hard problem so low
level threats right i mean basically
since it is open there is a sorry
because the the air interface is open
there are um like you can basically
sniff the the traffic possibly or do
jamming attacks sim cloning this used to
be a way bigger problem where you would
either steal someone's phone and copy
their sim their sim card and then
basically use their their their account
to make long-distance phone calls right
and nowadays more of an issue is really
people people cloning their their their
own phone and then and then using like
using using that to spread out their
wireless service to multiple to multiple
people basically have want to have one
accountant you know ten different 10
different 10 different lines basically
right and I really even that I like even
that I don't leave it like I don't see
that much of that happening threats to a
privacy by design I mean your phone
knows where you are at all times or at
the very at the very least if you are
like your relation like your location in
relation to a base station right i mean
if if your phone can talk to a base
station you're within some minimum some
minimum distance between a unique base
station and as we're saying now like
basically sprint and AT&T and Verizon
they have to operate this massive IP
based network now with you know
basically servers all
on the internet that's going to be a
little bit a little bit different from
from from before so the actual hardware
token you sim UICC it is more or less
identical to what it was in um TS which
is 33 g it actually points to the same
standard so just as hey look that way it
uses an l sorry LTE uses a new hardware
protected 128-bit key called k and k is
just really really like really really
important you need to look into k um
basically all keys are derived from k
session Keys long term keys whatever and
K never leaves your phone ever k k is is
basically instantiated or sorry k is
derived or you know generated and then
it is basically stored in the core
network at the enemy and inside of a sim
card and other than that it is it is
never it is never released so um a at a
nice segue okay yeah so one of the main
points of this key k is for aka aka you
know authentication and key and key
agreement this is how subscribers are
authenticated to to a cellular network
so it's basically a crypt a
cryptographic protocol it's originally
specified and that standard previous
versions of of AKA did not do mutual
often often it off an authentication and
that's the big deal here is that is that
LTE actually ties the name of the
serving network so it ties the name of
basically verizon's network into the AKA
protocol and so you are actually
authenticating both sides you're yeah
yeah an aka again this is confusing
we'll just talk about it for a second of
a look at the diagram AKA uses
authentication vectors it's basically
the main primitive inside of a ka and
it's just a bunch of different a bunch
of different security parameters
uh there's a baby a bunch of them but
basically and an authentic
authentication vector consists of a
response and aut in I don't know how
people say that authentication out in a
nonce a random number and then a local a
session master key is how we will call
that and that is qasmi or k as me so
it's actually not too bad though this is
a simplified version it doesn't have any
of the of the error mechanism sink in
case things go wrong in it but basically
you have your phone with the with the UM
on the left and on the right you have
the core network which which has access
to the HSS and and often often an
authentication center you can see at the
top at the top left and top right both
sides have access to the M C and K and
so what really goes on is that your
phone sends either a temporary identity
or or the MC over over the air interface
to the core network that's the the top
thing there the second step is that the
enemy receives that information looks it
up and sins and sends that information
to the to the authentication center
cryptographic magic happens we're
basically on the the MC and K and the
serving network ID all basically
generate a couple of different cryptid
crypto cryptographic parameters
specifically these the the the reefs
priests response and the end the session
key and only that information sorry this
whole authentic authentic authentic
Asian vector is sent to to the enemy and
then only the the nonce and the and the
authentic often an authentication token
I still forget what what a what a what a
you t n stands for that is all sent to
your SIM card your SIM card does
basically a very very similar process as
what as what goes on here to to
basically generate a signed response and
that signed response is then sent over
to the enemy at the core network and if
this and at this and if this expected
response
is equivalent to the signed response
then someone is authenticated to the
network yes sir they definitely do so it
that uh so I'm just because I it's
confusing how networks are laid out but
but uh basically it's not it's not all
your eggs in one in one basket there are
there are yeah there are basically
multiple baskets I'm not exactly sure
how say you know AT&T lays out it's it's
a it's often often occasion centers but
I would assume this is a complete josh
assumption here that there is basically
you know maybe a North Carolina
authentication center and there's a
Washington DC and then there's a new New
Jersey I have no idea um I just don't
have access to that into to that
information but but basically yes if it
is all in one in one and one basket and
there's a leak
yeah yeah I've actually I've actually
wondered about that myself and this is
just a another Josh thought maybe they
are like maybe it was just because the
network was built in you know late late
late late 80s Early 90s and they used
symmetric crypto up up front or maybe
phones have to basically authenticate a
lot and you know asymmetric cryptos much
more sorry is you know not not very
efficient um again that's just like
that's just a guess on my part that's a
good observation um um so yeah that's
how that's how you know your phone gets
onto its network and earlier versions of
this are like they look basically
similar to this it's just some of the
the acronyms are different and that uh
that uh that s nid and that nonce might
not be there so we don't have time to go
over this i'm running a little bit slow
but there is this is the the
cryptographic operation that is that is
used to generate the the authentic
authentication vectors it is a
standardized algorithm but it but of the
3gpp standards don't say that you have
to actually use it because someone like
because verizon actually owns basically
your SIM card and they owned the core
network they can actually use we know
whatever key generation and key their
rate derivation algorithms they want to
because they on both sides and so as
long as it works with him then their
their their network it's not a big big
deal and this standardized algorithm is
french is called Mila Nagy I hope I'm
not hurting that you know hurting
someones ears real real bad and this is
what this is the actual um verification
I mainly made these diagrams because the
ones inside of these standards were
super ugly and these ones you can just
take and do whatever you want with with
them your yourself so yeah the power
point is all is all is completely
available so LTE crypto cryptographic
algorithms used for you used for
basically a conf conf confidentiality
and integrity protection this was
there's like a
like a long super fun history here right
like basically originally with gsm
networks trying to trying to remember
exactly how how it went it was going to
be 64 bits was how far the original like
how long the original GSN key was going
to be but then the West Germans were
really were really worried about the
East Germans and Britain's didn't trust
anyone's sorry anyone and it eventually
kind of got nerfed and the this the same
way des did and so it's a GSM had a 56
bit key basically with like eight eight
eight eight bits of padding but in LTE
we do have 128 bit and 256-bit keys and
these are these are fairly robust
algorithms they are standardized
algorithms you can go and look in and
see exactly how they are they are they
are being employed affined not how they
are implemented these are all open
standards basically have e EA which is
in you know encryption algorithm one and
then EIA which is you know integrity
algorithm one and they're a bit they're
both based on snow 3 3g which is a UMTS
algorithm and then the the US and you
know be me being from NIST and you know
our history with AES and all that the
u.s. uses like the u.s. basically got a
AES inside of the 3gpp standard so
basically you have e ee a 2 in E I a two
are basically a esnc CTR mode and then
you know AES cbc-mac and then China was
kind of perturbed about this and so they
decided that they that they that they
wanted their own corrupt you know their
own a girl gorillas meeeeee and so now
zouk is currently being standardized and
it should be to my knowledge it's not
implemented but that doesn't mean much
because i don't know i don't know
anything about LTE networks in china um
yeah so I just I just don't and if I did
that would probably not be safe so right
now most keys in LTE are 256 bits bits
long but unfortunately only one
like there's basically 128 bits of zeros
and a lot of them but that is being
quickly changed and you know everyone's
being proactive about that just you know
FYI so here's what I kind of promised
right we're going to dip into the
standards and I'm really going slow I
thought anyway um so these are the three
different standardized algorithms and
what it says here is that um is that a
es and snow 3g have to be sub sub
supported but zouk is you know you don't
actually have to support zouk which is
which is interesting i don't know if
that's going to change in the future if
you know basically verizon an 80 if a
verizon and AT&T will have to support a
chinese cipher sorry yeah it might be
built in right yeah so the key the key
hierarchy and LTE it's a little bit
confusing but um basically you have K
which again is only stored in core
network and Sam and you have ck and I k
which are basically derived from from k
and they are basically stored in in the
HSS and then the phone itself but then
you get into the actual meat of it with
kaz me and k a sm e and this is the this
is the the the local master key and so
basically all these other keys are
derived from Academy for the for the
most part and there's there's so many
it's crazy I should have put a picture
of what the the the standard looks like
it looks like the most confusing circuit
diagram you've ever seen if you're
looking at how up like it what the the
Kia hierarchy looks at looks like you
should actually go in and look at it it
is very very comical and what you're
what you what you see here is that you
have different keys for different
purposes which is great but then you
start to have different keys for
different protocols which is even cooler
you have KRR siento i'm just do if KR
zie end here and the KRC in encryption
here so you have a different key for
both encryption and and integrity and
you have the the same thing here for an
ass
the non access stratum control signaling
here's a sweet little chart I found
online and i reproved pro who produced
and I totally cited them but um I really
like this because it just shows all of
the different main keys and their
strengths real real fast so signaling
protection what it's actually encrypted
inside of LTE so as we were saying you
know different different community
communication paths have their own have
their own keys and a common claim and
this is what really perturbed me i will
say that word um is that a LTE is fully
encrypted I've seen this in like I
Triple E articles I've seen this on on
just like all all across the internet
and that may be true but it is not
mandated by the standards and so you're
basically you're putting your faith in
what AT&T and Verizon and Sprint do and
they may vary it like they may very well
encrypt everything I don't I don't know
I yet but uh just I just I just like to
you know say you know I camera this
point this point this point home and
this is just a cool little diagram shows
you know which Keys different different
different layers of the the protocol
stacker actually are actually protected
by so we talked about NASA security I'm
going to speed up a little bit we talked
about NASA circus security here being
the the signaling beats between of the
actual phone and the court the core the
core network and and so that's called
the non access stratum the green part is
called the actual access stratum and
they get protected with different with
different keys and then nds IP network
domain system and / IP this is basically
using IPSec in the court in the core the
core network that's the standard if you
want to read up on it that's like a five
page standard it basically says you can
use IPSec in a certain in a certain mode
and then you can put security gateways
which are just basically hardware
hardware ipsec appliances on your your
network of various points
and this is not required either but to
prove that here we go so NASA
requirements so you see Nass signaling
confidentiality is an operator option so
the control signaling is fairly
important i would have I would have at
least suspected that the that the
control signaling would have been would
have been encrypted and it says there
you know note one rrc and a signaling
confidentiality protection is
recommended and a big a big reason for
this might be is that 3gpp standards
have to be deployed worldwide right a
minute they have to work in all in all
countries and it all says such
situations rrc signaling confidentiality
is an operator option and yeah the only
thing that's really mandated here in
terms of cryptographic protection is in
is integrity so integrity protection and
replay protection shall be provided to
NASA IRC signaling which is interesting
and yeah yeah so basically you can think
of it as the minimum and confidentiality
protection it and and there is there is
a caveat that says that if you
physically like if you don't physically
protect your network devices then then
you have to encrypt I haven't found much
about what physically protecting your
network devices means but if you want to
go look at these these are the the like
this is the standard and where you can
find it before I wrap up home homie node
B's I just wanted to let you guys know
that these things exist that these are
basically femtocells or or a doe cells
like these are just basically base
stations in your your your your house MC
MC catchers are typically some sort of
femme toast femtocell what's interesting
about the actual homie node b standard
is that it says that uh that like that
you have to have roots of trust and so
basically you have to have you know like
long-term cryptographic key storage
protected by a hardware on
as part of the home Nov no duh be and
that secure boot must be done which is
which is really really great yeah it's
just interesting and then lawful
interception just wanted to put this out
there too I haven't fully investigated
this yet but there are three different
lawful interception standards that I'm
aware of they're actually built into the
the LTE standard sends basically as you
can imagine so you know law law law
enforcement bodies can you know get
access to the the keys that were that
were used to come to to encrypt
someone's traffic hopefully this is
being this is being done to UM to make
it so it's it's it's done in the most
secure way as possible one would hope
that like you wouldn't want lawful
interception to basically make it to
where it was really you know like the
rest of the key structure was weak or or
you know reduce the size of a a key so
that's basically all I got LTE security
is imperfect and crazy complicated and
complicated things are all like always
really really secure right so uh in
general integrity and replay protection
are mandated not confidentiality
protection and just remember remember
that standards provide the bare minimum
level of security that must be achieved
um telcos may voluntary may Valen Valen
tara lee raise the their security it's
hard to tell so thanks for having me
here's some further reading if you want
go to open security training got info
and i just tweeted these slides with the
with the b-sides CL CL CL t hashtag if
you want to take a look take a look at
them so thanks