hi my name is shu and this is a work
with rafael del pino
so what we do is that we propose a more
efficient ladder space around optimal
blind signature in this work
and our work can be extended to satisfy
partially blindness and it's also the
first scheme to be proven securing the
quantum random oracle model
we follow generic blind's signature
recipe by officialino 5 where the user
commits to a message
and creates his com and the signer will
sign on this commitment
and user when given this signature will
provide us your knowledge proof that
this signature is a valid signature on
this commitment which is a valid
commitment on the original message
here and the whole issue here is that
the signature and this commitment must
be kept hidden for blindness to home
and our work is basically providing a
new approach to this
component
so prior to our work there were three
main uh
lines of work for blind signatures one
is a shore type line signature
and uh this has been the most active
area of research but hong kong recently
showed that provable secure parameters
require signature of several megabytes
there is also a very recent work by
lubusheski eron that constructs a new
type of blind signature from one time
signature with an or proof
this is an interesting deviation from
prior techniques but it requires an
upper bound on the number of signature
at setup
finally uh the third one is base
instantiating generated construction and
agro it all uh creates well provides two
generic constructions and the first one
is based on random oracles and um
evaluating that random oracle using fhe
so this is rather less heuristic
however the second one is very efficient
but it requires a one more sis
assumption which is non-standard and
needs a bit more crypt analysis to have
to base confidence on
so our work in more detail is that we
provide the first round optimal and uh
a scheme that supports unbalanced
signature
so uh the verification keys can support
any unbounded polynomial e-mini
signature it's also based on standard
lattice based assumptions and it's the
first to be secure in the quantum random
oracle model
and it is more efficient than prior
works so it provides around 100
kilobytes for the signature and since
it's a generic construction we are we
could be able to plug in recent niz case
to further lower the synchro size
and agro recently updated updated their
paper and what they did was that they
used the recent uh nick by lewishevsky
at all in crypto this year to achieve a
shorter signature size than what we did
so at the heart of our construction we
provide a new commit then sign and zero
knowledge proof uh proof protocol
so here the client will create a
commitment to this message it will send
it to the signer the signer will sign
this and then provide a signature back
and what the client wants to do now is
that it wants to prove in their
knowledge that it has a commitment and
signature pair such that this commitment
opens to this public message and that
this commitment is also signed by this
signer
and here we want to keep the commitment
and signature private because this is
how we get blindness for the
resulting blind signature
and we know how to do this efficiently
in the classical setting using uh elgam
i mean discrete log or ddh type of
arguments but it's surprisingly
non-trivial to do this in the lattice
setting and this is
basically why
most prior techniques or all prior
techniques
requires a relatively
inefficient scheme
so at the core of our idea is that we
use an abb style signature for this
signature
and to to proceed with this
commit and prove protocol
so for abv signatures
the message is embedded into this
lattice and the short vector e will be
the signature
and this is a transformation inspired by
del pino at all but here uh we'll just
replace this message times g by a
commitment c
and this commitment we'll be using a
very traditional uh lettuce-based
commitment and it will be in the form of
br plus message time g
and here um
if we combine these equations together
the
client can recompute this equation and
uh transform it into this kind of
public matrix time private matrix a
private short vector equation
and at this point this is a simple size
relation with an accompanying efficient
and i z king
so for more details please i refer to
our full presentation or our paper
and although i didn't explain it in
detail the most technical part of the
work was not the core idea but uh it's
it's a more subtle part where this
commitment c has to be proven well
formed via nizk but here due to security
proof issues we need this to be
multi-proof online extractable which is
a very strong property and to achieve
this in a very relatively efficient
manner we rely on the recent
techniques to get this strong nic game
and this will give us also as a bonus
security in the qram
thank you for listening