hello everyone i'm jolyan i'm here to
give a short overview of our results and
now manipulate your knowledge this is
john's work with alan kim and ankan
pandi
let's first briefly recall the
definition for knowledgeable commitments
and knowledge about zero knowledge
for nominal commitments we consider the
so-called mind in the middle execution
in this execution there is an adversary
we denote it as m
in the left execution an honest
committer commits to m
and in the red execution
this addrem plays the role of a
committer committing to some message to
the receiver r
what numerable equipment want to achieve
is that the value committed by this
adversary m
in the red session should be independent
of the value committed by the honest
committer c in the left session
to capture this requirement i first need
to define two important random variables
the first variable is the view of the
main middle address right um
the other one is amp tutor which is the
value committed in the real execution by
the mayan middle addition
in this beam execution
we concern the joint distribution of
these two variables
now we compare this real world with a
simulated world
where the honest receiver is talking to
a simulator
this setting is a little bit different
from a zero knowledge definition in that
the simulator cannot rewind the receiver
r
because r is an honest receiver
however the simulator can join the minor
middle adversary internally and
potentially revives him
the simulator is required to be
efficient
and importantly he doesn't know the
value m committed in the real game by
the left honest meter
at the end of the simulated world the
simulator output a tuple
and we say that a commitment scheme is
not measurable if these two tuples are
computationally indistinguishable
here the intuition is that in this
simulated world the simulator managed to
simulate the view of the minor middle
together with the value committed by the
main middle without knowing the honest
commuter's value m
therefore this intuitively implied that
the value committed by the main middle
should be independent of the value
committed by the honest committer
nominal zero knowledge can be defined in
a similar way we also consider the mayan
middle execution
but the minor middle adversary plays the
role of a verifier in the left
communication
in the red communication this adversary
plays the role of a potentially
malicious proverb
proving some statement to the red honest
verifier
similar to the numerable commitment the
goal here is to make sure that the main
middle adversary cannot prove statements
that he cannot prove originally
meaning without talking with this honest
verifier in the left
to capture this requirement
we look at the value output by the
honest verifier
this is the binary bit indicating if the
verifier accepts the adversary's proof
or not
now in the simulator board we again have
this simulator talking to the verifier
trying to prove the same statement
importantly this simulator doesn't know
the witness w and also he doesn't know
the witness for this executable
however the simulator is trying to make
the verifier output a bit b prime
which is supposed to be computationally
indistinguishable from very fast design
bit in the real world as you can see if
the simulator managed to do so
that means what the adversary did in the
real world can be done by a efficient
machine which is the simulator
without having the interaction with the
left honest approver
this is how we capture the requirement
written about
before talking about existing works i
want to mention that these two
primitives are very useful nominable
equipments are useful for reducing run
complexity of multiple decomposition
protocols
and non-metabolizer knowledge has helped
us obtain better concurrent secure
multiple decomposition
now let's take a look at what we know
about the constructions
in the theoretical set after a long line
of research we eventually have constant
round constructions from the minimal
assumption of wind functions
however in the real world the state of
the arts are less satisfactory
for nominal commitment there does exist
a efficient construction based on ddh
but for non-level zero knowledge there
are no reported implementations with
practical efficiency
in this work we present the first
non-metabolic knowledge protocol
achieving a real-world efficiency
our construction only makes use of
symmetric key assumptions and is in the
plane model meaning without any setup
our technique also implies the first
practical non-verbal commitment using
only symmetry key assumptions this is in
contrast to the bgrv protocol mentioned
earlier which is based on ddh assumption
this is all i want to share during this
short talk if you are interested please
look forward to our talk at full length
here is the related information you can
also find our paper at this link
thank you for your attention