we present an algebraic framework that
can be used to build public kpcfs for ot
and vector early and two-party
homomorphic secret sharing for branching
programs we consider and solve two
problems in the first one we have two
parties and a correlation rule c this is
a function that outputs two random
correlated values are 0 and r1 and we
want to give our 0 only to p0 and r1
only to q1
we want to generate many of these
correlated pairs using only one round of
interaction and sub-linear communication
in the size of the outputs
a possible solution to this problem is
called the public-key sheet random
correlation function or pcf for short
this is a one-round protocol in which
the parties exchange simultaneously some
public keys and then with the help of
public nurses they can
evaluate the public keys along with the
secret counterparts obtaining their own
part of the correlated randomness
in our paper we present an efficient
solution that works for ot and vector
only correlation
the second problem we analyzed is still
in the two-party setting and now the
parties have some private inputs x0 and
x1 our goal is to apply a function f
belonging to some clutch class on this
input
and we want to obtain the output using
only two rounds of interaction
a possible solution to this problem is
called homomorphic secret sharing
so a it is a construction in which in
the first round the party's secret share
their inputs according to some
particular secret sharing scheme and
then using only a local computation they
can derive an additive secret sharing of
the output
in our paper represent a scheme that
works for branching programs
all right our starting point is the rise
of palia it is a eurocrypt 2021 paper
that solved both the problems i just
described
the solution
is based on the polycryptosystem but all
the constructions suffer from a problem
namely that they need a trusted setup
that generates a public rsa module
in this work we observe that the
techniques of the rise of pali can be
generalized we don't need to work over
the group anymore we can work over an
abstract framework a group that
satisfies some particular properties
one of this
instantiation of this framework allows
to get rid of the trusted setups and
this
instantiation is based on class curves
okay our framework is a group g that can
be decomposed as the product of f and h
where f is cyclic
and d log is easy over f but hard over h
in this setting it is possible to solve
the distributed d log problem the
technique at the base of all our
constructions basically we have two
parties that hold two values alpha beta
whose quotient is a power of f f to the
m
and the goal is to convert these inputs
into another secret sharing of them
without any interaction
okay
in order to understand uh how to solve
this problem we have to rewrite the
group g as you see on the slide so
we split it into cosets of f and we
represent each of these causes as a ring
because f is cyclic
now we have these two elements alpha and
beta whose question here is the power of
f so that means that they belong to the
same coset of f
okay
now
we assume that the parties p0 and p1
both know a canonical representative of
the cost containing alpha beta
in this setting solving the distributed
d log is easy the parties just need to
divide their input by gamma and then
they compute the d log of the result
uh and yes the result is a secret
sharing of m
the question is how can we obtain this
canonical representative of the coset in
a polynomial time and in order to solve
this problem we introduced two new
notions the first one is called the cost
labeling function basically it is an
efficient function that maps each of the
cosets into a different element
the second notion we introduce is called
the lifting function and basically it
does the opposite it takes an element in
the image of the cost labeling function
and it map maps it back into the
corresponding coset
okay
now how can we find the representatives
well it's pretty easy the parties just
take their input they apply the cost
labeling function they end up with the
same element and then they lift it back
into the coset using the lifting
function now the question is how many
groups have cosset labeling functions
and lifting functions
well we came up with instantiations the
first one is pale as it was already
known since europe in 2021
the second one are groups in which f is
small namely polynomial size then we
have variants of joy early bird and
finally we have class groups
the first three
instantiations still need trusted setups
to build public epcfs and homomorphic
secret sharing but the good thing is
that the last one doesn't