hi my name is justin and i'll be talking
about faster sounders succinct arguments
and iops which is a joint work with ron
rothbloom
succinct arguments allow approver to
convince a verifier that a computation
was performed correctly using a short
proof
a major bottleneck in the adoption of
succinct arguments which has been the
focus of a large body of work is in
reducing the overhead incurred by the
prover
here by overhead i mean the cost of
proving correctness divided by the cost
of the original computation
in this work for a large class of
boolean circuits c we construct succinct
arguments for the corresponding circuit
satisfiability language
where if
we want to achieve soundness error 2 to
the minus lambda our approver will have
overhead that is poly logarithmic in
lambda
this result relies on the existence of
sub exponentially secure
collisions and hash functions that are
computable by linear size circuits
i won't fully specify the class of
boolean circuits that we can handle but
it includes uh
many natural types of structured
circuits
including batch computation circuits or
iterated hashing circuits
we obtain our succinct arguments by
constructing interactive oracle proofs
or iops
for the same class of circuits with
analogous efficiency parameters that is
to say
uh the overhead of the prover in our iop
is poly logarithmic in the security
parameter
uh prior to our work the best iops or
arguments for boolean circuits either
had a prover overhead that was poly
logarithmic in the circuit size or
polynomial in the security parameter
if you'd like to hear more about this
result please come to my talk or read
our paper thank you