hello my name is akira i'm from austin
university in denmark
so in this video i'm going to give you
an overview of our crypto paper musical
that is smooth signature with single
round online place
this is a joint work with cecilia
bostini from technion and raihman
university in israel
and meditech from ntt in japan
so let's get started
so what is a multi-signature
so multi-signature is a generalized
version of the user signature scheme
where are there many different
assignments holding individually
generated secret keys
so first the parties interact with each
other and then after some are back and
forth
they produce a single signature on the
same message
then the verifier takes a list of the
public keys that participated in the
signing operation
then outputs uh rejects to accept
so our goal is to uh construct a lot of
space with signature uh using some
interactions
so our starting point is a chanel's
identification scheme
so recall that in the discrete log
setting
the channel prover first commits to the
randomness
and then upon receiving some challenge
uh the approver outputs a responsibility
so once you have schnoor it is known
that you can instantiate a lot of space
identification protocol
which is originated in the vivacious
key's work
so here the program comes to the
randomness but this time the randomness
is sampled from either gaussian or
uniform distribution over some small
range then upon receiving a challenge
now the approval has to additionally
perform the rejection sample
because the randomness is small the
potential response value z
is not independent of the secret key
so then the prover has to perform
rejection sampling and abort in some
cases
so
there are a lot of channel-like move
signatures
with different techniques
so for example using existing technique
called commit and open or trapped or uh
commitment
uh you can instantiate three round or
two round
signatures
in the discriminate setting and that is
safe
okay
and then the the latest works on this
minor research
music 2 and dwms
which requires only one round of
interaction
in the online phase
and the first round of interaction can
be pre-processed in offline phase
and because uh the first message that
the first commit message actually does
not uh
depend on the message to be signed
so this is a very nice feature however
unfortunately the security proof of
those existing scheme
rely on either
algebraic group model or one more
discrete log assumption
so uh here the main technical challenge
is
whether uh we can construct a scheme
with single round online face from
standard larissa assumptions
so in this work uh we answer this
question
positive by proposing our scheme using l
so uh here's the overview of our scheme
so if you're familiar with music 2 or
dwms
you probably see a lot of similarities
in the first
interaction uh each party
generates a lot of randomness and then
exchange many commit values
and then upon receiving uh some message
to be signed uh every party locally
derives a random linear combination
coefficient and b
then everybody
obtains aggregated commit message you
and then uh
continues with the user of yatchamir
operation
so important difference with music 2 is
that this rundown linear combination
follows gaussian instead of uniform
so
because of this you actually have to
modify the rejection sampling because
the potential value z here uh depends on
both
the secret signing key and the rundown
linear combination b
so you actually have to both recenter
the
response value
and also get rid of the dependence on
the the quotient p
so our rejection sampling analysis
actually takes care of this slightly
modified rejection sampling operation
so uh in this work uh we uh show that it
is feasible to construct fiat xiaomi
with about one signature with single
round online phase
and remarkably uh we did a security
proof in the classical random work model
from sis and lw
and we could require no one more
assumptions as in ec2 or dwms
so our proof is enabled by essentially
two key techniques
first one is our generalized version of
rejection sampling lemma
also we can
exploit the pre-image sampling algorithm
of the mechanical pi card
based on the lary structure
in our paper we can even if the security
proof rely on these techniques
additionally we also achieve
non-interactive key aggregation
so this allows the verifier to take just
aggregated a single public key instead
of instead of many
different public keys
so as a concurrent work uh flashing hub
flash hacker sim ki and zhang
recently proposed
a completely different uh that is based
non-interactive signature uh using
different techniques
also in a slightly different security
model
uh in this work we mostly focused on the
feasibility of the one round online
phase
using analysis
so as a future work we'd like to exploit
for example in true
so that we can minimize the overhead
introduced by a random linear
combination technique
also uh naturally we are also interested
in giving proof in the quantum random
model
and additional one uh additional
interesting question is uh
to give a simulation-based security of
the moon signature instead of the game
so uh thank you so much for your
attention
um see you in crypto