hi everyone i'm chipotle from simon's
institute today i will be talking about
the work on the feasibility of
unclonable encryption and more
this is joint work with prabhanjan fatih
xinjian mark
the talk is about using quantum
information to do some uh something
interesting about cryptography and
perhaps the most fascinating phenomena
about quantum information is the unknown
ability it says a piece of quantum
information cannot be cloned into two
identical copies
this so-called no cloning theorem leads
to a new exciting area about quantum
cryptography which we call unclonable
cryptography
here instead of building and analyzing
the security of classical scheme against
quantum computers we are interested in
what quantum computer can bring us
there are a line of work leveraging
unknown ability including quantum key
distribution and quantum mining
among those one major area is to make
classical cryptosystems unclonable
this security says there's no way
to copy a key or copy identity or even
cipher text this is a way of enhancing
the classical security even further for
example achieving everlasting security
and just like one time pad is the most
fundamental primitive to cryptography
one time symmetric key unclonable
encryption is the simplest yet most
important primitive we should consider
the question was first proposed by
gosman and study by broadband and ward
broadband and lore consider the
following security notion
encryption of a random message is given
to an adversary and this encryption is a
quantum state
the adversary attempts to produce two
cipher texts
and later on keys are revealed the
adversary wings if and only if both
copied cipher text can be used to
recover the original message
birthday and lord show that it is
actually possible either in information
theoretically secure way or in the
random or in the quantum random oracle
model
however this is not the optimum security
as it does not rule out the possibility
that adversary recovers non-trivial
information about the message for
example they can maybe they cannot both
recover the whole message but they can
learn the first bit of the message
simultaneously
and they identify the problem but they
cannot give any security proof even with
stronger assumptions like oracles
and in this word we show that in the
random oracle model the optimum security
can be achieved
the alt the optimum security is defined
with the cpa style that is the chosen
plaintext attack style
in this security game a pair of messages
are chosen by the adversary
an encryption of
one of the message m0 or m1 is given to
an adversary and it attempts to produce
two cipher texts
and later on
um it also
will get the keys and the adversary wins
if and only if it knows which messages
are encrypted
uh
uh independently using the the
encryption and also using the key
the probability should be very close to
half
intuitively it says regardless of what
cloning strategy is used several texts
can only go
one way that is either go the upper pass
or the lower pass and the other
encryption will be completely jumped
and this is our main theorem in the work
we show that there exists an unclonable
encryption scheme in a quantum random
oracle model with optimum security we
just mentioned before
and we also have other results the first
result is to justify our the use of
random oracle we will prove that
unclonable encryption cannot both cannot
simultaneously satisfy
it being information theoretically
secure and also being deterministic in
other words
to achieve the optimum security you need
either
computational assumption or you need the
scheme to be randomized
and we also show applications to copy
protection for point functions
this is everything i want to talk about
today please come to our talk in crypto
2022 thank you