hi everyone i'm ken chung here from uc
berkeley and i'm going to present our
new work oriole challenge proof within
your approval time and this is a joint
to work with
donso
first let me introduce the definition of
dkp
a zeology proof enable prover to
convince the verifier some statement is
true
such diverse proof has three properties
companies funding and zero knowledge
the company needs enables only honest
approval to pass a verification with
property one
some needs enable on this verifier that
did not detect the malicious poor except
for negligible probability
and the knowledge enables
that means that the proof does not make
any information about approval secret
before we go into our work let me
introduce some background information so
here is a list of early stage dkps
this this one general tools require a
transit setup and
their speed is not so good
several years later there is a second
generation of geometry proof
they removed the traffic setup so the
security is much much higher than the
previous one
and they also improve the speed
but the proof size is much larger than
previous one
so
second generation
challenge proof has constantly improved
generation time and in our new work we
further reduce the proof generation time
from crossing india to linear time
at the same time we keep the security
so we don't have trusted setup and we
keep
roughly the same proof size with second
generation
so
in our work we are purely improving the
speed without sacrificing other
parameters
uh here is our technical contribution
and our linear approval comes from a new
expander sampling algorithm this
expander sampling algorithm enables uh
to sample
a fender with a graphic never successful
probability
and such expander enables us to
construct a linear timing called the
linear code which ultimately leads to a
linear time prover
and second kind of second contribution
is non-black box proof composition
and this enables us to further reduce
the verification cost from square root
to log n
and that's all about this short intro
and tension is here and here is
our paper link and the code link
and i'm looking forward to meet you at
crypto