hi
i am dorine riepel and i will give you a
brief overview of our new paper password
authenticated key exchange from group
actions
this is joint work with michelle
abdullah torsten eisenhofer ike kilz and
sabrina kunzweiler
at the same time you can follow our chat
and read a bit more about the story
behind the paper
so let's start
we use group actions as a building block
and more concretely the framework of
cryptographic roof group actions which
is an abstraction that is very close to
the classical diffie-hellman setting
various constructions were already
proposed for example public key
encryption signatures and oblivious
transfer
the most interesting instantiation of
group actions is given by the
commutative super singular isotony div
helmet protocol or short seaside
which is believed to be post quantum
secure
so the final goal is to construct a
password authenticated key exchange
protocol or short peak
such a protocol allows two parties to
agree on a session key based only on the
knowledge of a short low entropy string
for example a password
so here we have alice and bob who both
know the password
and after they exchanged some messages
they will be able to compute a shared
session key
when we talk about security of pake we
consider an adversary mallory who might
try to impersonate bob towards alice
of course mallory can always guess a
password then interact with alice and
see if the guess was correct
this is what we call an online
dictionary attack and this should be the
best attack against each page protocol
since password are basically used
everywhere pig is a nice tool for
practical applications
after an official selection process by
this the cfrg two protocols will now
also be standardized
one of the winners cpace builds upon the
simple password exponential key exchange
short speak
which is also our starting point
in speak the two parties perform a
diffie-hellman key exchange where the
password is used to hash
to a generator of the group
unfortunately this approach does not
work in the seaside setting since we
don't know how to hash into super single
eye sargony graphs
so our next idea was to use a bit a bit
by bit approach using a crs of two
elements
each bit of the password would then
determine which crs element will be used
for a group action diffie-hellman key
exchange
however it turns out that this is also
insufficient and this is due to the fact
that the elliptic curves used in seaside
provide additional structure namely the
twists
using twists one can break the
assumption underlying our protocol and
it also directly translates to an
offline dictionary attack
in our paper we finally present two
different protocols which both solve
this issue
the first uses a commitment so that the
party sending the first message needs to
choose the message in advance and commit
to it
so that the other party cannot use this
information to perform the attack we
identified before
in the second protocol both parties
compute different combinations or cross
terms of the diffie-hellman values
which ensures that they really need to
know the secret
we prove security of the first protocol
based on the gap cdh assumption for
group actions
and the second uses a new assumption
which we call strong square inverse
diffie-hellman
one advantage of this is that the
protocol can still be executed in one
round
we also show how to optimize the
protocols so that they are significantly
more efficient than the only known
previous constructions for seaside
which use oblivious transfer
if you want to know more details about
our new protocols i'll give a longer
talk at crypto on tuesday or just have a
look at the eprint version of our paper
finally i also want to thank luca defeo
for the pun with the twists