hello everyone i'm shaolian i'm here to
give a short overview of our results on
post quantum simulator extraction this
is a joint work with nahui cha
kamingtong and takashi yamakawa
extractable commitments are very basic
and important cryptography primitive it
requires the existence of an extractor
given the malicious commander c star the
extractor talks to the c star it may
potentially rewind sistar but at the end
of the execution the extractor is able
to extract the value m star committed by
the malicious c star
here i want to remark that in the
classical setting this primitive
enjoys some property that we usually
take for granted that is the extractor
is able to not only extract the
committed value m-star it can also
simulate c-star's post-extraction state
this property is particularly important
for protocol composition for classical
protocol this is usually easy to do
because extractor can just pretend to be
the honest receiver to execute the
protocol with systar
and then the extractor can rewind the
system back to the beginning of the
execution and start the extraction
procedure however what if the c star now
is a quantum industry in this setting
simulating c star's post extraction
state turns out to be hard work due to
no cloning theorem we cannot record
start state and rerun it back
now let's take a look at a typical
construction of extractable equipment
to commit a value the commuter first
sample two random strings a1 0 and a11
which export to the message m this
actually forms a sql sharing of the
message m
then the committee repeats this
procedure for n times where the end is a
security parameter
next the commuter commits to these
shares independently
next the receiver symbol run stream of
lens n
the receiver simply sends the random
string c to the committer the commuter
thickness to its initial commitment
according to the receiver's screen c
now let us recall how to extract the
committed value if the computer c is
malicious
our extractor simply sample a new random
string c prime send it to the c star and
learn the corresponding decommitments as
you can see as long as c and c star are
not identical there will be one column
in this matrix where the merger's
committer digmates to both positions in
one column these two decommitments will
allow us to recover the committed
message m
this is how the extractor works in the
classical setting
now let's consider the scenario where
the malicious c star is a quantum
machine
in this case it might be still possible
to extract the committed value m star
using say the techniques developed by
oneru for post quantum proof of
knowledge however it is unclear how we
can simulate the malicious sistar's
post-quantum extraction state
at this moment you're missing that maybe
this construction is not good
if we choose another construction of
extractable equipment maybe we can
extract the committed value while
simulating the c-star's post-extraction
state
however it is worth noting that
this construction is popular for some
reasons for example it makes use of only
minimal assumptions also it is constant
round and makes black box use of all
functions the last two properties are
particularly important for efficiency
concerns
so if you want to find an alternative
construction for extractable component
in the postcolumn setting you may also
want to maintain these advantages
now let's look at the state of the arts
if you want all the properties mentioned
earlier basically there are four known
constructions so far only the last
construction makes black box use of the
underlying primitive and only the second
construction managed to achieve constant
rounds in this column i also show if
these constructions require quantum
power for communication and computation
moreover the first construction is based
on assumptions as strong as oblivious
transfers the second construction is
algebraic assumptions
in particular it requires the existence
of fully homomorphic encryption for
quantum circuits as well as the lw
assumption
so it looks like the current state of
the arts are not satisfactory
actually there is a reason
this problem is hard even if we only
require constant run constructions and
simulatable c stars post extraction
state
the reason is such an extractable column
satisfying only these two properties
would imply constant from zero knowledge
for which we have negative results
due to time limit i want to explain
these conditions for now
if you are interested you can check this
paper in our reference
due to the lower bound mentioned earlier
we cannot achieve all the desired
properties
therefore we choose to imagine a weak
relation for simulation called epsilon
simulation
that is instead of trying to simulate
the post extraction state as tc star
with natural error we now allow a
noticeable error gap more accurately
we require the existence of a simulation
extractor se
sce takes a noticeable function epsilon
as a parameter now we compare two words
the first word is the real execution we
denote stc star as a state of the
malicious committee at the end of the
execution
we use this notion to denote the
transcript which consists of all the
interaction messages between c star and
r
in the real world we concern this tuple
this value denotes the message committed
by c star you can think of it as bonded
in this transcript
the second ball is a simulation
extraction word
this s e talks to c star it can
potentially revamp c star at the end of
the interaction
the xe outputs the tuple which is
supposed to be the simulated
post-extraction state
and the message committed by sistar
we say that a extractable equipment is
epsilon simulatable if these two tuples
are epsilon codes for any noticeable
function if so
i want to remark that
this weaker notion of simulation is
still useful
because epsilon simulation is always
sufficient to imply nd based or
game-based security
here a typical example is that epsilon
simulator zero knowledge already
impressed witness in distinguishability
now we ask a question if we are happy
with this relaxed notion through
simulation can we build extractable
commitments that maintain all the other
advantages
and the answer is yes in this work we
build such an epsilon simulatable
extractable commitment
to execute our protocol their honest
product doesn't need to be quantum but
it is secure against even quantum
malicious committers
as applications our extractable
commitments imply two-party coin housing
zero knowledge argument of knowledge for
np and zero knowledge arguments for qma
and eventually we also obtain secure
two-party computation
all these protocols also enjoy the
advantages shown here
but since our extractable column is only
epsilon simulatable we only manage to
achieve epsilon simultaneous version of
these protocols
if if you are interested please look
forward to our talk at full length here
is information for our talk and you can
also find the full version of our paper
at this link
thank you for your attention