hello everyone i'm takashi from ntt and
kyoto university
this is a short abstract video for our
work content commitments and signatures
without warming functions this is a
joint work with tomoyuki morimai
quantum information is awesome
one of the most surprising applications
of quantum information in the context of
cryptography is the quantum key
distribution proposed by bennett and
brassard in 1984.
this is the information theoretically
secure key exchange protocol using
quantum communication
information theoretically security
exchange is impossible in the classical
world so this changes the landscape of
cryptography
after the invention of quantum key
distribution
people expected that quantum
communication can also be used to
achieve information theoretical security
for other cryptographic primitives
unfortunately however it turns out that
information theoretical security is
impossible even with quantum
communication for many cryptographic
primitives including symmetric and
public key encryption digital signatures
and commitments etc
if information theoretical security is
impossible then the next natural
question is what is the minimal
assumption for these cryptographic
primitives with quantum communication
in the classical world it is known that
the existence of one wave functions is
the minimum assumption for essentially
any non-trivial cryptographic
functionality
so we would like to ask if this is the
same in quantum cryptography that is
our functions necessary for these
premises with quantum communication
in this work
we show that one-way functions may not
be needed for constructing commitment
and one-time signatures with quantum
communication
it is known that commitments imply
general multiparty computations in the
quantum setting so this means that mult
party computations may also be
constructed without warming functions
to show this we construct commitments
and one-time signatures based on the
primitive called pseudo-random quantum
states
which are roughly a quantum analog to
the random generators
recently grechmer showed that in
evidence that pseudo-random quantum
states do not imply the existence of
functions
more precisely he shares an oracle
relative to which pseudo-random quantum
states exists but bqp is equal to qma
which in particular implies that no one
function exists
combining our constructions of
commitment and runtime signatures from
through the random quantum state with
the result of customer we conclude that
there is an oracle right to which
commitments and runtime signatures exist
but no one function exists
the take our message if this work is the
following
one-way functions are not the minimum
assumption for quantum crypto
it is a fascinating future work to
identify what is the minimal assumption
for quantum crypto
for more details of our work please
check our paper or attend my talk at the
first day of the conference
thank you for watching