hello everyone my name is fansung today
i'm happy to introduce our work sheeran
transformation and dishonest majority
npc with tactical sharing this is a
joint work with vipalgoya and antigone
polychroniado
in this work we consider the designs
majority setting and information
theoretic security
to overcome the knowing impossibility
results we consider the preprocessing
model
people talk about this ice majority they
usually assume that all but one party
are corrupted
our motivation is to study an
intermediate case between ice majority
and all parts of one corruption say a
small constant fraction of parties are
honest
this can be motivated by the fact that
protocols that are secure against all
bottom line corruption are less
efficient than protocols in the ice
majority setting
however the requirements of ice majority
can be too strong to be met for
real-world applications
if there is no other majority but a
small constant fraction of parties are
honest can we speed up the protocol in
such a setting
a similar scenario in the ice majority
setting has been well studied in recent
years
in short when we move from the standard
is modality setting to the sub-optimal
cropping that shows we can reduce the
communication complexity by a factor of
n
in the desired majority setting the best
known result speed achieves out of three
times and elements of both preprocessing
data and communication
when moving to the sub sub-optimal
graphing setting
can we reduce the amount of
pre-processing data and online
communication by a factor of n just as
that in the ice majority setting
in this work we answer this question
affirmatively by showing an npc protocol
with overall cost out of c in both the
amount of resetting data and
communication complexity
our idea is to use pax equation rings to
evaluate a single circuit
we rely on two new techniques shearing
transformation and the sparsely packed
chemical sequestering scheme
confidently we consider the following
problem
given two linear sequential schemes and
the linear function
suppose all parties hold a sharing x of
the first equation scheme with secret s
we want to transform it to a sharing y
of the second sequential scheme with
secret fs informally we want to
transform one shearing to another one
and apply a linear function on the
secret
shearing transformation occurs
frequently in determining npc protocols
such as doing degree reduction in vgw
and dn style protocols converting
encodings of secrets when using reverse
multiplication friendly embeddings
performing more permutations and final
operations for secrets of attack
ring
previous solutions achieve linear
communication in the number of parties
only when the same shield transformation
is performed multiple times
this is sufficient for the first two
examples since we need to perform the
same transformation many times
however for the third example each
different permutation or different
pattern of finite operation corresponds
to a different shearing transformation
the efficiency of previous solutions
degrees to being quadratic in the number
of parties
our work gives an efficient sharing
transformation protocol which can
perform out of n differential
transformations with linear amortized
communication complexity in the number
of parties
to achieve our results we first reduced
the problem to repair random shear rings
for different linear sequential schemes
then review the sampling process of each
sequestering scheme as a linear circuit
and use pexip theory to evaluate a batch
of sampling circuits in parallel
our second technique is sparsely packed
the your sharings
our idea is to use different secret
styles to store secrets in different
sharings for example here we may use
positions 1 3 and 5 to store secrets
this is different from the standard
texture machine rings which always use
positions 1 2 and 3 to store secrets
combining these two techniques we show
how to solve network clothing which is
the main difficulty of using tactical
shear rings to evaluate the single
circuits
our work also shows how to relax the
requirement of the field sites achieve
malaysia security and connect to the
standard majority setting
for more details about our techniques
please refer to the full video on our
paper on eprint thank you