hey everyone this is jaspal and today
i'll be giving an overview of our new
work on structural aware private set
intersection
this is a joint work with my co-authors
kaithri garipela and mike roslich at
oregon state university
so let's begin by looking at the
traditional private set intersection
problem
so there are two parties alice and bob
and they both have a set of discrete
points
and they are interested in learning the
set of points that are common to both
their sets
however there is an additional privacy
constraint which states that both the
parties should learn nothing but just
the intersection
which essentially means that bob does
not learn any of the elements of
is set outside the common elements o n r
and s
so this traditional problem of psi has
been well studied in the literature
so let's consider a variant of this
where alice and bob are holding a set of
gps coordinates in and around santa
barbara
and they are interested in learning if
they both have gps locations of any
common locations
now it's extremely unlikely that alice
and bob will have the identical gps
coordinates for a location
more likely cases that they would have
gps coordinates which are pretty nearby
hence we can formulate this problem as a
problem of fuzzy psi
where our goal is to learn the points of
alice and bob which are within some
distance delta for some parameter delta
so one nice way to solve this for cps
problem is to redefine alice's set
as
all the points contained within a delta
radius ball
around all its gps coordinates
and then we essentially run plane psi
between bob's points and alice's
expanded set
traditional psa protocols have
communication complexity proportional to
each party set
so in this case alice's communication
would be proportional to the expanded
set size
which in this case would be union of
delta radius balls
however
unlike plane psi in this case there is
some known structure over alice's input
set it's a union of delta radius balls
the question is can we improve the
communication complexity of psi when
there is a known structure over one of
the parties input sets
so in this work we introduce a new
framework for structure aware private
set intersection
which gives a very viable approach for
doing semi-honest fuzzy psi as mentioned
before
so we give very practical symmetric key
based psi protocols
for the case when alice's input set has
some publicly known structure
in our work we reduce this problem of
structure aware private set intersection
to a new variant of function secret
sharing which we term as weak fss
using this framework we reduce the psa
communication of alice to order lambda
times fss share size where lambda is the
security parameter and fss share size is
the share size for secret sharing the
structured set of values
so this is a considerable improvement
over
just the cardinality of the expanded set
in the cases when the fss share size can
be really small
for structured sets
other than the framework we also give a
number of new fss techniques which
allows us to construct really efficient
weak fss for union of geometric poles
which has applications for fuzzy psi
to learn more about our psa framework
and our new fss techniques you're
welcome to attend my talk at crypto 2022
or read our paper for a of discussion on
all of these techniques thank you