hi everyone this work is entitled
superposition meeting the middle attacks
update on fundamental security of aes
like hushing
the meet in the middle attack was
originally introduced to investigate the
security of multiple encryption schemes
later dynamic meeting the middle attack
was used to discuss pre-image resistance
of block cipher-based hash functions
later the meeting in the middle idea was
used to devise dedicated attacks on hash
functions
in dedicated
meeting the middle text on the
comprehension function typically it is
difficult to find a complete partition
of the message worship so the attacker
only found
two separate subside of the message
words
well all other words are fixed one can
split the computation into two chunks
each chunk can be computed over values
of one subset of the method word and
independently from the other subside
those message words in the subsets are
called neutral word the two chunks are
typically computed forward and backward
independently and end up at a common
state where the results can be paralyzed
matched
several advanced techniques have been
proposed to fund better chunk
separations and to cover more wrongs
in 2011 the meeting the middle pre-image
attack was applied to aes hashing mode
in the attack the neutral words are
directly selected from the encryption
state where the key states are fixed
using initial structure and indirect
indirect departure matching the tag
successfully covers several runs of aes
hashing modes
in the attack published that eurocrypt
2021 the meeting the middle attack was
generalized by removing many artificial
limitations and automatic search were
performed over extended attack spaces
the tag configuration with the phone
list and translate into mixed integer
linear programming models the searching
for the best attacks was reduced into
solving optimization problems and their
constraints in mlp
in this work we enhance this meeting the
middle mlp modeling in several ways
the first point is that different from
the common practice of that oriented
decomposition of the state we propose to
use the superposition state
that is every intermediate state is
reviewed
viewed as the combination of two virtual
states each virtual state carries one
attribute propagation through linear
operations independently of the other
the two virtuous data combined only when
going through the nonlinear operation
a direct advantage of this
representation is the preservation of
the linear combinations
it opens up the possibility of new local
collisions between or within the
encryption and the key state
besides it facilitates the modeling of
various ways of consolidations and
modeling the matching
the next point is allowing the bad
direction attribute propagation and
consolation
it slides the attribute be consumed and
preserve the opposite propagation but it
finally benefits the original
propagation because it might enable a
remote consolation of impact by the
addrent key or what they mixed column
besides its contribute to gun the degree
of matching
the next point is enhancing the meeting
the middle mlp model with gas and
determine which was not integrated into
previous meeting mlt models for
automatic search
the next point is dedicated to the hash
function whirlpool due to the identity
between its encryption and the key
schedule the address key can be moved
easily around the mixed columns using an
equivalent key state which is already
involved in the key schedule
moving forward or stay as it was
one choice might have advantage the
the other choice
at different roles such we integrate the
consideration of both choices into one
model
the
mlp models for searching for pre-image
resistance attack can be directly
transformed to search for collision
attacks of hash functions
and the key recovery attacks on block
ciphers
with the enhancements in the middle mlt
modeling we obtain many updates on the
fundamental security of aes like hash
functions and block ciphers
including the first pre-imagery attack
on seven rounds were pulled and improved
the pre-image and collision attacks the
angle store and the aes hashimoto and
improve the key recovery attacks on
takeable black saver skinny
thanks for your attention