hi everybody
i'm going to present you a giant war
entitlement syndrome recording in the
head shot the signatures from zero
knowledge proofs
in this war we propose a new code-based
signature scheme built from a
zero-knowledge proof
to design this signature we chose to
focus on the syndrome decoding problem
for which cryptanalysis is stable for
many years
then we used the emphasis paradigm to
build a zero knowledge proof of
knowledge for this problem
this paradigm provides a generic method
to build their own knowledge protocols
using techniques from secure multipath
computation
to apply the mps in zl paradigm we need
to have an efficient and pc protocol
that checks
that a vector is a solution of the
syndrome decoding instance
by checking those two relations
the linear relation is easy to check
with mpc
but it is much harder for the constraint
on the handling weight
for this reason
we replace the second constrainer with
an equivalent one involving polynomials
this new constraint consists to prove
the existence of a polynomial fuel such
that
f divides the product sq where
s is a polynomial for which the
evaluations and some public points give
the coordinates of the test vector
and f is the smallest polynomial for we
which has four roots all those
evaluation points
in practice
such polynomial coup can be easily built
from the tested vector
we simply need to take a monique
polynomial of degree w so that the
non-zero position of the tested vector
are encoding as roots
now that we have the exact statement we
want to check
we can use the usual techniques
to build the wanted
mpc protocol
then
we convert this protocol into an
interactive zero knowledge proof of
malay
using the npc in the ad paradigm
finally we applied the fiat charmier
transformation to obtain
the signature scheme
we selected three parameter sets
targeting a security of
128 bits
the two first sets rely on synonym
decoding instance on the binary field
while the third one relies on a single
beginning instance on a larger field
for each parameter set we proposed two
trailers the first one
lowers the communication first
and the second one lowers the
computational cost
let us compare our scheme with the other
code by signature grid from zero
knowledge proofs
we can observe that the obtained
signature size are less than for all the
former schemes
we are the first such schema
which can produce signature size along
the symbolic cup of 10 kilobytes
now
let us compare our schema
with all the other code based signatures
we far we are far to have the shorter
signature
however
our skip outperforms all the signatures
when considering the sum of the size of
the signature and the pubic
to conclude we proposed in this work a
new code-based signature relying on the
syndrome nikoning problem for random
linear codes
and this signature has competitive
performance regarding the current state
of the art
thank you for your attention and see you
on the 16th of august for the complete
talk