[Music]
my objective today is that you should
come out of this talk having an
understanding of how automated bug
finding systems work our bug finding
system deploys two approaches symbolic
execution and coverage guided fuzzing if
you're not familiar with these
approaches we're going to take baby
steps up to them and there's sort of two
running themes there is how do we layout
the system so that if you know a fancy
new bug signing approach comes along we
can integrate it and how can we kind of
architect it all to work so that we can
take independent bug finding systems and
actually get them to cooperate even if
the systems weren't designed to
cooperate in the first place so before
we get into this let's have a bit of
history we created Cyberdyne for the
DARPA cyber grand challenge this was a
multi-year competition there was seven
finalists we weren't one of the
finalists however Cyberdyne itself was
the bug finding system in the team that
placed force the cyber grand challenge
it is a capture the flag competition
this means that you have a number of
competitors and they are given binary
programs they know nothing about these
programs ahead of time they have to
discover bugs in these programs they
have to develop exploits for these bugs
and they also need to patch the programs
so that they are invulnerable to these
bugs and the interesting thing about the
DARPA cyber Grand Challenge is that the
competitors themselves are machines
there is no human intervention they have
to do this all automatically and the way
they score points is that they actually
attack each other when you develop an
exploit
you attack competitor the attack works
on their patched binaries if your attack
succeeds you get points if you're
patched binaries perform well you get
points and so the competition itself it
really shaped the design of Cyberdyne
you know it had to be an automated
system it has to be able to find bugs on
its own
it had to be robust against you know any
type of program we didn't know what type
of programs would get ahead of time
obviously no human intervention and one
of the things that it actually had to do
is scale in the final event we had a
large cluster of computers available to
us and we want to make Matt like really
maximize a usage of those computers so
let's go see how we laid out Cyberdyne
you know what is what is a bug finding
system in general look like Cyberdyne is
the running example and so I'll always
tie it back to that but I will also talk
about more generic tools that are
available so our goal with with creating
a bug finding system is that you know it
should actually find bugs you know
otherwise it's not a bug finding system
it's just a system it should work on
real programs and most importantly it
should scale and I have a few
definitions for what I mean by
scalability first it should scale to
real programs big programs you know it
shouldn't just get stuck trying to find
bugs at the beginning of a program when
really those bugs are somewhere deep in
the execution the other idea I have for
scalability is that you should be able
to take advantage of as many cpu
resources as you are given you know
first you should be able to take
advantage of one computer and I mean
complete advantage of one computer and
once you can prove to me that you can
use one computer effectively then you
can have two and more and so we want to
develop system that can actually scale
out to as many computers as you
as you have available to you and it
should just work on big programs so
we're going to actually work up to what
a bug finding system in a large works
looks like we're going to start small in
fact we're going to smart with start
with a very simple fuzzing setup if
you're not familiar with fuzzing then
the idea is this you have a program it
has been written in such a way that it
is expecting good valid input it's not
expecting arbitrary input random input
and so it's possible that this program
will just crash if you give it random
input but random input itself is usually
not a very good way to find kind of deep
bugs in a program to find logic bugs in
the program and so ideally you want to
give it mostly valid inputs like inputs
that get the program into sort of a deep
programs state and then you give it
something slightly unexpected and so the
way you a simple way of going about
doing this is with something called a
mutation engine it takes these realistic
inputs or real inputs and then it just
starts a flipping bits or flipping bytes
it does a number of operations on those
inputs and the hope is that when you've
sort of corrupted these valid inputs
something interesting is going to happen
and if you don't feel like creating a
mutation engine on your own there's some
really really great ones out there for
danza's one of them we actually use it
in Cyberdyne as these off is another one
so this is sort of the process of a
simple fuzzing campaign we need eight
inputs you know this we can do as many
mutations as we want generate millions
or billions of inputs and we spend a bit
of time doing this we can execute those
inputs hopefully one of these inputs or
more than is going to cause crash we
don't really know though and luckily
these two steps they can be done
concurrently you know we can
we can very easily scale the mutation
execution they're completely independent
tasks and so we're waiting we're waiting
hopefully bugs are going to find a fall
out you know that's the whole point of
this of this fuzzing campaign but what
if bugs don't fall out you know we we've
wasted our time or we might have wasted
our time
those GPU resources we can't we didn't
we have no way of really justifying our
use and the problem is that you know
this simple bug signing set up with
sizing there was no accountability we
didn't have a metric to show that our
bug signing process was actually making
progress you know if you think of
deploying a fuzzing campaign into the
cloud you should be able to justify at
the end of the day that it has made
progress that you are potentially
getting closer to finding a bug and so
the sort of most common way of measuring
progress is to kind of ask yourself has
something new happened have we created a
mutated input that has generated some
new event that we can measure and the
sort of industry-wide and academia wide
approach to this is called code coverage
it's also you know there's other ways of
doing it like branch coverage but the
basic idea is we have produced an input
that causes you know some line or some
instruction of code to be executed that
no other input has executed before and
you know this is great you know we can
now run our fuzzing campaign we can
measure code coverage we can produce a
fancy little graph that shows like okay
we got code coverage we got more code
coverage we got more code coverage now
we've got this accountability but
eventually we're going to see decreasing
marginal returns the code coverage you
know it might just sort of top out and
go flat and then we're stuck twiddling
our thumbs again like before we're not
showing progress and so the most common
way of getting around this
is to use something called coverage
guided fuzzing and so the idealist
coverage guided fuzzing is we say okay
we've got this metric this metric says
that some input has has caused a new
event happened that must be an
interesting input so let's send it back
around send it back into the fuzzer and
tell the fuzzer to start mutating that
input and I think the best analogy for
why this is a useful approach is hill
climbing you know the we started with a
seed input we mutated it it got new code
coverage it's kind of like we we went up
some steps and now we want to go higher
up on the mountain and so we mutated
again and hopefully we're going to build
on the progress that we got based on the
first mutation and so this simple set up
we've got that original kind of pipeline
take inputs mutate them execute them
hopefully crashes fall out otherwise
measure code coverage send them back
around there is a great open source tool
for that already does this for you it's
called ASL I believe that if possible it
should be integrated into sort of your
daily testing system or your weekly
testing system it can be put into a
continuous integration system it is
great try to use it
so in Cyberdyne we sort of taken this
coverage guided fuzzing layout and we're
just extending it we've done a few
things differently for example that
small fuzzing pipeline we've got a mini
loop in there and we do a lot of that
stuff sort of in line in a single
program and we've tried to do it all in
sort of a scalable way that we can kind
of just run in parallel so let's
actually see how we took just this
simple coverage adding fuzzing
architecture and started extending it
let's let's sort of look into the skin
of Cyberdyne
this is sort of our layout now we've got
the buzzer
it's called ger this is an open-source
tool you can find it on github comm
slash drill a bit slash ger grr
not to be confused with Google rapid
response and what ger does is it just
takes inputs mutates them runs them
calculates code coverage and it does
this with really high throughput it Emil
eights all i/o in memory and it can
repeatedly spawn sort of emulated
processes just over and over and over
it's able to skip lots of redundant set
up code very easy to scale you just run
mordor's the one thing it doesn't do is
it doesn't do orchestration like AFL
does it is just sort of a cog in this
larger machine the next thing that we
have is paisa menu it is a binary
symbolic executor it is slightly harder
to scale most symbolic executors are I'm
going to go into sort of the scalability
challenges of symbolic executors later
but it's possible to do this and this is
a you know it's a simple program it's
written in Python and we will be
releasing a variant of it in the first
quarter of 2017 the last sort of tool
that we integrated into the system it's
a completely third-party tool that came
out of academia
it's called Klee it's hard to use
there's never been a time where I felt
like my investment into modifying it was
worth it but but you know it can
sometimes find bugs and hard to scale
and so I'm just not going to talk about
again I can complain about it offline
and so the next system is what I call
the Oracle and we have all these bug
finding tools they you know they're
independent they're not really
communicating with each other they feed
into
basically your operating system where
you're just running the input on the
program hopefully if you're crashing
inputs will fall out if they don't fall
out then you send the non crashing
inputs off to the inset and so this
means that is is exactly that coverage
coverage meant measuring system before
and it is the key to cooperation the key
to making it possible for completely
independent bug tools to actually work
together and we're going to see why this
is later so let's go down to a bit lower
level into our system to start by
looking at the min set and how its
enabling collaboration the min set
itself stands for the minimum set of
inputs that produce the maximum amount
of code coverage and we want to minimize
the set of inputs that produce code
coverage because the fewer inputs you
have supplies to seed to analyze the
more resources you can bring to bear for
input if you have a lot of computational
resources great maybe you want to have
bigger sets of code coverage producing
inputs but sometimes you know you're
like me might only have your laptop and
you want to run the system the purpose
of it though as we said before is just
to identify these interesting inputs
they get your code coverage they're
interesting we send them back around and
so I'm going to show you the process of
how the min set works we're going to
start with just four inputs let's say
they've come from the fuzzer
and so there were originally some nice
program inputs and we've mutated them so
we have the first input it comes into
the min set we try to measure it for
code coverage as the first input being
measured it's sort of setting the
baseline of code coverage so it's
guaranteed entry into the min side and
we can see by that sort of white that
red circle up there that is sort of a an
image representing what the code
coverage
produced by the first input is if we run
the second input it comes through we
measure it for coverage and we compare
that coverage to the first input and we
can see that we've got substantially
more code coverage than the first input
got us you know when we ran the second
input a lot more code was executed you
know we we we touched a lot more we got
a lot more programmed state to be
explored and so we add it to the min set
the third input we run it and it got
more coverage than the first but the
total code coverage that we measured for
the third input is subsumed by the first
in the second inputs and so we're
actually going to kick that out of
lumens we're just not going to include
it and you know this is this is
something where you know it's adding
stuff into the min set it's a heuristic
and so you run the risk of throwing
interesting things out but the idea is
that hopefully we're eventually we're
going to keep the most interesting
things in and then finally we get to the
fourth input it gets us new code
coverage above and beyond all the others
you know it goes out that way
and you know this is great we've we've
taken four inputs and we compress them
down into three inputs but there's a few
problems here
there can be redundancy in the min set
and one of the sort of ways you can
think about this is you know over time
we're doing that sort of stair stepping
where we're trying to increase our
coverage we're trying to walk higher up
this mountain and so what if when we get
up to say you know a certain a certain
height a certain amount of code coverage
what if you know all that coverage
covered kind of something that an
earlier case did we saw that with input
to it got a huge amount of code coverage
and it included the code coverage that
input one got us and so actually input
one is now redundant but it but it's in
arm inside the other problem again with
input one is it's at the base line of
code coverage you know we guarantee
heed entry into the mint set of the
first input we tested what if that input
is just totally uninteresting what if it
just quickly exits the program you know
we have now sent this input back around
our cycle we were dedicating CPU
resources to it and it might not be you
know getting us to any interesting state
it might be bringing us further from
interesting program states and so that
is a problem so the idea is actually you
know we've created this minimal set of
inputs that have produced the maximum
amount of code coverage we need to
compress it we need to even make it
smaller when we want to remove the
redundancy and the idea on doing this I
think the simplest way to do this is to
sort of fold them in set over on itself
let's reconstruct it and do it sort of
in a reverse order there's other there's
other orders to do it but reverse is
simplest to see so we had added inputs
one two and four to the min set so let's
flip them around let's start with input
four we're going to run it through the
program we're going to measure its
coverage because it's the first thing
we're measuring it's setting the
baseline and so I think a simple way of
deciding that you know just flipping it
around is the right approach is that the
most recently produced input input for
is probably one of the ones that gets us
the deepest in the program so let's use
that as our baseline we run the second
input again it gets us a lot of code
coverage so we're going to add it into
this new folded min set that's great and
now we run the first input that one set
the original baseline it might have been
very uninteresting and it doesn't get us
in your code coverage when we compare it
to one two four and two and so now we
can kick it out we've shrunk the size of
our min set and now that gets us more
resources like fuzzing resources
mutation resources that we can apply to
the smaller set of inputs
there's a few things though that I've
kind of shoved under the rug you know
code coverage I've said let's just
measure code coverage it's great how you
measure this and what you measure is
very important and it can be really
finicky actually you can have
coarse-grained measurements and you can
have fine grain measurements in my
experience of coarse grain measurement
like you know measuring basic blocks
executed measuring functions executed
these can be okay if what you want to
find is shallow bugs you know if the
coarser grained the measurement you have
the smaller humans that's going to be
the more redundant you discover but if
you have a small min set you have you
know more fuzzers per per input in the
mid set you have more static analysis
more symbolic execution and so more
resources you have it's just a
brute-force problem more things going to
fall out if you have a very fine grained
metric like branch coverage or the last
n branches then you're going to have a
bigger min set and this is you know this
can be good and it can be bad if you've
got lots of you know if you've got a big
cluster availability available to you
then great and sometimes and this was
the case in the DARPA Cyber grand
challenge you you don't know what
program you're going to be operating on
ahead of time you know if you're doing
like a code audit you can start to
tailor your coverage metric to that
program and that's usually a good idea
but in the case of the cyber Grand
Challenge we didn't know what programs
we were getting ahead of time it's just
whatever DARPA sends us and so you know
there is no one-size-fits-all code
coverage metric sometimes we want to
measure one feature like branch coverage
another time we want we might want to
measure a different feature like you
know the depth of the call stack or what
what call stacks we've seen and in fact
maybe at the beginning we want just a
coarse-grained measurement we want to
see if we can shake out these these you
know shallow bugs because we just need
to find an exploit and maybe there's an
exploit early on in the program
and so one way that you can go about
this is that you can just measure all
the things at once and the more things
you measure the more fine-grained metric
becomes the bigger you min sets and the
more resources you need another approach
that you can do and this is what we did
in which have a grand challenge is that
you can change how you measure coverage
over time if we want to start by
measuring feature one like branch
coverage we can do that for a little
while and then maybe we want to say of
those inputs that we have in our min set
which ones you know you know execute
certain call stacks which ones get us
this other metric maximize this other
metric and so that's where this folding
process sort of comes in and it's really
nice we can build one min set with one
metric folded over with the other metric
and we can just sort of do this at
regular intervals it can be over the
course minutes of the course of hours or
over the course of days and so the nice
thing to see here is that you know we we
had the min set as the sort of
gatekeeper of what goes around to the
other bug finding systems and it really
didn't care who was sending inputs it
could be the father sending it inputs it
could be a symbolic executor sending
inputs it doesn't care and so there's no
sort of collaboration problems with the
min set it's not actually finding bugs
it's just filtering out inputs and so
the real challenge with making a bug
finding system that is automated is
plugging in tools you know if if we
suddenly there's a new open source tool
that's great it finds bugs we want to be
able to plug it in even though it was
never designed for our system and so we
need to find a way to integrate these
things the min set is sending good
inputs around how do we give those good
inputs to other programs the easiest is
the father so here's an example where
we're going to see
the symbolic eggs here it's going to
produce an input it's going to go around
we're going to see it first you're going
to talk more about symbolic institution
later but to start off with we have an
input those S's in the input represent
symbols the sort of simplest way to
think of this is that that initial input
with the SS they really represent any
possible input that could be anything
and it is the symbolic executor that
discovers a kind of instantiation of
that file it discovers that you know one
of these sort of initial inputs can be
this sort of blue input and it can spit
out lots and lots of inputs it discovers
lots of inputs and so we see that the
Simplot goes through our system we
measure it for coverage and let's just
say it's added to our min set and so we
send it around it goes into the fuzzer
the fuzzer is going to run its mutaters
it's going to mutate them and then we're
going to see mutated inputs come in
we've got little squares on that
representing the mutations it passes
through goes into our min set this is
great we have now gotten collaboration
but you know collaborate collaborating
with a fuzzer it's trivial buzzers they
don't care who sends them inputs they
don't care where their seed inputs come
from so you know integrating third party
fuzzers into your system integrating
third party mutaters it's pretty trivial
but what if we want to send that input
to a symbolic executor you know before
we had that executor taking files that
could represent anything and now we're
giving in a file that's only one thing
how do we make the symbolic executor
work with some sort of arbitrary inputs
and I've said that integrating third
party tools can be challenging and
integrating symbolic executors in
particular and making them cooperate is
challenging and the way we went about it
is what I thought was the simplest
approach you know you just say here's
part of an input
the rest of it do your normal thing
treat it a symbolic and this is very
simplistic but I'm going to try to
convince you that this simple approach
is the right approach because symbolic
executors themselves there they're not
easy to work with they're they're not
simple programs they are monolithic they
they do a lot of things internally and
we want to fit them in and and in fact
they're not the easiest programs to
scale there's lots of scalability
challenges in them and so if we can
integrate them in the simplest way
possible then then then we can kind of
break through these scaling barriers we
can take a problem in the case of
symbolic execution that is really really
hard and we can sort of turn it into a
trivially parallelizable problem we can
take we can just run independent
symbolic executors and make them work
and that's going to be our our way of
scaling them up and so let's let's go
learn about symbolic acute execution at
a pretty high level and see where the
scalability challenges are with it and
hopefully this will justify why our
simplistic solution of sending in
partial inputs is the easiest path to
scalability so symbolic executors I said
they take in these files fill up Isis
full of symbols these these initial
inputs these symbols could represent
anything you don't know what they
represent ahead of time and so over time
the symbolic executor is going through
the program it's sort of emulating the
execution of the program and every time
it comes to a branch like an
if-then-else branch it says okay I want
to explore both paths down the true path
the condition tested must be true so
let's log that condition
let's assert that it must be true and
down a false path let's just assert that
it must be false and so it's going to
try to fork and and explore I'm going to
make concrete
sample of this so you can see and I said
that pison mu our symbolic executor is
binary is a binary symbolic executor it
works on program binaries and so this is
sort of similar to just a real program
it's just a CPU emulator a bit of a
special one it's got registers it's got
memory and it operates on bytes as well
as on symbols and sort of these
expressions of symbols if we have two
symbolic input bytes and we add them
together that is a symbolic expression
it's it's as an emulator it's just got
software implementations of every
instruction or every practical
instruction that most programs use in
the case of Pi so menu we've got
implementations of most x86 and AMD 64
instructions so let's see an actual
concrete example this is a picture from
the great disassembler binary ninja
check it out it's usable and it's fast
and up there this is actually it's sort
of intermediate representation for some
x86 code what we're seeing is we read in
an input symbol it could be anything
we're going to compare it against 10 and
so what I want you to think about is if
you're familiar with the C language or
Java or something we have a switch
statement it's basically a whole bunch
of v analysis and we have ten possible
cases in this or nine possible cases in
the switch statement okay zero do this
case one do this cetera etc all the way
up to case nine and so we want to say
okay we've got this input and it should
match one of the cases so we're going
going to compare it to the upper bound
of ten if if it's greater than or equal
to ten
we've got the false branch we're just
going to return from the function
it's an unhandled case otherwise we're
going to go down the false branch and we
are going to jump to the
code that handles this case so our input
symbol is an index into a table that is
telling us where the code is that
handles the case so let's see what the
symbolic eggs here is going to do on
this code it's going to fork it's going
to say okay we've got this input symbol
we've stored it in EAX we now do a
conditional branch on EAX down the path
here on your left we see that the value
is greater than or equal to 10 and so
the possible values of that input symbol
are anywhere from 10 to 2 to the power
of 32 or 2 to the power of 31 you know
all those positive numbers in that 32
bit range and down the path on your
right we see that you know this is this
is the case where we're going to handle
our 10 possible indexes but there's
something that's funny about this you
know we're actually handling negative
numbers as well as our 0 1 2 up to 9 you
know this is where we're saying let's go
handle one of the cases and we see that
the constraints are are bringing in this
sort of corner case that we didn't
originally think about when you
programmed this and so again the next
step of the symbolic executors fork you
know on that original path where we
where we were out of bounds on the case
we just return we don't care about it
that's like an early exit of our program
but down this other path we now have to
fork to handle all the cases and more
you know we can handle each of those 10
cases but what about that big negative
range where are we going to jump in our
program we don't know you know that's
undefined behavior that is GABA bleah
going to be a bug and so what we can
kind of see here is that you know we're
going to fork a lot you know how many
how many possible places could that jump
has gone not just 10 it could have gone
to 2 to the power of 31
or number of cases it can go anywhere
and so this is really the scalability
challenge of symbolic execution is it's
going to fork and fork and fork you've
got a bunch of branches
let's fork down them if you've got a
loop every time around the loop that's a
fork branches and loops you know this is
going to really explode and so the
problem that you have with these
symbolic executors is that it's hard to
get them deep into a program you know
they're monolithic they they have been
they're kind of they're doing all sorts
of complicated stuff
and a lot of times they will implement
implement different heuristics that that
the implementers hoped would get them
deep in a program one of those is like
the symbolic executor could follow the
Forks that get them new coverage but
these are religious band-aids you know
you can throw a number of PhD students
at this and they'll produce theses for
their favorite metrics but not going to
solve the fundamental problem and in
fact I would say there is no solution or
no generic solution to this problem it's
a my my my idea is like let's just let's
just skip over this problem let's sweep
it under the rug let's pretend it
doesn't exist and let's find a way to
sort of massage the symbolic executors
to do what we want and so that's where
that initial picture got us we said
let's just take an input let's chop off
part of it treat the rest of symbolic
send it into the symbolic executor this
is now a trivially parallelizable
problem we haven't solved the
fundamental scalability problem of
symbolic execution but we have found a
way to jump the symbolic executors
deeper into the program you know maybe
it's going to explore sort of shallowly
there there but it's still deeper it's
still got access to more program State
this is an improvement there's a number
of different ways that we can you know
we've got new heuristics to choose where
to jump in but that's something that you
can kind of tune to the program in your
analyzing and so we're finally coming to
the end and we've seen the high-level
architecture of
five or nine we can see now the sort of
communication around the system we've
got the symbolic executors there's the
initial one that's taking completely
symbolic in but producing outputs
there's sort of these partial symbolic
executors and that's our approach is
sort of massaging symbolic execution
into a trivially parallelizable problem
and it's taking partial inputs sending
things out these inputs they're all
going around they're being exposed and
we've now got collaboration where there
was none before we've taken independent
things they are working together and
they don't even realize that they're
working together and this is the nice
thing about this approach so what we've
seen is that we started with a very
simple fuzzing campaign setup we started
with just taking seed inputs we mutate
them we hope to we hope that crashes
will follow the other end and then we
observed that the problem was that we
could just spend our whole lives waiting
for those to find bugs and we would
never know if progress was being made so
we tried to find a way to sort of make
these systems accountable we tried to
find a way of measuring progress and we
use sort of the industry standard code
coverage metric there's lots of ways in
my dream code coverage there's lots of
different metrics that we can use but
we've now got a way of measuring
progress we integrated that into a kind
of a higher level approach where we
added this cycle coverage guided fuzzing
and that gets us sort of more you know
more inputs it's it's a it's a system
that's hopefully always pushing the
boundaries the min set the thing that
the service set measures code coverage
it was the key to distilling a corpus it
was the key to deciding what we send
around and then we saw that we could
start adding independent tools the
fuzzer it collaborates with anyone then
we had the symbolic executors and we
wanted to find a way to make those scale
even
so fundamentally they're hard to scale
so we took the simplest approach we made
we just ran multiple symbolic executors
we turned a hard problem into a
trivially parallelizable problem and so
now you've kind of seen how you can
architect a bug finding system it's
simpler than you think you can take AFL
and you can add to it you can make your
own system and add ASL to it when
academia publishes their new fancy bug
finding system you just add it on to
this and you find a way to send your it
like to take your inputs send them in
add this collaboration and so Cyberdyne
finds bugs now you can - i'm beauty
ribbon thanks for listening to talk
[Applause]
[Music]