[Music]
all right good morning everyone thanks
once again for having me here at counter
measure as Corrine mentioned this is my
third time presenting here and it's
event I always really look forward to
every year so I'm excited to share this
presentation with you all so we're going
to be talking about IOT s we're going to
be talking about threat data and threat
intelligence and my perspective on it
and how that's evolved over the years
but by way of quick background and I
will try not to repeat the same ground
that Kareem discovered I live in
Alexandria Virginia so just outside of
the DC area I've been there for about 13
years now just kind of an anomaly
very few people it's a very transient
area a lot of people move in and out as
they do contracting work for the
government or for businesses set there
but I've been there for over a decade
now I was at PricewaterhouseCoopers for
about five years
as a consultant first in their federal
practice then in their private sector
technology and security practice
primarily doing security assessments
penetration testing application security
testing and just the whole variety of
one-off things that you get asked to do
when you're a technical consultant
focused on security in the big four I
then spent six more years as a
consultant that mandiant left there as a
technical director and lead for their
Incident Response practice that's where
I kind of shifted from focusing on
offense to defense and investigations
and forensics and primarily led a lot of
Investigations for nation-state attacks
targeted intrusion cases and the like
and for the last year and a half or so
I've been with Danian where I both work
with our product team on helping build
and shape what we do in the security
space as well as run an internal team
that does a mixture of engineering and
consulting type work I'm a contributing
author to Incident Response to computer
forensics I wrote the investigating
Windows portion of that couple years ago
and as Krim mentioned that was a tech
consultant for last season of mr. robot
and I'm currently working with the
production writing team on season three
actually right now every night pretty
much
so let's go back to 2010 in 2010 I was
doing a presentation at mitre I believe
about indicators of compromise and this
was a couple years into my tenure at
mandiant and we were talking about the
need to have an ioc format to have an
indicator of compromise format because
we were plagued with this challenge of
inefficient and unsuccessful information
sharing about threats and so the thing
we ballon was that everyone had been
sharing threat data in these flat static
really brittle lists of hashes and IPS
that had no context no grouping no
intelligence and indicator of compromise
formats like open IOC we're going to
magically fix all of these problems and
the goal of IOC s as opposed to just
flat unstructured data was to produce
human readable and yet machine
consumable forms of threat data to
expand the widths or breadth of the
types of forensic artifacts that we were
going to share and capture and to
provide more context around groupings of
observables rather than just provide
lists with no information about how they
related or what they actually meant to
do better than signatures in short and
so you fast forward six years to now and
we've got a whole multitude of different
standards for different levels and ways
of expressing threat indicators
everything from cybox to Yarra Open IOC
sticks and then we've got a equal
actually a much greater number of
organisations both private and public
dedicated to distributing sharing
generating threat indicators in the US
we have quite a few that are industry
vertical align so you've got like FSI
sack for the Financial Services Group
div I sack for the defense industrial
base and then alongside with that
there's more and more government
agencies across all the major Western
nations that are working with private
sector to foster information sharing and
that public-private exchange and so with
all of this what is information sharing
and I OCS look like in 2016 and I just
took snippets from five or six different
IOC sets from some of the major
organizations that share them and I
this is going to be small back there but
hopefully you can at least see one thing
which is the shape of this data it is
flat lists of hashes and IP addresses
they happen to be in an IOC format but
it's the exact same thing that we were
trying to get away from and I find that
really interesting and part of what I
wanted to talk about today is why is
that why is that that we've invested so
much time and effort and money in
creating these codified formats the
threats share and capture threat data
and yet we're still basically doing the
exact same thing and as part of that
perspective my own viewpoint has evolved
just as I've changed roles and jobs when
I was an investigator I spend a lot of
time designing and testing and even
building mechanisms mechanisms to
automatically generate IOC s for both
proactive and reactive hunting but in
kind of a context of expert teams that
do this day in and day out for the last
two years I've been more of a builder
role where I'm really thinking more
about working with organizations that
are trying to take on this capability
themselves or integrate this capability
through third-party sources like
third-party threat streams and it's
really eye-opening to see a lot of the
challenges that organizations face as
they take in and buy these threat
streams and what they're actually
finding they get as a return on
investment than that just as the show of
hands here how many of you work for an
organization that is currently paying
money for third party threat data see a
few hands I know we've got a decent
number of folks in government here how
many of you are actually producing
threat data to share among your peers or
private private public sector I see one
hesitant hand at least yeah this is
still really young right this is still
evolving and this is part of why I
wanted to put this presentation together
because I think we're at an inflection
point where people are making really
important decisions about where they
invest in what they build and what they
share and it's across that backdrop that
I wanted to provide some of this
perspective and really what I'm seeing
is that there has been an erosion of
indicator based threat detection and
part of that is just reality versus
expectations and resetting what we
actually think we're going to get out of
threat data
it begins with brittle indicators that
are much much less flexible than we hope
they would be and have a much
shorter effective shelf life poor
quality control I'm going to talk a
little bit about what you actually get
when you pay for some of these so-called
professional threat feed services the
challenge of building effective
homegrown I OCS building good threat
data yourself is far harder than I think
I even appreciate it a couple of years
ago inconsistencies in the tools that
apply threat data and this is
particularly salient for endpoint
because endpoint tends to be a little
more complex in terms of the sheer scope
of observables that you're trying to
ingest and handle and map against the
state of an endpoint system so we'll
talk about that applying IOC s22 limited
a scope of data meaning you can have the
best intelligence in the world but if
you're applying it through a peephole in
your environment you're going to miss a
whole lot of stuff and so these are some
of the challenges we're going to talk
about before we talk about some ways to
actually do better and we'll begin with
why I OCS are brittle now I touched on
some of these points earlier but I want
to qualify one thing first and that's
really a terminology thing that I will
probably be guilty of violating in this
presentation but it's important to lay
this out so IO sees versus threat data
versus intelligence IO CSR structured
threat data threat data is not the same
as threat intelligence threat data are
the technical observables like an IP or
a hash or a registry key threat
intelligence is context analysis about a
collection of observables a collection
of VOCs along with who and how they are
being used by a threat actor threat
intelligence is really important to help
make risk-based decisions about attacks
and incidents and what you need to worry
about but I will also argue that threat
intelligence is ineffective without high
quality threat data that accompanies it
you can spend every single day of the
year reading PDFs of white papers by
CrowdStrike and fireEye and Cisco and
every other vendor that puts out this is
the latest threat group you need to
worry about this is what I don't know
fancy bear or sad panda or party parrot
or apt 38 is doing but you're never
going to make yourself more secure
you're never going to operationalize a
PDF of data across all of your
environments at the pace or cadence you
need to so quality threat data is
absolutely necessary for all that
context
intelligence to actually be useful so
let's look at the DB IR from last year I
think I'm seeing a trend here that it's
like obligatory to have at least one DB
IR slide so this is mine
most shared IOC types and this is
probably going to be a bit small in the
back of the room but I'll tell you that
the numbers here show that IP addresses
file hashes and DNS names are the most
common across every single information
sharing group both private and public
that Verizon DB are tracked in 2015 if
you go to the apt notes data set this is
kind of an interesting data set for
unstructured threat data it lives on
github and it's basically a compilation
of every single threat report that every
security vendor puts out they have
hundreds and hundreds of these and
they've extracted out all of the data
into one spot and so I ran some numbers
and found like you know how many host
names are in here how many URLs and if
you look at the graphs again the vast
majority of the data being shared in
these reports are hashes file names IP
addresses DNS names and URLs so we are
sharing the same really brittle static
data that we all know as industry
practitioners changes incredibly fast
the lifespan of a malware hash is
incredibly short the lifespan of a c2 IP
address is incredibly short and that is
all we continue to share and what I also
find interesting is that we seem to be
pursuing this notion and I think this is
coming from a lot of the anti-malware
companies out there that we're going to
solve this problem with the cloud and
more rapid analysis and big data and so
I did some digging in history and found
out wanted to see like what were we
doing seven or eight years ago so seven
or eight years ago actually as far as 10
years ago bit 9 was tracking four
billion unique executable files dll's
drivers and adding about 50 million
entries per day that's in 2007 2009
McAfee launches their global threat
intelligence initiative and is claiming
to track 140 million IP addresses and do
50 million file lookups per day in 2011
Symantec talked about tracking tens of
billions of linkages between users files
and websites and clearly we haven't had
a single impactful breach
from 2009 till today with all of this
great data at our disposal so if
billions and billions of these things
didn't solve the problem five or six
years ago there's no way in hell it's
going to make a difference now and so I
am really skeptical when I see a lot of
the practitioners and security espousing
that there is going to be an
intelligence led revolution in how we
handle information security because I
think and I'll talk later about how I
OCS and threat data are really important
as part of an ecosystem but to make this
notion that intelligence-led security is
going to change everything
belies the fact that we were saying the
exact same thing seven years ago the
quote on the left here is from David
Walt at McAfee and I'm not picking on
him or McAfee as you know being the only
one saying this but this is a history
lesson seven years ago McAfee is talking
about revolutionising security with
global threat intelligence and this vast
network of sensors and threat data and
then in 2016 at fireEye he's saying the
exact same thing and intelligence-led
approach is going to help us predict
attacks it didn't then and it's really
not going to change things now so with
that in mind let's talk about whether
what you're paying for in terms of
threat data is actually effective I work
with a lot of organizations that have
looked at the paid feeds and the free
feeds and I'll often get the question of
like is there a market difference in
quality between paid and free and the
answer usually is yes a lot of the free
feeds out there like you know if you go
to a site like hail a taxi you're going
to see a really really poor
signal-to-noise ratio but what I found
disappointing is I started to dig into
this is the sheer lack of quality that
you'll actually find in most of the
major threat intelligence sources that
you can subscribe to I'm not going to
name any names here I'm not going to
call attention to one vendor because
it's actually a complicated problem to
solve but I actually want to show you
some examples and get you thinking about
the fundamental question here which is
if you are paying for feeds or if you're
thinking about it in the future how are
you going to assess data quality in that
feed there's a quote here from analyst
at ESG from last year 2015 where he
tried to survey this and found 74
percent of professionals in our industry
said it was extremely difficult to
determine the quality and efficacy
of an individual threat intelligence
feed and I don't see that changing
anytime soon so my incredibly
non-scientific methodology for this was
to choose two top tier so I would say
like if you were to do Magic Quadrant
they'd be all the way in the top right
leading threat intelligence services I
grabbed the most recent twenty
indicators from each and I spent 15
minutes looking at them this was
literally all I did so from my
incredibly scientific sampling approach
here let's look at what I found like the
second indicator I found and this is
actually a very common pattern in a lot
of threatened Health Services is hashing
or taking the malware hash and grouping
it in an and block with a file name so
if you've ever looked at open IOC you
have this notion of logic trees and ORS
and ants when you and the hash with a
file name it means that the indicator
will never ever match unless the hash
and the file name are both set exactly
as expressed in the indicator well
that's silly right like if I have the
hash who cares what the file name is I
mean the whole point of the hash is to
reliably fingerprint the file regardless
of what its name is by ending it with
the file name I've just basically
guaranteed that this indicator is far
more brittle than it already would be
and that is in a paid feed I like this
one this probably came out of a sandbox
and never had a set of eyeballs on it so
this is a link file and the and the
block here has the link file name the
size and the hashes all grouped together
so for this IOC to hit you have to have
a link file with this size and those
hashes
if you've ever done windows forensics
you'll know that a link file inside it
contains a bunch of metadata including
the volume gooood of the file path that
it's pointing to that volume gooood will
never exist on any other system except
what produce the link file in the first
place so this IOC will never match on
any other box in the universe except the
sandbox that spit it out the first time
these indicators are both again open IOC
format and if you've ever done any work
with Python or PI 2 windows or PI 2 XE
type stuff you've probably seen like the
win32 Python PYD files that you get as
artifacts of that and what happens
probably here is that there was a
malware sample that used Python to exe
or some
work that allowed Python code to run in
Windows and so we have legitimate
components of Python libraries here with
hashes that you would find in lots of
developer systems because these are
legit files but their artifacts probably
of some malware that happened to use
these same dependencies so this is
basically tantamount to taking a
legitimate Windows DLL and shoving it in
ISC
and so I look at this and then I'm
really horrified when I hear people
talking about you know automatically
triggering remediation actions when an
IOC matches we've all seen what happens
when an AV update accidentally puts vc
host as malware and you end up bricking
every single Windows host in your
environment the same thing could happen
at scale with bad IOC s if you don't
realize that this is some of the stuff
coming through your feeds so this lack
of quality assurance really concerns me
on the flip side from having spent a lot
of time building IOC s myself I
certainly appreciate why building good
IOC s is difficult
David Bianco has a presentation that
he's iterated on for a few years called
the pyramid of pain which is a really
nice way of concisely explaining the
challenge from you know starting with
the very basic observables like hashes
and IPS as you move up to trying to
create more expressive more reliable
less brittle indicators that capture
tactics and tools and methodologies of
an attacker it gets really really hard
to do that and you know the reason a lot
of these threat data feed companies
provide IOC s that are just hashes or
IPS is it's a reduction down to a common
denominator that's reliable if you are
providing a threat data feed and you
have a really smart clever IOC that
produces a bunch of false positives your
consumers get annoyed and it's hard to
produce abstract methodology indicators
without having the context of billions
of systems worth of data to compare them
to on a constant basis so everyone just
goes back to the lowest common
denominator of let's just spit out
hashes and IPS because at least no one
will complain that it's a false positive
most of the time you know this is an
example and again this might be a bit
small for those in the back but if
you've ever looked at a robust open IOC
indicator open IOC is really interesting
it's got like hundreds of different
observable types you can build a
combination
of a file import table object and a
exported function and the PE type and
the hashes and registry artifacts and
memory are artifacts but who actually
spends the time building IOC s like this
for every single incident that matters
consultancies and investigative verbs
can certainly do so but if you're
running a soccer cert team even if
you've got a full-blown cert team
there's no way you're going to have
analysts constantly trying to iterate on
this stuff and ever keep up that's why
you pay for third-party threat feeds but
again from the the producer end they're
blindly sending these indicators out and
hoping they don't cause a ton of false
positives and when you start to get
experimental like this that's when you
start to produce a lot of noise and
people get angry that you're not giving
them the fidelity that they want
specific to endpoint indicator matching
there's another challenge which is
inconsistencies in IOC detection tools
and I think this comes from the fact
that open IOC and even to a lesser
extent sticks and Sai box defined
observables without defining the actual
way to evaluate systems for set
observables and so when you look at
tools on the endpoint side that are
trying to consume different forms of
threat intelligence what you'll probably
find is incredible inconsistency in how
they're ingesting and applying that
threat data
it begins with supported observables if
you're paying for an IOC feed that is
giving you things like schedule tasks
items or registry keys and all you're
capable of doing is matching file names
and file hashes then you're blind to a
chunk of the threat data that you're
getting in that feed the second thing is
logic handling if you've got open i/o
sees or sticks or sigh box observables
that are implementing this logic tree
are you confident your endpoint tool is
actually evaluating that logic tree and
not short-circuiting in a way that's
going to produce unexpected behavior
there's no spec that defines how to do
that in open IOC you just have to figure
it out and hope that everything works
and then most importantly and this is
where I see a lot of both third-party
feeds homegrown i/o sees and vendor
tools all fail is data normalization
what do you do when you get an indicator
that has % system root or % user in it
what do you do if you've got an
indicator that's for a redirected file
path because
of Wow 64 behavior in Windows like if
your IOC matching tool is 32-bit and
you're running on 64-bit Windows are you
accounting for file system redirection
if you've got an indicator that matches
to volatile state data like H key
current user H key current user doesn't
exist in the Windows registry H key
users and a Sid does is your tool
mapping against the static registry or
the hive's is their map and memory if
you got an IOC with this are you going
to miss and false negative because your
tool isn't properly capturing it again
there's no standard that defines how you
should do this every vendor has to
figure it out and do their own thing now
the fortunate thing and this is by
product of them coming from a true
standards organization and not a vendor
but sticks and cybox
which both came out of mitre through
joint work with US government do have a
few tools for data normalization make
the sticks and there's a Python cybox
framework that is a script called
normalized you can run this across your
threat data and get more normalized
reliable output if you're working in
those formats but I don't think many
organizations out there actually doing
that open ioc itself is a a world of
hurt and again I open IOC was kind of
first to market with a format like this
so I really can't pick on them too hard
but open IOC was basically created out
of the output format of mere mandate
intelligent response and so when you try
to create a schema or standard after a
proprietary vendor tools weird XML
output format you get indicator terms
like process item slash port list slash
port item slash process process port
process what the hell does that mean I
mean I know what it means because I've
worked with the technology so I know
that it's the port held by a process as
parsed out of process memory but that's
not at all intuitive if I'm just trying
to figure out you know how the heck do I
have an indicator term to map a port
held open by a process or file item PE
info detected anomalies string if you
read the description it's like string
for detected anomalies and the PE
headers well what are those strings does
every tool produce the same string do
you have a map that you can give me so
that I can consistently evaluate this or
use this term this is this is a
significant problem and this is another
reason why you see so many indicators
just dumb themselves down to hashes and
IPS because no one can deal with this
stuff so we talked about indicators
being brittle we talked about some of
the market forces that unfortunately
lead to really poor indicators being
shared and sold as well as the reason
why building good indicators is hard
let's now talk a little bit about both
challenges and opportunities to do
better and shift the conversation the
things that are more productive and
positive and I'll begin with widening
the scope of endpoint indicator usage so
the fundamental question and I'm going
to stick to endpoint here is what can
you see so you've got endpoint centric
threat data
what are you matching it against and the
way I always like to articulate this is
you've got domains of data and domains
of systems domains of data are in three
categories the current volatile state of
your systems which is essentially what's
in memory so what processes are running
what network connections are active what
objects are serialized in memory
historical activity so this is the sort
of like telemetry feed that a lot of
security tools produce of a rolling set
of historical events what files changed
what processes ran what network
connections previously were created what
users previously logged in so telemetry
and then third is data at rest so
objects sitting on the system not
currently in use not currently active
like a file on disk that's been there
for five years or a registry key or a
line in an event log so that is your
scope of data that provides
opportunities for threat data matching
and then where can you see that you've
got your workstations and your servers
I'll define workstations as end-user
computing devices and servers as
everything else that powers your IT
infrastructure so this is what you need
to be evaluating against then the
questions become well you know what's
your scope what's your cadence of
detection where your gaps and where can
you do in-place detection versus needing
to build data leaks to facilitate using
your threat data and no one wants to
build more data leaks where they can
avoid it so first thing that you'll
often see is matching on the sim and
this is just born from the fact that sim
usually gets stood up to ingest network
data because it's easier like there's
fewer sources of network data than
endpoint data so when you stand up the
syn
what you'll usually find is you'll have
your web proxy logs your firewall logs
maybe your network malware appliance
feeding into it and then on the endpoint
side it's a lot more sparse you get like
maybe your antivirus and Hipps alerts
and maybe your Active Directory log ons
maybe some critical application servers
but you don't get comprehensive coverage
like you can't reliably say I'm going to
give you a hash for a file at rest in
the environment well I find that in the
sim well of course you won't because no
one's forwarding from every machine in
their environment everything that's on
them to the sim continuously you'd be
making Splunk very very rich if you did
that so sim is great for what you can
centrally capture but that is a very
small subset of what you need to do on
the endpoint forensic telemetry is where
a lot of the EDR market has gone so the
notion of just having a recorder on the
endpoint that continuously captures
events and then keeps it locally or
streams it up to someplace where you can
say did this process run five minutes
ago or five days ago and you can find it
in some sort of data set and that's
really great like that accelerates
incident response and it's a great
opportunity for threat data matching
because you capture all those
short-lived events like a password
dropper that password dumper that ran
for a minute you've got attached you've
got its metadata it's recorded it's
captured you're good to match it against
your threat info the challenge is it's
still limited scope of data meaning
you're keeping a rolling window of
things that have changed in your
environment that doesn't help you with
finding things in your environment that
existed before you install that tool
that doesn't help you find things in
your environment that are outside the
window of time that you can centrally
preserve that historical data and it
doesn't help you with artifacts that you
don't keep in the telemetry feed like no
telemetry feed for any EDR tool records
every event log entry in every operating
system event log it doesn't record every
object in memory like every mutexes
processes start and stop because all of
a sudden your telemetry feed would
become a thousand times larger so you do
narrow your scope of data matching on
live endpoints is the third domain and
this gives you in some respects the
broadest opportunity because if you're
keeping telemetry and you have access to
the live system you can do things like
look across memory look across disk look
across Kalama tree feeds
but you have to consider other factors
like endpoint impact is this process
taking hours and hours and slowing down
your systems to a point where it's
unacceptable and you can't apply your
threat data effectively is your
environment available such that you can
use your threat data and reliably cover
most of your systems and does this
process scale can you do this across a
thousand hosts can you do it across
100,000 these are all really important
considerations that balance what you do
on the endpoint versus what you might
need to do in a data lake or in a sim
for me personally I like combining the
sim and live endpoint I think the sim
can continue to exist and be enriched
with more endpoint data but I also think
that there's a place for doing certain
work on the endpoint because as we grow
and as systems become more
geographically distributed and networks
become less like one monolith cloud I
treat this as a distributed computing
problem and uptime is much more
guaranteed now than it was a few years
ago like if the system is if someone's
doing work on their computer it's almost
always online and that provides an
opportunity for distributed computing
and distributed handling of this threat
data and endpoint evidence problem so
with that let's talk about shrinking the
detection gap and what I mean by the
detection gap is really the misaligned
expectations from what you think you're
going to get from threat intelligence
and I OCS versus what you're actually
going to get and for me the challenge
here that I see is organizations
expected threat data and I OCS to do
better than signatures and between your
AV signatures and your i/o CS you can
suddenly close the gap of undetected
threats that was the promise that's what
we aspired to what I have seen in
practice is that threat data and AI OCS
and reputation data sources at their
best are basically keeping us at parity
with where we would have been 10 years
ago with like signatures so as attacks
are evolving use of threat data is just
keeping our head a little bit above
water
it is not closing the gap of undetected
threats and it will not do so and the
reason I want to point that out is like
just like people will sometimes
disparage antivirus as being useless and
that's completely wrong antivirus gives
you an enormous amount of noise
reduction and automated handling of
stuff that you'd otherwise be wait
being sock insert analyst I'm on that's
a good thing like the problem is when
you expect AV signatures to stop you
stop all unknown attacks or new novel
attack techniques and we're making the
same mistake now with threat date and
what we expect of it
Rick Holland at Forrester who Tyler
mentioned earlier at this morning's
keynote he was a forester at the time
now he's at a different firm but he had
a really good quote this year at the
2016 CGI summit there's this desire he
was talking about to take a technical
feed dump it into your security
infrastructure and you just get a threat
intelligence win and you're going to
find all this new stuff and the reality
is that that approach completely ignores
the benefit of getting threat data from
your own environment meaning monitoring
your environment to understand what is
normal what is a baseline what is a diff
from that and that really provides
incredible opportunity to complement
threat data and external threat feed
centric mechanisms of finding if you're
compromised so it begins with do you
know the basics in your network and I
tried to I spent a while thinking about
how I could distill down the most
important things that you really need to
care about to detect the modern state of
breaches and most environments and it's
really three things
what are your privileged accounts doing
meaning your local administrators your
domain administrators
where are they logging on how are they
logging on from Intuit systems at which
times the second is use of OS native
tools that are commonly abused by
attackers because the reality is
attackers at this point live off the
land if you ever look at the
presentations by like folks at the verus
group great group of consultants matt
gray burrkc smith they all do fantastic
work on PowerShell and other mechanisms
of using native windows features for
offensive security for bypassing
controls for bypassing things like a
polite listing and it's really
emblematic of what attackers are doing
now the nice thing is legitimate users
don't run a lot of these OS native tools
how many users in your environment know
how to open a command line let alone all
of these so terror arguments that the
net command has or how to invoke
PowerShell with execution policy
bypassed there's a lot of opportunity to
find anomalies from the fact that most
of the OS native tools that attackers
Everage are used by your admins and
developers but really no one else and
then the third is persistence mechanisms
meaning if you have a reliable way to
track the ways that organ attached or
things can survive in your network and
persist through reboot through user
logon even remote access like you have
citrix gateways exposed in your DMZ do
you have single-factor VPN for your
contractors these are all ways that
attackers survive in a network and if
you can analyze and track changes to
what's persisting in different ways you
have opportunities to detect a lot of
unknown and so this all goes employing a
blended approach which is yes pursue IO
CS and reputation data as a mechanism
for noise reduction and for automated
context so that if I do have a hash that
hit I know that it's associated with a
certain threat group and I can make a
risk inform the decision on whether I'm
going to spin up an IR or just clobber
the system or mediate and move on with
my life
the second is pattern of attack
detection for common intrusion workflows
and I think the nice thing here is that
we have a surfeit of EDR tools it's not
like ten years ago where you basically
just had to spend hours scanning each
system one by one and looking for
artifacts like whether it be taenia more
other commercial vendors or open-source
tools or native OS stuff like sis Mon or
stopped by Google Rapid Response there
are tons of things out there that you
can use to start building out endpoint
visibility and apply it to look for
patterns of attack rather than just
using all of this cool tooling to look
for hashes and filenames and I'll talk a
little bit in a moment about some
examples of applying that in a practical
way and then finally anomaly an outlier
analysis and I'll touch on this a little
bit but the idea here is not to try to
just find anomalies among the millions
of haystacks that you have in your
environment but to pick discrete sets of
systems and users and compare them to
one another in ways that can surface
interesting things in the three items I
mentioned in the previous slide while
you're privileged users are doing what's
persisting and how are native OS
capabilities being used or abused so
let's talk about the middle one they're
patterns of attack when I talk about
looking for patterns of attack as
opposed to specific indicators
I like the thing of it as what are the
lowest common denominators that you see
threat actors both targeted an
opportunistic apply across intrusions
and these often just end up being
defined by the way corporate networks
and the most common operating systems in
those networks behave I'm going to use
Windows as an example here because most
corporate environments still remain
largely Windows centric and that is the
opportunity for the attacker they know
how Windows works they know how Active
Directory works and that's very
predictable from environment to
environment so that results in some
outlier conditions that we can look for
and track from incident to incident so
let's let's bear this out before I give
you a specific example I wanted to call
attention to a framework by mitre called
attack earlier if you saw Andrew Hayes
talk he talked about the CIS top 20
benchmarks for implementing effective
security and how the Australian signals
Directorate said if you employed the top
four of those you'd cover 85% of threats
I think this is an interesting angle on
this that mitre has recently put out
about mechanisms of attack across each
phase of the attack lifecycle and the
techniques that are employed and if you
look this up you'll get a really nice
single page table of all the different
mechanisms used for persistence for
privilege escalation all the way through
to things like data exfiltration and
command and control really good
references you're trying to align what I
your efforts across what I mean when I
say patterns of attack the only
downsides of this framework is right now
there's no prioritization to it
there's no ordering to it so a
persistence mechanism that is incredibly
obscure and ysou Taric is listed with
equal footing as one that might be used
in 80 or 90 percent of reaches that's
something I'm hoping to help work
towards sharing more information about
really like what are the top three in
each of these categories you should
tackle first but let's take an example
of this that I really enjoy talking
about which is detecting host-to-host
command execution so we're going to talk
about a post breach scenario where
you've got a least one infected system
an attacker foothold of some sort and
you've got an attacker with a
administrator account that lets them hop
around the couple hosts maybe it's a
shared local administrator maybe it's a
moderately privileged domain account now
if you look in a windows breach
and how attackers run commands from
system B or from system ADA system D I
think about the hundreds of cases that
I've worked or been exposed to and
almost every single one of them uses one
of these three or four methods remote
scheduled tasks Windows remote
management or PowerShell PS exec and if
I were to add one more WM I in real
command execution these are for
essentially native to Windows ways to
run a command on a remote host if you
have privileges to it and you're already
inside the network you don't need to
ship malware down to the host I mean
okay PS exec is not part of Windows but
it's a widely used administration tool
that would not raise eyebrows in most
environments so you don't need to bring
Metasploit down to a box to do this
stuff and this is a great example of
living off the land the nice thing is
when you use all of these tools you
leave behind a ton of evidence you
create logon events when you run remote
scheduled tasks or even PowerShell
remoting or PS exec you're creating
Network log ons on the target host you
might be creating explicit logon events
on the source host if you do process
telemetry like with sis Mon or lots of
commercial tools that record historical
event tracking
you're going to have execution of these
commands that again normal users don't
typically run on their own and then
there's lots of other artifacts over the
network in memory and so on but even
just these top two here are readily
available readily possible if you have
any modern EDR tool deployed in your
environment and this will give you
coverage of 90% of the ways if not more
that attackers move from host to host
and so what you do with all this data is
then apply analysis criteria to it so on
a rolling basis can you reliably track
who like which accounts are using these
methods in your environments both for
good and bad where they're occurring
from source and destination at what time
they usually occur and what they
actually run so what are the scheduled
tasks in my environment executing what
files are they dropping and this gives
you meat little stacks of data where you
can start to do outlier analysis and
just as andrew is mentioning it is you
know building a security team talk the
idea is to take small chunks and small
problems and then build out a hunting
capability piece by piece and you can
just start with scheduled tasks as an
example of this and schedule tasks
remain really really prevalent
for attacker behavior in Windows
environments so let's use Dooku 2.0 as
an example
Kaspersky AV vendor got breached by a
threat actor that was pretty
sophisticated and they actually
published a nice tell-all about what the
attacker did and what their tools and
tactics were and this campaign used some
malware that is called the Dooku family
and in particular their white paper
described how the attackers would use
scheduled tasks to run a dropper
component of this malware named MSI exec
remotely and so when they would do that
it would create this event log in the
task scheduler event log in Windows
saying task scheduler created this task
named MSI exec and they even mentioned
that this is similar behavior that the
attackers did back in 2011 so for five
years they've been employing this
technique so what was really funny to me
is if you went and looked at the IOC is
that Kaspersky shared or fireEye or any
of the other vendors I think this is
Kaspersky Zahn screen the IOC doesn't
have a single task item or anything
about scheduled tasks metadata in it
it's a list of hashes and IP addresses
like literally this is the whole
indicator exactly the problem we talked
about earlier so we could do better than
this right we could maybe add a task
item to the IOC that's part of open IOC
spec we could look for scheduled tasks
that run MSI exec and start to do some
outlier analysis but maybe that's still
a bit suspicious if 'ok and maybe we
want to take a step back further and
think about the problem holistically
which is if attackers are using
scheduled tasks so consistently across
breaches as a common mechanism of
lateral command execution how could we
just in general build a process to find
this stuff so let's look at the analysis
approach for event logs every single
Windows computer in your environment is
recording whenever a task is created the
user that created it and what thing it
ran and that log is really small it's
like 10 megabytes so you can harvest
that using windows native event
forwarding or pick your favorite EDR
tool and you can create a stack that
says which users create tasks in your
environment and how many do they create
over a period of time so get a profile
of what accounts in your environment are
actually creating these things you can
also create a stack by what your
are executing so when a scheduled task
runs what programs are there running and
this is important because you're going
to have stuff like Google's native
updater for Chrome which creates a
scheduled task you're going to have like
patches and ad hoc system administration
tasks all stuff that your admins are
doing legitimately to manage the
environment and should be largely common
over time and at scale to give you some
notion of prevalence and frequency of
occurrence and this will already start
to bubble up the one offs that seem more
interesting like a task named one dot
bat or test bat or dump dot bat or
something in a temp directory that might
warrant further investigation and
further analysis and that's where you
then go back to the full log context and
say who ran what at which time and you
can start to mark off for future hunting
recycling of this effort is this is
known good this was marked as commodity
bad you have a baseline of your
environment to hunt with for future
analysis and maybe you do this across a
one month effort and then you can start
doing it in an automated fashion and
scripted and soon you have such a good
baseline that when you are working a
targeted breach you're not looking at
this data for the first time and
freaking out at every single uncommon
good outlier that you find in your
network you can also do this at rest so
if you have EDR tools you can do stuff
like survey what scheduled tasks exist
on your endpoint now and what commands
they run and again these are files that
are sitting on every computer in your
network it is incredibly cheap and
efficient to get at this data it takes a
split second to parse this out and see
you've got a task named at 1:00 in your
environment and it's running something
named drop that XE and then finally
monitoring in motion if you have
telemetry feeds it's really easy to
start looking for some of the native
Windows commands that attackers love to
abuse and for scheduled tasks it's stuff
like the app command or the SCH tasks
command again most of your users don't
know that this even exists so profiling
whenever someone runs ax slash slash you
don't need to pay a third-party vendor
for an indicator or pattern of attack
for that like this is easy to monitor
for and there are a dozen or two
commands like this that will give you
incredible blanket coverage of a lot of
lateral movement techniques employed by
attackers so let's look at another
example of this which is stacking
binaries
so a lot of people when they try to do
anomaly analysis which was kind of the
third phase of what I described really
overwhelmed themselves with data and I
think the most common thing people will
chase first that gets them hung up is
they wonder how many unique executable
files do ELLs drivers are in my
environment and couldn't I just find
malware by looking for that XE or DLL by
name or hash that is unique or
relatively uncommon because strickman's
most of my users have largely similar
binaries on their endpoints and the
answer is absolutely not
even in a small environment the amount
of noise here is like breathtaking you
will see probably 10 to 100 times more
uniqueness than you expect and that's
because of different operating system
versions and add-ons it's getting even
worse now that Windows does like
slipstream updates where some users get
some versions of a file and other users
get other versions user installed
applications if you've got admin or
users with admin that can install
applications yeah have fun with all the
variants in your environment there but
then you've got stuff that you never
think of until you look at the data like
applications that like to drop files and
directories with a gooood in their file
name or their file path I think for a
while WebEx did this where if you ever
look at the binaries for WebEx there's
like a helper to the extension that's an
executable file that lives in a
directory with at least a partial good
in its file name which means if you're
trying to do stack analysis of
executables or names or directories
you're going to have a billion of these
unique one offs for every time someone
spawned off the the cisco webex
extension all of this creates a lot of
noise and in many cases unfortunately
dissuades people from pursuing data
analysis like this because it's just so
intrinsically hard to do right one of
the things that can help it doesn't
solve the problem but it can help is to
start by again approaching a manageable
stack of data when you build a hunting
program so I have a small demo
environment that we use in our own
company of a couple hundred Windows
servers and workstations and they're
largely configured the same and I just
wanted to show you what I mean about
just the noise that you deal with so
among these 250 systems if you were to
enumerate all of the loaded dll's and
season drivers in memory that small pool
of systems has 2490 unique files unique
based on path and hash if instead of
looking and that's a lot of data right
that's on only 250 largely alike systems
I already have 2500 rows of things to
look for the long tail is going to be
pretty big on that imagine in a network
of 10,000 systems imagine on a network
of 100,000 systems I work the
investigation where we did this like
file path uniqueness analysis for
binaries in a network of about 75,000
hosts and if I'm memory serves right we
had about 25 million unique XE paths by
name and hash that's an incredible
amount of data and you'll never find out
wires effectively in that so let's look
at a slightly smaller data set what if
instead of looking at all loaded modules
with hash and memory I only look at
things that are configured to
automatically run or load I only have
355 things to look at as opposed to 2500
that's a little better
instead of all auto start programs what
if I just focus on Windows services
which are a very common Windows
persistence mechanism for malware I only
have 225 unique things to start looking
at and monitoring and what if I want to
go really extreme and take a more
obscure but increasingly popular and
covert persistence mechanism like WMI
event consumers now I've only got four
unique things that I'm tracking across
an entire environment because there's
very few windows event consumers or WMI
consumers that the OS natively creates
so it's a lot easier to find an outlier
in for things so you can take on
manageable bite-sized chunks of data and
then build your way up from that and get
a nice baseline understanding of how
your environment works in the meantime
the other key here is to compare alike
assets if you're trying to hunt and do
anomaly analysis across users or systems
and you're comparing against the whole
estate you're always going to get
overwhelmed with too much noise and too
much of a long tail in this example I'm
showing you auto run Auto Start programs
across a mix of workstations servers
laptops and we've got three hundred
eight unique entries if I only compare
Auto runs against things that are sequel
servers in my environment I've only got
71 unique things so think about
from a monitoring perspective it's going
to be a lot more effective for you to
look for unique persistence mechanisms
across your domain controllers as a
group across your database servers as a
group across different your
administrator workstations than it is to
just compare against everything and if
you start to think about your
environment in terms of logical units
like that it becomes a lot easier to
proactively detect anomalies than to
just try to tackle the whole set of data
at once I have a whole other
presentation that's kind of
complementary to this it has some
overlapping content but then a bunch
more technical examples it's called
hunting in the dark it's on my speaker
deck account so if you'd like to read a
bit more about this do check that out
but let's wrap up with a few closing
thoughts and takeaways so one of the
things I also wanted to share is where
things are going in terms of standards
and platforms that solve some of these
endemic issues with good threat data
sharing and usage and there are a few
things that I like out there has anyone
heard of or used Mis P before two hands
so Mis v is malware information sharing
platform I think it is a open platform
for consuming threat data and threat
feeds it gives you information and
analysis and comparison of what you're
ingesting and it provides mechanisms to
then shunt that off to some of the other
tools in your environment it is a really
nice platform with soul true recently
announcing effectively that there yo
ailing it's probably one of the most
mature remaining open platforms for
threat data collection out there so I
suggest you check that out for thread
hubs and exchanges everyone knows about
the public sector and Industry vertical
specific exchanges out there
I'm unfortunately not too familiar with
the exchanges in Canada but I'm sure
they don't exist that the government is
working to build some of those on the
private sector there's one that I want
to give a plug for because I really like
how they're approaching this and that's
Facebook so Facebook's been running
thread exchange for two years they have
a couple hundred members across lots of
different industries and Facebook does a
really good job with how they've built
their graph to consume and manage and
rate and score threat data probably the
most I would say mature approach that
I've seen in industry to tackling this
problem and so they are free you have to
just agree to certain terms to join and
to share info if you want to but they
run a great program and then from
standards I beat up a bit on open IOC I
didn't talk a lot about stick since I
box I mean show of hands here how many
of you have worked with Sai box before
now I'm so sorry like it's it's not
pleasant because when they built those
standards they built them to try to
encompass so many edge cases and use
cases that you ended up with hundreds
upon hundreds of terms and so the net
result is people look at this and they
see this giant XML schema and your eyes
kind of just roll back in your head and
as well they should it's it's too much
sigh box 3.0 which Oasis is working on
finalizing is refactoring and
simplifying it greatly same for sticks
which is kind of like an envelope around
Sai box and other things so that is
going to help a lot because they
realized like look we don't need a term
for everything we just need to tackle
the most commonly used and commonly
shared types of observables and to do so
effectively and well better to tackle
the 80% really really well than to worry
about building a standard that
encompasses the whole universe and
becomes too difficult for people to use
the second is quantitative assessment of
threat feeds and this is really hard
like like I said before no one is really
doing this at any sort of scale and so I
looked to see if there were a lot of
tools or good resources out there for
quantitative assessment of threat data
quality and all I could find is
something from the ML SEK project in
2014 or 13 Kyle Maxwell and did a
presentation about measuring the IQ of
your threat feeds they produced this
tool called tick test that lets you do
statistical comparison of network IOC s
in your feeds and gives you a sense of
how much overlap you have and it's
really interesting when you take a
couple private feeds for pay a couple
public feeds and find out that maybe the
overlap is a much greater percentage
than you expected challenge your threat
feed vendor as you're buying the stuff
or evaluating or shopping around
consider where the data is coming from
are they doing just open source threat
Intel collection are they using honey
pots are they running managed services
or professional services where they're
seeing investigations and breaches in
the field all of these have strengths
and weaknesses in terms of the scope and
breadth and
all of data that you should consider
what is the breakdown of observable
types like statistically you should be
able to get a number on what percentage
of the items in your feeds or hashes
what percent are IPS what percent or
registry keys so you know where to apply
and where it's going to be effective and
challenge them for what QC they have in
place how are they testing their
indicators how are they testing them to
see if they produce false positives are
they doing spot checking have they
documented their feeds such that you
feel confident you can ingest it to spec
and then consider your own visibility so
are you really maximizing what you're
paying for do you have the tooling in
place to actually utilize threat data
such that you have better visibility
across your endpoints your servers and
your network infrastructure and are the
two aligned if you're consuming a kind
of endpoint threat data and only looking
really in your sim which has Network
centric logs you're probably wasting
your money and you need to either shift
the threat data you're buying or shift
your tooling so that you have more
endpoint visibility and the same is true
and vice versa and then again consider
threat data in the grand scheme of
things in the grand grand sense of
return on investment for security the
threats the best sources of threat data
are not going to help you keep pace with
emerging attacks there are always going
to be attacks that are ahead of that
curve and they're always going to be
things that you can more successfully
identify by looking inside at your own
environment that the intelligence that
your network intrinsically produces Rob
Joyce from the national security
agencies tailored access operations
group did a presentation at enigma Con
earlier this year where he talked about
how the NSA is worst nightmare is a
sysadmin who pays attention it's not a
company that's got good threat data it's
people that understand what's going on
in their systems and can find outliers
and anomalies and spot behavior that is
atypical so knowing your network above
all and investing in the security
hygiene and attack surface reduction
that shrinks opportunities for attackers
will always provide a greater overall
return on investment than just adding
one more IOC source or one more source
of threat data all right and with that
we have some time for questions so
thanks all and happily take any
questions
you
[Music]