to give a chance for people to arrive
with a bit of latency and with this
we'll be looking for minutes takers
is there a candidate to help us take
some minutes the etherpad is indicated
on this page it's also indicating the
next page it would be really cool that
you guys can attend the etherpad and
takes some notes in particular you're
going to talk to the mic then please
make sure that the minutes capture
correctly what you're going to say and
with this so do we have a summary a ping
on the minutes nice thank you very much
do we have JavaScript or a small room
I'm not sure anybody going to Jaber okay
you can okay thank you meeting so this
is 60s this is a usual ITF meeting so we
go by all the rules of the ATF and
there's a list of best practices but
processes or response at cetera and in
particular we've got the best practices
applying to IPR
so if you're aware of IPR on anything
that's going to be discussed today
please tell the room or let the shares
know by at the end of the meeting with
this remember you are being filmed the
movie will be played on YouTube
thousands and hundreds of people will
vision visualize it so be very smart and
so will publish the minutes and the
recording you need to sign the blue
sheets we are kind of going to pass them
along in a few minutes please go online
on the ether pad and contribute two
minutes taking and validating the
minutes and you'll find the usual links
about the 60s activities on this page
and with this we can start the agenda
bashing so basically we're going to tell
you where we are with this working group
our progress the status of documents and
related documents not a working row so
it goes
to the milestones and then we'll decide
what we do next well we'll have ten
minutes on the status of the
architecture then go to minimal security
that's gonna be Manisha then we'll have
Michael if he joins he sent us some
slides is not there yet and we'll have
Jay go remotely so Jay go did you I see
you so I hope you could set up your
mythical correctly then we have okay
okay that's nice we can hear you already
so that that's good and then we have
tanks fighting face same thing did you
could you set up your mythical correctly
thanks very well I hope it works and
maybe the most unusual and final
discussion we'll have today is what's
next because as we will see we have
pretty much concluded all the work items
for which we were chartered which kind
of means that either we reach out or we
just sell out so that's going to be the
discussion so if you have items that you
want to discuss in this working group in
the future then it's it's a it's a good
time to speak now okay and with this a
little bit of status for the twelve on
the other working groups so as you know
six teachers spent more time actually
pushing work another working group that
doing individual work inside this
working group we we mostly worked around
an architecture and open source
implementations and interrupt tests and
to make all those things happen then we
had a number of dependencies and a
number of working groups so there is a
list of documents that we actually
promoted in other working groups so in
6lo we've got all the fragmentation work
so there are two documents they are both
passed well groups last call and we
started getting feedback from the affero
on the minimum fragment so there was a
new recipient of the minimum fragment so
those two draft are basically on in a
good shape for to go through iesg and
they are in suresh carrying health
we also promote you to work on 6lowpan
neighbor discovery so that's one of them
is now RFC eight five four five and then
we've got the address protection in the
backbone router which is an T proxy so
also all this work is in good shape and
and continuing through the is G we have
this new draft that was proposed to
completely get rid of multicast enable
discovery using software registrar's
this is new job submission it's it's
related to the other three so that's why
it's listed here but I don't know what's
going to happen with it it's not needed
in the sixty's architecture it's beyond
six dish it's on the backbone and then
we've got the dead lifetime which is
also going through ESG at four we've
been promoting the Sdn model and that's
where the Dow projection goes there's
also this work on a leaf which would not
be aware of ripple so using only eight
five four five to signal the presence of
the leaf to the repo rotting and mapping
that into repo so that's going well both
documents have progressed I would say
immensely about the since the last IETF
there were several rounds of each of
those documents and roll is planning to
push quite heavily on the unaware leaf
because many documents are actually
dependent on that one including the
sixties architecture by the way and
enrollment priority I think the the
chairs have been asking for reviews on
that one to get through the age what to
do through the work of Wisconsin and
then we've get an email with the
constraint voucher and I hope that
Michael could tell us about it but it's
not there did you have knows about the
constraint voucher
okay so maybe Michael when he speaks on
the dead net the design team work on
zero touch will be able to give us news
on the constraint voucher because it's
really meet under zero touch is is the
constraint voucher so here is the
milestones
that we had I mean two of them Suresh ah
still waiting for accept but I mean
considering that it's just about
submitting the draft to ASG and that the
draft have actually been submitted to
Zermatt so the the dt securities you're
attached is mostly empty of its contents
we kept it just to keep the working
group informed about the progress and
virtual work so i guess it will never be
submitted to ASG or it will be moved to
animal or place that will take care of
it
and so there we go the only item that's
left is evaluate the work of progress
and talk about which are trying or
completing the work basically yes it's
not a way of saying yes
and with this we moved to the first
presentation and that's me actually on
the architecture
I will move to the mic so the 60s
architecture may be viewed as maybe the
most encompassing work at six dish
because that's really what shows what we
wanted to achieve in this working group
and why we pushed so many work items in
different working groups and and the
overall picture that we wanted to build
so there are a number of components that
we are done at home
unlike the minimal security MSF etc a
six six P protocol and then a good
number of work items which actually done
outside the working group but the
architecture is the document that puts
all things in perspective and also
indicates direction we want to take for
new work which may not happen in 60s at
all such as row for instance this buff
that we had on Wednesday so there are
really two pieces in one document and we
could have done to document some people
said we should but we have a very
high-level architecture that goes into
the domain components and articulates
them and then we've got a deeper dive
into some components which are most
specific - six - and - Tom being
explained for instance there is this
concept of a track that is now inherited
by the work at Rome so we actually well
we went through the ASU review so that
we had for review since the last IETF
that Eric maja Roman and in German with
Benjamin obviously we we went through a
deep review of the security section but
not only Benjamin has been going very
slowly through the whole document and
thanks to Manish Shah and you actually
thank you we actually did a lot of work
on the security section and expanded
quite a bit so that's that's one of the
big changes we also extended the
discussion of the various forms of
diversity that are viable ratios which
are not necessarily the pre off that of
and in that net so we would clarify that
we expanded on the joint process as well
and the minimal thing and I insisted
that we are well and not annamaria but
that we are too many references and they
were not really well classified into
normative and non normative with the
understanding that this is not a Star
Trek document this is a an informational
track but there is still a meaning for
normative and that meaning is if you
need to understand the reference to
understand this document then the
reference is normative right so it's not
normalization if you like it it's really
like you can't understand this document
without understanding the other if
that's the case then the reference is
normative otherwise just you can avoid
reading it it's informative just for
your own reading if you like - so we
actually had to move and shuffle around
the references to clarify what's
normative the problem with that is by
putting more documents into normative we
also created a good number of miss Roth
miss Roffe being those documents which
are normative reference to euros but are
not yet roc so you cannot publish the
architecture before all of the mistress
are also published as RFC and there are
now like six or seven miss rafts
including the raw document that I showed
including minimum security including MSF
etc all those documents are now
normative references and we have to wait
for those to be RFC before the
architecture is RFC so the RFC is the
architecture is really the document that
will close the door of all the work that
has been done at 6:00 - when this is
either IFC then all the work we've done
is there as well and that also makes
sure that the architecture is completely
compatible and represents well the work
which is done in the other document even
if they change will have to change the
architecture - to represent that
correctly and that's pretty much I had
to say about the architecture so
we have any question okay so so if
you're interested in the work that we
try to start with row by W reliable
variable Wireless you can see a row as
being the next phase four six dish but
focusing on the writing aspect of it
that's why it's it's done in the writing
area and most besides precisely on the
operation of a sixties track now row is
not specific to sixty shot or it seemed
to be abstract to be completely lay off
free operation but it's near it's
certainly from the the designs that
we've done for tracks and all this
capability to have this direct acyclic
graph to a certain destination and make
intelligent forwarding decision there on
this track
so row we'll be focusing on that if the
group forms and that's pretty much it
for now
Thank You Posca
[Music]
okay so I will talk about the minimum
security document which was renamed to
be the constraint drawing protocol for
six days after one is three review the
current statuses the document is in
third it's in thirteenth version that
the IRG reviews have been received as
well as up there and sec their reviews
and general the goal of this
presentation is essentially to go
through the main changes in twelve and
thirteen and discuss the issues raised
during the IRT reviews so after the last
meeting we discussed some text
prohibiting the mixing of different
levels of what entity authentication
tags this was incorporated in twelve we
added a new subsection is an ASN replay
attack after the last meeting
discussions and we also added some
mandatory support for extended tokens at
JRC as was received a comment offline
from Klaus Harkin from core we received
obviously two to two reviews be a pre I
usually use one of their and one
secretary review there were mostly needs
one concerned one added a new
requirement that concerns three
commissioning of a device where we added
the requirement that the pressure key
must be changed in case the device is
recommission and during the Secretary
will these were most units that we
received
I usually reviews we got four discusses
and three no objections and one year
setting from Suresh the so the comb in
the main goal of the presentation today
will be to go through the open issues
that we have on in is G from is G
reviews one issue that was brought up
was related to the you
of well-known UI for code rip and
essentially as it stands for you was the
/ /j URI as a URI we use /j yeah I think
Adam had a suggestion like co-op column
colon slash slash six to stop a slash
dot well-known slash a was this addition
so so that there was a couple of
parallel discussions on it essentially
we in during the drawing phase we it was
deemed okay that we can use /j as long
as we use sixty sharp ax as the
well-known host name the problem was the
after the join exchanged the parameter
updates
part of the protocol where sixty sharper
was missing well-known Yura host so what
we did what we proposed is the
resolution is to use sixty sharper also
in that case as well so that it is
isolated from all other uses of slash
stray yeah this is the proposal so
proposal make it but it is also one of
his comments which said like how do you
handle subdomains he just wanted some
clearer text on handling on submarines
it was part of the comment but I would
like to solicit she only has sex Edition
as well here so this was added this was
all added I mean I didn't bring it up
here because it we converts them that on
the list but Michael added this in the
document essentially all the proposed
text in the from from the male tried so
this should be resolved I mean we still
haven't published the version the
official version of the document but
it's in the working copy one comment
that would receive from media in regards
the parameter update response message
which which is as it now stands empty
the parameter this is response to the
parameter update message which is a cop
confirmable message and essentially we
define for well for generality
essentially another message that is a
response but that is essentially empty
that is piggybacked over over coop
over coops confirmable response and the
question raised was is completely
legitimate was like why define our own
our own protocol message when the
response is confirmable and that when so
that we have an indication of reception
at the sender of the parameter update
message so I mean why keep it
essentially and the proposes resolution
is essentially to remove the parameter
update response message from the
protocol yeah so another issue that was
oh one another comment that was received
was from Benkei deck yes again so for
the congestion control parts like I
gonna discuss it or it likely your a
greater than genius and it's done III
consider it done because it was on the
on the list yes yeah yeah it's it has
been discussed on the list and it was
incorporated in the document so I
believe we are good to go there here I
essentially the issue that I'm going
through are the issues that haven't have
had their resolutions in the in the
working copy of the document and no make
sense now I just thought like you know
you wanted to discuss like all the stuff
that came up during eval because you put
all the positions ends oh okay no yeah
no what the proposed resolution there
one is quite simple and it were starting
so so it should be fine so regarding
this issue that been Caidic raised it
concerns the traffic analysis of quadric
messages and essentially asking if we
can muddle up if you can make more
difficult if we can make traffic
analysis more difficult what options
would be available to us and Michael
responded to this on the mailing list
recently essentially summarizing the
types of traffic that are in the network
and saying that this kind of traffic is
protected at layer 2 in the network and
that this is pretty much all we can do
about it at this point
another issue is related to the use of
sexy sexy exempt mechanism in 15 for
standard and this was a this was a
comment received bump by Bank addict he
says I think we may need to say more
about how JP knows the SEC isn't is in
effect since that affects the critical
piece of the security posture of the
network and this true that in the
current text we don't have the clear
link between house Exantus set other
than it was considered out of scope so
what I propose here we had we have this
join rate parameter that can be used by
the Dre RC to enable any particular node
in the network to act as a joint proxy
so I I what I propose is that we link
the user of the join rate parameter with
the SEC exempt mechanism such that when
the jrc enables a particular node to
acted as a drawing proxy ii m to get set
at that particular node there are given
in psychic seemed is it's not per join
proxy it's in in join proxy for each
joining node so so you can't set it
until you know who is going to be
joining okay but you need a policy to
yet you read the policy that you are
allowing you know join but the first
complexities of course coming out of the
blue you don't know who do that one end
so so a first message to get in will
always get error because you are not
allowing it but then it up layer you can
see that okay check out the policy if
they you know join generate generate is
non zero then we allowed configuration
except for that know that I'm just
sending a message but but it's it's it's
not like for forty snow this actually
for remote draw that remote node is
allowed to
exempted security management in Pakistan
okay okay thanks for the con and I think
the one the one of the problem is that
when we of course after he had finished
joining we want to drop the SEC X and so
he we he of course doesn't send any
anymore pockets in clear but some you
know attacker mic'd you know send
packets in clear claiming to be him
because and actually do some nasty said
that's why you want to remove the
psychics and so it that it take it
dropped automatically by the Mac so we
do this after certain time out then for
a for a pledge or because we don't have
a way of knowing at the Jaypee that the
pledge joined essentially we have yes
that's actually one of the comments I
had earlier was that it actually would
be better to for JP to know when the
process is finished
I like currently and it's also you know
because one of the problem there is that
when we sent the final response back
that's actually sent in clear because we
don't have that one has a hundred keys
yet the problem is that the AK is coming
back with using the same security level
that was you know be sending so and we
have to respond to we have to be able to
receive that ACK which means they still
have to have an SEC accept own at that
point it's not transmitting that and of
course he if he doesn't get it we have
to retransmit and so so there's it did
either be the timeout or some you know
actually first time we see him sending
us any encrypted message we know that he
has you know received he has the keys
and we can drop the SEC extent that's
actually it's one optional or or I don't
know what this could could it depends or
the protocol little bit okay okay thanks
so okay so to sum up essentially we
enable the SEC exempt to be set when
drawing rate is nonzero but we still
need to process an incoming message from
from each pledge before the SEC exempt
is set for again for again it's not
global it's yapper
you know appear and the drawing rate who
is something that is a good
that's how about for the no global 42
note so in procs who has a global
setting join rate that tells you whether
it's allowing anybody to join and when
he sees the first you know message he
even said check except for that note
that okay understood then there was an
issue also raised by Bank a duck on the
use of quadric max enjoin attempts
parameter that appears only twice in the
text and this is essentially a remnant
from the
time join request was a non confirmable
message so as now we rely on quarter de
clave declared failure to the
application we simply can remove this
and remove it from the text this this is
the most simple resolution another
common from Bank ADA considers the
parameter additional info that was
deemed under specified because in one
there is one example given in the text
that during the processing of the error
message in this parameter we can include
a subset of keys that were not we that
were not being that could not be
processed so the idea was the Tenakee
compliant with link layer keystroke that
is defined in the document can be
included but apparently there is more
text needed here to to make this to not
make it under specified one other issue
that was raised by bank attack is the
the missing of the label of the elyda t
for each message he says that he feels
that it's little unusual to have a
consolidate registry for Quadra
parametres that are used as map labels
across different messages without some
indication of which map labels are valid
in which messages so essentially the
resolution to this should be to add a
paragraph rate arising and summarizing c
d dl c
fragments which already indicate a bit
what what parameters are valid in which
quadruped objects so clarifying question
we don't need to change the IANA section
for that right we just put that
somewhere else yes yes that's crackers
doesn't matter try now whether this is
used that message all that means as long
as it's being declared yes yes that's
correct so the next steps is just to
incorporate this resolution that we
discussed here and to publish
essentially on the 14th version and to
declare - I agree that essentially we
have we believe we have addressed all
the issues that were raised as part of
the review process that's all from me
many thanks Parishad do we have a
question in the room to haul anything
can heal famous last word on this okay
many thanks many the next that's Mike on
Michael is not there so J go I guess you
will have at least the ten minutes you
want it we are ahead of time in this
meeting so yes you go can you please
show up
we can hear you I don't see you showing
up at the cue there you go
do we have a question yes I know it's
more stuff and free so it's more a
comment michael has a presentation in
red so it may be that he's coming late
thank you very much and look at movies
presentation that's no problem
so you go can you check if you can
another HS I think I'm not able to
slides
and someone asked me to so we all sleep
in current status wait a minute are they
asking to to deceive you here
I cannot see they did the presentation
well you showed it somewhere I cannot
move the touch move it no worries just
go okay then I would I think - moaning
over there okay she's the mid-may over
here this is Diego - harmony I'm going
to present the the information element
the calculation for six dish and join
our enrollment information which is
rational zero zero six
and next please be brief I hope so
what's the status of the of this draft
we have already passed individual DLC in
case we have the last call you have a
one revision from Carlos Gomez waiter
really thank and we are going for the
version zero seven from shore revision
for judges and we noticed some few typos
and I covered on the interpretation of
the a of the link Oh case but this
checklist it's a simple it doesn't
change the core of their of the draft
and they do I also thank fear of about
the the
enlightenment or how to manage date the
name of the hundred fifteen foreigner
naming
now and remember three sixteenths he
mentioned this and for the future next
slide please so whatever we have changed
here it's a few filtration titles okay
and subsection 1 1 pitch 1.3 it's the
usage and meaning of a rotary
advertisement Association we should be
cleared so we clear it up okay and we
close the the expressions at the closing
of section 1 we have improved them and
some feel description or the change also
when on stage section 2 de to join how
to arrange them in the order word they
appear on the hospital then the cigar
decoration and we can lead locally glare
can be using description of the pivot
which was in Austria each other should
have been and fire finally has a small
citation explicitly for the area of fc8
81-57 if the subtype next please just
very few questions
finally we are going to move to 0-7 okay
after the all the comments we have
received and then I expect we hope this
draft will go through the ilg at the
next step and that's it for for this
draft happy this rough in fact has been
very stable for the last versions ok
only small changes and I think it's
ready to move on any questions
well actually actually yes you got I
guess from my UT direct right the
document is submitted to the ASG for
review with idea evaluation and it's in
the air in hands of Suresh again like
pretty much every document okay so
that's what we are just yet you know the
old in literally chart and you'll get
all those review okay right Thank You
Johnny start based on the length of make
you know roll in January as restricting
January or February
[Music]
many thanks rush so thank you you go for
staying without that this late time
don't worry
of your day don't even show you tomorrow
already so thank you very much no
question on this okay and we'll move on
then and next winner is it's for pretty
much thanks hey can you please join
don't you think fine showing up think
they can you please show on the mythical
mythical Joe big suspense tada
hello hear me
yes thanks I press the button hope
you're there can you only try thanks a
please because maybe the button
evacuated you instead of accepting you
[Music]
there we go
you should be starting okay can you see
the buttons to switch the slides or do
you want me to switch the slight sting
say I didn't see the button to switch
sighs yep yeah thanks
so they said update for the latest
version of the MSF minimal scale
function and will show the next slide
base so since the last re camp meeting
we have three main issues raised up the
first rate is the rules for salaries
which is pointing out to Pascal and
because of the curve its version the MSF
doesn't specify where the Souza's pick
it up though when generating the 6pu
request and so we should have to know
that maintaining a candidate is helpful
for this at least and know the world
keep listening for the clearance of the
cells and to check whether is a
collision sound ourselves and then when
generate the 6p request package it will
pick up the cells from this cell phone
so the another issues is the schedule
consistency pointed out by Christine and
the issue is when the mode is despaired
from the network such as when the power
of the south is reserved his parents
will live in the parent schedule of ever
without knowing the neighbor is gone
that we used to have the keepalive
mechanism for each node it will stand
some Q line message to to the neighbor
it has a sales and half before and if
this icky blob is not act by his
neighbor and the neighbor will be Claire
declared as unreachable and and then it
will stand a bit clearer to the neighbor
it may be filled but it will remove the
cell cell to the neighbor from its
schedule so we used to have it in the
previous version like 0-2 version of the
master and we removed out from those
trees because at the time we don't have
the dynamic scheduling for the
autonomous house at that time the
Ottoman cell wall installed apparently
in the schedule and in that sense they
may because they for install one cell
for our neighbors but now the MSF has
dynamic scheduling so those cells could
be removed the only installer wouldn't
necessary so so we bring it back in the
latest MSF job and the third one is we
added the downstream traffic adaptation
feature for the latest MSF and this is
the main thing I'm going to explain in
details and next one please so firstly
is the strategy of a downstream traffic
interpretation is pretty similar to the
upstream one and has two counters and
the number cell use themselves elapsed
and them cell use the world blood plus
when the frame is received from its
parents on a our Excel and themselves
the elapsed
number will increase me will increments
to win the current Salazar Excel to his
parents the different is the upstream
for upstream traffic it has a negotiated
txl at the initial but initially there's
no negotiating or excel for each node so
we decided to counting the auto or
excels at the beginning to start to this
downstream traffic adaptation so to use
them that that there is a tool there's
one problem is during network a forming
face those cells are used actually by
its children and these parents at the
same time and this CUDA caused a
collision on these cells and which when
the massacre is detecting the usage of
the downstream traffic is actually will
detect a lower value for this cell usage
but after the networks formed and the
traffic from his parents will transfer
to the negotiate eh cells
so the man-made traffic is coming from
his parents which is a downstream
traffic on this auto or Excel which is
ideal for a downstream traffic
adaptation so for the for the reason
that mostly down to traffic are
generated after networker is formed so
we can was a SAP to this this this
drawback on a theory in the network is
forming face and next slide please
I think they just one meter pointer is
basically when the network is being
formed I mean what you see there is
mostly control in that data right
because network is the diet and so those
collisions are a lot related to these
and Diu messages and we are working
right now after all to minimize the
chances of collisions like this by
intruding
introducing some some trickle mechanisms
in the das so the prime should actually
also be addressed at the operator at the
repo layer so as to to avoid most of
those collisions anyone so I mean saying
is that's cool that you do this way and
we are trying to limit the chances that
these events during the date rock
formation no that's good thanks for the
information
so we also implement the downstream
traffic we implemented Japan I was
opened up with an invitation and will
create a pure as especially for this
feature and currently had marched and we
tested it through a test pad from our
office building and we deploy our knows
ni rooms from the building and each room
we have four open Lobby so the totally
thirty-six smells there and so we run
this code through the thirty six mils
and run in network and to control node
and or enter by being we through the
impurity architecture which provides a
test bath and we are able to flash
models and also reading the 0 output
front melt which are asked to know to do
some analyze about network performance
and in the next slice and we the the
experience that has to face first we are
waiting for all knows synchronized and
building networks and the figure on the
right is showing the structure of the
networks after the routing is
established and by default there's a
background upstream traffic around one
packet per 30 seconds upstream
transmitting and to generate a
downstream traffic and we just using the
ping command provides by the OS and
we're paying to a one home node
be 5f1 there and with a spade of one
pain for two seconds is roughly once
loved one packet of course offering
duration and the reason why we only just
paying this first hop now it is the
experiment that's trying to show the
crowning correctness of the MSF
downstream epic adaptation and so we are
recording the data such as the traffic
changes which is when the pain pinkman
stars wind pains ends in terms of Numb
transmission per seconds and also the
number of th cells including the auto
txl and negotiate T Excel to see the
changes of them cell according to the
changes of the traffic and in the next
slide was showing the result so there
are four figures here and is grouped by
two on the left side figure I'm sorry
yeah but I guess we have a question and
the Trevor my name is Ryan can you go
back to the previous slide also why did
you choose there get to be a target
without the children I without children
I was noting tenth the thinking the idea
is I won't just won't choose the first
hop one I think if you have a children
or nowadays it doesn't really influence
the behaviors but maybe your question is
a y note paying a second elope note
because I think there is no different
paying the note with children or not
just calm it maybe it
better to choose the target with at
least one child like in the lesson that
left most part I think mm-hmm yeah they
feel pained and note because the the
first time not a will respond pain Iko
Iko response is actually there's no
traffic into interactive with the second
that the children of the first hope
knows right I think they just kinda fine
right in your picture you say that the
target is f1 but on the text you say
it's seventy one which is on the left
and so the question is I'm sorry yes I
that's a title sorry yeah thanks for
pointing out which one is a typo by the
way is it so is it twenty one that I
fight to target everyone is the one is
target probably the okay probably here
is a the I didn't fixes a typo here you
can see these figures on the top is
saying bf7 one yeah I think this is just
a typo it doesn't influence the results
so so there's a four figures here on the
left the results for his de Groote and
on the right side is the result for its
target and for the upper figures that is
showing the number of transmissions
during overtime and the bottom figure is
for the number of th cells over time
there are
serve things choose to see and first it
is for the decorate on the bottom
figures you can see is using the auto to
excel as beginning to standing the pain
requested to its decorate which is
showing in the green lines in the figure
and then it installed it to th cells to
th cells to the to the terminals and the
cells are removed from removed from its
schedule and as well on the target mo
side and you can see it installed in an
additional T Excel because as beginning
has a 1 T Excel there so so is a result
with two at the exit there there's a
there's a time for target notes you can
just see it's showing there's a cerise
out there which is as the right
beginning its dropped two to one so I
smelled ourselves faster in there Ryan
here I have a question the the upper
graphs are analyzed using it at all
cells right the uppers the upper figure
is showing the number of transmissions
for all the cells for auto cell yes I
think I think it would be just a comment
maybe it would be a good if you analyze
it per cells right instead of going for
the all cells total cells how you show
if only one so what do you would like to
see from line is for diya
total cell analysis maybe it would be
nice if you just put other per cell
maybe maybe many lines hmm cell analysis
and just a comment yeah I show you here
is trying to using this value to
matching the speed of a the pinging if I
summarize them together you can see the
lines is actually increasing one
transmission for two seconds I was
trying to trying to connect to this of
this lines to the actual speed of a the
downstream traffic yeah that's the idea
to show you some okay thank you
yeah thank you what doesn't show here is
if there were packets which were lost
due to starvation of cells did you
experience starvation like not enough no
your packets and so you have to drop the
packet just that during this experiments
it doesn't occurs it doesn't worker is
because I actually increasing the queue
buffer size I think this is the reason
yes it's just basically it will occur if
the traffic change is too fast for the
6p protocol to allocate its lanes cells
right so if it's a ping and there is a
packet every two seconds then maybe that
gives you enough time to allocate this
the cells I think it's pretty much the
answer so it can only adapt you know at
a certain speed so you changes of the
demand must be slow out and the changes
at which you can adapt to it yeah that's
true okay in a network like this because
the demand comes multi huh
[Music]
yeah so we are running so we believe the
drop to the set the 0-7 version is ready
then we we start a two weeks walking
group let's go around one months ago and
we didn't receive comments either were
responding hopefully people review it in
just no comments and so right after the
meeting this time we will publish
another version there are eight but the
man is just title fixing and to some
more refining is there's no real content
changings and for the current version we
believe is relative to send me to the
iesg
and we need some comments from the
community and also the six eight chairs
yeah okay yes I mean what compressed
called completed without any comments so
I left it kind of opening that maybe
that would be late commands and well I
wanted to discuss now what we do with
this document so we have not getting
commands we have experimental code it's
it does what it's supposed to do it's
just one possible scheduling function it
doesn't tell you that everybody has to
schedule this way so I think that's
that's good enough even if we don't have
come well good let's call commands to
move forward with this document and ask
for publication they wanted to get worst
advice on that there were a number of
people working of our long time on this
document and so as an extra and so
personally if there's not interest in
the looking to progress it I don't want
it but if it's like bunch of
implementations and doing it I think
it's like a mitigating factor so like
you know just try a couple more times to
prod a few people personally the draft
as possible for instance Ryan you seem
to be very interested in this topic
would you would you mind I mean I mean
if we reopen the welcome press color or
you know wait
- to a skull publication would you mind
trying to do a review of it yeah just
you know make sure for you as if you
want it to implement so so Ryan is an
example of somebody who read it and did
not ask funny change in the walk of
Lascaux because he was okay with this
back that's fine so it's really a
question of you know it's just sentim
sure it's fine and that's it like I I
don't mind like just doing you like the
I'll you get I your to the review for it
anyway so if you find like one of the
people who look look at it and say it's
okay and this has been a long-standing
work in this working group program we
started with other documents which
migrated into this one I mean it so it's
been a long-standing and there are
multiple people working on it I'm pretty
confident it's quite good and then it's
like a no - repo you
somebody could devise another ones
that's like we impose that everybody
worked this way it's just just
totalizing at its one possible way of
doing this job that's fine and as long
as you document like in the Shepherd
right up the implementations as well
let's could be very useful like you know
the question comes up why it's it needed
okay so thankful if you can send out the
implementation info to like or past
color Thomas L know who's gonna ship at
it or somebody else Melissa movie but
this was already on one of the slides
before no no in that Shepherd right I
started actually and all the rest go now
if somebody's interesting in experiment
experimenting with shepherding I can let
the you know give away the job but
otherwise I will be just doing it sounds
good thanks just additional information
also the MSF was implemented in the
sixty simulator and also there's also a
pending
pull request in the Kentucky energy
about it so they're made there are many
implementation of emesis that's what as
far as I know and we have we have a
comment from from jabber
yes Yuki Tanaka saying that he will
review the latest MSF draft and
comments on the mailing list yes I will
be waiting for your review comments
before pushing the button thank you and
so I don't see Michael coming so like we
so before it might be in rats so anyway
I could I could just push these slides
and we can just look at them basically
the work is no more happening at 60 it's
it's all about saying eh it's happening
elsewhere we keep 60 show where as long
as 60 she's interested which it is and
then you know that does not change the
the destiny of six - in any fashion so
basically yes I mean that little to
consider what's going on at at Lake we
need to look at follow-on constraint
voucher which is really the future of
this document that's pretty much it
so if yes the basically the rest of this
session is to talk about the future of
this work and the only document that
could have still be opened in the
working group would be this so can
office T if the discussion leads to -
you know closing the working group then
we'll see if we need to reopen this
document in like or just you know
consider that it's whatever happens in
the other working groups is enough to
cover zero touch description so that's
something we can discuss outline with
the like lectures as well yeah as as you
said it doesn't make a difference to
what's gonna happen - six - and so I'm I
think you can just get started off how
does it stay here well the question to
the room now is do people see that there
is work that should happen in this
working group for which we were not
chartered is there an interesting
discussion that we could for which we
would need to create new documents my
reading of what's going on is there are
two main aspects which I've been
discussed in these three of six station
from which we did not complete work one
was scheduling time slots along a track
and the other one was shuffling the the
cells in order to defeat some some
tracking attacks that was Marcos work
makuu Tanaka's work in both cases it
seems to me that the work is not really
ITF work but mostly I Triple E work if
it happens and so I hardly see that we
need our canvas which other 6-4 under
viewing this work which tells me that
all the work that I was aware of that
was supposed to happen at 6:00 - is now
past well group Glasgow apart from the
zero touch thing which also tells me
that unless somebody just
now to say hey we've got new work this
is probably the last time we meet so I
talked to Eric and Suresh and well the
advice was pretty much this right we
complete the document that we have
running so we keep the mailing list
active we keep the workgroup quoted code
following
see all those documents goes through the
iesg we probably don't need to meet
again as a working group at the IETF
and we keep the mailing list active for
the future just in case that's pretty
much yeah suresh krisshnan so that kind
of makes sense right so one thing I kind
of like I wanna add there is like let's
say in this period we keep it open if
something comes up we will see how
things go but yeah generally I see this
heading for closure
rather than a recharger right well it's
like some amazing what comes up why not
now it's not like the work on all this
is finished like I said we are trying to
create row at the routing area which
will focus on the concept of track and
generalize it over multiple macfay so
people in the room invited to follow the
work which happens in reliable and
viable wireless which is really the
logical continuation of this particular
aspect of the six dish architecture
Marko confirm rise and just comment to
clarify my personal opinion on the
belonging of the draft on circuit of
jamming and schedule shuffling to ITF or
typically I think it belongs to ITF in
fact just reading the introduction from
the Charter it mentions 15-4 does not
define how the network communication
scale was built so this is a kind of a
gray area because the attempt here was
to complete the building of the schedule
in fact second in the latest discussions
we had in the list in the draft mostly
with militia and Michael Richards and we
were starting to think about how to
handle the king as to the keys use for
that permutation possibly to Inca GP and
that working is something is definitely
not going to happen ethically
so do you have comments on that show so
my personal opinion is the document is
like in-between in what considers the
the scheduling part it's more I Triple E
related while what considers how the
schedule is built is related to six dish
so there are both aspects to the story
in my opinion the Rakeem can happen over
here though is there energy I mean we
can you can start to walk using the
mailing list and depending on how that
progresses we can decide to beat again
on this suresh krisshnan so marco do you
think you can split up the pieces of the
draft into stuff that's relevant here
and just put the rest of the stuff in an
appendix so we can so which rough that
because we luckily jamming two things
right well okay so jamming one is
freaking one that's to read different
aspects right so do you want to focus
the discussion on jamming because we
discussed a lot on jamming last time I
talked to him about the details but
there was a big reason why it could not
be done at the apparel a yeah I mean I
need to go through the minutes of
lifestyle because now it escapes my mind
but but you mean the full software
implementation of this sorry you need
the full software implementation of this
the moment some hardware module is
involved we say that really moves to
Italy there was something beyond that
that to do we security or something like
that I forgot do you remember something
about it what we discussed last time
Tarot last time we discussed the you
know Marcos proposal on shuffling that
the time slot to defeat tracking attacks
we ended up with a problem which was
related to security which made it so
that you had to do something at I Triple
E to make it work and I just don't
remember the details of that but that
was my conclusion of last time is if we
go through the minute that we could only
progress that work with changes that the
I Triple E level that
was that's my memory of last time okay
so suresh krisshnan again so marco can
you start a thread on the mailing list
trying to see if there's an interest to
work on this because it may or may not
be relevant is one thing is their
energies and other things I want to see
both of them okay so start a thread on
the mailing list we're not closing the
group right now right so I would think
like probably a year away or something
right kind of the timeline so if you can
drum up support for the work and this
relevant stuff will do it I can start it
again because there was support in the
group with three positive reviews when
authors asked for adoption but there was
never a call happening
yeah but then like I said last time we
discussed it extensively at this meeting
and my memories that we could not do it
here because it had dependencies on I
Triple E that we could not solve it in
this room that's my memory of it right
and maybe wrong but I mean you're
welcome to to to like start a thread on
the mailing list and see where we are
and make sure see if my memory is
correct on this for the scheduling of
cells we want it to do here to do that
work here initially it could have been
everywhere because it's mostly defining
a data model that comes from you know
magical guard up there and it's being
pushed to the devices it's a data model
thing an information model so do we
define this data model information model
at the HF hie I mean it's this gray area
it could have happened here but the
point is we lost the energy nobody
really did anything there that one
document started and they died so
keeping shout out for something and nope
no people doing the job doesn't help now
if we see those documents showing up
then so how it will be in your hands to
tell us then we continue we meet yeah
that's what I said like so marker starts
like to see if there's like interest and
support and relevance and then if it is
we can't we take it if not no right
that's pretty much it like so in my mind
there is no I supposed to you're
shuffling idea which is great by the way
so that's why you get positive reviews
including me there is no position why it
should be I triple your ITF it's a date
about oh now I understand right we don't
want to discuss
actual technology I'm just talking about
the mechanics how we can go about this
right so let's let's do this on the list
like this like few people here that's
like I don't want to make the decision
here but just go on the list see this
interests and then we'll figure out what
to do right as I said we have time time
to figure this out it's not urgent sir
and then there's this question of
freaking so my memory my status in my
own mind of freaking was like most of
the time it's not useful because ASN
will not show up or something like that
everything is useful when you want to
evacuate some devices because that's
pretty much the only way you can get
away you can remove somebody yes so so
what else exactly needs to be done is
what I'm confused so why do we need to
work on wreaking the moment good
membership change you're supposed to
recognize anyway and we found a way to
distribute new piece for this
permutation together with the process
described in code JP and that has some
complications for the moment where you
have overlapping between the old king
material and a new one and we were
starting to think of a way to handle
that issue there were similar discussion
with militia in my own on the list is a
clarification we're talking about
interaction of the permutation mechanism
by Marko and minimal security minimal
security already defines the wreaking
mechanism which doesn't play so well
with the permutation mechanism of
Marcus's correct so if your mechanism
comes into play we will have to look at
keys as well as long as we don't do the
permutation game what we have is good
enough absolutely ok let's retry Frank
stuff but it's not our intention to
change anything in Kahn's opinion the
way it works this is just an extension
more keys to be delivered in the
wreaking messages and how you can make
this very wrecking work it has no impact
on code rip itself does it mean that
everything could be done in one document
that's ideal to me also interpret
interoperability is something we are
quite interested now since the standards
wrapping up and there are many updates
since the last plug test I'm just
wondering is there any plan for plaque
test like 460 Sh well thankfully you can
speak on the elf of tomorrow something
tom has been rereading that kind of
activity yeah so why no for planning I
need to talk with Thomas to see other
plane what I know is a judge is working
on some trying to do some
interoperability with Kentucky
implantation so yeah we may doing
something but I can let you know later
thanks from Deborah we have a question
from Diego - Horner what would happen
with potential new scheduling functions
if they ever appear like we said we have
a mailing list we don't close the
working group we just don't have a plan
to meet next time that's pretty much
where we are right now I mean there is
not enough content that's very active to
justify asking for a meeting next time
unless you know something explodes on
the mailing list and then well so well
on this side which might sounds good so
like a suresh krisshnan so the working
group is kind of gonna go dormant like
waiting for the documents to finish and
if what comes up it's happened before
like same thing happened for dat right
so we didn't meet like twice and then
they did like so documents came up and
they found work so it's really about
like work showing up and interests in it
to keep it going but the default is it's
gonna close if nothing let's say we put
a time line once the documents are done
its closest that's the plan but it's
open until then really do if not
something new comes up we continue yes I
believe that 60-ish was a fantastic
experience it was very interesting in
the fact that it was orchestrating a lot
of work in multiple documents and
providing the architecture that ties
them all together and so that's one
aspect of it the second
spectres driving open-source there were
multiple open-source implementation and
the working group also acted as a hub
outside of the IETF to to integrate
those those open-source implementations
and finally the interaction with Etsy
for all this black test
so those three aspects put together and
orchestrate it from within an IETF
walking Rock I think that was a really
really interesting experience and that
leads to effective code running and
interpreting open-source implementation
and RFC's here and in multiple groups I
think this group did very well and I
wish to thank you know us probably the
best last time we meet I wish to thank
the IDS and and all the participants of
other like like six or seven years for
which we did six - for the intensive
work that happened okay and we are just
scheduling you back an hour of your life
so I would like to say we bit again but
no the meeting is that wrong did
everybody sign the blue sheets everybody
signed
you
[Music]