Oh
hi I do you know how to to mean there is
no left
you know if I want to open I would like
to do you know like different types
that's what I want to do yeah so do you
know how to do that yeah but how do you
write I mean I would like to open each
slide to another tab but I don't want to
waste my time on
oh you open manually all the slide you
don't have the right click and yeah
that's a yeah okay that's the tree yeah
yeah that I think I can do switch
exactly again so what time is it
good evening everyone I think if you're
not expecting to attend the 8th session
then you're in the wrong room
I'm wondering if people on emetic who
can hear me
so please note that there is a note well
that applies to the meeting I think you
you know that not well very well
otherwise just read it very quickly so
starting the agenda I'm going to ask for
who who can be who can play the role as
a minute taker it sounds the mic doesn't
work who could be the minute taker
[Music]
no minute taker who could be the job of
scribe who volunteers for
do we have a volunteer 4-minute taker
and job scribe okay so thank you for
Jessica Chavez crab so we need a minute
taker
no volunteers okay okay so is there a
name anyone willing to help volunteering
to help
[Music]
so no one is willing to help for the
flaminia ticker that would be appreciate
we're looking for a minute thicker okay
so let's start this flame is the latest
person coming agreeing to take the all
right are you are you agreeing to help
the minute taker okay driver so we would
really appreciate a minute Eckhart okay
right okay so that's perfect thank you
so we got jabber
minute ticker here's the blue sheets so
please sign and I'm gonna provide
some time for a band to provide any
comment so the the current draft we have
are the key group calm the group Chrome
OS core and the MQTT TLS profile I
suggest we start with the group calm
yeah yeah you can or do you want to say
something fresh Jessica as you wish
okay so fine Francesca I just want to
confirm with the remote participant if
they do hear me or hear Francesca hello
hi no I'm telling you any did it is nope
nope nope yes thank you so this is an
update to the a ski group document a
quick recap this document to specify how
to get keys and authorizations to group
members to join a group communication
scenario this is the general one and
then the profile the application
profiles define exactly what group
communication protocol and security
protocol are used and so this is
structure with the first phase that is
defined in ACE with the transition
request response and token post and then
there is additional steps which are
joining request response group rekeying
and secure group communication that are
also defined here
so Version three has it's been updated
following reviews of version two so
thank you very much Ludwig and Daniel
for providing those reviews these were
addressed in the mailing list and we
agreed mostly with with the comments we
had and we have incorporated them please
get back to us if you're not satisfied
with our answer we haven't heard
anything yet so we assume that
everything is fine also at IDF 105 there
was some discussion and offline chat
brought mostly from Carsten and Jim that
suggested that we Resta fie our
[Music]
interface so instead of relying on type
of request and response that we create a
restful interface at the key
distribution center and this is the
major difference in this document also
we did what I think our major
improvement on up in Appendix A which
specify requirements of the application
profiles that have to build on this
document we also got a new review from
Jim of version 3 we already discussed
this review with Jim offline and we
agreed on a way forward there is no
major problems with it and also
yesterday we got the review from Peter
so thank you very much we haven't had
time to look at this review comments but
we quickly scan through I don't see any
major issue with it I don't know if
Peters online but if he is anything that
anything is worth discussing now please
come and comment it so we can do that
but yeah some so about the major update
Resta fication so now we we define an
interface at the key distribution center
of different resources so we have the
some number of resources under these ace
group /g ID g ID is the group identifier
and we assume that it
key distribution center maintains one
resource per security group and this
resource supports get and post meta
method get would get the group key
material post would allow a node to post
its own public key to the key
distribution center and the response
will return the group key material and
all the public keys of the nodes other
resources are public key that is under
the group ID that will allow a node to
get all the public keys of the nodes in
the group or request certain number of
public keys thanks to the nodes
identifiers then we have policies
getting the group policies how these are
the finest application profile dependent
then there is something called context
number or CTX num that allows to get a
version of group key material this this
number is incremented by one every time
the group is Rashid and then there is
the node resource or endpoint that
supports get and post methods a member
would do a get to these resource to get
individual key materials to protect
outgoing messages or it would go at post
to request to leave the group and I see
Carsten has a comment
yeah custom moment there are three pairs
of getting post there and I think the
first and the third are idiomatic I can
barely hear you could you speak a bit
okay there are three pairs of given post
there and and I think the first and the
third idiomatic
the second really is one of those cases
where we designed fetch for yeah and so
we got this comment from Jim as well and
actually let's go to that slide they
have it yeah that's the that's a fourth
point using post or a public key
of note seems like the wrong method
James suggested fetch we didn't go with
fetch because that is optional
like in co-op it's not mandatory to to
have like you can have monetary to have
post either exactly the same status okay
I thought that would if you implement
co-op according to specification you
have to have post is that not the case
can I just defines the number of methods
and which of these you actually provide
as a server that's up to you okay Klaus
close yeah I just assumed that like the
beta base co-op implementation would not
necessarily have fetch because it came
later and you know it's not us yes so so
that's why we there is little point to
add something to co-op and and then
continue using the workarounds that were
necessary five years ago so I think we
should just assume it's clear and I mean
it's not not the amount of code you have
to write for supporting this is kind of
very small okay so okay we will add that
thank you for that yeah so this is what
we did so far and then we got we defined
the operations that by specifying what
endpoint to contact so we said for doing
a joining of a group you do this request
for doing retrieval of updated key
material or new key material or public
keys or group policies or in key
material version etc we define what
method on which resource so we have we
have planned the update of version four
following genes review so the main
difference is that instead of having
this node
path we will now have one node resource
per member of the node per member of the
group
so before we had just a node path there
would be the same for all the members
and now we're gonna have a different one
for each member
so instead of using get to get the KDC
to produce and return the individual key
material james's that suggested we use
foot and we use get instead to get the
group key material plus individual key
material that would allow also to
observe that resource and finally
instead of post to leave the group Jim
suggested delete so we thought these
were all very good ideas and unless
objections we'll go ahead and do this
change just to have a sense of the room
is there anyone disagreeing with us or
having any comment with that do do
people have a clear opinion or people
are fine either way I guess that we will
do the update and see if it's gonna be
easier to understand once the update is
done and then following that we will
have to do some update to the operations
yeah this is all covered by the previous
slide as well so there is also some
minor or other comments following Jim's
review so the first one was if the
client contacts the KDC endpoints not on
the secure channel it gets an error for
one and authorized and Jim was
suggesting that we include the AAS
creation hints so the response to the
token post in the errors payload we
thought that's a good idea so second
point is because of the change of three
source from node to the to the node name
every node will need this node name even
if this node is just monitoring it's not
gonna send any message so it does not
need an identifiers for the group but it
does need some type of identifier for or
name for this another comment was about
sending the array of certificate instead
of the UI of key repository refine with
that and then the usual
finally the using fetch instead of post
so we go ahead and do that and also we
got the comments from Peter that we will
add but we didn't see anything major yet
so yeah that's it unless there are
comments or questions from the jabber
may be any any remote participant has
any questions comments okay so I mean
I'd like to understand if the I mean if
if there are any comments or opinion on
how to move the draft forward any
comments so that we can move faster we
basically just need to do this update
now yes
well not but there is no I would like to
avoid that comments comes you know once
so it's it's time to to raise your
opinion if you have any
because man gently for implementers it's
quite useful to know whether a draft
currently is quicksand quicksand or
whether it's ready to implement so I
think at some point we should simply say
okay
we are done shifting things around
please go ahead implement it and then we
read more feedback so I think personally
that this draft has improved a lot with
this update and it's not ready to
implement because we want to do this
next update first and once we have
processed these comments for this update
and Peter's comments and if you don't
get any major objection I think we that
would be that will be it and possibly
before next idea so I would propose that
we actually in the front matter of the
draft at some point say hey this is an
implementation draft so we ask people to
implement it because we are done making
changes on our own and we know would
like to make only changes that are based
on feedback from implementers yeah that
should be a standard procedure because I
think when people implement this they
will find other interesting but they
won't when they think it's moving we
usually do state that when we post the
update on the mailing list but yeah yeah
but I think it really put into the draft
right after the abstract in the note
section sure so do you have any do you
want to implement that as soon as it's
ready or yes okay Jim shot from the
jabber I think a minimum of two drafts I
think he need means draft versions are
going to be needed before it is
considered too
be stable so update four and five I
would interpret it that okay if you get
comments on version 4 and we feel like
we have enough comments sure
so version for tomorrow and five the day
after okay any additional comments so
maybe Jim can you explain why we need a
version 5 so Jimmy's coming based upon
how fast things have been going in the
past and the fact that we're basically
major architectural changes I won't be
surprised if the next version 4 is going
to have to have some fairly major
updates in version 5 before things are
finished okay okay fair enough
and so version 4 when could we expect to
have that version 4 is that I mean a
month maybe a month maybe two no there
is Christmas in between you ain't right
it on the plane okay so December that's
what I'm hearing
yeah sure or generate okay perfect so
next issue is that slide
so I guess this is my chance to point
out that Jim had tried to ask a question
to prompt me about the things I was
supposed to be talking about at the
start when I was still getting in a
little flustered so Jim wanted to ask
when the reviews are gonna happen
reviews gonna happen for the two drafts
that are currently in publication
requested the profiles for DTLS - no
scar so I had sort of been playing those
unhold a little bit while we were
working through the comments on the the
core framework which is in very good
shape I think Ludwig and I were syncing
up earlier today and we have like four
points left that needed a few tweaks so
it's pretty solid and we're unlikely to
need more changes to the framework that
will require cascading changes into the
profiles so I should unhold if you will
the two frameworks they're waiting
review and so I'll select those back
into my review queue I think I've got
two drafts from second vent then I need
to look at first and then these the two
profiles will be after that in my ad
review queue the week when I get back
from here is mostly booked already
I've had people pestering me about
resolving their discusses or my
discusses on their documents but I think
the the week or two after that I should
have time to get back to this queue so
three weeks from now Thank You Ben and
when you we appreciated the good review
you provide hello this is Marco Tioga
from rileys this is another working
document and an application profile base
to support
just closer yeah okay market order from
rice this is an application profile of
ace also working document the support
group was called communication and it's
of course an instance of a scam that's
what that was presented before here in
particular we describe how client can
join an Oscar group in an authorized way
through the respective manager get the
key material to participate in your
communication secure with group of score
and as a current group member also have
further interaction with the group
manager to get latest updated new key
material and so on according to this
flow chart the were a few points raised
at the previous meeting on this draft
just quickly not on them we are still at
meeting for the time being three
different alternatives for the join node
to agree with the group manager on the
exit algorithms and related parameters
used for signing in the group that we
believe can definitely coexist we solved
actually the other three open points on
how to signal the exact encoding
protocol the keys in a group and how the
client can prove up process can prove
the possession of its own private key to
the group manager
upon joining essentially through a
challenge from the group manager plus
it's a month and we are also now
mandating that the group manager
preserves the very same sender IDs group
members in case it fully Ricky's and the
group of course thanks a lot for the
review gave us actually right during the
the past meeting that we processed for
this update on top of that we introduced
also coordinating with SQL comm the
concept of group name that now has
nothing to do with the oscar group ID
not to mention we were tools previously
use 0
by the and so on this is just plain
important identifier that is used to get
the access token to present the group
manager and then later on to refer to
the group the journalist was just
renamed as group membership resource Koz
is not about joining anymore for current
group members that's the resource access
to to have further more interaction with
with the group manager but that's just a
matter of renaming and we are providing
an example path for that and then we
have a number of profile specific
qualifications on the behavior and the
duties of the group manager as
responsible for checking compatibility
of public keys in the group against the
ones provided by the join node upon
joining and exact Asians it has to take
upon a new node and not joining the
group or current member leaving the
group of course now this is also lying
with the rest base product considered in
s click on that Franchesca presented and
we reference to that couple of details
we were signalling the exact encoding
publication in the group considering
values for the CWT confirmation method
registry so we we get rid we got rid of
the old register we were defining and
just reusing an existing one if there
are no objections we are considering to
recommend the size of 8 bytes for the
challenge nuns returned by the group
manager they'll be aligned essentially
with a choice and there is now in the
oscar profile and we got the question
from jewish out actually for SQL comm
that we think of specifying in profiles
like this one there are cases where the
group manager doesn't actually have the
opportunity to return announced to the
client for producing a signature for
proof of possession like the case where
in the first profile the access token is
conveyed you ready handshake itself in
that case a challenge can actually be
the TLS exporter of the vehicle session
and that's essentially what the nqt
profile is also doing during the join
request same thing we think recommending
an 8 byte nouns we clarify that
signature for possessions computing
especially using the very same signing
key despite the journey not in the Oscar
group and in the joining response when
returning public keys of current group
members to the joining node here comes
about identifying the exact associated
group members which is something the
Prophet has to define and here we're
defining that that identifier is the
sender ID of that member in the group
which is also included into the public
itself as value of the key ID field
according to the same interface of
course it's possible to ask the the
latest key material and we are
simplifying that as happening where for
instance enough messages are failed to
be a correctly processed or verified or
the material the material is expired and
we are also exemplifying the case when a
group member can get back to the group
manager to ask for new individual key
material and in particular we say a new
sender ID and that is especially the
case when the sender sequence number of
a group member robz around so in order
to be able to restore from zero it has
to change its own sender key material
and that can be practically at you
getting a new sender ID and read
arriving it's non center context the
other operation worth noting is possible
of course to leave the group this is
just consistent with the current format
of whisky comm in that case across the
group manager frees up the sender ID
value of the leaking node and unless the
public key of that knot is used in
another group the public is also removed
when it comes about getting public keys
of other members either get all of them
with a get or specifying a subset of
group members the request in all these
interested in having the public keys
again identifying them with respective
sender IDs
implementation wise we have numbering
implementation in californium from rice
it's aligned with this draft although
for time being we are covering only the
joining process full version based
on a post request and currently supports
as associated transport profile used by
the client both retailers profile and
your profile being you
Ludwick sites this address isn't correct
anymore I transferred the repository to
you yesterday
Thanks so of course we'll continue with
this consider especially the full
restful interface for the group manager
other implementations I'm aware of Peter
van der stock in the court and not sure
about the exact status but Jamie is also
kind of working of this so as a summary
most of the update is of course has been
of course updating this draft to the
latest redesign in SQL defining and
details expected from profiles of SQL
come a few open points we have in my not
address for the next update which will
be of course about chasing improvements
in sto comm continuing implementation
and interrupting I'm just so if we use
the the exporter I mean what is the size
of the exposure the GLS exporter don't
remember my heart because I just expect
it to be a little bit longer than a bite
yeah okay right and so these are the
questions you're raising or I mean is a
right there are no objections for anyone
we plan to go like this how does this
move it so I'm coming to it after some
time I may need some hand-holding here
isn't there an implicit assumption in
the whole design that all the group
members use public keys of a certain
type or is it like so if one group
member uses public keys of certain curve
that the other group member doesn't care
about what happens it's up to the group
member to the group manager to the side
was a type of public history
and how they're encoded and it's up to
joining not to comply with that so the
group member can say that you are not
allowed to join the node because you
don't have the public key in the same
format as the rest of the group members
correct I don't see this documented
anywhere in the draft I think this is a
big big assumption that every group
member then would use the same curve so
even if some of the group members have
moved to a curve that is stronger if
there is one or few that that use a
weaker curve the rest of the group would
be stuck to that maybe it's fine for
your use case but at least it should be
documented
what's the quincies were announced that
the group manager and enforces a check
against what the join node tries to
provide and what it is expected in the
group yeah but like you know curves get
updated so how do you now ensure what
crypto agility like I want to move to a
new curve but I am stuck because all the
other group members are are not updating
that was it my way yeah that's yeah is
that how would you how do you think you
is that the problem or how do you plan
to address that we haven't seen like
that so far I think it can be
complicated to admit that every group
member can do whatever he wants
everyone should be in the same page with
final decision the group manager that
can in principle change on the run the
type of public is enduring calling us on
but everyone has to converge eventually
because the the problem I would see is
that if you have device that are not
updated and then all the I mean it's the
least you have the one that is imposing
the weak security that's that so I think
it's it's fine as long as you document
it so just say that the group manager is
the one that decides when we move to the
stronger crypto curve for example so
those which haven't been updated won't
be able to join the group but this is
something that still worth at least
having in the document agree thanks also
provide some recommendations about the
node when you I mean when you design a
node and you put it so that should avoid
this situation that's that right thank
you okay so um any comments I'm just
wondering do you have how would you go
from the the exporter to the eight bytes
do do you have actually a plan for that
there's a user's truncate or that's a
possibility women we won't talk about
that yet okay that's an instinctive
answer to coming from Jim okay so the
NIST has a strong recommendation how to
do that do we have a strong
recommendation how to move from some
bytes to eight it's something that
affects the impurity profile as well I
believe because they are doing the same
thing in one particular proof of
possession okay Jim from the Jabbar the
exporter allows you to set the size for
exporting so you can have it fights okay
so there is no problem I didn't hear
that seems fine so next presenter
MQTT
okay yeah great should I start you can
start oh I mean I am can you order can
you comment the slide or do you ask me
to do I will have to say next slide okay
good
good morning at least for me so I'll be
presenting the MQTT TLS profile of ace
this is Cheatham Cheng from nominate
next slide please so after the draft was
accepted as a workgroup item in Prague
in ITF 104 we pushed two major changes
based on Jim's and Daniel's very
extensive comments thank you very much
for that I highlighted the major changes
it's just sampled there have been
various different minor changes as well
the first version in the first version
zero one we've revised the order of how
we present the different versions of
MQTT and the solutions we provide
through ace we make the MQTT version 5
the recommended version and explained
the interactions for MQTT version 3 wine
as a reduced set of interactions for
backward compatibility we also clarified
which endpoints are used between the
different entities in version 0 2 again
based on Jim's comments we clarified the
different methods that the client can
use to authenticate and authorize over
at Els and MQTT and moved the old set
info explanation for token transport
from the appendix back to the main text
next slide please
so one of the questions that was raised
in the reviews was it wasn't clear which
end points and which protocols were used
between different entities we clarified
that between the client and the broker
which is the resource server in our
profile we mandate the use of mqtt over
a TLS and the communication is published
subscribe
we also use HTTPS between client and
authorization server and HTTPS between
the resource server and the
authorization server but we of course
accept the possibility of using other
protocols in between client and
authorization server and resource server
and authorization server including co-op
I mean could you see but it was out of
scope the description was out of the
scope the reason why we went with these
choices when we were describing the
profile was looking at the MQTT broker
implementations in the practice and
noticing that they already support HTTP
based back-end communication like the
mosquito broker we basically also
described the profile with the JSON
encoding but of course it makes the
ports Ybor and we followed again the
same with the tokens JSON web token or C
board web token with proof of possession
one thing that needs to be clarified is
based on the discussion between high
nests I think that was raised whether
the descriptions for pop for jot is at
the same maturity as in this workgroup
and whether we have to be making more
clarifications or waiting on other
solutions from other work groups next
slide please
and for the client in a second for a
version version or two the major
clarification was on how the client
authenticates and authorizes to the
resource server and looking at the
different options through TLS and MQTT
and and this was a table of course
produced by Jim as well we basically
looked at the four options the case
where there is no authentication in
either of the layers this represents the
public topics where there is no
permission required to publish or
subscribe and also it describes the case
we're all set info following the
security properties of the core draft
indicate the recommended and described
authentication method
is in the in the draft is anonymous over
TLS and ace authentication in for the
client where the client provides the
token during connecting to the mqtt
server broker we also support the case
where token is not provided and this
triggers AAS discovery for the case
where the authentication is done at the
TLS layer we basically have the same
descriptions based on the DTLS
authorized draft where there are our PK
or PS game modes supported in the case
of our PK the token must be provided
through the outset info before
attempting the connection and for the PS
K it can be of course provided over the
PS k identity when both are used to
authenticate the client we say we should
this should not be done this is over
authenticating the client and we
described it as token in connect would
overwrite any permissions during the TLS
handshake next slide please
for the outside info this was described
in the appendix as a possible solution
if when the authentication is happening
over TLS this follows the similar
descriptions in the DTLS profile where
it's the same security properties as
well
it's a publish only topic about D broker
supports nobody can subscribe to it
other than the broker itself and in the
cases where this publication this
published message is sent with the
quality service level higher than 1 the
broker may also return a response code
not authorized however there is a slight
meaning difference here because in MQTT
they're not authorized represents that
the publish message is not authorized
not that the token is not valid so there
might be something to consider here to
clarify in the draft and the broker
stores and indexes
all the tokens and then find the clients
during the connection based on this
index next slide please
for the case that we describe and
recommend in the draft the
authentication during the ACE and MQTT
handshake when the client sends the
first connect message we assume that
they took that there are two ways to do
it the first case where the client
passes the token as well as it's work on
tongue challenge to the broker and then
using this proof of possession
information the broker validates the
client and the second option is a
challenge response handshake but where
the client passes only the token to the
broker and then broker challenges the
client and expects a response that it
can validate the proof of possession we
described two cases because the first
one is the only available one to the
Infinity version three one one mqtt
version three one one does not support a
challenge response flow but it can be
supported in the MQTT version five based
on Jim's recommendations we've
considered the challenge to any using to
communicated through the TLS exporter
and things but we decided here as was
this you know also raised by the
previous presenter whether this
challenge input should be configurable
should what lengths should be
recommended
I was thinking 16 bytes but maybe it is
to come to a group consensus or what we
recommend in terms of challenge sizes
and of course we will also need a group
input on whether we describe this
correctly and what kind of labels we
should be registering for the TLS
exporter label the same length issue
also is open for the challenge response
flow which is the second option next
slide please
for just completeness like I'll describe
the case where there is no token but the
method of authentication is a nice
in that case the broker will return and
not authorize connection acknowledgment
and it will use the user property in
MQTT defined - for the broker to provide
additional information to the client and
AS creation hints and be put in here
again this is not possible for MQTT
version 3.1 which doesn't allow
additional information to be put into
connect so it will be just a disconnect
and not authorized for infinity version
three one one next slide please
so at the moment we basically revised
extensively the draft based on the
chairs comments and we basically think
that there should be some clarifications
needed in the way that you know length
of the challenges and the TLS exporter
labels and whether we've explained the
different encodings correctly and how
the proof of possession is done I think
that needs it still checked up a bit
more and implementation wise there isn't
prototype implementation for NPT version
three one one but we've started a
collaboration with Edinboro University
which is looking at implementing the NPT
version 5 version and I think Jim is
also working on an implementation a
question to the group whether the draft
should stay at quantize like this or
should it also include the payload
encryption for the published message
based on the group comb draft so those
are all I would like to present today to
you
thank you have any recommendation from
the room Francesca is coming hi
Francesca just first a note about the
fact that the encryption is not exactly
in the a ski group calm is in the pub
sub profile that is individual document
right now yeah it wouldn't even need to
use the a ski group calm for that and I
do think
yes I think that would be good to have
to describe that Oh
for mqtt as well so okay yeah I support
that which means we have to wait for the
website to be published if we do it if
Signum defines that for mqtt referencing
the pub side profile then yes that would
be you will need to get the pub sub done
Jim from from the jabber says I think
that it can be done in a separate draft
without any issues yeah and talking
about that just um from from me now yes
he can be done in a separate draft it is
already in the pub sub it could split
out of the pub sub and we did discuss
that before in this working group and
the recommendation was let's not take it
out so yeah we're going back and forth
with that but yeah I have a comment on
was like six yes it was right on the
right side that proof of possession mode
so you returned the challenge and rated
by the broker and you sign or Mac that
challenge alone yeah you may consider
what we are doing in in the profile I
presented before where something similar
happens but what the client signs is
actually that challenge concatenated
with announced it generates of its own -
oh I see yeah I've considered - a
similar option as well I think I'll take
a look at it mm-hmm just because it's
better to avoid pushing someone to sign
something not including something
generated by a by itself - I understand
I say in that case probably it will
to whatever is passed through the tls
exporter maybe because it's something
that both the client and the broker
knows but yeah that's the way everyone's
cryin generated you know it's just fine
generated okay the thing is that then
you have to include that nouns generated
by a client also in the second response
you send to the okay I think that's
possible in the o'the data in MQTT I'll
take a look hi this is mode can we go
back to the last slide so again
pardon me for my lack of knowledge but
what's the use case for encrypting the
published message would it still be
discoverable after decryption or what
what's the use case so the publish
message this is basically addressing the
comment where the broker sees everything
that is published as a payload to a
topic in that case the only the payload
will be encrypted and the published
topics will be visible and only the
clients that are authorized to read what
the message is about can read it but
they can still discover the topic itself
so it won't affect the topic discovery
it won't affect the fact that broker
knows it's received messages to that
topic but it will affect the brokers
ability to read those messages okay
thank you and you had a question in one
of your slides which concerns the length
of I think it's similar to the previous
presenter where I was curious whether as
a group we're recommending a length for
challenges and I would like to make sure
that the district is basically agrees to
whatever is agreed in general in the
group yeah so has a group any feedback
to provide would be helpful
Benny's coming to the mic bank a doc we
had been Caidic we had a little bit of
discussion of the jabber room and
seeming likely that eight bytes is gonna
be the right trade-off here okay thank
you good so Mohit what's the reason for
picking eight bytes is it saving some
message processing because generally the
trend is to 6 to 16 and above so I'm
trying to understand why we are settling
with it and I had the same question yeah
so the idea is that this is a very time
limited challenge and so you get sort of
you get you're getting like the channel
binding sort of property the attacker
would need to guess the exact value so
uniqueness as opposed to collision
resistance so you don't need the
birthday attack at the birthday paradox
attack strength reduction and because
we're in a constrained environment you
want to save the bytes basically we
already have precedent for using like
the eight by authentication tag for CCM
and like I'm not super happy about it
because I'm used to the the big iron
cases very confuse the big novices and
not have to worry about it but given all
the president I think the the trade-off
is likely to end up at eight bytes so I
think that you should cut you should
have a security consideration at least
on the size and explain because I don't
see why what we're defining in this
working group cannot be used outside of
the constraint device sis so I think
that was being commenting in the
security considerations another question
I had was whether this should be
described
as length as of the challenge
configurable with a minimum size
recommendation of 8 bytes it sounds
better would you want it configurable
like on a per broker basis or a per
group or like broker broker basis I was
considering that as a per broker basis
suggestion when it is
you mean per day for broker deployment
where the broker would basically tell
what input challenge sizes it expects I
that's what I had in mind when saying it
but you know the main point is to be
clear about let's go that is perhaps a
little more flexibility than it's clear
we need but it's also not clearly wrong
so we can talk about more all right
think about it I guess but can't think
of any immediate attacks but I think
there's no reason to do this flexibility
if you're happy with it just stick with
it don't see any reason to more than 8
16 32 or con as I said can't think of
something immediately but may cause us
trouble later on ok I prefer to keep it
simple I just want to make sure that
it's future proof basically and it's a
fits to the protocols that is included
in the draft ok so I because I'm hearing
different things so
I I understand that having an 8-bit
8-byte it's not a problem
here is there anyone an understanding
something different so we can keep it
that way that's my understanding
yeah I'm um I don't know if you see the
room but I don't hear anyone saying
otherwise so I guess you can't go with
eight bytes okay do you think you can
provide an update let's say in December
I should be able to yes no problem okay
so my expectation is that this draft
needs
maximum to more version before the
working group last goal mm-hmm
when in December and another one in
January because everyone everyone's
gonna review the draft in January so
okay so thank you very much thank you
[Music]
bye-bye and
so now I sweep I try to keep my computer
open but is always in sleep mode anytime
I want to look at the agenda so yeah so
you're gonna do this one so yes first
document that is not a working of
document of this session the pub/sub
profile for ace I just wanted to add the
slide about motivation and a quick recap
so this document defines how to use ace
to authorize nodes and Parisian keys for
co-op pub/sub it also defines how to
protect coops of communication using
those keys and this second part can
definitely be applied to mqtt as well so
it was submitted the first time at IDF
98 so it has seen quite a few review
updates it also got several news it got
positive feedback he got support during
previous meetings and has been updated
according to the updates on a ski group
um
look could you make sure you check the
jabber just in case thank you okay
thanks so there is some related work to
this document the core co-op pub/sub
that is an adopted working group
document and i hope it's gonna be done
soon and then the mqtt pub/sub that is
an ace adopted working your document so
I only have this slide the status is the
document is updated version six complies
with a ski group comm there is a plan up
data version seven which is keep the key
to the update to comply with a ski group
comm we would like to or I would like to
clarify and expand on the fact that the
protection of content applies to MQTT
pub/sub as well as co-op pops up right
now it's not it's possible but maybe
it's not clear enough in the document so
I would like to clarify that and
possibly improve on encryption and
content protection also if possible to
get reviews from the mqtt authors to
make sure that they satisfies what they
had in mind and before I do so I would
like to get adoption from this working
group so that we can move forward so
know it yet again can we go back to the
previous slide so I understand that coop
ops of an mqtt pops up are different or
there is some some details that are
different but architectural II there's a
publisher there is a broker and there is
a there are subscribers so is like I'm
trying to understand okay the difference
between how the keys are used for MQTT
so and and let me just say something
that yeah I try to express in previous
meetings but it's good to recap here as
well this draft is basically two parts
the first part is a profile of coop
pub/sub as MQTT has a profile for MQTT
and the second part is how to use those
keys to protect the content of the
publication and that part is applicable
to both MQTT and pops up because they're
all pub/sub so you can use that and we
did have discussion before we go back to
should we split it should we not split
it should we keep it together should we
adopt one to both I don't know so we had
this discussion before
and the result was yes we want this or
I'm recapping what you know you can find
in previous meetings good feedback yes
we support this no do not split it
because this is simple enough to have in
one document so I would be supportive of
adopting this document and I still had
one question about the first first part
so you said it's it's a profile of coop
pops out yeah what does that mean
it's profile of phase four pops up so
it's - so is it a lightweight profile or
is it defining how to do security for
coop pops up and the original coop pops
up has no security there or is how to do
ace to get keys to pub/sub clients so
publish and subscribers thank you thank
you
because moment in the same vein when
another pub/sub comes up I want to do
this for MU P what do I have to do the
second part would apply of this document
because that is general pops up it's I
mean if there is a content there is a
broker publish a subscriber you have
keys you can use that can I use it right
away or do I need this glue that is in
the first part can you use it right away
or in the first part now you can use
that right away okay you mean with mqtt
yeah like any pops up so the underlying
question of course is there are forms of
pops up they don't have a broker and
well then I guess you would depend on
what is the structure of the pub/sub but
this is about in
of content you know generally yes you
can use that yeah that's what I'm aiming
at that the very old part here really is
the the content interruption so if I'm
using 0 mq with norm which is a
reasonable way to do pops up I this is
really just multicast groups and and
some people central the Marty has proven
some other people are receiving from the
multicast group can I go ahead and use
this yeah
[Music]
seek them from the jabber the name of
that draft is pops up
something-something will that change if
it also describes stuff applicable to
MQTT she was under the impression that
this or rad the stuff are applicable to
amputee t like the payload encryption
would be described in the mqtt TLS
profile so I'm not sure I got all of
that but the first part was about the
name of the draft which at the moment is
coop yes because that was born as a
profile of coop pops up yes when it
starts now to describe things applicable
to we can change I didn't think it was
necessary because you know it's just
being updated I was hoping we would get
it adopted so at that point we can also
consider changing the draft name and
then the second part was yes she was
under the impression that this
description of payload encryption would
go into the MQTT draft so I mean we
discussed it before in a previous
meeting me and her write that this is
applicable to both like this can be
reused in in MQTT I just put it there
because I thought that was the
simplest thing to do to have it in the
same draft but before like I mean this
is not even adopted working group
document I would like to get it there
before we can we think about how to
reshuffle things around switching to the
gym shop I would like to see a single
content encryption format for both
versions and not a different one for
each yeah but that's that's the idea
I think it's right now the draft is
written as it only applies to co-op
pub/sub and I plan on clarifying that's
not the case but it's already not the
case and another hat switched back to
Signum she would be fine with that
having one yes yeah just make sure that
it's somewhere where the MQTT
implementers will find it yes Kirsten
yeah so the question what do we put
where and when and so on mostly is a
question of timelines and who gets
normative reference as to what and so on
so III think that should be solvable the
question really that is not entirely
clear to me yet maybe that also was
behind Jim's question was is the the
interface between the second part and
the first part sufficiently well
understood excuse me is the interface
between the second and the first part
sufficiently well understood that I
would be able to just go ahead and to my
0 mq profile next week
I think so if you don't think so please
let me know that means we can improve
you we simply have to test that that's
my goal anyway so so I would again asked
chairs for so as anyone who read the
draft
I think Francesca as well yeah I think
so
also several people who are not present
I know for a fact that Gemma has read
the draft that Peter has read the draft
demo so okay so I think we have who
would be against a call for adoption
against yeah I guess a draft being
adopted against adoption
no no I mean I'm asking if anyone as
anything against this document being
adopted before I start the call so
basically if you have something against
this talking being adopted go to the mic
and explain so I guess otherwise mailing
list anyway okay so my guess is well I
think there is no need to hum because I
don't see I mean I don't see any purpose
of having a ham here we're gonna provide
we're gonna send that to the mailing
list and so well what I like is that a
few more people read the draft and who
would like to commit to review the draft
once adopted okay we got four okay so
Klaus Marco Carson Mohit I think that's
one point is that and anymore please
Signum yeah I don't know she she tears
I'm willing tearing her so we will yes
thank you okay so we will move for the
adoption on the mailing list thank you
and and yeah for now I keep it as one
document and I hope when we have
synchronized with MQTT authors and move
forward with adoption we can really
discuss if if the structure of having
these two parts in the same document is
fine or not yeah thank you okay so I
mean I'm probably this week or next week
I'm gonna start the cool adoption and
we'll see where it is
let's go profile market Lanka this is
another profile vase but the transport
profile vase
in the original sentence like your score
profile or details profile and this is
about enabling a client and the resource
server to communicate using Oscar or
grupo score especially at the previous
meeting we were asked especially to
clarify the applicability and the need
for this and to fix a possible
vulnerability for impersonation attacks
so why do we need this you have group of
score for secure communication among
group members point is how do you
enforce access control a given group
member access the resources at another
group member in a group and you don't
need to do big things in some simple use
cases where essentially being authorized
to access a group and get in the group
key material is essentially fine to be
authorized to do anything at any
resource at any group member and you're
just fine it's not fine
in other use cases with we need
something more complex and you need to
individually authorize each client to do
particular things at other group members
essentially you want to distinguish
different clients per different access
rights they are supposed to have
practical examples that we improved in
the introduction of the draft first
example thing of a set a group of logs
and you want some class of clients to be
able to check the status of locks only
while other clients can be able to check
the status and also change it so think
of different kinds of users like
children or parents or especially you
want the logs to actually act as servers
only so not to be able to open lock
other logs in the first place a more
complicated use is really the building
automation was provided but they problem
from botnet there are bug net
applications where you may have a class
of clients like light switch that are
supposed to perform
only low-priority commands while fire
panels can perform essentially any kind
of emitted commands plus set the system
at the status where only high-level
authorized clients can perform
high-level operations essentially you
want to enforce the different categories
of client to do all the things they're
supposed to do so you need fine-grained
access control that you can in fact
achieve using ace and that being said
then you have a problem because current
profiles of ACE don't enable a client
and resource server to use group secure
communication even if you consider the
Oscar profile you go for it a client
post an access token to a server they
establish a no score context they can
use Oscar but at the same time they
cannot legitimately use group or score
as an alternative or at the same time
they have to stick to the single
protocol indicated by the profile score
so bottom line you cannot have together
group of score for secure communication
and fine-grained access control and for
three days and this profile is exactly
about fill in this gap it builds over
the Oscar profile latest version
essentially admits to communication
protocols in the same profile or score
and group of score assuming both parties
are already in the correct Oscar groups
so like in the Oscar profile first of
all they establish a pairwise Oscar
context of course and then the idea is
to first bind the access token not only
to the pairwise context but also the
group context and second to bind the
pairwise context also to the group
context so you achieve the same
properties you have from the Oscar
profile plus essentially proof of group
membership of the client thanks to the
binding between the token and also the
group context how is this achieve
it's about slightly extending the
messages of the Oscar Pro fellows and
essentially and the derivation of the
pairwise context so in the access token
request the client provides the es
also the
it uses in the Oscar group the group
identifier and its own public key
together with the signature completed on
something the slide using its own
signing key essentially to prove the AES
possession of its own private key what
the sign well what we are proposing is
using something related to that secure
association between client and
authorization server for instance if
they are communicating using the TLS
they can assign an exporter if they are
communicating using a score they can
essentially provide an output from HK DF
extract involving information related to
the pairwise Oscar context between the
two laying around the AES produces well
an access token response back to the
client that includes again those same
parameters provided before by the client
and those parameters together with the
public key of the client are also echoed
into the access token that can be the
later on delivered to the resource
server this is essentially the outcome
of input and discussion with Jim in
order to avoid a naughty group member
another group member in the same group
of this client essentially impersonate
is client using the wrong sender ID at
least this way you are providing the
resource server with an opportunity to
check that the public key in the token
actually matches with a sender ID that
comes in the token in the salt parameter
then your sinusoid derive a pairwise
Oscar contest between client or server
just like in the Oscar profile
considering just a few more pieces of
information when composing the
parameters that are used for deriving
the pairwise contact so essentially the
context that is composed not only of the
analysis exchanged between the client
and the resource server but also of the
group ID of the Oscar group it was
indicating in the access token the salt
is composed also of the sender ID of the
client in your group and if not empty
the masters although the Oscar group
the master secret is composed
considering not only the master secret
indicating with the token but also the
master secret of the group and then the
context is just derived according to the
derivation procedure of Oscar as an
example that of course hides a lot of
all of the low-level details here we
have a client series for servers
assuming all of them already in the
oscar group the client asks for an
access token so indicating also its own
sender ID in the oscar group and the
group idea of the group and that
information is echoed back also in the
access token then the client posts the
resource server one exchange if Nancy's
derivation of the pairwise Oscar context
as described below
well the client repeats the very same
procedure to post an access token to our
sto and of course the Scopes here can be
different in the T requested access
token
they also derive a pairwise context and
at this point well we are admitting by
construction in this profile that it's
fine for the client to communicate with
the resource servers either with Oscar
or with group of score and in this
example there's a first Oscar request to
our s1 followed in by a multicast
request targeting the whole group so
both our s1 and rst that of course is
protected with a group of score
context so you can enforce fine-grained
access control with specific groups with
specific scopes as I agree with the
tokens so it's a new proposed transport
profile of ACE essentially for having
fine-grained access control as expected
in ace plus clientele resource servers
that can use model your score has only
possibility right now with the profiles
available but also group of score it's
supported by at least one real world use
is coming from back net and we are
essentially pairing the group in the
pairwise context as well as the token
with also the group context this is an
update that replies to previous
questions comments we got there was
meeting now we'd appreciate
reviews to this document
this is been kenick so I have to
apologize I was just looking at this
stuff for the first time like today
and I'm you're generally in favor of
fine-grained access control and whatnot
and all this good stuff I'm just trying
to understand basically why we need both
this and the stuff we already have and
is it may be that there are some devices
or situations that can do the sort of
base group communications with us car
but they can't do this or just it takes
time longer to develop group score as
such doesn't cover access control it's
just about protecting messages so that
can be processed by a group of devices
right but you know the work that you
just presented is is overkill for
situations that could use that but would
it still meet all of the use cases that
did that would you scale that I could
require right in production and one of
them is actually coming from buck net
where they can't imagine a problem like
this with different classes of clients
that you need to do or not do different
things so you won't go enforce this
level of granularity for access control
so you need something like ace right I
guess my question would be more like if
we did this document and and like threw
away the other one who would be sad
which is the other one the Oscar group
communication that does not have fine
granularity oh that doesn't cover this
that's about authenticating the client
to communicate with the group manager
just forgetting the crema the key
material to get into the group this is a
cluster about what happens after that
I say okay thank you I'm sorry for my
confusion thank you
so there's no fair lapping at all this
is just a continuation of our timeline
so today
so I'm just gonna ask how many people
have read to draft
are you cool with her Francesca
yeah Jim okay so my guess is that it's a
little bit too soon for the adoption but
I didn't want any comment or anyone and
has any what obviously are there any
reasons you didn't read the draft or
it's long I have to admit okay
is there anyone that's gonna read the
draft mm-hmm I hope people on me take
all the people on mythical we're gonna
read the draft yeah I think it's for now
it's a little bit too soon that's my my
opinion but the thing is that the
problem I have is what to expect for the
next time that's my okay okay so I'm I'm
I think for today it's a little bit too
too early to to to have planes for the
adoption or not adopting the draft but
I'm I would like that Marco can at least
have a clear plans on what he has to do
for the next step so so just for the
record for from the Jabbar there are two
reviews okay
actual reviews so and are they happy
with the draft or they will be coming
they will read the draft they thought
they will they come it okay good so I
think that Ben is a point we should
clarify better at what point of the
lifetime this comes in okay yeah yes so
I think you know what to do
and please update the draft pretty soon
so that the people that come in to
review don't forget they have committed
and Francesca got the names of the
people that committed so yeah so I think
next step is to maybe update a little
bit a draft but I mean don't overkill
and then I mean more people need to
review before we can proceed to the
adoption I think that's the if anyone is
find the draft I mean use less I mean
they have to stay it as a as soon as
possible
okay so when are we expected to finish
now so can you say a few words briefly
about the two remaining drafts yes I was
next presenter than was about Ludwig
okay but we okay so you can do this one
yes be very very fast yes just a few
words this is another restful interface
for the oscar group manager this is not
intended for candidate group members or
current group members like the profile
we presented before this is intended for
an administrator that as the first thing
wants to create those core groups set
update their configurations and
parameters and possibly delete oscar
groups it essentially describes
resources in the group manager for doing
that and operations on them for an
administrator acting as client that of
course is to get an access token to be
able tries to do that at the group
manager first of all the idea is very
much inspired to latest intended
redesign of the APS for a co-op pops a
broker in fact you can see in this
picture on the group manager we propose
that a single clip collection resource
and then one group confirmation resource
for each created active Oscar groups so
essentially on the group collection
resource you can send a get to retrieve
the list of active groups or you can
send the post to create a group
specifying the name and its
configuration parameters and we are
defining how to default to not specify
parameters and the response back will
include as a confirmation the name of
the group and the parameters enforced by
the group manager in the configuration
that is possible of course to retrieve
the current configuration or update it
or to delete the group just
acting on the resource specific for that
group so interfacing the group manager
for the application restful for
administrator wrist will create
configure delete Oscar groups as far as
I know Peter when their stock has an
implementation already in the Corp plan
to start one in California on the
recommendation from Jane we started this
as an experimental document so I wonder
if this is appropriate or can instead be
a standard track document we ask for
reviews okay good yeah
so very quickly draft basically it's
about being able to get notified when a
token affecting you gets revoked so the
idea is when token is revoked the client
or the research server that is affected
by that token wants to know about that
and why are we not revoking tokens at
the moment there is a draft
RFC in off but it's about the client
revoking its own tokens when it doesn't
need them anymore but in IOT space we
think there are use cases where the AAS
or the resource owner would want to
revoke tokens and then how did the
client and the resource server learn
that and the idea is when you register a
client or a resource server at the
authorization server you create a
resource and this resource is gettable
or get observable in coop
by the client or the resource and on
this resource the AAAS publishes which
tokens are revoked and not yet expired
that's the short version do we need a
longer version eventually
try to spencer curity question ludwik is
it bound to IOT devices or can this
notification also be used on the big bad
internet but currently it's defined for
co-op so thanks yes you can use it but
it would be easy enough to define
something similar for HTTP but currently
the draft doesn't okay
Thank You Ludwig thank you all for
coming and I think the meeting is
adjourned
so read the drafts