[Music]
sorry hello welcome to debt net we've
learned something at this meeting you
really don't want to be the session
right after a really nice snack break
because no one shows up so we have much
less people in the room than we normally
do but we really appreciate you showing
up we'll get more done that's right so
I'm Lou burger this is Yanis parkas we
have our secretary Ethan
Grossman here and our welcome to that
Matt what's that okay can you hear me
apparently I have to eat the mic welcome
to debt net our agenda is online and as
is our working group information please
take a look
this is towards we've been here for a
few days so everyone here should be
familiar with the note well if you're
not please be aware that everything you
say here becomes part of our record and
that we have rules governing
contributions and if you're unfamiliar
with them please take a look at the URL
at the bottom of the page ITF goerge
about note well dot HTML for the meeting
we are streaming video we're recording
also the everything is available via
YouTube or audio download we are also
using our joint minute taking via ether
pod
please join in and help make sure that
your comments are accurately captured
and just help us out to have accurate
minutes really appreciate that the
agenda is online and the blue sheets are
circulating please do sign the blue
sheets that helps both identify who's in
the room as well as how big a room we
get
we have two sessions the first session
you're here now so thank you
agenda is unmodified so this has been
what's basically been posted for a while
for the second session this is the
second session great we've had a little
bit of a change the one number ten and
bold is in addition a late request that
was added I think we've been doing a
better job of using the list as well as
incremental meetings or periodic
meetings among working group authors
that all of those are advertised on less
than open to all we've been doing a
pretty good job but it's really
important when there's a discussion to
use the list as much as possible that
ensures that well for new drafts and
ensures that the working group is aware
of what you're doing for working group
drafts it helps ensure that we have good
communication and good agreement and on
the drafts and as we know we're here to
have a consensus on drafts to submit for
publication as RFC's we follow an IPR
disclosure process here I think most
people are familiar with it at this
point but basically we do formal IPR
calls at both adoption and last call and
response by all contributors and authors
is required in order to move to the next
stage whether that be adoption or
submission to the IESE for publication
since the last meeting we've had three
RFC's published so that's that's really
great we we sort of were a little slow
getting going but now we are pushing out
documents which is a reflection of the
work that those in the room and those on
the list have helped us achieve so thank
you for all your work we have a number
of documentaries
that have gone through last call we're
gonna talk about status on those we
don't have to talk about details on them
and they're on the as I said they're on
the agenda we have some document we only
have one document that's not on the
agenda that's the bounded latency we
don't do we have anyone in the room who
is a bounded latency author Ethan is do
you know what the plan is for Sean
sorry not Ethan Sean what's the plan for
the next update of the document please
come to the mic and let us know
state your name and tell us what the
plan is the next step yes some mama who
from epfl
the idea is that for the next draft for
the next ITF you are planning to
finalize some sections that are related
to the calculation of the delay bound
which is mostly some mechanism that is
the depth that can be used in debt net
and we hope that we can finish it in
IETF 108 which is in I guess to have a
final version of the whole draft to be
to go for the next level right and for
the current for the current state we
have some terminology update and some
consistency check for that net based on
the other drafts that is existing and
that's it great thank you for that they
appreciate it
so where are we in terms of our
deliverables and milestones we had a set
of core deliverables that were called
out when the working group was formed we
are really in good shape compared to
where we were let's say a year ago we
have our overall architecture published
we have the core data plain documents
that have passed last call and the the
debt net over TSN was the first
technology subnetwork technology that we
had called out and we those documents
are closed you'll hear from the authors
how close we are hopefully we'll see
something IETF 107 that we can get to
last call the flow information document
also is proceeding along and we do hope
to get to last call there was some
discussion that you'll hear about
between the flow information model
authors and the yang models authors and
there might be some additional updates
based on that the egg models were is on
the agenda and that's in process the the
other part of that was pretty important
that was called out in the Charter
and my initial milestones was the
security document and we're looking to
do last call by IETF 107 that too is on
the agenda we'll get an update one of
the points that came up with our Adu is
whether to do an early review or just a
standard review from the security area
we're actually going to request an early
review as soon as the authors tell us
that they think it's good to go so we
have a question of what's next and this
question is based on who would like to
contribute to what and then what the
iesg says is our ID say is acceptable
work activities for the working group
and we've thrown out a couple of items
and the this the the intent here is to
spend a couple of minutes just getting
the reaction of the room but will a mean
towards a Charter discussion at the next
meeting and some of that Charter
discussion may also bring in some of the
results of the raw Boff where that
discussion was really I took it as debt
net over wireless my are no last week
for myself and you can agree our hope is
is that that is becomes a complementary
activity whether the isg chooses to do
it as a its own working group or within
this working group either way as long as
the works done I think will I think we
should all see it as a benefit so that
maybe also something that brings in that
we'll have to watch what happens with
the isg is the result of the of that
Boff so Lou Anderson I'm obviously not
up to speed really so the security
document what state is that in now very
close really close to what you guys
cause okay I don't have a look at either
microphone or away from the mic
okay david black yeah told me security
documents oh yeah a lot of good work on
security documents lot of good texts in
there however one of the reasons
requesting an early security area review
is the IHF version of no battle plan
survives initial contact with the enemy
we could see some interesting things
come out of that review and the sooner
the sooner we learn that the better
great thank you
so one of the reason one of the items
here was a set up for someone who we
thought would be in the room but instead
we'll just go talk refer to his may list
so greg mirskiy sent a comment to the
list about the OEM for MPLS and document
and we had oh here he is and we he
didn't come to the mic so also we'll
talk about it
so the he's gonna come to the mic so
they will give him a minute
Gregg Marissa tea well their authors
believe that om for dead net over in the
West Network provides their needed
technical solution and the document is
stable and we would like to work in
group consider adoption of this work
okay thank you we so we had talked about
this at the last meeting and there was
some moderate support the issue with why
we didn't do an adoption until now was
there was very few people who would read
it the people who had read it seem to
have liked it but very few at this point
our feeling is we're gonna do an
adoption call and see if there's
sufficient support and if there isn't
we'll go we'll go from there right so if
I may lean in really close because I'm
sorry there's just a lot of noise but no
don't get close because there's noise
behind that be calm okay
because actually I hear it's very well
miss so that's why I'm stepping back
because okay so you probably aware that
there is another document for om over
death net IP I've sent some proposal
because in opinion of offers there is a
big challenge technical problem of
mapping or a.m. session between and
points are on to their death net IP flow
that to be monitored so I send some
proposal appreciate your comments
thoughts let's discuss it in the mailing
list and then once we reach some
solution that we agree with then we'll
get to their consideration for adoption
of second document it's great I really
appreciate you fostering the discussion
in that area
I have hunger I have a question about
the chatter actually we eat bean
it helped me well we are contribute in
the work of SR v6 bass that's not and
the others including me are very very
confused whether this part of work it
belongs to the current chatter or it
will be included in the rich header part
I think it's a good discussion to have
one of the things that we'll have to
work out is is that work happen here or
in spring
generally the if you're talking about
new data playing mechanisms you go to
the group that owns owns that unless
there's an agreement to do it elsewhere
right now they own the data that data
plane so we would need agreement from
that working group to do it here without
that agreement we're gonna assume that
it's gonna you would have to do the work
in spring so the new there I believe you
have a new data playing mechanism and
that probably will have to be done there
but it's a good topic to raise and we'll
have to work that out with our ad and
the ad of that group it's a different ad
so we'll have to work that out of where
the work happens actually I am totally
okay with doing that job being spring it
doesn't matter but I think because the
MPI is a face that than that and
ip-based and that belong standard so I
think maybe naturally as a six basis and
that should belong to ten that as well
so I'm little confused and considering
that it is very busy in spring recently
and we have a time slot in spring in
previous session but there is no time
left for presentation and I think even
we have some time slot there will not be
a lot of discussions on that I think in
the current spring stage right
you have to go run over there it is
happening right now yes so as as the
older I prefer to put this part of work
in 10 L first I think sure but you the
chairs or AP have other suggestions we
can't discuss yes it's near technology
they're really gonna have first say oh
so it's really gonna be the working that
working group chairs call and then the
ad is call I think you know from our
perspective like that we were talking
about related to wireless we'd like to
see the work done and where it happens
is secondary but okay but they they sort
of have to say they don't want it before
we can say we want to take it okay so I
will talk with the chair self a spring
first sure and if that will be something
that we'll also talk over with our D
Deborah okay okay thank you
all right thank you any other comments
please feel free to make also follow-on
comments to the list another great way
to ensure that your topic is included in
the discussion for IAT f-107 is to have
a draft that you can an individual draft
that you bring forward and submit
towards the debt networking group that
will help us make sure that we don't
miss your topic the this is our last
slide on the administrative piece we
want to give the working group a heads
up that were talking about doing another
joint session with with I Triple E at OU
2.1 TSN we had a really good session in
Bangkok after the IETF at the start of
the the Bangkok I Triple E meeting so
that was exactly a year ago and we're
going back to Bangkok next year and the
I Triple E is meeting the week before us
so the thinking is we would like we'd
like to propose and investigate doing
another joint workshop or meeting on the
Saturday before the IETF so the I Triple
E ends on the fryer
we would immediately the next day we
would have the this meeting that's the
straw man proposal this is not yet
confirmed but we wanted to first let the
working group know that this is being
discussed and second just get a feeling
from the room of how many people a
participated in the last one so that'll
be question one and then question two is
would be interested or I'm not like
we're not looking for commitments but be
interested in participating in this next
one so well how many people participated
in the last one okay so it's it's a
small number but reasonable set and
interested in the if we have one next
year think they're they might attend so
a bit more so that's that that's helpful
thank you Greg mercy City question two
chairs you think it will be the same
format as more lecture or discussion it
depends a lot I would love to see more
discussions yes that was last time that
was the the first of this occasion and
maybe we should figure out ways to
foster more discussion okay depends on
how many people show up and we were when
we started we envisioned a small group
and it turned out to be a really big
group yes and that makes it a little
harder to get the discussion but it's a
it's good input that we should figure
out how to have foster more to spell I
think it's okay that we have the first
more like introduction to technologists
so might be in the second we can do
something for both parties
more like go for papers and people will
submit some proposals for the shorter
presentations so basically break it not
a big presentation that does an overview
over technology but people talk about
specific use cases and problems thank
you for that
good ideas okay we're gonna move now on
to the the first topic which is the
framework hi hi my name is manoj welcome
i will share you where we are with the
data paragraphs the first presentation
is about the framework you might
remember that we have decided to have a
building block approach regarding the
data playing drops so that is the first
of the a draft I will speak about each
of them so let's start with the with the
framework the current version of the
framework document is version 3 this
content is quite stable and it it is
providing an overall framework for a
deterministic network data plan so it is
covers the concept and the
considerations that are generally common
for any of the data animistic networking
data plain specifications inside the
document we have sections dealing with
the.net data plane there are some
encapsulation related consideration
deadness specific metadata's are also
covered we have framework topics on the
IP data plane and MPLS native line and
also some functions building blocks and
scenarios are covered like Service
protection aggregation and systems and
some network in the document we have
also a section dealing with the
controller plane considerations we have
the chef area review for this document
and there was a very last call it was
finished and the beginning of
Dober and we have received pretty good
comments how to improve the documents so
all the clarification a deteriorate
changes are resolved in the version 3
which is the current version so based on
that the authors think that it is ready
for submission for the EIS G so that is
the current status on the framework
document and it questions comments ok so
the next summer is about for data plane
documents two of them are the IP and
mpls data plane and two of them are
related to subnet scenarios where death
net nodes are interconnected over sub
network for each of this document we
have a version 3 and we will go through
all of them in the death net IP data
plane document it is specifying the
death net data plane over an IP packet
switch network in the current
specification of the IP data plane and
the format of the death net flow we
don't have a sequence number so that
means that from that perspective we have
only forwarding sub-layer related
specification also the death IP data
plane procedures are described and we
have also section dealing with the
management and control information
summary based on the feedbacks and
discussions on the list there were one
technical change in the document and it
is related to the ECN that ecn is
omitted from the flow identification
possibilities and there is also there
were some recent discussion and on the
list regarding the use of the five
topples and this is what I have
highlighted at the bottom of the of the
slide that in order to maximize the
reuse of five double based Mahoney's and
solutions it is envisioned that an
system and that net application should
not mix that net and known that not
traffic within the same singular five
that work the next document is the MPLS
data planning document it is dealing
with the that net data plan when we have
MPLS based at work in case of MPLS we
have description for both sub layers for
the service sub layer and also the
forwarding sub layer and also the data
plane procedures are defined in the
document so the flow identifications we
are using labels and for the segment's
number that not control guard is used
and similarly to the previous data plane
document we have a management and
control playing related considerations
in the document during the change of the
document there were only editorial
changes and fine tuning so the technical
content of the document has not changed
when we have created the version 3 and
now let's speak about the two data plane
documents which are dealing with subnets
scenarios the first is the IP over MPLS
document in that case to death net IP
nodes are interconnected over MPLS
subnet so that is the scenario but the
document covers it is describing the
data plane scenario the encapsulation
and it is also showing four IP over MPLS
procedures how the flow identification
and how the traffic treatment is that
and again as for all the data plan
documents we have a management and
control information summary the same
apply for this document as well and we
have created version 3 there were only
editorial changes and fine tunings in
the document so it is also pretty pretty
quite stable and last let's speak about
the scenario where to mpls that nodes
are interconnected over IP subnet here
is a failure on the figure so death net
over that net MPLS over that IP is what
we are covering and this is also the
procedures that we are describing and
here again for preparation for the
controller plan discussions the
considerations regarding management and
control is also included in the document
that is that document had also just
editorial and fine tunings when we have
created the version 3 so it is quite in
a good shape and in a stable format so
currently with the version 3 of these
documents the Shefford view were done
and we have also a very brief last call
it finished 11th of November so this
version 3 is the latest version included
all the comments that we have for the
document during during the work and the
others think that these documents are in
a pretty good shape so that they are
ready for submission to the ESG and it
combines questions there was a comment
that came in this week the IP document
you want to talk to that yeah this is
something I have highlighted on the
slides this is not yet included in this
format I will make a version for for
that document in order to make that
happen and there were also comments
regarding
references normative and informative
references I think this is also
something should be cleaned up that was
also recently on the under list okay so
for the last slide you said that it's
ready it sounds like there's one more
version before yeah it's ready but I
think we know exactly that to do word by
word with that document so this is via
thing that yes when that version four
are created then it is ready for the
submission okay maybe we can get it done
by the end of the session more but well
things are going on well we'll make the
changes and push them and get it
published that's that yeah as usual all
right thanks okay any comments questions
just a note it turns out everyone up
here is a contributor to this work so
Ethan is actually shepherding this and
sort of owns owns the documents from a
process standpoint so let's just want to
make sure everyone knows that and Ethan
do you want to add anything not really
except that these are the first Shepherd
write-ups I've done and I still have the
marked as you know waiting for review so
I I appreciate a little bit of input
just to make sure they're everything's
consonant okay
okay and now let's speak about three
documents where we have was a new
content from the compared to the
previous version and they are the TSL
related documents so we have two data
plain documents dealing with that over
TSN subnets scenario when we are
interconnecting IP or MPLS that not
nodes over TSN network and the last one
is dealing with the scenario when TSN
domains are interconnected by a dotnet
network for these documents we have
version 1 version 0 was created after
the split of the IP and mpls data pin
solution documents and these are
practically the new documents for the
documents we have created a new document
structure that is valid for all the
three and we have made at several points
clean up and we have also filled up with
some tags where we had not yet text so
there are new stuff in these troughs
first we speak about when to IP dotnet
nodes are interconnected over a TSN sub
network because we are speaking about
that net IP data plane they should take
only about the debt net forwarding sub
layer so this is what is covered in the
document service protection is not
possible end to end however in the TSN
sub network this is something what you
can provide when you are interconnecting
the IP that net nodes on the right side
you can see the structure of the
document just below here you can see the
scenario so this is the TSN sub Network
and the two IP that not poles are
interconnected
the concept to describe this scenario is
that we are focusing on IP that nodes
which are TSN aware so this is something
you can see here on the right side so
this is the TSN of our talker or
listener so this is the role but IP debt
net node place from the TSN sub network
perspective we have also collected the
management and control information
related aspects because you have to map
the debt NetFlow us to TSN streams when
you are crossing that that sub Network
the document is containing requirements
for the for a TSN aware IP dotnet node
such nodes are member both the
death-knell domain and the TSN sub
network within the TSN sub network that
IP that not node has a TSN a vertical or
listener role and the death net flow IDs
and the flow related parameters
requirements are met two related TSN
Stream IDs and stream related parameters
so this is a requirement that we what we
have to solve when we are speaking about
management and control plan
there is also some interesting scenario
when you are triggering the setup or a
modification of a TSN stream in the TSN
sub Network and this is where management
and control plane interactions might be
required between the death net and TS n
sub Network the document does not have
any requirements on TSN unaware IP that
not nodes because you have no new
requirements on them however this is
something that we have marked in the
management and control consideration
that in such a case is it might be even
more problematic or more complex to to
start
such a triggering between the two domain
because the IP that not node is not at
all aware about that sub Network the
second sub not related scenario is
covered in the in the next document this
is the MPLS / TSM scenario where a TS
and sub network interconnecting two MPLS
dotnet nodes they are speaking about the
MPLS data plane so both the service and
the forwarding sub layer are described
in the document you can do service
protection both in the TSN domain and in
the MPLS that not domain however has
Service protection interworking can be
made this is something that is left for
further study in the current version of
the document and here the concept is
very similar to the previous one so you
have your MPLS that not node and it
should be a TSM ever to occur or
listener from the TSN Sun network
perspective so again you have to map the
MPLS death net flows to TSN streams in
the network so that means that that
these MPLS that not knows has a TSN ever
talk or listener role the flow ideas and
the related parameters have to be mapped
to the streams and the related
parameters and if you have to change
anything you need some triggering and
the interaction between the management
and control plane of the dotnet domain
and the TSN domain the same statement
applies for the TSN aware and pls that
not knows as I have said in the in the
previous case and just highlighted again
that the Service protection interworking
scenarios are left for further study
but not least we have a data plan
document dealing with the scenario had
to interconnect TSN domains over that
not MPLS network in this case the
concept is that the TSN stream what is
there inside the TSN domain it is
treated as a dotnet app flow and the
death net domain behaves like big fat
TSN relay note from the TSN domain
perspective and the service proxy
function this is what is making that
mapping of TSM streams to death not
flows and this is what can be treated
like like a port in that big fatty SN
relay not so but we are defining in the
document is this Worr concept is
described and also the TSN over MPLS
data plane a procedure I defined in
detail there are some TSM related
functions that not serve a related
service proxy related functions data
service and forwarding sub layer also
described in detail and the Service
protection interworking is also left for
further study in that case but might be
interesting to highlight here that we
have slightly modified or created this
scenario specific version had this proxy
is working with the TSN side of the of
the network if you look to for example
to the architectural document there is a
high-level figure here in this document
we have a much more precise depiction of
those scenarios again management and
control plan related consideration you
have to map the data that flows and the
TSN streams and that mapping is
something what is happening at the
service box
a function of the mpls that not H node
and that that not H node is a member of
both domain and it is acting from the
TSN domain perspective as a as a tsa
relay node here again we need some
interaction at the management and
control plane when a TSM stream is set
up modified or tilled land you have to
know it in the MPLS domain and react
accordingly and just again highlighting
Service protection interworking is left
for further study so this is where we
are with these documents but we intend
to have as a next step to collect the
feedback from the group that there
whether there are any missing items or
something but you would like to describe
in more detail or somewhat differently
and then also to add the conformance
language to these data plane documents
so that is the plan
questions comments Ethan Grossman I note
in the security consideration sections
of these various drafts that they're
they're quite small and in looking at
the security considerations for the
other data plane drafts the iclicker
data planes IP and mpls we've been
looking in the security group for things
that are time-sensitive specific and
data plane specific have you given much
thought to that are you confident that
there isn't anything specific to the TSN
of the security considerations for fir
these or or do you think that that's a
subject that needs further study this is
something that needs further study so we
have identified that this is just
something to be to be done in the future
versions so this is something to be done
okay so presumably we will fill it there
is a section waiting for that in the
security yeah and so presumably we're
going to fill it in there
yeah one question that came up and just
discussing the structure was well say we
publish the security considerations
draft then we get another data plane
like some wireless thing or something
then obviously this draft will be closed
so everything will have to go into the
data plane specific document so I was
just curious whether it's a good idea to
keep using this model or whether we
should figure we're going to migrate to
a model where that information that's
specific to that data plane goes in the
data plane drive I think at the point
it's for further discussion so I'm happy
to have any working solution in order to
fill out those sections and being in
line with the other documents so okay
can I just have a communication to your
question so you because actually the
security document was gated by the base
data plane actually and the architecture
and my understanding is you want to
avoid any kind of situation like saying
this is it for now in the security
document and from a borderline if there
is any new data plane draft that has to
do with its own security considerations
did I get to find that that's what you
are after yeah I mean I don't see how
else to do it unless we pull all the
stuff out and and it's just it goes
there now but since those drafts have
already been last called
and we couldn't find anything anyway
we're sort of in at the moment we're in
a consistent state because we couldn't
find anything but if we go forwards and
we do find something that it might be
interesting but my view is is the we
have a base set of documents we're sort
of the foundational documents and as we
move forward we can either refer back to
those foundational documents and say
those we addressed the security
considerations there or if we identify
something new we do that in the new
document we do have to make sure that
those foundational documents do
adequately cover the security
considerations and we will do that and
do it early review as we talked about
and make sure we have a nice consistent
security Directorate review of all the
documents and they'll keep us honest
just to bring another example I mean SR
v6 contributions as a new that no data
plan I think there's that s our v6
document should have its own security
consideration complete that's my
personal view okay so I guess for the IP
and mpls that one maybe do we cut it off
there and and say or do we include TSN
and then cut it off after that what is
there right now basically in in oh in
the TSN one no and no security in the
security document do you cover TSN or D
coverage yes there is a placeholder that
says to be written so it's like
something that is there's nothing that I
would say cover the core technology and
move all the TSN considered security
considerations this the TSM document
okay I think the way then that way it
covers our core technology only okay
done and if you'd like you can make a
statement that that will be covered in
in the technology specific documents and
for example the TSM and that would be an
informational reference okay great so a
timeline what are you thinking in terms
of having a version that you believe is
stable enough for last call for the TSN
documents your media I think we need at
least two meeting cycle I'm sorry did
you say one or two I just don't do
meeting side because that that we do my
expectations all right great so
targeting where we Madrid yeah Madrid
okay how many have read this version of
the document that's really very few
clearly these documents have not had
adequate review to really know what the
working group thinks about to the
working side
no no from a process standpoint I would
hope for one but two sounds
we'll go adjust our milestones
accordingly I think you know aiming for
two is better I think the next what we
can discuss is when we have most of the
conformance language so that I also
expect some and some further
consideration so this is why I think
that at least two cycles okay keep in
mind we are contribution driven so if
you feel like you're willing please
review the document if you see things
that you'd like to see changed please
send this suggested changes through the
list you do enough of those you get at
it as a contributor or an author so
there's opportunity here some go I just
suggest that maybe we can send this part
work also to the actually because I
think TSM people may very interested in
how to do the mapping between the tenet
and Tessa because in the previous joint
meeting a lot of people they are they
are curious about how to use their three
deterministic technologies and how to
use them with TSN so I think maybe there
will be a lot of potential view
reviewers there yeah actually that is
just a suggestion okay so this is just
as once we have a stable document to
send it to the I Triple E or is the
suggestion to send it to the I Triple E
as is and say please help us
yes know which one is charge for state
wait for stable or I think this this
version is good enough and so I heard
the author and by the way I'm not an
author on these I heard the author say
that he'd like to get the serious review
once the conformance language was there
you know so maybe I think I would like
to also call like the feedbacks in
general right I prefer the practice of
sending a stable document to another
musician so it's written maybe is better
to do it like it becomes more Steve I
mean without conformist language
actually I just want to perhaps the mold
reviewers will they will give more
feedback to other drafts but I think
when the draft is they Bowie is also
okay good suggestion thank you very much
any other comments okay so the next
topic is update on flow information
without I will talk about a bit of
reminders what it is about and then
explain the updates of draft and and
what are the next steps so the focus of
this document is so the the flow
information as the title says plus the
information mundo for the service and
this is from the from the document that
both the figure and the text what is an
information model and what is data model
so the subject of this document is the
flow information model and the service
information model and data models are
the subject of the yank document you
will hear about after the my
presentation so what happened since the
last IETF we had version four for the
last IDF and two updates since then
version 6 and version 5 in version 5 we
had a number of editorial updates
in up in the language and current many
clarifications in the text and in in the
attribute formats for example making it
clear in that well-known names are
attributes and the formally empty
placeholder Security section has been
filled in security considerations have
been added and these were mainly
contributed by Dolph Eric who is now a
new co-author of the document in after
that in version 6 practically speaking
there was one technical change a new
attribute has been added for IP flow
identification the IPSec spi this is a
security parameter index which is a kind
of an identification tag if IPSec is
used so that has been added to the
parameter list for fly identification
and just a reminder this is the
structure of the attributes this is what
we is captured in in the draft so as I
as I said the key parts are data flow
and the service information with the
parts but it's very important input for
these how how we describe up flow
application flow and this is many to one
mapping from left to right so multiple
up flows can be mapped to at that net
flow and wonderful data flows can be
mapped to the net service so where we
are what is next this first question we
keep repeating to the group and this is
there any missing attributes and this I
would like to ask people to review that
often and then we give comments on the
last two item actually we had a working
session as you saw an email list last
night and it's very important that to
ensure
that this document and the end document
absolutely in line actually we find some
gaps kaesong we'll talk about it in the
next slide in detail and this leads to
the other question we told before that
it's a the flow information model draft
is ready as is for working with plastic
all now actually I would say after
filling in these gaps between the two in
some form
we think that authors think hey we are
close and ready for working class Co so
that's it on on my side
David David black I'm not correct merci
I'm gonna ask an OEM question anyway and
this is actually a bigger scope question
of which is the car which is the horse
and how do we cope with it which is MPLS
om looks like a fairly clean add-on via
the ACH IPO am looks like anything but
how far along do we have to get with IPO
am to figure out that we don't need
anything else it's probably gonna be
turn out to be mostly in the IP data
playing draft if we wanted up neat
needing to do something clever about
flow identification get the OEM flows to
behave how do we skin this one that's a
good question and actually I haven't
really seen the discussion on this in
the list so yeah that seems to be a bit
of an open question
no ideas have been bought so far and
that's a good question in the sense of
how do we get done because as you my
understanding of Greg's points and
proposal was to not to bind together the
MPLS and IP om but let the MPLS OEM
progress and then progress later as we
can with the IPO am yeah
the one question I heard from your point
is should we hold the flow information
whether
until we get done with the I promise I'm
not sure what I'm suggesting we're
observing is that as you said the
Empress om OM is clean it's pretty clear
that that that know how to tag the head
identify the OEM flows as Oh am i my
suspicion is that Greg's proposal
affects IP flow identification and hence
is gonna hit he's gonna hit the IP data
playing draft is gonna hit this one and
I do you want I guess the question the
to you is chairs is how how much do you
want somewhere i the choice is something
like do we push pause and unscramble
enough of only Emily we know what its
gonna look like
or do we carry on get the get the IPD
deplane done and then come back and
figure out how to do OEM possibly
revenue IP data playing if necessary so
so i think you're really making a
comment on the two talks ago not this
one
quite possibly but uh as good an excuse
to ask anything as both as its gonna hit
both rash right sorry i have to eat the
mic this is an interesting question
as chairs because we're also
contributors to it so as with the chair
hat on and with what we think is the
consensus of the working group and i'm
stating it so anyone can come to the mic
and tell us we're wrong including the ad
as chairs we've said we're going to
define the core get those out and keep
pushing along and duo a.m. when it shows
up
we've also has made the technical call
that OAM is going to have to follow the
path of the flows so has to meet our
flow definitions and we certainly have
had some conversations of ways that
could be done but we don't have a
document it at you know greg that's the
status right we don't have a document
that gives us an answer yet so we don't
have confirmation of that
okay I think it's a stand point we're
saying we're gonna move we're gonna move
forward and understand that OEM is gonna
trail and yes we understand that there's
risk here and it's important for the
working group to understand those risk
here and okay
I think it's a question which is that
that the working group consensus is
believed to be that the IP data plane
draft needs to move forward without Prok
without further further delay as OAM
gets unscrambled if it impacts the IP
data plane we get to complete we we get
to come back and revise that and deal
with that when we get there right and
just for your information I even had the
conversation this week with Greg about
it some of our thinking on this is to do
wait David I'm answering your question
if you're distracted you're not going to
hear it
Stewart let me finish so the the the
thinking is on OAM is that we'll end up
having to do some wider flow rules that
cover both the OEM traffic and the six
tuple for the data flow and that's
probably as good as we're gonna get now
we're gonna have to run that through the
whole process see if anyone has better
ideas but that's what we think we're
gonna sort of the direction we're going
to end up so maybe I stepped at the
wrong moment or something this is a
pretty jet lag meeting but there isn't
even a way for regular IP of getting an
OEM message to be congruent with it this
is way more fundamental than any problem
we're trying to solve here and that's
why I gave the answer that I just did
which is the only thing we have is is we
can have multiple flows be congruent by
adjusting our flow rules yeah I mean I
just think this is so hard that we know
how to do it for MPLS but oh but for for
IP I don't think there exists a solution
anywhere in the ITF I agree and so the
question for the
working group is do we not push the data
plane the IP data playing document
forward and wait until we have an OEM
solution or do we push it forward and
try to align our OEM solution with the
IP document though that's the question
for the working group and I think you've
heard what the chairs think the
consensus is its opportunity of the
working group now to say disarray okay
what I think I heard is the latter which
is push IP data playing doctrine phones
make sense and revising senior remarks
like I would say aligning and modified
aligning only with IP data plane
modifying the IP data plane if and as
necessary so as a contributor like I
think we we had a good job and effort
actually made effort to make the IP data
plane in line with IP principles and I
think it's good to go and if we develop
OAM it's a hard problem but that should
be in line with IP principles anyways so
please scale to balance we you mention
you asked is all the possible wave
signal in your flow well listed in this
document and there's another one which
is actually not listed I was just
wondering if you're interested in adding
it to it so if you have a ripple domain
and so you're using ripple to to do the
routing inside that domain then there is
work at a troll which actually enables
to what do what we call rod projection
which is really installing a route from
the roots directly into the network and
this this rod is what we call a track in
six dish it's a complex route have been
something very akin to what we do here
and it is signaled in the packet using a
hop-by-hop header which contains some
information which is akin to a vrf
information so our local and global he
arrives so the local ones really tie the
destination of the packet which is the
exit of this track with a number which
is locally significant there and that
basically tells you which routing table
you need to look at for the spider and
you can have huge numbers of those
things in a ripple net
so that's how we actually signor not
really the flow but the path that this
the flow is supposed to go which also
means that you could place the OAM and
the data on the same path and they will
follow it to the destination which is
the case I wanted to give to Stuart that
we actually have one case where we know
how to merge the flow and the IOM into
the same thing so is it something want
to capture here or do you see it as an
exception that's not interesting so one
way I understood what you said is that
that technology is kind of Association
of explicit routing encoded in the data
plane little packets like spring and
with the benefits of making like spring
can be very it's more like what you put
in the packet is more like topology
identification like a v rfid not the
source route path right okay so it's a
different other you just I if you if you
knew about multiple routing that's more
like that yes so so we actually the
mechanisms that we built the IP data
plane on or closer to policy routing so
if you look at policy routing you can do
very similar things and you don't have
to have topology and it you don't have
the topology IDs you have an MRT or the
SIDS that you have in spraying you just
have policies so I think what you're
saying is we would want that we should
pursue a path that maps different flows
to the same basically policy the policy
tells you which flow is good in which
rib and now you stamp the rib in the
packet and the packet follows this rib
the question is this is how we signal
the equivalent of a flow in our packets
it is something worth capturing it you
are missing attributes well that that's
a flow a notification attribute but let
me a flow its topology but I see it's
something below it's not a flow I as a
it's it's routing
kind of remember but but that is that
can be a good
technology choice I would say a lower
layer not seen at the level of flow
information but but if we can maybe
double check offline if what what you
see as a flow information flow idea out
of that one flow plus the OEM into that
particular topology because that's
redesigned for it right it there are
many of them it's design want of flow so
at some point it's family but it's not
the same thing so I think it would be
great if you collaborate with Greg on
his document and try to capture these
ideas and help us move that that work
forward because I think it I think it's
actually quite it would fit in quite
well yes ok thank you Thanks next maxi's
yong-seok a song if you could
oops okay you see the clicker it works
this is your song and I will present our
work about ten and a configuration young
model and thank you for the contribution
of other elders here is the history of
our work this this draft is accepted as
a working group document after IETF well
- and in the first version we separate
the done edit apology young another
document and the yen version - we
received some feedback from the working
group and we update the following
attributes we end the sequence number
generation considering the OEM and we
end then a service decapsulation and
also then I transfer tano decapsulation
in version 3 we do a lot of work about
the configuration structure update in
item well for and while 5 in version 4
which is the current version we modify
the scope of the 10 and Yamoto merely to
go aligned with the information model
work and here is the previous word
basically we define a 10 and a
configuration module which is defined
for that net flow paths built building
of flow statements reporting and then
add functions configurations we defined
through 4 modules inside the this young
model which include the attributes of
application flow survey sub layer and
forwarding sub layer and some network
this is based on the net data plan
protocol stack defined in the
architecture document and in this world
I tried to do some modification to go
along with the structure as the previous
slide show because in the information
model there is that another service
attributes so we end the than a service
module to include the service quality
attributes such as the latency the lost
the miss Audrey and we also end the
endpoints attributes to indicate the
start point and the end point of the
dinosaurus and maybe the encapsulation
type attributes is also needed it can be
MPs or IP and we keep the tended
configuration module stable just as the
previous slides but after some
discussions with the other of an
information model there is a call
meeting and we also meet each other
yesterday and we find that these two
Mojo's models are still not well aligned
yet so the mapping between the
information model and llamado are still
to be defined and we plan to work
together after this meeting perhaps we
will have a call meeting every week to
make this work down and the picture
shows that in the left hand is the
information model we see that there are
three boxes and in the right hand that
is the ten oh sorry I write this wrong
this is the the structure of the young
model and we have four elements so maybe
how to map the information model
attributes to the young model attributes
and make it very easy to understand
there is our next step work and that's
all thank you just to clarify here and
the next step so we are planning to have
virtual meetings working sessions like
we are having for the data plane
announced on the list to move forward I
don't think it will be weekly we will
need to figure out when but that's part
of the plan
David black wearing transport area tech
advisor hat small request
boo-boo top out in the past as you work
towards the next revisions draft which
looks like a lot of work there is still
in this version the dscp and the DSA
bitmask pair that needs to be changed
with dscp list just it's it's small item
that should be double sooner or later
thank you I think we're gonna end up
with a major revision one of the
comments that I saw is it's it's very
flat and not taking care taking into
account sort of some of the layout you'd
want to have an extensible free
foundation for future augmentation and
so I think you're gonna see oh I mean
I'm expecting major changes I'm just uh
let's let's check this box now so we
don't have to go back and discover
whoops
we forgot to check out three versions
from now that's all if I understand this
right I I remember that you have very
similar comments in the previous meeting
so we haven't updated the draft based on
your comments I remember down this okay
just since it's clean major revision
come and let's you simply check check
check the box while were there no
problems okay thank you if you find that
there is something wrong please that has
no final meaning this thank you thank
you so we're actually running a bit
ahead which is right which is pretty
rare which is actually really good
because our tech advisor David black
can't be here for the second session and
really wanted to be here for the
security document if the if even if
you're willing can you go now great so
we're gonna move that slot up
[Music]
okay all right I'm Ethan Grossman and
this is an update for the security
considerations draft so the intent of
the draft is to be a reference in a
toolkit for network designers who have
not necessarily dealt with
time-sensitive networks before so this
is relatively new in the IETF so we
figured we'd have a clearinghouse for
that kind of information so this
document doesn't address the general
considerations for security for IP and
mpls networks we leave that to the
existing documentation we're very
focused on only the time specific
aspects of it and the relation of this
drafts to the security considerations
sections in the other debt net drafts is
that basically each of those drafts is
to have its own security section
addressing issues specific to that
particular draft topic but then having a
reference to this draft to cover all of
the more general technology independent
and and other considerations that's that
way we don't have to duplicate these
many pages in each draft so at the
moment the technology independent
section in other words regardless of
whether you're on an IP based network or
MPLS that section is fairly mature at
this point this drafts been running for
nigh on two years and we've had a fair
number of eyes on that part and if
there's a fair amount of organization
there's a few little bits to fit in and
fill in but that part's pretty mature
the thing that we thought we're really
going to do is the next big thing was
the IP and mpls specific sections we
thought well there's got to be stuff
that's specific to both time-sensitive
networks and the IP implementation
versus the MPLS implementation so we've
had as many people as I could manage to
wrangle into discussing this look at
this and so far the result is that we
haven't really found any unique
that are both related to time-sensitive
and not covered in the general case but
are specific to that data plane so we
have later I have hoping we can have a
little bit of conversation but maybe
it'll just get deferred to the list but
my sense is that if you've ever read
read the Gladwell book about blink
there's this thing where people who have
been doing something for a long time
just have a certain sense of intuition
but it's not just intuition from nowhere
it's intuition from many years of
working on it so I guess what I was
asking is that if you could think about
that statement I mean at the moment our
stance is there's nothing technology
specific about these so we got sections
in the Security draft that say IP
nothing specific it's all just the
general stuff MPLS nothing specific just
the general stuff does that ring true or
does that leave a bad feeling in your
stomach because I haven't gotten anybody
to come with anything specific but I'd
settle for a general feeling about it so
that's just one way to approach what to
me at the moment is kind of an
intractable problem is trying to figure
that out so that's one thing so the TSN
specific section we discussed a little
earlier is not started yet but we're
going to defer that to the the TSN
specific draft so that's off of my plate
good the other thing that is I'm in a
quandary about going forwards is this in
the use cases draft if you've read it
you know that at the end of it I sort of
collected all of the related security
related statements from every other
draft that I could find at the time it
hasn't picked up the new ones lately but
basically particularly from the use
cases draft because they were like all
these little kind of funny statements
and there's not really a requirements
document so I thought well how is
anybody going to review the security
draft without understanding what the
criteria and the requirements are so I
said well collect all these things
that's as close as we have and that way
people can look at those and say well
this is kind of what's expected do we
think that we're covering the territory
so my question is well what do I do with
that stuff I mean do I leave it in the
draft if I do then that's our
a process of updating it and make sure
I've got all the stuff to date that's
been added since you know that was last
worked on which was many months ago or
do we just chuck it and figure it
doesn't really belong in the security
draft anyway
interesting questions to ponder we may
have a second for a discussion if we do
and we'd like to I'd like your
employment I will okay so I look forward
to your input any minute now right now
discussion okay so there were three
questions that I had intended to ask one
of them the third one we've already
actually managed to resolve about the
security Directorate review is it going
to be before after working group last
call and we decided that we would go for
it at the beginning of last call we
would also submit for an early review in
other words it would be four before it
was passed to the iesg we would also
have the security Directorate have a
look at it first in parallel with our
working group last call so I'm happy to
have that result the other couple things
are about the data playing technology
specific things does anybody have any
thing to say about that and the security
related statements from the use cases
any thoughts about that so I did but
some people who drew a blank on airplane
technology specific threats I thought
are come to the mic and explain why my
gut feel is that it's okay or I'm not
really upset about it and let's just see
if I can get somebody up to the up
microphone to debate me and we'll learn
something reason is that the security
reasons draft is very much written from
a threat model perspective it takes a
general functional model of time
sensitive networking and outlines all
the various threats that could disrupt
that at that level it's got pretty
complete threat coverage now if I plug a
data plane in underneath that time
specific of networking I wanted up we're
finding that general function model is
specific manifestations data plane the
threats haven't changed but how they
impact the data plane probably has but
with the security drive haven't been
written with
primarily in terms of threats and not in
terms of specific manifestations in the
data plane the fact that we can't find
any new threats against the data plane
is not that big a surprise
interesting point does that mean that we
should be talking about those specific
impacts on the specific data planes or
does it mean we're sticking with threat
models and call it good
I think you cast a die I think divers
cast awhile ago to write the security
the overall security draft as an overall
deterministic networking security draft
and that leads to its current Phet model
structure so I'm not criticizing that
try and just sort of have a look at is
there a gap there and the answer is well
no it's our they did did did
implementing deterministic networking on
a specific data plane add new threats to
deterministic networking perhaps not
know but I understood what she said I
thought but my question was we haven't
we specifically did not address the
impacts on a specific data plane is this
a place where we should be thinking
about that and not be talking so much
about the threats but about that subject
referred truth and beauty perspective I
would say no that when when you're
looking at a threat to specific data
plane mechanism it's a security
consideration for that data plane draft
so another way of David I like the way
he phrased that it actually triggered
some additional thoughts that I hadn't
had so they the you know what's really
different by the way this is Lou as
contributor or not as chair what's
really different between the different
data planes is how we do flow
identification that's about it and so
maybe we should focus on that and
highlight even in your general section
about technology specific threats to
articulate that the difference between
them is how we identify flows and so the
additional threat there or vulnerability
whatever the right word is is that it it
may be easier or harder or one flow to
impersonate another flow or to
potentially deny services based on the
number of fields that are used but
that's really about it between the
technology specifics the rest of it is
all about service and that's gonna be
common and when we get om done we'll
have another difference right right okay
so the next steps were looking at are to
basically at this point finish it up and
get through working group last call and
security review right thank you so we
still are running a little bit ahead but
I think if we try to squeeze in another
we might run it run out of time in the
session so what we're gonna do now is
break until the second session the
second session is back in this room in
half an hour so instead of a 20-minute
break we're gonna have a half-hour break
so see you all here at 5:40 there will
be all kinds of interesting friends they
really reliable of course they will
delays on TDM that's all well that's
history and that's what people have been
doing that's we're trying to move away
from the other thing too we might want
to watch out for a lot of people when
they think they buy a wire or serve as
an internet service for example from
their a turbulent area
I'll find what they think thereby
they're buying a moment sex right yes
well I'll not even if I mean so if
anyone missed signing the blue sheet
either raise your hand or come on up
here almost like Oh a.m. it's like to a
certain degree you just have to get the
thing out there and then find out what
happens once it gets out in the wild and
isn't limited to but I think a lot of
really new territory