come on Eugene
[Music]
you can get started okay welcome huh
this is the DMM working group meeting
I'm shrinking overly so today
the agenda for today I think before we
get started a few things so please look
at the IPR policy there are RFC
references 3 3 9 7 8 and other documents
please look at please review them and
there is note well this meeting is
dominant of you IET of rules and
regulations you need to be familiar with
these please be please review this
material and a few other things we need
a note-taker place any anybody volunteer
note takers please any volunteers
Dave thank you so much
truly appreciate it yeah so Dave Allen
will take the meeting minutes yes yeah
yeah on the thank you okay and one more
anybody else Carlos no meeting with no
Tigger yeah anybody else
all right so few you know updates these
are the working of documents the first
one is the use of plane protocol and
architecture analysis on 3G 4G system
yes just a Hummer from entity I'm a cosa
of the 5g user prey on Isis draft so as
you may know 3gpp over they started
released 16 in say to the city city
groups we will finish the release
released 16 in London next much so we
the authors would like to decide the
range of the goal of this work so we
continue to update the draft within
ladies 16 and after that we'd like to
proceed it to the next step we believe
that this draft will be help for many
idea first to understand 5g architecture
and use a plane protocol so if possible
we would like to request working working
group last call informations draft I'd
like to know your opinion yeah sure I
think solutions also they're all
straight my opinion so yeah I understand
the status of that work in 3gpp for
release 16 right so I think we need to
look beyond I think the way I look at it
is like you know
so what we can do in the release 17
timeframe that's that's my person I'm
not we have the working group but Suresh
is also there
let's hear what he thinks with ya
subscription responsibility right so I
think like you know it requires some
kind of review from the working group
right and one thing we can do to speed
up the process is we can send an LS
right like if the working group decides
to send earlier since statement we can
write one and send it right but I cannot
see anyway this will be done by March
right of 2020 right like so because
there's like reviews from the working
group complete the working group last
call okay
then it needs to come to me get the
Directorate reviews go to ITF last call
and the holidays Christmas holidays come
in between right
so it's very unlikely that this is gonna
be done before that okay we can do as
fast as we can but I think if you want
to inform the 3gpp officially I think
the best way is a liaison statement but
but one comment before I give it to
settle yourself so it leaves the
dependencies from the spring those are
in a good shape right at least compared
to previous IETF 105 now we're in a
better shape yeah right okay
yes I think this case on our intention
is a kind of the year the others work
based on the end of the state of the end
of the March not to complete during this
procedure or the ITF some procedure so I
the Kokua this time they'll be so we
won't also want to put the milestone two
to finish the walk based on the busy 16
if we they need to think the force
analysis based on the 17 that'll be
another chance to work so if it's like
wouldn't go process yet make sense you
can get it done I know if you need a
following lady 16 maybe 17 so we can
start as a new work okay now let's go
the the status of different working
group documents we talked about the user
plane protocol you
I don't believe your presentation slots
for this right now
for this one right the next one is the
signal routing for ipv6 for mobile user
plane I think there's a good amount of
what went in but any update on this son
this is a presentation start we will
review that it in your presentations
pocket then the FPC document I think
this is a really a bizarre situation
it's a credible amount of work went into
this FPC document but overnight it's
like a turning out the lights write
complete silence on this FTC stuff right
so I think the documents are expired and
you know the FPC work was on Charlie's
request and essentially we split that up
into the young the young portion was
separated out right but I think we need
a waveform for this so I think you will
give an update later for five minutes
update our yes sorry I tried to
summarize the yeah the update on the
Guardians PC I end up with this meeting
so so let's discuss on the how to
proceed or the fate I think we need to
one way or the other closing that's
that's the gist we did these are the
document that have asked what can you
last call I think you know one the
migration is going towards Mike I think
the the chair the shepherd note meets we
yeah so for both of these actually the
first to like the the shepherd right up
is very bad it didn't summarize pretty
much anything about the working group
process and I really cannot put this in
front of the iesg in that state so I'm
whenever you one of you get a chance to
update the write-up I'll try to scale a
little shack and and carlos has been
really good catching up with the
Directorate reviews and addressing them
so so I think it's good and the last one
it's RC so it's like you know it's it's
a it has a number it's a number yeah so
so it's pretty much done deal right and
it's one of the first ones with the
three format of XML - rc3 commentary
yeah so he wrote the the shipper notes
on essentially in just a little bit more
detail right now because it has nothing
about the technical summary because like
people who read the Shepherd write-up
will not be kurta or a C number it's in
the still the publication queue but it
pretty much it's a done deal
it's done yeah good stuff Congrats to
authors on that one
and I think now you go to the the
individual work items right I think the
first presentation is from Pablo I
believe
[Music]
Pablo if you can also it's kind of a you
know that's what change yeah this is a
great this once okay so good afternoon
everyone
so I'm here percent elated for region of
productivity at sorry six more unusual
play since the nice meeting they're
happening to release its so that that
first revision was the relationships you
were reasonable 66 or meet any flex
resistant to do set my rocking and
Eric's version which possibly a drop
there's an employee base six months ago
such good progress is not we've decided
to remove it and then they the next step
on the revision with one stories now
seven more person one so here in the
first changes that we have added a rocky
look so the rocking mode is a mode that
we have been using thought several demos
where we are just which is actually
different world where that's simply it's
just like they give you the signal
routing gateway because we are just like
we overlaid 476 with song and then we
are another star good way to reach
another you care which is more changes
that we also happen derivation of seven
we beat a lot of editorial updates
changes to the terminology some changes
to improve readability and unabated
referenced and then the last important
point is that we have removed the
support for an instructor to use so as
you know in 3gpp there are depending PD
users 346 either veteran instructor due
to some changes that we have having as
hobby six
particularly the conservation of
Internet videos now we can no longer
support a Star Trek videos this could be
done I will be to allocate a new
Internet Protocol number this content
year first eight address
a requirement from the operational
community to support it that we are open
to it or feedback salutes and then the
Yoast of how the wheels participated in
the hackathon this year we had a lot of
progress so finally after several
hackathons we have finished the DVDs
lamentations so we have a coupie
implementation of the code base in this
truck and we have submitted a disco
tutorial sucks when the next weekly
release that will be generating all this
good would be available to everyone and
that said we really want anyone to do
more comments I would be the draft even
though the progress being relatively
stable we believe that it's ready okay
thank you
so from your point of view it's pretty
much in a great shape right all the
changes any dependencies whatever other
groups to this document
like yes so that the biggest of NSA's do
you have a section of your programming
where we also proceeding with ask okay
so any questions comments so how many
people have read the latest version of
the document okay okay we need the few
more reviews common area my I can do one
review yeah thank you Thank You Carlos
so this is a a new talk your topic
this is uh it's still a I individual ID
right now use the plain message encoding
zero zero version yeah I think yeah if
you can introduce a copy what is it this
is the new booty I use the previous is a
four e yeah yes the a motivation so
sweetie sweetie PB is a trainee to
suppose here user premises associated
with you at the TTP youthful so in K in
the case of GSL switch to user day so
this message are also required with the
user frame interlock with the HTTP you
so instead it has a community
definitions so author field has a
capable to indicate the a different
profile you it is SAT there also
oh isn't it here we have the capability
to not see a user community has a
capability to provide the a metadata to
see a polygon so this capability LTS
rate should be leveraged to not hear you
the pregnancy include it's a bit no so
so and also in this approach so there is
no internal header or extension headers
totality any user privacy yeah how to do
that so here's the gdb message format so
or each user per message is indicated
with the a message file
so for example so include request is
using the
other message said and could apply is
using it to as a message that yes yes
yes single headed so single header has a
happiest definition so currently there
is no defined usage a usage of
destructive so obviously in university
eternity a message that put here mobile
user Pegasus so she I see a encoding of
the atmosphere so we are using Apple bit
left
like most pulpit to in Kodiak user
communities so pizza or it won't hear me
- Sophia honey right and it would be
erotic papyrus work and this week and
also some of user Craig message recoil
is here some additional information
arrogance
so all this information element can be
encoded with the SLS Tier II so we are
proposing to at IPS container key away
as a little XD away and also this theory
can can see a multiple of V DP acidity I
eat here with so he is switching with
hear me so oh yeah it's a sub clearly
obvious VDS container theory so however
3d PPI ETA V should be full with the SVG
specifications so user per message can
be carried with the insulate aside what
is
you know the in order to carry a user
pay message although it is a bit narrow
so instead it s on Heather must is
sustained here
although inside of TSA which never so
however so if enabling tear PSD so or in
select header is ophtho as he apparently
signals so in order to avoid here this
problem
so one solution eg a PSP must not be
used in das a bitch now in order to
keratea
use a pregnancy or if in identity a PSP
so another internet should be added to
Cali ta use of a message on top of Gaea
author ID which in a war a celestial yep
so OT our next step will like to adapt
here this dots with your walking the dog
okay MA hi my name is Omar from future
USA I read the draft what is the main
use case I didn't understand for this
like you know you won't remove gtp
completely with us our v6 so some parts
are removed with the current last call
document right I think some part of the
gtp with that's our basics this is a
complete elimination of gtp you is it
character what is it TTP 60 dropping no
[Music]
Nativity period for however so DD b 6e
neatly detail ATT here you'd follow so
we have to keep the required information
inside of it okay
also my was just like it's not written
what I was thinking is there any use
case you are thinking to send the
message with the gtp encoded message
right from the UE itself is there any
use case kind of that kind of thing you
are thinking or this is not from the you
a possibility right with this you have
the real possibility you extend all the
way till understood correctly is to you
know all the path management and all of
that stuff they want to put it back
Suresh suresh krisshnan Just Answer Roma
the reason why you don't want to do that
is like the spectrum is very expensive
right so you don't want to put in all
the headers from where the air interface
right that's why the gtp is starting
from the base station towards the core
network not from the UE that's correct
but you know I think that's only a
service six the only solution that's
really all the way can go to their UE if
you want it right there is no other
solution so but yes spectrum issue I
agree with you it's a good point I thing
you know you can explore int for the use
case so any any other comments questions
yes just I think the information that
gets carried on gtp either things like
the end marker etc they're only of
significance to the G note be that stuff
does not need to be extended to the UE
so any stuff it does need to be extended
to the U is done over the than the PD CP
layer so with respect to currently you
have the pad management that n marker in
marker it's not so but if you take the
the equate questi equal reply gtp is
number of options and all of them how do
you plan to carry all of those options
as I think this is a logical extension
to the earlier work I don't see any
problem I think this addresses rather
completes the whole world but we need
more feedback for the working group and
also you know from the ad and you know
to make this right I think my other
suggestion is engage without keeping the
world can like essentially like you know
we can in our trade off the document
okay thank you
any other questions call here done yes
that is it thank you
next one is a the transport network
considerations I think so this is not a
working document it's a proposal and
position with John McCauley in this
topic is transport network Abed Ruby
Papaji
it's looking iron
okay maybe a slight smell me
if you hold it
now let's give a subpoena okay just a
quick recap of this wrap this has been
presented first in 2018 I give honor to
0-0 version because later mean problem
and strong and solution also it started
updated in after updated and present in
the night economy and a major update
happened in last night here with the
original solution and two approaches
that we presented to put a framework so
they were multiple options proposed to
canopy MCRD proposed like a header and a
tent in CID they were sort of discussion
happen and they've got a lot of inputs
not only from here and also from
peaceful and also offline discussion so
what we have done with this virtually is
this very unified locus and finalized
path forward for reducing the staff and
also we narrowed down the options for
carrying the MPM CIT
mix like okay just to the abilities of
the people who are not here just to do
the background and in the problems that
is being addressed in this fact we are
no release 1555 to the 132 a speical
jocks picture and maybe SSST most new
mobility modes which are not fitting not
4G per se one is more satisfying but the
problem is the transport networks
there's no transport Venice for some of
let's take some of the spheres so this
is gives a default mirror our voice
better like LTE it's not an issue but
different traffic characteristics are
needed from the transport network for
example low and deterministic latency
are real dimensions with a lot DPR
characteristics that need to be need to
be fulfilled for some of the traffic
capacity types transport network need to
be awareness will be there the current
approach is very good for deaf
illegalities
so this is the one of the problem that
is being adjusted is fact and also there
is a unsteady
under specified Rafi function of a DB
PPD accession to the passport Qatar
place where different kind of te
technology supposed to in one of them so
the proposed solution in the last one
the last IDF to here this is the last
idea solution so we deduce the concept
of John novelist because the concept of
available context identified which
carries the to reflect the slice
characteristics like isolation man you
know that dealing at the sticks and
slice characteristics mapped in the PLC
identifier and this MPN see added
permittivity in is expected hi packet it
could be a solution that ended SRB fix
if it is the overall resolution GD you
can be used and there are also other so
other possible solutions are listed we
also comment from DMM what you wrote
that you know we're going to use the
lower 64 bits of ipv6 address and some
of the comments from peace what you hope
is why don't you use the fast because
kind of solution that is which is this
big by giving six so all these comments
they have taken care and we come up with
the final approach and the next slide I
think most of the solution that was put
forth by John McCauley
you will present
[Music]
so before we go into this one question
right so this mapping it's not a new
problem in that sense right you know
over delay to underlay mapping it's not
not a new thing it's not a new
requirement in solution 2016 Ferengi are
slicing solutions are deployed they are
using proprietary way of wrapping things
it's not a new problem
they were non standardized way of
mapping in early 2016 slicing solutions
we just streamlining this approach with
standard interchange so as I mentioned
there were two different solutions and
one of the suggestions was to come up
with one so we took the discrete and the
integrated once in the earlier one and
have one single approach a simple and
that's all in Chapter two and the second
part of it was what required more work
section two here carrying the transport
context invisible packet header so we
had a number of options are here on gue
and SR v6 I think so so maybe you
already did this transport context from
how do you so I can explain that
so here we have the four steps I think
the first step is partly 3gpp work and
we we have specified anymore they made
clear that we mentioned that it's not
idea to come up with this mapping so
somewhere I mean in 3gpp that there are
these functions like MSS and networks
like that is defined in the kv-85 30 and
they identified the 3gpp and that's
whenever functions and a transport
network in between so that's roughly
what we've done if you look on both ends
there are the network functions P Prime
and the UPF function and a transport
network in between and the management
playing manages to select the slice
aspects for the function to be funky and
the transport I believe they have also
selected a CTN in terms of managing that
slice but the details of it are still
under work in 3gpp a meaning s f5 so
that's why we've put in here that the
TNF is a logical function and it's not
something via specify the interface the
can see can is idea it's an idea I've
seen a 453 which programs the IP
backhaul so the problem in essence are
going back to series question is that
the 3gpp slice aspects the NSS ai the
networks like selection resistance
information is related to what a user is
supplying and so the customer for the
3gpp network is the UE and the customer
for the transport network is the 3gpp
provider so somehow has not been mapping
between
was offered to the customer in the
treaty P become a plus is what the
transport network has to couldn't we
the those are not the same there is a
it's not a one-to-one mapping you know
for example there may be a thousand
customers in green slices or slices in
so something has to be done and and
that's what is being I mean that part of
how they estimate and manage that
nothing is in 3gpp and you know we're
not specifying that if we're just
offering it as explanation assuming that
that has been done and now their
information is not programmed one at the
SMS to the Ryan and the UVF then
whatever has been programmed in the IP
network has got to be realized for every
IP packet that transits and that's what
we're trying to do I mean I think I've
now explained those four steps so on the
m4 or you what you are getting in the
context is truly an end to the you note
B so I think for the IETF side the the
T's work would be related to the SPL
SBHC and a CPA and here we can see that
once the information is in the G note B
and the UPF unfortunately it's got to be
conveyed in the active packet so that
whatever was promised can be provided by
the trust and there's an implicit
assumption that that context identifier
is the transport is aware of that okay
dangerous assumption yes we assume that
actually that that's a good question we
assume that it is not made third session
so the estimation of whatever there are
various functions which we typically
that estimate over longer periods of
Chinese and that's
programmed in the transport network so
when a session comes it doesn't try to
go and figure out other resources and
it's been allocated and in only the
mapping information is conveyed and so
maybe on elementary question right now
this is I'm going to understand you know
not a name
so today if you like DHCP and all of
that you do mapping at a session layer
alright so now we are dealing at a slice
level what are the pros and cons of what
does that burn days of being this way
versus on the session layer session is
fine except that if you go to the next
page I have yes okay so DHCP is not an
immutable field so as long as there is
an agreement so that's one of the even
more than that I think you know things
like failure or isolation and aspects
like that of our slice are not invaded
easy so that's one answer so we look
through a number of alternate is just to
see if we can use what exists you know
and even so that's how we're coming to
do so if you go through it this the tcp
is more beautiful VLAN
I suppose it works in some scenarios
where if you have a customer and the
provider in the same network it's okay
it's not they three PN's
use that I mean also works in some
scenarios but not in many others where
you you know it's very rigid provision
else time also should work but so it
works on the some scenarios but it's
harder to provision I suppose it's
possible
GTP header
the problem is they may be a qfi in the
count stream but not on the upstream and
in any case it's too deep for infection
and so that's what we were looking at in
terms of those video yeah I Know Who I
am so I won't say who I am for the
minutes but I'm doing this the
interesting thing here is is that source
port is normally used as a source of
entropy for ecmp so I'm kind of
wondering how either you're turning ecmp
off or I'll keep my powder driving so
we're only using specific ranges which
immerse for that entropy and make sure
that there are no effect and also since
it is gtp we can so we're not altering
the source port of the just a question
that's question auto farm so it's
interesting to to when we see the P out
to be able to look up the UDP source
code source port to handle which tries
pocket bringing bring doubt so on so
which working group will stand let
somebody walk on the the dot P router to
be able to handle source port so we do
not think of adding if there's something
that needs to be done no my question is
ID mmm is a place to just on walk walk
on you yes on dot for the mobility
monument in distribution mana and act on
work on the truck engineering and you
now propose the UDP source port other
yeah the ID to mapping the mobility
session to the transporter resource so
so which idea who are working group to
define that behavior there is no what
Cooper say here it's a local mapping
function and the PE nodes how do you map
the incoming session to this local
policy based routing right today to
falsely based routing based on various
packet fields you map this information
incoming traffic to map to the tunnels
so what we are suggesting is this it's
not a new thing putting in the UDP
source port that is used for today for
the for example what Dave is asking for
load balancing at both English side and
that ran side are also on the UPF side
both sides so we are latching on to this
mechanism we are extending one more
indirection
but some of this extra indirection we
created to encode this empty anxiety
indirectly so there is no working group
it's already working on working fields
so that's why this approach we felt that
it's backward compatible even with
existing 4G slicing solutions yeah
suresh krisshnan so one of the things
that concerns me here is right you're
rewriting the UDP ports are you
calculating the UDP checksum again or
like you know how does it actually work
because unless you turn off the checksum
the packet is going to be dropped right
encoding happens at the G note P or the
UPF so we are not doing any additional
stuff which if you see that what is
happening is this operator control this
particular range of the UDP port map it
to this particular empty and CID so
there's no rewriting the first time and
the GT encapsulation happens this
mapping happens so what happens in the
pierrot trees only lookup and map it to
the particulate eternal so there's no
okay make sense like it wasn't clear
because it looked like you know it was
happening somewhere and in the wire
there some like between the P and the G
not be so
okay this is Yasuo and I think the
v/line eye team should not be excluded
in this solution because in the first
hub from the run to the P note the
villain can represent the network slice
information and in the IP domain we can
use other NATO slice encapsulation to
respect the information so I think is a
reasonable solution to you Stadium name
yeah Mahoney purchases for correct
understanding so the since UDP is a be
directional thing so both end points of
the GDP tunnel have to use the same
transport network identifier in the
source port or is it can they be
different can you have multiple of these
identifiers to unambitious li identify
the slice that the traffic is associated
with I think it's an important aspect
because for implementation you may have
multiple IP endpoints through a
percentage GDP between 2 to same nodes
right followed balancing or whatever
if there is a maze electric that's that
should not be is there any reason to not
use identifiers which are part of the
gtp you header the upstream we don't
necessarily have to use energy 20 on the
downstream as long as that translation
is mapped in note to mean the same thing
and they are and the advantage of using
this identifier instead of using for
example the T IDs in the GDP is to have
less keys to to look up for the
transport network we could get some
viewers information from the QD maps to
Barrow right you do get the the
information transferred has no
atmosphere hi I am Erin Kelly J so for
UDP saucepot how does G never be knows
it's Aussie OTP no are you going to use
existing n2 and for interface with some
kind of extension should be handed by
the IP in terms of how to as Dave asked
the question about how to handle entropy
and how to make sure that there are no
rules
so you don't use existing 3gpp
controller function right p SG p okay
okay thank you pretty much yeah great
discussion any any other comments
cushions so yeah this is a looks very
interesting but I think so just you know
you guys any other serration leave any
comments okay all right yeah again good
stuff yeah thanks so you're asking us to
so I think before that let us ask how
many people you know read the document
can you I saw one two three four okay so
I think maybe you know we can ask but I
think you guys want to engage Carlos
erasure one comment I think the the last
part of the work the how to map in the
user plan from the run to the IP
backhaul I think this is whether this
part of work can be separated from the
current draft I think this is some
isolated work and this is very important
for the network slicing mapping
relationship you know data plan this is
just a suggestion so why are you say I'm
just curious on dirt so you want that
can be taken up in a separate document
and different working group I just think
this part of work is not so relevant to
the rest part of the I think it's not
connected very strictly together they're
just different work they are all
important but they can be existing in
different drafts okay that's just the
user plan map your relationship the just
some solutions you list
in the previous slides which I comment
yes yes yes I can openers again I I can
also take a look and provide a review to
okay
okay Carlos thank you so which truck do
you prefer informational or stone the
truck I think there's not they're not
defining new standards okay so we marked
it as informational but I'm not an
expert on this okay okay okay yeah yeah
let's make sure there's more discussion
and I think this good feedback but yeah
yeah thanks thank you
Thanks next one is all textual
discussions on a survey six mobile user
plain from my name is MIA and I'm
presenting on behalf of so today I got
to talk about motivation oh and I fixed
our discussion and some execs occasion
and so the direct the motivation is
pretty much similar to the previous
presentation how to map the
I'd like to address a candle with a
level 4 systematics I need to be looking
at the holistically and across layers
when drastic architectural transition is
required for example in the 5c era we
are various decisions are to be
supported and we are completely new data
intensive on services like an elastic
narrative is to get it within our soon
um this document discusses the
architectural implication of our prices
are the six memory user plain not
necessarily six button especially
regarding the possible optimization work
with existing conventional players yes
we hope it suggests that Excel basics
mobile user claim is a right afflicted
choice for E and Sierra
so mobile network and the transport
network are separated by layers
convenient Food Network it's um under a
layer to the mobile network and GDP you
is an over a tonal in the movie team
network they have solved any problem but
each they are developed independently in
order to solve any programs which could
result in overall efficiency right like
I'm famous saying by Peter on in KT so
let's take an example of network slicing
into a network sizing so in typical TTP
you over IP MPLS SSL configuration are 3
GPP data-planet entity such as UPF is a
c e to the transport networks are PE or
even needed extra see each lecture scale
on which of these are paper to analysis
easier in this nicely explained the
so with the current touch this since
mobile network and transport network is
separated on which complicated
complicates the architecture so as we
discussed in the previous presentation a
certain extra ID such as right william
NP or extra is needed for secure getting
traffic and nothing also artistic sliced
in the same week and also TLP is in ze
connection it's a sin organ failure and
so some form of be a leader you can see
using nothing protocol or ancillary kind
of things are required which complicates
the architecture fits right so and if we
then we can simplify the architects are
not and now that touch controls the use
of a separation it's a mainstream
practice and user training these are
dedicated to father so in that case it
is reasonable to have 3gpp take a very
entities like ups on the part of our
health network this is AC TPP and it
says the controlling abusive em
separated and if we move to the border
the main of this model is there's no
need for pece hierarchy but there's no
need for extracting
for traffic mapping and we can directly
control the underlying business
from the perspective of implementation
Cameron says it's unrealistic 630 PP SD
that don't care about resulting but I
would say it's realistic and even it's
more national in the new generation
since I still use cases in I own
flexibility of crowd negative and in the
clouds negative as hugs mich Mich
deployments aside the cod proxy on the
same solution good or the second copula
port would take care of the
communication thank you for coming for
more such kind of things so that service
can be cymatics and some may say that
the administrative domain itself I
reached and they don't more they may not
want to expose that to proceed but in
the case SL segment routing findings it
can be used if the protein is to be
hidden and for each computer um it's a
v6 fictional traffic's general
capabilities and the networking concept
for all freely describing instructions
and metadata RC suitable for providing
it distributed computing in addition
since is a v6 can be accommodated rain
regardless of a domain such as access by
the area mobility or there is a
datacenter some spreads memory and some
Cheney that used to be concentrated in
data center historically
can be expanded over our by the area it
is good for and with a certain six
system and the QoS information can be
exposed in the IP header which does not
affect performance with
uh thanks to the wrong estimate genetic
mechanism is I figured grunting so only
the services or applications will need
to meet that information for granular
processing ah to look up that kind of
information so this would are effects
replacement oxide applications and for
you our energy into undeniable low-rated
see communications 3gpp tier two three
is seventy seventy five investigates
that key issues for making the URL still
comments related see GTA V T in the
fantasy system however that solution
provided in such document are focused at
including the override protocol and the
limit to provide a few kinks in to hug
him out such a survey included and the
DA themes are based on the static
configuration or static mapping for
steering that over a parking garage
across medicinal and such solutions do
not scale and he does about economics
and that document six one six two six
two four addresses the issues on how to
support redundant data transmission via
a single uvf and signal our landlord but
how to ensure that this do it fast
is not enough in the government it just
says using different IP address or
different ever instances but it's not
assure that the path is disjoint Hana
GDP data plane entities need to support
pack identification and elimination this
actually requires the modification of
gtp you protocol itself so if it need to
evolve CPU independently but I would say
it's not good it's too much
the SLV six mobile user plain also has
an advantage in this list you need to
order house it's okay I kind of made our
discussions or and and I hope this kind
of discussion and comments discussion
I'll work on and I Drive I hope that the
Amen
Thank You Mia questions comments John
thank you good points on the URL LC in
the complicated Network just a question
how does SR v6 allow the paths to be
disjoint you know can you elaborate on
that a bit
also it could provide the TRAF a which
assure the some fifty minutes they can't
importance and the point is that the SL
is all-aware entities can directly
control that kind of mechanism know
maybe the question I didn't put it
particularly I mean if we have the path
between the G note BN I UPF and PSA UPF
and there are two of them how do we make
sure that these paths are disjoint using
a cell b6 maybe it's a detailed question
and you know
it's beauty obey some v6 fancy okay mini
John we can hire offline or because the
single topic right maybe I suggest I
think Suresh
yeah suresh krisshnan so one question
konasana like this is I understand why
you are doing this right I'm trying to
understand why it's a separate document
so why is it not something that's folded
into the satoru sons document or homo
sons document as like either an analysis
either on the solution to say like ok I
I think though and that I think the text
itself is useful I'm not sure about the
form of how it needs to go so I think
it's probably worth my discussing how it
actually proceeds ok because like as you
like know right a lot of the times like
you know when you have a document like
this which has like it's pretty
dependent on other stuff right so the
question is why should it be a separate
document right and this is something
that comes up in the iesg I told
straight right like we have an IE AC
statement right on what is called
support documents so I would really like
the working group to think about it and
if the working group decides it needs to
be separate that's fine but I just want
to put it up there so you think about
like why it needs to be separate and put
it in the write-up 480 separate okay
thanks absolutely I think great points I
think I'll just chime in there right I
think you brought out number of good
points there I think but salacious
cushion is a very fundamental to this in
the sense that there's already two
documents right now if we can fold some
things there it's great
if you still have some good stuff which
may you know if you're given justify
that you know we need one good one
document which you know covers the
overall thing if you can justify that we
can but again yeah it's good stuff in
there but let's get the feedback showing
us here oh my name is sumo furious a so
I read this document it's she's raising
very interesting overall big question to
the community actually she's asking I
think now I understand better the second
presentation because it has this
directly connection right like like you
can collapse gtp you and SR v6 and you
can have much more transport benefits
you can get that's all good but the only
question I have is so that we are
seeking like you know the it's kind of
envisioning in future only ipv6 based
transport right so what happens to the
backward compatibility these kind of
things I said I think this recipe be
stuck with gtp right like and with the
discussion started they were only using
an S for new they move to a nine now and
they were new they moved gtp u2f anew so
they are expanding gtp usage while we
are discussing you know how to give the
much more transport benefits right so
there's some tussle going on there so I
think this is a good document I think
you you laid out the points what s our
v6 can bring it to the network but it
says much more bigger discussion I
should okay on a flight from Nokia in
the slides you you mentioned service
miss you know I wonder what that has to
do with slicing I think it's more for
the control plane entities into a TPP
and its implementation so conventional
thinking about thinking need to be
double negative okay but but what is the
role of a survey six in with this
service
so that proxies I think we're talking
about different player doesn't know
routing doesn't know it's not v6 that
kind of argument could happen but I
would say just if there could be a kind
of proxy or sidecar which feat can only
do the routing for getting stuff right
now rafting on the console
implementation so the application
doesn't know the wrong thing but another
thing sits in de host in that case we
can provide being probably from the host
okay I just want to respond to the same
things approaching no Cisco so I think
it was actually really like that analogy
of site car I related to this specific
content in the drop because the site
card this whole motion is to allow for
the proxy to sit just sank to the
application themselves so if you think
about these different network functions
these different functions related to the
Ryan or than the FRG Seaside these
functions are now capable of hosting
where they are sitting which are hosts
now they can have these routing
according notes next to them just like
what the on where the proxies do so the
notion of having them adjacent to each
other clearly has tons of benefits as
proven in the cloud scale so thank you
for actually including that site cars
are functioning at the HTTP level not
assert v6 which is quite low in in the
protocol stack so I still I'm on the
opinion that we are mixing things now
very bad if there is application level
routing HTTP level request routing
that's the business of sidecar and then
we have this services which is an IP
level or maybe even below it
indeed so there's also the notion of
application routing so with HTTP then
there's a network services mesh which is
at IP so I think that that those lines
have been blurring for for quite some
time
suresh krisshnan just like closing off
on this one all right like so the way I
understood it is right like you know the
the the cyclic pattern as a design
pattern allows for the application to be
unaware of what's happening underneath
right so as I said it's right now used
for HTTP like certificate like offload
and things like that for the security
but I think konasana spoink was like you
know if your s r v6 is like put in a
sidecar pattern then your application
doesn't need to know about it so you can
take your vnf today is inside a vm and
you can continue eyes it and that can
take s r v6 asses and use it i think
that's kind of a thinking that's how I
understood it ok any other final
questions cords ok thank you me I think
yeah this is again good work a lot of
good stuff in there like the previous
sir docker right I think we need more
discussions and we'll take it from there
I think the last comment is this
presentation - on this presentation are
very much connected actually what you
guys are trying right so one of the
document this one more on a maintenance
track this is from mobility capability
negotiation protocols okay one second
sorry thank you too much of our call
last night no sheets please ok get
everybody sign the blue sheets ok sorry
turn it on is it okay thank you and the
other authors of this draft isn't only
from Hawaii and li geom her and actually
I guess the UH noona has pride in did
this draft last time and we did a lot of
extensions and polish it a lot and now I
will introduce it here
[Music]
and we all know that the ATF and other
organizations has standardized my new
mobility management protocols and we can
put him into two categories the network
based solutions and the host based
solutions and in the network based
solutions the main protocols other PM IP
based protocols and the extensions and
similarly for the host based protocols
and mainly based on the movie accurate
six and some extensions so a question
here is the item okay and the window
mobile node access to the network maybe
the first time access all the handover
what kind of mobility management
protocol can be used and because of the
network may support some protocols and
the host miss supported some protocols
and maybe the host to pray for something
and different from the capability of the
network so this charter mainly research
on this problem and to choose Portland
negotiation of the mobility capability
between the host and the network so we
may have some basic principles here is
that the first one is to during the
negotiation when to follow the network
ability and the second is follow the
host preference and third a supporter of
functional extensions and the first one
is to support the performance
enhancements for example some fast
handover or something like that and in
default in order to guarantee are the
performance of the mobility management
the network based schemes can be should
be used if it can be supported so after
the initial attachment of the mobile
node a profile will be generated in the
management store to recover the
selected I'll pray for the protocol of
this host and when the handover happens
the network network will check the
selected or preffered protocol but the
network also need to notify the host if
the slack here the protocol cannot be
spotted in the new area and we have some
examples in the draft and I at least one
example here is that a host and network
post supports a network based protocols
and for example when the host of support
to the basics
proxy mobile ipv6 and the network's for
some extension extension solves the
based on the proxxon mobile ipv6 then if
the extension protocol no parity
racing's has no requirement for the
mobile node in a moment it can be used
and otherwise the basic theme of the
ipv6 should be used and the second case
is is the item when the network and the
host post is supposed some extension
protocols and if the extensions are same
it can be used otherwise the basic
approximate actives proximity heuristics
can be selected and then we need some
solutions here is that the signaling
messages should be exchanged between the
host and the network to exchange this
preference and the ability and may be
based on the extension of the icmpv6 or
some authentication messages and another
problem we need to consider is who will
initiate this negotiation the host or
the network solution are you done with
the presentation or last and we give out
a possible solution is based on icmpv6
is a new option here is proposed on it
namely mobility capability MC option
with the corresponding flag in the eyes
a message when the mobile node and
network exchange of the eyes I a message
the private
preference and the supportive protocols
can be can be can be included in this
option and then the protocol get
disliked either final yeah okay suresh
krisshnan ass like responsibility here
right so one of the things is that like
everything you say has been tried before
the idea
yeah multiple times so if you go back to
like 2007-2008 the net lmm mnar
interface is exactly this okay except
that it never worked because like a
network usually decides if the network
decides is going to do some kind of
mobility it's gonna do it
right so it's not going to negotiate
with the host why it's gonna do it
that's kind of something we found out
like as a result right it's not that we
didn't try so there's been multiple
iterations of this I know there's one
like Raj and I did for like you know see
my purses pmf is something you tried
like she did some prefix coloring stuff
so there's been like multiple failed
attempts at this right
mainly because of not technical reasons
okay so there's like you know it doesn't
fit any deployment scenario there like
so I'm positing that there's no
deployment scenario where this would be
useful right because if you take the
architectures none of them are made to
allow this okay so if you can figure out
like you know where you would use this
like you know who are the people
interested in this I think we can pursue
this but otherwise like we know there's
like a lot of past history of failures
in this thing because the incentives are
not aligned for people to do this okay
so think about it how you would apply
this where you would apply this I think
that could be very useful input for the
group to decide if it's useful Thanks I
think that's a great time input I think
mmm er interface document that was
Julien published it and say I think the
network to end point interface was one
thing we truly missed you know we don't
have it even today right in any of this
right having a standardized interface
makes sense but we could not somehow we
always feel we tried but we fail so so I
think it's the question is you know we
need to see you know we need to look at
the previous work and see what we can do
now is there
the situation change can we push it now
I do not mind an answer but what this
was tried before it's continued last
night no okay okay so I think my
solution is I think you know you may
want to you know work with few people
you know get some more feedback and see
if it has potential then invest time on
this otherwise you know what to think
that makes sense or not okay any other
questions comments all right thank you
so much
next is sort of a small will give an
update on yeah just one quick one minor
one Rajeev Cisco so if you think from
the endpoint being attached to cellular
then I presume this message would go
from potentially the end point towards
the UPF of the side gateway in case of
the mobile area happening between
cellular and say Wi-Fi then this message
is assumed to be going from the endpoint
to where it's the same thing access
rotor it so there may be two distinct
right excess water or in case of EP
digit might be the same thing as a
psychic way when upstairs but then there
are number of possibilities so this this
notion of having something in the RS an
RA would mean to allow for the nobility
to work have to be comparable at not
just within the cellular realm but
outside as well potentially something to
think about though I do like the fact
that this is not a sari so it's really
low hangings small footprint in terms of
protocols extension and thankfully
doesn't require anything to be done in
the mobility protocol so that's one
difference thing I see from the past
Suresh
okay so why is sirisha sorry I don't
have the background on this why the why
you said it's failed because it's a
security show Union to face it's always
problematic right user to network
interface is it security is the main
thing or yeah I want to hear that sir I
really think like you know this thing
was not anchored in architectures
anywhere site so somebody used to say
like you know some wise people used to
say in the idea we do protocols he had
not architectures right so like for like
good or bad the architectures are done
somewhere else right like so unless you
go and anchor this like the other places
where like I think like you know I know
is like she has the same scars right so
we have to go to 3gpp go to 3gpp to like
and everywhere to make sure that our
stuff is anchored there right because
without that happening these things are
not going anywhere right so that's kind
of the path that's really missing is
really the deployment support for this
thing so Security's like one thing we
can fix it so if you look at the Julian
and Pete's traffic I which is am an IR
interface like everything Rajeev said
was actually looked at we spent like a
couple of years on it address everything
except that it was not deployed right so
it's I think it's mainly a deployment
issue the incentives are not right to do
this like so nobody was really
interested like for example like
Qualcomm was doing the chip and they
didn't care about the network based
mobility right and the operators didn't
want to have the you easter-egg mobility
now themselves so the incentives really
were not aligned very well okay thank
you so much okay so yeah okay next is
not bleed on FPC so so this I think just
you know a lot of work went into this
but it lately you know the document has
expired and I think we thought it the
work was done but it never you know you
know cleared last call yeah yes thank
you on this is Satoru speaking I
I try to describe the the little bit
background of the SPC work with him the
course Marco
Danny Rio and sorry so um the work had
been started at I remember that around
the twenty thirty and then first
document submitted to DM a working group
on 2014 I think so
DVM the mmm working group adopts that
document as a working group document so
we work a lot to to update the document
spec based on the our discussion how to
configure the foreign policy for the
user playing data plan note so as a
result of the our discussion we are FPC
did not touch any outside what a wire
protocol so instead of that we defined
API to configure the user playing from
the application so so that's the reason
we decide we decide to define the we
hang model to provide the API so after
the a discussion javi around the 2016
after the Bursar's working on meeting so
we decided to change the data model and
the information model to divide to the
topology and mobility and policy to
those three model conjunction to derive
the action forum post configuration to
the to the data plane node so after the
zero for revision we take that model and
if you see document describing the
information model of that and data mode
data model order by Jung
product information model so after that
decision we make bunch of the division
maybe yes
yeah have a revision though I think it's
being mature and live from Sprint take
out with a walk to edit the document and
the Chari volunteer to to divide the
young model from the main document to
make the documents short because the the
hold of the document becoming over the
hundred page so it makes the viewer
really difficult to make write comment
and to decide whether it'll be good or
not so that's the latest status of the
the FPC work after the the last update
of the young model by charlie there's no
update happened so then the boss of the
information model document and yang
model document is expires that's the
latest a total of the FPC
so so the reason why I shared in the
background of the FEC work after the
long silence of of the last update so
how to be happy to discuss whether we
proceed or not the defi C work into the
DMM working group with with you guys I
think many people put the much effort to
this work at the beginning of the
discussions a the control frame is a
frame or data plane separation so I
think to be good outcome here but it
depends on the interest of the industry
or community for the mobility area I'd
like to hear your comment please
that explains the interest so i'm
co-author and I know that the work that
we put into this that would just been
revised in details quite a lot and but
it's pretty mature as well pretty stable
since a while it's a stable as drafts
have been expired so I think there was a
plan how to further progress the reviews
on these two documents now there are
there was one document which was version
12 then we split it wait and I think
only the young part has been published
so far and as you said your opinion is
that is pretty much sure so since we
have to pretty much show parts I think
what we still need to do is the review
part but in my opinion we should
progress these two drafts towards RFC of
course we need reasonable reviews and
comments for moniker but I also think
it's reasonable work and a lot of work
has been put into it so it would be a
pity to not progress these drums okay
Thank You Marco that's more opinion and
an author any other points okay so I
think we will confirm the same in the
mailing list if I think this sufficient
interest will move forward with the
obligation process or a complete the
last call forces but we definitely I do
think the document is in a great shape
but still you know we need to go through
the process we need reviews I think it's
not just authors to you right but in the
working working group has to say that I
think that that hasn't been established
if it that happens we move it forward
otherwise we'll kill it Suresh is that a
reasonable option yeah all right with
that thank you so much and did anybody
everybody sign the blue sheets if not
please sign it
thank you so much the meeting is now
closed
I don't know I don't understand you
oh yeah Azhar thinks lights are mere
slits a good