[Music]
to the folks in the back of the room
we're about to get started please take
your seats all right so welcome back to
DNS service discovery just very quickly
for those of you who weren't at the
previous session or any other session
this is covered by the note well if you
haven't done so please read it if you
have several years ago read it again
it's not that interesting but it's
really important
the two main points that I always
highlight are your IPR requirements so
if you know about patents relates to
this stuff there are rules that you need
to follow and also we will be enforcing
the ITF code of conduct which generally
covers being nice to one another so
without further ado Christian otherwise
the anvil is gonna miss you
there's a human that controls it I think
okay do that thing okay so we have a lot
of time to discuss DNS SD privacy
requirement in fact we have spent a lot
of time on that already
the I started this work and dannielle a
case I came to work with me a couple of
months after that in March of 2016 and
it went through various iterations in
the group and eventually we decided cut
off years later to not not really push
for solution because we could not get
consensus on the solution but we excised
from the proposal of a solution the
analysis part which was basically the
privacy requirement and the general
consensus at the time that was in 2018
was that this requirement were useful
because it was interesting to be stuck
in the ground to a record before saying
hey when you do discovery and especially
if you are using a multicast protocol
whatever it is and you have to be
concerned about requirements and if I
understand correctly the working group
last call on this draft is
almost finished our yes so we started
the working Alaska a few weeks ago and
it extends to the end of this week so
you still have a couple of days to
explain why it's great and we should we
publish it or not
so what study that effort is that when
mdns genesis the in general but mdns in
particular is the one so noisy and leaky
protocol it was done to be in quakes
your configuration etc but the use of
broadcast and the use of identifiers in
the broadcast allows people to track who
is doing what and when and that
generally a bad idea so you can have
some kind of a bad act or there it's
there and the bad actor will be
listening and and you could extract the
fact that someone is contacting someone
or that what address what they are doing
what an application set up which is
further off for all kinds of mega data
acquisition and tracking so what we want
to do is private discovery in which
those bad actors that are listening in
which the bad actors cannot gather
information by merely watching the
exchanges and we we went for values kind
of solutions there are value solutions
to that thing it's one of those problems
in which you you could slice it in
different ways I am not particularly
attached to one solution of the idea
that this one should be recognized and
we should try to solve it we as I said
we excise the requirements from the
draft that we add before
and we've already presented that who was
in the London ITF a year and a half ago
yeah okay
so you you must have seen those slides
already okay so we we went through the
anything the three big scenarios of
discovery the first scenario is when you
want to find the printer or when you
want to find a fixed device whatever it
is and in that scenario basically you
don't care that people discover that
there is a printer on the network
because of course there is a printer at
the network but what you do care is that
it'd be better if you did not identify
who is using the printer at what time
and that's that's really the requirement
there to give an example of how mdns for
example doesn't completely meet that
requirement mdns in order to participate
the guy was doing the discovery as to
initiate and DNS and to do that they
have to broadcast their host name on the
local network and that broadcasting of
the host name is worth tracking you so
that it's easily fixed it's not hard to
do but it's not done yet
the real requirement for discovery is
for peer-to-peer scenarios and I say for
example the head the airport scenario
you're in an airport lounge and you are
preparing a presentation with a
colleague and you are discovering each
other it'd be better if the people who
are also in the air for F of launch did
not immediately identify was doing what
I mean because that might reveal that
you have is cover operation going on and
finally okay thanks as you know about ID
so here whoever in this scenario SD we
got a piece of feedback that the the man
in the heart was not identified properly
in the in the picture as the bad actor
so not in the heart is hiding in the
background is listening what's happening
and because all these message are sent
in clear text
you can see them on the network and it's
obvious how you see them in with a
multicast but even if they are sand as
GNSS deal with the DNS SD server as long
as you can get the flow of messages
you're going to identify that David here
is looking for stores laptop name and
and finding it on the network and and
you can discover that so that that's the
kind of stuff we want to not happen and
there is the third scenario is a variant
of that with wearable devices if you
have wearable devices and you use this
kind of discovery scenarios to send
broadcast messages to find them and to
initiate communications not only do we
discover that there is this
communication but you can track the
person doing that like if in order to
for your watch to discover your your
iPhone the iPhone ask to broadcast its
presence on the waves then that becomes
a beacon that anybody can touch and so
these are basically the scenarios and
the purpose of the draft is just to
delineate those scenarios delineate that
we have a problem and effectively get
that on the record to commit ourselves
to fixing it later or by whichever ways
adequate and that's pretty much where we
are and and basically my might say hey
hey we have been trying to bang that
message for some time now are we done
yet I mean can we publish it and so can
we
so could we have a show of hands for who
folks who have read this draft
yes could we ask you to just say a quick
word if use of your opinion on is this
good to go or if you have concerns Chris
well appo I think it's good go thank you
Jim what work yeah so if I had any
substantial feedback then I would have
posted it on the mailing list so yeah
thanks yeah okay so I think we're gonna
let the working group last call go until
the end of the week and or I forget the
exact date that it's running too but so
sometime I think either end of this week
or next week and see if we have any
anyone speaking up before then but
otherwise I think we're good to go and
ready to submit this is G ok thank you
very much thank you Christian and so
that is a current state of the art from
privacy we might have more in the
pipeline once this is published but I
think that's it for now does anyone have
any other topics do you want to discuss
so those who might be able to adjourn no
um I think he's saying that he's read
the draft thanks Ted
all right then we might have Daniel so
Daniel MeeGo Erickson I just have a
comment regarding the first scenario so
one thing is concerned how we make the
discovery but I'm looking at who's
become being connected to the printer is
another thing
would say there is a DNS part as well
even though you're using TLS maybe you
can sister this IP is connected to that
one sir well you will know that someone
is doing a TLS connection to the printer
and hopefully it's a TRS connection and
it doesn't give the text of the document
in the clear of it okay you will know it
is a printer because that's not a secret
when you are in this hotel lobby and
they have a print of all which you use
it's there you know it's there that's
you're not trying to hide the fact that
there is a printer what you want to not
disclose is who exactly is using the
printer so suppose that you are using
say MAC address randomization so you
cannot be identify your MAC address or
by your IP address you want to not have
the discard protocol is speed art
identifiable information racket like a
host name or something okay
thank you all right I think we're then
ready to adjourn we heard may have beat
a record in terms of shortest ITF
session ever congratulations everyone
and we will hopefully be seeing a lot of
you in Vancouver but most importantly on
the list before then for those of you
that haven't read this draft please find
it in your heart to do so maybe on your
plane ride home and even if your email
just says yes this is fine this helps
reassure us and the ADEs that this
document is ready to move forward so
even if you don't have any feedback if
all your feedback is it's fine please
just say so like a short one-liner all
right thanks for coming
it's different something over Yeah right