okay so I think we probably ought to
make a start
given the clock is now ticking good
afternoon everybody welcome to the VIP
room so you should all feel dutifully
special trying to make Chrome there we
go so this is the DTN working group if
you are in the wrong room now is your
chance to creep out quietly I'm Rick
Taylor first off as this is an IETF
meeting it this meeting is held under
the no well you should have all read I'm
no 12 before if you're not familiar I
recommend you have a look on the
internet and read it thoroughly that
much more adieu I'll move on a bit of
admin first off let me try and make this
do something sensible there we go so we
need a note-taker would anyone like to
volunteer to make some notes there is an
etherpad URL so you can dynamically take
notes and other people could take notes
I know edge normally takes some notes
but he is speaking so if somebody else
can jump onto etherpad while EDD is
speaking and try and capture any of the
comments that are made at the mic or
anything like that that would be greatly
appreciated also can somebody please
monitor jabber for us we need to jabber
scribe although we have meet echo a meet
echo is very good it would be great if
somebody is watching the jabber Channel
any volunteers please thank you very
much and the other little bits of admin
are obviously please state your native
name at the microphone because we have
remote attendees and presenters there's
a pink cross up here so you are stood in
the right place for the audiovisual
recording which all eventually ends up
on YouTube and the remote attendees can
also see you
so we have some apologies which is as
you can tell it's just me at the table
here mark launched a senses apologies
and Magnus Westerlund is also remote he
can't make it in person so he's our ad
but I'm sure he can jump in across meat
echo and tell me where I'm going wrong
so first off the agenda we have a
reasonably light agenda for this working
group meeting I will briefly run through
some of the document status we as some
of you know oh the other apology is I
have very nasty cough so occasionally I
may splatter we have three key documents
that are all in the eye let me get this
right they are all currently going
through the area reviews so we have had
some reviews from the Janerio sec area
for the various documents these of
course came back with comments as they
always do and so I will cover some of
the status of some of those documents
and two of the authors of two of those
three documents are here and they're
going to say a few words about the
comments that were raised and how
they're being addressed there may be
some open questions for the working
group which we have plenty of time to
discuss and of course that discussion
would be taken to the list as well I'm I
have the feeling they're not too
contentious but I'll come on to that and
Scott said he wanted to say a few words
about bundling bundle encapsulation if
he had time and some notes I Scott has
no slides if we have time in there's
interest can you do something freeform
that's very kind and then we have an
open mic at the end so prior to this
meeting the chairs put a call-out on the
mailing list to say does anyone have
anything interesting they wanted to
present there was a resounding silence
but that doesn't prevent somebody who
was too shy or it was too early to put
something on the mailing list if they
have something interesting please bring
it to the microphone we have time to
discuss these things so okay does anyone
want to bash this agenda do you want to
add any items and we missed something
important
okay
so going through the document status for
those of you who are not entirely up to
speed with what we're doing in the
working group at the moment there are
three critical documents that are the
foundation of the DTN protocol stack for
the IETF work one of which is the update
to the bundle protocol BP bists so the
status of this is the genic review has
come in there were questions over the
definition of time and we are still
waiting for the ops area review and the
secondary review to come back in I'll
let Scott cover that in a bit more
detail tcp CL version 4 so the the DTM
stack is divided between bundle
processing agents which know how to
shift bundles around and the concept of
a convergence layer underneath which
actually acts as effectively a link
layer to move the bundles between nodes
the first defined protocol for doing
this moving is based on TCP and hence
the TCP convergence layer and this is
the version four so this is updating the
work that was done in the IRT F now
doing it in the IETF so this will be a
standard tracked document and again
we're going through the review phase
with it
ops dir came back and said it's fine
there's some typos can you fix sec dir
came back with a couple of queries about
because we're running over TCP that
means we are using TLS because it makes
good sense and I won't go into all that
detail here there are plenty of people
who can tell you why using TLS is a good
idea that raised questions about
certificate revocation so how is
certificate handling managed for that
TLS connection between peers and also
because because DTN can be a DTN subnet
effectively so a an administrative area
could be running in a controlled
environment such as International Space
Station where
your traffic isn't travelling across the
public internet and you're pretty sure
about which devices are connected to the
network mostly because you put them
there the option to say look I don't
need TLS I am an embedded device without
the power to do TLS can I not please as
[Music]
means there's a flag in the initial
handshake in TCP CL which says look I
can't do it please don't demand that I
can and if you are happy with that we
can proceed so obviously as security a
DS came back and said well that's is
that a downgrade attack how can that be
exploited have you considered this and
Brian C posish the primary author has
answered these two what he believes is
to his satisfaction we're waiting for
comments to come back from the sec a DS
to see if they're happy with that and
brian says he has a new version of the
draft which captures his comments sorts
out the myths and I believe he is
waiting for the general to review to
return before he actually pushes out
another document and the third document
is so we know how to define a bundle and
we have an example of how to move a
bundle the missing pieces how do we
secure this bundle not only for
integrity but also for encryption and
that's covered by the BP SEC document
which again is in the review phase so it
is currently marked as on hold because
it has a normative reference to beat
this BP Biss is waiting because I Anna
raised some questions about the reuse of
registries from the IEEE RTF documents
now being taken on by IETF documents and
I will let Scott try and get into a bit
more detail about this although it's
quite a hazy area otherwise Janet came
back and said there were some typos and
some small knits not a great problem and
we are waiting for the SEC Arya review
so BP SEC is a it's a security document
it
lots of deep security aspects to it and
I I have no evidence of this but I
believe the SEC will take a little bit
of time to make sure it's correct they
have done an early review on it before
so we're hoping there's gonna be no
showstoppers but I think Eddie's gonna
say a few things about that as well I
beg your pardon and that pretty much
covers me so next topic is some of you
are are aware that we held a virtual
interim between Montreal and today 18th
of September to be precise the purpose
of the virtual interim was to make sure
that those 3 key documents that really
are blocking they have to be done by the
working group to give us a foundation on
which to build everything else so it's
critical that these really do get
through onto the standards track as fast
as possible so it was a discussion about
how do we the progress of those
documents and we'll go over that again
there was a big debate for those who
aren't aware BEP abyss is an update of a
document that was originally worked on
in the IRT F not the IETF so there is
some politics and admin around although
this is bundle protocol version 7 and
obviously we would like to say use
version 7 not the previous version 6
because it is better TM version 6 is
owned by a different standards body so
how do we indicate to readers of bundle
protocol version 6 that they should go
and look at version 7 and the conclusion
that's the virtual interim was that we
should work out the chairs should go
away and discuss with the 80s and the
IRT F people involved in order to just
make this happen
so rather than leaving both documents in
existence try and work out the best way
to mark RFC 5050 so bundle protocol
version six as obsolete ie
if you're starting a new implementation
don't use this use the new one that's
coming and the other thing that was
discussed in the virtual interim was
given we've got these three critical
documents almost complete and they're
you know they're going through the iesg
review phase and they're heading for the
RFC editors what do we do next in this
group so I know over the last a couple
of meetings people have have said they
have ideas we still have a couple of
charter items and so as part of that
virtual interim we started to draw up a
list of some stuff people would like to
work on or like to see done and that was
published out on the mailing list and
there was some good feedback and
discussion about it the ad magnus had
some concerns which was that the list
was too ambitious and too big and was
there enough energy in the working group
to get this done in a reasonable amount
of time so that's the list I mean it's
it's quite an ambitious shopping list
and there are some really exciting
topics on there so from my perspective
yes this would be great to work on these
kind of things but it does depend on is
this doable and do we have people
willing to do it so yes so I'll go back
to that slide in a minute and if we have
plenty of time in this session so if we
want to go back to that slide at the end
of the open mic spot and discuss that at
some length I'm absolutely happy to do
that so my only other item was there is
a fourth document that's been lingering
around so for historical reasons it was
taking quite a long time to get the fine
detail of the TCP convergence layer done
to the satisfaction of the working group
and of the ISJ in the Secretariat etc
in the meantime Scott Burley suggested
that he had a very minimal
we were avoiding the word simple but a
really simple TCP implementation that
might be able to avoid some of the
complexities that was holding up the
working on the TCP CL draft and so he
wrote that up and submitted it and it
was accepted as a working group document
however now that TCP CL is has left the
working group and is now in the IHG
pipeline do we still need to bother to
work on a minimal less capable subset of
that functionality or are we just making
work for ourselves
so I'm looking for comments from the
room about this at the mic at the market
now is good Scott at the mic
Schiaparelli I'm the minimum TCP CL is
simple and small enough specification
that it's not a huge workload whether we
do it or not it's more of a and it's
more of an administrative workload then
then then a compositional workload if
the TCP CL specification is is making
sort of progress that it is then I
certainly am NOT a great champion of
pushing head with MTC PCL if it's not
needed so I'm happy to let that fall by
the wayside
obviously I will take that question to
the list but I am interested just quick
show of hands in the room how many
people have read TCP CL or MTC PCL Scott
you wrote it both of them no only one of
them okay so only a couple of people so
this might be a better topic for the
mailing list so as I said it will come
back to propose new charter items at the
end when we've got a bit more of free
time but in the meantime I think we'll
move over to Scott if you're okay noon
everybody Scott brought the Jet
Propulsion Laboratory I'm going to talk
about the the gen arc review of the BP V
17 specification latest draft and I also
am extremely sick so there will be
occasional interruptions here while I go
and lie down draft 17 of the
specification was reviewed by the
generic reviewer Stuart Bryant and on
these slides about 20 some slides list
of points that were raised in his
responses and sort of by to frame this
Magnus westerly the area director also
read this review and he had some
responses of his own and it was his
feeling that there were some of these
points that actually needed to be
discussed in the working group and I
will call those out as I go through the
ones that I think are are none our
really sort of open to some question RC
50/50 this is sort of a big one but I
think that what happened in on the
mailing list since the interim meeting
was it was decided that it was not our
job to obsolete RC 50/50 so this
document that's not obsolete RSC 50/50
Stewart's question was it's not clear
what the statuses RFC is with regard to
our C 50/50 if it modifies the status of
50/50 s and we need to say so and so in
the interest of not pretending that into
50/50 doesn't exist at all I proposed to
add this sentence to the introduction
and the abstract to make that clear just
to say that and this is this is a
distillation of what came out on the
mailing list that I RTF is advised this
document is an update of RSA 50/50
reflects lessons learned does not
obsolete RC 50/50 probably can't so
anyone reading this document should be
aware that we believe it's an
improvement over our FC 5050 but our
5050 50 is not obsoleted if you want to
use it then at least for the time being
of course you're welcome to hold on
Scott Magnus is coming in with a
question
oh yes yes I'll read your comment here
so I think it careful about using
updates in that because I mean updated
in IDF terminology has different
meanings and nothing puts intended here
I mean we're basically talking about
something which is revised or I mean or
it's it's in some sense replacement but
it's I mean it is revision so it's I
think something else needs to be said
there but adaptation maybe I I think I
think I took update from the the text of
the email so this was I think was his
lifted
from what came out on the mailing list
but I'm happy to change it to something
else I think adaptation makes sense also
Magnus so Rick here yeah from my
understanding of the results of the
virtual interim and the and the poll put
onto the mailing lists the consensus of
the working group was to recommend to
the IRT F that they did obsolete it
so although we can't prompt salute it we
would strongly recommend as best we can
that they do so and the IRT F chair at
the time or I remember who he was
he's calling yes instead I'm quite happy
to do that I mean it was a semi informal
statement but he said I see no problem
that if the IETF have gone ahead and
worked on something then we can just
mark on documents as as you recommend
yeah in some sense we actually put in
put in place a process for this case to
actually have ITF obsoletes iot of
documents in some sense so so that
process has inside it has been created
due to the discussion we had before also
saying when we but yeah I mean you know
the working group consensus supposed to
not Erica obsolete it but there it's for
the future we had you see I had to have
this process in place where we can ITF
can actually all sky or Taft directly by
in in base setting obsolete and I RTF
document and then they can agree on it
so I my own feeling is that this
document is the wrong place to explain
all of that that that they're having a
sentence that said that there's a
relationship makes a lot of sense but
explaining the whole procedure and thing
is that we worked on the process back
besides say of doing that jobs basically
in the future if you put an IRT assess
an abstract document assess obsoletes an
IRT F experimental we now know what to
do with it that question will then in
the approval stage go to IR to the IRF
share and if they agree on
obsoleting IRS documents that's what's
gonna happen so Magnus he's like we went
the other so what would happen because
like I understood just right now that
the that you expect that the IRT F is
obsoleting this document right so they
would need to write another RFC that
obsolete this RC which seems like a
little bit an overhead right so if you
want to have this document obsolete it
you should do it now
we were RFC 5050 is is the I RTF
document understood and we the consensus
of this working group which is made up
of people who worked on that document
already in the in what was the IRT F
working group want to believe that we
want to obsolete the previous document
it's just that it's held by the IRT F
and therefore we don't have the power to
do it it's not true we set up this
process I was unaware of that process so
really the chairs and you guys need to
help the chairs just make that happen
and whatever text has to go in whatever
dock in this document we can just get
put in is that correct yeah but
basically what we put in place now is
basically if you yes we add the obsolete
5050 it that's defect it would happen
but I think from a process standpoint
that's what's what's you know however my
interpretation of the consensus call in
some sense was that it wasn't clear
capped at the absolution should occur at
the same at the exact moment this gets
published this New York C which is what
will happen if you put in that absolutes
and the IRT F share with Moses for
asking hours he agrees on doing it
Ratigan that's not my understanding of
the consensus that we saw on the mailing
list so I will probably have to go back
over ice I bred a pretty resounding yes
obsolete 5050 yeah or do whatever
mechanism is required to say stop
working on stop building new systems on
bp6 build it on bp7
I think the process would be you just
degree at the obsolete you say in the
abstract it does obsolete nothing else
needs in the text and then when we
process a document we will actually ask
the I ITF chair to confirm that this
obsolete is okay but that happens in
background sir okay so as I understand
it's got that last phrase in that music
is not correct well okay so absolute
we're going back to phase a that's fine
well so I will revise this obsolete we
which it said six months ago if we do
that does that also obsolete the other
RFC's that we're supporting RFC fifty
fifty and I'm thinking there
specifically of the RFC's for for the
Ayana registries that RFC fifty-fifty
but references uh in a way it's actually
easier if it does because then we can go
back in and and and set up new
registries for RFC 50 of our for for bpp
seven and and avoid trying to merge with
the existing registries no go ahead
so my understanding is I mean because
it's the it's formerly no you need to be
explicit about which RC skits obsoleted
by this document and and I think what's
currently in the ANA section do work
without a specific I because you have
this is 6255 isn't it yeah yeah which
which will defines the registry with the
updates to the registration rules that
these documents specify so I think we
covered and and I don't want to go back
on that decision also that seems to be
that from the main list that we have the
young registry between the different
versions which is what's now setup so
with the updates so do I understand then
that we're saying that we want to change
this document is to say that it
obsoletes RFC 5050 but it does not
obviously RFC 6255 or whatever it is
yeah and and that the merging of the
existing registries that support arts at
5050 with the new values that is
reflected in this in in draft 17 is
still goes forward is that right yeah
that's my my understanding okay say okay
yeah thanks I guess
okay that was easy CRC's Stuart remark
that surprised that we're using CRC's in
this document given especially given the
the harsh environment and so what I've
done is I've added in 4.1.1 a note
saying that if you want more robust
protection then use a a bundle integrity
block a block integrity block rather as
defined in BP SEC the the expectation
being that in some environments crcs are
fine in some you do need a stronger
protection of of the blocks that was
stood noted that that the manifest block
because it's not defined it seems out of
place and so what I've done is I've
removed all mention of manifest block
from everywhere in the specification
that's all all gone we can talk about
adding it back in as a new RFC later on
time we spent we spent a long time and a
lot of cycles I'm the maleness talking
about time I think the the salient point
that comes out of this is really in my
view this is the the third sentence and
in the ex extract that I've got here
from what Stuart said is that all you
need to say is that you need a
monotonically increasing
system and our software convenience it
shows the latter so what I've done is I
took for table 1.6 which is about DT and
time and just took out almost everything
and said a t10 time is an unsigned
integer
there's the count of seconds since the
start of the year 2000 UTC and it's
going to be represented as a seaborne
signed integer and how you figure that
out is a implementation matter and we
don't even say that it's an
implementation matter because it doesn't
matter so Scott Rick Tyler is that shall
correct it shall be represented as a
seaborne unsigned integer gives me
enough wiggle room to make it a double
or format as a string I sure there
should be a must
oh no probably wrong there I thought the
same thing I may be full of cold sorry
Magnus is backing I mean they are the
same so but I think it's I mean this
your I don't think you should use 2119
language there at all you I mean this
protocol uses a particular
representation of this value and and
that's I think you have state that this
is represented as as a C Brown side
because it's it's not you defining how
it's being represented and you don't
need to make that a must shall or
whatever it's it's not debate about you
just declare that this is defined well
only thing how it's presented is is that
a general comment applying to all of the
remarks on representations through the
document because we we essentially say
this sort of thing for for all parts of
the bundle right because everything is
supposed to be in in C bar format and
and what we say is specifically this
thing people in C bar format isn't this
C bar format yeah so I mean what you
define these the exact representation
here and that's right yeah and I think
you can I mean I its I've in many cases
may be the unnecessary use of 2119
language this
because it's saying if you just declare
that this is represented in and implied
basically MVP v7 it is represented this
way about okay change to every place
else where where we say how its
represented it's it's I mean it's not
necessarily and maybe so i actually that
was so that this is a very minor point i
think it's not like people
I mean having it as chalice is not a I
think it slightly will be use of it but
that's actually not I'm a little bit
worried about that this what's written
here is not easily decodable for an
implementer either I'm just saying it's
you see on the second since started near
2000 on you to see scale because the
time it again me back to this question
about okay how the hell is asleep
secures handled well but but that's just
it's not then that that's exactly saying
is d'Arnaud leave seconds it's it's a
it's a count of seconds that have
elapsed and there are no loop seconds in
there okay so this is actually now it
read an actual change to the time format
because it's not a matter of format it's
just it's just that it's a number it's a
count of seconds yeah but the unix time
wasn't you to see scale next time is is
a count of seconds since a since unix
time is a count of seconds since
beginning of january first nineteen
seventy UTC yeah so magnus rick here
yeah what we're not doing is recording a
date time we're recording an interval
how many seconds since 1970 yeah and and
and this and this usually gets into
confusion say okay it's sleep seconds
how is the on you to see scale but
nothing compared to ta which would be i
mean if
say you to see then includes sleep
seconds which means right but it's it's
not saying that as a UTC interval it's
saying that's a count since a UTC point
so there are no leap seconds involved
yeah then then I think you should
clarify that's back together it's like
okay this is as usual not time it's I I
don't know how to make this any clearer
than it is it's okay yeah okay do you
want to continue this discussion on the
list
Magnus yeah okay because I was just
having a quick look through the back a
log of messages about this and there is
a reference to a seaboard raft about
time stamping where they appear to have
some good text exactly covering this
talking about an interval of seconds
since 1970 and they covered the leap
second thing and it might be I think was
actually reference from Caston it might
be a good bit of reference material to
agree around possibly even kill the text
in some way okay okay thanks okay there
are in after which section where there's
a mention of some anticipated extension
blocks and Stewart's comment was that
these should be handled through an iron
a registry and the block numbers 13 14
and 15 and they shouldn't be in the text
until they're standard so all of those
have been removed everything that's
that's not defined is removed from the
spectrum there's some comments on
securities our definition of the bundle
and bundle protocol
and well I've done there as I've added a
note in Security section saying that
it's a current research topic there
there isn't it it is a work in progress
and there is an internet draft we could
refer to it here or just says the
current research topic whatever
whichever makes sense
rick has chair I wouldn't say current
research topic because we've got a
working groups document on and we're not
a research organization okay we are we
are engineering that solution so I would
say is is a work in progress okay
rather than it's a research topic okay
I'll change to work in progress and do
we want a reference to the I think
referencing from this informative
possibly I'm not sure where the
referencing drafts in progress from a
document you're trying to get through
standards track okay that will cause
more trouble than looking at Miriah for
advice here you go first yes if it's not
a normative reference it's not a problem
at all
yeah okay so you put it in as an
informative reference okay I'm gonna let
Magnus hopefully he's conscious okay all
right and spirit other comment on
security was that there's material in
the security section that seems to be
defining protocol there's actually a lot
of shouse language in there and he
points out to be better to define that
in the body of the text or point to a
definition or another document which is
B P SEC so what I've done is remove all
the text in the security section that
has any of this normative sort of
language in it so though the last
sentence and security section is talking
about the distribution of public keys
which is a current research topic which
is yeah I had a considerations a lot of
this stuff namespaces do not seem to be
identified and Here I am at sea I don't
know the difference between a namespace
in a registry and I'm hoping somebody
can clarify that for me here comes
Magnus
yeah so I think what's he really
referring is that he thinks it's unclear
which particular registry because I mean
and especially in this case we have the
registries that grouped together in that
general upon the protocol versus on the
protocol it's actually well I guess it's
the group now but I think we just need
to be clear on which particular registry
the registries are are called out
specifically in that section every
Sierra and that was my reaction too tall
so and I mean I commented that I think
it's because so should i the word
registry be changed to namespace or does
it matter
no I think in the anatomists called the
registry you'd be your correct producing
registries I don't see you should change
that okay I mean yeah I mean I think it
was like in some cases to what bundle
protocol when he was missing in some of
these cases so that it wasn't clear that
this was the bundle protocol particular
registry so just check that you go to
Layana registry page check that you have
the full registry name identifier so to
say the string that's actually on the
eye on a web page for each registry that
that's actually written exactly in the
draft okay sure yeah yeah go ahead
no no that's this is this is mostly text
from from mark who wrote the the other
draft so I I suspect he got it right but
I will double-check the iron registry
for new allocations ought to be this RFC
so I think Ricky said this on the
mailing list that should be RFC to be in
a lot of places you said that one I
think was Magnus wasn't me so from
experience of this sort of thing you let
Ayane
yeah to find it you know yeah right so
well but it's it's not it's not a matter
of what the numbers are going to be it's
a matter of how you write the name of
the reference and so I think that the
references currently are in 16 anyway
were or 17 where
or section numbers in the specification
so we can just change it to RFC to be
[Music]
yes I mean in the straightest tables
where comments you use like the what I
put in the shed which is square bracket
RFC to be defined as shortened together
it comes RFC to be D and square brackets
and you put that in the reference part
of the tables so and then during the
this publication process I notice in the
arts the editor will change that to the
RFC number assigned okay
okay and then with the third part of the
INR considerations comments were that
how come there are references to our
state 5050 and does this indicate that
our C 50 is expected to remain in our
current protocol how do we do that
and I and I'm here again I'm I'm
uncertain what we do about this if we're
going to have an eye on a section that
comprises a merger of the original RFC
50/50 oriented registries and then new
values then the reference for those
things sort of has to be RFC 5050 if
we're not then then we can take them
away so Scot the Rick Taylor again I'm
slightly confused about the context of
this was the question around the fact
that you have tables of new entry
suggestions for Ayana
in the document which have the previous
values reused by RFC 50 50 in them
that's right so from my non chair
opinion if I was writing that I would
not include values that weren't defined
by the document
to your writing so you say dear Ayane
please add these values and update
existing if required the following
values and let Ayane maintain the
registry you just defined the Deaf okay
so I would like to just make sure that
that mark agrees this context is from in
this case I think you're on WIC often
wrong because what we're doing here is
we actually we are so going forward
after this nurse Lee becomes published
but the anti section currently does is
saying that yes if these following
registries that we have been updated by
this RC so the registration definition
is being the combination of obscene 6255
and the RFC to be and therefore in the
tables we actually want to show how the
tables is supposed to look by after this
update and that includes reference them
for that's going to be both 50/50 and
RFC to be and I think the missing the
fact that they were missing in those
interests that's it's used by both BP
six and seven didn't have the double
reference set right it might be part of
the confusion here from so when you're
showing that thesis this is how the
table will look at the point of
registering this new updates to the
registries and going forward of course
you can add to it individual video
saying as you say WIC adds the following
entry in the table and that's gonna be
hanged by Anna but at this point we
actually defining a snapshot of a
reorganization of the table okay okay so
so the current structure is the correct
structure don't look at me because I'm
wrong about in the document yes okay
yeah you just need to add where you have
fifty fifty and in cases like those
based on like if you take the bundle
formats registry or saying which
different I mean there you have to have
those interests you know this is both 56
and seven and
of course this is included order the RFC
to be and the 50:54 that's my opinion
list so yeah so this is the types are
redefined in this document right there
the definitions are repeated in this
document yeah I would like just a
actually they are defined for bp7 in
this document well no they're the the
the the registries in that in the IRS
section are they show the union of the
original RFC 50 50 values and the new
vp7 values and the definition is of the
original values is now in both documents
the there are definitions the
definitions of some of these values are
in 5050 and the definitions of others
are in this document okay so in there
not like anything that's in 50 50 is not
repeated in this document know that they
are repeated yeah in their repeated in
these these registries registry
snapshots no I mean the definition the
extra text the definitions are not okay
then it's fine yeah okay okay so we'll
leave that alone and the processing
control Flags Stuart said that these are
critical enough that there should be a
more demanding criterion for updating
them such as standards action so I said
fine so I changed the registration
policy request as shown here the
registration policy has changed to
standards action and because there's a
limited number of bits available that
should only be granted for stannis tract
RFC approved by a iesg
this is an existing registry Stuart says
how come there are no private use of
experimental allocations and I don't
know what we should do about this should
we
define some that are not currently
defined the original registry did not
have any private use or experimental
allocations I wreck taylor here i'm
actually just looking at the the
registry filings 21 to 63 amount is
unassigned so the insurgents from
private and yes so you could redefine an
area of that good i personally not
personally i think it's worth having a
few okay that's not my chair opinion
that's my personal opinion because
people do experiments and let's not get
them rampaging across other people's
face i for five daga mad okay so it's
just a gut feeling some some handful
eight maybe something yeah it seems
seniors most power of two
okay good could do that and following on
from that I'd make them right at the top
yes it seems logical does help those you
know top end of the spectrum this is a
free-for-all area sure okay Norman of
references this was just a
misunderstanding on Stuart's part though
that he thought BP second meant RFC 6 to
7 and and and it actually does not it
means they're the Big D sex
specification which is assumed to be a
an RFC so it shouldn't be down revved
let's see a normative reference Turner I
should leave paper on on crc32 so but
that reference has been changed in now
refers to RFC 3385 instead of the I
Triple E reference defining crc32 seeing
the there was a there was a reference to
the definition of epic time and Stuart
said I'm not sure it's a good idea and
it becomes moot because everything
relating to definition of time has been
removed so that that handily
Lutz this question is there there's a
there's CB VL at the end of the document
what's the license position for that and
I'm quoting from Magnus's email here
that it's it's not code it's it's format
description comparable to a B and F so I
don't proposed it to change anything
there and then there was more on
namespaces there several places where
Stewart asked what where's the namespace
but something in space and I we've been
through this just a few minutes ago so I
think the resolution here is it's it's
fine the way it is I'll go back and make
sure that the registry names are correct
that match up exactly with what's on
Ayana but that we don't need to be
saying what the namespaces are because
the registry names are essentially the
namespaces there's a URI scheme types
registry and Stuart's reservation here
is that it's made bit field why are
there not more reserved values that more
require more considered action to
release and that's a good question so I
don't know what to do about that and I
open the question up to the working
group what do we think about this go
back there we go sorry I'm just trying
the reference my cell phone my laptop
yeah you're asking types so is that the
that's in the bundle protocol it's yeah
scheme types I think is the name yeah I
didn't copy the whole name into the
header here
yeah I'm not certain just what the name
is it could be scheme type codes or but
if but it's your ice scheme the bundle
protocol URI scheme should if you search
for that it should come up
under the actual Ayane URI schemes yeah
I I think I think there I there are the
schemes but there's what the things that
the schemes are definitions of URI
schemes but we're defined here as codes
that are numbers that were that
identifies those schemes and that's a
new registering that's why I can't find
its new go ahead - yeah yeah so what
would be talking about this section
10.16 right the trade history and and it
has serious research one is DT and two
is IP n and three to 254 is unassigned
and 255 is reserved so that's and III
don't think this is an issue and the its
specification required which seems very
reasonable for this you need to have in
your ice cream definition which you want
to add to this protocol and that Suffolk
is sufficient it has some documentation
on how to use this in bp7 Tony the
larger values Rick speaking personally
now I've worked out what on earth we're
talking about sorry for being slow no I
don't think so I as me speaking
personally not as chair I don't
particularly like this eight bit field
anyway but I know the reality is IP n
exists and the DTN text-based schema
exists as well so we need to have a
selector yeah let's and there look at
conceivably the others and there was the
intent is that it's a URI so you can
have like lots of different ways of
doing it exactly and then having this
sort of numeric selector in there seems
to go against the grain of what the URI
guys are trying to do so I think
philosophically it's not a great idea so
making it bigger than eight is just
inviting people to agree to go off and
do more crazy numeric stuff which is
probably not right right yeah well
there's only one reserved value in that
field is that is that sufficient yes
okay good
I think at least is because I mean
what's like 255 would be used if we ever
run out of space at this table you would
use 255 sucess oh by the way you need to
go look at something else he actually
understand this okay and and I don't
think this never will occur in this
because doing so many different URI
schemes for upon the protocol doesn't
seem that likely mm-hmm start here so I
used to see a lot of rfcs with you know
reserved for future standards action and
point taken that we may not be fond of
the existence of this field in the first
place but we'd be even less fond if
people start using it and and filling
vast regions of the of the 8-bit space
with with different things so it might
not be unreasonable to you know reserve
half the space for standards action and
only leave half the space open for
people to do whatever crazy things
they're thinking of doing Rick hit point
point taken I thought the idea was to
reserve that the whole 8-bit field is
under standards track control so you
have to understand a stripe document to
get one of those values so to begin with
then you have a need use that your iced
tea mean inbounder protocol and that's
and then you need a document that
defines how you do that and that's I
think a reasonable bar and it's
basically for expert also check that
cells this is a reasonable request to
add it I think it we don't need to put
the board at high and split I mean I
wouldn't expect an issue with this okay
so we leave that alone good
there's a reference to the DTN research
group website in the for additional
information section they thought that
was a bad idea so I've removed that
reference and and he objected to the
word contraindicated which is actually
goes back to RC 50/50 but as points out
some some of us may be less familiar
with this word than others and so can I
jump in as Rick here um I had a similar
instance in a previous RFC I got
published where and this sort of stuff
is picked up by the RFC editors I I had
a statement talking about magic beans
and the RFC editors are very good copy
editors and they understand about the
use of English for non-native English
speakers and understanding that this is
legible and clear from my perspective
these topics are to be picked up by the
RFC editor and they will quiz you about
this and other things you didn't realize
okay they they they didn't pick it up
for our 1650 ah well perhaps we'll get a
different editor this time or you know I
I'm not sure it's worth spending time
working on the English language at this
point it's a perfectly valid I don't
find that I I've proposed to stick in
four words here well we we have an
opportunity here we have a room full of
I mentioned some non-native English
speakers does anyone who image is their
second language have an opinion about
the word contraindicated yes I think
it's it's it's fairly far out in my
vocabulary at least it's not obvious
not one word which is like the immediate
springs to mind of what that means so if
you can change it to something simpler I
think that's there is a point in it okay
so I would propose then to just leave it
for the copy editors and and not deal
with it now and I think that's the last
of my slides
yeah all right yes
thank you Scott any questions thanks
okay goodbye Magnus so Nick next up we
have ed who's going to be talking about
what's happened in the wonderful world
of VP sex so hello my name is ed brain
you may need to be close to microphone
this look great and I work at Johns
Hopkins Applied Physics lab and I wanted
to just go over some updates to VP SEC
so the version of BT sac that went in
for review was VP SEC version 12
we made some responses to those reviews
which was BP section 13 none of the
changes or comments were significant
certainly nothing that changed the
processing or the data structures
associated with the protocol so it's
used up a little extra time while we
have the working group together I wanted
to also talk about some of the
interoperability work that we are doing
and some policy rules associated with to
see if the working group had any
comments on on those before before the
internet drafts associated with them
would come up on the list so for BP SEC
12 the the general review came back with
ready with nits there were some very
very minor comments associated with
making sure that we had spelled out
acronyms before they were used or there
was an extra space in between two words
and we fix all of those without any fuss
we did not get sector review comments
back I believe that they were initially
requested to be do about a week ago on
November 14th but we don't have an
update on that so if anyone does have an
update on that or if there's a way that
we could appropriately ask for an update
that would be appreciated otherwise the
only other reviews that came in the
Ayana reviews or were not significant
and it talked about the question of how
do we look at the registries from the
point of view of BP is an RFC 50 50 and
I think that we came to an understanding
there
in particular the the Ayana updates most
recently where that we converged on
these registry questions the new bundle
protocol specification VP Biss will
register bpv seven block types and we
will not have conflict with those block
types and RFC 50:50 the BP sec document
had called out block types two and three
for the integrity block in the
confidentiality block we won't do that
because RFC 5050 block type registries
in v6 had already defined two and three
and we don't want that kind of collision
so these will be moved most likely to
eleven and twelve instead of two and
three it really doesn't make a
difference from our point of view it's
still all in codes within one byte so it
would have really practically no impact
on on VP sack or the size of the blocks
and in VP sack version thirteen I
updated those to be eleven and twelve I
will probably have to publish a fourteen
which I'm going to wait on for SEC
sector review when I won't even put
eleven and twelve and I think the right
thing to do is to say as assigned by
iana or whatever the appropriate text is
Rick unless there's some compelling
reason why the values 11 and 12 have
meaning then just ask for the for some
numbers indeed and and really as long as
it's less than I think 22 or so which is
what what you can pack into a seaboard
mic without going into two bytes that
would be our preference so but to
respond to the to the comments that we
gotten to date we put out a VP 613 we
made all of the minor changes we
corrected the gen our nets and we
cleaned up some other terminology in
particular there was some leftover
terminology that talked about key
parameters as opposed to just parameters
and there really isn't a sense of
parameters and key parameters they are
all just parameters so we cleaned that
language up actually walking through the
description the text-based description
of example blocks in an example bundle
the text did not match the figure which
was surprising when I went through and
did a final read-through so we made a
few minor Corrections to make sure that
the text matched the figure the figure
was correct and then really because we
had made a
terminology change from security from
cipher suite to security context we made
sure that we had used the proper
terminology security context everywhere
if that was needed in the document so
these were all clean up things nothing
that changed the standard the data
structures or its processing so what is
left once we get the security reviews
back we will apply any comments that we
get we did get an initial review of BP
SEC version 6 even though that was seven
versions ago there really has not been
significant technical change to the
document is but mostly clarifying text
some of which was responding to the
comments that we got from BP SEC 6
sector review so I think that we're good
there we're not expecting any
significant problems or changes or
showstoppers coming back and we do have
the same reviewer as the person who
reviewed this seven versions ago so I
think we'll be ok we'll update the Ino
section as we need to we will make sure
the only other thing that has come up is
the BP SEC document makes a reference to
something called PID reference as we use
it in the document it just means the
reference to the security source a ID
however someone noted that in BP v6
terminology ID reference has a specific
meaning which is a pointer into a
dictionary in a primary block in BP
version 6 and so that is something we
should not use we should just say Eid
instead of Eid reference so we'll clean
that up in the next version to make sure
that that there is no terminology
collision and otherwise any review
comments will will apply as we get them
so unless there are any other specific
questions or concerns around BP SEC as a
as a standard in review or recommend a
standard in review I wanted to move on
talked about a few other things so we
introduced the concept of a security
context separate from a cipher suite
because a cipher suite is a suite of
tools that you would use to apply
different security constructs into the
bundle to generate
Saltz to generate ciphertext from plain
text however a cipher suite assumes a
set of configurations and one of the
things that we would typically see such
as in IPSec is a security Association a
security Association would be some
predefined or pre-configured set of
configurations that could be shared and
to end that's not necessarily one-to-one
a reasonable thing to expect in a delay
tolerant Network however the concept
that there is a security context around
a cipher suite which is the cipher suite
plus the configuration or understanding
of configuration associated with how to
use and apply that cipher suite is a
useful concept and if we just use the
term cipher suite it doesn't imply
cipher suite plus that additional
contextual information so to make sure
that there was not a confusion of those
terms we decided not to say cipher suite
we decided to say security context in
that to then give an example of how this
would be used we define some
interoperability security context and
there is one called interoperable
Interop - SC - zero zero which is a
working group document and presumably
would would go forward or once we make
sure there are no changes in BP SEC and
we have then started looking past the
initial draft security context into what
other ones might be useful to have and
so here are three examples of current
thinking on security context concepts
that are out there I wanted to put them
in front of the working group to see if
there were any comments the first is is
there value either in the existing
interoperability security context or in
a new one
to add a self signing bib and for those
of you who are familiar with the context
of a bib a bib is a security block that
is added to a bundle and the block type
specific data in the bib has among other
things a a result a signed integrity
signature over the target block that it
is targeting and is there a value at
having a separate signature result in
the bib that
is a self signature over itself to see
if anything had changed in the bib and
and want one of the reasons that that
had come so so there is not a draft
associated with any of these three
things and one of the one of the items
that we will propose is another internet
draft will show up that has either 300
net rafts or one that has multiple
security contacts in it which will have
some of these ideas and so perhaps at
the next IETF if there is time we could
present it as a draft but just to prime
that discussion we wanted to bring forth
some of the ideas here to see if there
was a strong sense or useful comments
that we could get prior to writing such
an internet draft Scott brewery just
asking about this and really asking I
don't know enough to comment but would
this self signature on the bib be would
it be obviated by using asymmetric
encryption or or would you even need it
even if if you have public and private
keys so so it could be but again if this
were a security context if the security
context has a superset of the cipher
suites used it would say if you are
using a security context the security
context would say here are the cipher
suites that we would be using and we
would use these particular cipher suites
to generate target signatures and self
signatures and handle them in this way
if you then were to chain if you were to
use a different cipher suite with a
different context it would be a
different security context not this one
so so a concept around the security
context is it is the cipher suites that
you would use and the context around it
it isn't we could keep the same security
context and swap cipher Suites in and
out under the hood this is permanent
Schiaparelli again so that I I think
that wasn't exactly my question I think
you you asked what would it be valuable
to have a self signing bib and and my
question was do you need it do you need
self signature on a bib
if the cipher suite did you happen to be
using is based on asymmetric encryption
or do you only need self signature on a
bib if you've got symmetric keys III
don't so I don't fully understand that
question because because if you have
multiple parameters in the security
block itself do you want an integrity
signature over those parameters or if
you look down to one of the questions
that we have for bib a little bit couple
bullet points down would you also want
to include things like the block
processing flags of the bib in the
integrity signature and I think that
deciding whether you want to protect
changes to the bib block itself is
different from whether you're using
symmetric or asymmetric key to generate
some of the contents of the bib block so
I thought that's I I don't know that I'm
understanding that question
so if I create a if I create a security
bib it will have security results in it
but it will have a lot of other material
in it and I don't want an attacker for
example to twiddle some bits in the bib
in a parameter field or somewhere else
that that never touched a cipher suite
symmetric key or a symmetric key okay so
sorry Rick just jumping into the queue
here just because I can't be bothered to
stand up and I if I understand what
you're saying is given now security
context is more than just the cipher
suite selection there is also extra
metadata that is carried in that context
you could use a cipher suite that's self
protecting in some way probably probably
key pair but that other metadata isn't
isn't covered under that protection and
therefore your question is what if you
could put a bib on that and then you put
an endless
recursive loop of self signing each
other so so you probably wouldn't want
an endless but but if you look at the
contents of a big a bib would say this
is the security context identifier that
I'm using then these are the parameters
for that security context and then here
is a set of key value pairs of results
the result type 1 has result value and
yes that value would have been generated
by whatever cipher suite was used but if
I see if I am a malicious person I'm not
but if I were a malicious person I would
come back and say if I see a bib I could
change the security context ID from a 7
2 & 8 & and that would result in failure
perhaps to to verify at a security
Waypoint or a destination because I have
changed something about how we would
apply a cipher suite but you might be
able to catch that even sooner and say
specifically something had happened with
the parameters as opposed to the the
result data and is there value in that
or if someone were to change the block
processing flags of a bib would you want
to understand that and then react to
that as well as opposed to ignoring it
and that's the kind of extra data around
the cipher suite results and the
question is is there value in signing
that Rick again I would solve that
problem by using bundle and bundle
encapsulation ok I would just at that
point it gets so meta in terms that I
would take a step back and say just
encapsulate the whole bundle and then I
can guarantee integrity of it I guess I
guess in my mind the the endless
recursive loop that you're talking about
is is the issue and maybe not maybe
incorrectly but but why would the self
signature itself will not be susceptible
to being fiddled with so that it no
longer works there's probably a reason
for that but I don't know what it is
well know
and is the impact any different if
whether you I take your point that
earlier in the path of transit of that
bundle an intermediate node may say hey
the integrity signatures have been
tampered with
mmm-hmm drop is that I suppose the point
is that you could do that check earlier
in the path or could you not I suppose
with the security context where an
intermediate node could not work out
where the tamper has occurred I I'm
trying to work through the use case
quite simply in there is data in a bib
that is not integrity site right so so
there are three ways that you could
handle that one is to allow data in a
bib to just never be integrity site the
second is take the entire bundle and
encapsulate it in a different bundle and
then integrity sign the intention which
is a little heavyweight yeah the third
is to say of the data that is not
integrity protected in the bib add an
integrity signature to it which does not
force you into infinite recursion it
simply says you can you can construct an
integrity signature over the data that
is not signed and carry that signature
I'm gonna drill the line okay because
let's take this to the list this is
really interesting but I think we all
need to have a long think about it so
absolutely and point being is that I
wanted to okay so I think there's
interest in taking this to the list and
just in the points we got a little bit
more time the other is a single target
multiple result something else that came
back was it would be nice to have a
security context that would say here's a
cipher suite you don't need to
necessarily have a single signature with
a single key over the target data what
we could do is provide multiple
parameters for the security context and
you would generate multiple results and
the security context documentation would
then come back and say if any of these
verify then then the block has verified
and it would be okay or some quorum of
them verify and that might be a way of
saying
if I don't know all of the recipients
and I don't have a single multicast a ID
key then I can I can carry multiple
signatures and we think that that's a
reasonable thing to do as opposed to
having multiple bid blocks or multiple
individual entries you could capture it
in a single security context and that
would be a little less bytes on the wire
Rick again I can see some as far as I've
understood it I think I can see some
value in that you to handle the case of
expired certificates so you could multi
sign with out-of-date information that
at least the person that the other one
knows they can unpack it and know it's
out of date because one of the targets
validated the integrity but they knew
they were using an old key or something
like that yeah that's a great idea
particularly if you have key rotation
schedules or something else you can go
over it's a DTN you could be away for
long for longer than you were expected
and all your certificates expired while
you were away yeah so that is good
that's good feedback I'll take it from
the notes and then the last was for for
even just the interoperability security
context that we have right now the
integrity block only captures integrity
over the data portion of its target so
if it is if it's looking at target block
b1 it will look at B ones block type
specific data fields and generate a
signature over that however there's an
entire block header separate from the
data there is no reason why you could
not take the entire block or large
pieces of the block canonicalize it and
generate the integrity signature over
more than just the block type data
fields and there are three things at
least that could be done there one is we
could leave it as is and only generate
the integrity signature over the block
type specific data the other is generate
a signal signature over the entire
extension block or at least a superset
of just the block type specific data
which would which could be done or the
third is you generate two signatures
which seems like a lot of work one over
the block type specific data and one
separately over the block extension data
and
have rules as to whether both are
required or one is a nice to have in
case someone changes a block processing
flag I know if there were any opinions
about that and then the last one is the
sim the same question reimagined for a
confidentiality block which is again the
ECB will replace the block type specific
data of its target with ciphertext and
it will generate a signature over that
ciphertext is there then value in having
a separate plaintext signature over the
the non block type specific data fields
of its target the block type ID the the
block number the block processing flags
things like that then that information
is pretty canonical isn't it I'd say I
sorry Rick Taylor yeah I'm gonna have to
think about this I'm gonna have to think
about the representation because I think
this comes down to do we have a
canonical representation of these things
that can be validated correctly and I
believe BP biz has a canonicalization
algorithm for extension blocks that that
this could be used I believe that's the
case I no longer believe that that is
the case but but one could however a
security context and this is something
that the BP SEC document describes a
security context is able to define a
canonicalization algorithm to be used if
one does not so so those were some ideas
as we start we will start putting
forward some security context internet
drafts to describe this idea of not just
cipher Suites but cipher suites and
behavior and context configuration
associated with them Oh Scott burly I
actually think about it the
canonicalization we do have
specification in BP biz for serializing
a extension block and so the student the
serialized represented the sea boar see
realized representation of extension
block I think you could think of as
being the canonicalization of that
extension block and so in that sense we
do have it as long as it is there some
normative way of saying well here are
some
user reserved bits in the block type
processing flags and set them all to
zero or set them all to ones truncate
them in some way so Rick we've been
round this before and I believe that the
the the C but there's this there was a
working group working on C Burrell
signatures and certificate and key
material who works through all the
canonicalization of C bore serialization
rules but I'm I will need to look
through my notes and try and remember
what nerve I'm talking about but I know
that would be a good reference to have
yes I think we're gonna come up with
that as we define the behaviors of
various security contents I'm thinking
that works being done already for us and
we don't need to reinvent it so so those
were some security context ideas then
the the last topic and if we're
stretching on the line would before we
do so the the next is the BP SEC
document defines how security blocks can
be added into a bundle to implement
security services however there is a
separate out-of-band question which is
if i am a waypoint note or if i'm a
destination note how do i understand
whether a service needs to be in the
bundle or not and there's a problem with
encoding that information in a bundle
because if you go through a malicious
node the malicious node could remove
that information or put other
information in an example of that would
be if a source of a bundle adds a b ib
into a bundle and it goes through a a
malicious node the malicious node could
drop the b ib signature change the
target block if the destination doesn't
know that a big should have been there
it would not think to check the
integrity of the target block and would
pick it up and use it and so something
has to exist at destinations that say
this is what you are expected to have in
a bundle and when you generate bundles
this is what you should put in based on
those specifications and that's an
out-of-band mechanism and it's covered
in the vp SEC security consideration
document and policy cannot document
security considerations section and
policy consideration section we've
started looking through what that
could look like it is largely informed
by the ion implementation which is
thought through some of this in what
they call the ion second min tool and
and the processing rules the security
processing rules in in looking at this
we've defined three different roles that
a BPA from a protocol agent may have a
bundle protocol agent could in some
cases act as a security source which is
an agent that adds security blocks into
a bundle either a bundle it is creating
or a bundle that it is modifying before
retransmitting or forwarding a security
way point which is cases where a bundle
agent would verify a security service
like integrity before forwarding a
bundle and the last is when the bundle
agent is itself the destination of a
security service perhaps a nose that
would do decryption which may or may not
be the same as the bundle destination
itself and and those are a single node
could be each of those four different
bundles that it encounters so Rick just
jumping ahead of scope I have a question
about your security waypoints and I
understand this are you attempting to
tackle the problem of malicious
intermediate nodes moving corrupted
bundles around the Cheka Waypoint no no
so we're not trying to do path based
security the the use of the term source
Waypoint and destination and the
connotation of those terms with routing
and there is no expectation that there
is any routing or path computation for
expectation with that when we say
security source security Waypoint and
security destination we we mean
literally the source the Eid that is the
source of a security block the Eid that
is processing a security block that is
not the destination should be the end
receiver of that and a security
destination is not the bundle
destination and is not a part of a path
and a route a security destination is a
BPA that say I am the end consumer of
that security block I will process it
remove it from the bundle and then
separately perhaps deliver that bundle
or forward
to someone else okay hmm
Schiaparelli I'm security security
destination of course I immediately
raises a flag for me
I we were saying that it has a thing to
do with routing how do you ensure that
the bundle that the block reaches its
destination if you don't route using it
so so when when we looked at the
original BSP there was a concept of
security destination which was itself
somehow conflated with routing you know
such that you needed to get to the
security destination before you got to
the bundle destination well you needed
to get to the security destination yeah
I guess before I got to the bundle
destination because otherwise you would
never get to it sure so so that was
certainly a problem and was one of the
things it was one of the reasons why we
looked at VP sex effort from BSP because
it was one of the implementation
concerns there there is no expectation
associated with routing when you add a
security service into a bundle for
example if you say I am going to encrypt
a target block there is there is not
necessarily anything in that block that
says only some future other block in the
or other node in the network can decrypt
this you you encrypt the block and you
send it along its way what who decrypts
it later is a function of this kind of
policy implementation that is
out-of-band with BP sack if you are the
bundle destination and you receive an
encrypted block you will try and decrypt
it you may not succeed you may not have
the security context you may not have
the cryptographic material to do the
decryption and you may wind up at the
bundled destination receiving an
encrypted block that you don't know how
to process now that but that is a
network configuration error not an issue
per se with the security specification I
I would suggest that it be nice to find
a term other than
destination then because destination
connotes intent it connotes direction to
up to a point as opposed to here it is
whoever it is that receives it and can
do something with it please do something
with it could I could I suggest
something like origin and targets I mean
well it's not really target but its its
I my first thought was producer and
consumer but but I don't think that's
exactly we're talking about roles not
moving things I yes I agree with you
again notice we have a little bit of
you've got about three moments point
being the the I agree and I'm open to
other terms the the the insight into
this is the originator of the bundle
does not determine who the destination
is it is incumbent upon the receiver of
the bundle to self identify as the
destination and and from that
perspective there is there is not intent
from the sender side it is a self
identification on the receiver side but
and and my concern is that someone
coming to look at this specification
doesn't know all the context in the
history might be confused and and and I
think it would be good to avert that
confusion so I I'm not tied to the term
in particular if there's a better term
perhaps consumer okay that was some that
something okay sukar Tier three quick
ones starting with the last first a word
that seems somewhat cumbersome but that
might have the correct definition would
be accept or security accept or I can
see that then a second question security
source second bullet item last word may
or may not be the bundle destination
setting aside the I'm sorry okay thank
you and lastly security Waypoint
responsible for actually verifying
security services is that the only thing
that a waypoint can do or could a
waypoint for instance do proc Syrian
Krypton so
as we have laid out the roles we would
say that verification but not changing
would be would be the role of the
Waypoint and that if you were to
re-encrypt re-encrypt to me means
decrypt from in existing and then re
encrypt with a different security
context in which case that node would
not no longer be a waypoint it would be
both a security accept or and a security
source that's separate from the idea of
super encryption which would be you take
the initial ciphertext and generate
ciphertext over the ciphertext which
which we currently don't believe is a
useful thing to do and because it all
fine but one clarification proxy
encryption doesn't necessarily involve
going from ciphertext to plaintext and
then back to ciphertext there are tricky
Ari encryption I think Rick here I think
the point is that the way point has has
read-only access to the bundle I would
again suggest Waypoint is probably not
the right word and verifier or something
like that
someone who examines the bundle checks
it is all okay but doesn't touch the
security context involved now I
appreciate that so then in in what we
can skip over that unless unless anyone
wants to test their eyesight but it is
just sort of some of the some of the
illustrations which we can now do an SVG
yeah to the internet drafts when we talk
about these different roles and we'll
keep security source what would they
look like and so part of this process is
to put together the at least the data
model or the language associated with
how these rules would be specified and
for security source there are two pieces
to it one is how do you identify that a
security service is necessary and then
how do you represent which security
service that actually is borrowing from
ion we've said that the way you identify
whether a security service is required
in a bundle is to say if you are if your
bundle was sourced at this particular a
ID with wild card matching and it is
destined for some other a ID with wild
card matching and you have this type of
block in the bundle then this particular
block type going from
source bundle source to bundle
destination should have this security
service associated with it we don't call
out in particular integrity versus
confidentiality because that's captured
in the security context ID and then the
security source would be which EW you
want to represent this BPA as we know
with with BP a particular physical node
can have multiple a IDs registered with
it and so you would you would perhaps
want to configure when you add a
security block into the bundle and you
want to represent that security source a
ID in the security block you have a
option of e IDs to choose from which one
would you want to use and then if there
are any particular security context
parameters that you want carried in the
security block they would be listed as
well and and a simple example of what
that would look like would be if you are
generating a bundle coming out of IP n1
dot anything going anywhere and you have
a payload in it then you will identify
the security source ID as IP n1 dot o
and you will use contact seven with some
parameters associated with it and this
list of rules would be the security
policy associated with security source
then if you are either a security
verifier or security except door then
you would have a slightly different that
rolls off the tongue thank you
you would have a different set of
information the identification would
still be the same if you are receiving a
bundle from this source bundle source to
this bundle destination and it has this
block type in it then this is what to
expect this rule would say if you if you
match that with wildcards you should see
a security block with security context
idea of whatever over that target block
and in addition to the security
parameters in that security block here
are some local parameters that you would
also want to feed to the cipher suite
and the reason we do that is there are
times when you may not wish to put all
of the security context parameters in
the security block because you
understand that there is some pre
configuration or pre sharing or
precalculus
of information that doesn't need to be
in the bundle and can be assumed across
obviously if you were in networks or
cases where you can't make that
assumption you can find ways of putting
that data into the security block itself
and then lastly regarding on whether you
are a verifier or an acceptor you would
say what are the processing actions that
I might want to take based on how the
verification or the acceptance of that
security source would go and this would
give you fine-grained control by block
type and by security context of how you
handle certain behaviors so so what I've
started putting together and this is by
no means either correct or complete is
the set of actions that you may want to
or into a action bid field you know if
follow the block processing control
flags if you failed something sorry ed
can I jump in here so there's this bit
field where is it is this going in is
your intention to put another extension
block in which contains these rules
which travels with the bundle no no not
at all so so that would be an
implementation as part of your rules
that would be lookup in some sort of
data table and then that's my action
absolutely okay if I were to show you
this which is an even worse picture Wow
if we would come back and say I am a bpa
agent that is receiving a bundle I would
have a local policy database associated
with my source rules my verifier rules
my acceptor rules and and the verifier
rules and the acceptor rules while they
may have the same format made themselves
be different because you may take
different actions based on what role you
have but this is something that would be
local implementation associated with the
BPA and it would allow you to say things
like saying if the security context
failed to verify in some way then we
would set bit four which says please
send a report signifying that to the
report to be ID and that is Ord with bit
eight that says and delete the security
target that failed the processing and
that's word with one zero which is
delete the security block associated
with that as well or somesuch there so
the point is I'm not saying these are
the correct action
points but the idea is that from a
formatting perspective this is likely
the set of information and then you
could see a series of rules or rows in a
database that you could walk through
saying I've gotten a bundle in it's from
this source to this destination within
wildcards like I got a bundle from IP n
1 dot something it's going somewhere it
has a payload in it I should expect that
this would have a security block over
that payload using ID 7 it may not
itself have a key name in it but I'm
gonna hard-coded that the key name
should be 1 and here are the actions I
will or will not take based on how the
processing goes
Schiaparelli I'm just as I'm listening
to this I'm wondering if this is the
moral equivalent of firewalls for DTS
yeah this is excess control yeah yeah
okay so I'm there and a reason to bring
that up is that several years ago there
was work on on a deacon analog to be
peat iptables
EP tables and I'm wondering if if that
needs to be revisited and maybe
superseded by this fair enough point
well-taken it and our point was that as
we start trying to do reference
implementations for BP sack we need some
way of capturing the policy associated
with what blocks you put in what blocks
you verify and what actions you take
based on those so Rick with my chair hat
on yes I can see there's two parts to
this yeah it's a there's a lot of
implementation detail here but I
evaluate for that implementation to
ensure that we've covered all the corner
cases in BP second we've got the the
power to do this sort of thing so I
obviously I really like the work I think
it's really clever but yeah it's it's
filtering access control list stuff and
it's a good demonstration of what we can
do with with BP sake I'm not sure we
dive too far into sponsoring work about
bit layouts for implementations and so
on but I'm not sure you're proposing
that no and perhaps the output of this
usefully would be something
informational yeah absolutely so I'm
looking at the time
okay any other questions from people no
thank you very much it so Scott you
don't have any slides about bundle and
bundle encapsulation do you want to do
something off the cuff
sure and really all I would want to do
is encourage people to to take a look at
the latest internet draft for bundled
model encapsulation I'll probably be
posting another one because the window
is closed right now but as soon as the
window reopens I've got another draft
ready to post the the reason bundle
bundle encapsulation I think is
important for a couple of reasons one is
there are some security features that
you can get from bundle and bundle
encapsulation that are difficult to get
any other ways such as
protection from traffic analysis another
though is that the bundle bundle
encapsulation specification includes the
custody transfer mechanism that was in
RFC 5050 and actually extends and
updates that to to implement a an
aggregate custody signaling system that
has been in ion for several years
developed by guys at University of
Colorado to bring the overhead of
custody transfer down I think that's a a
useful mechanism and I I think it's an
important work item for the recharter
which is our segue into the next topic
and for in in my mind it's the the that
my mind is the top priority work item
for the Charter after we get these three
documents in in place any questions on
that
Thanks thanks thanks
so we have 20 minutes left of the
session and following on from the is
that full screen following on from the
interim the list of proposed new charter
items as was circulated on the mailing
list is this so
Magnus at the time raised concern that
this is a very long list and I know
there are drafts so you can see that
there's March or D have an active a
recent draft and those parts with an X
have a draft from the IRT FD Tian
research group so some of this stuff
does have some documentation already but
the critical question is before we
update the Charter for the working group
so DTN working group phase two we need
to make sure that the items that go on
the Charter are achievable so I'm
looking at the people in the room here
only our ad is on meet EKKO but I'm
assuming or hoping there are a couple of
other people on Jabba and there are
other people who are willing to step in
and help put some of this together so
this is now an open mic opportunity for
people to say yes I'm interested in
working on some of these things yes I am
interested in this new thing which I
think should be really important etc etc
or no I think this is nonsense
help yourself so ed brain I know that
the asynchronous management has a lot of
items under it but I would say that this
work will continue it has some years
behind it it has years ahead of it and
so we would be able and have the energy
and people who are already working on it
to continue it and obviously if anyone
else wanted to to join in we would
welcome that and then if we talk about a
manifest block or a table of contents
block or something else that provides
expectations of what should be in a
bundle would be very interested in
helping
with that as well so Rick speaking
personally I the top half of that list
so bundle protocol additional blocks
that's bundle and bundle is working
progress manifests block I know that
Scott and Ed are both very keen to see
that work being done as ed said
asynchronous management is very much
underway the bottom half of this list is
actually something I think is as
important but has less interest or less
input from from the regulars so to speak
so neighbor discovery outside of very
fixed deterministic delay tolerant
networks some sort of neighbor discovery
starts to be relevant when you're
looking at ad hoc style DT ends which is
obviously for non-space communities main
driver for DT ends you've got to be able
to discover potential forwarding
opportunities potential adjacencies how
is this done at the bundle processing
where we know how to do this with link
technologies but how do we bridge that
link to bundle protocol gap and there's
lots of room for ideas experimentation
suggestions and all welcome also naming
an addressing that's people outside of
this room assume that there's a naming
scheme there is but it's fairly simple
I'm trying not to be rude about it
but it's it's it's it works for small
systems if we want to try do we want to
try and build a global heterogeneous DTN
network because if we do we need a
proper global addressing we need to
solve the global addressing problem let
me put it that way so that might pique
some people's interest marble SAE is
very keen on a registry of service
identifier I'm really hoping he drives
that work personally I have a partially
written HTTP CL I just don't
have the time to finish it I'm looking
for co-authors I'm looking for anyone to
just help me get the words out I have an
SMTP implementation it's partially
broken it would be nice to write up what
I'm doing it's not brilliant I need help
or I'm happy to just give it to somebody
else to work on this it's about
collaboration and we need input okay
that's me
scarper Lee I'm of course very committed
to doing bundle bundle encapsulation I'm
certainly interested in the naming and
addressing I definitely want to be part
of that conversation neighbor discovery
there's a informational experimental RFC
that is implemented and and works I
think it's a good prototype for us to be
working from in ion in particular what
I've been trying to do is support
opportunistic forwarding based on
contact graph routing and and in aid of
that I've got a definitions for a for a
non-standard administrative record that
communicates in neighbor discovery
history through the network so that you
can guess at likely contacts in the
future with some some degree of
confidence and and and base forwarding
decisions on that there are a number of
other extension blocks and
administrative records that we are
finding that are non-standard
that we are finding useful in particular
quality of service at some point I think
needs to be addressed and I'm certainly
interested in working on all of that I'm
happy to leave the registry of service
identifiers to mark
so go ahead stir if you so one of the
questions put to us by our ad was given
the amount of effort involved in the
size of this list what what does the
working group want to prioritize we have
to put up we have to prioritize these
things so does anyone have any strong
opinions about which are the key next
pieces to do still carry here I guess I
will speak before prioritizing because I
get more things to prioritize so the
whole naming an addressing area that's
an area in which within my severe
bandwidth constraints I would be
interested in contributing we've had
some thoughts at our shop about mapping
between DTN endpoint IDs and other
identifiers spaces
you will probably grown would not be
surprised when I mention host identities
and those of you who are familiar with
high-frequency radio communications and
the AL e standard automatic link
establishment as al identifiers which I
think are sometimes relevant here
another area where again within limited
bandwidth I would be interested in
working on the norm convergence layer
when it comes to SMTP there's some work
that our shop did way back in 2001 where
because the bundle protocol didn't exist
yet we gave a different answer to the
question of is this just SMTP in our
case the answer was yes and we bundled
all sorts of things inside of SMTP and I
think it would be great to be able to
put a real bundle now that we have a
bundle protocol inside SMTP and vice
versa
sometimes you want to transport a bundle
across SMTP sometimes you want to
transport SMTP across a DTN with model
protocol the folks over in the network
coding Research Group are interested in
supporting DTN with network coding they
are pretty bandwidth limited as well
and finally I think the the ICN
application somewhere should be on this
radar and and the the profit draft the
profit extension draft I think is pretty
neat so I'm just throwing more things on
the list before we start ranking them so
quick question you raised that about the
profit extension draft that came in from
the ICN the guy who put that he's not in
the room is he because there's
occasionally this is me with my chair
hat on just in case somebody's listening
to the audio in the future occasionally
we get drafts coming in from far eastern
universities and academic institutions
talking about DTN work talking about
crossovers with ICN and it's interesting
interesting things and there's not a lot
of communication with the working group
they just submit a personal draft and
that's the last we hear I would really
like these people to come and talk to us
just put up put a message on the mailing
list to say hi I have submitted this
individual draft because there is a lot
of interest with people who read these
we read these things and say hey that's
really good let's move it on I are the
authors of this these drafts do they
want them to become working group
documents to do they my question I
suppose is is this a way of publishing a
paper to achieve part of their degree
which is not quite what it's for but
that's okay but the work is good and
when the work is good let's work on it
in the working group and and let's go
make this a standard so it's a bit of a
plea to any of the authors of a couple
of these documents to say we like this
you know come come talk to us it's an
open forum we can do this work okay
and I'm Whittaker critical technologies
um I want to just dovetail on that point
maybe at some point somebody I'm not
volunteering myself but reach back out
on some of those drafts that were really
highlights they we saw
reach back and say hey we've been
looking back through this was really
interesting is there anything else going
on because then maybe they continued
working on it um just to put up into
Stu's point I generally try to relieve
the stress and take load off of him for
his work so we're both constrained and I
share a lot of what he's interested in
as well but I'm also interested in just
reviewing if you have something throw me
an email
I'll review it I'll read it I'll try to
give you some sort of feedback so the
best place to review stuff is get on the
data tracker look at the active
documents and just literally put a
review on the main leanness to say I
read this you've got a typo here I don't
understand paragraph four all review
helps I hate to go to the might choice
in a row but it's too card here alright
so I guess if nobody's throwing more
things on the list I will nominate
naming and addressing as a priority
okay Rick speaking personally I agree
with you Stu I think naming and
addressing is the elephant in the room
as they say it's the one thing we all
pretend works but when you start to look
at it it's not actually there yet I will
also add ie we have some of the
asynchronous management is already on
the Charter as an architecture I know
that ed and his team are working hard on
this and doing good work and I think
it's really important so my plus one is
for the asynchronous management so so we
have seven minutes left I get the
feeling that we've covered quite a lot
of the topics I think the new charter
item priorities and people offering to
work on it or saying what they're
working on that they want to contribute
into the working group I think we'll
take that to the list so last five
minutes any other business or I will
shall close early and we can go and see
if we can find a cup of coffee and I can
get another drink for my throat okay in
which case I'm going to close the
meeting early thank you very much and
we'll see you all in Vancouver okay blue
sheets blue cheese blue sheets blue
sheets thank you very much
the problem