a good morning good people can you hear
me I can hear myself just not a good
thing anyways good morning and welcome
to the IETF and welcome to IC crg if you
are here if you don't believe you're
here for IC crg stay on anyways this
might be more interesting than anything
else you are going to go to before we
start I need the standard things I need
jabber scribe and I need a minute taker
volunteers come on I can start naming
names
Gouri you're looking at me like you want
to do some Janna I'll take the minutes
but I don't have a jarek on what do you
say Andrew I see it I'll take the
minutes but I don't have a jabber client
so someone needs to JavaScript Thank You
Andrews gonna do minutes jabber thank
you sir
so we've got a jabber scribe and we've
got minute minute taker so we can move
on so we have a pretty packed agenda let
me see how do I do this but before we
start we will just briefly I will flash
you the note well very very briefly we
follow the IETF IPR disclosure rules and
if you do not know what the note well is
you should go read it before you come up
to the mic and say anything at all
there's also privacy and code of conduct
which again I will not go into right now
but
you're welcome to read it their slides
are available online and the code of
conduct is available online at that URL
and the goal of the IRT F just to be
very clear we do research we don't do
standards development so if you are here
to push a standard Strack RFC or on the
wrong room
but if you are here to hear about
research ideas and not just sound let's
work then you're on the right rope and
there's our agenda for today so we're
gonna basically we have a fairly packed
agenda and I'm not going to walk through
the entire agenda but we're gonna try to
get done on time here so to the speakers
please come up just as your talk is
about thought and please make sure to
stick to the allotted time and that
includes me so I'm going to go through
this fairly quickly the first thing to
note here is we have to site meetings we
couldn't really bring them into this
meeting but they are very relevant and
you may be interested in them so do go
to them if you think you are interested
the first one is on data center
condition control and Paul Congdon is
organizing this Paul's there raising his
hand and please ask him speak with him
if you have any questions otherwise the
those details are sill correct Paul okay
lovely thank you so that's tomorrow
morning in room VIP a early in the
morning the side meeting time slot and
then you have l4s on Thursday in this
very room at the same time at 8:30 in
the morning Bob are those details still
correct so this will basically be an
update on l4 s yes o l4 s and okay TCP
Prague it's about TCP Prague not a
bottle for s not just sell for us yeah
okay but itself for SNP CP Prague euro
the details are that the l4s is mostly
in the th vwg meeting on 3rd on Thursday
this side meeting is mostly TCP Prague
fair enough thank you for that
clarification David and that's happening
Thursday in the morning so again these
are very relevant to ICC RG so we just
don't have enough time in here to do do
all of these conversations so these side
meetings are you're encouraged to go to
them I will be there and with that I'm
gonna start off on just a one topic I'm
gonna spend at most five minutes on this
we had started a conversation last time
how to do this beautiful fit the page
maybe okay that works we had I had
broached the topic of doing documents in
IC crg publishing documents through ICC
RG adopting them in ICC RG
I've had a number of conversations with
various folks since then and I'm
basically here to say now that we will
start adopting documents in this
research group I intend to use
discretion and the RG is guidance in
proposing what documents makes sense but
that's the the goal is to adopt and
publish documents here we've done this
way back in the past I'm gonna start
doing it again what does it mean to
adopt documents well broadly the
document is the reasonable fit for what
we do in this room and by what I what I
mean by what we do in this room is not
just if it fits the letter of the
Charter but if there's energy in the
room and if this is the right sort of
audience to do this work or look at
these documents typically any condition
control other fits in internet-like
environments is an absolutely wonderful
fit for example but we need to see
author engagement we need to see author
engagement with the research group and
to show that there's interested in
continuing that engagement to be adopted
in this research group and again I
intend to use discussion and research
group guidance in determining relevance
here what does it mean to publish a
document it just means that the research
of things the document is in good enough
shape yes this doesn't seem like a very
firm
process but that's by design this was
not intended to be a heavy process this
is not the ietf again I expect to call
upon the RG folks in the RG for reviews
and for other decisions and we will
figure this out as we go
there's I have faith in the community
here that we can make this work
I feel great saying this by the way this
is a good medium to say this because I
feel like I'm I'm handing off this I'm
doing this thing from upon high looking
down at all of you I will decide but
this is this is the plan going forward
is to publish documents in ICC RG and
starting off I'm gonna propose adopting
the following documents we will hear
about them today
the first one is led back plus plus the
second one is our LED bat if you haven't
read these documents please do I think
they are fairly good and I think
laid-back + + s is actually I'd say it's
it's almost an update to let that and
it's it's a very important update to
like that itself so I'm going to propose
this I will also send this out on the
mailing list and we'll adopt it when
unless I hear somebody yelling and
saying this is a terrible idea that's
the plan going forward with that well
any any quick thoughts I give you 30
seconds and your 30 seconds are up
Thank You Corey sorry go on Corey first
I'm cold account real quick
III think this is a good idea
I like this and these two these two
documents fit well because they are less
they are more conservative in other
transports therefore they definitely
fall within something that could be done
in a research group other things we
don't have to tread carefully on and I
guess we'll figure it out as we go on
but these two documents seem like good
candidates for here to me yeah I think
we will have to figure this out as we go
so question is the Martin Duke f5 is the
desired outcome of these documents to
produce informational RFC s or something
else
I yes I would think so I don't know can
we publish experimental a lot of C's
here anybody no we can't do that here
right who says we can Andrew says we can
I come on Perkins yes you can publish
experimental or informational RFC Thank
You Colin that's the voice of authority
there so yeah I would I'd be interested
in experimental but that's what I'm
gonna be pushing folks for anyways thank
you for that with that I am going to
move on with the agenda again this is
the agenda
pravin Europe first you're gonna talk
about that bed plus plus and I'm gonna
give the slides up morning everyone can
you hear me morning everyone I'm here to
talk about led by plus-plus this is now
a draft if you haven't read the draft
there's version zero one that was
published recently so please read it
LED bed plus plus is a less than best
effort congestion control so the goal is
to use unused capacity bus but quickly
yield to for ground flows example
workloads include operating system
application after it updates or backup
replicas sort of burglars next slide
please
slide is a summary of led by plasmus the
original RFC 68 17 has a bunch of
problems which were found in prior
research as well as in our efforts to
implement the RFC in the Windows
operating system I'll quickly walk
through the problems and the mechanisms
that had bad plus plus proposes to fix
those problems one way delay
measurements are hard in practice for
example in TCP the clock frequency is
not known of the pier as well as there
is a clock drift problem let my plus
plus users RTT there's a downside which
means on the downlink you may measure
congestion and react to it but because
this is less than best effort in
practice this doesn't cause problems
there's a late comer advantage problem
if there are multiple flows already in
the bottleneck link a late comer or let
bad flow would end up getting more than
its fair share led by plus plus
introduces two mechanisms to address
this problem one is the multiplicative
decrease instead of additive degrees
giving congestion avoidance as well as
initial and periodic slowdowns the
original RFC said that natural gaps in
application traffic would allow led by
to measure the base delay but that
doesn't happen in practice so led by
plus plus immediately after slow start
would enter a slowdown period and then
would enter subsequent slow long periods
with a goal to sacrifice throughput of
at most to be at least 90% of standard
tcp when there is no competing traffic
there's a internet but fairness problem
as well this is related to the late
comer advantage problem and you can
measure the base delay but although the
queue is stable the flow is bound fair
sure the led by plus plus introduces
multiplicative decrease to solve this
problem the original RFC does not
specify slow start in very great detail
there's two things that led by plus plus
does it does slower than we know ramp up
during slow start and it also does a
variant of high start to exit slow start
when it senses delay increases on the
bottleneck link there's also a latency
drift problem when you let connections
run for a long time there's a ratchet
ratcheting effect where the measurement
of the basically key keeps increasing
and that causes us to keep increasing
latency from the link
initial and periodic slowdowns help
address this problem there's also a low
latency computation problem if you have
a bottleneck link where you can't reach
target delay for example if the buffer
is too small that causes LED bad to
basically just compete with standard TCP
and the bottleneck link so slower than
Reno increase during condition avoidance
addresses this problem there was on the
mailing list there was a problem that
was brought up I think need card will
brought this problem up there what
happens when there are multiple flows or
large number of flows on the bottleneck
link do we see a ratcheting effect
problem or not so we actually did this
experiment recently so this is a hundred
millisecond or titi link we actually
changed the target in later hundred
millisecond for this experiment but yeah
the results are similar with the default
of 60 milliseconds and this is a 10x 10x
bdp bottleneck buffer so even with the
increase in number of connections we see
that the latency remains near target at
or near target so when we look at traces
there's two reasons one is when the new
flow starts even though the slow start
is slower than Reno it still causes a
deal increase and that causes other
flows to back off and then the newcomer
flow would immediately enter it slow
down phase allowing all the flows to
measure phase doing we find that all the
flows are able to successfully measured
by anyway there is another experiment
this is with both 1x + 10 X B DPS again
with large number of flows as we
increase the number of flows we find
that things mostly stabilize around
target so this is 100 millisecond or TTN
and the D for 60 millisecond target so
we would like to experiment more there
was a suggestion that we use B be our
probe our TT phase and see how that
doesn't comparison that would be a very
interesting experiment to do in the
future but currently in practice we
don't see a problem what are the changes
since the first draft so I read and
rearranged some sections to make
readability easier and thanks to
Marshalls review so I fixed all the
feedback that he gave to make the text
better the multiplicative decrease cap
was not specified very well so the
intention is to basically ensure that we
never react more than
what Reno would do in if it sees a last
signal so the delay increased signal the
worst-case decrease even with
multiplicative decrease would be half
the condition window removed the
reduction factor just to simplify so if
the reader has read that bad we just use
the gain parameter now one of the
requests has been to make the document
stand alone currently it's a addendum on
top of the original RFC so the goal is
to make the document stand alone so that
any implementer could just read this RFC
and be able to implement the algorithm
we also want to add pseudocode so that
it makes it easy for implementers so I
request to folks in the room would be
please review this draft I think like
less than best-effort congestion control
is extremely important so please review
this we provide feedback if you could
implement this and do some experiments
on your own that would be great any
questions
Jake on I was curious whether you had a
chance to examine the impact of a
queuing of FQ systems on on this
strategy we have not so I call that out
in one of the prior presentations it's
also an active area of research I think
like both testing with a QM as well as
newer congestion controls like VB are
they currently are testing is limited to
cubic and you know so yeah testing with
other delay ways congestion control
algorithms which are aggressive would
also be I think part of that future work
thank you
[Music]
other questions we have a couple of
minutes all right all right thank you
thank you a presentation Marcelo morning
hey I'm Marcelo Angelo going to talk
about the receiver driven led but so I
represented this in the last IDF so
basically this is an update of the
changes that I'd done in the draft so if
you remember LED body is a set of
mekinese that allow to run a less than
best-effort congestion control algorithm
at the receiver in order to throttle the
control centers rate right so in the
original document I mean the in the
version zero document that I represented
last time the document contained both
the mechanism to implement this in the
receiver and the congestion and
congestion control algorithm controller
is now move to to the level plus plus a
document that Praveen just presented so
in this document we only kept the set of
mechanics that allow the receiver to
exert control over the sender's rate
right so in particular in this document
we kept how to use the receive window
how to manage it safely in order to
avoid window shrinking handling the
window scaled option and this type of
things in order to control the sender's
rate right in addition we work out the
different dock mechanics in order to
feed the information that the congestion
control economy needs including the
Artic measurements in order to estimate
queuing
lay and the detection of retransmissions
at the receiver so basically the the
input that that the congestion control
algorithm form of RTD measurements delay
measurement and some form of loss
transmission detection so the changes
since the zero zero ssin is we remove
all the kind of the part of the
congestion control algorithm we defined
so that elaborate is compatible with any
less than best F for congestion control
as long as it uses some form of delay
estimation and all packet losses in
order to work and we currently are
referring to labelled plus plus or any
other a congestion control that uses
this type of signaling we could point to
LED but if we consider that using LED
but with RTT instead of one-way delay
make sense assume I mean consuming that
leopard plus plus is essentially an
upgrade on on lead but we believe that
this may not make a lot of sense but we
could do it if people feel strongly
about LED but and regarding our LED what
implementation we're currently working I
mean we haven't an implementation we
presented some results in the in the
last IDF we're now working in order to
make it perfectly aligned with the level
plus plus latest version that Praveen
just presented this is this is ongoing
work we hope to be able to present a
results in the next meeting and we also
became aware that a apple have a
receiver based less than best effort
implementation that is available in this
in the it's open source and available
here it seems somehow aligned in the
sense that the use RTT use timestamps
and receive window basically the tools
that we are that we are describing the
draft but it would be interesting to
actually have some input from from from
apple to see if they actually are
aligned to to what we present here and
if not to be able to align properly the
less than best effort control congestion
control agon that they use clearly it
seems different
then LED but misplaced but as as I said
are LED but is compatible with different
congestion control I'll go and examine
xed steps will be will be very useful to
have reviews comments from from the from
the research group and feel free to
contact me if you have further questions
or comments and with that I available
for questions or I can leave questions
folks come on it's Monday morning do
that the mic is all I'm saying some
engagement people well I actually do
have one question for you myself
have you considered expanding this to
the mechanisms would just be slightly
different but I think the concepts still
hold for quick yes do you plan to write
that in the draft or do you think in
this particular draft yeah yeah I'm
asking ah I was thinking to I mean once
I'm done with this do it in a different
document but if you love define do I
mean I mean if you want me to do this
talk mean I'm happy to it it seems
reasonable to do it if you're gonna
cover both TCP and quick in the same if
it's possible to write I don't think the
differences should be that much okay but
yeah if it becomes big enough it might
be worth separating it out okay yeah
sure thank you gory Fair has just asking
about what you actually said at the mic
were you asking about strange Eckles
were you asking about whether this
document could describe a method that
could be applied to quake or were you
saying the document would include a
mechanism described how it applied to
quick I see the two is quite different
that's fair I was asking how you would
apply it so the mechanism itself is not
an underwire change it's entirely a
receiver side
it's its management of the receiving
door in the world of quick it would be
how you advertise flow control credit
and so it would be slightly different in
the sense that you're not just talking
about modulating the window but you're
talking about modulating the size of the
credit that even advertised and there is
no equivalent I mean you can actually
shrink effectively so that gives you a
degree of freedom that is available in
quit because what I mean by shrinking is
you advertise lesser credit in the
future right because you can actually
shrink the window so if that I don't
need that's that's what I was asking me
this right the way it applies to quick
would be slightly different so if I
understand that that means this is a
mechanism and you're not going to
describe the protocol but you're going
to describe the mechanism we saw what
you were talking about yeah so so maybe
maybe then what I'm asking for thank you
for for for teasing this out Cory what
I'm asking for is how would this apply
to like a credit-based flow controller
as against there in the window waste one
okay that's the difference I'm looking
at clear thank you Robi Praveen from
Microsoft I do think that both of these
RFC's are kind sort of transport
agnostic there are certain like
transport mechanisms were using to
communicate information as you point out
but yeah I think they could be written
aware that they could be applied to both
TCP so that's true but does the avoiding
of the risk of the window shrinking
right which is very tcp specific it's
it's very ecosystem specific to now
that's not applicable to quick possibly
not but III don't think it's illegal to
shrink it's what's not illegal it's it's
not illegal to avoid it certainly but
I'm saying it you have the degree of
freedom if you want it okay Nokia versa
I'm wondering about the windows
shrinking thing is that like what I mean
I understand what it is but I don't know
what what would current TCP sender
applications to if you if you put you
know if you would submit
the window that is too small and you
would actually shrink it they might just
ignore it right because they have to
have a way of handling it on the sender
side anyway if that happens what did
send a reset or sorry buddy no so so if
you so as far as I can tell there are
some situations where the window
shrinking is general when you're using
very large window scale for instance
that the granularity of the window that
you are able to announce will will
result in window shrinking so I
understand that implementations usually
can handle window shrinking without
losing packets but that's that's what I
think Praveen Tony so gory Fairhurst not
answering the question directly but
saying that will because I'm going to
talk in a side meeting on quick for
satellite later in the week and one of
the things I'm going to talk about is
the way tcp windows are managed in bsd
using receiver window advertisements and
how you grow and shrink the receiver
versions and how that relates to what
quick does so this is an area where yes
you can't change the receiver window and
it doesn't will impact maybe that causes
you to send more than you're expecting
it ends that we ditched or whatever but
this is a mechanism that does work in
real implementations and and talk more
to me if you wanted to find out what I
was saying thanks Maya
okay thank you so these are the two
drafts that we are planning to adopt if
you have any thoughts please send them
to me or send them on the list like I
said I will send out an email I enter
the list after this meeting and I see
news already there and are there miles
on you guys can you guys hear me yes we
can hear you
okay and your slides are up gonio all
right great
hi my name is Neel Cardwell and I'm
gonna talk today but with a brief update
VBR version to work at google we think
of EVR to as a model based congestion
control and today I'm going to focus on
some recent performance optimization
work that we've done this is joint work
with my colleagues at Google you Chong
and Sohail Puri Ranjan you suck in Kevin
the quick folks in Victor and bin a
summer intern I had this year Luke and
Matt Mathis and magic I'm hearing
substantial echo in my hand are you guys
okay yeah we're fine go but that says
the function of the room okay great
all right next slide please yeah so just
a quick outline I'm gonna talk for a
while about the performance
optimizations I mentioned and then I'll
give a quick rundown of the status of
the VBR version to code and the
deployment at Google and then wrap up
next slide please
so yeah performance optimizations next
slide so what are we doing here what's
the goal here well we basically want to
ensure that bbr version 2 gets to a
point where it's doing a good job as a
general-purpose congestion control for
both TCP and quick for the environments
where those transport protocols are used
today
so that means LAN and when networks data
center networks VM guests and we want to
get to a point where it's a good drop-in
replacement for the predominant
algorithms used today so reno Kubik DC
TCP and we want to make sure that it's
providing in performance improvements
across all of those environments and has
acceptable coexistence properties when
it shares with common congestion control
algorithms like renown cubic and of
course as a stepping stone to number one
we are deploying bbr version 2 for all
the TCP and quick traffic at Google and
we are working on that as as we speak
and as part of that of course that
involves a fair amount of testing and
that so we basically want to ensure that
PBR is doing a good job on both the
production where
clothes we see at Google and a wide
range of test matrices in synthetic or
lab tests and we want to make sure it's
doing at least as well as we know and
cubic and DC TCP next slide please so I
mentioned some tests of production
workloads a cool so so what's that so at
at Google we do a fair amount of testing
on our production kernel changes this
includes TCP loss recovery and
congestion control including VBR changes
and there's a fairly rigorous suite of
application benchmarks that we apply
obviously web search is included but
also databases and storage on and we
look at a fair number of scenarios and
not just sort of simple bulk transfer
dumbell tests and not just looking at
only traditional congestion control
metrics like loss rate or throughput
fairness queuing delays and so forth we
also look a fair amount at CPU usage and
median and tail RPC latency and why we
do that well you know it when you
operate these things at scale in
production environments of course the
details matter a lot and in particular
one of the important details that
doesn't always get as much attention as
it should is is CPU usage and the sort
of contributing factors including data
packet send rates acknowledgement rates
offload birth sizes interrupt rates all
the things that feed into CPU usage and
in addition there are a lot of sort of
tricky and stressful scenarios that are
important to test like when you have
thousands of flows coming from a single
sending host or sharing a small BDP in a
data center like environment those are
also important to test and as we've been
running bbr version 2 through these
kinds of tests at Google we've developed
a number of performance improvements to
tackle various issues that we've seen in
these tests and so I'll go through these
in a little bit of detail but just to
give a quick summary I could say that
basically the the first two improvements
are in order to match the CPU usage for
Reno or a cubic
DC TCP and number one we developed a
fast path for PBR on number two we did
some improvements in the TSO auto sizing
calculation and then the third
improvement was to fix in a sort of
interesting issue we uncovered with the
Linux TCP receive code path and for that
we've developed a mechanism that
generates faster acts and then finally
the fourth one is to enhance PBR version
to you so that it gets better
performance than the widely deployed
algorithms like Reno and cubic and DC
TCP and the sort of interesting case
where there are more flows sharing a
bottleneck than the bdp of the path
expressed in packets
all right next slide so the first
improvement that we worked on was a fast
path for bbr so why did we do this well
much of the traffic in the real world is
application limited so web transfers RPC
traffic adaptive bitrate video and if
you think about it cubic and Reno and DC
TCP when they're not receiving ecn or
lost signals they take a essentially a
fast path when they have application
limited traffic the the first couple
lines of most of them basically say if
this if we're if the flow is not
currently see when limited and then
let's return and not do any of the other
processing that we might normally do for
the congestion control the problem here
is that bbr when run on these very
simple application limited workloads I
ran into CPU usage issues and even
through progressions and some of these
simple application limited workloads and
why is this well thus far the BB our
code base has tried to prioritize
simplicity and basically ran the entire
algorithm on every act so that means
updating the entire model of the path
updating the probing state machine and
then adjusting all of the control
parameters the pasting rate congestion
window offload chunk size and this was
causing up to sort of 2 to 5% CPU and
throughput regressions on some of these
synthetic tests in these workloads and
to tackle this we basically constructed
a fast path for bbr where the idea is is
that we only run the portions of the
algorithm that are strictly needed based
on the properties of the information
being conveyed by a given acknowledgment
and this resolved those cpu and through
progressions without sacrificing
throughput or latency an excellent
please
so we also worked on some improvements
in TSO auto sizing so what is TSO auto
sizing so in high-performance transport
stacks often they achieve a very big
performance improvement by bundling
together consecutive segments into a
single unit when passing them down to
lower layers like the IP layer and the
the NIC driver and in particular the the
core Linux TCP stack has for about seven
years or so used a TSO auto sizing
algorithm that adapts the offload chunk
size largely based on the pacing rate
and it goes something like this so the
the core TCP stack computes a pacing
rate and whether that's used for pacing
or not it still uses that pacing rate
for the offload sizing decision so it
computes the pacing rate as some
constant scale factor times the
congestion window divided by the smooth
round-trip time and then it takes that
pacing rate and it calculates how much
data it thinks would be paste out in one
millisecond and then it applies a floor
of two segments and a ceiling of 64
kilobytes that's determined by the the
offload mechanism itself and an
interesting thing happens if you have a
workload where the sender host is the
bottleneck for a large number of flows
and in that kind of scenario because the
sender host itself is the bottleneck
there tends to not be any easy on or
lost signals that the sender's get and
so with an algorithm like DC TCP or a
cube occur we
the Seawind can be surprisingly high in
these cases which then generates a large
pacing rate and then a large offload
chunk size and that large offload chunk
size allows very low a very efficient
CPU usage and then the problem is if we
if we take a b b our scenario where we
have a large number of BB r senders and
they try to use reuse this auto sizing
algorithm now BB r is computing its
pacing rate based on its estimate of the
flows fair share of the bandwidth coming
out of that sender host so if you've got
thousands of flows the fair share for a
given flow is quite small so PBR was
choosing small offload chunks and using
a lot of CPU and so to solve this issue
we developed a mechanism that adds a
term into the auto sizing calculation
that is a function of the minimum
round-trip time so that as the minimum
round-trip time goes the saw the size of
the offload budget that is added for the
min ITT falls off rapidly but for very
small men are TT's there is a
considerable budget that's allocated for
the the TSO offload size and you can see
the exact formula there and you can read
the the code for the the details on the
constant next slide please
so the the third issue that we tackled
was and it's sort of an interesting
issue involving the specifics of the
Linux TCP receive code path and the
delay dock logic and DC TCP and BP are
v2 both have a nice property where they
emit an immediate act when the incoming
stream of congestion experience gets
change but that mechanism doesn't always
save you because if you're under heavy
enough congestion then there's
continuous C II marking and that
mechanism doesn't kick in so it can
happen is that you can actually get into
trouble as a Linux TCP receiver because
the the details of the code for the
traditional TCP every other
Paquette mechanism are actually a little
surprising and they're actually two
conditions the first one is what you
might expect which is to say if more
than one MSS has been received since the
last time we sent an AK then that
condition needs to be met but it also
has to be the case that the next
received window that we're about to
offer is at least as big as the previous
one and the problem you get into is if
the receive window stops growing
this causes check number two to fail
which causes the receiver to wait until
the application actually reads some data
out of the receive buffer to allow the
receive window to advance and then
trigger and acknowledgment and this was
actually this sort of surprising detail
was actually causing 2x higher p99 RPC
latency x' was sustained congestion and
some of the tests we were running and as
as a solution what we've done at least
thus far is to just remove truck number
two and this is taking care of those RPC
latency issues and we should say that if
this works well in practice as we deploy
I think will propose this as a general
fix for the Linux TCP receive code path
next slide please
so this is just a quick picture to give
a better sense of what's going on there
because I know the the text doesn't make
it entirely clear so here we have a
picture that's a time sequence diagram
of one of these scenarios and you can
see at the beginning of the connection
the receive window is is opening up you
can see that as the received window the
the yellow line is growing further away
from the act line the green line and
during that phase the receiver is
allowing itself to acknowledge
immediately just giving a high
throughput which is reflected in the lot
and the high slope of that line but then
as soon as the receive window stops
growing the yellow line sort of plateaus
you can see that the acts are all of a
sudden very delayed because it the stack
has suddenly waiting for the application
to read some data before it sends an
acknowledgement so that's just an
illustration of an example of this next
slide please so finally the final
mechanism I'm going to talk about is is
some work
to some work in progress that we have to
reduce the queuing that we see when we
have lots of flows so next slide so
what's the scenario we're talking about
here so this is a scenario that's been
documented and and talked about for a
quite a long time and I think it goes at
least as far back as Robert Morris's
paper on TCP behavior with many flows in
1997 and maybe there are earlier papers
as well but the basic issue is that when
you've got mini flows and al-obeidi P
then most existing widely deployed
congestion control algorithms like DC
TCP Kubik you know and BB are thus far
tend to run window limited and they're
gonna have a standing queue when the
number of flows times the minimum
congestion window of those flows is
bigger than the PDP and the problem that
you then get is that there's a standing
queue that's basically that budget of
the aggregate in flight the number of
flows times minimum Sealand minus the
bandwidth delay product and that can be
fairly substantial and just as an aside
here the to give some sense of scale the
the B be our minimum C wins
aside from RTO recovery is for segments
and that's to avoid stop-and-wait
behavior with TCP s every other packet
policy so the diagram here sort of gives
you an intuition about what's going on
you can sort of see that the Q of excess
packets here is building up at the
bottleneck due to the aggregate
in-flight being larger than the BGP of
the path and all of these flows running
when they limited next slide please
so the solution that we've been
investigating is to improve PBRs use of
ecn and loss signals to make sure that
we do a better job of adapting the
pacing rate to match the available
bandwidth and so there's sort of two
core pieces of this the first is a
multiplicative decrease in the pacing
rate and in-flight data when we see ecn
marks as well as loss and that allows us
to sort of quickly match the available
bandwidth and then drain the queue and
also helps
in converting converging toward a fair
allocation bandwidth and then when the
cue seems to be low enough based on the
EC on signals we're getting we then do a
small additive increase and then
continue in the BB our bandwidth Pro
beam growth curve and this is a paper
this is a sort of approach that's been
discussed before you know there's the
the google timely paper from 2015
discusses this kind of approach and I
also believe Bob Brisco has done some
work in this area for TCP Prague if I'm
not mistaken and the picture here just
sort of gives you an intuition about the
the dynamics that we'd like to see where
all of the flows are matching their
pacing rate to the available bandwidth
of the ebon link so you can try to
reduce the queuing there at the
bottleneck next slide please
so this slide has some details about the
the mechanisms that we are experimenting
with in the PBR version two code base
and the at the top there's a sort of
summary of the core mechanism as ecn
marks are arriving once per round trip
time bbr v2 has thus far been reducing
it's in fly cap or in-flight low
multiplicatively based on an
exponentially weighted moving average of
the ECM mark rate and then for this
experimental variation we are also
capping the the pacing rate or bandwidth
low as as we call it in the code base
and decreasing that likewise and the
other sort of pieces of the puzzle here
as mentioned before we're cutting the
the bandwidth low multiplicatively and
we're as as another piece of this we're
increasing the the ecn factor which is
the sort of magnitude or scaling factor
for scaling the ecn response into the
pacing and in flight response and then
we're also decoupling the bandwidth high
parameter which was already
in the in the BB rv2 model from the
maximum bandwidth sample that we've seen
so that we're sort of refining the
notion of this bandwidth high parameter
whereas before it was just the maximum
bandwidth that we'd seen recently and
now we're turning it into a more refined
notion that says it's tracking the
maximum bandwidth that seems consistent
with the tolerable level of EC on and
loss marks and if we're not seeing a
tolerable level of those signals then we
do a multiplicative cut in the parameter
and then finally when it seems like the
level of queuing is low enough based on
the EC on mark rate then we go ahead and
do a very small additive increase and
then continue on in the bandwidth
probing state machine so those are just
to give you a sense of the details and
next slide please so I'll present some
synthetic lab test results to give a
sense of the properties of the
experimental algorithm here here we have
two Center machines and one receiver all
on the same switch all with a 50 gigabit
Nick and the switch here is configured
to use DC TCP style ecn marking where
the congestion experienced bit is that
if and only if the instantaneous Q is
greater than 80 kilobytes in this
particular case and we've got 60 second
bulk knepper transfers here and we've
collected a number of typical metrics
which I'll go through as they talk about
the results and then when we're
comparing three different congestion
control variants here one is the Linux
DC TCP code the very latest and then one
is the VBR version 2 baseline which is
the algorithm without the changes I just
described and then BB are two new is the
algorithm with the changes I just
described next slide please
all right so here the results next slide
so the most interesting metric here in
these experiments
is that if we look at the queueing
pressure as reflected in the
retransmission rate as we scale up the
number of flows with notices we're sort
of Inc doubling the number of flows in
each experiment you can see with a small
number of flows all of the algorithms
are doing quite good at keeping
retransmission reloj and as more flows
are added there's sort of varying
degrees of retransmission rates with the
largest number of flows you can see d
c-- tcp because it's necessarily running
window limited tends to have a fairly
high retransmission rate around sixteen
percent in this experiment experiment
and the newer version of EVR is able to
keep the queuing pressure lower and has
a lower retransmission rate of around
1.6 percent and a next slide please
similarly if we look at other metrics
that reflect the queueing pressure we
can see that on the newer version of
BiBi ours is doing a slightly better job
at keeping the queues low this is the
average RT t next slide and here's the
95th percentile RT t it's sort of a
similar pattern next slide please
and then the throughputs are relatively
similar for the for the variance the
older version of e b r2 is not quite as
high as the others but otherwise they're
fairly similar next slide please
and then you can look at sort of the C e
mark rate is sort of an interesting way
to look at how good the algorithms are
doing at avoiding saturating the signal
they're using and you can see the PVR
the newer version of PBR is doing
reasonably well here next slide please
and then finally we also look at the
fairness the jain fairness index for
lips small number of flows that are all
doing quite well with larger number of
flows they're all not quite ideal and
there's definitely some room for
improvement and we'll be looking at
proving that but it looks to me like
their use ibly fair and all you know in
the same ballpark but there's some work
that we'll be doing in that area next
slide please
so wrapping up next slide so where are
we in terms of the status of the code so
the performance improvements that I was
just discussing we pushed those to the
Google will be our github repo you can
follow the link there for instructions
on how to check out and play with the
code as we mentioned in July and there's
also a bbr aversion to implementation
for quick and you can follow the URL
there and we again we encourage folks to
take the code for a spin try it out
share any test results they have our
packet traces share any ideas about
issues they run into or ways to improve
the code we're always looking for a
feedback from the community and then we
have links to the slides and video from
a previous IDF's
on next slide please so where are we in
terms of the deployment status
we've got PBR version two running for a
small percentage of users on YouTube
where we see lower queuing delays than
both PBR version one and cubic and
considerably reduced packet loss closer
to cubic than VB R version one and then
we're in the process of a large-scale
test pilot program pushing BB r v2 out
as the default congestion control for
TCP within and between Google Data
Centers and we're seeing some nice
results there and we're continuing to
iterate both in production and lab tests
next slide please so finally in summary
we're actively working on VB our version
2 at Google and doing some tuning of
performance especially in data center
contexts high-speed data center networks
so that we can enable VB our version 2
globally at
Google for internal traffic and we're
working as you saw on improving the
algorithm to scale to larger numbers of
flows and as always we invite the
community to share any test results or
issues or patches or ideas they have we
also wanted to give a shout out to the
freebsd tcp community and the team at
netflix which has been working on bbr
and they actually released a an ability
shinobi be our version one for FreeBSD a
couple of weeks ago and we wanted to
finally leave you with some food for
thought it's sort of an interesting
question of if you have to design a KPI
or key performance indicator for
congestion control what would that look
like
basically the question is how would you
tell if your congestion control is doing
well in a production environment given
that in a production environment the
traffic is dynamic the routing is
dynamic topologies are dynamic and so
it's it's it's non-trivial as far as we
can tell to to develop a good key
performance indicator and we encourage
folks to tackle that as a research
problem if they're interested we think
it's a valuable area for contributions
so thank you very much any questions or
comments I I new mardukas
thanks for giving up your Sunday night I
have two questions one is is there a
plan to update the BB r Draft at some
point we're trying to track with an
implementation I know obviously Netflix
as well we really nice them a fixed
target yeah an update of the internet
draft to reflect version two is
absolutely on the to-do list and I
apologize we weren't able to get it done
by this ITF but rest assured it's
definitely on the to-do list
yeah okay thanks the second can you
return to the sequence number graph you
had yeah so um maybe I'm missing
something here so this strikes me is a
for certainly for legacy t speak gesture
controls this is a feature not a bug
like you're not getting pulling more
data out of the system when the app is
not able to consume it is this a problem
in bbr just because the act pacing
messes up your bbr or your bandwidth
estimation no I don't think so the it
it's it turned out to be a problem in
practice in these RPC workloads and it's
you know it showed up in the detail
Layton sees for one of their storage
applications that we're benching
benchmarking so we could definitely go
into detail offline if would be helpful
but yeah not sure what else to add it at
this point okay well I mean I guess III
think you were proposing that maybe this
should just be a blanket changed TCP to
remove that second condition about the
window increase and I I don't have a lot
of experiment remember why exactly that
was put in but it strikes me as it as a
fairly obvious thing for for the reason
I just said which is to not just pile
more stuff on
on a backlog client on a backlog
receiver right I mean I think there are
probably a number of trade offs here and
I guess it you know at the end of the
day maybe it's something that is going
to be context dependent whether it's a
an improvement or not and so that's you
know why we haven't offered it
immediately as a fix for upstream we
want to get some experience with it in
production workloads and see if it is
you know see if it is a net win we think
that you have good reason to believe
that it will be an at least acceptable
if not an improvement in every case
because we the the previous congestion
control that was deployed in Google
actually had a de facto behavior that in
congested cases actually did essentially
bypass check number two so we do have a
fair amount of experience at least in
the congested case with it helping but
you know well reserve final judgment
until we've pushed this for all of our
workloads and and we don't see any
regressions thanks Neal right there just
to ask a follow-up question do you know
why that second condition was was
instead in the kernel right now we don't
know for sure I mean as Martin said
there there is an argument that you can
make about trying not to overload the
receiver another argument that Eric
dooms a pointed out was that this check
works nicely with the underside fast
path which has only taken if the receive
window is is constant and so this can
save some CPU on the sender side if they
received window stays constant yeah
but where this this check predates they
get history in Linux so it's a little a
little tough to talk Wow
all right well thank you so I'm I'm very
amused of course because my question was
what was condition to expected to help
solve Roberto who are you hi
I'm Roberto and I'm with Facebook right
now and III you know one comment is say
hi to everybody
the other comment I love the data-driven
approach and in cases where there is no
clear answer why I'm really hoping that
you will be able to drive changes in
behavior this particular one with number
two here seems exceptionally odd to me
because it it it provides a cliff of
behavior and we know cliffs and in
control theory tends to be bad for being
able to understand the systemic
properties so I think it's super awesome
to try and either eliminate to or prove
that there's a good reason for it to
exist given that nobody seems to know
why so anyway thank you thank you a
couple of questions
so the minimum congestion window for so
TCP traditionally had that value one
matter standing is quick is using two
because of the problem that you
mentioned in the slide I'm just curious
why you would pick four instead of two
so the details have to do with the
dynamics that you get into given the
delayed act behavior so the basic idea
is that you want to have four packets in
flight so that two of those packets well
the simplest scenario to imagine is
basically that two of those packets are
in flight in the data transmission
direction and because you have two of
them that's going to force out quickly
quickly force out a delayed ACK or
quickly force out in a community rather
than delaying the ACK rather so then
you've got also two a two packets worth
of budget coming back in the reverse
direction in the form of acknowledgments
so that those packets when the windows
acts when they arrive at the sender they
can immediately release the next two
data packets and you basically want to
have all all four packets worth of
budget in flight so that there's always
data going
in the transmission direction and always
acts flowing in the reverse direction
and the only way you can sort of ensure
that that happens is if if the receiver
is acknowledging every other packet is
to have 4x or sorry 4 packets worth of
budget in-flight on and yeah so
obviously there's that does increase the
aggregate in-flight in these sorts of
scenarios but the I think architectural
II my sense would be that a better
solution is ensuring that the flows
tends to run pacing limited because
that's a more complete solution and
you're always going to have there's no
matter what your minimum sea wind is
there's always going to be if you're
running window there's always going to
be some number of flows and some B DPS
at which you get into trouble so it
seems like a more general fix is to to
run pacing limited with a C a minimum C
wind that's robust ok I'm gonna ask
folks to be super quick because we are
well over time at this point and I'm
closing the lines one more question was
the target loss rate so currently how do
you determine that for various workloads
to do pickup constant value or do you
tune it based on some parameters right
so far we would like well so far we are
using a constant value in our deployment
but we are leaving the door open to
making that something that could be
conceivably tuned by deployments for
example if you have a background file
transfer like a less than best-effort
transfer you could that is isolated to
its own cue in your quality of service
implementation in your switches you
might want to tolerate a higher loss
rate for example but yeah the we the
final loss threshold that we'd like to
target for the public Internet sort of
yet to be determined and we're open to
ideas from the community about that yeah
thank you
I came up it when you put up the thing
about key performance indicators which
was quite a time ago now just that just
to say to people go and have a look at
there's a hot Nets paper in on its this
year yeah called beyond Jane's fairness
index which is quite interesting sort of
thoughts on how to do that being hot
Nets obviously it's not completed work
but it's more about measuring the harm
one flow causes others rather than
equality and they'll be on that
conversation about packet windows and
things like that I'm gonna just forward
reference to the slot about TCP Prague
Assad's finished his and defended his
thesis in September on that work and the
code will be available hopefully before
Thursday and well it I mean it's it's
completed but just chickened out on
everything and it I'll give a link to
his thesis and things that we we did
manage to get it working with a window
based algorithm inside the base TCP
stack in Linux quite quite nicely but
there are other ways you can think about
it so I'd like to hear when we talk
about it on Thursday more about it okay
tests on that particular paper but
you're gonna have that presentation in
Vancouver I think the Hartman speaker
initiative I have very simple question
so you mentioned about the documenting
baby I'll be too but I might be wrong
but my impression is birria bytes
consists of lots of small hello
complicated Rosic and then some
sounds like our implementation tricks
and then so I'm wondering how do you are
you going to document spec over the
b-b-b our beta I yes we as we mentioned
with when Martin Duke
came to the mic we definitely intend to
document the algorithm in an internet
draft yeah how you know strike a hospice
think something like Fast Pass seems to
be an implementation trick from my sure
right so that is not something that
would necessarily need to be in the
draft because as you say that's an
implementation detail
I think the much as the you know the
traditional TCP fast path is also not in
the the RFC 568 Lauren's back I don't
think that the VR fast path would be in
the internet draft but I do think it's
you know we definitely intend to to
document the the high level algorithm in
the internet draft yeah if the
implementation Yoshi we we have to move
on I'm sorry Jake we've closed I close
the lines earlier okay last question if
you have you are still in the line
before it closed it if you have you have
ten seconds okay yeah John's Norton I'm
just wanting to ask whether you cope
well with our cc-16 eight style ecn for
example if a TC and is not negotiated uh
that's far we're not planning on
integrating bbr with RFC three 168 style
ecn we expect that thus far people using
VBR would not negotiate three 168 ecn
that's that's the current plan thank you
so much I am going to thank mean for
staying up late and doing this and I am
hoping that we'll see the draft sooner
than later
but we should talk offline about that
especially now that we're talking about
adoption of documents in this in his
research group and yeah thank you knew
thank you
I'm going to now handoff to Nathan Gert
from
Facebook who's going to talk about their
experiences with Coppa hello everyone
can you guys hear me should I move
closer or further away close is better
okay so yeah little bit about myself
my name is Nathan GUG as you can see
it's my first ITF here and I'm super
excited to present some of the work we
did at Facebook comparing Coppa with
cubic and VBR for live video upload
use-case I work in the videos
infrastructure team at Facebook this is
the rough outline of my presentation
I'll start with the motivation for our
work then I'll go over the experiment
setup we used and the results we saw on
the application side then I'll do a
brief overview of Coppa how that works
although that is not the focus of this
presentation but I think it's important
to go over our understanding of Coppa
and how we applied it and then Indian
I'll go over the conclusion and the
future work that we apply so motivation
in videos infrastructure team we work
with a lot of product teams who work on
videos and give realized the different
type of video experiences require
different quality and latency trade-off
so on one end of the spectrum you have
applications such as video calling where
the end-to-end glass to glass latency is
super important and these applications
are usually willing to tolerate some
quality loss in order to get that
desired latency on the other end of the
spectrum you have applications which
don't care as much about latency but
they require extremely high quality
playback and then there are applications
which falling between which are kind of
like yeah we need low latency but we
also need high quality playback so
normally you would need different type
of condition control algorithms
compatible with different trade of
scenarios what we wanted to find out was
is it possible for a single congestion
control algorithm to offer a dial to the
application and the application could
use that dial to just make it compatible
with the desired quality versus latency
trade-off this is where we evaluated
Coppa which is a delay based
condition control algorithm it has a
dial which is in the form of parameter
called Delta which you can use to
control the delay sensitivity of the
algorithm so in our experiment setup we
wanted to start with something so we
started with the big one extreme where
we are optimizing for throughput at the
expense of delay so we tune Copa to
optimize for throughput and we did some
comparisons with bbr and cubic which
were which are two popular algorithms
available and a for testing we use the
Facebook live streaming application so
in this application any user with their
mobile phone they can go live they can
broadcast their live feed to their
friends and followers and one thing to
note here is that like this is a very
this is very different scenario as
compared to HTTP style traffic HTTP
traffic would be short and burst years
well could be app limited a lot of times
as well in this case we have
long-running flows over a single quick
connection no multiplexing with the mean
duration of around 3 minutes so you
always have a constant flow of data like
which you are pushing with the wire
other a different thing about this
application is there is an adaptive bit
rate algorithm running in the
application which would change the
encoded bit rate in response to the
network conditions such an example if it
sees that the network queues are
building up and the throughput or the
goodput it's seeing is lower then it
could change the encoder to produce less
bytes and hence that which that will
result in less bytes being written on
the wire and we implemented a coupon in
the Facebook quick library like quick
because the transport is in user space
it allowed us to implement Coppa quickly
and experiment with it quickly and we
use the bbr in cubic implementations
which were already implemented and
deployed for several other use cases
with quick so for conducting the
experiment we used facebook's eb testing
framework so this framework allowed us
to conduct this experiment all over the
world this framework
helped us divide users into three random
groups a one random group got a copa the
other group got a b BR and the third
group got a cubic we conducted this
experiment for
three two weeks and we collected roughly
four million samples in each group so
before diving into the results I want to
spend a little bit of time explaining
the metrics and how how we define them
so we mainly focused on two metrics on
the application side to evaluate the
condition general algorithm the one
metric is average good word so the way
we define it as as you guys might
already know number of application by
its sixth sense successfully over time
so because they do not cast could be
long-running we calculated the total
number of audio and video bytes that
were sent during the entire cast and
then we divided that by the duration of
the broadcast in seconds that gives us
average code word
the second metric we used is average
application observed oddity this is our
proxy for video ingest latency to
explain how this is calculated the
there's a diagram here to calculate this
the live streaming application inserts a
pink frame with basically no payload
just a bunch of headers in between the
audio and video data now a dark pink
frame travels with the rest of the audio
and video data through the transport
send buffer through the kernel through
the same network through the proxies and
it reaches the Facebook live server
which is processing the audio and video
data then when the server receives the
ping frame it immediately responds back
with an acknowledgement frame for that
ping frame which goes all the way back
to the live streaming application now
the application uses a timing of sending
the frame ping frame and getting the ACK
it calculates an RTT which is its
picture of what is the round-trip time
for the application so the application
does this measurement every second and
it gets roughly one sample every second
and to calculate average application
observed RTD we take the average of all
of these samples now let's look at the
results clarification question method so
these are basically measured on the
upload this is site yeah so looking at
the results for goodput we saw that both
coppa and VB are provided better goodput
as compared to cubic however we saw that
coppa provided much better good word as
compared to BB re not
to be specific of the p50 good port was
increased by 5% for bbr and it increased
by 16% for Coppa and similar trend
followed even if you look at the look
the verse connections which have a lower
quality and as you can see like at p90
it maxes out because our encoded bit
rate is capped at 3 Mbps because that's
pretty much like a reasonable max
quality that we want to have from from
our our users and this this improvement
was massive for us and we also saw
positive impact on some of the top line
video metrics that we observe which tell
us how much people are watching those
videos and how much people are engaging
with those videos the second metric we
used is the video ingest latency or
application observe data team in this a
metric what we saw was a bbr was able to
improve it slightly more for the best
connections so as you can see in the
left graph bbr reduced it the bbr a bar
length is smaller for p50 BBI reduced it
by 8% Coppa reduced it by 4% but but
those connections already had like quite
low RTD and the reduction was not as
visible for our users
if you look at the verse connections P
75 P 90 and above are Coppa reductions
were highest
for P 90 Copa reduced the application
ITT by 27 percent whereas BB our
application RTT was same as cubic in our
tests um so this told us so in the
previous slide you saw that Coppa had
better good put so that meant that Coppa
was able to help like it helped
transport to send more bytes
successfully over the wire and it also
impacted the application ABR to produce
more bytes in response to a better
better transport but it was able to do
it at the same time as keeping the
latency slow especially for the users
like that had high latencies and where
it mattered the most
so to be honest like this result was
quite surprising for us we did not
expect both goodput and latency to be
better so we spent some time trying to
under
and more like why that might be
happening so in in the process we found
some interesting observations on the
transport side but before going into
those I want to spend some time
explaining how Cooper works I'm sure a
lot of you are already already now aware
but I want to explain like how we
applied it and how we understood it so
it's a tunable delay based congestion
control algorithm the tunability kappahd
comes from the delta parameter which
varies from 0 to 1 the closer it is to 0
the more the algorithm will optimize for
throughput the closer it is to 1 the
more it will optimize for delay and it's
a delay based algorithm which means it
uses RTT variation and signal of
congestion and not loss or something
else in order to do that it maintains
two key variables one is RT t minimum
which is the minimum RTD the flow has
observed over a period of 10 seconds
it's its estimate of the two-way
propagation delay which is a property of
the network path the second metric the
second variable it maintains is RTD
standing this is a minimum RT t observed
over a much smaller period s RT T by 2
to be precise this is a copepod estimate
of what is the current round-trip time
including any queuing delays in deep
water like links so the reason it does
it chooses RT t by 2 is to make sure
like the measurement is correct if there
are some jitters or there are this
compression on the on the transport
which might mess up which might make the
algorithm think that there is queueing
even when there is not then it uses
these two to calculate a queuing delay
which is RTD standing - Artie T minimum
so on every ACK the algorithm the main
controller calculates the queuing delay
and then it calculates a target rate
using this formula the formula is 1
divided by delta x queuing delay i am
not going to go in details of this there
is a long mathematical justification
given in the paper they show that like
you can critically reach Nash
equilibrium if you have certain modeling
assumptions on the packet arrival
pattern so please do read more about it
if you are interested and then it
compares the target rate with the
current rate and accordingly it adjusts
the condition window to what said by
using an additive increase additive
decrease a variant
so it moves it by a V divided by Delta
times condition window so condition
window factor in the denominator helps
ensure that the change in one RT t is
going to be at max V divided by Delta
packets V here is a velocity parameter
it is 1 by default and this a parameter
comes in handy when Co pi detects that
it has been trying to converge towards a
target rate for far too long and it
needs to do a better job at converging
at it faster in that case it starts
doubling the velocity parameter I think
every RTT the other unique thing or
different thing about this algorithm is
that it has a competitive mode normally
deliveries condition control algorithms
we lose too will lose in the presence of
buffer filling flows in the owner in the
battle in the bottleneck link and
because if the buffers are filling up
for no fault of the deliberate sender
then the deliberate sender will think
that this congestion or it's the delays
are building up and it's going to back
off before the lost beast flows are
going to back off hence it loses some of
the throughput coppa gets around this
problem by using something called a
competitive mode so in competitive mode
it uses a heuristic which I will explain
a little bit more in the next slide to
detect the presence of buffer filling
flows and if it detects a buffer filling
flow then it adjust the Delta to be more
aggressive basically optimize more for
throughput and perform better in the as
compared to fulfilling flows however in
our experimentation we did not implement
competitive mode we wanted our
experiment to be like smaller in scope
so we just tested like what will happen
if you use aggressive value of Delta
without using competitive mode so this
is the steady state dynamics of cope
algorithm this is what the bottleneck
you looks like in steady state so the
bottleneck you goes oscillates between
having zero packets up to 2.5 times
Delta inverts packets and this the
entire pattern repeats itself every 5 RT
so what I was saying before was that the
competitive mode and
computing flow detection so Coppa
actually exploits this property that the
queue is going to empty every five RTD
and if it's not doing that then it it
thinks that there is a buffer filling
flow which is preventing this from
happening so hence it concludes that
there is a buffer filling flowing in
sharing the bottleneck link so here like
if you see let's say at T equal to zero
the queue starts to increase for the
first time so it will take about half
our TT for the RTD standing measurement
to be available and the target rate to
reflect this change and the target rate
will be lower than the current rate at
that time because of the inherent RT t
delay in the network it will take one
oddity for that change to be effective
basically the change of reducing the
target rate and then in another oddity
the queues will start to drain again and
then the entire cycle repeats itself
like half our TT for the architects
timing measurement to reflect the change
and then another oddity for the
congestion window increase or the target
rate increase to result in the queue
length to start increasing in our
experiment V and then the results that
I'm presenting they used a delta value
of point zero four which means roughly
twenty-five packets in the equilibrium
twenty five packets equilibrium queue
length and the maximum queue length is
like two point five times twenty five
now let's look at some of the transport
level stuff we observed so one metric we
looked at is how the how is the
transport Arcadia varying so we saw so
this is measured as just taking the
average of all the quake RTD
measurements over the duration of the
broadcast so the trend we saw was a very
similar kind of similar to application
architecture meant bbr for the best
connections which already had pretty low
RTT bbr was able to reduce it slightly
more as compared to a copan cubic
however if you look at the tale cases 75
1995 Copa reductions were very higher as
compared to VB are so for a p90 for
example Copa reduced the RTD by 38
percent whereas bbr reduced it by eight
point eight percent so this was pretty
good to see and this told us little bit
like where the application IDT
reductions might be coming from
and it also showed us that like it Koopa
flow is not just improving the
application latency but it's also
improving the RTT for the network so if
there are any other flows which are also
sharing the bottleneck length like they
will also start seeing a lower equities
the other metric we looked at is the
retransmission overhead so this we
defined it as the total number of bytes
retransmitted by the transport during
the course of the broadcast divided by
total number of bytes acknowledged
during the course of the broadcast I
think it's a pretty important metric to
look at because it tells you how
efficient the transport is if you are
wasting resources and bandwidth
rewriting the same bytes over the wire
again and again it's just not good for
anyone so what we found here was that
for 90% of users coppa retransmission
overhead was available as compared to
both be brn cubic it was about half of
what bbr had and around 1/4 of what
sorry cubic hard so this gave us an idea
like why application goodput might have
been better like this might be one of
the reasons why we were able to send
mode by it successfully for the
application however for the last 10% of
users we saw a different trend that
coppa retransmission overhead grew very
rapidly and it became three to four
times as compared to cope and cubic and
VBR which was concerning as well as
surprising because we did not see a
corresponding proportional degradation
in the application metrics for any other
tail users so we spend some time
debugging into it and the first thing we
did was we sample a few cases some some
broadcasts which had a very high loss
rate for coppa so we notice two things
one thing was that these flows had very
constant or throughput as you can see by
the red line here the number of bytes
act over time it's it's a it's a
straight line and the second thing you
observe is that these flows actually
have very low arteries so in this sample
except the one spike the RTD stays
constant around 75 milliseconds so this
did not look like congestion or loss is
happening because of buffers filling up
this look more like network policing to
us because if there's a token bucket a
police are in effect which is
identifying your traffic and and
limiting it as a bit at a bit rate it's
not going to result in any increase in
queuing delays or equities but it will
look more like this
we also grouped our retransmission
overhead numbers by ESN and we found
that they do vary greatly depending on
which s and you're looking at some
essence which are known to police
Facebook traffic they had very higher
retransmission overhead for tail cases
for Koopa and there was some other a
essence where the retransmission
overheads look very similar so to
generalize our finding we did some more
aggregated analysis we looked at the
relationship between artery transmission
overhead and our TT queuing delays and
we found that for cubic they are highly
correlated as the retransmission
overhead increases our TT and queuing
delays also increase for cubic which
indicates that all the losses are
happening because of congestion instead
for but for Coppa we saw similar trend
for the first part of the graph but
later on we see that the retransmission
as the retransmission overhead increases
the arc titties and queuing delays
actually start to come down so this kind
of solidified our hypothesis that this
net the network policing is a big factor
being playing a role here in the high
retransmissions although it's also
possible that there are some other
reasons at play here and network
policing is not the only one for example
short buffers if there's a short buffer
and Coppa sender is trying to maintain
an equilibrium queue length of 25
packets then the buffer is smaller than
that then like definitely going to run
into losses so definitely there are
improvements are possible in Coppa to
handle this case better competitive mode
as I described before could help because
it could adjust the target Delta based
on whether it sees loss or success we
could also add a heuristic to change
congestion window based on something
simple like multiplicative decrease
based on target loss just like cubic or
Renault or even BB are now is doing
other option is to have an explicit
network policy detection similar to how
BB R by V one had it so in conclusion
the aggregated results showed us that
Coppa provided better
and lower latencies in artists these
tests were for mobile broadcasts for
uploads and we compared with cubic and
VBR
with quake but one thing to note is VB
are like via tuning VB are in our
internal implementation and also like
Beiber veto is happening so the results
may differ in future one of the big
future work items is a better
understanding of the reasons behind
these improvements could are these
improvements because of lower
retransmission overhead or is it because
Kupa is just doing better target rate
estimation by sending fewer packets and
it's converging to that faster or it
could be something else in the beginning
of presentation I spoke about our goal
of having a tunable delay based
condition enroll algorithm which could
be compatible with all the video
experiences and so far we only ran
experiments on one extreme where we are
optimizing the throughput we would also
like to run some experiments with other
with goobie condition control as a
comparison where the end-to-end ultra
low latency super important and we would
also like to test for more use cases
like playback and all the traffic this
is these are a few links where you can
read and learn more my email is here and
I'm happy to answer any questions now or
offline thank you so much nothing
I'll intake myself in the front of the
queue
so I'm asking this question from the
floor basically the scenario that using
this under right now is when the client
is brought is uploading video up to the
server and this is almost a textbook
example of a situation where there is no
cross traffic or there's no other
traffic that is going to be competing
with Copa at a bottleneck because I
imagine that when people are uploading
video they're not doing anything else on
the phone so it seems to make sense that
the that even without the competitive
mode which I like to think of as TCP
friendly mode because that's what it is
no that's what cubicles it but we don't
get there the the point is that that's
that's simply a it makes sense that it
works without that so I'd be interested
in
seeing more evaluation on on what
happens when you when you have
competition with cubic with PBR with
other things in the network because
that's going to be useful for
downloading download streams and in the
common case that's gonna be an important
factor definitely like that's like I
said that's one of the future work items
although then to be honest when we
started working on this like we did not
really know that there is going to be no
competing traffic and like even now like
I'm not totally sure like if there is
any evidence like a real life evidence
of that I would love to read more about
it I know from textbook that it is the
case but like yeah this is one of the
future work items thank you Michael
Mike reverse begin by saying that I
greatly appreciate Facebook coming here
and bringing this here and some some
good results and I guess the mechanism
is not altogether unreasonable I have to
say sorry for that I have to say that
the base idea or that this you know it's
based upon of a delta that that reflects
a trade-off between having high delay
and good throughput or low delay and not
so much support is fundamentally wrong
just because well I mean if you look at
the Intuit the base intuition between
mechanisms like bbr or alpha s or things
like that you know they aim at having
high throughput and having a low q and
having a large q just isn't good for
anybody I think there is such a
trade-off when you're trying to compete
with TCP so there is you know you had
this in your in your competitive mode
you can try to be a bit more or less
aggressive which will produce more or
less queuing so I guess there you have
to trade off but whenever you are able
to detect that there isn't only any
other traffic competing with you I don't
think the idea of have of including such
a trade-off in the design as a base idea
is good at all so my answer to that is
like maybe you're right
like I don't know for sure but the
trade-off does exist on the product side
because on the other hand we have video
calling applications which have not been
able to use cubic or bbr so far as far
as I know
they have to use something like Google
condition control where they have to
really optimize for end to end delays
right on the transport side like we did
run some limited experiments by using
like a very high value of Delta right
and I did see that queuing delays
decreased even more so I mean I don't
know like fundamentally if like it's a
good idea or not but from the
application point of view this
definitely a trade-off and if the
condition control could also kind of
like give you a varying performance
depending on like what like it could
also be expressed in a different way for
example prop 8 exposes a target delay to
the application and it will just try to
optimize and limit the queue the
bottleneck you delay it to that like
that could be an alternative way for
application to benefit from it like I
honestly don't know
I can maybe point out some other work
offline yeah Stuart Cheshire from Apple
you presented some results showing
marginally better application throughput
which is interesting I think it would be
interesting to understand where that's
coming from
because either the other congestion
control algorithms were letting the line
go idle and wasting capacity or they
were retransmitting unnecessary and
wasting capacity with duplicates or
something else and it would be really
interesting to know where that extra is
coming from where these tests done on
Wi-Fi links or LTE good questions so we
ran these tests globally and when I
looked at the data like about 3/4 of the
users were using cellular I did not I
don't know like LTE versus 3G or
something else and about 1/4 were using
Wi-Fi but in the Wi-Fi case there would
be competing traffic at the bottleneck
because it would be probably the first
or probably
and when I looked at the results and
compared them like the trend was similar
for Wi-Fi and cellular although we saw
more wins on cellular as compared to
Wi-Fi and what is the Delta value for
these experiments no 2.04 Thank You
Roberta they own
I just wanted to push back on the labor
sis bandwidth not making sense
I also want to agree with delay versus
bandwidth not making sense I'm holding
both of these opinions simultaneously
because it's hard to define what the
network is does the network diff'ent is
the boundary of the network between the
application and the operating system or
is it between the nic sending packets
and the fabric to another NIC right the
you know depending on where we are in
the stack we tend to think of either of
these as the network and try to exclude
one of the others generally the internal
to the host part so we know from
previous presentation by Neil Cardwell
for instance that there are parts of the
stack that are trying to reduce the
amount of overhead that we are
experiencing within the host and the
effort by which we do this and of course
there's Nagle's etc right the effort by
which we do this is really a trade-off
of how expensive it is in CPU versus how
important it is to get the information
through so there you go sorry thank you
thank you so much folks and I want to
thank mitten for showing up here and
presenting this please make him feel
welcome it's his first IETF /i r TF /
ICC RG meeting and for everybody else
watching I love to see more
presentations like this if you are doing
in experiments in your house or in your
lab or at your company come share them
with us
and we now move on to Marcus and get
this up mc/dc CP
there you go take it away my name is
Marcus Armand from Deutsche Telekom and
today I want to present some joint work
with Karcher at University and City
University London on multipass
multi-party ccp that we intend to to use
for providing multiple capabilities for
UDP and IP traffic why I want to
presented today here at ICC RG is that
we see a challenge there in respect to
congestion control and I think you you
are the right group to become aware of
this and maybe work together with us on
a solution B and we also think that this
is not a limited issue to the multipass
tcp maybe that is also something which
affects in future the community we come
to this during the presentation first of
all I want to give you a short
introduction why are we working on multi
pass DCP what is the reason behind I
want to make you aware about the
development we did so far and then
coming quickly to the point where we see
the issue of congestion control the
multipath TCP as such is usually pushed
at TS vwg where we also have some
updates in the afternoon session okay
starting with them motivation why are we
working on on a solution for providing
multiple capabilities to two UDP or IP
traffic so as you may know there are
specifications ongoing in the 3gpp area
and also in the BBF proppant forum on
multi connectivity architectures to
provide multi-part usage to either
mobile phones though that is on the
upper part that is directly happening at
3gpp
released 16 so within the 5g
standardization and they're discussed in
in the area of 80 s SS XS traffic
steering switching splitting it's an
operator controlled approach so that's
why we are so telecom are very
interested in that
that means multi connectivity is
terminated in the operator network the
same is also happening for the hybrid
access use case where multi connectivity
is applied between a multi path capable
CPE using cellular and fixed access and
again the operator network in future the
IP Texas will most totally also rely on
the 3gpp a TSSs specification and
currently in release sixteen multiple
CCP is a protocol which is defined for
making simultaneous use of multiple X's
if you start now with having a look on
how the traffic mix has changed over the
last years I I think I don't tell tell
you something you we see that the quick
traffic is coming up more and more
though that is some statistic from our
fixed network in 2018 where we already
see more or less 12% of quick traffic
and we think with HTTP 3 deployment this
will become more and more and maybe it
comes to the point where Creek or UDP
traffic in future dominate the TCP so
that is totally different to what we
have seen maybe three four or five years
ago where TCP where the dominating
protocol with almost 100 percent with
all almost 100 percent share but coming
now back to to these multi connectivity
architectures we have seen before
within the a TSSs
we're multipass TCP the protocol for
providing multipath transmission this
means that it cannot cover anymore all
the traffic which is today generated
between customers and and the internet
the Gothic week is coming so our finding
so far as we have a long lasting
experience was not a past TCP it's a
very well working protocol it's
efficient it's a good candidate to use
or to provide yeah multi connectivity
services and there's also finding that
the congestion control should buy TCP
and also used with a multi pass TCP for
scheduling decisions and so on it's very
beneficial another finding is so far if
you look at IKEA for example there is no
multi part of a call for UDP or IP
traffic and an encapsulation into
multiple TCP of such protocols it's not
an option at least that is our opinion
and that was also something discussed
years ago in the multiple TCP mailing
list that this does not make sense
because if you encapsulate UDP or IP
traffic into multiple TCP then you
impose the reliable nature of TCP so a
potential multipath solution for a UDP
or even IP traffic must not impose TCP
like reliability additional high latency
packets cramping or head-of-line
blocking otherwise it Prague the UDP and
IP principles on transportation and
service expectations before I come now
to the solution and talk about the
multipath DCP itself I want to present
what what are the key components for a
multipath transmission sure for sure you
have a generator and a receiver part in
between you have multiple paths or
multiple X
so at least more than one path to
provide multi-multi connectivity and you
you need a you need a scheduling unit to
distribute traffic over a multiple part
and it is very beneficial to have a path
estimation for the scheduling unit which
gives you information about the path
characteristic latency is data rate
available capacities so that the
sketching unit can make proper decisions
efficient decisions and that's not
overload the path may be according to
two policies preferring paths with low
latencies and it needs this information
which which latencies are applied to the
individual path and also in most
scenarios and real scenarios you need
some we or a queue to compensate and the
different paths or icterus takes to
compensate the latency differences and
so on for the three ordering unit or
poor for making this reordering working
for sure you need also some some
sequencing but that is that is very
simple as such so the the the most
critical components I see are the
scheduling the path estimation in the
reordering so all of this has worked
together and to make efficient
multi-party which possible now coming to
the solution multipass DCP so at the ITF
which which types of protocols are
available which can support us in
finding a solution to transport UDP IP
traffic over multiple paths and there we
came up with the DCP protocol which is a
mix between TCP and UDP it's it's of our
unreliable nature but it has a
congestion control
and that we think we can exploit for our
purpose purposes so what we imagine is
we have the multipath DC CP as such
which by itself is only possible to to
distribute a TCP traffic over multiple
paths but if you combine it with a
multipath framework which more or less
means we have virtual network interfaces
which can consume any kind of IP traffic
and the the traffic which is is incoming
into this virtual network interface then
encapsulated into the multi pass TCP
distributed and then on receiver side
again may be reordered and then stripped
all the DCP information and send out of
the outgoing virtual network interface
so that is a rough description of how we
imagining a solution you can you can
find more details in all the draft I
have mentioned here on this slide and
that is our prototype and also our
simulation test that we have available
so we have a Linux kernel implementation
extending the the available DCC keep of
a call by multi part capability and the
same we have available in nf3
for simulation purposes and it's the
descender side you can see on the on the
left side the multiple CCP home gateway
as we have called it and that is very
similar to to multi pass tcp we have a
modular scapula which can load different
kind of scheduling algorithms
round-robin for example a cheapest pipe
first which is a path prioritization
scheduler but also more sophisticated
ODS for example out of order for inorder
arrival schedule
on receiver side and that is something
you compare to to multiple CCP we have
reordering modules so we can apply
different kind of reordering mechanisms
we have a passive one which more or less
does nothing we have a adaptive fixed
algorithm which waits for a fixed time
when when packets are missed and then
skips possible gaps in the reordering
queue we have a depth effective so that
is a dynamic approach using the RTT
informality the latency information from
the congestion control put a ten-time
and last but not least we have delay
equalization which is more or less no
reordering approach it just tries to
delay the packet on the faster path by
the latency difference we have a path
manager we have this virtual network
interfaces from the multi path framework
implemented so it's more or less
complete a set up which we can use for
testing presenting now some results in
short that is really a short sort of
results just to make you aware what is
already working and then coming to the
challenge we seen so that is that is our
na 3 setup where you see that we have
plenty of possibilities we can simulate
different you ease we we can simulate
you know tea or cellular axis we can
simulate Wi-Fi access and also and we
can simulate moving scenarios where we
move you ease from one point to the
other which maybe lead to the effect and
therefore I have results in the next
slide that we lose connectivity or that
we enter
you access nodes and we can get
connectivity so that that our results
from last ITF but again just to remember
you so switching and aggregation is it's
possible with our multi-party ccp setup
so on the top you see when we move and
you e out of a Wi-Fi access so that the
the Wi-Fi access is not available
anymore
then the ue automatically connects to
the LTE and the multi-party Suzuki is
capable of doing this in a in a seamless
way and with the fewest switching
approach you see between switching from
by factory suddenly you have a get with
aggregation mode which was also
supported by multiple CCP you see a more
or less as seamless hand over without
having a gap between switching from
Wi-Fi to LTE we think that is a very
beneficial scenario the same test we
also did and MP think that is very
realistic maybe I have to switch back so
that what was pure UDP traffic it was
some some iperf UDP traffic we generated
but that is not very realistic so we did
the same test with UDP combined with
Nara congestion control most of the UDP
traffic we see in the field is to some
extent congestion controlled and if you
talk about quick then it's it's pretty
clear that this is congestion control
and you see here in the same scenario
you're switching or aggregation it also
works to some extent but you see some
some interact
between the Nara congestion control and
also the D CCP congestion control you
have this black reference line so that
is from the previous slide the results
where you have seen more or less yeah
maybe where you have seen that after
switching from one access to the other a
direct use of the full capacity was
possible whereas whereas now with the
nadir controlled UDP traffic you see it
takes on time to to adapt this one I I
will skip for time reasons and that is
now also exploring a little bit what's
going on in in terms of delay that is
also some result from from last our ITF
where will be proved that reordering
makes sense we need reordering in a in a
multi pass set up supporting UDP traffic
and the cream bar here that is proving
that reordering is beneficial over
scenarios without reordering and you can
find the details in the slides from from
last ITF what is new we have some real
world results with YouTube traffic based
on the call now and you see here the set
up we have the multi Party CCP client
and multi pass TCP server that is a
local set up and but connected to the
internet connected to the multiple TCP
client we have a laptop running the
Chrome browser and between the both
multiple TCP boxes we have two links to
ethernet links going through so-called
TC boxes but which we can shape the
links and where we can change the path
characteristics as I said we use the
Chrome browser with that we are able to
request YouTube videos using the quick
protocol we requested a static video
with a fixed resolution and we skipped
this video at ten thirty fifty 70 90 and
110 seconds and to force a buffering the
total curation of the test were 120
seconds and the network condition
chained at 60 seconds we see on the next
slide again so we had to part both at
one megabit per second and a latency of
10 on the first path and 50 milliseconds
on on the second path of the 60 second
be changed from 10 to 90 milliseconds on
the first path and on the right side
view you can see the playback ratio but
is a data rate where you can see that
the green circles that are the one using
multipath in combination with reordering
promise promises the highest gain
whereas other scenarios like single pass
usage or Multi multi Party CCP without
reordering ya have have some have some
lower playback ratio compared to this
multi-party which with with reordering
however that is not part of this slide
the detailed evaluation revealed and the
imperfect parts use it even in the best
performing use case which means
even if you have reordering and
multi-part usage combined there are
still some room to improve the customer
experience and now coming to an
intermediate conclusion before coming
later to the final conclusion so our
multiple CCCP prototype and also the the
the standards or the the troughs we have
available at TS vwg making very clear
that this is something which can brought
a work scheduling profits from the TCP
congestion control and can therefore
perform similar to multipath TCP the
reordering on receiver side is is proof
mandatory for efficient multipath
transmission of unreliable traffic smart
algorithm to keep a traffic flow
smoothly ongoing are required and can
make use of congestion control
information head-of-line blocking is not
purposeful and should always assess if
it is worth to wait for missing out of
other information which means
encapsulation into multiple TCP doesn't
make sense for for UDP or IP traffic you
have also seen that we have plenty of
scheduling and and reordering algorithms
in our prototype and all of this
together benefits from from the
congestion control the ship with TCP so
from this perspective it was a very
clever decision to use the TCP and also
with the congestion control we can make
sure that we do not overload paths
though that we do not force a packet
loss however the main target protocols
transmitted over the multipath TCP
framework like quick employee and own
congestion control in combination with
multiple TCP this leads to a kind of
congestion control over congestion
control scenario with well known issues
from literature so
now the point where I think it becomes
very interesting for ICC at ICC Archie
so in all of our tests we used so far
the CCI d2 which is a TCP like a contest
in control and we asked ourselves if it
makes sense to use CC ID - what could be
the alternative and how intra neural we
tackle the problem of congestion control
over congestion control and such
scenarios if we assume that combustion
control for multipath purposes with the
right way to go okay so as I said we
have this issue of congestion control
congestion control identified we think
also that affect the the community so
there are troughs regarding quick
tunneling where at the end you you have
the same question depending on which
type of traffic you want to tunnel
through through Creek
my main question today is ICC actually
the right place and dealing with this
question of congestion control over
congestion control and who is interested
in elaborating this topic further not
dedicated to this multi parties yeah I
think it's a general question but for
sure it would help us in pushing the
multi processes EP further thank you
very pleasant Dacian Marcus I think just
very quickly to answer the question
about is this ICC has the right place it
can be is the Shorin said that I have I
think the question I would have is other
other folks who are interested in in
this problem and I'm not just speaking
academically is this a real problem
folks interested in deploying our face
are they facing this problem in
production that sort of question if you
can you know you could you could have
this conversation on the mailing list
and see there are people who are
interested in working with you on on
establishing relevance
any other questions we have - Anita a
quick question
have you ever experiment with that pass
is not disjoint no for example with some
savvy multipass DCC subfloors share the
same bottleneck
have you ever experiment with that kind
of environment the question was will be
experimented with couple congestion
control like multiple TCP uses no that
is on our to do this but I'm not sure at
the end it also ends up in congestion
control over congestion control for sure
we have to do this we should do the such
test what we have done but what was not
able to to show up that we have
implemented PBR 40 CCP and we did some
tests with that that was very promising
but copy congestion control is on our
to-do list we have the issue that we
have to report everything into the DCP
world to make such tests I think that's
important make sure it's on our to-do
list but again the problem stays at the
end then we have inner congestion
control of the piggyback traffic then
over couple congestion control where
also think that this end ends up in some
challenges or conflicts thank you so
much Marcus and with that we end the
session I'm going to quickly note that
in Vancouver I'm trying to get together
there's been a recent spate of academic
work on EPR analysis so I'm gonna try
and get those authors and even need to
show up or BBF folks to show up in
Vancouver so I'm hoping to do two ICC re
sessions in Vancouver four of those
panel this is tentative of course one of
them will be around bbr specifically and
the other one will be more generic but
if you have any work around that if you
have any analysis that you've been doing
with DVR or vrv - please write to me I'd
love to have that be a part of the
program and that we will end thank you
so much
specifically tank Marcus for winding
down his kind of his presentation
quickly and we'll see you in Vancouver
thank you folks