[Music]
we're about to start it's true hello
everybody this is IDR we're getting
started so please find your seats or
find the door or you know stand up and
back at the peanut gallery or whatever
su is going to put a note well on the
screen any moment so that you can have
seen it but
I bet some people in here have seen it
but I think yeah here we go
it is our note well it is the ietf
policy you did agree to this thing when
you registered to come to the IETF if
you don't know what it says you probably
should acquaint yourself with it enough
said we're gonna try to cut the whole
comments from the chairs thing well
short because we would rather spend our
limited time on other stuff especially
because sue has been doing a bang-up job
of sending out periodic status updates
so it would be kind of redundant to
spend our time here and now sending out
status updates but I realized I should
walk around and get these blue sheets
moving please sign into the blue sheet
and whenever they get to the back of the
room please someone bring them forward
and so they don't get lost it's always a
pain to have to find the blue sheets at
the end of the meeting do you want to so
here so this is sort of the last minute
thing that I put together because
essentially I noticed that
you know I guess I didn't just notice
but we have a lot of flowspec related
drafts they continue to come in every
meeting I think we've talked about this
before but as a reminder if you go and
look at flowspec flowspec does its thing
using NLRA the NLRA contains flowspec
components flowspec components are
structured as type value pairs they are
not structured as type length values
just type value what does that mean that
means you can't write a generic flowspec
parser you know unlike unknown path
attributes that we can just skip over
and keep going and everything's good you
get an unknown flow spec component and
game over this isn't really good for
flowspec extensibility there's an
exception which is if you're defining
flowspec over a new a few Safi that's
fine because you've got a demultiplexer
up you know that you do know how to find
that either you know you either you
exchange that fe Safi in your MP bgp
capability in which case you'll will
know how to parse the components or you
don't in which case you won't get the
component so that's fine but you just
get one shot you know once you've
defined your your new a fe Safi with
your new components in it that's it
forget about extending it later some
years ago we had a flow spec v2 proposal
that among other things represented
components as type length values so
obviously they wouldn't have this
problem but instead we have not worked
on that actively because we have taken
you know did the quick thing of doing
the bist document first
with all quick things it wasn't quick so
the thing that I would like to put out
for you know potentially a couple
minutes of discussion right now and I
will also follow this up to the list of
course is just it seems to me as as the
co-chair that it doesn't really make
sense for us to advance documents that
define component types that can be
expected to make
peirong sessions fall over if you
actually transmit them across the
session so that kind of implies that
either we stop extending flowspec or we
get back to work on some kind of follow
on whether it's you know resuscitating
the v2 draft or doing something else is
up for discussion we have a few minutes
for discussion if anyone wants to make a
comment otherwise we can talk on the on
the list later chaired much Akamai makes
sense to me that we should fix the TLV
oversight what which method doesn't
matter to me Jeff has spent a lot of
time in the last year actually working
on flowspec code and some of the reason
why you have the some of this stuff 255
something like this number one piece F
actually picked up our format and was
going to stick it in their protocol they
received this morning they did the same
thing except for their components
actually include link fields so they do
not suffer from this problem so we have
at least one existence proof of change
the format makes it happy thing number
two we should gate these new things I
believe and something that has a TLV I
think that if low spec v2 makes sense
I think the scoping of the faux spec fee
to proposal may need to rediscover feet
in place make it TLV flowspec v2 also
try to advance it in terms of like
firewall rule ordering have to decide if
we still want that
thank you thank you go fishing skiing
Verizon Media Yahoo edge cast absolutely
agree with Mike absolutely agree with
what both Jeff and Jared have said we
the current mechanism of we really
cannot extend folks but because it will
make routers fall over and govt is just
an oversight and let's bite the bullet
and fix it thank you
let seems like consensus in the room so
anyway we'll we'll discuss it further on
the list but I think that will be the
you know even though I'm standing up
here I'm I do have a chairs hat on right
now I I think that's going to be the
position of the chairs going forward is
you know you can you can discuss your
your extension draft but I think that we
are going to want to prioritize the
groups time on getting the the TLV thing
done so that we can actually roll out
those extension drafts so as the author
of the previous one I really don't care
just as long as we fix the TLB problems
so open proposals are are okay on this
we have an a flow spec in working group
last call the chairs wanted to make sure
we knew what we if we had any sense for
the room again we'll send more of this
out to the mail list but seems like it
would be a whole lot better to fix it so
speaking of flow specs are we ready for
Donald yep and he's using a different a
piece a FISA which is why we wanted to I
think I've got it it should be dance mmm
okay hi
so after that oh that's not quite right
so I'm gonna talk about two drafts in
only 10 minutes hopefully with some time
for discussion so I'll be moving along
here pretty quickly layer 2 VPN and the
tunnels so
the l2 VPN flowspec draft has a number
of changes from version 11 particularly
clarifying that it applies to efi 25
Safi 134 included some stuff about
validation so you can tell it if
flowspec is coming from a source
authorized to send that it has a very
minor extension for the drop eligible
indicator bit which is a bit in VLAN
tags as I can be checked and so it
basically defines new component types
for l2 and those now have TBD values
rather than fixed numbers which used to
be in the previous version and there of
course there are various editorial cages
so I'd like to resolve questions at the
end because I want to make sure I get
through the expository text on the
drafts but the question arose on the
mailing list with expert on whether this
can use Saffy 134 so a fee 25 is defined
as the a fee for l2 VPN and Savi 34
currently in the IANA registry says VPN
v4 dissemination of photo spec rules the
ipv6 draft is going to expand that to be
l3 but ie then this staff proposes a
change change it to VPN dissemination
because you can tell from the a fee
whether it's VPN ipv4 or ipv6 or lastly
in this case level layer 2 so why do you
need to use a new different Safi from
134 because the a fee tells you what's
going on and you also might be able want
to apply what's in this draft to non VPN
cases and there's a convenient a fee for
that you can use fe6 and Safie 133 an
ambiguously from the definition of that
affiant a fee would clearly make what
case it was appliable too obvious to
anybody getting that so that's the
question people can think about it while
I go over the other draft is there a
good reason to have another Safi which i
think is a burns one for no particularly
good reason for this ultra VPM so the
other draft the file name is unchanged
and has n vo 3 but
the revision to the draft I've that's
been made from zero version zero six
digital seven makes it really not nvo
three specific the oh six focused there
it didn't really say anything about sad
it wasn't really clear what's a feat was
being used or anything it's a matter too
good a draft in that regard was I had
lots of other good stuff in it it only
supported VX land and envy GRE and it
worked by having a delimiter component
which marked boundary so it sort of was
like adding a component which is we
found least currently doesn't work at
all and may not be the probably the best
way to do it in this case anyway so the
new draft of the sex 7 changes this
quite a bit it's really a general
tunneling or encapsulation kind of flow
spec it proposes to use a new Safi
you've just TPD and it has in it details
about the ex lam not just vehicle and
env GRE but also l2tp v3 IP @ IP jerry
etc and has a new NLRA structure which
can contain one or optionally also a
second flow spec so what applies to the
outer header and that applies to the
nested inner header which you would need
frequently but not always so this is
what things look like this shows the
overall attribute at the higher level is
the multi-protocol BGP attribute where
it is a naffy Safi next hop information
then there's the ml or I and it begins
in this draft with a tunnel type so the
hole type actually acts sort of as an
additional thing if you don't understand
the tunnel type you can skip over the
hole the hole attribute so we you could
add things for specific tunneling
headers later even with the same a few
Safi as long as they had a different
tunnel type okay then there's some flags
regarding discriminator and a second
flow spec flag and some reserved Flags
routing discriminator field and then the
then there's the outer flow spec which
is always there that's the next to the
last box here and that essentially
parsed or whatever based on the a fee
that's at the top of the attribute and
if the second flowspec flag is on then
there is another a fee and the inner
flow spec net inner a fee applies to the
inner
let's back of course so there's also
this Rodney discriminator bit so if this
is the VPN case you need a routing
discriminator to tell what VPN vrf the
stuff is in that you're trying to look
for and right it might not be so that's
an optional thing this way that you only
meet once a fee rather than two
different Saffy's for the VPN an on VPN
case you could do with two Saffy's but
it seems cheaper to use a bit which
determines whether the routing
discriminator is present so this just
blows up the NLRA gives more detail
shows the link fields and so forth
this draft also has more components that
defines because of the other kinds of
tunneling it covers previously only was
fee excellent NB GRE and only had added
the tunneling header components for
those it extends the flow spec ordering
rules so you can tell what precedence is
if you have a tunneling and a non
tunneling flowspec that both match or
something like that includes validations
based on entirely on the outer flow spec
so whether the source of the flow spec
is authoritative so here's two examples
the first one is IP and IP so you could
have in this case you would almost
always have an outer and inner flows
back because it's not worthwhile doing
really for IP to simple IP and IP
intersect which can match the the inner
IP address and the outer one matches the
outer one and in case of l2 VPN there
might be Mac stuff there which case you
need to use a appropriate a fee and you
can have l2 stuff as well
this is VX lamb so this is a little more
complex but over at the right side it
shows what would be covered by the outer
flow spec they let us say the flow spec
that's always present that applies to
the outer header and what would be out
of the inner flow spec so but he can
either one of them can contain
components that match on VX LAN content
fields and in both cases there be a
difference the tunnelling flow specs a
fee would be there so you could you
would only get to code that knows how to
parse this additional field and you also
would have to have match the tunnel type
so I don't know I
go over these different fields but I'm
not sure there's too much here that's
obscure or anything so for once that's
always what particular would like to
have some indication whether the working
group thinks we actually need to use a
brand new Safi for the l2 VPM or whether
we can use a fee 25 just l2 VPN and
Safie 134 for flowspec
and i'm hoping to get to early
allocation of the code points for that
but he needed to resolve that question
to a more Reb of the draft for the N via
3 full spec which I could change the
name or something if people like don't
like that file name because it's no
longer fully specific to n vo 3 I'd like
people to look at the latest version of
the draft and provide feedback I do
think it needs another pass to polish
things and improve it and the goal is to
get Kol points they're also on a goal
the code points of course is to get
implementations and see what we don't we
do that and so I want to underline that
the the the purpose right here is to see
if this is ready for lis allocation of
code points so they can try out some of
the ideas and make sure they're ready
for having an implementation we are
looking for feedback at that point jeff
has so one of the reasons that a
different efi Safiye pairing is a good
idea no matter what is your changing
flowspec precedence rules so the problem
would be like let's say that you just
stuck this into what are the existing
efi Saffy's as just a new component type
you want the evaluation to be a
different order than what's actually in
there and that's the whole point of an
athlete Safi the route selection is
consistent across the entire domain so
if you want to actually break that rule
by changing and so your full spec rule
adds slightly different comparison steps
you discover that the prior slide well
this is okay so that in the end vo 3
what everyoe 3 unquote flowspec
rule yeah it does extend the precedence
rule
for multiple matches but that uses a new
safiya TBD and that's my point there's
one to have it happy for that got yeah
but yeah my question really is for the
for the l2 VPN one where I think we can
us use 134 25 134 for a fee Safi and it
has been asserted by at least one person
that that's terrible and we have to have
a noose a fee there I don't I think
that's unambiguous and it's well define
so well I knew Safi Ford the tunnel
aspec I completely agree with you and
the only reason that wait is sort of for
the reason that we were talking about if
you stuck this into the existing a fee a
fee type stuff regardless whether the
evaluation is correct a lot of
implementations say I don't know what
this component is and drop the peering
session so your gated behind the v2 work
or you go with a different Africa's
having yeah well I would claim that it
wouldn't it needs to will need to have
specified the anafi with this noose a
fee for the tunneled one and if it did
that then it would understand that there
was a tunneling type there and if it
accepted the tunneling type but
understand the components associated
with that tunneling type hello working
group member John Scudder in my opinion
you're perfectly fine we're using the
existing Safi as you say both a fee and
Safie provide context so sincere you
know contextualizing it with the ABI as
well great don't burn the extra code
point fine sounds good to me
okay okay one of the things that again
because John presented at first
hopefully you're thinking about is
should this go in a in a B to fixing the
type length order my suggestion is to
give him code points even if we make it
to v2 decisions so that we can get
experimentation going as soon as
possible and so just to add I think that
in the case of this pair of drafts in
fact I had a bullet on my my one slide
that but I think covered your dress
which said that if you're defining
flowspec over a new a piece a fee pair
you're okay because it's it's fully
defined and I think that's the point
Jeff was making it the mic to you so I
don't see there any impediment you know
on that basis to you know moving forward
with these two drafts right it's
actually the pairwise of the Fe and the
Safi together that is the important
piece the you know you could reuse the
same magic number in Safiye
if the fe is different the code is
different so that's okay one other thing
I'd point out is that looking at the
Safi registry 241 up to like 254 is
reserved for private use you could just
grab that and start playing with it okay
for temporarily Cumbria's yeah but don't
be shipping it I don't ship anything I'm
going to talk about the BGP yang model
to begin with if we have a new author
edition and Jeff has a agreed to join it
and be an author on the draft and for
thanks for his contributions I'm not
going to go through the status you can
go through it look at it the tips are of
course there if you have any questions
feel free to post on the mailing list so
I'm going to talk about five issues that
we are tracking they're being tracked
and github at that particular location
feel free to comment on any of the
issues there if you
or on the mailing list either one is
fine I'm gonna go through each one of
them and if I don't hear any objections
and by also posting on the mailing list
if I don't hear any objections I'm going
to zoom it's okay to proceed and
implement them all right so the first is
should Confederation be a peer type
currently we have three internal
external and Confederation which was
probably not the correct way to do it so
the new two new additions are the
Confederation internal and Confederation
external it's any comments okay none so
noted we'll take you to the mailing list
also Jeff so I think the question is
would you differentiate Jeff as the
question from Randy Bushwood to
differentiate it yes so the motivation
is hearing sessions are internal and
external and are you appearing with your
Confederation yes or no from upstate you
know we've always shown its internal or
external and we need the show if it's
Confederation because the rules differ
but they're orthogonal so you could have
internal Confederation external
Confederation you've got four right so
our two choices for modelling this was
to have no enum for internal external
and then have a boolean that's
Confederate which is sort of what you
have but when you're trying to reflect
the actual state of the session for what
each EP rule you do you basically have
to say which of these four things it is
is the cross product so we're not saying
it's no the best one we were the other
you know that I said there is a second
option in there please take a look at
the model and see which one you think
makes sense
mmm differently one question to you
we're talking here about operational
state or configuration state this is
strictly for
operational state maybe that was not
clear okay thank you okay
the second issue that we are tracking is
the list of s bad segments so s path
will always be maintained as a four byte
if riders started that are not four byte
capable route update should consist of
either year strands value the magic
number is two by comments questions I
see really good we got for Church
telecom I think this is my standard
comment and remark for something like
fifteen years are we expecting that the
young modeling is going to happen on
Reuters that do not have 4-byte asn that
was my say AC Linda I don't think you're
gonna find somebody implementing the
yang model that doesn't support for by a
SS I mean what it's it's it's it's would
be there how many implementations are
there of this yang model I mean I know
there's a few open camp 8 but this yang
model so I would interpret both of those
comments as supporting choice number one
allows people to keep their comments
brief just because we have a lot of
material to cover yeah just a
clarification comments they for bite
capable in this case is not the this is
you at 32 data structure this is
supporting our C 48 93 for 4 by TSS okay
the third issue that we're tracking is
the a spat Lent container ill ill
contain the calculated s padlet four
routes per 42 seven rules and this is
mainly for the user to see the number
that serves as input to the BGP route
selection are in odd state yes
okay
comments support for authentication so
currently we are tracking supporting
authentication either over IPSec TCP md5
and TCP AO with the idea that we'll
probably try to achieve this using IDF
keychain model that they see and others
have locked on AC is this work for you
we're looking to use the cheat keychain
model a selenium ha I believe we have
everything you need if you look at the
algorithms and the key role or know the
key rollers is there ok
here's an example how you would do
hitless key role over the implementation
just have to support it even we've been
doing it in the co not not the egg model
but the CLI version for ages it's just
that not all protocols support key
change with the key rollover
Randy Bush is the key role over 40 808
sorry is the key role over 40 808 well
I'm in trouble with care I'd have to get
back to you on that I don't know what
for it I don't know the details of 40
808 I was asking you know says it
supports key you over 40
RFC 48 oh yeah it's real simple so if I
was Randy
Mahesh does not know the details this is
us reusing existing models so if the
exam a ttle that is being defined by a
C's yang module supports it then we'll
support it by inheritance that's the
idea okay yeah if that was the question
[Music]
yeah Stephanie kievsky are gathering CP
md5 do we need to support it if we want
people to move to display oh oh great
Jeff
yes so you want to make sure that this
can support existing routers and
existing deployments even if this is not
something that we would recommend is
security a solanum cisco systems
so for IPSec as far as I know there's no
native IP set for TCP you'd have to
define a an IPSec tunnel that uses that
as the top as the selector so this is
orthogonal to this model
you wouldn't include IPSec in this model
so tier point AC our implementation
juniper and at least couple of your
flavors over at Cisco have direct
integration into the BGP
configuration for IPSec aesthetics
associations that's what's being done
here is to allow the keying of the
session to be tied into the BGP
configuration I I don't know if the
existing keychain model supports every
algorithm because the keychain model
supports both key and algorithm agility
for the rollover ok so I don't know if
we have every algorithm that you might
want to use the question AC is not
whether you have every algorithm but can
we express what you're doing in most of
the current vendors if this time if you
think that's to be true then we'll go on
we looked at both TCP al and TCP md5
while we were doing the key chain mod
right can I suggest that you know a few
of you that have all the details in your
brand sit down together sometime this
week and just thrash it out and make
sure it all works right so that the meta
here is that we don't want to invent
this ourselves this is something that I
ATF is trying them standardize and if
they don't have a standardized we want
them to help standardize talk among
yourselves ok
quick North capital R cos the the King
mechanism that is described here that
sees his trough supports us as he said
for md5 nao for IPSec you probably want
to look at something which was discussed
in carp working group that's close but
you need a king mechanism or a key
material to be exchanged okay and final
issue is features and attributes that
like references there's a list of them
our su in particular to see this is this
is where the chair I take off my
co-author hat and put on the chair had
this is essentially in order to get to
be effective within the yang committee
we need to actually define these so
we'll need to put together a description
there are two option in a chair model
separate draft or this draft my
suggestion is to make that clear and and
easy for everybody to debate on we put
it in a separate draft if you're from a
vendor and you implement some of these
features I'm interested in talking to
getting a small cadre of people to push
this quickly very quick very quickly a
sealant of what we did for the IGP
models is we put a lot line and we said
no more features in them and then these
features are going to have to come in in
augmentations okay put this particular
model one of the thing was we wanted the
common features that this has the
inheritance from some of the open config
work where we have the common features
these are as far as we've been although
yeah these are old as the hills yeah
okay so this is part of the base alright
this is part of the base model we
believe they're widely implemented but
they're like references I have a
question now for the model how to arise
to implemented for multi public instance
not for we are all behind for I mean
that if I have money for PDP incidence
both wrong we came before or other
adjust by then I have some way of
instance it's also wrong P P for P to ze
but L 1 for example 1 we have 1 I want
to use the PDP instance the one to
advertise beginning for roles and the
reacted to I have a for another
excellent point but not the focus of
this particular model this particular
model is just the base if did I
misunderstand he's coming and Jeff go
ahead and answer one other thing I don't
think you said your name can you please
give your name for the minutes standard
male Meli's aha he is hypo yang yeah
okay go ahead and we the partial
discussion that we had was the nmda
battle for the Rick instancing gives him
a portion of what he is looking for we
need to close the loop and the last
piece of the component that he was
discussing
I think I remember the thread in
question okay so just to completely
complete on this slide so these are
individually will be surrounded by
individual feature statements so that
make them optional to implement just
wanted to make that so a question about
anything so you're saying you're going
to document what these features how
these features operate somewhere else
question Mahesh gave us a pre look at
what the anchors might say that that
these would need to have some
documentation they can point you yes and
I love references and I'd love to see
what this actually means the question is
again the intent is to have a draft a
separate draft one or more standards
track draft the documents these features
in in this case that we're all I'm
treating it in my chair hat
as a case where you have a document and
for clarity's sake you break the
document into multiple documents no
that's that's fine so the observations
that ever make is that we know how long
the process can take for each one of
these documents and if it's not one if
it's multiple one six right maybe
consider if there are features that you
can define in there
I don't know advertising active routes
that sounds like a true sentence thing
that you where you can describe what
that is maybe that is something you
could just put in the draft right this
it's not normative or anywhere else
maybe something you want to do you want
to put there just surely the current
discussion among the authors is a
separate draft of arrow if you have more
input please let us know a Celinda m--
so maybe not for some of these it seems
like you could just put them in the
description in the egg model and that'd
be enough I'm not saying that applies to
every one of them but like always
compare met that seems like that would
be a paragraph like this and you could
completely describe okay in interest of
time I'd like to cut off further
discussion even though I have some
comments I would like to make about it -
I'm not going to make them so we can
continue later
thank you very much working group for
active discussion here trying to do
hey Percy hi everyone today I'm watching
okay-y much hang on the future way today
I'm going to talk about the PGP for ite
allocation so basically we have adoption
call from April then we we have a number
of comments I think the major one is
that some people don't like using PGP LS
for SIDS and also suggested that using a
new epistatic
and then the other are commands so in
this draft I we addressed all the
comments so it's basically the first one
the first of the important one so some
people don't like this kind of extension
to PGP lr s for s ID so we just get a
raved get rid of that one and then we
use the suggestions so we use ur new at
the NS a v4 s ID as suggested and then
for those are other comments for example
people says why you use a BGP why not it
is a young and then those are stuff so
we give more detailed explanations for
those why and why not in the draft and
also some people mentioned that we're
missing something we straw if we want to
withdraw these SIDS and we need to put
something so we also addressed of the
one in addition to that we ad the cap
with the negotiations so any other
comments regarding for this new version
I encourage discussion on the list as
well
it's sense if it
we made a Lunt option call and they've
tried to address it it would be helpful
if if there's something you think still
broken or still needs to be worked on ok
thank you we'll go on to
next okay thank you yeah I also go
quickly yes go ahead
so another why is a fruit spec or as rv6
so basically with very small extensions
so for existing flow spec is for
traditional IPS so we eat we extend that
much infield to the I si D is in the s
rh so just two component type so in last
version we've already talked about it
these two new types so one type is for
margin conditions to a whole si D so
another type is for matching conditions
so focus on the some part of that IDs
such as a locator and the function or
arguments so basically we the fact that
the format of this one this is similar
to the existing rules back so each one
will contain at least of all OP and
values so these at least will define the
match conditions so has this much
condition are satisfied so action will
happen so both axes are at same as the
existing one so the format of for the
opportunity for in this version is that
we just give more detail specific format
or the second component type which is a
week we would like to focus on some part
of SIDS such a locator function and
arguments so any comments for this one
so
we recently improved the v6 flowspec
by releasing it and making it and this
thing had co-author on the v6 have you
taken a look at it I realize we just
made the deadline so maybe you didn't it
might if you haven't if you I forgot to
mention that yesterday that if you're
looking for the v6 if you're only SR v6
that that may not be as germane but if
you're if you're looking at regular v6
and you need to harmonize so I it does
the SR v6 need to be harmonized with the
regular v6 oh yeah a little bit
different because radius ripple of
physics is also focus on those kind of
traditional IPS means yes for this one
we extend this kind of a match domain
inside those are SRH it's a word we're
two different app apples and oranges
that's what I had initially thought but
as you were presenting I I wanted to
listen is there any other comments how
is the sr6 work coming are we progressed
enough to look at flow specs easy later
I just have a comment on all these flow
specs and the idea of getting a flow
spec for every end cap is the ID is
there a framework for what you're gonna
do if this is it seems like you're doing
open flow with flowspec right is our is
there some document that describes the
requirement and what you're doing of
this or is it just just because if
there's an MP and that end cap exists
we'll do a flowspec um okay see John's
first slide our first thing is we think
we oughta as chairs
again chair hat on we have to go back
and fix the basics of TLV then as to the
rest that would be an appropriate time
to say what if you think we should
narrow our scope at the original
definition of flowspec there was a very
targeted audience and a very targeted
focus the addition requests have
indicated that the same denial of
service attack work is concerned we
haven't done when I presented the
original v2 I had called for a thought
your exact question of harmonization the
working group asked to put it off till
we got the Bissau so your comment is
germane and I think the working group
should reconsider all these things the
reason I asked about the SR v6 this is a
new type of caring planter that seems to
take the v6 control plane I don't know
enough personally as to the deployment
so that was a question I guess yeah ac
Lindemann it seems it seems like the
header document is at least done I don't
know about you know locator it seems
like there's only there's only a couple
ways you could do it so so we have some
time to discuss the v2 and to talk about
this limitations go ahead and make your
comments please keep them brief if you
can line is closed after you guys
because when though still has one more
thing to go through care was up first go
ahead Capitol artists I think I think we
should hold this work till we have the
flow spec v2 hashed out and you could
then use this as a capability or new TLB
and carried having once a fee would be a
much better choice from an
implementation perspective then to get a
Sofia explosion within flows back yeah
that's good feedback
jeffires as far as the applicability
goes the
motivation that all these different
authors have for trying to drill into
the contents of various tunneled packets
his flowspec is being used for two big
cases right now the first one for
dealing with standard DDoS type things
at various number gauges which may be
under some types of tunnels as an
example you know if for example if I
would pick a topic near and you're like
Linda's heart fit so that's the UN type
of implementation you may need to be
able to do a flowspec filter targeting a
specific port for a specific
encapsulation and still do all the
firewall type things that flow spec is
good for so that's one motivation the
second motivation and I suspect from
some of the people in the participants
is that they're using the flowspec
filters to be able to be used for
traffic engineering purposes this one
Mia is about a extension to BGP for SR
pass ingress protection so right now we
already have SR policy draft is invoking
is walking walking with document so as
our policy well sender s are passed to
the ingress node of data pass and
English not West set up that pass but
when that humid in Lhasa fails so in
order to prove in order to provide
protection for the failure of that
English node so we needed to also send
up another by car pass through a
backpack Harper English note so the path
back a path will be from that back by
coupling with note to the equals note
unity so that we may have some kind of
informations will for protections so
basically in the previous version we
already talked about these kind of
extensions so the extension is the first
small and then we just made
stop at least this opportunity contains
the information for the protections and
then in this version we just make made a
little bit change a damn war description
as a subsidiary which described the
traffic that a backup as well
well we'll transport so this is the
sapaterre of the details yeah that's all
any comments so on all of this a couple
of times i've queried these bring chairs
on some of the policy i also ask if
you're working toward using this spring
policy that you at least give me a heads
up operationally what what this is being
used for on the are pd acceptance as a
draft i also call for operator input hi
andrew here from liquid telecom we are
using s or policy a fair amount of it
primarily for steering traffic around
places that how do I put this certain
customers do not want to root over
certain locations of a certain hardware
etc etc and so we give them the option
to steer around far away patch that is
all done with s or policy injection and
it's a big deal for us looking at this I
I will admit that I have not read the
drafts this proposal before this meeting
my bad
but my question here would be if I'm
going to send a backup off at the moment
over the SR stuff why am I not just
going to send two separate paths using
two separate communities to dictate
which route or accepts them and send it
like that
rather than complexified my policy
saying to the Ruta create another part
when I can simply inject the two paths
do all the calculations on the back end
and then set the communities to
determine which route or accepts to me
that seems like a lot simpler option and
it leaves the control in my controller
to calculate all of those paths that
would be my comment on this I would
appreciate if that type of comment also
went toward the spring chairs with the
reference to this there there you know
some of this is refreshment and that's
very good feedback and questions okay
alright so I think we're up to Europe
and we're we're almost running on time I
will ask people's indulgence to say just
a few extra minutes so that he can have
his is full ten minutes but we're we're
darn close to being on time anyway so if
almost on time you mean I have to go
slow or fast perfect do I have a clicker
[Music]
job Snyder's entity I want to provide a
small update on some work that was
presented in ITF 104 in the Gros working
group and my hope is that this work and
transition to the ID our working group
which is why I'm here but some of you
have already seen parts of this
presentation the topic at hand is bgp
maximum prefix limits HB maximum prefix
limits are a very popular mechanism in
the operator world to dampen the
negative effects of mostly full table
route leaks so it's a very crude
mechanism or it
helps against very common occurrence
that we see in internet in the internet
routing system if you look at the core
BGP specification there is which
introduced BGP maximum prefix limits
there is no notion of whether those
prefix limits are applied pre import
policy or post import policy and I've
created an image where on the x axis we
see a progression over time and the y
axis is the amount of prefixes that one
network is sending to the other network
and when a leak occurs the amount of
routes advertised to the adjacent
network goes up until it hits a certain
threshold where the common operational
procedure is to configure the device so
that it tears down the BGP session and
from that moment on even though maybe
bgp session is destructed both networks
are in a safer state than they would be
if the leak persists now this is what
happens pre policy well can occur if a
maximum prefix limit is applied post
policy is that between an e BGP prefix
based filter that derive from say IR
data or or in case
RPI based HP origin validation is
applied that so many parts are rejected
in the policy that the amount of routes
that make it through the policy does not
exceed the trash hold in which case even
though you have a full routing League
full table route leak if you have high
quality filters the a part of the leak
still makes it through and the session
does not tear down because the
thresholds are not reached
this is discovery we've made in the real
worlds where at some point we in NTT
realized hey we were contributing to a
route leak that lasted for multiple
hours how come why do we even observe
this behavior there are benefits to both
pre policy maximum prefix limits and
post policy maximum prefix limits the
pre policy limit feature is very
effective against full table route leaks
and it is also very effective to protect
against memory exhaustion in case a BGP
implementation is operating with a fully
populated adjacent grip in the
advantages of a post policy limit could
be to protect against rip or fit
exhaustion or to enforce contractual
agreements between parties an example of
this could be that as part of a layer 3
VPN service only X amount of routes are
allowed in into that that VPN the
illustration here is that that both use
cases exist in a world and I think
they're there they're valid use cases
now if we go take a look at what is
available to operators these days
it appears there's a wealth myriad of
interpretations of the particular
sections of the core BGP spec on how to
do maximum prefix limits specifically on
iOS XR + XE the concept of pre policy
limits does not exist at all
and then on other platforms for instance
OpenBSD is open Beach PD the post policy
variance does not exist and I believe
that the is this inconsistency between
HP implementations
a result of the lack of mentioning that
pre policy and post policy limits could
exist in the original BGP specification
my hope is that by specifying that both
exists and how they should how they
should behave that we can encourage
vendors to consider implementing both
types of limits and I believe this will
have positive impact on operational
community a second aspect of the draft
we would like to work on is the notion
of outbound maximum prefix limits very
very crude character stationed a
character that's a difficult word from
the concept of entities perspective
being a simple internet transit provider
the general case is that we will either
announce a full routing table to appear
or a subset of that full routing table
say half of the full routing table and
in the instance where to the piers where
we only intend to announce our customer
routes which is half if we would exceed
a threshold of say 400 500,000 routes
whatever is happening is wrong and we
would be better off if we self-destruct
our sessions on that particular ebgp
neighbor so this the concept of maximum
of outbound maximum prefix limits serves
to to facilitate situations where maybe
the peer did not configure any limits
but we have expectations of what we
expect to announce to the specific
adjacent network and that we can opt to
shoot ourselves in the head should we
shoot certain high-water marks be
reached now
only birth as an implementation supports
this today and I if a battle of open
Beach PD to to consider for testing I am
aware that there are a number of
complexities related to this feature we
should this be adopted as a working
group we will need to identify those
complexities and see if we can resolve
them so this I'm not passing this off as
a trivial feature but I think it is
worth attempting to specify this so
compared to ITF 104 I've come to an
important insight in that grow meeting
back then and there I advocated that's
only a cease notification should be
applied if maximum prefix limits are met
reasoning from the perspective of
internet routing we're tearing down the
session is a more desirable state of
being compared to keeping the session up
but stopping stop accepting new
advertisements however upon rereading
the core BGP specification it became
clear to me that already today in the
course back we have two options of
dealing with hitting the maximum prefix
limits one is keep the session of block
new extra announcements I want us to go
through the motions of tearing out the
session so we will need to rework the
draft to provide compatibility with what
already exists even though as an
internet operator it is not my favorite
option I do not wish to alter that part
I want to my goal is to to revise and
clarify and not take things away
sue has been very kind in providing a
extensive review of our first step at
this draft and she also provided the
primary notes fish and who moved the
word from grow to idea as she was able
to articulate with some patience to us
that these things can only materialize
if we do this as a update to for 2001 in
doing so I've come to realize that there
is a fair bit of spaghetti to untangle
because the concept of maximum prefix
limits is mentioned in numerous sections
and well it is a very exciting puzzle
and and yeah III we we would benefit
from from help in how to not only
articulate what we want to accomplish
because I think a natural language the
notion of pre policy versus post policy
is fairly easy to explain from from one
person to another but we should also be
very careful in not making the current
text that we want to update worse and
and foremost in this effort is to drive
consistency across multiple BGP
implementations and provides users of
BGP implementations with a reference
which they can maybe consider in their
RF piece so the next step is to go
through another round of cleanup to see
if we can improve the language and undo
some of the spaghetti and then I would
like to move forward with asking for
working group adoption and work on this
jointly thank you I would like to say
let's not have questions at the mic
because we're at two minutes over our
three minutes over so now we're five
minutes over and I don't you know I've
seen people filtering out so I think
it's you know sort of let's respect the
group's time if you have points to make
by all means please make them on the
list or
you know where to find job thank you
again thank you
[Music]