good morning everyone
this is a first and imagination of of
the week welcome everyone I'm Lauren
chavala and here is Jean Francois from
hanya the new coach of energy first time
live so we have a very tight agenda
today so we will start right away and I
will ask the presenters to really stick
to the time and if you are willing to
make comments please be to the point and
try to be short so goals of the IGF the
IGF conducts research it is not a
standards development organization
this is a sort of message reminder that
we are putting in research groups to
highlight the difference between rhf and
IETF nevertheless IETF follows IETF
policies and so this is the note well
reminder on the IHF policies in effect
on various topics such as patents or
code of conduct so please be aware of
those policies and comply to them so
this we can skip we already have thanks
to Dan for being our meter call scribe
and gentleman myself will take after of
the minutes if anyone is willing also to
help us with the minutes we have the
heath apart here and you can directly
put it on your notes
blue sheets so please circulate the blue
sheets if you are the last in the row
please bring it back so that we can also
circulate them during the meeting
a quick glance on what will be left this
week so we already close to the end of
the meeting but today we have our first
session which will be concentrated on
intern base networking and tomorrow we
have also a second session with two main
topic discuss a bit of the rich
authoring process and a synthesis of the
different activity on network artificial
intelligence as I said we have two full
agenda so please stick to your time and
be concise in your comments this is the
agenda of the first session so we are
currently in the introduction after that
we will make a quick report on the
interim meeting in October in rabaa that
was focusing on in practical aspect of
IBM then we have a couple of technical
presentation on the active internet
draft for the group intern
classification from all there that will
be removed and Alex which will make an
update on the IBM concept draft and then
the final sort of today we have a set of
technical presentations I will not go
through that but this is covering a
different set of topics and also new
proposals anybody has something to add
or change to the agenda
squit for you so a bit of overview of
the status of the research group there
is an ongoing revision of the Charter we
have sent email yesterday to the group
and also to the IETF chair we think we
have a stable version of the revision
but it's welcome we welcome your
comments and we'd use on this new
charter so you have the link to the
Charter and on the mailing list you have
also links to the comparison between the
document and the first version of the
Charter so the idea is to have a kind of
umbrella text covering describing
quickly the main research direction of
the group and the relationship and also
to highlight a more detailed word plan
on the intern by topic which is the main
topic the working group the research
group is working on so far
we aim to approve the new charter by the
end of this year and of course your
comments and feedback are most welcome
we will have a bit more time to go
through the recharter ring tomorrow
but in the meantime you can either look
at this and send us your comments we
have also sent to the group and discuss
about a proposal for procedure of
adopting research group documents there
is no formal process in the ITF for the
research group how to approve in to move
internal documents to research group
documents this is on purpose we don't we
are not a working group so this is not a
formal process but still we want it 12
to document a clear process so that
everyone is willing to move towards
research group documents and can know
how be the criteria we will use as a
research group chair to to validate or
not the progress towards research group
documents so work as usual zero
precondition so update your individual
draft taking track on the comments
discuss the issues on the meaning list
so keep dating your document this is a
good sign that this document is alive
then for the adoption first check that
you validate a set of criteria do you
have a precise scope of the draft needs
to be clear and hopefully will not
change once the research group document
is adopted we are looking for we are
doing research we are looking for good
scientific quality and we expect a good
impact also in the community so it needs
to be a rigorous scientific base and the
current contents must be mature enough
we are not looking for finalized
document but still we need to have not
mature enough technical contents in the
document we need to also have indication
how you plan to continue the efforts the
content of the draft evolution of the
document must be already player if you
can have also an indication of work plan
on milestone this is even better and to
know a bit more we will work on the
draft so this is we hope commitment from
the authors but also in the group if you
have indication of people willing to
review or if you are willing to join the
effort this is also important indicators
to know that this is of importance to
the research group and that it will be
progressed I need to speed okay and then
request for adoption so you can ask it
on the meet during the meeting on the
mailing list and also the
research group chair we also forward the
the the call for adoption on the meaning
list to let anyone a chance to to
comment an overview a few projects that
we have inside the research group so
idea and resource a project this is an
idea to create a place website to get
whatever the form we have not said yet
which will be open to all and to a user
for an interface to collect external
resources on intern base networking
technologies article standards
documentation on product whatever it
could be useful for the community to
have in one place we're also working on
a participation to Akutan we have a
target a bit in the future July next
year in Madrid we would like to grow the
idæan activity on practical aspects with
development of tools demonstration of
proof of concepts so the idea is to also
work theoretically in the research group
but also make some implementations and
we want to leverage the European
location also to invite different teams
European or white teams but also in EU
funded projects and so we have made
first steps at this hackathon to connect
and you will hear more in the coming
weeks we also need network AI challenge
project as your home will make synthesis
of that tomorrow
different aspects were working on
definition of the use cases
identification of datasets oil relation
platforms and publication aspect of the
challenge meeting plans for next year so
this is tentative there is a lot of
things that are still open but we plan
to meet in the difference i HAF meetings
we also plan to have a few internal
meeting face to face co-located for
instance with IM noms to 2020 in
budapest as we used to do we are also
looking to have ensuring either in tokyo
with the IPOP conference or in a
brazilian with SPRC conference this is
still being discussed with the local
organizations and we have also monthly
virtual meetings so we will see if we
need one in december but at least next
one will be surely in mid-january
was it for the research group status any
question on the research group before I
move to the report if not okay so this
is a quick report on the interim meeting
we had in October in Roma and co-located
with the network of future conference
the focus of this interim meeting was
practical aspect of intern business
working we have invited for a joint demo
session with the conference and we
received four papers three demos and
invited invited torch to make
demonstration on IBM technologies and
also discuss we have two days of
sessions discuss a bit more the
practical aspects of intern base
networking technology we wrote a report
of this event so this is currently
available on the data tracker you have
the link here but this user will also be
published as part of the Proceedings of
the conference so you have you can find
it on an ultra poly Explorer and also
the the demo papers were part of the
conference and they will be published
with the proceedings
we thought this was a very useful and
kind of different meeting that we have
here that we used to work with virtual
meeting order interim we have a lot we
learn a lot from the implementations
they had to make decisions on the format
of intent the infrastructure to support
it the transformation of intensive it
was really useful to compare different
choices and also to confront theory and
practice because in the group we had
several drafts but this is a theoretical
design and then in the implementation
this was not to report on implementation
choices and it's also it was also
helpful to generate further ideas for
for instance the akhaten project and
collaboration between different teams
working on those tools again the idea is
not to go into a full report if you want
to read a bit more there is a four six
pages reports available you can also
come to us it's very synthetic very
quick to read you have all the
information on the demos the links and
all the materials also available on the
the interim meeting page
we have also identified a few further
directions out of this meeting so to
create a code repository for the tools
and the demos and with insert
installation guides and installation and
user guides this is still in our to-do
list we have also defined a Ibn tool
data sheets to describe the different
experiments so the participants of the
meeting committed to describe their
tools using these data sheet you think
it will be useful also to have these
data sheets so that people can know a
bit more what are the the tool is doing
and also provide a bit of documentation
we work with we're also proposing to
have a kind of mapping table mapping
table is to make the bridge with the
draft on intend classification so in the
demo they have made choices of the
environment the intern format so the
idea was to use the mapping table to see
where it fits in the classification so
maintains and updates of your overall
IBM told you so this is this kind of
this is the true review so we have a
draft intent lifecycle and we try to map
the component of the different demos to
the different stages of the lifecycle
the different functions so this was a
work in progress during the the meeting
and we want to keep updating this table
and use it to understand if we are
missing something in the life cycle if
some fortune ality are well designed or
we need to split them etc so this is -
to use this as a tool to understand a
bit more the the entire life cycle we
have follow-up interactions there have
been point to points between the teams
say ok what you have done can also be
used in my demo we can interconnect so
they will we expect that there will be
more exchange between the different
teams and to have also follow-up
meetings on particle aspects and as I
said we are developing a project to
participate in the a cotton in IETF one
write in Madrid next year and we are
working with your home to make a kind of
presentation of what we have to do there
and and connect with a set of teams so
that's it for the report some questions
on this meeting and perhaps
so if not we will switch to the next
presentation
oh god the floors
olga this is your turn to talk can you
please tell if you can hear us
oh yeah try to talk please
[Music]
okay Olli I hope you can hear us so the
instruction is to please click on the
mic icon which is a next to your name
top left corner you need to unmute in
mid eco Olga can you try to talk please
[Music]
hello can you hear me now
yeah no it's good sorry like I didn't
have the list of names I only had the
video because of the format of the
screen sorry for this I'm really sorry I
was not able to join you in Singapore so
I'll try to be quick because I took a
few minutes of your time
so what I'll what I'll present today is
the version 2 of our intent
classification draft and and here is the
list of contributors through version 0 0
0 1 & 0 2 so next slide for those of you
who sorry the previous for those of you
who were not who are not familiar with
this draft our goal was to achieve
agreed terminology related to intense
and to propose a classification approach
for different types of intends for our
group but also to guide other groups in
ITF ITF and even other standards so
folks of this draft is the user intense
and to define and classify those intense
the scope was you know relevant for any
system or node that expects interaction
with human user in the int and River
networks and that human user besides
being operator administrator and use a
customer is also the application
developer who is building applications
on top of the intent interface and
intend driven approach is applicable to
both autonomic networks and and networks
the new future networks it machine
learning and AI as well as the
traditional networks where it can intent
could be used on top of the existing
controllers and management systems etc
our classification approach was based on
different solutions users their purpose
lifecycle
judgment requirements scope in the
network scope network function scope etc
and also abstraction for the interns
whether they're technical with technical
feedback or not so and we have different
intent examples next slide please so
this is the these are the milestones for
draft as you can see version zero one
and we are here now in November 2000 and
nineteen we are proposing version two to
be adapted and then we are looking at
potentially at March 2020 for the
version three which would include all
the comments and outstanding things so
the the following is the list of
comments received and and we addressed
all of these comments we added some use
case references some of the comments
would be addressed by different draft
that we started for the intent framework
because this draft is only about intent
classification some of the comments one
of the comments that Diego had was more
related to the framework so therefore
there is a new draft intent framework
being started on there was also a good
suggestion from Lauren about the
classification table and as the table he
discussed when presenting the status
from the Rome meeting and that is we
added that table as Excel but then also
to the draft so that everyone can use it
and that box can use it for their
classification so we would appreciate
any comments for any of the paths but
especially for classification table
there were also comments from Ericsson
about the they they proposed not to use
the term granularity and instead to use
potentially abstraction so we also
addressed this issue added abstraction
section but also use the input from
China Telecom where they were suggesting
to talk about technical feedback or not
so we we we now have a
proposal to use for clarification
obstruction technical with technical
feedback or non-technical without
technical feedback there are other few
comments that we are going to address or
been addressing at the moment next page
so so this shows the table of contents
for version 1 and what parts have been
changed
mostly main updates in this version so
you can see that section for those who
want to review only the change sections
already review the previous version its
section 3 the two intend solutions and
intend users in section 4 by point 2
which used to be granularity and now
it's called feedback section 5 has been
added and it is a intent classification
table example with table for careers
table for data center solution and table
for enterprise solutions and section 5
has been moved to 6 and we added 7
clarifications in section 6 which has
been moved to section 7 next slide
please
so the use cases and some reference is
valid the example for carrier networks
scenario use case where the user wants
to watch high-definition video and the
system then has to map their intent into
the technical requirements for the
network for data center network
scenarios the use case was about intend
such a flawed balancing where the
administrator wants to restrict the
maximum load on the node container below
50% and maximum load on any link below
70% for enterprise network scenarios
when hosting a video conference
the remote access is required
and the network operator has an intent
that for any use of the application that
everything has to be synchronized
between 50 milliseconds the video in
order to reach the destination viewer of
each conversation session so these are
the use cases in China Telecom and help
to bring this use cases next slide so
the feedback section was added and and
we classified we created two categories
here your ordinary users so that would
mean customers and users or
non-technical users or application
developers you know some applications
that there where they don't care about
how intent is executed really did what
they interested in is the feedback in
terms of success or failure of that
intent other type of the users is more
technical users and for them they that
intent may be more technical but their
feedback may also be technical because
what they are interested in is they're
also interested is how intent is
realized on the network so they
interested in network resources parts
some some resource information so in
that case it would be a technical intent
with technical feedback and next slide
please
so also there was some request to add
some more information about how a I a
technology what role it can play in the
intent driven networks intend based
networks so we added some explanation
into section 6 the originally section 6
was talking about that a IML driven
system would be driven by intent by the
goal intent or policy intent goal intent
would present the target state and
policy intent would present some
guidelines in how to realize and deliver
that goal intent but there are
additional explanations added and maybe
I won't go through all of them here how
a I may be used for security translation
or closed-loop self optimization self
correction so you can maybe look at that
chapter section and do your comments the
next slide it's also additional
explanation in that section so these are
some examples of how ml and AI could be
used and some example of how clustering
algorithms could be used next slide so
here is the just example of one of the
tables and this is really where ever it
would be great for all pox from our
previous meetings to may be position
themselves and of course any comments we
consider this table we did take a lot of
comments and and we'd kind of spend a
lot of time working on it but of course
we are hoping that in version 3 of this
document there would be more reviewers
and contributors which should bring
value to this table this is example of
different type intents this is for
carrier solution normally where we
identified different intent types based
on the solution we did some descriptions
and we also proposed initial categories
which could be based by the intense
scope or a network scope or abstraction
and also life cycle because we believe
there are two types of intense those
that are kind of Golden Goal intense
that that a persistent one that that
focused on the full life cycle like a
target Network service or and there are
those transient intense like short
living interns which are some actions
that intent users are doing so that
there are two types of interns so please
see these tables and
tell us if you have any comments on
those next slide so so the conclusions
here our current version addressed most
of comments received online and offline
there are some comments that we received
also in in the last few days and we
would be addressing them in the future
but we do believe that because of major
updates and as well of addition of
classification table it would be good we
want to ask for adoption of version 2 as
a draft so that this draft could be
reviewed from now on by the community
these are some of the next steps like
start using collaboration tool and we
put it currently on the Google Drive as
the version but we we would communicate
with all contributors and maybe get
their preferences we won't alter the
section briefly describing intent work
status another SDOs
and we also want to work with community
to de river unified intent definition
that encompasses all intent types for
all solutions and intent users so these
are some of the next steps and also to
address all additional comments and
update a document based on the response
and feedback from the community they
also have few additional contributors
that that show the interest potential
contributors that show the interest so
they may add more contributors to the
list so I would like to I would ask for
adoption as a draft thank you Thank You
Olga so come in from Christian for
people in the room
no okay
so maybe a one question from from for
myself jean-francois not not as a as
charity group you are mentioning in in
the modification you have done I think
you you are mentioning this
classification rating the feedback from
the intent realization and when reading
the text for me it seems that you it's
exclusive classification that an intent
will provide it back to the user or not
in the realization of the intent but I
suppose that for example an internet
express by hand user can actually does
not need to project back to the user
itself because it does not need to know
the technical realization of the intent
but at the same time yet misrata of the
system may want to have the feedback to
know all the user intent as mineralised
13z basically gez the feedback that you
were expressing there may not be any
directly to who has expressed intent
yeah you are right for the for the
customer intents and application interns
administrate and operator would always
be able to see the states of the network
and to check the network but this is
specifically mentioned if the
administrator and operator is the intent
user so in that case their intent would
be more technical than the intent even
if their intent does the same thing as
the intent of the customer let's say
network service so if the customer
requests the network service it may be
it may be non-technical if the
administrator requests it would it could
be more technical but also the feedback
it receives for that could include some
realization information and if it's
another user non-technical intent user
then that feedback wouldn't contain that
information so we are talking about both
intent we
technical or non technical but also
responds to that intent being non
technical technical but I agree like the
administrator and operator would also
have his ability into intense of all
other users yeah so the zelich's come
and I also dress also from a cursory
read but perfectly explained this year
so looking at all the tables that you
were adding with a classification one
thing that is not quite clear to me is
how you would actually use this I mean
this is very refined you can be given
greater and hilarity tag basically the
the different it tents that yeah they're
not being defined but how would that be
expected to be to be used I mean other
different the different methods going to
be associated with different types of a
tensor is this a way to basically
catalog which she intends belong
together or can you perhaps comment a
little bit on the usage of thanks for
the question the the the comment the
suggestion he really came from the
chairs from from Laurent and I think
that was a good very good comment for
the previous revision because the
original revision was mostly text and it
was talking about you know we can have
these type of intense and death
those type of intense and then during
the last meeting we had parks and demos
so we were saying it would be great if
he can classify those different parks
and demos so the teach POC or dime or
any tool in the industry can say these
are the categories that we are
delivering and this is our focus so
primary primarily we were looking at
this table as being a tool that could be
used with different pox and Deimos to
say this is the intent that we are
demoing or this is the type of category
that he addressing I hope that answers
the question thank you
sure thank you
okay thank you we have to close the
comment now because we already bit over
time so thank you very much olga for
presenting you all you have some word of
conclusion on the the coal gas for as
egyptian as energy 12 so my first
question will be to know who in the room
has weighed the document please raise
your hand okay around 10 people okay how
many of you think this document is
useful for the group okay great and so
many of you think this document is ready
for edgy adoption okay yeah so between
between 1 and 2 I will say so maybe oh
yeah we will anyway you send a formal :
the milling is to have all the feedback
from all the participant as we say in
the procedure and then based on the
feedback we will be able to take a
decision and discuss with you so you can
also review the difference in back you
will have but thank you again Olga we
move to the next speaker
I think it's Alex right
[Music]
so I think this is easier so good
morning everyone I'm Alex Clement
presenting a status update on the
intent-based networking concepts and
overview draft first number revision 3
this vergis also found vision on behalf
of the co-authors blown his angle con
villain chef Francois so basically since
last time the draft has undergone one
one revision cycle so you know in
revision 0 3 and basically the updates
are all pretty much every tutorial
nature one thing basically there is
consider section con said the intent
life cycle we did a number of diagrams
but relatively little text so basically
these text textual gaps have been have
been filled in and the life cycle has
been described in much greater detail
including the various intent fulfillment
in and intent assurance functions which
are part of it life cycles and how they
interact with each other so that there's
one update the second update is there
was a section on research challenges
which we felt was actually not
appropriate for the scope of this graph
so this section has been removed so this
is just again the intent life cycle
diagram which is ok I think in the
interest of time we don't have to go
through this this has not really been
updated this has not change but
basically this is about this concerns
the aspect of the document it has
undergone a lot of texture of revision
and so this here is the document
structure so the updated document
structure and compared to previously you
will see it's essentially the same
structure but - the research challenges
in terms of open items and accepts for
this document so there are a few
editorial updates that that still need
to be made one thing is basically
there are currently two diagrams on the
intent lifecycle which need to be
consolidated there's one aspect second
aspect is because a lot of the function
have been defined as partner of the
lifecycle there's some textural
alignment that editorial and yes that
has to occur between section 6 which
talks about the lifecycle and section 7
which talks about the function so you
could not really talk about the
lifecycle without talking about the
functions so there's some alignment that
these would take place there the third
question is but you listed currently as
an as an issue whether or not to address
this here this concerns basically
whether we need to distinguish between
different categories and then and
different intent granularity the
questions may be whether the rock when
should talk about this at all or we just
leave it to the intended classification
document and perhaps that is actually
the appropriate answer but anyway this
is maybe one of the issues that is
listed currently in the in the document
and then finally basically we want to
update or we want to add security
implications and challenges so busy the
security considerations that are unique
to intend it because that introduces new
security issues okay so in terms of also
next if we do believe actually that the
document well this is very weird fits
with e within the energy charter so
basically documenting the fundamental
concepts background and terminology this
is the main focus of this document and
accordingly we wanted to actually also
request like the previous speakers and
requested option as anonymity work item
because we believe it supports directly
the our Charter um questions
[Music]
hello viola p.m. I think that when it
comes to the to the categories precisely
when you mention this category is
another like this is precisely one of
the things that they still miss in the
in the other document the classification
because establishing those categories is
whether classification missing maybe you
and this is something that is not mature
enough in the other one I believe it for
the other one because it looks like they
tried like the natural ways that were
making a classification establishing the
categories there so so that we have here
well not a problem but the mother of
synchronous synchronizing the other
thing and when it comes with the
security implications and think that is
a great idea because it's something that
is essential and the when talking about
the intent and having you know this kind
of long-forgotten issue when talking
about this about I'd say ice prayers or
whatever what and I think it deserves
note that it is also more attention
about how is the security of intent and
how you express security requirements by
intent basis and something that deserves
more attention note that so far what I
have seen in the draft is still in a
burly early stage but this I think it's
a it's a quite interesting path to
follow
thank you yes so we'll definitely I
think the implication need to be
analyzed clearly in regarding the
classification and one thing the
discussion we need to have actually but
we had in mind originally for this
document not the the other one was
actually a much coarser level but just
distinguishing between the high level
operation content intent versus intent
for service instance versus the intent
for the force for fro and just leave it
at that but anyway thank you for your
comments
so if the reason now is our comments I
will go through the same question as
before as you call also for LG adoption
soku has read the document please raise
your hand okay twelve cool things this
document is useful
same and could think this document is is
ready for the group adoption okay ten so
as before so this is the first feedback
we get and then we Center official
calendar on the mailing list to have a
more feedback thanks thank you Alex
so next speaker Luis please can you come
hello everyone so I represent the Indian
basin working approach that we are
following if I Yi pro yet so this is a
tool basically developed by the people
from winds which is opponent of the
consortium and I will present basically
on behalf of him so just for
understanding what 505 is basically to
set up facility for a foggy
experimentation across Europe so there
are facilities in Spain Greece Italy and
France with doing the currently
datacenters and it is to offer
abstractions to the vertical vertical
customers in order to deploy services in
that's all services they kind of
vertical customers that we have in the
project are a utility companies like
electricity de France or train companies
like Trenitalia or a give assistance
assisted different sectors from
industrial space so sorry briefly the
architecture of I give what we have on
the bottom part of the site is this
multi-site facilities with a number of
tools for orchestration and
programmability of the networks we have
osm we have phone app we have different
kind of Sdn controllers there on top of
that the blue box that you can see there
is the multi site in a
interworking framework which basically
tries to work the different sites for
the deployment of the other services
just to mention that the service here in
the context of I give are basically
experimentations or are experiments to
be run and to check the industrial case
in in in every situation and on top of
that we have a portal and through this
portal the vertical customer can request
the this presentation and can order this
presentation and the deployment in of
your site's holding 10 basis stuff is
here in the box a agree box and I will
explain basically what well it consists
now so in 10 base the purpose of
inter-basin if I give is to provide a
way for this vertical experimental set
the instance it is an experiment so they
experiment designed at the finish on
face and little on the trigger for being
deployed in insights through this
intent-based what we basically do is to
translate the the request of the
vertical to the political service
blueprint so basically - we filled we
fill a form for the describe in the
experiment and passing through the
orchestration framework the the final
step is the creation of this experiment
descriptor in such a way that what these
services deployed and experiment is run
there are two choices at the time of the
clay in the service one is the usage of
a guided selection through a graphical
user interface a kind of wizard and the
other one is the free text translation
where basically the requests of this
pediment or the vertical is interpreted
and is translated for filling up that
form only tool will be documented in
deliverable for the one from this
project that this is likely to be
released as public in a in the for
coming months so probably by the end of
the year will be already public the
galena to design we have a graphical
user interface that allow the dispara
mentors to provide their intention so
they write down what is the objective of
the test experiment to be performed
there is a translation tool which
basically take that information from the
same vertical vertical customer and
translate and try to fill the vertical
service with a blueprint for for the
play in the experiment at all in case
that the song fields are missing and so
there is no process of iterative
interrogation such a way that finally
the system can fill all the details also
the tool is consists of a database where
all these experiments are stored and
also these databases use for check-in if
in in the intended site to really play
the service there are enough resources
for further breeding the service and
also the to check the scheduling of the
experiment and basically a server all
this application insist or you have here
a link to the tools so probably this
tool also can be
of the tools that are positive that you
you were mention at the beginning so
didn't beat the the two different
notions that we have we have this free
text format so basically the
experimenters made if in my define an
intention by using natural language so
they express the experiment that they
will they want to perform the way of
expressing the Perriman is basically the
political customer requires to use some
kind of key words or some key words they
say and in some cases on special
characters characters for identifying
the specific field for instance the
specific format for the time of the day
so my specific format for the date to be
run this spellemann' also for signal in
the number of instances and so in case
that there are NT files that the office
that cannot be completely filled after
the intention of the other political
customer the system is able to
interrogate the vertical again for
completing the information which is
machine yeah
and in case the the vertical
experimenter put some data that is not
run at all that is wrong or this is not
good at all the system disabled as well
to innervate the vertical in order to
fix what is what can be be seen for you
cannot see from there but the the here
some examples of how this is happening
and in any case this will be documented
in a in the variable that I mentioned
before the second way of requesting the
service with this guided selection which
is basically a kind of Whizzer well the
vertical customer can go through
different menus let's say and start
filling the data for this Perriman if
something is not filled the system is
able to provide default values and at
the end of the process also the system
integrates the vertical customer to be
sure that the parameters that will be
part of the experiment are correct at
all so that was what we are doing in
fact if the next steps that we are
considering is to generalize this
concept to the processing of the SMA of
the EPP as ice templates so in both GSMA
and 3vp
both are working in this and apple slice
template so the idea would be to take
this ideas that we have developed if I
give porting them to the request of
services that would be expected from
coming from fy'y
from front VPP let's say for for the fiv
services for the new college license
another intention is to document this in
in address target in annex ITF for
reporting well having some some grapple
of how this has work in reality in the
de ferran experiments and also we're
exploring this way of holding this ideas
to 3d PPS stuff and that's all from my
side do you have questions any question
on the presentation so you mentioned
that I see clearly a connection with the
activity want to do on the
experimentation this could be a good
addition to the to the pool of demos you
mentioned that you would like to work on
a draft yes
have you already identified if it will
be more towards the IETF or IO GF or and
what will be the it would be a kind of
use case experimental type of draft or
more and they be able with those
properties I mean to take this idea that
we have a sporting fate but port into
the generic case nice template and then
I want a slice template from VPP
so because they did what we have if I
give these vertical service blueprints
are not does not much higher actually
the area slice templates and whenever I
see a plate so they do would be to take
this from experiments that we have done
in five but moving to work with what
could be a true as I Stan a slice
request from VPP okay thank you thank
you
our next speaker will be Mitchell good
morning everyone my name is Misha boffin
I am a PhD candidate at to invest
further on the worst of Pernambuco and
I'm here today to present a work that is
part of my pd thesis and it consists of
a solution for goal oriented policy
refinement in FEV man assistance so
let's start by defining policy
refinement this is the process of
transforming high-level policy into
directly enforceable low-level policy
however policy framing is a non-trivial
process and it remains a much neglected
research area and concerning and a few
mono systems this task is usually done
manually and the situation opposed the
presence of a knowledge expert whenever
this procedure is required and besides
this K of change can be massive which
can lead to improper specification of
important enforceable policies due to
human errors so we argued that this
procedure must be done in automatic way
in order to reduce the gap between human
attention and in FEV mano behavior so a
fully automated refinement process in
nefi I'm an assistant editor an open
issue this contest we take we tackle
this problem and we propose a dns
planner that is coronated policy finally
procedure for an FEV my assistants and
basically it combines the rich
description logic is expressivity with
the efficiency of automated plan
assistance base it on your desk iroquois
task networks so it you basically use
our well-funded
etienne planner to perform the gory
netted policy refinement procedures and
it proposes the use of one ethology in
addabbo l to call it on top laner this
is mythology will be responsible for
store the current state of the world and
of course the state constraints so this
figure showed the architecture of NS
planner and we skip some parts and focus
on the three main functionalities and we
will start talking about the the
functionality that is performed by this
model they go oriented polish management
model and this model enable one to
describe store and maintain go policies
and for this we propose it these discs
agreement there's this language
agreement and basically summarizing one
goal applies for one or more visual
nature functions of I specifically
network service and of course we can
define one or more service attributes
for this goal and the response it is
also possible to define the degree of
importance of this go as high medium or
low
disfiguring illustrate how on complainer
enable one to describe a go policies but
I want to get deeper here in the
interest of time just to lift straight
this second functionary that I want to
discuss with you is the policy
refinement procedure II and there is
perform at by the planet generation
model and once I go require a gory find
many requires arrives to the system this
modeling work as follows the first step
it study its instant heat our copy of on
top laner in a memory and it distracts
the curity state of the domain and they
requested to go information all this
information are stored in the on top
laner and then after that it builds a
planning problem dot met in Lisp code I
will talk I will talk about more later
and it used this plenty problem domain
model and a preview lose definite
planning domain as he put for an
eighteen planner in order to perform the
planning process that is basically
policy the policy refinement and once
the the planning process and it created
a first of all policies using it outputs
and it stored these enforceable policies
into the on top lane a copy
finally it performs dl reason to provide
constants verification this in consists
this dis check is performed in order to
detect if the states constraints I'll
cross it okay
and if the there are no in constants the
enforceable policies are extracted from
the on tone plane a copy and return it
to the usage API move on this figure
illustrates how the
enable the creation of policies they are
basically if it condition action rules
okay again I I want gatekeeper I would
get deeper in this context because we
have a short time and continuing the
last functionary I want to discuss with
you is the detection of volleys
conflicts name it policy analysis and
it's worth mention that policy analysis
requirement for policy refinement
systems and to achieve its functionality
we created two as double air rules one
for to detect go conflicts and another
to detect the echo rule the enforceable
policy conflicts in this context we can
perform the detection of Polish
conflicts that the detection of pulse
complete is carry out through dialing
constants DL constants verification when
originally is real reliable so if there
are constants the reason we identify the
the arrows and provide the possible
explanations so we develop an NS planet
prototype in Java and basically it use
the spring boots implement the rest for
api's and the auto WL API in order to
enable the auto planning management and
the conflict that they conflict
detection mode we use the Amity reason a
fully compliant
Sado wl2 reasoner and the plenty
management model use the top - well
found an ATM planner that is pertinent
by university of maryland and of course
in order to validate the NS play
we implemented a use case that is
basically a plain domain model for the
resilience attribute and this figure
here sure show parts of the test the
composition of their resilience goal and
I'd like to highlight two sub goals that
are the failure prevented and a failure
controlling the the foreman focus in
setting redundancy and out scale
mechanism inside the NFIP mono and FA
the the the ladder the failure is
controlling focus on setting some
healing mechanisms we we also conducted
a performance evaluation
I'm not going deeper than the results
but Verizon an s planner performs in
scale as well as the autologous size
grow and these results in able to to
indicate the DNS planet as an
appropriate is appropriated to be use it
in our production environment as an
auxiliary tool for an FF e mono
frameworks and we believe that this work
leverage two contributions to an emoji
the first one in s planet enable
oriented policy refinement and this
contest an Esplanade focus on entity
specifically aspects since go policies
described is already states in our
environment are a sequence of actions
and finally we believe that an S planner
provides a decomposition logic to
resolve intents to relevant service and
select appropriate management functions
and that's it does anyone have any
questions
hello developers a few questions first
one is when you show the the resolution
and and the oncologists do they apply to
I mean to the initial planning orders
you are making making a re resolution
for for some kind of service assurance I
don't know if you understand but what I
mean is that you do it once when you are
planning with with the man who is going
to deploy the service of you repeated
regularly for for taking decisions on a
scale a scaling out or things basically
the solution at this presentation just a
short view of the entire solution so we
have another mechanisms to perform this
replay nning was this dissolution
detects that some policies are not
working properly and besides these
disciplinary process generates some
enforceable alarms that can detect any
problem in during the the infrastructure
and of course it applies the the correct
the corrective actions but the repair
process is performing but it's another
part of the work motivation just to be
clear when you talk about planning here
I mean planning is we consider that the
planning process is similar to the
policy refund we considered the policy
refinement is a kind of planning problem
and here we use that's the composition
that is basically we have a high level
go we only you can decompose in how many
tested to you what and basically we
planning means that you can verify if
the policy are are working properly and
if doesn't you can replace by formed a
idea how do you verify that the police
is not yeah yeah I have another system
that to this okay and you're going to
present it today you know no no but if
you want to get Scott Slater
no definitely and yes just a question
because you I see so three three inputs
I mean you mentioned the operator and
twice the orchestrator to two different
modules let me see little bit that's
where no no here so you have the
operator provides some pretzels the nav
Orchestrator provides any goals to this
goal happy and at the end to the plan
area yeah in in if I consider I might be
detest the entire work we I propose it
the operator can can define a predefined
alarms that will be created in the end
of the planning process
okay understand we proposed it extent an
NF if York is treated in order that we
can define this goes inside the network
service descriptor and it will be
responsible for track this goes and then
storing the using the NS planner okay so
basic basically each network service at
each NATO service comes with a set of
goals yes what that ego applies just to
one network service you just need to
define for each and we don't do it for
us and in the planning do you consider
possessive interaction among the
different NS goals or not the
interactions I mean do you mean if I
prefer yeah I have a network service
that is saying
has as a goal use as much bandwidth as
possible and there is another natural
service that has as a goal use half of
the bandwidth available for example do
you consider that they are requesting
things that probably are conflicting Oh
as I mentioned I defined these rules
where I can find conflicts between all
those that are storied that are
registered in the Delta planner and
basically were at water check here if
let me see her
that's better if there are at least two
goes that applies to the same network
servers and intersects with but that
apply to the same network service or
that they apply to the same magnitude in
the network because it's not the same to
the same network service but I went to
that active here that I will don't have
duplicate enforceable policies for
example if I have a network service and
I defined two goals that could same
patrol a choke functions probably when I
generate that the final plan don't move
another strike maybe Diego is mentioning
more if you have goals conflict between
different network services not no no no
no services I just check if
apply to the same network service so is
not let's say this is not multi-tenant
yet basically okay just very minor
clarification question because in your
your presentation you have some acronyms
just to clarify when you say DL it's a
description logic yeah yeah yeah okay
yeah and HTN it's a your article tasks
what's HTM in a TN is performing a TNS
the the planning system no HTN in the in
the task decomposition I think
connects up next next okay see the
planner use shop to as HTN yes I choose
it to I decided we decided to work with
an eighteen planner is this automated
planning system well in which we can
define up planing domain model in a
plane any problem and it these two
models are using as input for this
planar and but based on what you define
there do you it it to you generate a
plane a sequence of reactions that you
have to perform okay
what does HTN mean a TN is it's a kind
of automated system planning it is
different from the classical planning it
is wasted in task the composition that
we believe that is better to work it's
it's it's more CLE clear about how human
feels so basically and we need we need
something that from this this kind of
test the composition because we don't
want to define just a sequence of
actions and generate a planning based on
their preconditions and effects we want
something that we can start for from
high level tasks and then generate just
the actions that okay I mean there exist
order paper in the literature for task
decomposition and operation
operationalization of policies of young
also do you have some related work yeah
this work is created this work is under
submission for the a triple transaction
actual working so I have a lot of
material if you want to know more about
the related works and how they
they tell you the entire solution works
we can discuss later no problem but we
have a lot of related words okay so I
think this work is quite interesting for
the topic of intern base networking in
the research group I see that since you
have already some implementation it
could also fit with the practical aspect
the tools I will encourage you to get in
touch with the activity on this thing
and you can also come a come to us to
know who to contact my question is also
from the more on the theoretical base
because you are proposing some
techniques to address the the golda
composition the the planning phase and I
can see relationship with the lifecycle
so the different steps that we have for
the intent we have also decomposition we
have conflict resolution so I will also
encourage you maybe to link with the the
author or on the meaning list whatever
so because I think you can propose
things to refine our understanding of
the the functionality and maybe also
propose some suitable techniques okay
for solving for being solutions to the
different functionality okay I'm glad to
contribute thank you thank you
[Music]
next speaker please Sabine
so hello so I'll stop I'll stop the
presentation by a use case that
motivated this work on the over-the-top
intent based networking and sorry oh so
can he is it better then a description
of the framework we proposed the first
conclusion and the challenges so the the
the initial use case was this demo that
involved several burlaps facility and
this was about deploying slices for IOT
and EMB B of over a cloud run so as you
can see you have already several types
of clouds so and so the problem was that
to have it up and running each time it
was in requiring like one and a half to
two hours of expert engineer and
researcher configuration operation so
when we looked at existing research in
intent on intent based networking for
those type of use cases we found out
that as it is written in several drafts
currently the current work at that time
was focusing on policy the service was
connectivity and there was already there
was that lack of languages to translate
instruction from one system to another
one
so what we proposed is to extend the
intent based networking from
connectivity to applications from
network operation to over the top
application provisioning and from fixed
network to more heterogeneous networks
such as cellular width and the current
focus on this work is to look at the
intent request feasibility check we're
not working this work is not about
translating and natural language
processing and stuff like that and also
the the other focus is on intent Network
application slice automation so this is
the framework so I tried bit between the
two versions I uploaded I try to play
with some colors to map it with the work
that draft on intent based concepts
so this sorry so the so the functions
this is the architecture framework for
the intent based the in OTT intent sorry
and this was already here the only thing
I did was adding the outlines so we have
already this space here so in the draft
you have the this is why I took my paper
the user space here and this the
functionality of the use of space as
indicated they interact with the user so
this one takes in the application slice
request this one provides system
feedback and this is a key function to
in our vision because this makes the
difference between a Gillian and
then stuff it it is this system feedback
that the user gets this is the history
ASI stands for application slice instant
so these stores like what happened the
name and and whether it was interrupted
status and this is some dashboard that
is exposed to the user
given that of course underneath the
dashboard you have more system no lower
level computation this is what is called
the this is the core IBM framework
functions
so these function Maps the intent
requests to a first a first level of
what is called service graph it's a
graph of the the main function that
needs to be that needs to run to perform
the service so this is not yet talking
about how many replicas and stuff like
that this is like a blueprints so so you
have this initial graph and upon this
initial graph before ever going
continuing the first thing is that given
once you know what function you need to
run your service you should be able and
once you know of course what application
you want to run once you also know the
population of your application which
means how many endpoints for example you
should be able to provide a first level
of dimensioning so this is not there's
nothing new there there's lots of
literature and studies and online
learning system data driven
functionalities to help you have a
coarse grain dimensioning so before ever
continuing used you have to check the
resources available
whether your infrastructure is able to
deploy the necessary functions so to do
so you so you go through this function
and this function is fed by other
functionalities that compute the
dimensioning and that computed based on
patterns and where these patterns are
based on system measurements so this is
like some classical loop but we feel
that it is very important for a reliable
intent-based system to have already at
this stage this check because if this
does not work your intent will never be
fulfilled and you will the risk is to
run steps here unnecessarily to lose
time whereas if you check this
immediately
you just have a system feedback and say
for example no not enough resources or
other reasons I am this does not cover
the no go on ok from the system due to
access right our policy user policy okay
so once you have once your you have the
ok regarding the resources the systems
the system computes the deployment plan
so you know theoretically that you have
several classes of servers on which you
can deploy your functions and this
functionality computes the deployment
plan so this I will not detail this what
this will be presented in December in
Dropcam and then once this is finished
so the system generates the ibis control
commands where Ibis stands for
intent-based application slicing so the
system genera
it's the commands it can also
progressively have several sets of
commands that map to given sets of
instruction and then once it is ready
these commands are sent to this
functionality which is the iPass control
this work function and the other blue
function belong to the network operation
space and in this framework I also have
outlined here are the the blocks in
different colors and this corresponds to
intent fulfillment so intent fulfillment
is the block for intent fulfillment are
surrounded by grey with grey and the
function the function blocks for intent
assurance are surrounded with blue so
once the instructions already they are
sent to the iPass control and this
entity is able to talk to all the
management functions so the the intent
framework here
hence over the action and the commands
to control functions that's where the
intent scope stops in in all other
proposed view for ott intents and here
you can see that you have something that
is named live intent because the one
main implementation for Sdn controller
is on us and you have this famous ad on
us intensive which are encapsulate s--
quite complex computation for
connectivity but in our sense here for
ott it can be considered as too
technical
because somebody who requests a costumer
who requests to deploy a slice for I
don't know agriculture has no clue of a
hostname and port number and stuff like
that
but the system here at this layer at
this level this function is able to talk
to other controllers and this one this
one function does have the skills to
express an intent which is much more
technical and these technical intent can
also seem very abstract to the
southbound of a controller so just the
the first conclusion of this framework
is that already we already have the
complexity although this is considered
as a basic example because you just have
one request that is expressed on the
northbound ok so I will rush so this is
the proposed framework and how it fits
to with the concepts and what we think
we should be added so basically control
function that warranty that you have
their availability resources and also at
this level verification and validation
and for example so I'll skip this this
is how the the intent is expressed using
just parameters a parametric model so
typically regarding the assurance the
validation is done here by just
verifying the traffic it can be done in
two-way verifying that the traffic is
flowing and that the expected traffic
pattern regarding growth for example a
scalability is respected another way of
where validation or assure another
assurance function
is to verify that there is no problem
with a with the resources consumption
and so here so and this and that this is
to validate the dimensioning rules that
have been used and the last function
here is to verify just make a pose we
are starting to run late again I think I
think that as a criticism early on that
ethic just a question so you ask you a
question you answer quickly and then I
think you need to rush to the okay what
is emergence traffic one more slide back
yeah what is emergence traffic it's big
bursts of traffic emergency uh-oh sorry
yeah
this is a typo I'm sorry yeah okay so
okay so this is another another way of
valid a buddy dating the system there I
think there is a need for specifying
validation functions at several level
even looking at the how long you take so
by the way the set up time was like a
couple of minutes even if this is very
system specific of course this can be
used again to verify that the the slice
has been correctly deployed so matching
this again against expected results and
this is something that is very that was
discussed in Montreal as well this is
something that is very useful I think in
this intent framework and in the work
that is being defined here is define
some targets and look at what happens
and compare maybe adjusting the target
but now and then decide should I adjust
my system should I adjust my target so
the challenge is here
is that okay this was a very basic
example although very complex because
involving several clouds or classes of
clouds and several functions but this is
basic and we we believe that in real
life the the system the deployments are
much more complex you in real life you
have several you have a constellation
you may have a constellation of such
deployments and the the big I mean there
is a lot of work still to be done on
what I just presented but the big
concern is what happens if I have a
several such system interacting with
themselves what happens if for example I
talked to several controllers to five
different implementation of controllers
so there's a lot of work that is needed
to be able to to send correctly my
instruction to these controls how do I
know that the controlling function I
talked to has understood my my request
and how do I expose how how can
different system expose a request that
can be at some point not immediately but
at some point understood by all system
and you can have you can look at the
feedback slides if you like if you like
some more details so I think I am done
okay quick comment please well I first
of all I like the acronym do you know
what I see means paying I see you know
what I see it's application slicing no
no but I mean in Spanish when do we say
it means this way so I like it just know
yeah and now with the
and another thing that I like is that
you mentioned topology here because it's
something that I have always believed is
essential and composition that's two
things that let me let me go to my notes
if we have running out of time there's a
question
drew are defining as a slice the unit
for intent right it's basically this but
you have not defined the slash you just
say is the application of slice intent
how do you define a slice okay the slice
is the set of cloud and network
resources that is allocated to run this
this application I mean in this it was
very basic and typically the slice was
specified by the chain of functions and
replicas that we use to run this
application and together with the budget
of infrastructure resources
okay so is computing plus Network
end-to-end application okay so I would
not use the term OTT but that's another
story that's yeah this sounds a little
bit that verse our deal with anyway
that's yeah maybe I may change the
terminology the point was that the
tenant is supposed to be a customer
already we use it in vertical so we
calls and that's well and the rest I
will keep talking about this okay
they are morons I have a you're
mentioning slice but I would I'm not
very interested in the intent on the
service topology then actually on the
slice I could have multiple different
service apologies within a single slice
can you repeat so when I deploy a
service
I'm creating a service topology and I
can have multiple service topology
within a certain slice because the slice
is defining me in the ministry
domaine but the actual service will be
defined you know by the application on
top of the service topology yes I'm you
know viewing the slides just as an
administrative domain a set of resources
that is given to a to a an entity to
have control over that
I completely agree and I see your point
this presentation completely skips the
aspect of whether I would call the
definition set of the application that
definition set of the intent that's yet
another issue to to tackle but so in
this presentation yes indeed we only
consider we well this is a very basic
example and we on purpose we started
like a zero point with no complexity
regarding where do I deploy this and we
and the as I said the the definition set
the topology up abstraction and what you
can already request and have as
constraint regarding the topology where
you I mean the infrastructure when you
want to deploy your service that's yet
another problem ok
[Music]
thank you all right the pink cross be
difficult not to move but okay so what I
want to present here this is service
assurance for intent-based networking so
words come from
at the last Montreal meeting we spend
like a day of any margin intent and I
say to explain a couple of concept there
in the end I wrote the slide about it
the way we have to understand this is
okay if we want we want to use to what
you do service assurance other as a way
to do close the automation and maybe
solve the antenna later that's the way
you have to understand that I presented
those two draft in upset ability already
so the issue that that we have is that
okay we configure a service as an
operator great it's configure it doesn't
mean it works correctly then we're
telling we could be sending all the
telemetry you know data like he do
machine learning etc and we've got the
issue of the needle in the haystack what
are we trying to do operators they want
you know one or service degrades where
is the fault and it could be an easy one
like the faces down this is the root
Coast but most of the time we need to
have the centum of what's happening and
we to do some more analysis the second
thing I'd like to do is when a network
component fails which service are
impacted typical data center issue of a
D&C CMP issue and we've got no clue what
the services are which one are impacted
so we know the end goal would be like
self-driving self-healing networks with
the closed loop automation we could take
a top-down approach the creative way
it's a nice concept but that works
mainly for a Greenfield deployment and
in my world of operators well it's not
that easy so let's try to service
differently by trying to decompose the
the issue of assertions into smaller
components
trying to assure those smaller
components one by one now if we combine
his approach with the end-to-end cinetic
traffic test then we have a complete
view of the disservice if we only take
the synthetic traffic then we have a
kind of black box view of the network
we've got no clue where the issue is and
we need to drill down into the different
components and assure them and to know
where where it is so a couple of
concepts in the draft so the concept of
the assurance graph where we've got like
a service which is source instance sorry
which is decomposed into sub services
typically for a very simple example here
a tunnel that depends on both sources
Nishant or interfaces that depends on
physical interfaces that depend the
respective devices right and same thing
for connectivity so if you could assured
those subservice types right then we
could infer the the score the highest
score of the service and we could also
report a series of symptoms up to the
health of the of the service now for
that obviously in an assurance graph we
have like two type of dependencies the
one that are impacting well if the
device is down obviously interface is
down to nourish down and etc if the
interface is down same thing so these
are the easy ones what is more
interesting is maybe not more
interesting but the most applicable is
informational dependencies who are in
this example I just put ecmp
right so I've got the multiple paths in
my EMP group and then one of them is
buddy behaving is my service impacted
what it depends is the answer that's why
we have this as informational
dependencies so what we knew so far if
we know the Ashwin's graph and if we
know the house of the different
components in there we know were default
s or at least to start with were its
not because everything is Halcyon green
except a couple of points we could start
by investigating those components we
know also the symptom for the root cause
now because I've got the three in one
direction I've got it also in the
reverse direction which is something
interesting I see this component my
network is failing or degrading and I
know the impact on all the services that
are configured now this is the
architecture let me quickly go over it
we've got like a service configuration
Orchestrator I made difference between
this one configuration and the one for
assurance which is the sin of castrator
so we extract the service and this is
for us a starting point for the intent
so we don't go from declarative right we
try to extract it from the from the
service now from there we did use the
assurance graph and we go in this
architecture with some agents that are
doing the mapping between the graph
itself and the actual metrics that are
occurring on the device or the devices
and that that agent query so it creates
like a health status which is composed
of the score itself of each component
and the symptoms and we send that via
telemetry back to the configuration
that's where we could do closed loop
automation if we know exactly which sub
component is is degrading so if we don't
do it by component and we say okay the
service is filling what do we do do we
reconfigure it well not quite right
there are a situation between but this
is the point now this is a flexible
architecture were both orchestrators the
one fresh trans configuration could
obviously be the same box and same thing
for the the agent which could be in the
Box in the router or not now it's also
it must be an open architecture right if
we solve this one for a single vendor
great but not many networks every single
vendor and how do we do this with a yang
module obviously for me a yang mode
using API and we can recommend this yang
module for multiple service types and
for vendors
cific information these are two arrows
in there in red that where we opened the
API we could read and configure the
assurance tree and also we could send
that telemetry to the score and there
are the symptoms what we're not doing
here is trying to get the kind of
standard ARS Orchestrator or open source
Orchestrator and also the expression
that are used to say this is how we we
get the house of you know data plane is
is not in there but this actual
architecture should be open so this is
the full yang module I don't want you to
look at it this way but I want you to
just read it through Omni what is in
blue there so even if you don't want to
go into details of Yang you want to
understand that we are able to configure
this tree and augment it right this
assurance tree with multiple service
types and that's a way to do it you want
to understand from the yang module that
we could get the house score and
symptoms per sub service type an ID and
this is what we're going to push to to
the character for the closely automation
you want to understand from the yang
module that you can create your own sub
services with your own parameters
obviously a parameters what is this if
I'm doing the house of this device this
device ID if I'm doing the health of an
interface this is that interface on that
device ID so the parameters will be
different and finally you want to
understand that we could open this even
with some vendor specific sub services
which in the end will happen anyway even
within a single vendor we have different
platforms for example coming back this
an example of the device health and I
think I've been fast enough as you want
it to provide discussion which is more
interesting so this is the time to to
discuss this and get your feedback I
received quite some feedback already
from from operators in the ops aw gee so
up to you now for more feedback if you
want I love your questions as a
participant I will see that the Asturian
graph can be used I mean you can map it
into our internet life cycle in the
phase of your service where you want to
you have already decomposed your intent
and you want to be able to monitor what
corresponds to an intern so to make the
way up so I think this could be a we
could use that as an example of a
technique that can be used to fulfill a
step of the life cycle I think it's a
valid contribution in that sense a
question I would have is where do you
see what do you do the relationship is
the intent I mean the input intent I
mean where would you with your proposal
fit in a kind of intent architecture so
I have to redo this version of your
draft that for me okay
my personal view and then the answer to
your question I never liked the term
intent because it's fuzzy to me at least
when I speak to you to operators now
however I I take the beginning of an
intent starting from the service
definition which I get from the
orchestrator configuring the service and
most of the time those services are at a
specific type I want to do an l2 VPN an
ultra P and I want to do that vnf and
for a specific service type then we
could just reduce from the configuration
of it the start of the intent
make sense thank you
[Music]
judgments your abstract there's a layer
that's missed it cannot be an intent or
and l3 VPN l3 VPN is an implementation
of intent so again there should be to
your question layers that could consume
internists coming from the user and tell
the the way data model is built look I
need you to implement particular intent
as LCVP and our evpn or sometimes
so I would agree with that someone need
to maintain all the bindings and
actually expose northbound what intent
is and normalizing down to the data
model but it should be in terms of
instantiation I agree that's why I
mentioned where the the Intendant could
be defined
it's a vague term right it could be
defined and user from the from the order
from the SLA from this technology or I
don't even care energy so I would agree
with that I wouldn't call it wake
because you just bill kind of bottom
there and if you go bottom up you could
start building bindings given on Ted of
technologies that are available to our
definition of service but in business
terms not l3 VPN our villain terms I
agree Alex trim yeah I think actually
the dependency graph and those sort of
things I don't think it's specific it
and clearly but I think it's more widely
applicable but one question that I would
have I think it raises the other day as
well as actually how do you maintain
this dependency graph I think this seems
to be one of the key things that you
basically yeah that you capture do you
basically establish them as part of the
provisioning basically you have
basically additional operations there or
do you discover them or how do you how
do you maintain them and I think this
will be one of the practical issues
perhaps with this so it's both part of
the configuration and both discovered
you know if I take for example if I rely
on ecmp for service we're not going to
configure a CMP part of a service right
if we if we're depending on ice is or
SPF we're not going to configure si as
part of a service definition is done by
a different group right so it's part
partly what you get from the search
definition and what you get from a
network and yes you have to maintain it
and please we are a bit over time thank
you Bruno and for the comments and the
presentation but we would like to give
also enough time for Dan to make his
presentation if you have further
questions please on the mailing list or
after the session thank you
cool thanks okay so 33.3% less time
approximately great okay so I'm dropping
down a little bit from decorative slash
intent looking at imperative policy now
this was a piece of work that was
presented in net mod earlier this week
so apologies if you attended that
session there's going to be some slight
repetition here but just wait for the
final slide and hopefully I'll try to
put the discussions the context of the
nm RG so we don't really need to spend
any time I think talking about ECA
you're all sort of highly aware of flick
ability of ECA for applying policy to
technology selection service deployment
may be resource usage just a reminder
actually that for some of you you may be
have been aware of a previous working
group super simplified use policy
abstraction which look to sort of
harmonize some of the imperative policy
usage across various technologies in the
ITF unfortunately we never actually
managed to publish a data model we just
couldn't constrain the problem space
enough even for ECA and apply it but we
did actually have some success with
publishing a framework so there is an
RFC that was published by the ISE so as
you're kind of discussing or continue to
discuss intense and the you know I've
looked at a couple of the documents that
the NMR do is working on now you may
also want to look at that super
documents although it is does talk about
sort of two information models one is a
general-purpose information model the
other is an ECA BAE
information model so going back to net
mod essentially what we wanted to do
with this document was treat it as a
gravity world and pull some of the
philosophical
Fissel of some of the general discussion
of eca
out of the data model solution work so
in terms of what are the use cases how
do you define the process how do you
manage a condition and event and an
action where do you store the state what
type of language might you apply or how
you would not all the tree to actually
implement the logic how you handle
notification things like policy
management rule management and policy
resolution especially in the case of
conflict or competing rules you know all
of these are actually quite important
aspects and not necessarily discussion
that you want to have in the solution
documents themselves so that's why we
kind of put together this framework
document and you don't necessarily
implement the framework you just use it
you know for your your own maybe sort of
vendor or operator specific
implementation so it doesn't necessarily
give you an exact guide of how to
implement ECA obviously into your
network the document also talks about
some implementation considerations
around operations and security and I
noticed that earlier today security was
kind of mentioned I think in Alex's
documents as an open issue but it was
also it seems to be an open issue as
well in terms of discussion in the
intent classification document so there
may be some text that we could actually
build on that's actually used in this
document now because we're kind of
constrained on time for for this
presentation I'm not going to go to all
of these slides what you could do
offline is if you're interested in the
framework document is kind of take a
look at some of the questions that we're
asking at the moment so you know things
like the preparation of ECA rules are
scheduling delegation cataloging how you
manage state is essentialized as a
distributed is a combination of both yes
probably depends on the application and
and if each of those actually represents
almost another set of decision trees and
sort of some fairly complex systems
management again things that you
probably don't want to specifically
describe in a solution document ie the
data models themselves so this this
document may never be published actually
in net Mott it may have a time horizon
of six months and then we just kind of
close it down it was just a way to kind
of consolidate discussion rather than
just flooding the mailing list that may
mean actually that we could use some of
the the text for ongoing work in the NMR
g which are kind of get to in just a
couple of moments i think another big
important area that will probably
require further study is managing
conflict when you're trying to apply
policies now Ben was just kind of talked
about sort of service assurance and
applying almost kind of a hierarchy of
ECA rules you know which which could
actually be if you think about recursive
ECA that in a sense is decorative intent
you're essentially starting at a high
level you're noticing aggregation of a
particular service or application
traffic and then you're gonna drop down
through a hierarchy of ECA rules in
order to identify a specific attribute
potentially that's causing a problem
where
it's packet last or just aggregation of
signal or application traffic and there
are going to be sort of there's gonna
have to be some kind of control of sort
of what you enable and when you enable
it and you obviously don't want to break
your network as well so all all of these
things are actually sort of really
important I mentioned that the the
document in net mod also has some sort
of implementation considerations
discussion text so these around
operations and security
so here again in terms of database
management
so using ECA how do you authorize it you
know how do you manage who has access or
how you delegate a particular ECA to a
device who's allowed to do that when are
they allowed to do that
what kind of method would you use in
order to apply that policy we also sort
of highlight some database discussion as
well specifically the various states of
data so what are we looking for in the
NMR G currently well not much really
just sort of highlighting that this
particular document exists and then it
points to some of the solution work
obviously it's it's low level it's
imperative policy usage but it may make
a lot of sense actually to consider how
this work I you know II see a maps to
intent you know your things like intent
classification or service insurance so
documenting the relationship between
some of the net mod work and some of the
discussion that we're having in this
document to existing NMR G discussion
documents although they are individual
efforts at the moment you know could be
of interest and also a piece of work
that I'm working on currently under the
UK project called NGC di which has
converged digital infrastructure it's an
EP SRC funded project so not
european-wide just focused in the UK
we're actually looking at ECA
implementations we're establishing what
kind of devices could we apply ECA
against and essentially a device isn't
just a router or some kind of forwarding
or functional element but it's a limited
controller in you may be in a very sort
of specific technology domain comprising
of a couple of notes and actually what
we're doing there is also trying to
identify what are the applicable
languages the rules what is the current
arch how widely deployed are they are
they applicable for all types of ECA
obviously not so we are looking at
network and resource and database
management and just trying to classify
them thanks Dan for very being very
concise questions to the presentation
from done quick Diego yes developers
again not just Mark III I think I agree
with I would say yes to most of the
questions there or to all of the
questions I think it's interesting is
interesting among other things because I
agree with them that is not everything
is suitable for ITF activity but it's
interesting here especially because ECA
probably is the best way we have to
discuss about what I would call
low-level intent or base intent or
whatever we call it in the previous
presentations we'll be talking about
precisely through a conflict resolution
reasoning etc and reasoning about how
this is translated and how different
sources of intent and different channels
this is something that would help and
well would help us well to understand
better what we are referring when we
talk about intent this is something
interesting so definitely yes
and if we can translate this into some
kind of easy a framework document happy
supported them probably probably help
with it cool yeah great text is even
better yeah and I think especially for
question two this is something I
indicated to Dan through some exchange
that I think a good starting point could
be positioning we offer the kind of
internal proto intern framework you have
your ETL framer proposal I really think
that there is a link between the two
where ECI is kind of end of the chain
application of an intent could be
interesting to see how the two maps if
there are gaps how they get into work so
potential interesting questions to
discuss and again if you translate into
documents even better for IHF or IETF
thank you very much cool we at the end
of the session time thank you very much
for the presenters first all the good
questions and comments especially for
the to last presentation since they were
also linked to draft that are being
proposed in the IETF I would propose
that the offers can send an already been
done partially but send the draft to the
nlg mailing list and ask for opinion
from the group a way to maintain some
kind of relationship between this
different bodies of work I think it's
interesting proposal and I we really
would like that it doesn't stops after
this meeting so maybe try to entertain
some some some discussions thank you
again we have a session also tomorrow
last session of the meeting so please
join us there will be discussion on
relation I mean use of artificial
intelligence for network and also some
feedback on the side meeting and
discussion on the Charter thank you see
you tomorrow see you tomorrow thank you
if if you are not signed the blue sheets
they are here on the table don't forget
to sign the blue sheets