yes hello hello welcome to the perigee
session thank you for coming everyone
get right into it
there's no well I'm sure you've already
seen this from the morning session if
you haven't please familiarize yourself
with this keep in mind going forward for
the session a couple of Ministry of
notes before we get started
blue sheets are somewhere up here did
you pass and run we will pass the blue
sheets around please fill them out we
need to jabber scribe we do okay great
as well as a minute taker oh great
excellent
[Music]
this is the agenda pretty sure for we're
gonna couple presentations from sort of
researchers in the area and then some
individual draft presentations does
anyone have any comments or adjustments
they'd like to make before we get
started so I think
so Joe offered to do a quick update for
one of the adopted jobs that we have
either maybe come up so Joff censorship
is an adopted RG draft and Joe offered
to like give a quick overview and update
yeah so this is a draft that's been
alive for a very long time I've made
absolutely no progress since the last
IETF because I changed jobs and my job
now is been uh difficult so to speak but
anyway I have a list of issues I think I
just threw in the chat I may not have
hit return Christian if you want to hit
return on my computer they'll post but
I'm hoping to get through those in
December and that's I guess the update
thanks already thanks Joe
when the update comes you going to take
a look provide some feedback on the list
and that would be helpful going forward
with that we can get into the
presentations of the presenter for the
first talk could please come up this
professor Shoukri here do we have
professor Liu do you want to go first
perfect
and from scripts and you thank you for
imitation and today I will share our
research on privacy preserving my home
oh home amorphic encryption and my talk
was divided into two paths first ever
introduced some Merrick back ones of
homo encryption and then I reintroduce
the main applications of homework
encryption and now let's begin with the
first part
okay that's simple definition what is
homophily encryption and both of these
tours are variations for example
encryption is the process of encoding of
a message and a meaningful message into
randomness like message for example we
can use the side Caesar cipher I used
which was invented about 2,000 years ago
and in this encoding the message welcome
to NTU can be transformed to a
meaningless message
the key is dusta to shift every
character three positions and what is
homomorphism home of ism is a structure
preserving map and that's it will
preserve the Arabic breaker structures
and combined it together
we'll get the whole mafia encryption so
that's the definition of homogeneous and
if we can preserve the arabika structure
then we get the home of encryption that
means if we have the mass encryption of
the message one to message N and also a
function f we can just simply computed
the unencrypted data and the get the
encryption of F F M like this so now we
have the definition of how much
encryption it's a special kinds of
encryption algorithm that supports
subtext the computation and there are
mainly two types of hama encryptions and
the first type is a partial homomorphic
encryption and the second type I is
fully Houma in Houma encryption and for
the first the type it's only support
single operations such as addition or
multiplication and it was used the in
data aggregation or some construction of
MPC protocols and it is very easy to
design such a kind of algorithm and but
for the second type of form of
encryption the follicle mark encryption
we required to support unlimited numbers
of operations and it can both supports a
multiplication and addition and a little
surprise it is very difficult to design
such kinds of encryption algorithms it
was named at the holy grail of the
cryptography area and remains at the
open problem of about 30 years and it
does result of our entry in 2009 and
between these two types of form of
encryption there are many method helps
of algorithms for example the humorous
some words home of encryption
it's a keen supporter limited the
numbers of operations and it is also
widely used in the area of privacy
protecting okay said this is a brief
history of home of encryption
I taste nearly as old as the public
encryption itself it was first proposed
in 1978 and after 30 years development
the First Folio movie encryption
occurred and after that's about ten
years we have the folio moving here they
were developed a very quick light and
then now we have many public
implementations which we can get from
the github oh and and elsewhere and the
standardization process is already
underway and for the standardization for
the partial home of encryption we
already have a standard that was
published by ISO this year it includes
two algorithms which is the exponent
show alchemist encryption and the pad
encryption algorithm and for the case of
fully homomorphic encryption and the
researchers and the government have
already organized for workshops
processing and okay this is a list of
the mainly current open source libraries
for home of encryption and and for
integer or finished field operations we
have Cu an HD lab and on the hand rhythm
and for the bullying gates operation we
have tfhe in the effort aw and this our
alpha baker in the internet we can get
so freely
now to use the Hamoui encryption in real
applications the most factor we care
about is the performance and that there
are mainly three kinds of operations the
integer arithmetic and the proxy proxy
the arithmetic and the bull engage and
for arithmetic operations currently we
have very fast computations are integers
or fixed point numbers for limited atoms
of operations if we want to achieve
unlimited time approaches then I took
was not that efficient because of the
slope the scraping technique currently
and for bullying circles the
bootstrapping is seems very fast for
example we need 13 milliseconds for one
operation of the n kind of gates but
since any real application if we
constructed by using the boolean gate
gates and it may take many gaze
operations so the real applications may
be less efficient now let's see some
tests the results of the different kinds
of libraries if we want to do the
integer addition or multiplication for
example we want to do the integer
addition then we can use the exponential
argument or pallium or just simple
lettuce based encryption and the
performance is very good of example we
only need to one microsecond for the
exponential argument and the women need
eight microseconds for the Palio and
less than one microseconds for the
lettuce based encryption but this three
kinds of libraries cannot support the
operation of a multiplication and if we
want to support some multiplication then
it will be less efficient
for example the seal library King
completes the interior edition in six
micro second and also for one
millisecond for the operation of
multiplication and if we want to do
unlimited operations of addition and
multiplication then we can use the AG
lab it may takes five milliseconds for
the addition and about 200 milliseconds
for multiplication
it is much slower and if we want to do
the interior addition by using the basic
boolean gates then it takes about one
second to complete the addition
operation and about 20 seconds for
multiplication so it's much slower with
the bullen's also the boolean circuit is
Matsuura but we can construct any kinds
of operation by using the blowing gates
for example we can design the the
circular for integer addition and the
flows number addition and subtraction
and a multiplication or even the square
root operation or the sine function or
the exponential function that we can
construct any kinds of functions by
using the bull engage and it is much
slower for example the exponential
function may takes about 100 and some
save for our seconds okay and now let's
begin the second parts how to use
homomorphic encryption to provide the
privacy protecting generally speaking we
can solve the piracy problem by using
home of folly for Morgan who very simply
the frame worker is firstly in the first
step we just encrypt our data's and then
we do any kinds of operations on the
cipher text and finally our the user
does that to decribe to the surf text
and get the results of the computation
so
it is very simple but this kind of
realization it's always not very
efficient of our real applications and
so we need to design different kinds of
protocols are specific protocols for
different kinds of applications for
example in the data collection data
retrieval is a sharing and a determining
we may need to design the protocol of
data aggregation private information
retrieval and private set intersection
and the privacy preserving computation
protocols to design these kinds of
protocols we may use many kinds of or
primitives and for example the
differential privacy technique the
searchable encryption function
encryption on even the oblivious Ram and
the searching secret of sharing and
oblivious transfer or garbled circuit
today we are mainly focused on the
common morphic encryption now let's
begin with the very simple application
that's in occurs in the data collection
and the left a the famous feature
published the banister it shows that the
power usage gets from the smart meters
may leak the information of the users
what you are doing your home for example
from this video when we get the
information that the user may be get up
in the morning before AIDS and prepare
his breakfast and then washing and then
about went to eat his lunch and went to
get to sleep so in this scenario we need
to aggregate the data the power usage of
each hot work each user and get a
summarizations and send this
summarization to the control center and
this is mainly the most simple and the
most mature application of home
encryption in this case the online needs
additive homem of encryption for example
we can just add the usage of each harm
together and according to the tables
previous we can see that addition is
very efficient and in case of data
retrieval for example the user want to
get some public database access some
public database although the data itself
is public but the access pattern will
leak the privacy of the users for
example if we are access patented
database then the server may know what
kind of product this company will be
playing that you two took to construct
and theoretically we made it seem that
we may add only way it is to get
download all the details in the database
because even if one item is not touched
that then the server may know that the
user is not interest on these kinds of
data and so this is very efficient
previously we can solve this problem by
using multi servers and we need to
assume that these servers I will not
concluded together to recover the
privacy of the users but this kind of
assumption is not reasonable for most of
the real applications so let's see how
to protect the privacy by using
homomorphic encryption that the user
only need to encrypt every index by a
separate text and for the item he want
to get he does the encrypt one for
example that the eyes index and for all
other index he just encrypt 0 and then
the server will multiply each data to
the ciphertext
and we know that for for the index I the
X I will be encrypt this position will
get in quick encrypt of XII for our
other positions will be the encrypt of
Bureau then this server summarize all
the staff tags together and only to send
one ciphertext to the user and then the
user can be grabbed it and it gets what
he wants so in this simple protocol and
the server that the communication pen
wise that the server sent back to the
user is only one ciphertext but the
users do need to send many subtext to
the server we can optimize this protocol
are very simply for example we can
divide the potatoes in the server into
one hundred blocks and in this case the
user only need to send one hundred the
ciphertext and the server all like I
need to send over one hundred suffer
texts the back so instead of sending
about to us to a ten thousand subtext in
this case we all I need to send 200 a
server text is a balance between the
truth passes and we can make if we use
the most of the more powerful form of
encryption we can make this project
still simpler in this case the user only
need to encrypted enix I want only one
self text and this server for each index
he doesn't finish the compare operation
and if i equal to j then it will be
encrypt of one and for all other
positions it will be in subtext of zero
so and he still summarize all the
subtext the NS and the results back so
in this protocol we only need two to
ciphertext
and communication bandwidth is very
efficient but we have already seen that
fall aha moment inclusion may be not
that efficient so we can improve this
protocol by our very careful design of
macedon coding methods we can encode the
message instead of encrypted the message
directly we just encrypted it to a
polynomial for time limits
I will not have enough time to describe
the technical details so I would like at
this equation and in this case we only
need the additive hormone encryption and
to complete the Equality test and
achieve the bandwidth efficiency and the
computation physician together this a
more complete scenario maybe the user
want to outsource his data to the server
in this case all the data's X is also
the encrypt a safer text and in the last
scenario it is a plain text so in this
case we may need to to do much more
about the design of the protocol and the
encoding to avoid the usage of
multiplication and only use the
computation for additional home of
encryption and makes the protocol and
more efficient and in this case
besides the operation of a read
operation the user may be want to update
his data's stored on the server then the
writes operation may also leak his
privacy so to protect this kind of
privacy we mainly the more complex
oblivious Ram techniques and I will not
describe that this thing here ok that's
the case of a data retrieval not let's
say that they are the case of for data
sharing in this case Alice and Bob both
have to
parrots at it assess and they want to
computer the intersection it is a very
simple as Nauru obviously we can solve
this problem by using the hash function
for example Alice just said that each of
his value the hash value of each of his
data to Bob and Bob send back each value
the hash value to Alice and then each of
them every of them can just compare the
hash values and to find out their
intersects but this protocol is notice
cure forgiven boy if the the space of
Alice and Bob's in the setter is not big
enough then we can search all the
possible inputs and find that data's and
we can also we can resolve this problem
by using a very different exchange like
protocol and this is secure but as in
Bob also needed to many to do many kinds
of module exponential computations which
is very time-consuming and with himavan
homomorphic encryption we can intend
only a few more minutes okay okay ah
that's the finish so we can we can
design a particle based hormone-free
encryption and to the Equality test and
LSD dances and the encryption which is
data and the Bob does this - every of
his data and the multiplayer random
number if X is equal to ID and Alice
will gets the encryption of Bureau and
if X is not equal to Y and Alice will
get a random number so he'll find out
their intersections okay with the
quality tests that we designed in the
data retrieval protocol we can design
our more efficient protocol to come to
resolve this kind of for applications
and finally is the privacy preserving in
this money
the two phases in neural networks and
the training phase and the prediction
phase and the remaining folks on the
prediction phase because the training
phase is self in the plain text is still
very time-consuming and but the
prediction is in plain text it's
efficient now and the the first step we
need to analyze what kinds of
competitions we'll need in application
of neural networks for example the
commercial convolution there's is a
simply the computation of matrix
multiply a vector and the loot layer ok
is we need to comparison in this
direction and in the for connection they
are we also need computation of matrix
multiply vector and so we can design a
very simple protocol to complete the
computations based on the bullying
bullying gates although we can see that
it is very inefficient and we can
achieve the operation of the linear
operation by using additive homo be
inclusion but in this case we cannot
compute the active layer or the signal
or the redo function by using the
additive home encryption this is what we
are still research now and ok friendly
it were concluding with komova
encryption firstly we can achieve the
bull and circular gates at the X or in
the end and the arithmetic addition and
multiplication and with these rhythms we
can achieve many any kinds of algorithm
or bullying
circuit and then we can so any kind of
generic or some problem with a generic
resolution and we also can design as
basic approach calls for each kinds of
applications and we can get efficient
solutions okay thank you
all right yeah unless anyone has a very
very quick question or comment perhaps
we can move on to the
presentation thank you very much for
coming can the presenter for the first
presentation come up yes thank you
alright ah hello everyone
and you need to stay in the thinker's oh
here alright ok it's for the benefit of
the remote people my name is Reza I'm an
assistant professor at NUS I run the
data privacy and transporting machine
learning lab and today I'm going to talk
about the privacy risks of machine
learning but I need to start with how
does this ok perfect so I need to start
with a very important concept of
inference attacks if you have some data
about individuals it's possible to
combine it with some other information
and use advanced statistical methods or
machine learning algorithms to infer
further information about those
individuals this has been shown many
times in the research community and on
different types of Delta for example on
Facebook Likes you can infer information
about personal data and also it could
help to identify whose data is in the
data set for example for location data
you just give me five random locations
from their trajectories you are almost
unique in the world
alright so this is a this is basically
the main risk of sharing the data itself
either it can infer some sensitive
information further than what is already
in the data or identify the individuals
in the data set so there has been a lot
of efforts on how to protect data
privacy data sanitization through
removing sensitive information or
removing identities has been one idea
but and there's a huge business on this
by anonymizing data but what is missing
there is you know what is the definition
of privacy because the bad news is that
by removing identities or sensitive
information
from the data you don't make the data
privacy preserve okay anonymous data or
anonymized data isn't but there is not
anonymized which means that the attacker
can link the anonymize data to the true
identities of the entities in the data
set or is not data anymore which means
that you have to destroy it so much to
break the link between identities and
the data basically what happens is that
an attacker has some background
information that links it with the data
that you release to infer information
about the data which is not in the
release information right and this can
go for like different types of data and
recently we have also shown that machine
learning algorithms can extract patterns
from the data even it has been
obfuscated a lot so if you see this kind
faces in the that are used for
anonymizing data it's not anonymous
anymore
so machine learning models can can
reconstruct the identity of individuals
so in general this is what I call
inference avalanche there is some piece
of information that is released there is
some information that the attacker has
combined together can lead to more
inference about the individuals whose
data was used for a computation and
doesn't matter what type of computation
I'm going to give you some information
about at an oil statistics and machine
learning and for example for for
statistics you have some data you want
to release many statistics about the
data records in your data set the
attacker can run an inference attacker
to identify which data sets could have
produced these statistics and as you
increase the number of statistics that
you about your data set the plausible
later said that could have produced
these data 6 reduces and some of them
have higher probability of being the
true original data set and it has been
shown that the attacker can actually
reconstruct the via the full data set
with
negligible error as the number of
statistics increases even if the
statistics are noisy a little bit all
right or it can be used to identify
whose data was using the in the data set
for example NIH is to release the
statistical information about the DNA of
individuals who are in their data sets
so the allele frequencies if you're
familiar with the DNA data and from that
researchers managed to find out whose
data isn't that data set that resulted
in this summary statistics which are
very harmless right so just I'm just
releasing the average value of each
attribute but but if there are so many
of those statistics the attacker can
actually identify whose data is in the
data set and this had consequences a lot
of data holders now stop releasing their
data stop releasing the statistics about
their data and so on and so forth
now I just want to move to what is the
topic of this talk that I want to
briefly talk about and that is the
information leakage through machine
learning models right so you would say
well if I'm anonymizing data yeah there
are a lot of attributes which are in the
data set I understand how the attacker
can join this data set with some other
it is to reconstruct the identities if
you really as a statistics maybe I can
tell why this can lead to the inference
attacks but machine learning models even
those who design machine learning model
don't know why the machine learning
models work right so then how can an
attacker exploit the information which
is embedded in a machine learning model
to infer the data set that was used for
training of it so in a setting that we
have is that we have some data set and
that we use using some training
algorithms to construct a model that
does for example a classification for us
at the time of inference or the test
what you do is that you send some data
points and the model tells
you what is the probability of each
class associated to the data that you
have shared all right very simple very
useful there are a lot of services out
there machine learning as services
provided by cloud service providers
today that you don't even need to
understand how machinery works you just
upload your data they train a model for
you and then you have this very simple
API through which you can access it all
right and also you know we know that
machine learning is eating the world so
everyone is now using machine learning
for everything any data that they have
so it's very important to ask whether
the predictions that I get from the
model actually leak any information
about the data that was used to train
the model but note that at the time that
you get the predictions the data is gone
right so at first phase one we train the
model now in Phase two we just interact
with the model you send the query you
get a prediction right so how can this
leak information about the training data
I mean before that I need to clarify
what leakage means because when you
interact with a model you learn
information from the model right you
didn't know that this patient is
susceptible to cancer now you know you
didn't know whether you need to invest
in this plan or invest in the other plan
but now you know which one is more
important right you didn't know these
things before interacting with the model
so not any information that you learn
from the model is privacy violating so
what is leakage here if I can learn
something about you by interacting with
the model that I could have not learned
if you were not in the data set means
that the model is leaking information
about you right because if I get some
model and then I interact with the model
and I learned that you know half of the
population or male half of the
population or female it doesn't matter
if your data was there or not right so
this is just generic patterns about the
data but if I learned that the chance
that an individual particular individual
has cancer
but I couldn't tell that while just
looking at the general patterns of the
population means that the model is
leaking information about that
individual right so this is what we call
leakage and one more particular way of
measuring leakage is to tell whether by
interacting with the model I can tell
whether your data was used in the
training set of the model or not okay
and this is what we investigated as I
said there is machine learning as a
service Google Amazon markers of others
provide this data sorry this service and
you have no idea what models they
trained and the attacker has no idea to
tell what models they trained but it can
access the model through this API so
what we went and we designed an attack
that can tell with a very high accuracy
so for this data that was some customers
purchase data that was used to train a
model online on Google and Amazon
platforms with close to 90% accuracy you
could tell whether your record was part
of the training set or not and the only
access window of access to the model is
just a prediction I send a query get a
prediction and from that I want to tell
whether some particular data was part of
the training set or not so these are
award-winning set of algorithms tell us
that there is a huge risk of using
sensitive data while we're training
machine learning models so so that
because we don't know how the model is
trained therefore there is no way to
extract information about the model some
very simple statistics that I want to
show to you is that basically the models
are more confident on the data that they
have seen compared to the data that they
haven't seen and this piece of
information could be exploited by the
attacker right so the behavior of the
models with respect to the data that
they have seen during the training is
quite different from the behavior
the models with respect to the data that
they see for the first time right and
this is statistical difference could be
exploited by the attacker and this is
exactly what we explored if the model is
released for various reasons now you
hear about transparency in machine
learning so the yes okay on what model
do you use for certain decision-making
you might have even access to the model
parameters this is what we call the
white box access in the model you know
how the model come up with with a
decision and you know if you look at
these different types of machine
learning tasks they extract all sorts of
simple to very complex features about
the data that help you then later on
classify the data and what we ask is
whether the parameters of the model each
information for those of you who want be
interested in the techniques basically
there is a training algorithm there's an
optimization problem that we solve for
coming up with with a model and that
optimization problem the way that we go
through different values of the
parameters until we solve the the
optimization problem and we find out the
final model totally depends on the data
that was used for training them all so
the footprint of the data can be seen
and extracted from the model parameters
and this is exactly what we looked at
and again some other statistics that can
show that the behavior of the model
parameters with respect to training of
test data is different and what we did
was that we looked at where you will
generalize models out there the best
machine learning algorithms that are out
there for some benchmark data set and
what shows is that the ones that are
even the best in terms of accuracy that
generalize the best leak the most they
have huge capacity these machine
learning models have so many parameters
to embed the function that they want to
learn
and they use some of this capacity to
learn the task the rest is used to
memorize information and that's a
footprint right so we went through all
these different values of parameters by
looking at the data and later on the
attacker can can exploit this and in
fear whose data was in the training set
and even reconstruct the data that was
used during the training so today I'm
asking this question if you look at
different privacy regulations it says
that the personal data or any
information which are directly or
indirectly related to an identified
around at fybel natural person so
basically the information that can help
you to single out an individual and say
okay this is this this information is
related to this particular individual
and now I'm saying okay that the models
enable us to single out individuals from
any data and until ok this data was
using the training set now can we let me
just simply release models or use models
in the cases where some attacker can can
have access to it or on trusted entity
have access to it it's it's a it's a big
question is model
personal data should we treat models
similar to the way that we treat raw
data because what the attacks show is
that you can infer a whole lot of
information about the models from the
models about the training data right so
it's a big question here so I want to
just say a few words about what to do
right so as privacy experts the first
thing that that we do is to just
identify why you need to use the data in
what process and what is your trust
model do you trust the machine on which
you do the computation to trust the
entity that is going to see the the end
result of the computation what is a
trust model
and based on the trans model based on
why you want to use the data we can
design privacy-preserving computations
that protect against these kind of
inference attacks whether you're
outsourcing the data whether it's a
collaborative type of computation
whether you want to do data analytics or
you want to enable data release for
acceleration and visualization all of
these need different types of tailored
defense mechanisms so for privacy
tourism and computation in order to
protect against the attacks that I
mentioned what do we do do we need to
make a choice and one choice that we
make is to just say what I am I'm fine
if general patterns about the data set
are shared but I want to protect the
information about individuals right we
need to allow some information to be
shared otherwise the data is useless
right the computation is useless
so what computations what kind of
information do I allow to to be to be
communicated the general patterns the
ones that are not dependent on
individual records and at the same time
I want to protect information leakage
about individuals I don't want one data
point to significantly change the result
of the computation so that the attacker
can exploit in other words if you want
to go and collect data or convince the
customers or the data holders to provide
data for you for your computation you
want to tell them that well whether you
participate or you don't participate
right the information that someone can
learn about you by observing the results
of the competition is the same or more
or less the same right because you
helped us to learn the general patterns
but your specific patterns are not
leaked a few other techniques that I
refer to them as sharing without sharing
you have huge data set you want to
release this data set or you want to
learn something from the data set
instead of
sharing the data why not constructing
another data set which is very similar
but not the same as the original data
this is through the process of data
synthesis and the data synthesis itself
should be done in a privacy-preserving
manner so that the results the data set
that is release cannot be linked back to
the original data set right and we're
designing techniques that can probably
using mathematical rigor show that there
is no way to link back the release data
from the original data and nevertheless
you can infer you know you can construct
models on the synthetic data you can run
statistics on the on the synthetic data
and then use it for whatever purpose
that you another one is collaborative
learning and the idea is that and this
is this is very important because in
many cases we have many entities that
have data but but they don't trust each
other to share the data with each other
right but they have the same task
multiple banks multiple hospitals
multiple financial even different
departments in one organization and the
the platform that that you're designing
allows these different entities to learn
the same machine learning model together
without sharing the data with each other
but sharing some hints about how they
are constructing their models but in a
privacy-preserving manner so that those
hints also don't leak information about
the individual records in their citizens
these are just two examples of how we
can construct mechanism that can enable
privacy preserving computation I'll stop
here and be happy to take questions but
if you want you can also look at our
website to find out more about our
research results thanks
all right Thank You Reza are there any
questions like once going twice
ah that's away from dkg hi Daniel Kahn
Gilmore ACLU thanks for presenting this
year I think it's useful information and
background for folks to have at the IETF
especially as we move towards things
like software-defined networking and
other kinds of mechanisms that might
incorporate machine learning in ways
that I I'm personally kind of terrified
of I was curious about your point about
personal data whether you know if
there's any attempt to classify so one
of the things that gdpr and other
similar privacy regulations require or
want to encourage is the ability to have
your data removed from the data set and
I'm wondering if you think of models
machine learned models as potentially
containing personal data if anyone has
attempted to categorize different
machine learning models as models that
you could remove your data from that is
not only can your information be added
to the model to make the model more
accurate but that at some later date you
could take an existing model and and
knowledge about a person's information
and effectively remove them from the
data set is there any attempt to break
that kind of does the question make
sense yeah so basically there are two
ways to look at this problem right one
is by construction right when when I
include your data in the training set
can I minimize is the influence of your
data to the model so that somehow
approximately everybody's data is
removed already right so I learned the
general patterns but the information
about it in the individual or the
influence of each individual on the
model is bounded right so somehow
everybody's data is remove
except that like there is this small
epsilon information about each
individual which which which influences
the model so it is one way to to look at
it and the second way is well if I want
to totally remove all the bits of
information that you contributed to the
model can we provide the provable
guarantee that now your data is removed
for certain types of models is much
easier for complex models I don't know
such as deep learning there does not
exist a provable technique yet but but
people are working on it so this is a
problem that that researchers are
working on it on how to I shouldn't
prove that all the information about
your data is removed from the model
because otherwise you can just now
retrain the whole model but you don't
want to do that right so how can i with
minimal effort remove all the
information and prove the guarantee
proof yeah you can only retrain it if
you've actually kept all of your
training data around right in which case
you may that that requires you to store
even more personal data in order to
retrain with a smaller so you don't want
to retrain right so what I'm saying is
that overall you want to have minimal
effort but provable guarantee that the
data is completely removed if you train
it with differential privacy as this is
what we are we are doing now then the
the influence is already minimum okay so
how much more guarantee can you provide
then then that's an open question right
for complex models your chrysocolla
trying to put together this talk in the
last talk I know there's been a fair
amount of work on on trying to build and
there's been a fair amount work on
trying to build learning models that
don't involve the central server ever
having access to your specific data
using things like homework for
encryption dollars and more techniques
does that have any substantial impact on
this on this problem ie fuses techniques
you don't have to worry about release of
the models
or is that not solve the problem yes so
these are two different trust models
right so who the adversary is right is
the adversary the one who is doing the
computation or is the adversary the one
who is observing the result of the
computation right so what I was talking
about mostly is about the adversary's
observe the result of the conversation
all right so let's say for example if
you have a central server that blindly
trains the model for you later on you
use the model for certain applications
then the inference attack is against the
one who can observe the mulcher yeah no
I understand but I guess my question I'm
getting at is that many situations in
which the adversary is the is is is the
people doing them is the site which is
doing the training itself right which is
the machine learning site and that's why
you want these privacy-preserving
training systems and so I guess the
question I'm interested in is is that a
stronger model in the sense that if you
were in the formal sense of strong
namely that if you were protecting as
that model do you also protect against
this kind of attack no no no no okay so
these are two different types of attacks
basically one one is the attacker who
observes the other one is the one that
infers later on with whatever is or
catch you later yeah so you have n
numbers you want to compute the average
somebody computes the average for you
without seeing the numbers right
somebody observes the average value
right these are two attackers you don't
you want to hide the averaging but also
you want to hide the fact that my data
was used as one of these n data records
Thanks all right thank you as a
[Music]
presenter for the next hour come up
please Sandeep
hello can you owe me hello guys so this
is a talk about how we can improve
privacy preservation by using a method
of personal tagging it at the source so
let me start with some basics what is
log data so obviously so we all
understand log data is nothing but a
record of information activity of a user
system or an application so the lot of
devices application services do log the
information about the activity of the
user so log data is always useful to
many actors in the systems whether it's
a developer who can use it for debugging
troubleshooting purposes also it could
be operationally useful to monitor
system performance measurements Layton
sees and not and of course now nowadays
for marketing to do analysis on the
systems who understand what is the user
behavior what is the user usage of a
system of a service resource usage
metrics and things like that and a very
important obviously the use of log is
security monitoring so we all already
have a lot of tools which can consume a
lot of blocks and be able to determine
what happened to an event if there's a
security breach if there is a anti abuse
or a fraud so logs are very useful
source of information to go back track
and figure out what happened to the
system and what went wrong in the system
so this is a basic life cycle of a log
if you look at right from this
generation of the log to its
preservation it starts right from the
source where a user activity gets
triggered and it could be any
intermediary in the path looking at the
user flow as its forwarding it or
processing it so every system in the
path does contribute some information
about what is happening to the user and
what
system itself is doing with the user and
user activity typically we have many
devices in the system so that kind of
generate these locks and at the end of
the cycle comes the log preservation so
now the question is what you do with
some of the log data that you have
collected so there could be many
organizations do invest on tools that
have some kind of protection to the
locks that are generated because we see
a lot of locks now being shared with
third party services for either
monitoring or marketing purposes as we
saw so there is always an activity to
reform the log redact it in terms of the
data that the log already has and then
eventually give it to a third party or
outsource it to different vendors to
process the logs and then come up with
some interesting information so if you
look at the logs logs have been that for
many decades right so we have seen right
from the Network Devices to applications
generating the logs so what has
fundamentally changed from the log
semantics so obviously there is more
personalization of the log itself so
there is more applications that are
trying to pin the user information into
a log so obviously and another trend
that we are seeing is locks are no
longer just owned by an organization or
owned by a department in the
organization so it's more shared either
within the organization or across
boundaries or of course geographies as
well so largely for kind of purposes
that we already saw and and also the log
itself is no longer analyzed in in silos
so it's basically combined with other
events of the user or the system so
there's tools that can do indexing and
then come out with a common
understanding of what the user or a
system or a service is trying to do so
it's no longer just in silos
there is also cases where the log itself
can be vulnerable especially when
when you're sharing with the third party
services the log data can be vulnerable
which can result in sensitive data
leakage so obviously also app also has a
lot of regulations in terms of how you
handle your log data and how do you
share it with different parties so and
also a very important shift in terms of
the log usage is the monetization of the
log so just going from from monitoring
and management ability management to
monetization so what about privacy and
log so it's there are already
organizations that define log data as
part of their privacy policies they
basically address what which log data is
being collected how they're using the
log data and with whom they are sharing
a lot of vendors do provide that user
policy log usage policy but again the
shift is now towards more regulation of
the loss especially from a privacy the
privacy working groups are more focusing
and regulating the log itself the log
data itself so how so when we look at
log so we see a lot of challenges in
terms of how do you identify something
that is sensitive in a log how do you
protect the log so obviously is a lot of
ways in which we can process the logs
but at the same time it's very
subjective in terms of what a log what
is sensitive data for in a log so it's
something that the application knows
very well so this whether additional IP
addresses is something sensitive or
personal again it depends on how the log
is used and how it's collaborated with
other events in the system but at the
same time we are seeing a lot of vendors
providing various tools like machine
learning data set dictionary based
methods to actually go into the log read
the log and find out what is very
critical about the log and try to
provide a way to mask it or hide it so I
think if you look at what is happening
in terms of the privacy preservation or
data preservation in in locks so it it
requires some
kind of a framework that we see here
like right from this generation to the
point of preservation of privacy
preservation so it starts with log
generation so this is a kind of a
framework that we can envision in terms
of the whole privacy even you apply
privacy to the log it starts from the
generation where potentially you can tag
the log with some kind of a metadata so
some kind of an accession token or
whatever right then there are various
ways to do that so imagine if we can at
the source point to a system that this
data that I'm going to put it in a log
is going to be very sensitive or it's
has some degree of sensitivity to it
right and that in turn can go into a
detection system so where we don't have
to do any specific hard coding of course
you can complement this with other
existing methods and then be able to
detect what is private data or personal
data in the system and the log and then
be able to additionally define what you
want to do with the data whether you
want to remove the field from the log or
you just want to anonymize mask it or do
anything any actions specific to the log
so and also you can have different
actions defined to different fields in
the logs potentially so that's where we
saw it could be differential reduction
actions that you can enforce in the law
so based on that idea so the proposal
here is to look at a way in which the
source can define some kind of metadata
so as I said like which can potentially
indicate the interesting fields or
sensitivity fields within the log that
is being generated so most of us have
standard long formats that most
applications use so imagine if you can
add another framework or another data to
it saying that while you're defining
this log also look at what is going to
be sensitive in the log so if you if the
source can assert that within the at the
time of generation so it could be more
useful or more deterministic in the way
the data could be preserved or
policy enforced so this is a an approach
that we investigated where you can add
something like a PII data within a log
so it could be at the field level saying
that every field you can tag it with a
private true or false kind of indicator
or it could be at a log level where you
can enumerate all the variables or all
the identifiers in the log saying that
this the private feeds so this is not
something new that is happening with a
lot of precedence in terms of how or the
the whole method of identifying data so
I hear some vendors that are already
doing one way or the other so the so
each one has of course its own way in
syntax or a CLI that they define to
pretty much define what private data is
in a what constitutes a private data and
in a log so this is of course a proposal
that has been submitted so we'll be
welcome to get feedback on what you
think in terms of this problem statement
so here is some hackathon results we
just try to put it together and try to
compare it but one of the reg X based
approaches so obviously the results is
that that an explicit marking you have
of course has more deterministic results
with heuristics or maybe a data set
based approach you can get into wrong
classifications or Miska or something
else which is not private better getting
mangled so that's it's a very short talk
and so you would be very interested to
hear your feedback and what you think
would be the next steps and can we do
from a working group point of view thank
you
hi Daniel Congo Morgan thanks for this I
the your your point about the way that
logs are shifting globally is I think
very well taken and something I I don't
know how traditionally the IETF has not
bothered too much with what happens
outside of the network protocol and the
this is now is starting to sort of
starting to look at what gets into
what's what's stored as a result I think
that's useful but I can imagine there
might be some people who are scared
about seeing mission creep or something
around it but I do think that we that we
should be addressing it I'm wondering
whether you've whether you've looked
also at systems for like deterministic
or format preserving encryption for logs
yeah it seems like it sort of fits into
this general framework I know that there
was some discussion with Indy Prive
about IP address within deep breath
the I don't remember there was other
discussion here the IDF about about that
kind of work and it might be worth
trying to fold in these questions about
you know key rotation and things like
that like what you can do with these
when you have fields that you want to to
scrub my one other piece of feedback for
this is that this seems to take for
granted the idea that the way that you
identify PII as you say this field this
PII and this field is not and well I
think that's tempting from an
engineering standpoint I think it is
very unrealistic in terms of what
actually personally identifiable data is
that I did is identifiable in
combination and not as specific fields
and so you could I mean my name is not
personally identifiable because there's
somebody else who has my same name but
that in combination with my with say the
state that I live in is and so maybe the
name is not be iin the state's not PII
but the two together are P and so this
is this is a problem with the Const
PII itself but I think we need to be
careful about
enshrining that in in our data
representations yeah that's a good
feedback thank you yes so just I'll just
respond as to your last point EKG also I
think we were definitely I see as your
draft thing that we're just saying that
PA equals true I think definitely agree
that that's not you know that's not
sufficient I think one thing you were
looking at was sensitivity level so you
could maybe classify certain fields as
belonging to a certain set of feel you
like in terms of how sensitive they
could be in combination with others and
then you could have a policy where if
you know there's too many of these then
you say that Oh redact all of them
that's something we did think about this
is interesting we have actually been
trying to address this at the basic
level because it's sexual a problem you
have whenever you have an application
that generates logs today in Europe at
least you have to defend and perfected
that personal information even just the
IP addresses that are in the logs so we
have been experimenting with for example
and clipping the IP addresses in place
and in a way that they can be light of
the cripton if necessary but with proper
procedures in case of monitoring law
enforcement in this kind of stuff so
maybe it would make sense to have some
kind of best practices across the
industry on how to do this in a
consistent way even if each application
even for the same kind of service has
different log formats maybe but maybe
some discussion on general principles
could be useful so that we get to a good
way of doing this was heard Karzai two
comments one actually did tkg's point
the ATF has a lot of protocols that
actually shipped logs around in various
formats including you know everything
from and actually shipped straight in
DNS they're shipped in syslog they're
shipped in syslog-ng they're shipped in
net comp they're shipped and you know
there's actually a lot of places where
log information is sent an SNMP
that so I like your approach a lot
there's only one question that I had
with it
which is you specifically said no
hard-coded rules and I don't understand
the motivation for that of why you
wouldn't do both hard-coded rules and
machine learning because her rule
hard-coded rules are pretty much a
guaranteed ground truth always will
match because I'm removing you know a
user name field that I know about
whereas if you just let the machine
learning component take over it just
make it a 80% chance of removing now
sometimes can you just debate it because
I think you the question was about no
hard coding was it that so go back a
couple of slides that one this one yeah
so you said detect personal data and you
had no heard coding okay and so I would
think that you would want a combination
of a you know of an automatic you know
machine learning best approach and you
know expert knowledge where you know
it's always right yeah yeah that that's
a good point
so obviously it's going to be like a
compliment to what mesh methods are
already there so just that it could be
another input for a machine learning
model to see okay this is the indication
from the source that the degree of
sensitivity could be there so that way
it could be used well specifically I
would think I would use the log
detection mechanism and with that
augmented with you know expert knowledge
at the end so that the redaction took
both you know the the fixed hard set of
rules and the machine learning component
and then did either or of them you would
remove this channeling Chris lemons from
Comcast
from Java I think this was in response
to de cádiz comment which is what
happens off the network is often a
consequence of what happens on the
network it's easily in the scope in my
opinion
what happens of the network what happens
off the network is often a consequence
of what happens on the network and it's
easily in the scope in Ben Schwartz if
you're looking for a place at the IETF
to do this kind of work I would suggest
narrowing scope here or narrowing
generality and trying to look very
specifically at a specific existing
systems that generate logs one that
comes to mind is HTTP request logging
which is of course almost universal
that's a case where the IETF has
substantial authority and if we for
example identified different kinds of
different specific header fields that
that should be logged differently in
different circumstances that's something
that we could reasonably make a
recommendation about I also know that
there are there are people out there who
believe that servers will log their HTTP
requests in different ways and have
encoded assumptions about that into how
their clients behave so for example I've
seen I've seen assumptions in systems
related to doe that requests of the form
get will have their full query path log
but requests that are formed as a post
will not have the post body logged right
baby and that is in fact a popular that
is consistent with implementation but
it's not something that's ever been it's
documented and standardized maybe it
should be yeah I think that's agreed
that generalization is it a part part
yeah because some of the vendors that we
are seeing there again focused on a very
specific type of log that they want to
provide the redaction so the very
specific for instance they only look at
HTTP packet or they only look at maybe
SF CFL kind of a formatted log so but I
think you're pretty right in terms of
saying that we have to narrow the scope
one reason to keep it general was to
like have a deliberate decision to keep
it like a research document trying to
see explore the space essentially but I
agree like if subsequent jobs try to
make it more narrow that would be it'll
belong in the IETF Thank You Allison
Menken Salesforce thank you for the
great presentation
I support adopting this as an IEEE RTF
document just to
back to something that Ben just said I
think you don't really have the option
of being very prescriptive but you can
actually provide of you can but it will
won't be standard but you can provide
questions and guidance that can later be
valid valuable into the standards
process a thing that struck me about
that was I mean there's a there's a
saying that the best logs for privacy
are the ones you don't retain and you
you gave this great statement that you
know people have more and more reasons
why they're retaining and using logs
perhaps this document could also talk
about kind of a time limit like at a
certain point you really have made a
tremendous loss of privacy by keeping it
beyond that point and give some of the
reasoning for that and that might help
to advise people to to improve their
policies I know if you have a comment on
that okay so I think it also depends on
the policy privacy policy itself right I
think there are a lot of organizations
the regulations that define what is the
timeline I think it's a good input but
we'll have to look at it from the
privacy policy point of view and see if
we can put those guidelines but you are
right in terms of identifying a specific
time limit as you said right it should
be useful at some point of time it may
be we have to be more pragmatic about
that agree thank you
it's Chris lemons of Comcast in the
Jabra chart again consider the audience
who will read this document
people who write drafts that
standardized or generate logs might be a
good set of members for that audience I
didn't quite get it can you repeat it
again yes I'll repeat that consider the
audience who will read this document
people who write drafts that
standardized or generate logs might be a
good set of members for that audience
thank you all right so there seems to be
some interest in this document and
there's some overlap with work that's
going on in the IETF can I get a quick
show of hands from people in the room
who have read this so a couple hands go
up how about a show of hands of people
who are interested in this particular
topic a lot more hands noted okay so I
guess based on that I I'm gonna do a
home for adoption right now so the
question is pretty simple if you support
adoption of this particular document
into the research group please home now
and if you do not support adoption
please home now all right so there seem
to be stronger support for adoption of
course we'll confirm on the list and go
from there and if you have any comments
on the document in the meantime please
you know reach out to the authors or
something on the list as well that'd be
helpful thank you thank you alright
hello everyone names Chris Wood this
should hopefully be very quick because
we talked about this last meeting in
Montreal or there was a talk similar
today in our W paper that was presented
and we presented some results that were
similar to it so this is just going to
go over the document that we have sort
of describing the network based website
being a pending problem and ask you some
questions so some background for people
who were not there in Montreal and don't
really know what I'm talking about
website fingerprinting very vaguely or
broadly is this class of attacks that
basically try to use metadata of some
sort to figure out some sensitive
application data so a common example
this is looking at Ben
from TOS connections like the sizes of
records or the timing of records that
are sent over a particular connection in
trying to infer what application data is
sent equally could be looking at the IP
addresses of you know a particular
connection in trying to infer what the
service or domain a particular
connection corresponds to we're not
being super specific with this
particular definition it's just
generally about using metadata to
identify a particular website or service
and so this document sort of was born
out of discussions with Ian Goldberg and
Tawang who are heavily involved in the
Tor community basically asking whether
or not all the attacks that have been
done on tour or sort of relevant to or
applicable to you know things that we
would do on the ITF and moreover to what
extent are these attacks applicable in
practice and do they scale well to you
know the internet so in trying to you
know get our heads around this we
basically went and looked at a bunch of
research papers that were published on
this topic and summarized them both for
our own knowledge and hopefully for the
benefit of others who potentially read
this here's the outline of the document
if you have not looked at it so it
basically it goes and describes the
general problem describes the known
attacks that are that are in these
papers describe certain defenses that
are also been experimenting with and
have been deployed in practice to some
extent particularly in the Tor space and
then ask some open questions for how
these might be relevant for you know
existing ITF protocols or ITF protocols
going forward so pretty straightforward
very similar to Joe's draft on
censorship tech in the sense that we
were just serving existing stuff so a
question to people here are first is
this useful to anyone besides me because
I in writing this down I had to read a
lot of papers and that was useful so I'm
learned something from it maybe it's
useful to the IETF or I or TF who knows
and if it is useful
should this happened here in perigee or
elsewhere who knows does the scope need
to change if we take things out remove
things whatever and similar to Joe's
draft this is sort of problematic
because the nature of this document is
whenever new paper is published I go in
and summarize it and put it in and that
sort of implies that you know publishing
it something that's sort of stable is
not perhaps the best way forward so I
will defer to the mic that was a lot of
questions all right I mean yeah go I
mean yes this is absolutely useful um
you know we you know there's like a long
list of mechanisms that allow you know
that allow passive or active observers
to determine what your you know what
browsing behavior is and you know once
we finish like removing all the ones
that like just like steak flat out what
pressing behavior is you know eventually
this will come like the easiest way to
do it and so getting a handle on how to
fix that it seems like super critical
I think PRG seems like the right place
for this it's hard to see where else
it's gonna sit I don't think HTTP really
is gonna like know what to do with this
um I think you know that the output of
this work you know or recommendations
for a shippi should do to like actually
pretty figure pretty harder would be
something you could feed into HTTP um um
I I agree like probably having an RFC
doesn't seem like super like how fol cuz
it's kind of static um um you know I
don't know maybe the IDF application
process is lightweight enough that you
could like crank out new RC every year
or something but the existence of this
document seems like super helpful um so
I would encourage you to keep at it and
I guess I don't know the RTI process
well enough but you know a dump things
working group items at the signal this
is like something that we think is
important sometimes viable yeah it may
be with respect to the how frequently
update the document may be the approach
is just make it a github page or
something and then I just update it
there and point people to it from the
purging thing I don't know yeah I'm
gonna I see Cullen's bike way behind us
so he has an opinion and how does that
work but this is a good work and you
should keep that Thanks
yeah I totally agree I think it's useful
for our chef and I think ietf I think
folks you're gonna get wider readership
from folks who just like with the
censorship graph people walk up to me
and they're like wow this is really
helpful for a number of reasons and
they've never you know touched protocols
I think the scope is right I do wonder
if there's gonna be a way to capture
things that maybe don't make it
necessarily into the academic literature
I know that's where you sort of started
from and maybe that's something to think
about like what what level does it reach
to make it in there and I guess in terms
of being living I don't know there's
nothing wrong with having an ID that
gets updated occasionally and and peeled
off if we need something to point to as
canonical but yeah I don't know if I
have anything useful to say there but
yeah thanks all right this is Joe from I
suck that just to clarify the criteria
for the criteria for putting something
in this document was very low I had to
do something with what's I figure
bridging and it had to show up in my
Google Scholar Alert so that's pretty
much it this is general Khan Gilmore so
thanks for this seconding previous to
commenters we definitely need this work
the the framing of web site
fingerprinting I think is maybe a little
bit confusing given the way that we're
talking about HTTP as transport these
days and so it might be worth trying to
think about what we want to talk about
there right yeah I'm a bit unhappy with
the term website fingerprinting it's
just what's used traditionally in the
literature typically because like it
started off in tour in that particular
way and they've just carried it forward
so yeah if there's a better term the
more accurately capture what we're
trying to actually do today I will
happily use it not sure what it would be
so so what's interesting is that it used
to be that you'd say website
fingerprinting because you were
distinguishing between that and other
forms of network traffic fingerprinting
but now that most network traffic wants
to be HTTP traffic in the first place
all of a sudden we're back to kind of
network traffic fingerprinting point
yeah so so I'm not sure what
balances as far as the live document or
whatever
please keep working on it
let's have revisions for it if it turns
out that it's useful to say here's what
we think network traffic fingerprinting
looks like in 2020 that's a that's a
perfectly legitimate document to produce
as long as we continue to revise that
you know the the baseline draft that
produces that so that maybe we want
another one at four twenty twenty five
but that but but yeah I do I do think we
need a place to collect this information
and we need a place to point people to
when they start designing new protocols
as they inevitably will that make these
same mistakes again thank you just like
given up on the mic stand here gotta go
back to first principles here miss
Richard Barnes I'm just gonna +1 all the
comments about this being valuable work
and caging mostly cover what I was
thinking about you know extending to non
web applications because like everybody
uses HTTP now and concerns for
fingerprinting what apps are on your
phone is very similar to consume a
fingerprinting what websites you're
visiting as far as stability like I
wouldn't be it doesn't seem like we
would fail here if we produced a
snapshot at the time and revisited at
the time a one thing that could be done
to give this a bit more longevity is to
think about whether there's some you
know abstractions one could make over
the techniques in the literature and to
discuss general classes of attacks I
mean kind of call those out as guidance
for things people to consider in in
designing protocols we did this there's
something similar a few years ago a few
IAB folks and I did a draft about
censorship techniques on ways you could
do blocking where we talked about
generic classes of approach to that that
problem so to speak and in ways that in
the you know the advantages that the the
ways they could be deployed and the
things they break and so I think a
similar approach could could work here I
haven't
I admit dived into the document real
detail but that would give that this
document a bit more longevity yeah good
suggestion we haven't taken the time to
sort of try to generalize anything it's
really been just a brain dump of what
we've discovered in the literature but
that's a very good suggestion yeah thank
you hi Colin Perkins we'll see if this
microphone falls down before I finish
talking see ya I think this work is
useful I think this research group is as
good a place as any to do the work and I
don't have any objections to that in
terms of the the living document type
thing if you've only ever published
RFC's via the IETF side I think you'll
find the process is perhaps lighter
weight in the IRT F yeah I mean XML
fee-free but you know means you can add
pretty pictures no but I mean seriously
I think you're keeping this sort of
finger life as an internet draft and
occasionally pushing out snapshots as an
RFC and makes a lot of sense you that
this is the state of the world as of
2020 or whatever it is and then just
keep keep it ticking over and then in a
couple years time well we'll publish
another one okay yeah that seems you
deal with me yeah we got plenty of RFC
numbers right yeah I'd might as well is
it even opposed to us asking for
adoption right now please step up to the
mic right now okay so all those in favor
of adoption of this document by Paigey
please hum now all those not in favor of
adoption please have now perfect same
we'll take you to the list also and yeah
take it from there thanks Chris yeah
Thank You Bernie
[Music]
afternoon my name is Bernie niacin I am
having a short presentation to frame the
discussion of the next document is
presented by Eric Ries
so there is an activity going on called
meetup missing elements for
decentralized usable privacy and just
following background so we are working
on solutions that are decentralized
end-to-end peer-to-peer for reasons of
mitigating the adverse effects of
process monitoring because it's an
attack to privacy and has been
documented in RC and centralized
elements are usually more prone to
attacks because if you have two
centralized delavane you have everything
and if it's centralized the effect is
limited usable because message
encryption has law for most Internet
users I mean who of you has already
tried to set up PGP not so many who of
you managed to do that in less than one
hour the first time okay
a bit less anyway but whoever would
consider that people who are not
attending the idea throwing something
completely different are able to set out
the PGP kind okay zero and that's
actually where it comes from we need
folks fixed is usability challenged by
automation because people are simply not
able to do it on their own if they are
not getting enough help and that's where
it's coming from is usable and privacy
we consider privacy is a human right so
this medical tech TV team show I can't
go into all details but basically it's
about enhancements to application
protocols for decentralized usable
privacy it's based on opportunistic
security and the whole thing emerged
from the initiative of pepper pretty
easy privacy it's a foundation that
piece doing implementations in this area
but it's not limited to that it's also
like other people working in the field
for example autocorrect are invited to
participate directly actively contribute
to meet up and the goal is to define the
missing pieces like key management
private key synchronizations message
formats trust well change etc I can't go
into details of this we meet in
so-called non working group sessions
during IDF meetings with the exception
of this one
you're not having these kind of sessions
otherwise he had it last free IDF
meetings I think we have a mailing list
set up made up at ITF talk and you can
subscribe there if you're interested in
the field and at some point in time we
are aiming for both to be an ideal
working group and work on this a bit
more in the proto sense so what's there
so far all these boxes for representing
internet craft
I don't know how much time we have that
I can go into details of all the boxes
or should I just summarize okay yeah
right okay so basically then I talk
about the four corners like the pink
corner is more or less what has to do
with handshake and Trust then there is
the application corner which
the brown corner for example use it in
email but also instant messaging and we
are even using it for banking
transaction for example Swift Network is
using the same technology then we have
the private key synchronization area
like that you have different devices and
generate the key with one the ability to
encrypt your email and read the email on
the other devices usually don't work
unless we share the keys and we have a
solution for that it's already
implemented and the green area is like
the core area with requirements the cost
of end what you hear as next is basis
for that green area
it's the fret analyzes that out of the
fret analyzes that is discussed in this
next presentation requirements are
coming or part of requirements are
coming so now we know where this next
presentation is fit to and I would end
or to in raqqa stem
okay I might need the speaker maybe not
like that so hello everyone thank you
for Pierre G and ITF for inviting me and
for this long-standing contribution I
want to break this presentation actually
it's a call for stimulate discussions
and to call for contributions under the
keywords a break down the title of this
presentation on this four points a
systematic analysis of security and
privacy threats for private messaging
and what I'm talking about private
messaging I'm talking about emailing and
instant messaging okay are miracles many
ways I'm a postdoc to give ambassador of
Luxembourg and this is a joint work with
pet with Bernie Hansen and Nanak Carol
character so very quickly is still a
relevant problem private messaging in
mail and it's a message II so does
quickly in the numbers I'm not gonna
sting - Matt's 3.7 billion users email
with a future predictions even more we
see a little bit dropping on the private
use but still like 75 billion users
approximately females here just to say
on these numbers and the statistics that
these prominent these two are messaging
applications actually are belong to a
single application provider and we see
this distribution roughly I would say
the percent of the world is under a
single service provider so do have a
systematic way of analyzing the threats
and the requirements what is usually
been done in the RFC and the first f70 P
821 back in 1982
we build it I did with a very nice
system SMTP but initially without
security into consideration so we found
out a bunch of threads for instance two
least one monthly middle attacks then we
started designing systems that you have
that ahead like client-server decryption
like start TLS and you had all these
nice analytics of Gmail showing is to
our browser like all your flight is at
that time you should consider going
because there is a traffic or not
surprisingly in 2013 we got the spring
project which is not the revelation that
they showed us oh by the way this
information is not going only to you but
is going to some Secret Service
analytics systems so we shouldn't
consider trusted the servers of email
servers and be some basic servers that
they only keep the information only to
ourselves so we start building
end-to-end encryption as mine we thought
that centralized systems they might even
not be that robust and privacy security
privacy preserving because they might
send different public keys we have open
PGP and this summer we had this proofing
of certificate poisoning which I'm not
going to go into technical details but
essentially they break up open GP
because they made it very buggy and
large start shining sorry signing
certificates they make very large and
buggy certificate certificate and then
when you download it sexually was
breaking of new GP ok we found out ways
to have internal encryption with great
security protocols but then now what
there is a harder problem with metadata
and this great person the general for
NSA director said that well by the way
we might don't know to what you are
saying but we kill people based on
metadata and even there are like
academic work very good academic work or
like projects successful but still there
is no application so where are we now
there is a lot of academic work but
usually the approach is like we think
that these threats are really relevant
but what we if we do it the other way
around we start mapping the list of
threats and we start like instead of
running after the attacks we start
designing systems by very beginning so
EF first started to on this direction
try to evaluate and try to make a list
of design security features but this
specific is a website but this is
limited categories is obsolete right now
and it evaluates only existing apps so
the aim of this internet document is
about to assess to have a security and
privacy threat modeling requirements are
a holistic systematic approach and for
assessing existing systems or this when
designing a new system systems you can
use it for as a guideline and this takes
into consideration technical threats
security and privacy but also the user
threads there is keep on discussion on
intelligent service about backdoors and
this is not a technical vulnerability
this is an issue of opening a backdoor
in their system and this is a user
threat so we think that as a basis for
private messaging maybe it's a good fit
for later and for ITF and ERG PR to
consider adopting is as a working item
okay what is in the internet draft what
we have what is our contribution until
now so as we will
we'll show you a little bit later on we
have a system model we define the system
model meaning what exactly the entities
and the functionalities which are the
adversaries what the adversaries can do
the class of threads the class of
requirements and later on in a later
phase in this document or in a later on
we will have the risk approach because
now we consider the threads uniformly
but maybe you want to evaluate the
threads and then which are the crypto
protocols we have all the crypto
primitives for instance OTR so if I am
to say the system model in a halt it
could be the Italian Bob wants to
communicates and want to exchange
messages or it wants to exchange emails
or instant messaging using instant
messaging systems and here we have the
networking nodes and we have splitted
the trust establishment which is
essentially to have identity key and
contact management and third parties and
what we can do is we can start playing
with the threads with adversarial models
and when we say adversary model we are
talking about whether advisor is a
passive we say owners but curious it
tries to not break the system but it
tries to extract as much information as
possible it can be active adversary and
can be internal or external and here is
the list that we start have started
compiling and this first list the first
two columns is about security threats
and and security requirements and this
is extracting this is a methodologies
being used by Microsoft with a straight
framework so essentially we try to find
out all the possible threats in these
classes of attacks classes of threat and
the corresponding requirements so the
same
seeing as a methodology we did it with
privacy but I ever see uses we used an
academic were called Linton which we
adopted it for our needs and I want to
highlight three specific points so for
confidentiality information disclosure
there is this is a threat to security
and privacy however for non-repudiation
it might be a requirement as a security
but an issue to privacy in the for a
privacy can be an issue and it's
actually how are the arts been built
that has plausible deniability so having
a map of threats and requirements we can
very beginning at the very early States
point what we need to do another thing
is the privacy interdependence think
about the case where you're installing
an what's up or a signal and all your
contacts go into the clouds and that is
a matching who has this application so
essentially what you do you send your
whole social network to the cloud
provider of what's up to do the matching
and notify your home has the same
contact who has the same person stole
the same application so in signal there
was a lot of discussion how you can do
it privacy preserving word so we might
have had recall the previous slide it's
not only metadata about who
communicating but also like with whom we
have exchanged information we have our
contacts shared so just a case study
just to show you what we can do with
that what we can do with this internet
document and what we have done if we
start discussing about okay if you start
placing at the other siren model that
could be for instance the mail servers
we can have protocols as start TLS which
can preserve confidentiality NDT and
data fornication but we consider what
about if we start consider in mail
service as passive adversaries or as
materials that will constantly try to
read our information to read our email
and instant messages then we start
playing with for instance s/mime we
thought that okay what about I don't
know okay here's great
so what about if public keys that are my
shirt are spoofed for instance I'm using
a public key that's supposed to be for
my friend Bob but this actually is not
we have this issue of certificate
flooding as I said which in specific a
third party we can frame it after party
and external adversary is aiming to
break to do a denial of service attack
and in this particular case Bob is
considered as adversary an OTR has been
designed considering this this very much
this very principles of confidentiality
entity and data education forward
secrecy and deniability so we can start
called peeking threats that we need to
design a system for and we have specific
countermeasures and having the whole map
of adversarial models we can say exactly
what we need to do instead of going the
other way around
saying I believe which can be as an
expert you can have a very good overview
of what is needed but we think that as a
systematic systematically it's even more
important to do it as we can see the
whole map of threats future directions
well there's a lot of work that needs to
be done so usability issues on top of
EDP
and bgp has been discussed in the
previously and there are three Kaka
demic papers from 99 16 and 0 6 so we
have a key management issues and still
the problem remains about how we can use
it how we can make it more usable so
that can be another issue and the
requirement that we need to design our
system but we need to consider our
system design so that not only designed
in an engineering way but also like to
make it practical so there is a lot of
push from intelligent services with
different arguments about back during
and this is like very recent news about
us and UK and a stress in Australia to
just start back during and we think
Australia already passed a low but I
think that it's not active they say
they'd have inactivated and us there is
a human rights and law of the private
privacy of correspondents of females
you cannot offer males we cannot open
the mail in a non war times the same
should apply as a reasoning the same
should apply in the deed in the digital
world and finally there is a lot of
discussion about post quantum crypto and
there is a call by professors and
academics and experts in the field that
we need to start considering moving
towards that because the time that will
pass so companies to adapt for new plot
to design new protocols it takes time
information that we are storing in our
system needs to keep it for 10 to 50
years so we already need to start
designing new systems that would
consider post quantum security instead
of running afterwards we need to be
proactive so that's all for my site if
you have any questions
it's very welcome thank you
then Schwartz thank you for forgiving
the deep thought to the important topic
I I definitely support this work in this
area and and this draft seems very well
written but I had a few comments about
this I think that this is a fairly
opinionated draft it doesn't seem like a
neutral summary of the field it seems
more like a coherent framework that
you're presenting I was just giving it a
name
essentially presenting it as a new named
framework I would also suggest thinking
about it as a framework instead of
describing it as an analysis or
especially using the word requirements
which occurs a few times in the draft
certainly if the IETF requirements
refers pretty specifically to setting
yourself up to do specific protocol
based work at it doesn't seem like
that's the real purpose here
I would clarify the scope some some of
the research I've seen here suggests
that at least for ordinary users if you
ask them what kinds of security threats
they're worried about in in private
messaging context the things that you
listed here are not at the top of their
list the things you listed the things
that they tend to list our insider
threats things like people peering over
their shoulders or their boss checking
their phone while they have it in a in a
locker those are really important
security threats and it's fine to say to
make them out of scope but we should
clarify scope and I would suggest
thinking about this in terms of
communication not just messaging both
because I think the the technology
itself doesn't matter and because video
because that what we're really thinking
about here is communication between
people whatever form that takes in
particular video chat and related stuff
I think it has important privacy
concerns that we should be thinking
about thank you very much I would
suggest to take you to a flying and go
point by point later on you tell me
exactly and
very much up in exchange I just want to
be sure that I understand what's the
objective of the work you're opposing
because I mean are you trying to write a
set of requirements to then design yet
another instant messaging protocol that
this time will be private and secure and
so because I think that it was already
pointed out first of all in the scenario
an email and instant messaging is pretty
different because an instant messaging
you only have walled gardens and when
you have walled gardens there's no way
you can exclude it whoever lost the
server of the service you're using so
that's already I mean a basic problem
from any care for any kind of privacy
security you want to to grant with email
it's different because you could choose
your server but still you you have lot
lots of other things to address but also
I mean having spent some time time to me
in the real world convinced some big
email operators to just adopt existing
technologies like Dane and DNS SEC for
example to make it efficient more secure
I agree that that the problem is this
problem is not very high in request of
their users or of the people that runs
the service so some if you really want
to advance the discussion maybe there's
non-technical things that we should
discuss if you want to put this only at
the technical level then I would like to
understand what the objectives are what
what you want to achieve in practice so
the objective of this internet document
is to do it in a way of mapping the
threads in the technical aspect from a
very beginning instead of pointing later
on we have this thread let's try to
patch it let's try to figure figure how
we're gonna design a system so this is
like for evaluating existing systems and
protocols and all you want to design a
new and I've you are a security engineer
or a privacy engineer that you will be
able to see which are the threats what
you need to do what what are the
existing systems crypto primitives
protocols one point that you said I
don't know if I've covered your with my
answer we can also take it offline
one thing that you said is system
messaging and emailing is different yes
but one is low latency the other is high
latency well nowadays both systems and
in the in the messaging aspect they both
have common points with both if we just
remove the XMPP if we just remove the
SMTP like the transport how we transport
on the format if we see it like us what
we need to safeguard so we send text who
set attachments and we have our
archiving or searching we have I agree
that technically I mean we are working
on chat or IMAP so I mean that's not
what I was pointing out is that they are
very different in that architecture of
the market and the service that people
actually use so it's a non-technical
difference okay okay thank you very much
Paris koala I mean this is an
interesting space I guess I'm a little
less sanguine about this document
particular document that Ben is the as
Victoria was saying like trying to like
span email and instant messaging in
video straight me just really difficult
you know like the MLS work here house
like a fairly well-defined threat model
in the organizer document that rise like
map output the threat model is but a lot
of it's actually fairly specific like
the MLS setting and so and and the if we
try to like expand that to email I think
it wouldn't work very well and I think
actually part of like like as an example
of that on the slides you have about
like how awful PGP is interface is like
basically don't apply any instant
messaging systems it actually have
extremely streamlined um you know you
know key discovery and set up if I call
just other problems but they don't but
they don't have these problems about
like key discovery they're complicated
um so I think trying to like you know
have some document that like is a master
document like for all message like model
for all messaging like ends up with you
like rating like a quarter feet export
and like you know and describing dole of
yeah which is like not super helpful
so um so I like
I would encourage you I'm given that
like that we have existing work um in
the IETF on in
it is like designing secured your first
measuring right now to like um if you
want to work in there's a meshing
problem to engage there and if you want
to write like an email for analysis like
this might be an okay place for this but
then this document needs some provision
to like actually be that understood
correctly the question I don't know I
don't want to say open PGP or PGP is
awful okay no I know that's not my point
what I said is we have some facts and
some analysis of whether it's working
until to which extent or which issues we
have to be considered like based on the
academic world that exists so time check
one minute yes be mine so this is more
like here in this room and in ITF as
Badar there is a lot of expertise and
that has be done a lot of work so it's
more like a call for discussion instead
of doing things like I do believe or
like with us maybe you were set up
like we start doing as a systematic way
of threads and identify the whole
spectrum by bringing the expertise
everyone has and then have an internet
document that will help and guide others
that will like to design engineers that
would like to design right is it like
did I answer why again what's the
question I guess what I'm saying is that
like this document would not be helpful
for designing MLS it would not advance
the state of the art it might be useful
um some other versions dog in the beasts
for analyzing email but if you want to
contribute to the design of the
protocols we're actually doing here then
I don't think a document census tract is
gonna be very helpful very quickly
Richard Richard Barnes yeah similar page
to echo at all I think you know I I
agree that this is an important problem
with the state of messaging security
especially for email is really terrible
but I don't think it's because we don't
understand the problem sufficiently in
contrast to dr. Woods document about a
fingerprinting where there is like
open uncertainty you know active
research about what the threats are I
think we actually understand the problem
pretty well and even in the MLS case
we're writing a document to document the
threats were addressing in the
architecture for addressing those
threats that's more about kind of
consolidating on a view and making sure
that everyone's in the same page because
everyone already had fairly detailed
internal models all of the vendors who
are coming to the table for MLS and so
that was more of a consolidation effort
than research really so I think this is
probably not appropriate work for a
research group here this is dkg so I
think I agree with Eckert and Richard
that this document might be too broad to
be particularly useful in contrast to
what Ben was saying Ben I'm suggesting
maybe we could abstract it even further
I mean the way you had split up your
architecture it looks a lot like you
could use it to discuss IPSec in that
you have trust you know Association
context and then you have the actual
messaging security and you have to
transport all of these things right you
could actually evaluate IPSec with the
same framework that you have but at some
point it becomes vague enough that it's
hard to know what's actionable where
with regards to whether this is actually
useful for research Richard I think that
the that the work on a fail in the last
year shows that we actually still don't
understand scope of attacks against
email against and and protected email
and and I actually do think that it
would be useful to try to document this
for a specific application domain like
email because I I believe that there
actually is more I mean we've done such
a bad job of defending against the
attacks that we do know about for email
that no one feels like it's worth
showing that it's even more broken than
it is but that doesn't mean that it
isn't actually also more broken and so I
do think that there's actually room
given the evidence for like the
low-hanging fruit that we saw from a
fail there's room to identify more
problems there and so I don't I don't
think this is going to be fallow ground
for for research even but but I do think
that it needs to be more scopes to be
useful or entitle more tightly scopes to
hi I'm Mallory noddle from our 19 it was
a question I'm I didn't understand what
you were trying to document was it that
how the actual threat is compromised or
is it the threats themselves because I
think what you're trying to do is look
at threats from a like bring user level
threats into the conversation which
would be very useful but now after do
these comments I'm not so sure that's
what you're doing user threads it's
mainly these documents about technical
threats which threats can be the classes
of threats and what actually does it
mean and private communication private
messaging system in a future
consideration we need to think about
just we with we think that we should
also consider other user threats in
terms of but this is can be in another
document not in this one it does this
one I try to capture all the directions
that we think of that should be but it's
not in this document so for I'm sorry um
we're way over time can you take this
offline thank you thank you everyone
you