all right you're probably right click on
the link and say open on your tap let
yourself or the Russian tennis right
click go back let's see if I can
minimize this no can't do that but then
don't scroll down here ok this is the
just it just goes right back to you what
is one more about and you're gonna go
back again this one yeah yeah this isn't
seat chair it doesn't let you do that
ok though think I can do it you have to
just kind of manual is just just copy
that URL up there yes just copy the URL
I'm not a manual they just click on the
+ to create them to tap and then paste
it just open like 10 cents or so I don't
know how you
there's no it not a dialogue for copy
control V control now so I'm thinking is
there's two control V here so I'm
thinking okay that's mm that's not what
the one that wanted them now let's see
okay so this is something else
Gary spin materials so I'm thinking copy
this then just open like pick up eight
types of salad that's
then each tab just go to a different
presentation so like in this one we can
go to the agenda status this one will go
to BFD agree yeah hi
[Music]
this one didn't truly down low I'm
having the problem is that this hasn't
been converted maybe don't know if it
can actually display it don't you know
it did work another line of the problem
was okay not registered packing multi I
have on this scroll down
almost done
okay so think we got all of them now
open one more with the agenda see what
the agenda slides we've got B if the
orange multi this one you think we got
all of them so here I can do with you
okay what's going on here
okay escape okay now I figured stuck we
can revert you control L now you know I
think like some PDF viewers use control
L but that doesn't work in a browser
let's see is there some kind of
presentation this one I guess no that's
we cannot quite what do you want but now
I guess this this is the best and there
is some other option I think in the
browser
mmm yeah how do you do this guess maybe
over here there's our full screen
No well it's here
this is this whole screen yeah yeah how
do we get out of this there's a button
to press for full screen okay cool there
is a button here for full screen which
is the same as that it is a browser and
so oh really
why are there so few people here that
I've given it to get going oh just
waiting for everyone to show up demo
people are talking to lights just the
way there's also dis foot to water to
the slides I mean that's what this is
for I never during the okay let's start
it okay
welcome to 2 p.m. working group see you
know hopefully seen enough to battle
before it should be the same as you've
seen in other meetings this is our
agenda so yeah the first step is what
you're doing right now just go free
working up status and stuff any comments
on the rest of the agenda hope we didn't
miss any requests don't think we have
all the presenters in the room by the
way but we'll see how that goes
yeah thanks for taking notes ok so this
is to work nerd status big news is that
we published our first yang model so
that took a long time a lot of effort
from people so happy to see that dumb
there's also a PA on mobile that also is
completed it's just waiting for some
references I think basically some other
other documents that need to be
published as RFC s as well yeah we got a
lot of stuff in the queue now also the
reserved bits is in the RFC editors
queue
we requested publication for the IGMP
Emily sleeping young model so just
waiting for our ad to get the cycle
salute Khalid and also PMD our
improvements we also just requested
publication so what's the stuff we
completed and also MSTP young model so
we did get some response from Alvaro he
revealed that and we needed have waiting
for a new person I believe do load
balancing as well he requested
publication Alvaro had a lot of comments
that I addressed of one of the offers
and it's going to rsg evaluation now
then we have some working group drafts
just three more drafts so basically all
the drafts and just mentioned they're
all like in the queue to be published
but they got three drafts that are
current working group documents that we
are working on so now register packing B
if the point to multi-point and the
Arjun P Emily proxy young models so
those are the existing working work
group documents they got some new
documents presented today and guess
we'll consider adoption for some of them
yeah that's it right all right any
comments on that okay then the next on
the agenda should be yeah probably yeah
should be let's see maybe this one yeah
so so should be present it's working
your special we figured we have to
actually push it all the way in others
other chairs can't figure it out
okay so this is an update there was very
interesting discussion on a list about
more experienced detection for the world
balancing and we already have proposal
how to do dr BD are expedited monitoring
using a point-to-multipoint b FD or how
to refer to in RFC as leave d for multi
point networks am i doing it wrong no no
it's probably i have that's alright I
know I broke it in alright okay we'll
give up on that okay thank you okay so
how it works
for designated router world balancing so
RFC introduced what now will be our C
because okay the draft introduced to
hello options capability advertisement
and group designated router candidate
list what we are proposing that a pin
router that includes capability hello
option may include be the discriminator
PM option that already been defined in
this draft in support of dr BD are
monitoring and when the router
advertised that it creates BFD session
as multiple in head according to BFD for
multi-point networks which is now our
50 85 62 it sets the session down so
only creates a state no the packets
being transmitted if the PM if the
router receives that they used the
discriminator with a cap hello option
sees itself in a group designated router
candidate list that dia router
distributes then it's a move session to
the Upstate and start politically
transmitting MIDI control messages at
the same time
dr creates or before sending the first
up or updated candidate list it creates
a session as multi here multi-point leaf
and starts the multiplexing packets
because well them could be a
multiplicity of candidates so that's a
multiplicity of point-to-multipoint in
video sessions so it looks for the
discriminator
but since the discriminator only in my
field which is specific to this type of
BFD session it needs to know the source
IP address so and as already stated in
the document the source IP address must
be the same source the same ip address
as included in hello pin hello so the
idea is if we can go next slide so the
idea is that they are monitors the
well-being of candidate or it could be
they are in video because it's a
multi-point
network and then can detect whether the
candidate is available so if it's not
available it can generate
updated candidate it can generate the
hello message with updated Kindle at
least nice faster then hello interval
and that's the convergence in a world
balancing will happen much faster so
that pretty much the same the idea of
course are the dr itself is the
candidate but since it doesn't need to
monitor itself others can monitor it if
dr is using a point-to-multipoint b FD
is already defined in this draft to for
expedited convergence so for example b
dr can monitor dr as a candidate for the
load balancing as and as a they are so
don't need to create two sessions next
slide so that's their new update to the
draft and we welcome your questions
comments and will ask well if there are
not many comments from the consider
working group last call and come now
from cisco so if you are running these
BFBS from GDR to all endpoints are two
endpoints is between Dr Ng Diaz yes Dr
Ng there's dr dr and v dr because ok the
the benefit is that because it's a
point-to-multipoint session so firstly
is it creates less state because it's
unidirectional right so the specificity
specifics of our point-to-multipoint BFD
it uses demand mode so only there one
side generates messages but at the same
time since it's not active tail
listener the leaf knows the state of the
path and their route so in this case
they are in vidya will know can monitor
the state of an arab candidate okay so
basically if you detect a failure you
read on the VRA like yes okay that's the
idea yeah so everyone so by the way
thanks for that clarification you just
had it was one of my questions as well
okay but one thing I was wondering is I
agree that you know you only really
needed the art to monitor the GDR but I
know there are some some payment
limitations would be a fever you just
have hearings between all the neighbors
and you just listen you know to check
your neighbors going away in general
yeah well again we are not mandating it
this is option and they're nice about
point-to-multipoint that comparing to
RFC fifty eight eighty which described
all actually fifty eight eighty
described all the possibility for the
team applicability is I believe it's a
single hobby FD so it's a synchronous
mode a synchronous mode will create more
state because if we have the more
routers we have on the same shared
segment the raw the more pin routers on
the same shared segment so the more
state of BFD sessions that create full
mesh between will be there so and I
think that that's where the benefits of
using the land mode and
point-to-multipoint BFD will become more
significant yeah the main the main thing
I was wondering about in a way yeah was
you know there's it says here that you
Lachie they are you take the session
state up or down based on whether you
are currently announced yes
and I was wondering a bit in
does it make sense to just always keep
it up in case some papers are well the
thing well actually its again if there
is a use case when it's might be
interesting just to track the world
being of a node yes but at the same time
well again we might make it optional yes
I don't really have any answers but I
was wondering about that but I see you
know on the slide here it says must set
the session you know such as day two
down maybe it shouldn't well well again
the idea is that since we're using it to
track only the those who are listed in a
candidate list so if if we want to make
more generic saying okay well we are
tracking everybody who announced the
capability to be candidate then we'll
probably will change that because then
then we'll change it even from the
beginning that we're after they
announced their capability they will set
their session up because current text
says that the session is initial state
is down and you bring it up only if you
see yourself on the candidate list so if
there is a use case to make it well let
me see if it use case to make it less
restricted okay so for example we can
say should say that set it down so which
will allow implementers to consider some
environments where they want to start it
up to begin with and then we can say
should take it down
we shall Gail give them justification
not to take it down yeah yes so I don't
have any answers but but one thing for
instance I'm wondering about this one is
the our state right it's useful to use
PFD to quickly did
Herman who is the Dro GDR but also
possibly maybe things like a start state
for instance if you this if you track
neighbors and you see that you know the
Oscar winner went down that Islands you
know there could be things like that
that's what again I you know I'm not
that versed in a Pimm's scenario so if
there is a use case I would be willing
to discuss it and then we can modify and
make it less restrictive this but but
yeah I was gonna say thanks for doing
this I mean Shimano the offers so the
allowed balancing - and I think you know
that this makes it better thank you okay
thank you again
since Stig mentioned that there might be
some scenarios that might change the
normative language let's keep it open
for comments from the list if they will
really like idea of making it less
restrictive for example change must -
should and if there are such requests
yeah I think that there is no problem
but I would like to first understand why
before making it and after that we'll
see yeah I'll try to provide comments on
the list and see if we can you know make
some progress you know with pity for the
next meeting
great thank you okay that should be
imagine proxy yeah yeah yeah that's them
no no that's the one we had some trouble
with so if Connor came out in the wrong
order
all right
yeah at cousins work you can try it but
now it's not actually maybe it's
pointing here we have it working for a
few seconds again good afternoon i'm
shefaly oh I'm here to give a quick
update to the I jump in with the epoxy
your model next week so this document
that just recently being attacked update
to the adult working group document so
after that this is a first update after
the talk at option nice place yeah so we
after the adoption and during the
process because someone reveal comments
so here some updates so one acted the
way I did the option at the confusion
leave to specify the sender sauce I
dress so in case we have multiplied
dresses so this one will be used through
the reporter D and kima option a
flexibility for the user so I think
highlights used to be highlighted but
anyway okay so that's aligned with the
source address next my spleen
same thing here to the I'm ready
[Music]
vacation tree same the pinheaded extra
space so another leave your comments is
about the future mode were stainless
also each sauce which tell me makes
analysis so it shouldn't be there the
theater mode for the core team so you
can either any particular sauce or xcode
included extras or should be either
black also only so we remove the not
proper position the filter mode so this
is a clean up next are trees seem seem
to the MRD that the same changes next
fights so yeah that's it some quick
updates to the changes alright thank you
so this document was just adopted but I
was gonna say do you feel like the
document is complete do you have
anything more you plan to do with it for
and yeah well still discussing and we
asked further review unless you saw
anything to remove one thing I imagine
for any vendors to see if this if their
implementation works well with this or
if if you know needs some adjustments to
the model and also for anyone using the
model for any management if it has what
what you need yeah thank you anybody
Thank You Craig thank you guys thanks
okay sorry it's too late
[Music]
just my after shots that are just a
question about expressed more to try do
you think that you were drafted already
includes explicit mode the tracking
function well well the the reason why
I'm asking this is that because Express
trapping sorry for my really great but
the explicit tracking mode itself is
really important it it's well known the
problem is that that function actually I
was I am still also that expired draft
but so so so this is a question so it's
already expired and well maybe it's
maybe it's my problem but the question
is that whether we should include that
function because that function sir is
very important the problem is that the
doctor was not it was not draft rejected
I mean that the draft was accepted but
the problem was in my I'm not sure what
the intention of the draft state is for
example it should be a standard track or
information or experimental and the
other vendors are already implemented
and that there is no consideration about
wired communication so so there was a
comment from the ad so why we definitely
need to have that kind of draft
especially for as a standard track
document so that's why it's really
stucked and but that function itself is
really important and I'm sure that
several vendors are already implemented
that function and young mothers should
focus on that kind of important function
so the question is what we or they
should do yeah so at least it's possible
to have a young model for something even
if there is no no draft right of C for
the actual functionality like yeah I'm
trying to think here but but basically
you can
you can define you know as long as
there's implementations that have like
certain ways knobs were for a
neighboring or whatever you can you can
define the young model for how to do
that even if it's not 100% define how
the feature works which I'll put a mean
to the draft expert Oh exact problem
cause problem even worse than not
referencing that right so yeah it's
important that I think that there's a
common understanding what explicit
tracking means but I think that's pretty
well understood it's just that there's
no document for it if technically I
think it's fine to have an informational
reference to expire draft in all right
yeah but but it has to be just
informational usually in the model if it
put any laughing state in there you know
what I mean is just in general with
RFC's you know if it's if it's not to
achieve them it's okay if it's just an
expired draft but another thing is
whether it's okay for the reference to
just be informative yeah okay we think
about that it's to see if we can catch
some direction from Charis I'll be good
another thing though is you know in when
you are making this model you try to
define what is kind of common for all
the main implementations right so do you
know whether all the months you looked
at already have explicit tracking or
yeah we need to have some feedback any
vendors can have some information that
you great so we know we'll be doing we
will try to actively pull some vendors
see if we can have
so yeah hi I'm presenting the
non-registered packing draft I'm not an
offer I'm just doing this on behalf of
the offers I should say though that um
I've been close involved with with the
offers discussing this and stuff so just
just so you're aware of that but but
just a quick status update or this draft
really so there was I worked in a blast
call for this draft some months ago or
weeks ago and and there was only one
response to that I think and and there
are several suggestions in that in that
though and one of them was that it
should be with some way of coping with
that what you see here basically as part
of the register packing you try to
discover if the RP actually supports it
you don't want to send a packet register
unless you know for sure that it can be
processed so there is to find a way of
detecting that the RP supported was
having a flag in a register stop but
what happens if your RP is suddenly
downgraded so it doesn't support this
anymore so the draft discusses how to
detect that basically if I remember now
if we send a packed register and you
don't get a register stop back then
there's a chance that your RP no longer
supports it but is it that there's some
new disc text to to discuss how the
system otherwise I don't know what else
is missing there was only that one
response and and this was done to handle
that so yeah I guess people need another
last call or what do you think Mike why
don't we do it last call last dinner
might be like two months ago I think it
was after last night EF okay yeah I
think yeah you you sent
of the last call requests but well yeah
so at least has a chair you know I feel
like you know we need more we need more
responses than one person at leasts yeah
and we're entering a create where it's
gonna be hard to get sponsors to with
the whole guys coming up so it's gonna
be tough I mean we either wait for the
new year and do it again or well let's
you and I figure that out together but
ah but probably good ask if people in
the room think it's ready for a working
group last call yeah I mean we decided
that it was ready
you know previously but we haven't got
very few responses or basically one
response yeah but yeah I know should we
ask the room or just a good I mean okay
so as a chair how many people have read
this drafts to two people do you both
think it looks useful or yeah yeah I
should say we also have another a cert
packing draft that we will discuss later
and it's basically the same idea
I believe it's there's a number of pages
that are Paris comma G but similar to
join prints it might be useful to to
have multiple a long message okay I
guess we'll figure it out yes responses
now anyway it's doubled it yeah yeah
yeah so yeah you should go after those
people and get their feedback okay yeah
but I would say it's a challenge for
this working group in general to to get
people to respond in there yeah if
you're able to be great to have more
activity on the mailing list and more
responses in general okay okay I think
Toshi
is up let's find it you presenting okay
okay so hello everybody I'm Reese
controller from telefónica or could do
it with you Toshi a xylophone Nick in
this idea of multiple absolute interface
support for IEP
I am PMD proxy
so the idea well we were turned to
revive this the other we did take in
some time ago and now trying to be more
pushing a little bit more be more active
on on that so basically they they be
able be to having to support in a in the
proxy the capability of having multiple
option interfaces this enables a number
of use cases I will detail later on but
basically the point would be to make a
more efficient usage of the network and
also enabling new new situation so the
point will be basically to be able of
receiving the multi multicast packets
multicast content in both of these
interfaces according to different
situations different policies could be
applied to on top of that
so the we've mentioned there this one
possibilities like well receive a LT
wife a over so the day the the span of a
scenario sees is quite large and we will
take a little a bit later next slide so
the objective yeah basically to have the
possibility of receiving multicast
sessions because content in different
upstream interfaces the solution sohow
addresses the requirements that are
documented in in another draft this and
now progress in in the dependent stream
or stop actually progressing so who's
moved to the in the potential mission
stream and yeah there are get pain in
the comments to be addressed is somehow
has been in doermann by a while by one
year or so so ideal is also to push
again these other graphs on requirements
but basically a
we are looking at those requirements in
order to define the the solutions that
are and at the scope of this draft next
slide please
so regarding the benefits that we
foreseen if this was implemented is
basically having a flexible operation
so either we could select the do what is
they obscene interface based on the
subscriber that is requesting the
service or either even a in base of the
channel of the content that is being
provided so we could play with these two
alternatives let's say a part of this
flexible operation this solution could
enable a robust data reception because
we will be able even after the same
content receipt by the two interfaces
this could be one of the of the
situations and this enables only
scenarios of high availability for
instance in the network and all okay
even in other situations where we just
received the condemning in one of the
two we could have mechanisms for
protecting the the delivery of the
content and having a switch between
interfaces if required in order to have
the service alive yet even in the case
of events in the network
next in the use cases our refreshment on
this huh I will detail trying to tell a
bit different use cases that were
documented already in the requirements
draft one situation would be the
multicast wholesale offer for
residential services so we could it
could be the case that one operator
enables also enables also the delivery
of content from another provider an OTT
provided for instance in such a way that
a subscriber to this operator has the
opportunity to receive and a content
from either the own content or the
content from the this OTT provider
multicast resiliency for sure in the
case we have these two interfaces we
could or two or more interfaces we could
provide more resiliency to the delivery
of multicast traffic to the network load
balances for multicast traffic so in
this case we basically could take prof
the fact that the in a normal deployment
in the normal they mentioning of the
network for unicast traffic
we basically dimension the network with
a V of having a low and maximum load per
link of fifty percent of the traffic in
such a way that if a link goes down to
the link inducks of all the traffic in
normal conditions most of the time the
these capacities is bacon so having this
possibility of receiving traffic by
through more than one interface we could
take profit of that in order to use this
per capacity in the level for a receive
more content and only reducing the
available bandwidth in case of an event
so we could enable also these kind of
things also there are situations or
procedural real operational situations
were having more than one assume
interface would be beneficial like the
case of the network merging so you are
matching networks and and you have
different contents may be overlapping
the addressing of the content and so we
could play with this fact in order to
have a smooth integration of all
networks and finally the multicast
service migration so the same idea if we
need to somehow to migrate a service we
could enable a second interface a second
upstream interface for the migrated
content while keeping the ribbon another
interface for the old content so all of
this as I mentioned before is documented
in the requirement and draft so it's
available also for for you to check so
we in this solution drug we are
proposing to two ways two chances one
would be the automatic upstream
interface configuration to for this case
for this choice we have yet we need to
do some more investigation how to solve
the the point so here there is a list of
questions that we are trying to address
so for instance how the proxy can
automatically is like the appropriate
obscene interface for this channel so we
will show how to identify what would be
the required logic for doing that or
even if they would be required some kind
of signaling for enable that how the
procedure detect inactive obscene
interfaces maybe
checking the status of interfaces maybe
enable enabling messages for for that
and also starting to research
investigate is what could be the
triggers that would make the the proxy a
command switch from one absolute
interface to the other so these are open
questions I will try to address in the
next version next slide please
for the second choice that will be the
centralized control something like Sdn
basically what we would require is to
have a centralized controller that is
able to instruct the proxy in order to
use one interface of the other based on
either on the subscriber or in the
content or both so basically for that we
will require to define a kind of
interface in the proxy to for the
permitting the controller to configure
the proxy for the for this election one
benefit of this centralized view would
be that the controller could have a
centralized overview of all the the
proxies in the network and probably
coordinate all the mechanisms of
delivery instructing the proxies
accordingly in order to set up the
properties of not not at least but in
order to identify what is that they
appropriate absol interface for for
delivering the traffic and this could be
done based on information about
congestion you should recall is shown
etc so we could rely somehow also in
things like telemetry and so for having
these these kind of decisions next slide
please
so regarding the next steps already has
to keep the analysis to keep working on
the analysis without Maddie
configuration so understand what could
be the on stand train to figure out what
do with the scenary procedures for
enabling this they are in the
centralized approach sorry
trying to understand what would be the
implications on the interface that we
require for managing and controlling the
proxy and our idea will be to provide a
revised version of this draft before
next site even meeting and keep
discussing it is of interest for the for
the working group so any comment
to provide he's more than welcome and
that's all for my say thank you any
questions okay very good so this is
still on the individual track right yet
I mean that is that was the yeah the
plan forward and it's gonna stay on that
track well actually well actually the
the difficulties of this solution is
that we don't have automatic best
interface selection mechanism even in a
pinwheel out I think so but I'm not sure
so if some of you already know that
there is some good mechanism to detect
the let's say the interface that does
not have a good quality and different
interface that that has a good quality
for the same content then we can switch
back to the or we can just use that best
interface or better interface but even
in a long tie itself
I don't know how we can get such kind of
decision so if there is such kind of
mechanism in Pimlott or whatever then we
can just add up the same way make a new
into this one so the our header equi is
actually the topic we service the
selection mechanism for our jpml the
proxy upstream interfaces it's something
like a specific question our specific
topic but the discussion point or the
core question is actually really a
similar to the pin loudly so maybe so do
do some does some of you have some good
answer for that one
so the heat today made some presentation
about Sdn I like situation maybe that is
more feasible yeah so controller knows
the quality and that's why he made a
presentation today it's actually he's
from operator so he has a great
knowledge about operators point of view
so I'm not operator
his proposal mainly his proposal is with
Sdn like controller based solution if we
concentrate on that one
then maybe we may have a good chance to
provide a more complete solution for the
March perhaps 3-meter face selection
mechanism but for the pure distributed
mechanism like a ping lauter
autonomous routers so it's a really
difficult to address this kind of issue
what do you think yeah that's a good
point you have yeah so not sure how
relevant but I know this one
implementation that supports multiple
interfaces that makes you so the well it
means it's a team router to but it makes
use of the RPF interface to reverse the
RP address to towards GRP to determine
where to send a report so let's say you
have figure typical use case for this is
you have to pimp domains but you don't
want to run pin between them so you do
your P between the two pin domains but
the pim router dance downs the
downstream pim router what be configured
with two different IP addresses from two
different providers or something for
four different groups and and you might
use the RPF interface to figure out
which provider like where should you set
the LGP report for which group that's
just one example oh there could be other
ways so you know koala matically
determining where to send the report
well for the pin router the router
logging protocol
depends on our lanai on the LPF mekinese
but for the proxy it doesn't we cannot
rely on our PF interface so this is a
biggest difference from the proxy and
router because Roxy doesn't have the
unicast routing table toward the source
right so currently the proxy only decide
one single interface he doesn't have any
outing protocol allowing proto
bandar-log in table itself so always
fixed us one single interface this is a
problem so we don't would like to
address this kind of a situation the
reason why I think are you already
remember that wise so why the proxy
doesn't allow the multiple upstream
interface because it's just for the
simplicity reason so previously map in a
magma we discussed several time for this
kind of stopping but finally we decided
we should fix the single upstream router
and because proxy doesn't have any
routing protocol routing table so we can
just fix the simple oxime router and
that previously thing is over 15 years
ago it's sufficient but now it's not
optional so that's why we want to have a
multi-core interface but again we don't
have a locking protocol we don't have a
loading table
we cannot have this idea I hear you're
saying that but wouldn't the the proxy
often have a unicast routing table I
mean you want to be able to forward
únicos packets to the to the correct
upstream interface right yes but usually
it assumed that the external outside
like a home net so downstream is
something like home network the upstream
is a internet the internet so usually
the the downstream network segment is
something like a private network and
outside is external Internet but it
depends on the use case where it's a
home network or not but but least like
for instance you know you might like
prefix of prefix delegation but but
basically there are cases where you
might have a route saying that for
certain prefixes always want to route
the traffic to a certain provider and if
you have something like that then
especially for SSM you you know it would
make sense to send s Komachi reports to
to that already had a route for the
source right in that case the question
is in that case the dethklok's eBooks
allows multiple upstream interface that
is not defined in the policy no
no but yeah there's a lot of different
use cases and scenarios and I know in
some cases you don't have any
information
you basically just connected to two
providers you have a maybe a default
route for each and that's it mm-hmm so I
think the discussion so that draft
itself is really important and it's
really the lease and situation we need
this function but the problem is again
the solution may be a little bit
difficult except the situation using Sdn
are like them troller if we can just
concentrate Sdn based solution if
working besides maybe we can just
concentrate yeah depends what the
working group think is important but but
yeah I would say it's probably not a
good good idea to try to solve every
possible use case of non documents okay
okay
pick your up again yeah see there's some
interesting formatting here we looked
fun in the PowerPoint okay so this is
motivated by some working in beer so in
the beer working group we are working on
love an IBM PR MLD overlay to signal
interest in receiving certain flows
across the beer the beer network what we
figure though is that we don't get all
the information we need there's some
beer specific information that would be
quite useful to to receive via the
Audion pure ml d report so we have this
this side you have in beer we have some
other overlays like a pin overlay for
instance where we usage own attributes
that comes past this extra beer
information and we are looking for some
other way of doing this for a GMP or MLD
and what i came up with is there is this
additional data part in our MP ml d and
maybe we can use that to make an
extension and that's what this is about
so this sounds like it's gonna be all
beard but because we are responsible
responsible for our EMP and ml d in this
working group and it's kind of like a
big change I think it's important to do
it here so so this is beer specific but
it might be useful to have a generic way
of extending our GMP an ml d so let's
see yeah next slide so in our EMP
version 3 and Emily were since you RFC's
there is this text about additional data
for both queries and reports
it basically says that if the message is
longer than expected there is some
additional data at the end of the
message
you should check some everything but
usually otherwise they just ignore
whatever is there so it means that if we
were to sum up with some extra date at
the end existing implementations would
just ignore it which is great
next slide so what I'm proposing in this
draft is that if you have an idea peer
MLD message like in this case an IP
version 3 query at the end there in blue
there is like an extension type and
extent extension value so you could say
if you don't support some kind of
extension and you just ignore this
the current implementations would just
ignore it but if we if we want to do an
extension and say you support a specific
extension type then you check what comes
after there and you might say why do we
need an extension type why don't why
don't they just put the beer data at the
end but just in case someone comes up
within a few years so whatever with some
other reasons you extended your peer MLD
to be useful to have some type to
indicate what is this data and make sure
that that implementation doesn't
accidentally try to parse and think what
what is what is there next slide so
excuse me so even though I'm not
considering any other extensions I think
there's a chance at some point in time
it might want some other extension and
that's why I want to have this accession
type there and the idea is current
implementations would completely ignore
it based on the current RFC's if you
support the specific type in extension
and fine you process it if you don't
understand or don't support that type
then you again just ignore it like you
would do today for us
I haven't seen any bit trying to kind of
distinguish between what I think you
want to do right now which is kind of
ignore if you don't understand versus
the sorry this is not
backward-compatible please panic if you
don't understand it it's a narrow yeah
right
so one thing is i don't want to require
any changes to existing implementations
but yeah if you support but I mean
you're defining here watch what you do
if you support extensions and then then
something we could say is yeah if you
see an extension type you don't
understand them no it's it's it's it
sure like I mean I I was just thinking
that in the past we we had in other
protocols I'm trying to remember where
this this thing and I don't have a good
example right now but there are people
to consider that ya know certainly I
mean depending on what that extension is
you know it could be that it completely
changes how we used the data and the
message and if you just treat it as a
normal message it could be bad
somehow I'm not 100% sure but I giant
beaker he doesn't have a virgin number
field
it's right yeah it's based on the length
so they're right that's it right right
so currently hostile just recognize the
size of the Curie message and then the
some let's say 100 this is gesture for
example 100 bytes shirley is like a
virgin one 120 32 130 is version 3 like
this yes yes if you just add the query
message and it changes the length there
are the clear message you may fail if we
have the RGB version food right so yeah
let me comment on that so at least the
way it's defined now is RGB version 2 is
28 bytes maybe I'm not sure now it is a
certain size and if the message is
larger than that size then it's supposed
to be
sergeant Pearson three right partly
because at least for like a specific
query you know it that the length is
variable as well for version 3 so so
it's not always a fixed size but I get
your point
if we were to ever define Olympia worse
than 4 we would need maybe some other
tricks than just the length to decide
which which worse than this okay it's
something I'll look into that but yeah I
believe it should be whether it's the
minimum size or longer I and that this
is the Terminator okay I'll look into
that so about this extension types so
yeah I was saying how he would ignore it
if you don't support it and stuff also
would say though yeah mostly in general
it will be a non-starter to try to make
changes to IGMP queries and reports
because just millions some
implementations or deployments out there
and they wouldn't change but if there's
some extensions like in this case it's
beer specific then you know it might be
doable to expect at least those
implementations to change or there are
no implementations yet so that is
helpful as well okay next slide so so
that was about a generic part and then
there is this specific beer extension
I'll do this a little bit more quickly
it was presented in beer earlier today
as well but the main thing is the
purpose so this extension is to identify
who sent the message for beer we would
like to know the subdomain that beer
prefix and the B Friday like the beer I
D or the sender so we could potentially
have used the the source address so the
EMP or ml d message but we would prefer
to have all this information specified
and what I'm saying in this other graph
did not be working group is that that
mentioned on the top there is that you
should always use this extension so we
can know who it came from it's mostly
useful for reports but it could be
useful for queries as well if you want
to do some logging or something ok next
slide and this is what the extension
would look like so you would have your
normal id Imperium LD message and then
this will come at the bottom with some
extension type assigned by iana and then
the content itself next slide please
if there is one no no okay
so so one question is is it a good idea
to define a generic way of extending
this I would say if you do though you
know we should create a registry and we
set the requirements for creating a new
extension it should be something that is
strict we don't want people to come up
with lots of different extensions and in
this case for beer I'm at least the way
I'm arguing it is it would only be used
must only be used when you encapsulate
an attempt you MLD message inside beer
so it would not be seen by non beer
implementations if they do it though
accidentally see if they were just
ignore the extra data and the good thing
in this case it's only support need to
be supported by the beer routers that
originates or receive these messages and
there's no implementations today really
so it's not like we need to upgrade a
lot of implementations from Cisco so
question is more for the whole working
group instead of only you so so this
extends and I know that with beer
definitely it adds a lot of value but
are we expecting more of these kind of
use cases if some host or some
application who is using IGMP and wants
to add some extra context about join
membership requests it's
in future I mean I said today all the
hosts they work either in v2 or v3 mode
is it's more of stuck
it's stagnant that we don't we don't do
anything else in IGMP as of now but when
we are opening this channel so is it
good it is bad how it is it might add a
lot of value as well if there are some
new application coming they might want
to add some extra content or extra
context about what they expect from
upstream Wouter yeah yeah I mean I think
yeah I think I know you were us in the
group and happy to hear what others
think but yeah I think there could
potentially be some use cases and well
filo we you know in this working we
should be in control of what use cases
get sterilized so what extensions so if
someone has a use case we should
consider it here and see whether it
makes sense but yeah you could imagine
for certain cases that maybe some host
implementation for instance was
announced to support something new the
thing now is you can't expect devices in
general to support new extensions I
don't know if we could also be some
interesting things to think about
related to like sleeping and proxying
and stuff and what happens if some
support and extension and always do nots
and in the beer case at least it's
encapsulated and there's no no LTE
devices on the path so that's good
one question I have for the working
group is well one is is it okay to
extend our Jim PNM LD if we do is this
scheme reasonable with this extension
type another question is I'm trying to
figure out what should we do in this
group I what should we do in beer and
there was some discussion about that in
beer this morning too so I feel like the
extension mechanism itself should
definitely be done in this working group
but the actual beer TLV that you see
here that could potentially be done in
the beer working group depending on what
people think
mom come not from it Cisco so I think
yeah you clearly mentioned that this
part of the work can go to be a working
group and I really feel that I am
extension defining a new and you might
be good there might be new use cases
coming in future from multicast and host
might not be just hosts what they are
today they might be some kind of
application which can do much more than
just doing a jumpin so yeah it would it
would it would open new opportunities
there to do something yeah yeah okay so
yeah that's an offer I'm curious whether
you know this can be adopted or what
interest rates and they group or okay so
who who's read this draft of those two
hands do you think it's ready to be
adopted by the yeah okay so obviously we
need to ask the same question in the
list but yeah so yes some other way in
in beer working with we have this
overlay draft that has its adopted that
has been around for a long time and to
progress that it would be good to get
this done
sorta quickly if we can I mean I may
have been confused but its own is if you
mention in beer something like it was
first onion work one working group or
some other document had first been done
in on working group and then thrown over
the fence was they actually something
like that because as long as we don't
find another example then the beer one
it might be better to kind of bring it
into good shape and beer first alright
so I think that's that's a little bit
what I what I'm worried about that you
know how do we verify that this is in
good shape without another example that
that's best done in beer right so yeah I
mean if you ask me as some
offer or whatever I mean I'm also
working on that Amidala drafted beer I
feel like it makes sense to do this
option in beer actually and and you know
there's been like tlvs for our GPS and
so on to that were defined in beer
because the actual use case of the
option how it is handled what you put in
there and so on that's all beer
specifics so my current thinking now if
you guys agree is view this the
definition of this actual option into
the MLD overlay drafted beer which is an
existing working with document in beer
and just focus on the extension scheme
and the registry and their rationale for
having extensions in general in this
group I think I think it would be good
to have a second example right I mean
just even if just yeah even if we don't
want to standardize it just you know is
there any way for us to to better vet
the idea of extensibility so what would
shake one example alright so one thing I
know is I think some people have been
suggesting putting like me and I or Ian
ID or something into what is that like
you know for me excellent whatever so
you can know the context or some context
identify in general if you have like
births as well well I mean Greg is
sleeping so I mean either the obvious
idea coming to mind which would be the
same would be something like if you do
it that for rsvp-te or so if you want to
build a point-to-multipoint tree would
that have something like similar
properties because you need to know the
leaf some specific identifiers not that
I would want to do it right but yeah
just that we kind of vet the
extensibility somehow yeah another thing
there's been a proposal in this working
group for reliable IGMP or saying that
you said an AK or something so for
instance you know you could have an
extension in our GMP queries saying I
support a core please sit on a core
whatever or yeah I Cisco so I think I
good steak actually got he's taking a
right approach here that's a there's
undefined space now that you can use but
you cannot use it once for beer right
you have to put his steel research in
place so other features can be added
later
so splitting that into drafts want to
define that you have a structure and one
in beer as a use case I think that's
perfectly enough to do this right you
don't need to another use case I think
yeah I should also say at least my
thinking is I don't want to go overboard
I mean in theory we could define some
kind of a GMP options like how options
we could add like lots of theories and
so on but I'm intentionally thinking
it's best to keep it as simple as
possible
all I want is this identifier to just
make sure that it doesn't conflict with
other possible extensions in the future
maybe maybe I wasn't expressing myself
while I'm certain I'm not saying that
the document itself should have a text
about additional examples it was just
kind of if we had a discussion just in
terms of okay you know each of us thinks
about something and then we feel more
safe that you know it will work for
extension right so that's great and I
certainly be happy to hear from from
people will yeah yeah that sounds good
okay okay so yeah sounds good thanks so
there's up next while you're coming up
just to confirm with the working group
we've had an understanding with the
spring working group that they are not
chartered to work on multicast related
type stuff in the spring working group
there's been a little bit of question
recently because they had something
added to their Charter and so people
were kind of curious if that was the
case so this is Ian and I had a
conversation about this earlier so just
an hour ago in the the ad the spring
eighties and and chairs agreed that
spring is indeed not chartered to work
on that type of work that they expect it
to be done here in pym and if we need
their help or get their feedback and
you should we should do so we were under
this understanding that we could always
put things back to them if we need to
but it sounds like there's not any plan
for that to even anytime soon to take
place there's not gonna be any change so
does anybody have any questions or
comments on that before hooman goes that
that's our understanding so if we were
to adopt we were certainly free to adopt
these kind of drafts is what I is what
our point is yeah also I think hopefully
we'll mention this as part of your
presentation so there is this one draft
being considered for adoption and spring
that is like a replication option or
something but this is kind of going
further with with that so so this small
part might be done in screen we might
consider yeah exactly maybe if you can
bring up this slide so oh yes yeah so if
you can't go to the next slide but let
me let me start from a score one what
what this graph is trying to achieve so
currently when it comes to the transport
and mainly in in 5g and some of these
converge course signal routing is
playing a big role when it comes to
traffic engineering slicing you guys
heard about a slicing at lunchtime
segment routing is eight and that's
because of the controller has the view
of the entire network it simplifies the
overlay it simplifies the underlay it
actually signals the MPLS labels via IGP
and all those good stuff that you guys
know so the issue becomes that when we
go to providers and we try to sell them
sigma routing if they have any multicast
type of services that is running
currently NL DP or point-to-multipoint
rsvp-te and the question becomes i want
to say in MPLS type of
transport but now I have all these MPLS
signaling that I removed from unicast
what should I do and this is where this
draft and this idea comes into play
so basically when it comes to the
transport it's the same transport that
we have today in MPLS it's just an
incoming label outgoing interfaces and
outgoing labels so there's nothing
changed on the data path of the MPLS
it's just how we nailed down the
point-to-multipoint tree this idea says
let's use the controller to nail it down
previously we were using signaling like
LVP and rsvp-te so that's the only part
that this draft is trying to resolve
it's trying to simplify multicast remove
some of the current legacy and I used
that term careful in Legacy multi called
multicast protocols and moving to the
Sdn controller if you can go to the next
so here's a brief a story how it started
I think my previous explanation kind of
explaining you know what was the theme
behind this idea now we have started
introducing a draft in is free spring
source routing multicast every single
node you have a state and you need to
make a decision at every single node on
transit or even on the leaf so it's not
so much of a source routing when it
comes to the multicast and that's where
they become a little bit of what's the
right border clash maybe not on what's
the right word to use here in the spring
Charter saying that this is not source
routing because every single router has
to make a decision and this is why we
introduced one draft in this spring
it's a replication segment I'll explain
later on what the application
replication segment is but the bulk of
the work which is the point to
multi-point policy how the whole thing
works we decided to bring it into the
pane just
we felt like you know there is more
multicast expertise here and you know
they can address this point multi-point
three better in NP mattered in in
signaling so this is how the
architectural Draft has been a slice and
dice as of now there is one a small
graph in segment routing in a spring the
reason that we put it there at the end
of the day this draft talks about seats
it talks about policies and a little bit
of signal routing so we needed to have
something there but then as you will see
in the next slides the entire idea is a
point-to-multipoint three and and the
bigger architectural draft is is gonna
be we are hoping that is going to be
worked on in this working so next slide
please so here are some other relevant
draft do you guys can go through it so
the entire idea is T there is to
architectural draft the PMS our
point-to-multipoint policy which we're
gonna explain here the replication
segment it's a very a small subset of
the point-to-multipoint policy so the
point-to-multipoint policy actually
covers the replication segments and and
the bigger picture and then there is a
yang draft which we put in the spring as
of now to you I don't know whatever you
need to bring that into the PM or not we
can discuss that but if you look at the
yang it kind of explain how their
architecture is it gives you a good
overview of what this whole idea is all
about and then we need to have
southbound and northbound
I guess communication between the router
and the controller and that's where the
two last draft is there's a PCE draft
that actually takes care of a Southdown
and also there is acknowledgment a
northbound from the node to the to the
controller and then obviously the sexy
one is IDR point-to-multipoint policy
for pgps RTS
that's another way to actually program
this screen so there's two way of
programming the tree depending on the
operator they can either choose PCE or
they can choose point to multiple
and as our bgp depending on what they
were so next slide so maybe we can for
the sake of time go through the next few
slides like you can skip the next slide
and go to the one with a pretty picture
usually pictures explain much much
better so here's a the entire
architecture of point-to-multipoint
policy so on the route there is a policy
that actually displays the the root node
and the leaf node so you go under decree
the point of multiplying policy you say
what are the Leafs how you learn the
Leafs it could be manually configured on
the controller or you could actually
have the controller listening to the NP
bgp bgp multi-protocol communication
that is going between the route and
between the Pease and learn the Leafs
weird about that communication so that's
how you build your point-to-multipoint
policy their route builds up the
point-to-multipoint policy it uses P SEP
as of now to shoot all that information
to the controller so the controller then
understands where the route is where the
Leafs are and because it has the view of
the entire network it can create a
point-to-multipoint tree and download it
to the routers now there are a couple of
ideas here and the first one is a
candidate path so these ideas are not
new to this graph like a candidate pad
if you look at the SR policy unicast our
policy all these ideas are already there
we are just using them so a candidate
path within a point-to-multipoint policy
simple term is LSP redundancy so under
that policy could create multiple
point-to-multipoint LSPs and they can be
redundant based on the preference the
one with the highest preference is the
active point-to-multipoint tree now each
one of those cat candidate pads you can
optimize them globally so there is fast
reroute concept here let's say one of
those candidate paths because of a
failure goes into a fast reroute you can
optimize it globally and that's where
the ins
ideas come into play so each candidate
pad can have two point-to-multipoint LSP
instances and those are actually used
for global optimization and make before
break on the root note so if one of
those instances is doing a fast reroute
the controller can compute a brand-new
tree with with the SLA s that are in the
laser that are relevant to that
multicast path and download the second
instance and on the head end you can do
a make before a break between one to the
other
now the trick is the point-to-multipoint
policy doesn't have any forwarding
information and that's where the
replication policies come in
so the replication of policy maker long
is very short it's really impaired less
as of now instruction incoming label
outgoing labels that's it that's all
there are some tricks that you got to
keep in mind as an example in this
diagram node a and node C are connected
via node B but not being is not
multicast ever it doesn't understand
multicast so you can actually connect
node a to node C which both have
replications segments via a unique SSR
so you can stack up labels if you are
going to a unique ass domain but as soon
as you get to a multicast domain and you
need to do a multicast replication you
need to have the replication policy and
you need to be having an incoming label
and your outgoing interfaces so this is
the the very high-level idea of this
draft next slide please
so I put a couple of examples together
just for like a case study so in this
case we have a route that is on North a
and we have two leaves which is T and E
so what will happen is that if there's n
P BGP going on between piece between a T
and E a we learned that router D and
router
or actually beliefs it's gonna send that
information to the controller the
controller will create a
point-to-multipoint
policy with those information and it's
going to note the tree ID and it
multicasts tree needs to have a
identifier and that identifier is a tree
ID it builds a candidate that gives the
preference of 1,000 as an example to the
candidate path it goes to note a C D and
E it creates the replication segments
and all these nodes that said sorry
it goes on node a C D and E because b is
not multicast ver that said when it goes
on note a it creates a seat list that
says push B which is the unicast C and
then push C which is a multicast
replication C so in this case if the
packet comes in on a is actually going
to push be on top of the stack see at
the bottom of the stack the packet goes
to B B just does normal segment routing
pops the label forwards it to C which is
a replication segment and the
replication segment gonna say that your
outgoing interfaces are DNA and here the
labels that you need to use to shoot the
packet is the forwarding state with this
replication sit effectively the same
what I have an N LD p or rsvp-te kind of
if I'm using SR MPLS I got one incoming
label look that up get a list of
outgoing labels the other absolutely so
why do we need to reinterpret this in
the SR terminology so that's that was my
first friend right off the bat when it
comes to the data path it is the same
it's just that because of the controller
each router gonna have a segment and
this is this is all just terminology
right I mean I could simply have MPLS
terminology for the same thing but what
is what is Sigma routing it's MPLS so
like if you look at UNICAMP nice it's
have F some slightly you know
more abstraction right the fact that
you're heading on a per hop basis on
seats that are forwarded by that are not
local sit but global sits right on every
forwarding hope you're changing the
offset that's the key difference you're
not using this year I think right so so
on there is traffic engineering involved
here because of the controller has the
whole view of the of the network we are
not in the mercy of IGP so the
controller can create a tree through the
network for that's for the district you
can create different and slices through
the network for the same
point-to-multipoint policy no I
understand that all I'm saying is that
I'm not persuaded they're trying to
apply the city terminology to what the
forwarding plane is doing is the correct
thing right it looks to me more like
normal
MPLS forwarding state on every hop right
that that I have in ml DP rsvp-te so
whereas it's as I said right ARP you
know network of network wide relevance
with you know per have sets that are
changing so that's why I mean I think to
me the use of CID is more confusing than
helpful
I mean sure we can definitely talk about
that yeah good point I mean we can talk
about if you come up with points here
this is why this is a sit right I mean
that would be be helpful to write down
otherwise why does it do it all I'm
saying the the other point was a with sr
v6 how does it work because I mean is
this kind of prop D cap and re and cap
logic we we haven't skin that cat yet
you want to because I mean yes we
definitely yeah we want to we are
working on a draft for sr v6 but let's
get let's get this one through first the
MPLS the planing pls and then we'll get
to their services but yes there is
something I've worked because I mean we
do have nice address spaces where
effectively this
thing could simply be setting up
aesthetic you know a replication tree
for you know right I'm saying kind of
again the same thing of oh yeah
everything has to be segment routing
where in the end what kind of controller
built you know static tree right which
we've done forever I'm saying if you
want to run with ipv6 right you don't
and you don't need to try to kill
yourself by making this look like SR v6
with D cap and rien cap you're simply
having you know your encapsulation
destination address in ipv6 multicast
address and you're effectively setting
up controller based replication state
for that right
so again yeah I appreciate the comment
for SRB six so we wanted to make this
very simple
right b1 the MPLS one as one single
draft because we want to pass it true
you guys have been in the spring you've
seen all the conversation on a survey
six right yeah so I think that's fine
right III I'm pointing to the fact that
I think this this thing might fly it
easier the more we're trying not to
fiddle it through you know the needle of
trying to make it look like a segments
routing but just you know using
controller based established MPLS
forwarding or when we go to v6 you know
controller based traffic engineering of
existing v6 Nautica's now okay point ik
nice just like okay so here's a example
of global optimization so previously we
had candidate Pat one and then there is
a failure which was going ABC now there
is a failure between B and C so the
controller kind of realizes that in the
draft there is a fast reroute that he
can actually do a fast reroute between
link protection and you can go through G
to make it all the way back up to C but
then the controller tries to optimize
that path so it's gonna create an second
instance for the same candidate path and
it's gonna nail down the replication
segments for that second instance
throughout the network so basically what
that means that
is on each note C G D and E you're going
to have to replication segment one for
the previous primary one and one for the
instance to LSB ID two throughout the
network when the second instance is
nailed down throughout the network you
go on on a on the route and you do a
make before break and you that's how you
do global optimization on the point to
multiplying Policy hidden so Nexus
likely or if there's a gum so here's
another example with regard to the
candidate pad itself you want to have
LSP redundancy you want to give
different preferences so there's a
candidate path with preference 1000
there is a candidate pad with preference
100 by the way that letter flashing
should shouldn't be in this slide I
think a copy page that mistakenly so
that the first candidate path gonna go
through the north direction a b c d e
and you create the second candidate path
that goes through the south direction a
B G D and E and this is how you can have
LSB redundancy throughout your entire
network so this is the basic idea
without going to through too much detail
on the fast reroute on other stuff I
think the the seat comment that was that
was put under the table you know we can
definitely discuss that the reason that
we decided to go with replication series
obviously because we had an innerspring
right so so what are we trying to
achieve with with this draft if you
could go to the next slide please
it's just just a quick comment right I
mean that either you can you can do I
think what is less work and in pitches
up to the people who already got MPLS
multicast deployed whether it's RSVP T
or ml DP by naming this what I think it
is which is you know controller based
MPLS multicast or you're trying to you
know go through
more hoops and making it you know sound
like SR because it's a better marketing
term which i think is where this was
coming from I understood I do have a
question are these SIDS so because III
confess I read it and I inferred from my
reading and I'm I probably skipped many
words in the process of reading because
I was an early that day like I usually
am I I presumed that they were SIDS so I
I thought there was it would be a sit at
D and a sit at E and and so on upstream
towards the root for every point in the
network where some sort of multicast
awareness was required and that these
were indices into a table that would
then give you a multi-car a label for
which D for example would map and
understand when it saw that label
incoming and that that to me is a SID so
our SIDS or not so here's the thing we
all know when it comes to a spring and
segment routing you can go on and pls
back on you can start stacking up sits
right what is a sit it identifies a
resource within the network what are the
resources right it's adjacency see and
know what see and based on the label
stack you can traffic engineering source
route your LSP throughout the entire
network with multicast you cannot grab
replication seats and start stacking
them up the reason for that is that when
you get to a point that you have
actually you're like a branching point
in multicast
and if you have stacked up seats then
you don't know on north direction which
seats are relevant on south direction
which seats are relevant that's the
issue with multicast that said the
reason that we keep calling a CID is
because this entire idea can work in a
unicast it could be actually source
routing source spraying so you could
actually go on the head and router
create a replication seat and that
replication seat is actually built from
unicast adjacency seats binding seats
Nord seats all the way to the leaf so
multi-hop unicast seats all the way to
the leaf and the leaf has another
replication see which just says this is
multicast on the leaf that's higher so
this is the entire idea that's why we
call it a replication seat because it's
really identifying a multicast resource
a multicast seed within the network now
it's how you skin the cat you could skin
the cat and say that you know this is
MPLS label and I'm gonna add a bunch of
unicast sitting on top of a tooth so a
CID ultimately results in getting a
label when you're using an MPLS data
plane yes but the city itself isn't a
label they may be identical values and
then the recommendation is that they are
identical values but it is a it's an
index into a place where you find the
MPLS label value is that true of these
or not yeah this is exactly so even with
these ones we actually grab so I did
understand yeah yeah so it's it's it
could be globally assigned it could be
locally assigned because of the
controller so that is exactly it has to
be in done in coordination with the
boxes that will process that's it so
they understand what the hell it means
yes exactly yeah as I said as long as we
stick with MPLS the distinction of
whether we calling it MPLS right or SIDS
is a lot more subtle but the problem is
as soon as we starting calling its it
we're running into the likely dead end
then you know we're doing something a
lot more complicated with v6 right as
opposed to keeping you know just as a
single you know just making it native VC
three established by the controller
right with some you know v6 multicast
destination address where every existing
ipv6 multicast router could you know
from the controller build an engineer
tree that's basically you know if you
want to have backward compatibility
right for people that like to do things
from the controller that is the only
thing you'd be able to do right now
anything where you would have to do
rewrites you know in SR v6 on every hop
is not going to fly with any of the
existing equipment let's just say I'm
not guessing I just go so I think here
the is the label I don't think
there's an indirection here right
because you carried that in the
packet and that's what you used to find
your next application so I don't think
there's a difference between what you
call a and the label so no but
they're those seats are can be a sign
but so I can go let me put it I think
you need to unpack FRR and a bunch of
other stuff rather than skipping it over
to sort of get at all of this and I
agree on there and and I think that it
would be really good if we rather than
having an oversimplified presentation
spend some time thinking about this so
so this was exactly the point of this
present and I am absolutely agree with
you it was just to bring some awareness
to this so you know on the next ITF we
can go in more details about fast rerun
on all these other stuff so the argument
for the sit if you really want to go
that way right which I'd prefer not to
do because if I want to talk to people
with the you know existing deployments
with MPLS that's not only the easier
solution but better marketing for me but
as I said the difference between the
cities when it goes across multiple Hopf
and then basically every how change is
the offset right so that's basically
something you want to have anyhow right
then that's a good argument to call it
is it so that so when we started with
this it was just a global seed that
represents the point of multi-point
three right so a single label was
presenting that tree on every single
router
right but now that would be tree-sit
more than a replication sit yes now
exactly did ya need to net get new
glasses I'm sorry so now when it comes
to the replication see each one of these
router can have its own seat area if you
will can have its own bucket that will
choose the label from that bucket so
what happened with the tree said I'm
sorry I didn't follow that so it could
be either it could be the controller
creates a three seat and to NH one of
this replication policies gonna have the
same label
or it could be uniquely each one of this
replication policy is gonna have a label
or a seat that is relevant to that now
no but what I'm saying is that a tree
sit that is consistent through the whole
networking it's not going to be written
on every hop it's something you can
translate into SR v6 yeah but I want to
keep like this this is exactly why we
try to keep their service six out of
this if you if if you don't want to
think about the different transport
options for something you call a segment
routing solution you shouldn't call it a
segment routing solution so then the
next the next slide please so the next
step is I think we had the the sip
argument in in the spring too so this
the next step is we are hoping that we
can have a working group adaptation in
came and work on this whole idea and in
the pink yeah like if you guys can adopt
this draft on the pink group you know I
mean if there is interest why not so
who's read this draft one two three four
five six of those six hands who do you
do you feel that this dress should be
adopted one two okay just we're not
raising their hand right I mean except
for reading all the details but it is I
really
think that the draft the way you
presented it still struggles off of oil
defining you know where it wants to be
right so I'm all for having you know a
controller based you know forwarding
scheme for existing MPLS multicast
hardware but the way that this is being
done you know with calling it segment
routing and you know only carrying
calling it technical thing but not
caring about both transport for it that
that those seem to be really sure again
of he scoping issues that did we should
we should discuss yeah definitely we can
have a I'm not sure if I understand your
is our v6 argument but you can have
offline yeah I think that it's highly
premature to ask for working group
adoption I think that at some point down
the road when you've actually answered a
bunch of these questions and thought
about it more and maybe gotten some more
participation from others to help you
think about it it could work out but
it's way too soon for that
yeah we are completely open to the
questions here I mean please send the
questions to the working group man
definitely have a look thank you yeah
add that you know it seems to be in
charter and it's okay to do the work
here and we're happy to discuss it here
but yeah it may be too early to actually
adopt it okay I'll go quick we have a
Bobby about five ten minutes and then I
cannot over committed myself so we we
need to move on if you haven't signed a
blue sheet please do so where's the blue
sheet here anybody you need to sign it
yeah okay can you get that D in that'd
be great
okay so I presented this draft to ITF
segoe so I don't need to go into too
much detail but I'll quickly go through
it it's basically trying to find a way
to optimize asserts in the occasional
situation where you could have a lot of
messages a lot of certain messages on a
land whether it be in an exchange or
some other type of environment
when you've got a lot of asserts this is
a way that you can pack asserts into a
particular packet to kind of reduce the
reduce the traffic on a particular line
if you can go to if you can be our my
slide guy
so this that's the problem and just go
to the next one if you would just keep
going alright so there's no change in
the assert state machine we do develop a
new pinhole option for assert packing
and we have two different ways if we
decide that this is something that we
want to do as a working group we have a
simple packing solution in a more
involved packing solution next slide so
this is the PIM hello option to
determine whether this is a something
that these the routers on a land can do
next slide so if you're announced that
you support the a the aggregates packing
then it's a student you also support a
simple one yes the the one is a simple a
packing type in the two is a grading
Pepe so to support both do some to hello
I'm ever you ask this question or and I
don't remember we I don't think we've I
think we've answered that one thing I
would sent a good question so just this
maybe you say if you support yeah
aggregate them it's assumed that you
okay so that's a good point won't add to
the draft if we pursue it thank you so
this is a simple way to go about doing
it you just take that existing assert
and put it into an assert record and add
it several of these asserts records into
one particular packet need there's
advantages in that it reduces the
packets on the land but there's
disadvantages because the disadvantage
is that you're you you have you you're
wasting the payload because many of the
packets have the same sourcing group
next slide and this is the packet format
next slide I just yeah this is the more
involved aggregating packet solution
where you are aggregating based upon the
source address of the
Arpi address or the group address and so
you're not you say you're more efficient
in the packing method but it's a little
bit more involved adds complexity next
slide and this is the packet format yeah
that's fine this is good out there just
for the sake of time yeah so people can
look at that later so there was a lot of
discussion last time I presented this on
whether this is something that's worth
doing to assert should we pursue it or
just leave asserts alone do we if we do
want to pursue it so we replace asserts
some people mention that you really just
don't do asserts and just live with
duplicates and this draft is saying well
there's one option is to optimize
asserts and so there was some people who
mentioned that it would be you know this
could be a good idea there's many people
that said this is probably not something
that's worth doing and so we thought
we'd just bring it to the working group
again since it's been a couple working
groups and to see if the attitudes
changed at all if there is interest in
in working on this if so then we will
continue to work on it
any comments yes I have a couple of
comments just as a working with
participants yes
so sure it could be nice to get
completely but I think we have to live
with asserts in my scenarios or less
forever so I think it's I think it's
worth optimizing asserts if you can't
get waited on grades but but if he
counts them but it's better to optimize
it i I know law so well actual issues
out there in the field where there's
issues with a cert packets getting
dropped and stuff because there's just
too many asserts and if you drop on a
Start packet bad things happen like
duplication and stuff so I think this is
worth doing I mainly have two comments
one is a lot convinced that the more
advanced packing is necessary you still
have a huge
benefits just with us simple packing I
mean if you send the 1500 byte packet
you will be able to learn what's the
math you can put quite a few a search
until one packet if you do jumbo grants
you can get a lot more the only thing is
I don't understand in your advanced
format while you have an RP address
there because you don't tell an RP
address in the starts today sourcing
groups yeah you want just source of the
serie with it's like an start G assert I
think that's true
so G right that wouldn't be needed
you're right I mean in the way logical
it makes sense because all all the
eskimo G's in the message are for the
same RP but I don't think you actually
need RP address okay okay well we'll
consider whether we even include the
more advanced in the draft anyway maybe
take your advice to only focus on simple
I mean in a way it makes total sense
because you have all these metrics the
same metrics file off to ask emoji often
but on the other hand here maybe it's
not worth the complexity okay so won't
need a Tatarstan list but can you ask
the working group all right so who wrote
this draft okay
two people three three people might wait
okay three people no does that well it's
who thinks it's useful or actually I
should say who should thinks it should
be adopted okay including myself
I think there's three people that read
it and two people wants to be adopted I
[Music]
think we can take it to the list if
you've been presenting this a couple of
times now and there is something some
interest it's okay very good thank you I
think we're done yeah all right thanks
everyone thanks for coming
and I'm Bondi by the way is in this room
just after this so please don't leave
the room and body
you're permitted to leave but please
come back there is some coffee or
something laughter I mean I feel like it
makes sense maybe say certain qualities
are you so lucky never certain scenarios
but what the actual you know
[Music]