and icon yes
welcome to qi RG quantum internet
research group still proposed as of our
current status let's see I am rod Van
Meter and I will be running today's
meeting welcome and the blue sheets have
just begun now circulating around so
please sign in as the blue sheets come
around let's see so we have both a
scribe and a and a note-taker setup
Thank You let's say so today you all
know where and when we are for those of
you who are new to what we're doing just
a quick review of the current status the
idea of this a writ was originated by
Stephanie in Stephanie Vayner in January
of 2018
I presented remotely at the IRT F open
in March 2018 the mailing list opened
that month it's ongoing the the traffic
level is sort of low to moderate we were
approved as a proposed RG on November
6th last year in Bangkok or just prior
to Bangkok and the tentative proposal is
or was to to meet one time a year at RT
F once a year at a quantum conference
and once per year at in a virtual or
online meeting so far we have actually
achieved three face-to-face meetings at
IETF s 103 104 and 106 and so far for
online meetings all in the last couple
of months focusing on one of the drafts
in particular the Wojtek is leading and
so far we actually have not held a
meeting at one of the
quantum related meetings that will
happen hopefully sometime next year
let's see so agenda administrivia blue
blue sheets going around note-taker we
have done scribe agenda if anyone has
any comments at this point on the agenda
and the RG documents we have three
active drafts which we will be looking
at there's a fourth report to there
under RG business on qkd in SSL and then
I hope to run an open mic discussion for
about 20 minutes or so I spent some time
last night this morning updating a list
of proposed topics for discussion
including whether or not we whether and
how to move from proposed RG to our Jeep
or perhaps in Vancouver suggestions for
the next meeting date advice from the
floor on what and how to move that our
existing IDs to our FCS beyond whatever
gets discussed about the documents
themselves and a couple of things that
we one thing that came up on the mailing
list
just recently denial of service attacks
and integration of quantum internet
services into the larger internet
there's no documents associated with
that but it's been actively discussed on
the mailing list if anybody has any
comments during the open mic section and
also potentially a list of things to
take on next including suggestion from
from the mailing list on qkd
architecture or how to integrate qkd
into the internet architecture naming
and addressing of nodes came up early
this year and has not been and has sort
of gotten pushed aside as a discussion
issue routing quantum resistant crypto
or PKI and how do you integrate that in
and security of the networks all of
these things came up earlier so any
suggestions comments questions on the
agenda
: hey Colin partners just a note that
some of the security working groups have
quantum resistant crypto things to make
sure you're talking to them yes
absolutely the point would be the point
of doing that in this venue would be to
coordinate with them rather than rather
than have it go on in some some way
that's completely unrelated to IETF or
IR gf Thanks anything else on the agenda
the details of these specific items we
can talk and we can talk about in the
latter part of the meeting itself if not
first item up white deck draft IRT fqi
RG principles let's say you want to use
this device all right let me find the
slides architectural principles of a
quantum Internet how's that okay
everybody I'm gonna talk about the work
we've been working on on the draft on
the architectural principles of the
quantum Internet there's a brief recap
as a brief recap the first version was
prepared and presented at the IETF in
Prague in March the main motivation for
bringing it forward to the key are G's
to address actually one of the charter
points which is that to create an
architectural framework delineating
network node roles and definitions to
build a common vocabulary and serve as
the first step toward a quantum network
architecture and also because the IETF
is mostly people who don't know quantum
mechanics at all and also to create a
good starting point for people with no
quantum background and kind of service
that document you would read if you want
to kind of understand what the
challenges problems are and how do these
things relate to the other work done in
the IETF
the draft was adopted and at that
meeting
after that first meeting I received a
lot of comments but the first round of
comments was actually mostly either
editorial or they're very vague
open-ended questions would be good to
add this would be good to do that and so
towards like in the run-up to this
meeting and I eventually organized some
web calls through which we started
actually going through these open-ended
questions as a group rather than just me
hiding away and trying to do all that as
part of that I've set up the work on
github we're not actually it's
convenient because it lets us share
updates at a finer granularity then they
strike her and do convene diffs and
people know who know good help know how
to navigate it but we're still doing all
discussions to the mailing list and
essentially I don't think there was
enough inertia to move too much to get
to github so before view I will actually
go into more detail for those who don't
actually and I was going on but a brief
overview of the changes since March 3
new authors have been added and multiple
small editorial changes has been updated
to the security stuff in the draft and
I've we've reworked two sections to
essentially better address the concerns
and provide a better understanding of
the situation to people with a
networking background but no quantum
background for those who have been
monitoring the mailing list not all
contributions have been reflected that
have been made and the run-up to the
meeting essentially goes busy in Penang
getting sunburned on my shins instead
rather than incorporating changes and so
here's a list of the things I still well
as a group we still need to do a run has
provided quite a lot of comments by only
incorporated some of them and to do with
section 4 and 5 but there's still quite
a lot to go through there is a sub
section written by Sarah and my fellow
about link generation I just have to
incorporate still and there's a pull
request and github from Patrick about
encodings which I still have to actually
look at so what were the major updates
the major updates are to do with
security and
works and it's kind of actually an
interesting thing security I think
because we do kind of have a clean slate
and it's kind of not a secret that
security is kind of poor on the non
quantum internet and so it would be good
to get a right especially since one of
their selling points of building quantum
networks is better security so I think
it would be good not to kind of delegate
it to a second-rate question which is
too easy to do and there are two updates
to Section four section four is
essentially about a kind of a more clear
description of what's the lifecycle of
entanglement in the network entanglement
being the key resource in a contra
network as you created used in delivered
and updated section five intercept
because essentially it's not clear to
the non quantum audience is that a
classical the number there that a
non-core network which is what we call
classical network is actually a key part
of a quantum network the quantum network
won't exist in isolation it will heavily
lean on and use the networks built we
already have like the public Internet
and hence we will have a dual quantum
classical data plane so what was the
update to security essentially that the
point is in a quantum network user data
is not actually and enter the network
and the network delivers so-called
entangled pairs and these entangled
pairs are used to teleport the user data
by passing the network however there are
still security considerations because
you can leak information which could
allow a malicious third party to
intercept your communication and there's
obviously also questions about
authenticity integrity stuff
however most crypto applications and
most security applications essentially
do that kind of security at the
application level and so as long as the
quantum network kind of satisfies the
model of a entangled pair source and the
network itself should not tackle at all
the questions of integrity
confidentiality and authenticity that's
up to the application and and an
interesting question is because it's
fidelity which is the quality of the
entanglement you deliver if it's less
than one kind of means you've leaked
information but because it's not it's
not actually
doesn't mean here communication is not
less secure it actually just means that
your applications will have a lower rate
because they have to abort more attempts
than they would otherwise with a with
better entanglement however and so that
was just about end-to-end security but
there's also obviously a lot of security
in the network and I was actually
ordinary mentioned on the question that
kind of came up but it's not actually
considered well yet are things like
denial of service attacks and kind of
network level threats and which as far
as I know are completely untouched I've
put a point that I think it's likely
will piggyback on classical solutions
but I actually have no idea there's a
question mark of whether this should
actually make it into this draft another
major update and was an update to the
life cycle of entanglement and as we
read tend to clarify the whole process
for the purposes of and now the reader
with a networking background by with no
quantum background and again when I
wrote the draft first I kind of wrote it
from my perspective which is a physicist
perspective with networking knowledge
and but that's not actually the audience
we're targeting so based on the calls it
was kind of a lot of issues where they
became clear as to where we should
clarify etcetera so as part of those
changes so first in the updated section
we illustrate now the challenges to do
with what what's the main challenge of
in a quantum network and essentially in
a quantum network with there some major
challenges are the fact such as the
measurement problem in a classical
network you can look at your packet you
can actually read the headers and you
can relive in the user data if you so
wish and you can't do that in a quantum
network when you do you destroy your
data and your entire state so you cannot
do that which kind of already already in
that it makes copying difficult and why
what makes copying really difficult is
the no-cloning theorem you cannot
actually copy anything in the quantum
world copying is basically how you do
networking and you can't do that in
classical and quantum networking at all
it's just physically impossible it's not
a it's not a technological limitation I
was actually key to know this is
a fundamental limitation of quantum
mechanics and the last challenge is
fidelity so in quiet in classical
networks when you deliver a packet you
basically either deliver it perfectly or
you don't so you drop it by checking the
checksum if it doesn't match you drop it
and quantum networks delivering a
perfect state is incredibly challenging
technologically potentially impossible
but also most applications don't
actually need perfect states so they can
actually get away with in perfect states
and the key point to note about that is
that imperfect states means you can
deliver them faster so there's a
trade-off between the quality of state
and the rate which you can deliver
things however as I point out below a
kind of mixed trends these kind of
things makes transmission difficult and
the point is rather than in a classical
Iowa query we send bits from source to
destination we were not going to be
doing that and in Contra now we're not
delivering a qubit from source to
destination instead we will distribute
entangled pairs of particles to the two
end points and the two end points are
then free to do what they please were
those entangled pairs and one of those
things they can do with those entangled
pairs is quantum teleportation which is
data transmission quantum data
transmission and the life cycle of and
tango and roughly like what it perceives
basically first you generate
entanglement on a link you generate a
pair on individual links on your path on
all of them potentially in parallel so
now you have an entangled pair on every
link on your path from source to
destination and then you combine them
using a technique called entanglement
swapping where you can actually combine
neighboring and tangled pairs to create
a longer bell pair and at the end you
want to deliver that pair those two
qubits that form that one pair to the
endpoints who are actually going to then
use it for things such as quantum
teleportation but before you deliver to
it to the end of an application there's
three things you have to consider how
the corrections what that effectively
means is you have to either deliver
always the same pair to the endpoints or
you because there's one of four possible
pairs that can be delivered and so you
either always deliver the same one so
essentially you have to do the pilot
correction to bring it to the same state
or you actually tell the end
I know it's what you have delivered to
them another key important feature is
that the two end nodes must be able to
identify which qubit of theirs belongs
to which belters they can coordinate
actions on the same entangled pair if
that information is lost having just one
qubit of a pair but not knowing where
the other end point is is useless you
might as well just throw it away
and another important point is you need
an estimate of the quality of the state
that you have been delivered if you
don't have an estimate basically you
then just have to rely on other
higher-level processes which means that
your performance will degrade can't
yeah you can't optimize base base you
can't ask the network for what you
actually want so just to highlight with
an illustration of what I mean so if
this is like a three node network ABC
you'd first generate an entangled pair
between a and B and B and C so here's
one entangled pair X 1 X 2 and another
entangled pair Y 1 y 2 there's being a
qubit another qubit Y one thing to keep
in a way to being a qubit squiggly line
denoting entanglement between them and
entanglement swap basically takes X 2
and y 1 and perform some operations on
them and you end up with a entangled
pair that spans from X 1 to X 2 by
performing on the operations our node B
you do have to send some classical bits
between from B to either end node so
it's not entirely done just by B there
needs to be some coordination at a
higher level as well
was about the lifecycle of entanglement
and other work that was done was about
the network model and effectively what
does the network look like because I was
actually a big question and raised by a
lot of people and from a networking
background and essentially the biggest
question was like a biggest confusion
was like are we using qubits to encode
header information or not and that's or
is no we're not using qubits to encode
header information and so what are the
actual challenges
so first illustrate the model by
Lestrange the challenges we have when
building quantum networks
number one being there is no equivalent
of a payload carrying packet we're in
the classical in a normal network we're
used to having payload and a bunch of
headers attached to that tell the
network or we're gonna do with it this
does this is not possible in a quantum
network
it kind of is resembles also like
transport networks and or you can have
just like optical networks where you
can't actually read the header data so
there are some similarities over there
there are also many differences as well
an entangled pair is only useful if you
actually know where both qubits are so
one of the key roles of a network is
actually keeping track of this
information and you can't just send a
qubit one way in another qubit on its
merry way and hope for the best
you actually have to know at all times
where they are actually not at all times
not gonna be that strict but when it's
delivered when you actually wanna make
use of your entangled pair you do have
to know who and where it holds the other
parent have to be able to identify it
unambitious lee another key difficulty
is that generating and time requires
temporary state when you receive a
packet in a normal Network you kind of
just look at his headers look at your
routing table and you throw it out
another an output port it's kind of a
bit more difficult in a quantum network
because your qubits arrived separately
from the control information you have to
maintain state to correlate their
control information with your qubits and
vice versa
and so therefore there is a bit of a
disparity again some similarities to
gmpls networks and however generating
and turn entanglement is actually
paralyzed above operation because since
we're not transmitting user data
you can actually just generate all these
individual link pairs in parallel they
don't have you don't have to wait to
generate the next one only after you're
done with the first one and so it means
quite importantly that you're going to
be doing a lot of things in parallel and
it's quite important for optimization
purposes to actually do these things in
parallel and here's the point that kind
of just to really drive at home
classical communication is necessary
quantum networks were leaned very
heavily on the existing classical
infrastructure for two reasons
number one is you need to be able to
communicate classical bits of
information and between the various
nodes one example is in an entanglement
swap you actually have to tell the next
node what was the result of your
operation because the result of the
entanglement swap operation is actually
a number between 0 and 3 so there's four
possible outcomes and that has to be
sent to the receiver to the other end
and this has to do with the four at
possible entangled pairs that you can
create another reason why you want
classical communication is simply the
same reason why you want to have that in
a normal network you want to do routing
you're gonna do signalling you want to
be able to set up circuits you want to
do a bunch of management stuff and
there's no point in doing that with a
quantum network we already have a bunch
of stuff that works and again I'm gonna
go back to the example of gmpls because
there's a lot of similarities and
actually theirs has already been work on
doing some quantum with J MPLS I also
added like actually defined the elements
of a quantum network a quantum network
will consist of contrary features
quantum it features are effectively the
devices that perform the entanglement
swaps they're the kind of way we get a
past the fact that we can't amplify
signals I've pointed out that they're
automated and controllable because for
example if you want to build a long link
you can't just lay down a long fiber
because eventually you lose your signal
and you can't just put small amplifiers
or something along the way you basically
have to put full quantum repeaters and
but these contractors will probably be
fully automated in the same way just
have a simple switch layer to switch or
something
I distinguish quantum routers from
quantum repeaters to kind of distinguish
and knows that have a control plane so a
quantum router would still be a repeater
because it's capable of performing an
entanglement swap but if it has to make
decisions such as like well I actually
have more than just two links I'm not
just going from one side to the other
side I'm actually I can probably may
have to make decisions and so these kind
of repeaters will have a control plane
and there's actually distinction between
these two you'll have automated nodes
fully automated notes simply performing
repeating of operations and you'll have
essentially nodes with a control plane I
distinguish end nodes because end notes
can be simpler than a contributor they
don't have to be able to perform an
entanglement swap they don't even need
to have a quantum memory they can
literally just receive their end of the
pair and measure immediately so there's
actually smaller requirements in the end
nodes than on the intermediate nodes
there may be non quantum nodes to
perform management tasks a centralized
controller and obviously you will have
quantum links and classical links and to
kind of again highlight the fact that
you have two data planes you have a
quantum data plane and a classical data
plane a kind of an illustration of what
it all looks like you will have
applications at the top communicating
with each other over a classical channel
the applications will run on end nodes
and these end nodes will be connected
via a physical link at the bottom and
straight and that physical link will
most likely also be the quantum channel
through which they distribute air qubits
but a important point kind of an
important point to make is they will
also need a classical channel to
communicate the control information I
was discussing but that classical
channel doesn't have to be essentially
the same physical link as the quantum
Channel it can be completely separate
and they can share that thing there I'm
pretty sure there are technologies to
share quantum and Confirmation on the
same fiber as many ways of implementing
that but that's kind of not part of this
draft
looking forward and what else is there
to do I'm going to finalize the updates
to sections four and five based on the
feedback from the last call from 11th of
November I've mentioned there's a few
pipeline changes still need to be
incorporated and and another work to do
is like whilst we don't really tackle
too much physical stuff physical layer
stuff in the draft it is very important
to highlight what are the difficulties
brought into the architecture based on
physical constraints essentially one of
the biggest constraints is memory
lifetimes and you can only store qubit
currently technology lets you store
cubes for a very very short amount of
time which require very strict timing
controls and then essentially the
purpose of the draft was to kind of
outline the goals and principles of how
would you design a quantum Internet and
that's kind of still untouched and I've
got some feedback on that and but that
will essentially now that we've kind of
laid down the foundation for a better
understanding or what's going on and to
kind of now move on to the goals and
principles and I put down Network level
security with a question mark and it's
good question should it should it end up
here or should not sure to have a
separate and it should be separate work
and I don't really want to delat
relegate security to a second-rate
concern because it's actually say since
these content networks are built around
the idea that they're going to be more
secure it's kind of important to tackle
any concerns that might arise and that's
it for me all right so that was actually
about 19 minutes out of our twenty
minutes get scheduled for this but the I
only have 60 minutes of agenda items and
we have a 90 minute session so it's
totally okay by me if we run over on
this for however much QA we have because
I think this is the single most
important item we're actually working on
in the group so questions from the floor
[Music]
name two busy Nalini Elkins now I'm just
wandering into this slowly but and I
will tell you that my I have had a very
misspent life focusing on measurement
and diagnostics and so so so I get the
jitters you know when you say you can't
measure anything and having said that
the success of all this depends on a
good management system so so I'm just
curious you know because I was kind of
going through and thinking well what are
the parameters one would need for this
good management system and what can be
thought of you know I mean what can be
measured like number of like where
qubits were at a particular location and
how many you did or you know I mean I'm
just I'm just I just want to get your
thoughts on on all this rambling yeah so
that the examples you've given like are
good examples you kind of keep track of
essentially like for example the
entangled pairs come with our IDs so
when these entangled pairs are generated
even on a link they come with an ID so
you can keep track of the ID well comes
with meet means we have to build the
protocols yet maintain yes that's our
responsibility here in this room yes I
say allocate an identifier to entangled
pairs and they can keep try and actually
one part important thing to actually
keep track of is which entangled pair
have you entangled with which entangled
pair because it's actually critical in
their end to end delivery so that's one
thing you can definitely keep track of
and you can keep track of failures to
generate on the link you can keep track
of how many have successfully generated
the entanglement generation it's kind of
still missing from the draft because
it's one of the pipe light changes but
actually the entanglement generation and
link is heralded so you actually get a
notification and when an entangled pair
is generated so that's something you can
keep a
tract of information of and actually
there's also a lot of other information
mostly this other information is kind of
metadata like such as like when did your
parents accessory generated which time
bin and when did you perform operations
and it what result it came out was
delivered successfully and so on
there's obviously anything we can keep
track of anything apart from we don't
actually need to measure the cubit the
cubit actually doesn't carry anything
interesting to the network the only
thing we cannot measure at all is
effectively the fidelity we can only
have an estimate of the fidelity there
really is no good way I think of because
to measure fidelity would have to repeat
the generation multiple times and then
measure it multiple times and have to
make sure that it's the same area that
you've performed the same thing many
times so that's the only one thing that
I think would be difficult to measure
everything else is fine like what would
be the things I mean if the group thinks
that's an interesting topic I'd
certainly be interested in working on
something like that let me take a
process interrupt for one second blue
sheets if you have not signed the blue
sheets please do there's one up here in
the front I'm not sure where the other
one got to okay yes so the model here
which is great in some ways says that
there are n nodes for which we're
computations and applications run and
then they're repeaters which allow you
to build longer lengths and more complex
topologies out of the communication
channels with both the classical in the
quantum so something that's happening in
parallel in this community is something
called computing in the network where
intermediate devices in the network that
we classically think of as either just
repeaters or switches are also doing
computation so I'm curious what happens
to this model if the things that you're
calling quantum repeaters are actually
quantum computers and the this internet
thing this quantum internet thing is
actually sort of a way to distribute a
quantum computation it's a good point I
think Rodney actually often calls the
problem of distributing entanglement as
a distributed computation
but it would be a distributed classical
computation to deliver the entangled
pairs so yeah well there's there yes
there are actually multiple choices of
operations that can be done besides just
the entanglement swapping most having to
do with with error management but you're
exactly you're exactly right and and as
what tech said you know I often call
this really a it's not store-and-forward
building an end-to-end connection is a
distributed computation and in fact
right before the meetings started here I
was talking to a Aaron Falk about about
the the coin work and and I really think
there's a lot of potential at least
intellectual synergy I'm not sure if
there's actual technological overlap or
not and that's that's something I'd love
to pursue with with the coin people you
and even whoever else hi their news
Moira
and so I had the pleasure to play around
a little bit with kis kids so the IBM
quantum computing hub and so what I did
was initialize 50 cubits with 0 perform
a no operation and measure the results
and I think in 50% of the cases at least
one qubit flipped so without performing
any operation right so what you do about
this if you're talking already about
routing and maintaining a state what do
you do about bit flipping there so there
are quantum error correction codes
they're not really considered in the
near term because they have quite high
resource requirements and however it all
actually kind of comes under this guise
of fidelity so fidelity kind of also
encodes potential bit flips essentially
how close you are to your desired state
and effectively what it means is that
your end-to-end application which is
performing some security protocol will
effectively detect an abort transactions
it detects that you it's got at least
too much information into the
environment so that's how it's going to
be dealt a near term in the future there
will probably be proper quantum error
correction codes implemented there's
also
the idea of distillation but I don't
think the solution would solve bit flips
it's all about like delivering a better
pair but yeah error correction is kind
of a more long-term concern and we deal
with imperfect states as was what we
have now it basically just reduces the
right with which you can deliver at the
end okay thank you
so the the distillation that we tech
just mentioned is in effect it's error
detection as opposed to error correction
pollution I have a question I'm
concerned about measurement because is
there a danger that when you try and
measure entangled pairs you may
decompose maybe a quantum system now to
a classical system and therefore it will
now behave more like a classical system
yeah that's why you want you don't want
to avoid measurement in the network I
accept during the entanglement so one
part of the integrant swap is actually
measurement so you will want to measure
it then but in that case the measurement
is done in a way that actually
transports entanglement rather than
destroying for this thing a essentially
they what your concern about is like
reducing your system to a classical
system is effectively decoherence so
interactions with the environment it
happens and currently it's taken to
account by the fact that your fidelity
degrades and you're going to be
delivering imperfect entangled pairs to
the end nodes does that answer your
question let's close off the line with
the two people who are here in line
there both of you are there that fine
but let's let's end it there and then if
there's more we can do it the open mic
section at the end okay no well
developers I'm the boys that claims in
the deserts about the physical stuff and
all the like now seriously what I think
and and then trying to I'm taking this
moment just to try to clarify a little
bit with my thoughts we have a
conversation pending but the point is
that I think that we are running too
fast in following the same analogy with
the current network model of the current
classical network model in the sense
that we're assuming that there's going
to be a physical physical
physically we live in a physical world
that's but thing is about talking about
links talking about Network talking
about application I think that we are I
mean that we are running too fast
because we don't have right now the
operational experience of connecting
several quantum computing computers and
see what happens with them and probably
we could step back a little bit and
start thinking about and probably the
physical energy is not good because it's
it's as misleading as well intense that
when we are talking about this what we
have I work with an entanglement we
could be talking about we have a channel
we have a secret something that that
connects two or several because
theoretically my understanding is that
you can connect at the same time with
you don't need pairs of entanglements
you can't look event an entanglement
with several ends thinking about setting
but that so far what we know is about
building entanglements that we know what
can be done is building entanglements
and calling them out whatever call it
whatever probably would avoid the term
link or whatever this is equal in the
air in the air in the classical network
case and tried to elaborate over this
that that was my my my point probably
was not clear on the list and this is
why I wanted to trances here is it's
about trying to avoid over the the
excess of analogy I'm sorry I get your
name I'm sorry did you say develop this
I'm over telefónica research Thanks
I'm still actually because you say avoid
analogies with the link but we won't
need the link no no no not to the link
avoid analogies with the current network
mobile with the seven layers the link
the physical the length the network the
transport etc because probably the
number of layers the layering etc will
be different yeah
actually I actually actually agree with
you and kind of that's why on the calls
I actually have resisted trying to put
an explicit
Nishan of layers into this draft there
is work in this in this community about
layers but that's fine if it's separate
because we kind of need to start
understanding these things but I
actually did try to explicitly avoid
talk about layers we did start talking
about responsibilities which having
which people try to relate to layers but
I really do want to avoid defining a
stack in this draft completely yes no I
agree with that
your name please
I'm actually the chair I'm actually the
chair or the co-chair of this coin group
and it's great that we're talking KO'ing
here because in coin we thought about
you guys and the ideas that we had
comments from the IAB about putting
security in our systems especially when
we start putting computing elements and
actually without a homothetic security
which is not very feasible without some
form of of quantum computer and I was
wondering what were your thoughts on
future of security systems inside the
network now that we have this type of
communications I actually I have not
thought much about security apart from
so very so you mean about security of
the in network nodes computing nodes
yeah and also of the overall
infrastructure that needs to be secured
if we're going to have access to the
information while it's in transit
because a lot of people are developing
more and more and to an encrypted system
and first we have to have trusted nodes
in the center but if there's strong
encryption well you know it takes a
while to decrypt them so frankly it's
not a really great idea than to put
computing because we never will never
get access to the data and we started
thinking about I'm erratic signatures
and security but again you need very
very high level of computations for this
and I was wondering in your system again
when you're thinking about how is this
going to be dealt with both from I would
say the traditional computation where
you start like they've they've said to
have quantum computers
the system but also even for your thing
how are you going to deal with security
it's more of a comment maybe the
question but we've we've we've because
we are pretty in computation and the
network we are very much involved in
thinking about what's going a bit next
generation of this and maybe it's here
yeah so it's probably so the only
security that I'm aware of that we've
thought about is end to end between
applications and I have mentioned that
we have not thought about any security
in the network yet I don't think anybody
has thought about any security in the
network for quantum stuff maybe a tiny
bit somewhere else but that's part of
that's something that rod has suggested
for the open mic so I would I would say
you are much closer to helping us than
we are to helping you yeah but I will
actually disagree so we actually have
one paper the title which is the network
impact of hijacking a quantum repeater
that actually looks at whether or not
the hijacking of an individual node in a
network is actually fundamentally
different from from the hijacking of an
individual router in the internet and we
found yes but it's possible to mitigate
it I think I actually mentioned that
paper on the mailing list but maybe
meant maybe miss Talent
all right um let's let's finish this
discussion here now if we have more to
talk about with this we'll still have
some time at the open mic I hope let's
see and now the next the next task is
actually challenging for me technically
technologically next we are to have a
remote presentation from axle on the
link layer protocol wants to get who
wants to show me how to run the me deco
on this or as a how do i how do I bring
it up so that axel can run run this run
the presentation remotely or aha let's
see so if I just actually you with us
yep can you hear me hot let's see do I
run the slides from here is that what I
do all right Axl you're up okay sound
good
speak louder speak louder yes yeah you
hear me now good okay okay
we're always better that will do yeah
let me know if it's not good enough but
I will try to speak loud so my name is
axel Dahlberg I'm at Q Tech in doubts
also with Stephanie Boehner and I will
give a brief presentation I won our
[Music]
draft which is called the drafts Coburg
ll quantum which you can find with this
QR code here so this drafts is on the
link tire service and what's the task of
the link layer service in a quantum
network and what would an interface be
through this link layer service and I
would like to just briefly recap what
our view of the link air service is and
what this craft is about and also what
changes have been made since the last
meeting so just to be very clear so this
is about our definition of a service so
not of a protocol implementing this
service and what is then the task of a
link layer service so depending on how
you want to formulate it in some way or
another in a classical network non
quantum network the goal is to send a
message
classical message from one node to
another and you might think that in a
quantum network then the fundamental
task would be to send a qubits from one
node to another however this is not the
most fundamental operation which Voytek
mentioned the more fundamental operation
is to generate entanglement and the
reason for this is that when we have in
tango
we can use this to send qubits through
teleportation so in our view the task of
a link layer service is to generate
entanglement between adjacent nodes in
the network
let me just maybe check in here if the
if this is working and whether you can
hear or understand me I can hear you
receive so but you'll have to tell me
when to change pages yeah okay you can
[Music]
okay so the task of the link layers as I
mentioned is to generate entanglement it
turns essentially a physical layer which
is possible which is can make
entanglement generation attempts that
might fail with some probability into a
robust service of entire generation what
was also mentioned in the in the
previous talk is that the link layer
service will give will return an
identifier of this generated
entanglement that can then be used in a
network to track this entanglement and
for nodes to agree on what qubits are
entangled so as I mentioned this is
about the service but if you want to
read about a protocol that we propose
that provides this service you can find
this in in a paper from ours which is on
the archive which we presented also at
seecombe this year next slide so in in
brief you how would this work so in our
view the link layer service how you
interact with this is that you you you
ask it to create entanglement we do what
we call a create message this create
message contains a few different things
and I was going to the details now but
for example you can specify what is your
required fidelity and the reason for
this is that there's usually a trade-off
asphaltic mentioned between fidelity and
the generation rate and not all
applications
requires perfect fidelity because some
of the noise can be corrected
classically in in post-processing
and force upon generating key another
type of argument in this create message
is the type of request and we currently
envisioned two types of requests where
one is to create the entanglement and
keep it in memory at the end nodes this
is the difference from creating
entanglement which is measured directly
to generate correlated classical bits
which can be used for for example key
distribution or quantum key distribution
and how this then works is that this
create message is supplied from one of
the nodes and later when entanglement is
generated and okay or a signal is
returned to both nodes that now there is
entanglements and this is your qubits
that's entangled so and I should maybe
mention that in this draft of our link
life service we've defined basically
what goes into this create message as
fields in the headers and we specified
the bits of these headers which might be
confusing and caused some confusion in
the sense that I think this is not
generally the way to maybe define the
interface to a service and there's been
some suggestions so maybe next slide
from various people and I just wanted to
briefly mention that we have we also
have a github repo with this draft and
there are current issues there and for
example one of these issues is that we
maybe shouldn't fix for example the
number of bits in these fields of the
headers but maybe we can instead use a
type length value message to make it not
as fixed okay but what
has changed since the last meeting so
next slide so this was the this is the
new header and I just wanted to briefly
mention what has changed so next slide
one thing that's changed is that in this
create message one can specify how long
are you willing to wait before you
receive your entanglement this because
perhaps some node cannot wait
indefinitely and we earlier had a just a
single field which specified the next
time one is willing to wait there's now
a new field which specifies the time
units of of this next time you can
specify a maximum waiting time in
essentially microseconds milliseconds or
seconds so this is one of this change
next slide the other slightly bigger
change axle we have a question for just
jumping really quick because we face the
same problem somewhere else I look at
something called time TLV which was
actually done from an a a while ago
which is a TLV encoding mantissa and
exponent so you can choose between short
times with high resolution or long times
with low resolution with one data
structure a Dave name for the record
Dave I ran sorry I said the last time so
it's probably a better encoding than a
fixed time encoding where you have to
choose your poison once great thank you
very much that's very good I will
definitely look into that so the other
thing that changed which is like the
technical is that as I mentioned there's
this type of request where you want to
generate the tournament and you want to
measure it directly now in quantum
mechanics you can measure in different
bases and depending on what your
application is you might want measuring
different paces and you might want to
measure in a random basis so what has
now been added is more possibility to
define what bases you want to measure in
for both
requesting note of entanglement and the
remote node and also how to sample these
random basis by specifying essentially a
probability distributions next slide up
so I should have said next slide earlier
but this was about the time units next
slide yes
so there are now new fields to specify
the probability distributions and the
basis is you want a measuring next slide
so I had to get up story there's I think
currently ten openings mostly pointed
out by Bruno Reisman for example about
this type length value messages and also
something that came up earlier is about
the scope of a remote node when you
specify who you want to generate
entanglement wait and we're very happy
for contributions about this so if you
want to contribute either use the
mailing lists or go to the github repo
and submit pull requests or or issues
and I'm very happy to discuss this ok
let's try
the questions or the answers to about
three or four minutes for this one Diego
yeah mm-hmm developes just a suggestion
again about the the analogies etc I well
well I can understand we call this link
though I would prefer something
different because to avoid the analogy
but well let's keep it as a link what
you're mentioning here what you are
sending when the what you call here
headers are more I would call them
control messages I mean you're not
generally putting a header plus a
payload with data right
it's just say it says the header it's
more like you are communicating in
modernist services it's a control plane
communicating to a data playing or to a
quantum data playing I would talk here
about control messages or control
actions or something like that because
it would be clear to understand for
those of us who are more used to to the
normal Network environment and he's and
I think it describes better the goal of
the air of what you were shown I like
that suggestion axel sorry Dave I ran
again so there seems to be a missing
link here in the sense that the
architecture document talks about the
really nice fact that you can do a lot
of things in parallel but this seems
like you have a very serial make one
call create one entangled pair make
another call
send another message create another
entangled pair so I wonder if there if
the protocol really shouldn't be some
type of parallelized such that you can
say you know create me 75 of these
entangled pairs perhaps all with the
same characteristic because you're going
to you know you're going to do the same
thing with all of them so I'd give some
thought about you know given the fact
that we have the opportunity to do a lot
of parallelization designing a protocol
that is seems to be biased to doing
things serially so that's a very good
point and I didn't go into the full
detail of this draft but this is
definitely something that's that's
already there so one of the things you
can also say in this great message
how many pairs do you want so you can
say I want a thousand pairs and I want
to measure them directly to generate key
you can also it's not sequential in the
sense that you need the okay message
before you send another crate you can
submit multiple creates and this will be
stored in a queue essentially and you
can do various scheduling of these great
messages hi Wojtek from Q tech just a
clarification about what I meant by
paralyzed below operations that
sowhat's paralyzed about is so over here
and this draft Axel's talking about an
individual link and whereas if you have
a multi hop path with say three four
links then you can definitely paralyze
those three four links where you have
three or four fundamental link pairs
generated at the same time rather than
hub by up so that so that's one thing so
the so when I said paralyzed abode
that's what I meant
although I do also get your point I
guess that on that individual link you
can also paralyze okay pollution on the
record I went through the draft and
there is actually the number field on
the link there and it has been set to
16-bit so the number of entangled pairs
that can be generated is around 65,536
is this a hard limit and I just wanted
to know the design decision behind this
because is this been set because maybe
of a physical restriction in the number
of entangled pairs that can be generated
no I think comes back to the question
that it's maybe not the best choice to
now set the length of these fields and
it might be better to move away from a
fixed
the question from from Java I don't have
the name because I have asked for it and
is not yet here but where the question
is a federico sant andrea is asking
whether it could be possible or useful
to generate entanglement all the time
and distribute pairs as needed that's a
good question
so why we didn't go for this approach is
that at least in some physical systems
it's not so advantageous to do this and
the reason being for physical
considerations is that in some systems
for example the system we have in doubt
whenever you try to generate
entanglement you produce some noise on
your memories so you would like to not
unnecessarily try to generate
entanglement if there's no need for it
so that's the motivation for not always
trying to generate statements okay with
my individual hat on I want to ask one
quickly so axle the the the new
additions you talked about with the
requests are getting to specify the
choice of measurement basis when you're
when you're actually measuring the the
cupids out directly does that belong as
part of the link service or should that
be end to end well so so this is for
basically I guess if there's some
application running directly on the link
so generate for example key mmm the
reason why this is part of the
entanglement generation request and not
something you do after the entitlement
is generated is that when you measure
directly you can generally go faster
because you don't have to wait for
communication essentially to if there's
a midpoint and or her welding station
yes but my point I think you think that
I think that argument holds over
multiple hops as well as over a single
hop so I would argue that belongs at a
different level in the and the the
stream of specifications there's
to be part of the part of the
specification of the end and service
rather than part of the part of the link
specification but okay I'm not sure I
agree because it should still need to go
to the link layer generation service
such that it's known already what the
measurement basis is when you try to
generate entanglement it could also come
from higher above okay
I'm not sure I agree but let's let's
let's there is more recommend that
anything else is it comes from which is
it it's a number I don't know I only
have a number but they say I agree with
wrong that they measure immediately
logically belongs in a hika layer the
transport layer but I am sure Diego
won't like the name and that's true I
don't like it
okay thanks axel I hope you're hanging
around there may be more questions for
you later yeah let's see if I can figure
out how to turn you off anything thank
you
let's see good okay see if this is gonna
work
um so my own internet draft on
connections set up in a in a quantum
network so sooner or later you're gonna
have to set up a connection from from
between a pair so I've marked s and D on
here but that's really rather than
source and destination it's really sort
of initiator and responder in terms of
setting things up because we are talking
about a entanglement as a service rather
than a transmission as a service if you
want to go into some of the details of
this the slide set from from Prague is a
little bit longer let's see so there are
sort of four stages of the overall
problem one of course is at first of
course you have to select a path or a
route through your network you have to
collect a set of information for
planning the set of operations that
you're going to actually execute at each
of these nodes in the middle and this
again do
it's sort of the the distributed
computation part of it then you have to
actually do the planning of this
operation and then you have to convey
the sequence to the to these notes and
all of this is done in the set of
constraints or assumptions the links are
heterogeneous and that not very much is
known about the links a priori and at
the moment resource management or
multiplexing is beyond the scope but
that's something we probably need to
discuss and so this this draft is aimed
at the collection and distribution of
this information rather than the process
of actually planning the sequence of
operations itself and does not
specifically target it at the routing
itself so each of the nodes has some
information about its own capabilities
including the amount of memory that it
has and the memory lifetime and its own
local Fidelity's it has a little bit of
information about the links and those
who its neighbors are and as in OSPF or
a similar protocol we're assuming that
it knows something about the topology of
the local network with some sort of
routing metric and where the gateway to
the outside world is but not a lot of
detail about the other things so for
example it does not have full
information about every single memory
qubit everywhere in the network we don't
think that that would scale um so the
basic process is if you picked a path
from the initiator to the responder so
at each of these nodes you send a Matt a
message across the path sort of building
a stack of information about the the
total set of resources that you're
actually going to be using and then that
runs from the source and through the
nodes abcdefgh I once that arrives at I
I turns around and sends that
information and performs the actual
planning of the entire computation and
it creates a stack of operations to be
executed in each of these notes labeled
with the the node for it and that entire
stack is then sent backwards through the
network and each node progressively pops
its own set of instructions off of the
top of it so it passes through D to C to
B to a and each one collectively gets
what it needs
this once you have that you have
distributed the set of rules for which
each node is actually going to operate
and during the course of this connection
let's see so there's a different diagram
of what we're looking at there and some
of the distinctions that you have to
worry about is you have to figure out
where you are going to perform the
entanglement swapping operations that
what that got mentioned earlier which
order you're going to do things in are
you going to apply some sort of error
management scheme which qubits you're
going to use if there are a long wait
intervals how long a wait interval is to
high and at which point you discard the
states you've been working on reset and
go back to the beginning those sorts of
issues are the kinds of things that get
established in these sets of rules the
details of those particular operations
are out of the outside of the scope of
the particular graph we've written all
we've written so far is the messaging
for how this process actually goes back
and forth let's see so that's a list of
the a couple of the challenges there
so first draft of this the zero zero
draft was just before the prog and we
got some questions on the mailing list
around that point someone brought up the
the suggestion of segment routing as an
alternative this or similar thing I'm
not particularly familiar with segment
routing so if there's anybody who wants
to continue and wants to bring this up
and discuss it more by all means let me
know dieppe not me but they have a
couple of colleagues that are working
very heavily on that I will ask them ok
I myself an expert there but think I can
gather a couple of them ok let's see so
and just before the deadline for this
meeting I put up the o1 draft the only
change is that from the 0 0 draft to the
old one graph were really a fairly minor
improved the definitions of end nodes
and repeaters but those really need to
be coordinate or reconciled with
actually what's going into a white X
draft we improved the discussion of non
data teleportation uses of entanglement
teleportation is the equivalent of
except it's done in a very distributed
fashion but there are other uses of the
entanglement as well so there's a little
bit more discussion of that in the in
there and a little bit of a discussion
of multiplexing and resource management
there's nothing prescriptive yet but
just sort of a description of the need
for it I really kind of wanted to avoid
putting that into this draft because I
think it's a really a very big issue and
so I think it belongs um sort of
elsewhere or at least as a as a
follow-on work out of Giga Java I think
it's a someone that's again a number is
that number nine seven six four eight
nine three five two at Hulet conf
attacker.com okay and says I don't think
segment routing is applicable we'll send
an email to the mailing list with
details okay thank you and a couple of
people in the audience who have been
making faces about it as well it's not
that it's not a universally approved
solution apparently let's see no I was
Bruno okay yeah yes Bruno has been very
active and involved on the list on a lot
of these discussions so following on
from that from the posting of the o1
document and actually some of the stuff
even going back farther I spent some
time digging through the mailing lists
to see what issues are still open
probably the single biggest issue is
actually the question of creating what's
called multi-part tied entanglements so
we've been talking so far about
entangling two things in across the
network and a service is to your
point-to-point entanglement which you
would use for quantum key distribution
or for sensor networks or distributed
quantum computing or whatever but it's
also possible to actually entangle more
than two sites or more than two devices
and that's actually there are a number
of uses that have been proposed for that
and so it was brought up on the mailing
list as to whether or not this
particular graft addresses that and
whether or not it should my own
preference is that yes we should
eventually address that issue but we
should not do it in this particular
graft I think we should do
point-to-point first so that we have
some understanding of what we're doing
before we try to add that additional
complexity
we're also I think much farther away
from actually needing that in the field
and so of course I want the architecture
to support it but I don't think we need
to actually address that right now
someone brought up the notion of a
kicking context and connection tear down
which I realized while digging back
through the through the mailing list and
that's a good point I wrote I wrote a UH
a draft on how you on how you create
connections but not how you tear them
down and presumably you'll want to tear
them down at some point
Wojtek suggested moving from the
terminology that we used for the rules
themselves of being conditioned in
action to being match in action that
would be okay by me there was also the
suggestion of separating the rule set
definition from the distribution and I
do want this draft to focus only on the
distribution and not so much on the
rules themselves but there is in fact a
little bit of discussion of that inside
so we can go into some of the detail on
the on the mailing list about what
should stay in and what should come out
as a result of that yes just the div
around just a quick comment on tear down
if you'd have to have a justification
pretty strong for needing it because you
can just do soft state timeout and that
has very nice properties because it
doesn't it it it recovers nicely if
there's a network partition you don't
have to sort of remember stayed during a
disconnection to reconnect and only to
be able to tear things down and throw a
state away so I would say start with the
notion that the these connections are
soft state timeout and just get
refreshed or on a timer in order to keep
them going and unless there's some
strong reason why you really need to
recover resources deterministically with
a with a explicit teardown that's a good
thought you know that the set of
resources that are going to be available
in any network in the short term is a
very limited set of resources and so
potentially we may want to recover that
or include it in some sort of resource
management scheme but personally I sort
of agree with you I would sort of leave
it for sort of soft timeout but at least
incorporating that into the draft in
some way as this is what's expected to
happen I think would be a good idea
the other big issue was whether this is
single domain or Internet work and the
draft as written is for a single network
my own proposed approach to the overall
inter network architecture is to build
off of the recursive network
architecture which Joe touch and others
defined quite a while back for classical
networks but it is not not sort of
widely adopted at this point but I think
it actually suits quantum networks very
very well so we have one old paper from
about 10 years ago on that working on
that let's see and so those are sort of
the the issues of what we're planning on
doing for that and that's it for my
draft any any further questions comments
how many people have actually looked at
this draft Oh 10 or 12 here in the room
that's pretty good that that's good
thank you all for doing that all right
if there's nothing else then we'll go on
to the next scheduled presentation which
is on the integration of OpenSSL in this
hangout all right question something
from Java yes
Fredrik for the regular science I feared
that focusing on point upon links now
instead of considering multi-party
entanglement for the stat will freeze
some assumptions well I'm sorry well
what some assumptions will freeze will
freeze would or badly okay point taken
I'm not sure I agree with the the I
would certainly say that the multi-part
ID is a substantial more complex problem
and I want to keep things as simple as
possible and add complexity only when it
starts to become necessary so that issue
is actually entangled with a different
issue which is you're also assuming
congruence between the classical and the
quantum channels as opposed to
independent topologies for the classical
channels and the and the quantum
channels so that you know for example
you can't you don't have a way to
optimally use a broadcast classical
channel
in order to manage a set of
point-to-point quantum channels I mean
one could design protocols that worked
where there wasn't congruence between
the classical channel and the quantum
Channel I think that it is probably an
interaction between that and whether you
want to do multi-part tight
entanglements I'm not sure there's
actually a direct relationship there I
do think you're correct that so far we
have not assumed to the existence of
that classical broadcast channel
although I don't think anybody's
actually written that assumption down
and I would like to keep that assumption
I do not want to assume a classical
broadcast channel we do assume this I
used what cast as like the that's the
other extreme right of completely
congruent one classical channel for
quantum Channel but there many
intermediary possible deployments right
yeah I would say yeah I'm fine with
keeping the congruence for now right we
do we do have to have quantum
communicator or a classical
communication between all of the the
classical controllers for each of the
quantum nodes along along the path but
there may be boundaries beyond which the
communication between these two nodes
never never crosses a / to a network
boundary or even the existence of nodes
within a particular network may not even
necessarily be exposed outside the
network boundary that's one of the
issues we've worked on with the larger
recursive network architecture but for
this particular draft we're assuming a
single and individual network and that
all of the all of the classical and
control nodes can communicate with each
other as necessary yes jabber language
when do decide but sofa Bruno
saying that he says I see strong
resemblance between this protocol and
RSVP RSVP has point-to-multipoint LSPs
which which are similar to multi port
items on government and Fredrik saying I
think like Bruno that the adaptation to
some multi-part identical meant
distribution is not too complex okay
Bob Braden was I used to have an office
next to Bob great and he was one of the
sweetest humans on the planet so I I
like RSVP but all right let's go into
the next
is this a very big file 250 kilobytes
turn 50 kilobytes it should have been
there all right there we go
all right okay so right so I'm going to
talk a bit about integrating qkd in to
openness cell where does this come from
so on November 5th and 6th right labs
ripe ncc organized a pan-european
quantum internet hackathon where
multiple nodes participated Delft Paris
Sarajevo Padova Geneva Dublin in Geneva
was actually CERN and the idea was to
tackle various quantum internet
challenges and I was one of the
technical coordinators and one of the
challenges I proposed for the hackers
and I was actually integrating qkt into
open SSL so if you actually want to look
up what the challenge was afterwards
it's actually all on github publicly
available and but essentially what I was
trying to go over and kind of lay down
in front of the hackers was that having
an end goal was to basically open up a
browser on one computer and run a server
running some basic website on another
computer and actually have an HTTP
connection which was encrypted using qkd
all over a simulated network and they
wouldn't really give us the real network
once they built in but what was the
motivation for the challenge and so my
it's kind of like my personal Eric with
the way the state of quantum networking
is today it's basically we either talk
at a very low hardware level low level
operations like entanglements while
being linked entanglement generation
gates it's very very very low level and
then we also have the other extreme
where we're talking about application
protocols but they all like quantum
cryptography
protocols with really complex
mathematical proofs and I with a physics
degree I struggle to follow them and to
be honest I just give up most of the
time anyway and it's not my area of
expertise so I kind of wanted to bring
one when I was to a user level
application kind of raised the level of
abstraction and led people to actually
hack at a higher level then just you
know stringing together gates like you
do in kiss gate or QED sharp etc I kind
of open up the field to software
engineers who don't necessarily have a
condo physics background because I spent
two years as actually as a software
engineer in a company that was doing
control plane protocols and at that time
I kind of completely stopped thinking
about physics and kind of learn the
software engine is actually a very
creative bunch and they're much better
at coming up with like practical uses of
various abstractions and stringing them
together into something more powerful so
that's kind of what I wanted to open it
up to do and also just practically
relate the hackathon to I'm going to qkd
because qkd is actually a commercialized
technology already exists and people
actually do sell devices and make money
well whether they make profit is a
different question I have no idea but
they are being sold so the challenge was
built around an API that Etsy a European
standards organization is trying to
standardize I don't think it's
standardized yet but they're working on
it I have a bunch of documents about it
and and it seems they're in a quite an
advanced stage the API is very simple it
has five functions but they're really
for basically you open a connection you
well you open your connection to your
qkt device you connect to the other qkd
device you get your key or you and then
you close what does the flow roughly
look like the flow looks like basically
on your server and the client you
basically you open your connection to
your qkt device through your qkd api you
use a key handle to essentially identify
the session at the two ends the key
handle can be sent in the open to the
other end it's not just an identifier
between the two endpoints there's also a
version where you can pre distribute the
key handle and you don't actually have
to send it between the two ends you
initiate a connection between the two
ends and then you run a get key again
and again and then you close it now
that's roughly the API and what were
they elements of the challenge there are
basically two parts one was to actually
integrate
this API was OpenSSL and and the other
was to actually implement the qkd api in
software and so basically there are
people who actually understood the
physics and wanted to implement a qkd
protocol could do so and basically
provide that API or people who wanted to
just have an abstract API and actually
do hacking on an open source repository
of open SSL it could do that and then
the first part is the one I'm going to
focus on and talk about here so there
was actually a team and Delft that
attempted to integrate this qkd API into
open SSL Composer Bruno Evo and Tim and
Bruno actually has a very thorough
write-up and if you follow this thing
it's very thorough it has a lot of
background information about like
encryption by the SSL and why quantum
key distribution and so on it's actually
it's not just about the projects also a
very thorough background explanation so
I do recommend visiting it it also has
running code if you would actually want
to try out and saying roughly there are
two ways of extending open SSL and
basically open a Cell provides an NG
provides a way of extending open cell
using what they call engines and they're
basically a way for openness cell to
offload some of the heavier
computational functions onto Hardware
normally and so if you have like
diffie-hellman key a protocol you can
actually offload some of the more
computationally intensive stuff onto
hardware that's what an engine is for
you basically provide callbacks for the
sink sweden hardware or you create a
first-class key exchange protocol state
machine the other one would record the
first one doesn't actually require you
to change anything in the open a cell
code base the second one does actually
require you to change the open a cell
code base the team opted to go for to
implement an engine they abused the
diffie-hellman protocol so basically
open a self but it was running
diffie-hellman
but really the callbacks were just doing
qkd and what does their architecture if
they look like so we provided a mock api
in order to let one of the teams
actually implemented an edition of the
api so actually the hackathon they just
had a mock which just didn't do anything
quantum I just provided the API in a
mock way and then basically they
an engine difficult and benjin built on
top of their security API that would
actually communicate with the openness
the library so we're just a call back to
the OpenSSL library and the OpenSSL
library would therefore do qkd thinking
I was doing diffie-hellman difficulty
and challenges and there's some the
engine actually behaved differently on
the server the client side but the
callbacks were actually symmetrical and
opened a cell and so that kind of was a
challenge in the end the team actually
implemented two different binaries two
different openness silk libraries and
also the design of the mock API was
actually pretty limited because it was
actually meant to be just be simple and
so that we didn't have to spend too much
time implementing a mock API and but it
turned out and actually the design led
to deadlocks and you wouldn't use the
engines because of the way the state
machine worked so they actually had to
hack on the mock API as well and in the
end they did there's actually running
code on this github link and the
conclusion is open ourselves actually
quite difficult to extend and even the
easy hacky way of doing it and actually
something I didn't put in is like I
found this project quite cold I saw a
team working on it because we've done a
few of these hackathons already and very
often people without a quantum
background would spend a day or two just
learning about quantum how do you
combine gates what do they do it cetera
where I said this will make actually
could like really get on it actually
implement an application and into an
application so I found that quite fun
okay am i speaking so actually I used to
work on similar projects ten years ago
my target was i ke so and I'm asking a
question so do not showing a favor of
qkg so you know the qkd come and they
fail i do to restore ping then we isn't
you need some kind of a fallback or oh
so oh yes so the fallback em so the way
the api was designed actually i actually
should have put a picture is was that
basically all the complicated stuff
about qkd
was the below the API so essentially you
had the whole system connected to each
other it did all the post-processing all
the all the difficult stuff was done
below the API none of the difficult
stuff was expected to be done above the
API but no we didn't have any so I
actually don't even know what the API
specifies it does if it can't get a key
I think it just blocks I guess so now we
didn't have a fallback a couple of
commands one from let me recall I think
is a Bruno yes
Bruno's I'm working on an implementation
of VB 84 in Python using the simulacrum
simulator the quantum part is done but
I'm still working on the classical
post-processing information
reconciliation and privacy amplification
once the Python implementation is done I
will translate it to C and integrate it
with open SSL work down at the hackathon
I expect this work to be completed
within a few week weeks at most
everything will be posted on github no
no no yes oh yeah Bruno is the guy who
actually led the team so he implemented
this hacker and stuff so yeah do follow
it yeah I still do strongly recommend
visiting that website his write-up is
actually very good if you're interested
in this project okay let's make this
let's wind this up quickly because we've
already burned almost all of our open
mic time and I want to get somehow
anyway yes well Bruno's opinion is
important cuz he's a guy who didn't know
is my question precisely when it comes
to the fallback and all the like is
about identifying a set of proper proper
ciphers which to be used in TLS to with
open SSL this is something you have not
done yet right or not that I'm aware of
no probably would be once we have this
or you have this more or less stable it
will be interesting to discuss about the
cipher suites and even trying to to
standardize and why not well again new
Tomoya here so I didn't
the employer that I worked for before so
I work for the German Aerospace Center
and first of all thank you a lot for
bringing the subject up for a very first
ITF that attend here so in 2013 we got a
nature in a science article for already
trying to run a BB 84 protocol and
synchronized with a plane so plane
flying did the key exchange and the data
encryption everything done so this is
something that we're very much looking
forward to coming out you know because
I'm this a huge project in Europe going
on called the qci quantum communication
infrastructure that's based on the qnet
project and I'm pretty sure you're also
aware of the media satellite project
running by the Chinese run by the
Chinese so I think this is a very
important topic and I think next time
I'm gonna be here with ten more of my
colleagues hopefully working on that so
thank you a lot
sounds cool that's exciting alright
we've got five minutes phone phone for
for open mic out of the 20 I'd hoped it
to have but I think all of this has been
valuable so far questions anything
related to the working group at all or a
device on running the the working group
or advice on where we should go next
someone should have something yeah sorry
for kind of hogging the mic so I do it I
only have one thing to say a topic
another time so one of the topics that
reoccurs in the mailing list is
multi-part of entanglement but there's
also one more topic that pops up every
now and again on my mailing list which
is the relation between the way we do
quantum networks and MPLS or more
specifically gmpls there's already work
actually done that qk d ng MPLS so
there's actually even a publication I
think you worked on that and so there's
actually already work on that and I
think you'll be I know one of their an
interesting question actually to tackle
as well and Kure G given that there will
be MPLS and gmpls experts in the ITF and
so I think that's actually and actually
Bruno has also committed to work on
actually adding an MPLS section to the
architecture draft and so there's
definitely scope for a lot of questions
and how do you do these things what are
the similarities what can we piggyback
on etc other comments or questions one
in particular I want to bring up before
we sort of finish here on the proposal
that's on the table is to push this from
proposed RG to full RG as of after
Vancouver which is the next IETF we have
not yet committed to actually doing a Qi
RG meeting like this in Vancouver yet
but but it's very likely to happen and I
almost certainly will be there in person
any any comments or questions on on
Vancouver or becoming a full RG people
in favor of that
other comments or questions ya wanna hum
for whether or not we should push for
full large e okay everybody who's in
favor of pushing for full RG as soon as
sort of feasible let's let's hop
sounds like consensus to me anyone
opposed to to moving toward full RG for
this um sounds like consensus to me any
other questions comments
if not we'll end up about 90 seconds
early here see you all at the social in
door at the plenary tomorrow blue sheets
anyone who did not sign the blue sheets
please do so before you go out and
please bring me the blue sheets
[Music]