welcome to one of the two routing area
working group sessions here in Singapore
we'll get started in a moment when
everyone kind of sits down and people
come on in
so I'm Chris Bowers this is Jeff tonzura
and jingxian is down there
she's our secretary and she'll be one of
the note takers and she's also been
doing a great job keeping a lot of the
logistics running for the working group
so probably you've seen the note well by
this point things that you say while
participating the working group have
certain consequences so please pay
attention to to be note well and read it
well if you haven't already so there's a
sort of generic IETF policy about our IP
our disclosure the routing area working
group interpretation of that that
process so that we you know we got all
of our eyes and cross our T's is to
require that document authors and
contributors state whether or not
they're aware of any IP are relevant to
the document in question that you know
it also others should generally do it as
well if you're participating in the
working group in any in any fashion and
we do it at two stages in the working
group document process both when
adopting individual dress and then
before working group last call so we
have
engine doing the note-taking do we have
a jabber scribe okay you're on jabber so
that's good the blue sheets are already
circulating that's good
I'm gonna switch over to the agenda this
one so it's traditional for people to
have an opportunity to get feedback on
the agenda this is the agenda that we
have published for today we also have
another session on Friday that we can
you know if there any issues with this
agenda we can generally catch up on the
second session so moving back go on to
the whoops yes I'm gonna go through a
review of the working group document
status
we had no RFC's published since IETF 105
documents that have already been
submitted to the iesg for publication
have changed state a little bit but
they're sort of winding their way
through the process this document has
been on you know in this state for quite
a long time so I think Jeff is going to
comment on this so we've decided to
change the Shepherd and engine thank you
agree to the Shepherd's of you and
little progress has dropped
we recently adopted the Q s model draft
as a working group document there are
several this is a list of all the
existing working group documents several
of them the ones listed at the top the
draft that's published has expired it
would be a good idea to we have an
update from the first I think the editor
of the first draft the tlf a draft would
you like to address this yeah
so defendant of ski speaking for a draft
I'm currently working on it I just need
more time to work on V data pen
procedures which requires a lot of text
review but some changes are already done
but is that a print part is our will
take more time sorry for that okay well
thank you thank you
the ATN bgp draft is expired it would be
good to just keep it current even if
there aren't substantive changes just to
keep it top of mind the the data tracker
now is a way to show expired drafts as
well so I'm showing these but it would
be good to you know not require that so
the VRP PFD point-to-point draft I sent
out an email to the authors of that and
requesting that they at a minimum do
just a bear update with some sort of
administrative changes on that you know
it would be good to get an understanding
with respect to that draft about if
anyone's implementing it and that kind
of you know when we look at it and see
it's expired what does that mean exactly
does it mean that it's stable and no one
you know or does it mean that no one's
implementing it so it would be good to
in terms of figuring out how we proceed
to get that feedback but first off
please just update
the draft so that the administrative
issue can be dealt with the desk source
routing draft is also showing expired I
guess David had asked about adopting
that we should probably start a
discussion about adopting or rather not
adopting but doing working good last
call for that draft it's been in its
current state for probably a year and a
half or so so the other drafts here I
think the first two we're going to hear
about and I don't think we have
presentations on the other ones okay
okay so our family require - changes and
we plan to last college after this ATF
policy model I assume the same engine
the main author that we discussed it we
plan to La Scala between this and next
state here speaking for post the
extension model Andy for both the RHIB
extension model and policy model besides
they've over 180 more than my IETF I
think we are gonna last car after this
idea okay so I think
first up is Linda well so maybe they're
gonna adjust it once someone's there am
i good afternoon can you hear me okay
good
okay give an update and this is my third
time doing this update I hope I won't
fall into those well those expired draft
and give up but anyway thank you for the
comment and I made changes to this
presentation so so I'll give the update
on since I get 105 on the network -
cloud problem statement and gap analysis
so the purpose of the document I got
quite a few comments while reach out to
people hey can you give some comments on
this draft I got some comments people
say why describe lots of problems and
what are theirs for it's not really for
educational purposes right so I want to
make clear to people that there are lots
and lots of problems associated with
cloud interconnection and some of the
problems not something I think we think
IETF can do so this draft in particular
is really to identify some of the
problems on the network problems or
network in cloud interconnection and to
see that if there's anything our idea
can do or maybe I can already have so
that was the purpose of this
documentation make it clear so since
IETF 105 it was pointed to us that
we need to include a scenario of inter
cloud connection so okay ultimately this
is a benefit I think that it's bigger
now so there's a temporary setback but
okay so the oh the cloud public cloud
data center today is primarily between
client to the cloud okay you can have
different ways to access the cloud and
however if you have some workload in AWS
if you want to connect you as your you
pretty much have to helping back to your
customer gateway to interconnect them
together so the scope of this document
we call network to cloud is really to
address the net network perspective to
interconnect them how do we manage like
be PC from one cloud to v-net in another
cloud and maybe like Oracle may have a
different way to identify their the the
private network and how they use
different net ok so here's just a brief
summary of what's added we added
interconnect hybrid cloud the problems
associate with them we also add a
section to talk about some
characteristics of application hosting
the cloud the connecting to them well
the thing is like we know the network
augmentation it's not just one that were
connecting to the cloud and lots of
times multiple ways and you may have
networks stitched together
or you may have network magic multiplex
together
another thing is application based
policy those policies can change based
on where the application is so it's
basic
away from the traditional we have a
firewall with defying our access list or
our security policies on the specific
appliances and when you have application
in the cloud the the policies actually
move with the application you have to
have a way to specify those policies are
specifically for those applications when
application moved from this location to
another location the policy has to
follow them basically that's another
difference from the traditional
networking and third part is application
based forwarding instead of destination
based forwarding in the network for so
many decades has been always using
destination as the way to forward but
many of the application today is really
using application ID to forward and
different application many different
topologies so that's one some of the key
characteristics of connecting to cloud
which is different from traditional
networking at a slide this is actually
primarily from earlier suggestion the
key requirement so for accessing the
cloud while the key thing is
authentication authorization right so
you could have a particular application
in the cloud and then depending on who's
accessing it you have different policy
right or you can have policies on this
cloud application saying hey if the
traffic requests from the prams
headquarter data center coming the
request you can grant the communication
or processing but if the request traffic
coming from a sure data center then you
don't have any communication you drop it
all you may report or maybe the policy
is changing like for example from a
certain time to a certain time you have
different authentication method
and then when you have our to cloud data
center when one application need to
connect to another cap application how
do you do the authentication how do you
do the authorization so that's a big
thing about intercloud communication
second part is in the cloud access one
Enterprise can create multiple B pcs
right
like for example a big corporation you
may have a PPC for your testing
environment you may have a VP C for your
production environment and you could
have the same application running in
different B pcs but when the traffic
actually coming from this data center or
cloud data's in a to your campus network
lots of time you can now tell which VP
see it's coming from you have an address
it doesn't attach with the PPC number
and similarly you have ensures v-net
similar thing the v-net and vp c how do
I make sure that they actually belong to
the same client or same domain so you
may have a subnet like we call subnet
belong to one particular group but when
you assign something put something into
the EWS they have a VP see you put
something else in to the assure you have
v-net how do we combine them as well and
entity to show they can actually
communicate with each other
so thus something has to be addressed
and that's another thing is about API
right but this API actually I'm not sure
if I can do anything about it
it's basically different cloud
datacenter have different api's to
create their workload to to do assign
that to do all kinds of functions and
many many of the enterprises today they
all want need consistent API so they can
move from one place to another place
still where you have questions so maybe
I don't understand what you're proposing
Linda but
we keep talking about preparers
proprietary cloud designs which are of
course entirely within the scope of the
provider to define and modify the api's
as they want we don't normally sort of
do interfaces between proprietary
systems we only really ever design
standard solutions so you could have a
sort of a shim layer that we define that
they have to map to but I don't think we
should be talking about mapping between
proprietary systems I'm not proposing
that I'm just saying this some of the
problems appearing and this may be out
of the scope of IETF I just put it there
this is one of the problems facing by
many enterprises when they access
multiple clouds that's all I'm doing
here I don't think that's something we
need to address that's my personal deal
okay that wasn't coming out coming it
wasn't very clear okay okay and another
problem requirement is the neck how do
they do the net different cloud provider
has different methods and how does the
network handling different net methods
and DNS and also that is any way to like
discover how many cloud data centers
this particular application is connected
to right those are some of the key
requirements for the multi cloud for the
key problems that's the focus of this
particular document is really to address
some of the problems Enterprise facing
to connect to the multiple cloud so so
the with different cloud is basically
like we have different access methods
right so I I'm repeating myself so that
today you have to here ping back to the
campus network before you can reach to
another cloud make it very difficult
second thing is as a application self
hiding inside the cloud it's because the
cloud allowed different ways of access
right you can access through public
Internet
you can access from IP sack you can
access from the direct gateway they were
connect and as application themselves
residing inside the cloud they can now
tell which which entrance which gateway
comes in that's how it today's design
and with that it's difficult to make a
consistent like performance measurement
or maybe applying different policy
depending on which entrance you coming
if you comes in from IP said maybe I
should have one way one set of security
functions if you come from direct
connect maybe I should have another set
of security functions if you come from
the internet maybe I should add more of
DDoS attack right there could be many
DDoS attack coming and another thing is
the the IP set itself right so Abby set
itself IP set is point-to-point right so
point-to-point works well when you get
just have two points when you do the
configuration you configure who are you
who is your remote end and but the
problem is when you have multiple sites
when you have ten twenty sites and this
configuration becomes very difficult and
especially you we have two different
cloud data centers using a preset
becomes not not easily to manageable so
even though the ensure today allow you
to I think it appears at a recent
announcement to support Ikey v2 so that
allow them to be automatically exchange
the key is to allow automatic creation
of the IPSec so another problem with
them I'm POS like many enterprises today
use npos and
but MPLS network is fixed and it's not
easily to be extended reading into the
card so for whatever access you have
today to access your workload in the
cloud you have to do some kind of
stitching so that bring up another issue
of how do you do the end-to-end
performance measurement and what kind of
measurement you need to attach what kind
of metadata you need to attach for
example if your enterprise here residing
inside your on-prem data center when you
have traffic coming in from different
cloud what kind of metadata you can
carry within your packet so that when
you arrive into your unprimed data that
you can tell immediately which location
come from which VPC it comes from which
v-net it comes from with those
information coming attached in the
metadata you will be able to do
appropriate actions and not advocating
particular solution or anything but
there's just some examples or ITTF work
like metadata in SFC can be applied to
this kind of situation
well the gabilan analysis I just added
this in the past we've been talking
about using tunneling cap to carry the
IPSec information to carry the net
information that is in ID are they
already there already a document
proposal on how to do that and in the
best we have a informational draft
showing how do we use PGP to be able to
distribute the IPSec information to
establish those tunnels
but one thing hasn't been addressed is
this application base boarding in this
example is showing that I have those
nodes like for example
a payment system they can only talk to
the payment gateway in a particular
location in their headquarter and then
other applications can communicate
point-to-point is a multi-point
connection and if those applications
have different address then this can be
achieved very easily with the routing
protocols we have developed it could
happen that the application ID like this
read application payment system and some
other application from the same user may
have the same address and this can
create some problems how do we
distribute that information because the
application read has to only follow the
point-to-point topology the tree
topology to the payment gateway they
don't allow the read application to talk
among each other the purple one is
another type of application which is
allowed to be multi-point so one address
has to be put on into two different
topologies I think that's something I'm
not sure if ITF has anything or not I'm
putting here on the table and then we
have lots of experts in this room and
solicited an input if you have any good
suggestions hey this is something I have
already done that'd be great and would
love to document that into that into
this document another thing is the IPSec
today is among the client traffic you
create a client traffic and you create
IPSec tunnel among those clients that is
well between if you just have two nodes
but if you have multiple nodes and it
can be difficult so so that it would be
good to be able to create some kind of
port days IPSec tunnel so treating the
IPSec tunnel as a transport PI
so that different traffic can be
multiplexed together or be forwarded all
those notes along along the way less CPU
one on CPU can be the one as a forwarder
I almost like creating a vif over this
untrusted Network so that's something
it's not yet there yet so next step so
one more review I promise chair that I
know that people are very tight on time
you don't have many times much time to
do
everybody has lots of work I promise
I'll write a very simple document just
along the line I present today maybe one
page two page take you maybe five
minutes to review it to see if those
problems have been properly identified
yes women Rick's Enochian I know that I
have to start but in my view your this
document is all over the place in my
view right because your started with
saying I problem statement for net to
cloud but you're mixing as the one
problem statement with net to cloud
problem statement and I think you have
to contain to a specific space you want
to address and either it's cloud or it's
as the one and but right now you're
mixing it all over the place and as a
result I think you're putting too many
things into it and as a result it
becomes unreadable and people probably
get lost with it right that's my
personal view so my my question is
should you focus on cloud
interconnection and I think then that's
one option or you should focus on as the
one problem statements into working with
clout or something but right now from
reading the document personally I don't
see where you want to go here alright
that's a very good suggestions we're
going to focus on the net to cloud for
the cloud interconnection so I'll take
out all the sd1 mentioning we're
focusing on primarily we use network to
connect to different cloud or multiple
clouds what are the problems we have
today what are the possible
solution there could be IT have already
had because I think then I if that's the
states then I would say focus on to
requirement because you have internet
facing use cases which are like sauce
internet focused and there is private
VPN use cases ok I think my suggestion
would be to focus on these two areas ok
and and and contain it like that because
otherwise we are you're mixing things
all over the place and as a result it
becomes much more clear what what is
there and what needs to be done for
those type of things
thank you very much so the note taker
please write that no sir that's very
helpful suggestions
definitely any other comments ok so if
you feel that this demand work is
valuable but lower growth he could spin
out another draft and just postpone the
work till the first one is resolved if
put quite some effort into it would be
too bad just to delete it okay so you're
saying like separate the work like it's
up to you to your work ok so what I
would do is create a very short draft
just to describe the problems with
network to cloud and then associate
problems I want people to give input
just for that specific domain not not
worrying about sty oh and he was just
talking about that and if I find some of
the material in the document available
maybe I'll create another document ok
thank you thank you very much
thank you for your suggestion that's
very helpful
next up is shoe ping
hello everyone I'm shooting from Huawei
and
hello hi I'm shooting from Huawei
and on behalf of all the co-authors I'm
going to present you about the AP and
six that is a application-aware ipv6
networking and currently we have to
draft one needs a problem statement and
use cases the other is about the initial
framework proposal and we would like to
have your reviews and comments thank you
and the first about the motivations that
is why we want to propose the AP and six
as we know that the network operators
have been facing the challenges of
providing better services to their
customers and especially nowadays as the
5g and the industry verticals involves
and the more and more new applications
with diverse service requirements
accessing the network and so that will
be desirable for the network operators
to be able to provide that
differentiated fine granularity traffic
operations and to guarantee their SLA
and and okay sorry I thought it was and
and also moreover and as the
technologies involved and the currently
there online gaming live reuse dreaming
and also the video conferencing those
applications are widely deployed and
used by the end users by the company's
enterprises and the dos applications
have even more demanding requirements
and they are the actual revenue
producing applications so the applet
that the network operators
would be good to provide the the
application level SRA guarantee fine
granularity and as Eric guarantee but
however the current network dodging
doesn't have such capability of
application awareness and the network
operator is not aware of watch
applications actually traversing the
network infrastructure and to support to
guarantee the SLA currently the
operators can only use the light load
and sometimes even 10% in network
utilization so the network operators
just to keep investing in their network
structure but they haven't counted the
corresponding revenue increases and the
actual actually they are losing the
opportunities and to have the new
revenue so fundamentally for us the
motivation is to bring the application
information into the network and to make
the network aware of the applications
and as well as their requirements so and
here and we also we would like to take
advantage of the big chant for now that
is the ipv6 and as our v6 are being
widely deployed and and and the
programmability provided by ipv6 that is
our basics that is the programmable
space in there encapsulations can be
utilized to convey some information from
the application side into the network
but of course and other protocols where
certain extensions could also serve the
same purpose but we cannot ignore the
ipv6 and as our v6 other big trend for
the for now and for future so basically
a paean 6 wants to achieve the
application awareness and to have the
application visibility in the network to
empower the network of operators to
support to provide those fine granular
granularity traffic operations and to
have corresponding revenue increases and
to allow the requirements of the
applications to be specified to the
network and the regarding the
application informations that could
include the application identification
and the SRA requirements of service
requirements and with those application
information carried in the package and
the network could provide and the up the
corresponding network services and we
have identified the three key elements
for AP and six the first one is the
application information conveying and
that it could be the application itself
or the edge devices to add those
application information and ways the
augmentation of the existing
encapsulations
and just to be noted and that is not a
enforcement that is optional as up to
the applications to decide whether to I
did or not if they don't add the DOS
information and their packets will be
traded in the with the traditional way
of course they couldn't get the benefit
of the provided by 18:6
and the second element is a matching
between the application information and
the network so that is like the network
provide its capability towards the
application and according to those
application information and the network
could provide corresponding services
like the network slicing deterministic
latency guarantee OSF see if Center and
the third one is the natural measurement
and that is to achieve the pattern or
accurate matching for the second element
so the net because the network
capability is changing over time and in
order to have the accurate matching and
the natural is to
keep monitoring its performance and and
then provided is the better matching
here and here is the framework and as I
said as I said before the application
and the edge devices could add those
application information and then in the
head end of the network and according to
those application information and the
network could for example to steer those
application flows into corresponding as
our v6 tunnel with certain as our a
guarantees and along the path and in the
meadow point and according to those
application information and the some we
could also do some manipulations to
those packets to guarantee it here as
our a and the here another highlight is
that this flow driven method could
enable this faster service for reasoning
and we have done a lot of communications
with our customers and with verticals
and the industry here so we have
identified some use cases that could
directly benefit from the AP and six and
here we have categorized into the
following five the first one is the
fundament fundamental one that is a
application aware I saw a guarantee that
is to enable the network operators to
provide differentiated service treatment
and the fine granularity traffic
operations capability and and then the
second is the application aware network
slicing this is for some applications
that they have the specific requirements
and in order to guarantee their to
satisfy their requirements and some
levels of isolation problem problem
probably in terms of the service
isolation our resources isolation to
guarantee their requirements so for
those
locations they could be steered into
certain networks lies and to guarantee
their requirements there and for the
multiple different applications and they
have errors that requirements they could
be steered into different networks
slices and and those applications could
be served at the same time and in
parallel and again and the third one is
the application aware deterministic
networking for some applications and the
day will require at the deterministic
under the latency guarantee and for such
application flow they could be
identified first and steer into the
certain deterministic path and and then
is the application of our service
function chaining so here is again and
the application flow is identified but
without the help of dpi so it could be
identified and then steered into certain
SFC and in the sequence steering you can
just use the information information
carried in the package and to manipulate
the packets and then for the finally for
the application of our network
measurement and that could empower us to
monitor the application level the
performance and to locate the failure
the past the potential failure that
could arise and here just briefly to
update with you and what happened in the
last time and we host AP and six-eyed
meeting in 105 when this is the meeting
room and we have about 50 attendees and
we have very good discussions there and
we roughly achieve the rough consensus
about the value of the work that's why
we decided to continue and this time we
have two new drafts and together result
collaborators and and so we want to push
forward and for the Knights tab and we
would like to have a meeting list for us
to continue our discussion and now we
can only have the separate discussions
and and also we are also planning to we
are thinking to have above for the next
meeting and here and this time we are
presenting in the RT GWT and we are
really sincerely looking for suggestions
related to the chairs here and how are
we going to move forward on this work so
that's all thank you any questions
women Rick's Nokia a quick question or
why do you contain it to ipv6
wai-wai-wait can be why do you contain
it to ipv6 because you can also do this
with v4 in my view yes I agree as I
mentioned before it doesn't have to be
at ipv6 and it could be our other
protocols but for example v4 NPR's but
we have the mate they have limited the
programmable space we have to do it with
extensions to segment rather you have I
whether it's with umbrellas or with v6
it's you have as many parts as you have
available so it shouldn't be contained
in my view to only v6 for that I can use
as FC as a tagging there is already
application definition inside so it can
take information so you could use that
work which is available to achieve this
objective yes and we acknowledge this
and we have done analysis on all the
fuse and to figure out the possibilities
but and here we would like to carry not
only the very simple ID and the Azeri
requirements actually we could take the
metadata related with that location
whatever you can email which you can do
as I see her
that capability you can put metadata in
the packet okay we went a pseudo beam
from hobby the first one I think that's
the the first one I won't say it as the
why we discuss in rqwg I think the data
plane I use a true now you saw open
because at the beginning we see the ipv6
advantage you because this the
applications about the ipv6 and now this
a network aside also the SRA six can be
combined through ipv6 a similar
seamlessly that's at the point but I
think that usually truly can be open to
the I'm chars or we axel I'm based here
it possible the second one I won't say
that the SFC I true it's a higher some
days of the application information but
from our point of view I think I use
nothing enough on the other hand
therefore the metadata I think I use it
because the metadata is another standard
is the whale that's a pond my only
comment was it's perceived as it's
contained to ipv6 and I think we if we
go down this part which is to be decided
I think we should make it open right
although I believe ipv6 is the future
that doesn't mean that we have to
contain it only that yes there coin a
couple of thoughts one for a technical
body I don't find revenue based
arguments very interesting I would
suggest maybe remove those from the
documents also broadly speaking this
work has some serious network neutrality
implications application where edge
devices are one thing but in the I guess
in the framework document you talk about
an application of end nodes sending this
metadata and then have some serious
privacy applications and market dynamics
being what they are you know RFC 21 19
may vs. must it's a very short step from
may to must for some networks and you
could end up in a situation where you're
forcing devices on say a large network
in a country to to basically self DP
their traffic and I think I don't and I
know in one of these documents discuss
any of these issues that I could see and
I think it's a huge problem yes we
acknowledge the security and the privacy
issue that is also noted in the draft
and actually post draft and we know we
are we are aware of those mechanisms are
needed and for example so some
automation access control and I also the
authentication of those IDs application
information son needed and here that
would be one topic for us to explore
there right ID the potential for abuse
isn't it's not discussed really right
and that that's the real concern here I
think so I would like to add to that and
looking at six men Suraj discussions
they are very much focused on single
domain you're proposing internet right
we single domain first and well as we
discussed with us operators now they own
their the network and as well as
application the cloud so they could do
it within one domain my point privacy
should be central point of your work if
you cannot provide proper privacy
technology used it's not really
beautiful yes the privacy to my
understanding is related ways
information exposed by the applications
but that information could be encrypt in
some way so and also those information
once the application registered itself
it needs to be authenticated so I would
like to encourage you to point this
issue centrally in your work and work on
it so you have clear explenation how
you're going to do it okay my
measurement from title I think this
approach useful for the application
where readability because you know we we
often said they want to make sure the
applications confidence avoid end-to-end
but for the
applicator are there sa SLA insurance I
think it might be maybe this is some
difficulty for the department here
Network because you know the application
there are many many application
application so if you included the
application ID in the network letter
I think the rotor cannot keep so many
state for the selection of the different
posture I do not know how you consider
is the accessibility yes and that is the
so first of all and that is depends on
the device capability and from the
camera the scalability provided by the
large number of applications and first
of all it's not all the applications for
you preserve in this way that is only
for the like the demanding applications
they have specific needs to be satisfied
in the network they could utilize in
this way and you I think the unfortunate
is no IP network for the SLR assumes to
be often classified the traffic into the
several category so I think for the
number the adult category the network
can easily deployed the different parts
but for the numerous applications
requirement I think it is not possible
to deploy these different cuts the line
yeah sure that I think that is about the
application ID the how to design is ID
currently we have the segment different
part and that could somehow to
categorize as you said into the traffic
into groups so just a time check on this
discussion we had only allocated 10
minute
so let's we'll hear the questions or
responses from the two people that are
currently up but we should wind it up in
the next two or three minutes okay I dug
Montgomery I apologize I haven't read
the drafts but I had two simple
questions you you said that you clearly
say in the drafts why you can't achieve
what you want to achieve with existing
virtual path and cost technologies you
you you do that gap analysis of why you
can't achieve this with the existing
mechanisms versified the problem
statement Holly are you in the document
oh we have these to the analysis of the
youth Network yeah you're the first
draft statement requirement and my my
second question is of equal ignorant
about this it are your IDs something
that have global significance and global
uniqueness that is depends and for the
certain domain and we are thinking it
first of all it will be valid within
this is operational domains it's it
doesn't have to be global for the first
stage and for sure I think the mati
doming we also acknowledge the in the
tract and that needs to be considered
because the IDE needs to be delivered at
corresponding Linda Dahmer from future
way of this course I haven't read this
track before today's meeting but just
glancing through the draft I find is
very useful even though people bring up
security concerns if we can have a
mechanism to hide the user information
do some kind of mapping that bring the
application information into the network
and that will bring tremendous value
this bring up to the discussion which
happening other as deals in a math in
the cloud architecture discussion
customers wanting application based
forwarding is not based on IP address
but based on an application ID different
application require different topology I
think this will be very very useful not
just my comment thank you
next up is why no Chen hello everyone
I'm a quatrain from a future way today
I'm going to talk about sf-86 past
increased equals protection so first we
have a overview right now we have SR
pass fast protection for transit note
here we propose essa fast protection for
equation node so for example we have
here we have a as a pass from p1 ingress
and then to p3 as a egress so this pass
is a pass carries the
VPN traffic so in order to provide
protection for p3 which is is the egress
of all this as pass this as a pass so we
have we will have a PI cap equals node
here is pp4 so in order to provide
protection we first we configure on p4
which is a biker believers so the
concrete configuration that which has a
configure bureau ID which is to protect
ps3 and with this kind of configuration
and then there's some actions going on
so one action is that the information
about this protection will be
distributed in the in the network and
then at the same time and PE for which
is egos note a backup accuser node so
pg4 will generate a map a map in so this
mapping will map that traffic for for a
VPN traffic from when the traffic when
the traffic coke received from backup
has total traffic volume through data
mapping map into the destination which
is c2 so after configuration so on the
previous hope of a equals node for
example here is p1 and that the p1 will
create forward entries for protect the
ps3 here for example on PE 1 when 1 P 1
which is previous hope of equation P P
is 3 when P is really fails P 1 P 1 will
detect the failure so P 1 we all seen
the traffic which is a packet to PE 3 to
the bike hub equals note which is PV for
through bike a pass so before sending
those traffic to the backup path to the
bike a believer's node so p1 well just
to modify party a little bit just add
that mirror ID for the package so when
this modified package
deliver to a PE for which he is back
Kappa equals note so PE for where I'll
use that my pin to map this because we
have a map Bureau IDE in that package
and then we have a my pin entry in the
PE for sopia for where my buddy's
package using that my entry to the local
raping ID and then that local wavy had
idea where awesome because well you in
the same VPN so that package well
finally deliver to the c2 so we provided
protections for failure of us note ps3
in faster way so regarding to the
updates to the previous version so we
just the ad the two sections
why is the security considerations and
that's why is a ionic institutions and
then we updated the reference and the
third why the some editorial changes so
any other comments and suggestions just
a question have you considered whether
this will work with SRM six this is our
physics you may m6 oh you mean the yeah
I think that's a cool topic and that one
moves forward and then we can upgrade
this one to also provide solutions to
that a conqueror esta or use that one
yeah okay good okay we change from
channel move out
at first I think this solution is a
really useful I think because of during
4G China Mobile deployed a lot of a dual
homing protection function so I think
this function can be used in the future
and that I have a question about the
mayor note so here you just released the
one major note is
other possible configure more than one
mirror note right now I hear we have
only one backup plus a backpack have a
eCourse note so you mean we are want so
here for the mural to one load or two
dolls I think in the in this document so
we can provide protections to multiple
locators so if you use single data
that's a marrow to Mudville and the
marrow tomato I don't know whether you
mean that so my meaning that currently
you have a ps3 as a working node right
yes a p4 maybe it's a protection note
accomplice yeah the bad cop one is that
possible we have a such as a p5 well you
mean so we need a DC is a one just one
redundancy we want maybe M redundancy
yes my poor redundancy yeah I know yeah
that's a that's a I think that's a good
topic I think I think we so in these are
job that we're gonna provide a solution
for that one I think maybe in you know
draft like we can consider that one we
can provide a anyway protection
something like that okay thank you I do
I'm from Tottenham a long question first
yeah Cara Mady Cara met him activity be
finished automatically under the backup
router such as people come into the met
here my PSA dollar allocation
automatically you mean country you said
the median say the either
configured on the backup or your
so right now it's a one-way this or
configuration so another way maybe a
source so this right now because we have
a central controller you will have a in
the controller environment so those
those kind of configuration can be
automatic through the controllers so the
controller can do can select which one
protocol which one and then which ID
provide which locator and then those can
automatic mean that way yeah I think
this is in Canada should be a remand
automatically in network so you know in
Korea we cannot know which node or which
link will be broken down in network so
you know we I think if in such a such
mechanism become deployment
automatically to India network we are
either
management of the VPN protects them yeah
yeah all right I think these draft is
just for a proposal based solution and
then based on this basic solution we can
have a very comprehensive or automatic
and that solutions because with some
notes or server controllers have a high
level view and then he know which node
can provide for some kind of protection
for which node and then whether we have
another resource and link to support
this protection okay with juniper so you
could use in any caste locators to
achieve the same thing right so I was
just wondering why that that doesn't
work here any caste locators and okay
turist yeah these are located as a
profile some can there Association for
the note for the he was a note so for
example here we configure PE for to
provide a locator some number and then
this is just the same locator on p3 p4
and same customer would get same SIDS
it's
same-same VPN seed say mrs. hatten
wanted to you mean exactly same as ease
or same indicator or different location
locator is any car so it is same locator
on p3 p4 VPN CID can also be same
because it's just another 128-bit
address
yeah you mean that sense I is ok
associated with okay yes you think it
works
yes so if he's an okay there so she has
it that a note and then that low to fail
and then we have for the traffic light
would it be correct to understand that
mature proposal is backup solution so
unless primary is down secondary will
not take cover while with any caste
you just used Lotus not semantics in
this context so if you could address on
mailing list so again I assume that what
you're talking about this backup while
what Chad was proposing is any class
there's some difference in Seema Louis
Chan juniper one question is that appear
out on p1 if we want to protect the VPN
are we need to we need to look into the
more packets
I mean dipped into the lipos so that to
locate whether where there is a
protector or no protector I mean if you
want how many labels you need to mean
I'm a release X labeled in to inspect oh
you mean the okay so I regarding to the
VPN so we for example here we use a VPN
SSID so because VPN we also get more
information so those are key value
information nice and easy in the trough
so here we we turned in this picture we
come give details about this total
information I think basically for VPN
for example of he be honest so so these
are VAP here and for one prefix those
Vivian can be associated by those kind
of or same a VPN and the same way of a
VM for example on the
history where I would have Libya ID for
the backup girls we have another VPN as
ID so because the way I was
we know this on the same VPN and then
those we can associated those one so
that's the my opinion come from so for
for the VPN ID on ps3 that's different
on ps4 v and E as another one so when P
is three files
p1 we detect a failure and in p1 we
modified the package just a add a mirror
IB through the package and then the
Viviani on on the ps3 not changed so
when this package is delivered to the p4
and then because we have maro we use
melody mode at a VPN ID on the ps3 to
the local VP ID which is on a PG 4 and
then because of those even so will have
different V Vivian IDs but those two
different one of for same Vivian so we
can deliver to the same destination
which is synchronizing we even your even
into your second presentation would you
be okay to present it on Friday because
we are running out of time so what do
you okay okay can I please be quick so
ask my question or not do so me also
because okay also can we ask for this
one more well before you ask for
adoption I think there's a few technical
problems you need to solve not the least
of which was whether the anycast
solution is a better solution or not and
also exactly we are whether you're
actually conforming to various
architectures in the design so I think
we're a little way from calling for a
so I really ask you to your sleeves to
discuss all the options provide all the
comments and we'll see after that but
you understand you need to resolve all
the comments before we can you need to
resolve all the comments go to the next
presentation so this wise about
architecture for youth basically as a
central controller so basically PGP is
already you the controller is somewhere
in somehow
for example we ratify the SR policy and
then direct traffic and then we have
some advantages we use PGP as
controllers we list the number of
advantages here so basically these are
draft we propose us as three reference
architectures for PGE as a central
controller so why is a single controller
and then that's why is a controller
cluster so which is the middle middle
one so we have here we have a two
controllers which is forms a cluster
women in January's and controllers which
forms one cluster and then the server
reference architecture is a hierarchical
structure so this is the these documents
provided some kind of informational
architecture reference so we presented a
couple times I wonder do we have any
questions for this one so can we ask for
this one John okay
John who is probably asking CGI chair
John scatter I am NOT up here with any
chair hats on I I guess my question is
and I think this has been asked if I
remember right in previous meetings and
I don't really know if it's been
answered or if I if it wasn't I forgot
I'm sorry
why do we need to work on this in the
IETF and and I'll give my own answer
which is so far I don't think we do it's
something that people already have been
doing for some years now seemed like we
could do it just fine without any RFC
and so I would discourage the working
group to take on this extra work but if
you have a convincing reason for me why
we do need an RFC please go ahead you
see I know we have already used this
kind of idea whatever so I think maybe
we have some document so just that
document is some kind of reference
architectures just as a reference as a
informational maybe I think it's however
stiffening of key
I don't like that you talk about bgp as
a controller bgp is just protocols so it
can be a self interface of a controller
but it's not a controller at all so you
can define a controller architecture but
it has nothing to deal with bgp bgp is
just an interface that the controller
could use to program a path but we
already have the extensions defined to
do so so I don't really see yeah Sooni
idea that we we can generalize so these
are PGP as are already some framework of
controller architecture in IETF we are
going to cut here in Europe neck
then we're gonna go to the next
presentation since we've already cut it
down to 20 minutes thank you
hi my name is Dan Bogdanovich and I want
to do some thought experiments and here
are some of you know the food for
thoughts
anyway it's also continuation from the
last presentation and to figure out how
we can evolve the network automation and
the network program ability we have to
ask ourself a little bit more and how do
we want to continue getting you know to
the goals in order to enable better
operational productivity for the network
operators the is there a value of
splitting things up into multiple layers
splitting the decision making where
should we make some decisions should we
focus on continuing everything on the
network hardware should we try to think
more of that and see what should be
running there what should not be running
there and what benefits can we get out
of that what are the useful feature for
us that you know we are looking you know
to do what is important to the operators
something like hey can I inject retrieve
information that I can change some
routing policies do we want to be able
to do that fast presumably in the real
time or do we want to inject it and say
oh it'll happen at one form at a time
which is pretty in indeterministic
and do we want to offer them different
traffic engineering optimization in the
points that that can be done how can we
you know again this comes down to
real-time actions if there is something
happening that we can react in there
that we can enable an application that
detects that to put the fast reaction
without waiting for the human network
operator to execute on the action so
there are you know are any of those
features useful and the reason I'm
asking that is that traditional
traditional vendors in the past I'm not
sure if this still is the presence but
in the past day you know they were
giving you some lackluster support for
that you know they were I mentioned here
too that I was part of it you know I
know about it but like another one but
it was proprietary interfaces
it wasn't the friendliest you know
environment to develop to the third
parties you have to adopt many vendor
development policies in order to be able
to do that and they were never too happy
to do it or to expand it if you were
asking me I want this I want that Bob
you cannot have this any kind of that
but maybe you can get this and that but
in general many operators found it
useful because it enabled them to react
faster and automate some of the
reactions you know on to their network
and many years ago you know we looked
what is considering the network element
and we said okay we have a network OS we
have a network hardware we have
essentially set of demons that are
running inside that you know everything
nicely packaged up and what we did at
the ITF at you know some other
organizations we decided we will be just
bolting on more and more things onto
that and we did that we were saying oh
we need more and more things to execute
on the network and at the same time we
were running into a problem with the CPU
and you know in the memory and we were
trying to build bigger systems but there
was more more software and more shared
infrastructure they had to run on top of
that and then some people said hey you
know what I Torres it can help us solve
some of the problems that we are seeing
we know with the growing network
operating system and not having enough
resources on the box it is we can also
take in there like PC and PC you know I
just chose I Torres because it is pretty
interesting to me and the things here
that bugs me the most is our controller
agent architecture that we are somehow
continuing to pushing on and I'm saying
guys it's so complicated in my opinion
we should really abandon the controller
agent architecture because
it it is ending up being a mess and then
you have controllers on the controller
hierarchical controllers you are you
know getting in a way lost in different
controllers what each one is doing and
you are hiding too much Network
information behind multiple agents and
controllers one of the thing which I
really liked about the Aitu RS it was
the initial services focused on the
services they included and they said hey
you know what we would like to
manipulate these services this
application as well you know as the rib
in this focus on this you know
applications is something that I find
attractive and that we are touching upon
in different areas of the ITF but at
least to me it looks you know a little
bit of unstructured and I would like to
see more proper layers because if you
look at any network element we can say
we have the forwarding and hardware
abstractions we have the shared
infrastructure in the data and then we
have the applications on top of that now
if we look what is where and saying hey
look what is the forwarding and the
hardware abstractions we have people who
know packet by plants we have people
here in the ITF community who are
building and working with them to
provide us a you know what here are the
here are the models here's what we can
support visiting what we can provide as
a high-level model and decide what to
I'm not saying what should be the
transport for that I'm just saying
here's the model what that hard work can
do it can be vendor specific but as long
we can agree on the common semantics and
the common syntax we can make a big you
know step forward in having some you
know common model that everybody will
understand I love to go back to the ACL
example you have ACL and you have
filters why can't we have one common
name whichever one it is to enable
filtering
on a box if we can achieve on some
functionalities to have common names
it's easier to build forward so with
that if we can decide for each one of
those layers to have a common naming
convention with the common models with
the minimum functionality we can either
move forward and say look if we decide
that we can layer that in you know such
examples where we would be X for each
application for each in a shared
infrastructure a framework that we will
be saying here are the models here are
the frameworks that we would you know
like to work on and support we can make
again I will say we can make lot of
progress and there are things like that
already out there because if you look at
the G RPC oh you want a G rib does it
work for everyone no it worked for
someone but it's already out there you
can manipulate it giving you the API GT
you can get the photo buffs you can you
know change it model it but do we want
to adopt that or do we want to see and
make sure that it can work for a much
wider community and for much why the use
cases then for just a certain type of
use cases that that has been the
proposed and done and I would say you
know with all of this is rip 2i Torres
it should rest in peace it was a useful
exercise but the outcome of that wasn't
very useful the architecture wasn't
there
I liked ok here are the services that we
should focus on this is what you would
like to be able to manipulate let's find
what would be the right way to get them
you know at each correct layer the
actions that we will provide to the
users in different ways because I don't
want to address a protocol through a
controller I don't want to add another
layer of abstractions between it I would
like to be able to talk directly to the
protocol daemon you know get the actual
state from the protocol daemon compared
to the state on the
on the wire and no what is this
situation between and on my intended and
Maxwell's day if I going through
anything in between that I'm you know I
don't know how much information they
sent them from me what you know what I
can really actually what I can change
what I cannot change and simplifying
such actions would move us forward in
again achieving better program ability
of the overall network now do you want
to do some work like that I'm not sure
because we have some of our own you know
employer restrictions we have you know
some of our own ideas but I said it's a
thought experiments that each one of us
can do and I just want you to give you
some food for thought and say maybe we
can you know propose something else and
see if it can be useful or not
thank you Jeff as former ITRs chair so
rest in peace would be wonderful except
for this is not resting in peace this is
the undead coming back to haunt you I
don't want to you know like resurface
azam be that's fine so the the
presentation has a lot of excellent
points I Taurus in all no objective
criteria for what was supposed to have
accomplished failed we ended up with
models we ended up with no the vestiges
of a mechanism that supposedly used that
comp to actually do that work and people
are not deploying it so from that could
stand point it is a failure but over the
time that the working group existed and
that the models got worked on you know
we helped the net modern epitaph groups
changed the protocol changed their
mechanisms you know the current data
store model is largely influenced by the
ITRs work a lot of the Dynamis adeno
that we had in terms of things in
Metcalfe was pushed partially by hrs
back in the day a lot of the components
that we actually talked to the RHIB
model that we have an IETF got a big
upgrade because the hrs people were
looking at
you know the contents of things with
great scrutiny so there's a lot of
inputs that this failed experiment had
in terms of pushing on the rest the ietf
ecosystem to develop good stuff and to a
large extent about your components no
we're we're looking at to some extent
the result of the failure that was
projected which is if we don't actually
solve the problem in IETF we're going to
see is that vendors are going to you
know fork off and do their own things
and you know the most successful of
those obviously is the work from Google
for doji ribbing company and are the
problem is the work is not done here we
don't get a lot of no say in the matter
it's you know walking dead of SNMP
returned in many respects so we get all
the sins from that but people are
solving exactly the problem spaces we
knew were need to get to be solved and I
dress people are doing rip programming
some people are doing fib programming
with different models we're getting
telemetry via very various streaming
things and lots of different faces the
one success that we got out of a lot of
that is regardless of the transport
whether it's you know thrift whether
it's protobufs whether it's something
else a lot of people have actually gone
down the road that we sort of pushed
them to which is gang is the high level
modeling language this stuff gets done
in so that at the very least the models
can you interchange so with most of your
comments you know I agree I put back
this slide on because this is what they
see what was the value coming out of the
ITRs I still see there's you know a lot
of controller agent coming forward and I
would like to say let's try to remove
that put in proper software layering in
between it and decide whichever
framework we want to support on or
whichever one will be the juror at that
moment that can be easily you know
plugged on top of that so I tend to
agree I think those things are necessary
and I will leave the final comment with
prediction as long as we force this work
to touch net cough it shall fail the
groups and that the people that
participating that group do not have an
agenda that aligns with us
Robinson Cisco actually going back on
Jeff's point I think in terms of where
we got in net mod with Andy and MDA
architecture was we almost got to the
point of defining what you'd need for
ITRs and then we didn't do this the
small bit at the very end and so the
architecture talks about how you would
do a dynamic datastore but doesn't
define us have but actually defining one
and ideally saying how does the data
merge in with the existing one so I
still think that actually there's a
small step from that point of view to
enabling this functionality because the
data models have already been written
and whether that's the right thing to do
is a very different question I will
resist my comment on being an MVA
architecture I almost took the bait Dean
what's your personal position this
excuse me
you've kind of presented the facts
what's your position what do you think
well we have developed bunch of models
that people will not implement it
because they are too complex and too big
there are parts of the models that are
being implemented and are being used but
it's a very minor you know part of some
of the models that are being used and it
is the idea to instead of trying to
model everything under the Sun trying to
see what are the you know to come to
your common semantics and syntax for the
key functions and services and say
here's the model what framework we will
use for the you know to generate the API
so will it be net confined or will it be
G RPC or drift or anything coming down
the future we should be make sure that
what we built is flexible and open to
those new frameworks that it's easily
that is is that you can easily move it
one of the thing is that
I'm saying why can't they have a fit
model and the RHIB model understand how
the rib to fit translation has been done
on those models and just compare them
and know what is my actual state I you
know so there I have to know too many
rib too many rib models and then too
many fit models from all the different
vendors and then I can you know and have
the access to all of that in order to be
able to start doing things like that
which gives me a much better overview
and much faster ory what is actually
really on the wire versus you know what
some of the other groups are doing I'm
also a little bit worried that we are so
pushing forward and that a 20 year old
technology which was first proposed in
November 2002 so we are now coming to
the 70th anniversary of a saint Iran of
you know of a 10th year of technology is
becoming the main network management
technology and is it is not the
friendliest programming tool we have
moved forward and I would like to see us
being more flexible to those new tools
and new frameworks I've been saying a
long time the couple that come from yak
don't keep them connected
are there any actionable points of your
presentation you would like working
group to take is there anything you are
calling for are you just for your
information
so I'm just trying to finish something
with regards to work for the previous
presentation and for the dis
presentation I'm planning to write up a
draft you know set of requirements and
action items and release it know before
the next ITF meeting that would be great
and thank you for presentation we are
just in time thank you everyone and we
will see on Friday
and anyone who hasn't signed the blue
sheets please either come up here or go
to young gen holding them up on the left
from your point of view