uh Paul you keep trying to get you put
yourself on the queue I recognized you
and then you drop out
he's I don't know welcome it's going to
get into the jabber room
all right try it again you drop off as
quickly as you get recognized
it's up he's up all the reserve about it
yeah right
yeah restart your browser we are trying
to get Paul connected here you just
wanted to check that you could okay you
haven't said anything it'd be nice to
hear you well I'm going to give it one
minute and I'm going to get going I can
do that ministry via I really did think
I was going to have more people sorry
we've got a lot of people on remote
which is good so this is uh the rum
meeting note well yeah all right so this
is rum well there's the agenda really
just talking about the one draft and
where we are in the open issues does
anyone want to bash the agenda anything
you want to change if you're
participating remotely by all means ask
to speak and we'll recognize you on
including bashing the agenda you're
certainly welcome to do that if you have
any suggestions
yes we have someone in the jabber room
if you just want to have someone come up
to the mic you can type it into the
jabber and and we have someone who will
do that it's because you're so quiet and
reserved yes all right
so if there's no agenda bashing to do
I'm gonna switch to get back to data
tracker there's this and the slides this
alright so you know audit work yeah yeah
yeah yeah all right
so the first thing I want to talk about
is the discussions we've been having on
the list having to do with media the
current state of the document is that
g.711 and opus are mandatory to
implement there has been the discussion
of what what does it mean if your gate
wing from the PSTN and I think that
we're we've agreed that that's you don't
have to offer opus if your gate wing
from the PSTN that's the silly thing to
do there's no requirement to be silly
and we can I don't we'll make sure that
the text is clear on that subject I did
try to do that on the current version is
is there anything that people think that
they want to see in the audio section
that is not there or if we solve this
one issue having to do with yes you have
to implement it but you don't have to
use it in every call is there anything
else that people want to have modified
in the audio and again if you want to
speak on me taco go ahead or put
something in the in the jabber room any
any way that you want to feedback if
you're operating remotely that that
would be just fine
there's anything that people have on
audio that we have not covered I'm
hearing nothing and I'm not too
surprised Richard shields Richard go
ahead okay can you hear me okay yeah
it's not terrific but it's it's it's
understandable go ahead okay oh so what
I did post something on the email list
about supporting devices that are older
than then maybe opus would be able to
run on given that we're already pushing
the limits on some of these devices I
don't remember who some Oh someone
posted back saying that that we don't
plant them I guess using these ancient
devices here's here's my concern
my concern is as a VRS provider the FCC
will give us direction based on you know
input from RFC's and so forth if if they
simply say we must comply with this RFC
without any caveats about our older
devices that we do not support anymore I
mean we don't push new firmware to them
that best concern so I I I think from
our providers perspective this really
should be us should if there's any way
to word it in that way because should
you might with my understanding is that
it's essentially a must unless there's a
good technical reason why we can't
implement it and there might be cases
like that for some of our older devices
this is Brian I there are a couple
things that
we need to say one of which is that that
there isn't any way to control the ITF
has no control over but the FCC does but
we have to do things that we think are
the technically best solution that we
have in a new document and if you're
trying to make the assumption that you
can upgrade and a very old device to new
firmware software and meet the the
the Roo spec I'm not sure that I think
that that's reasonable or possible in
most cases but and and and so on I I
understand the issue I I personally just
speaking as just as an individual at
this point would think that that you
really do want to implement opus and
mandatory to implement so that you can
achieve high bandwidth connections in
everything other than a PSTN
circumstance and my experience with
implementing opus which I mean haven't
done the nuts and bolts but I've had
many people implemented in in in devices
that I've been associated with and
generally they record this got very low
overhead I mean it's really easy very
very small code space very low compute
requirements and III doubt that that's
really going to be the reason you can't
run Roo on a on an older device Adam
Adam Roche as an individual Richard do
you have some notion of what the CPUs
are in the devices you're talking about
why that's that's a really good question
III I don't I know we have some like
older mobile devices customers use and
[Music]
yeah those might be the ones that are of
concern okay if you have some way of
finding out what those run on and like
sending that to the mailing list I work
with some of the folks that did the Opus
development work and
happy to poke them to find out what they
think is is fusible on those okay thank
you
yeah dumplings I'm just sort of again
sort of questioning if you're not
pushing firmware updates to these things
how is they going to run Roux at all
right I have to do I mean old soft no
old systems that aren't updated aren't
updated by definition so yeah III I
think I understand your points but if
but if the FCC simply says we must
comply with this RFC you know going by
the letter of the law than we would have
to update anything that does not meet
that specification yeah yeah so just
from my own you know following the list
I think generally I can arm m3 which is
sort of the very like embedded ARM chips
are able to run opus with only a little
bit of tuning because I understand it so
yeah they running video as well if
you're running video so if you have to
run video
I mean it is if you're running video
either you're a dedicated video hardware
in which case it doesn't matter or the
opus is trivial compared to the video
yeah yeah I mean making we're this is
Brian and I I I do think that we're in
we're the the load that opus places on a
cpu is very small compared to what video
does and unless you're running at 99%
CPU utilization and 1% will take you
over and I can imagine that you could be
in a circumstance like that but it's you
know I hope you aren't but but I think
the the real problem is that getting a
document through the ITF requires that
we do you know put our best current
practice in an opus is clearly our best
current practice and you know we can
make accommodations for backwards
compatibility that's always a possible
thing to do but in terms of meeting the
requirement
so the device meeting the requirements
of us of a new specification that it
would be very hard to get it through the
a document through without without
requiring what we think is best current
practice all right thank you thank you
appreciate it is there anything else
about yeah anything else about audio
that people want to want to bring up I
will work with anybody who wants to make
sure that the text on gate wing the PSTN
is clear enough if there's anybody that
that wants to make suggestions on
wording on that please send them to the
list and I'm happy to to to work on that
because I do want that to be very clear
Paul there you go
no audio see your video don't hear your
audio nope no audio at all
yeah Paul I'm gonna let James Hamelin I
have the floor and you can work on your
audio and try try bringing me back James
your yeah yes I just to come back to
Richard was saying I think our problem
is that the there are two sides to the
rum interface there's the iue itself and
this the provider side and the way the
documents phrased I think the provider
side represents essentially the
interface to the PSTN and a whole load
of legacy things which are not are you
ease some of which as we said may not be
possible to upgrade and so it's not just
the PSTN that is the only place where
you have legacy and and that's what I
think needs to be made clear in the
wording okay yeah yes I I'm gonna this
is Ryan out I'm going to read back to
you what I heard out of that and I
certainly if if if I'm interpreting it
correctly I agree with you you're saying
that that in addition to gate weighing a
call from the PSTN you may be connecting
to a device which is not route compliant
and you want to be able to establish a a
a communication with room on audio path
and the only thing offered by that
legacy device is g.711 and you want to
make sure that that the ROO spec clearly
allows talking to a device that doesn't
support rum it doesn't support opus and
and I think everybody agrees with you
that that if you're calling a device
which is not Roo compatible but is
otherwise able to create a video session
and an audio session using g.711 that
that that that should be fully supported
by a device
conforming to the document and if again
if the wording is not clear on that
point I'm very happy to work with you to
make sure that it is very clear on that
point all right Adam Oh again again as
an individual and so sounds like
basically wanted to say instead of PSTN
just like any legacy yes certainly I
think that's very appropriate we should
do that okay thanks
yeah all right I'm gonna try Paul again
Paul nope dropped off yep all right
if there's nothing else on audio I'm
gonna go to video and a reminder that we
did agree that h.264 is the only
mandatory to implement codec and the
question I have for the room is is there
anything other than what WebRTC says
about h.264 that we need in the document
it if you go read the specs there are a
number of things that it says that you
have to implement in order to maintain
streams and you know restarts and all
that frame framing all that kind of
stuff but is there anything else that we
need to say in addition to what's in the
WebRTC that that will get us what we
want and again I'm thinking mostly about
the backwards compatibility part if
there are pieces that we want to require
in addition to what WebRTC requires in
order to get better backwards
compatibility I'm happy to put that kind
of thing in so if anyone has any
suggestions on on what might need to be
added to the current text beyond what
the WebRTC specs say about video again
I'm real happy to put that in no one
apparently has anything to say again if
you if you think of something oh okay
Isaac
go ahead Isaac hi can you hear me okay
yes you're fine awesome great thank you
um one issue we do have with providers
and I'm not sure what WebRTC says about
this but we need we do require mode one
because there are a lot of there are a
lot of devices they can't encode our
there are some older devices and codecs
that weren't able to do mode one and so
they would end up sending really large
packets that ended up getting fragmented
so we did require endpoints abort mode
one for packetization for h.264 I don't
know what where RT C says on that but
that might be something we need to
include to ensure interoperability
across many devices Adam Adam Rochester
the the WebRTC video specification
indicates that factorisation mode one
must be supported and other modes may be
dikko ciated and used by actually didn't
understand upon your making enough to
know whether that's a problem for you
that yeah I think you're alright
yeah if mode 1 is required then I think
we should be okay so great we can be
great um I certainly would encourage
anybody to who's listening or you know
and any of the providers or anybody else
interested to to go back and look to see
what's in the WebRTC spec and think
about what you think you need to have
I'm not opposed to adding some more
requirements if that'll get us more
backwards compatibility we've had really
good good success in getting
interoperability with WebRTC but that's
WebRTC to WebRTC and and and I
understand the limitations that you know
saying oh yeah well Weber C's work
really great yeah not good enough
so if you wouldn't mind taking a look at
the details here and making sure that
the things we need are there I
appreciate it and
again send send that to the list and
I'll make sure it gets into the next
version is there anything else on on
video anybody wants to talk about all
right the next media I have is text and
following our prior discussions the only
thing that's required is RFC 4103 which
is RTP transport you'll require recall
we had the discussion of whether we're
going to require the data channel from
WebRTC and decided not to so this makes
it compatible with any other device that
does real-time text with sip and I don't
think there is anything that needs to be
done there but if there is anything that
people want to bring out happy to talk
about that now but I think we're okay
that in the in the text side any any
comments on text all right so the the
next subject I want to get into somewhat
relates to the discussion that we had
earlier about how the document currently
treats providers and and and Andrew
devices and the text does in fact have
things like the room us do this
providers may do that
etc and I'd like to propose that as an
IT after app that that really doesn't
have a lot of relevance to the kind of
documents that we typically create we're
defining a protocol or really were
profiling an interface and I'd like to
see if their support for getting rid of
that wording and just talk about the
interface as as what's required across
the interface and and that that you know
speaking to our VRS provider u.s. VRS
provider folks that means the FCC may
not get exactly what it wants out of
that because it doesn't doesn't put a
requirement on you that you do anything
particular it just says across the
interface this must be supported and
and that that would make it more like an
ITF document the current document is a
little strange for a long time ITF
participant and and it if people like
what's there I'm all right leaving it
but I'd like to move it to a just having
a specification of the interface and not
of which side does what any any comments
on that I hear no one if there isn't an
objection I'm going that the next
version will will say we'll do that I
will at least to take a crack at it you
can always back out if we're don't don't
want to go forward but that's that's
what I like to do James
just an observation and I guess a
question
surely this kind of situation must come
up quite a bit for example in pure
client-server interfaces where there's
definitely one side which is different
from the other and I think for the
reasons we've said though there is a
difference between the two sides in this
interface in the sense that we're
standardizing it a new interface to what
is a range of systems some of which
contain legacy elements so there is an
inherent asymmetry and what we're trying
to do
is it really that unusual to have to
address that kind of situation well you
you most certainly have two sides of an
interface and you know you might have
clients and servers and the server's may
have different requirements the clients
that that that's certainly not all that
unusual but usually what you say is that
that it mean but but we don't have a
circumstance like that here we're really
talking about a device interfacing
towards a service it's the service you
know the what in the the PSTN we call
the Uni interface right it's the user to
network interface and what happens in
the network or what happens to some
other device that's connected to the
network or anything like that is is
outside of the range of the
specification the specification only
talks about what does it look like on
the wire between the end device and the
the the network in this case the
providers network but but it but that's
what it looks like
it's only there and that that means that
you don't have to well that we're not
saying what happens inside the provider
network we're only saying what happens
on the connection between the user
device and the network does that make
sense to you and is that helpful in in
in in in getting work where I'm
proposing you go
I think so
my first instinct is to think that
because there is some asymmetry that the
language will be will be simpler if it
makes the kinds of distinctions that it
has but I think if the structure of the
language has changed what will care
about is is the meaning in the end so
this will come down to what which way
explains things most succinctly I think
yeah and and III as as editor I won't
mind having a reset if if we try
something and we don't like it and we
want to go back to where it was
I'll keep the source text around and I
can always undo text let's see I got
several people in the queue so let me
move on to call let's do C does it work
this time and you hear me yes ah
Rome works better than Firefox today in
in in the VRS provider specs I mean we
have a more complex architecture yeah I
mean it's not just devices talking to
similar devices or something like that
you know we have roles for these things
so you know the provider has a rural
separate you know and the point-to-point
call between two crews you know is
topologically different and so I I think
that's the perspective from which you
know there's a symmetry in you know and
so if you just make a point-to-point
call then it's really ruined there's
it's all fine but if the roux is calling
and it ends up at a provider it may be
talking to it you know an IVR kind of
device for a while and maybe talking to
a to a conference or the conference's in
the interpreter
and you know it's technically Elise says
things currently stand there is no
requirement that the devices that
interpreters that work on the arrests
use meet the ruse back yeah and maybe
maybe that'll change too but so to me I
could see a utility in an asymmetry but
I think to deal with it I think we would
have to introduce some more terminology
and stuff like that in the document that
to define what the rules are on top of
that I mean as far as the the earlier
consideration I mean there's a lot of
concerns for the providers that
ultimately come down to what the FCC is
going to do and I realized that the FCC
is kind of like out of scope for us sort
of but I think we have to yeah the
situation is different if if the FCC is
going to issue a regulation that refer
you know that for which the respect is
one part and there's you know like other
parts for backward compatibility or
something like that then it is if the
expectation is that the FCC is just
gonna say you know everybody's got to
support this and it's not clear to me
how we sort that out but I think it
would it would help the providers if
they knew what was going to happen and
because it makes a big difference in how
we write this stuff yeah I I don't know
how we go about getting a clarification
there if we can well we can
on that there are a couple other people
in the queue so I'm gonna move on good
Isaac well Isaac dropped out all right
Richard
we'll get Richard oh great um so back
kinda what James is saying about the the
must for ruined me for providers for one
thing of course let's go through the
document with an eye with that in mind
and understand trying to see how that
was well play out I I did briefly just
run through the document looking for
muss and May and one one jumped out at
me and I'm wondering how oh you would
deal with this with your your your
current approach and it's it's a
paragraph in section five it's in
addition the room must and providers may
conform to an ELISA series series of RCS
like for example one of them is ice and
as far as I know I think Sorenson is the
only provider that uses ice today so how
would you go about rewriting that would
you say that the room us and just drop
the providers may now uh well I I
wouldn't what I would say is that that
ice is mandatory to implement for a
route compatible device and if it sends
ice candidates out it may or may not get
responses depending on who what it's
trying to connect to and so I across the
interface ices support it but as with
any other mean you picked on ice which
is something we know a fair amount about
and you know if if the other end doesn't
know anything about ice then you're not
going to get any candidates back and if
it does you will so rue de rue is going
to work and route it back to two old
vice may not
and you know something in the middle can
screw stuff up and the devices have to
cope with that but that's the way ice is
built anyways so I I think you're
probably okay but I think but you know I
think your your your intuition of look
well let's go look at the cases where
they're asymmetric and decide whether
there's a problem is probably the right
one and when we'll do that and I found
another one which is in 5-3 and it so it
that one is Roo must and providers
should support info requests well you
know again the same thing across the
interface you should allow the info
request and and whether it comes up that
is whether it's ever sent is is is is an
issue but if you get it you should
handle it
and I I think that that's that that's
where the that's more of a the example
that I had where I don't think that we
should have an asymmetry in the sense of
across the interface an info should be
supported okay so so in that example I
gave the simply just be reworded as in
addition the room must and and not
mention providers at all correct okay
that's exactly correct all right thank
you
anyone else
so what I'm getting out of this is that
there's some concern that that might be
problematic but there's no there there
there isn't really an objection as long
as the reality comes out all right and
as the editor I'm I'm making a proposal
that I'm willing to back out if it
doesn't work out so it'll be on me to
back it out if it doesn't work but I'm
gonna do that I'm gonna put out a
version that that that that doesn't use
the word provider in a in in on the
interface side I mean it's not got rid
of all cases of provider because just
what's on the other side but I'm gonna
I'm gonna try and get rid of the this
asymmetry thing I mean I kind of feel
like if this isn't actually making
narrative changes to what it actually is
done that's a provocative yeah yeah okay
yeah it doesn't alright anything else on
that subject when we started the work
and I brought in the original draft
which was based on work that mitre had
done on that the FCC's behest there were
a couple of things that were flagged as
maybe they would survive in the ITF
draftin maybe they wouldn't and I'd like
to start the discussion of what survives
and what doesn't the two things that I
know about that are worth talking about
are the provisioning mechanism and the
contacts mechanisms provisioning
currently in the draft there is a
provisioning mechanism which works by
discovering and downloading a JSON
object that provisions the device
there's a known issue with that having
to do with usernames and passwords which
we would have to come up with an
alternative for the the question I have
for the room and the people on the call
is our is this do we want to keep it I
personally would like to keep it
think it's useful I think it's very
helpful to be able to provision a device
with a file instead of having to do it
manually
and so and I think the mechanism and
that's there which is downloaded JSON
divide the file is pretty reasonable
mechanism there was discussions of using
other mechanisms that the ITF is defined
but I think this is probably what people
would first see so other than how we
handle user name and password are we
keeping it is it alright to keep it or
or is it something that we we're you
think we'll have enough trouble coming
to agreement on um I'd like to leave it
so this is we discussed whether this
happens I'm asking the question now I
personally would like to keep it as it
is pretty much fixing the username and
password we can deal with the details
right if there's Mecca if there are some
aspects of the file or the you know the
provisioning the things that it does
happy to deal with any of the details
it's just that I'm asking the the
top-level question of does the mechanism
itself stay in the document
any comments on that the default is
leave it it's already there and I think
it's fine do people have a preference
for how to handle the username and
password I will propose some mechanism
I'll figure out what I'm gonna propose
but it'll be something that most modern
substrates can handle reasonably right
it'll encode it'll be encoded in some
way right as a file of some kind and and
that'll it'll it'll be something that's
standardized I mean I'm just going to
use an existing standard not a no I'm
not gonna make anything up Isaac yeah
I'm not sure exactly what you're
referring to can you in we can you be
specific about what section that's in
yes sure
young-kyu so what I'm talking about is
section 9 provisioning and provider
selection and if you go through that
you'll see there are really two one for
the provider selection and the other for
the provisioning piece there are two
JSON objects defined that provide all of
the data for choosing among multiple
providers and provisioning for a given
provider that but that's the part I'm
talking about section 9
go ahead Isaac some that it just says so
a configurable URL so that implies that
there's some type of service and
therefore a provider that would then be
providing this JSON with all of the
providers information in it or is this a
provider by provider you are
it it's it's it is provider by provider
and it's you you you provision each of
the providers you are eyes and you
retrieve from that provider the JSON
object okay so from so there's there
must be some global thing then that says
here's all the provider URLs that you
can go to to get the configuration
password etc for that provider then yeah
the current document doesn't describe
how that works it just says you
provision it with one or more you are
eyes I'm happy to change that but wait
I'm not I'm not in love with that
mechanism I just that's just what's
there now yeah I'm just trying to
understand who where that's coming from
so you're thinking that could just be
something that's part of the rule and if
it needs the URL needs to get added
there would need to be a new version of
it that would have that in it like it
say for example a new provider comes
online or a writer goes offline how does
that get handled and then the other kind
of follow-up question to that is I'm not
even sure how that works for the hearing
calls side right so let's say I'm you
know I'm a Sorenson user I use the ROO
but then I say oh I want to I want to
use purple right now and so I get the
purple configuration URL it gives me
everything I need to register with with
purple or Z how then does my hearing
call get routed like that's still going
to come to the provider that owns the
number so it's hard to even understand
how that works outside of just a test
case kind of like what mitre is doing
now would be a TRP just using it to test
interoperability so the
the way it's currently described it's
not clear and I and then I think that's
a fault of the document and we'll have
to fix it whether whether a device is
allowed to are required to support more
than one registration at a given time
but ignoring that little detail where it
doesn't say the the the way it's
described you have entirely separate
accounts with entirely separate
telephone numbers so the idea is that I
would know that I would be switching
phone numbers at the same time if you if
you have another selection zvrs purple
number and then I have my Sorenson
number yes which back and forth so
you're really not trying to do like a
one-stage dial around no like that not
that's not what this describes this
describes the ability to have more than
one account each of which has its own
telephone number what it doesn't say is
whether you can have more than one
active or not and that might just be an
implementation question yes so I can
reread the document but it might be good
I think it would be good to clarify that
no problem and and and please send I I
agree we want to clarify that part so if
you wouldn't you know if you wouldn't
mind reading it and strengths them some
text suggestions I'd appreciate it but
I'll take a look at it and try and prove
it
because I I agree that it's not very
clear just sort of launches into the
mechanism without a discussion of how
it's supposed to be used okay thank you
Paul I'm just trying to dredge up
memories from like three years ago of
what the original thinking and this
stuff was and my recollection is that
yes there was imagine some sort of
service that made this advertisement of
what all the different providers were
that you might choose among that that
you had the
in order to go through that step and
pick which provider he wanted to
provision with and I think the other
thing we're we're dancing around here is
dial around in the sense of there was a
distinction between yeah you yeah at
least in principle the Rue yeah a
sufficiently capable rue implementation
might allow you to have registrations
with multiple providers each with its
own phone number but in addition it
would have you know a mechanism to to do
what's called one stage dialer round
which would you know allow you to just
click a button to say which provider you
wanted to place a particular call
through when you're Flint placing
outgoing calls and then then your call
would be outbound which I think would
address part of what was previously
being asked about yeah yes I'm sorry say
apologist interrupting you a little bit
section five to two independent of the
section nine that we were talking about
discusses one one stage style round
so so the document does what you were
recollected it it was gonna do yeah the
other thing I think is if we're if we're
trying to have this deal with hearing
users that that have video support then
I think there would there would have to
be a mechanism for them to get their get
their route like device configured so II
either the existing providers would
somehow have to be able to support
hearing users with with with with route
of Isis which is it currently within
their mandate or else there would have
to be some other pseudo pseudo provider
that provided that service like what
mitre sort of does but I think you know
between those things I
you cover all the possibilities but like
I say the original imagined mechanism
was that when you turned on a brand new
route or something like that
it would it would know where to go to
fit to fetch this list of providers and
then it would bill such that and then
basically provide you some sort of
configuration mechanism that picks what
people want the one you want and then it
would go through the the provisioning
mechanism with that one mm-hmm and then
and then you'd be set okay
the the text does seem to follow what
you just said so we'll we'll work on
yeah I got Isaac behind you and he may
have more information
sorry I cut you off and I didn't mean to
I think you have the floor yeah I just
wanted to clarify that it has nothing to
do with a hearing user using video or a
roué client or anything like that it's
just when a hearing person places a call
to a deaf number that that call gets
routed to the provider that owns that
number yeah
there's no way I just don't see a
reasonable way that you would have a
hearing call going to one provider and
then somehow routed to another provider
so this idea of one stage dial around
where the user just picks which provider
they want to use there might be some
ways to make that work for an outbound
call but it just it's not bi-directional
and doesn't really seem feasible given
that so I just wanted to add that
clarification for Paul thank you yeah I
agree with you Isaac your your that's
what I think all right I what I'm
hearing is leave it as it is but make
the text clearer about how this
mechanism is supposed to work which I
will do I will do and if anybody has to
text suggestions send them to the lists
and I'll try and incorporate them in the
next version but
I'm hearing leave leave the mechanism do
a better job of explaining how it works
any other discussion on that okay then
the next one is contacts so the current
document has two mechanisms for context
there's an upload and download of a file
of J cards and then there's real-time
sink using CalDAV not called F I wrote
the wrong thing carddav sorry that's
carddav not called AB it's not calendars
its context and I the the floor is open
for people's opinions of what to do the
you know that we currently the upload
download mechanism is supported by most
providers and carddav isn't what what
shall we do with this Isaac yeah I just
want to mention that you know really the
issue with carddav is that it's fairly
limited and compared to what you know
some of the things we do with our
current contacts especially for deaf
users where we implement things like
visual caller ID
whether that's color or patterns there
are just there are a lot of things we do
sherry and sharing contacts across users
and groups I mean the card card dab is
just pretty limited in comparison like
it might might be okay for somebody to
go or some third party whether it's
might or somebody else you know there's
no reason they couldn't host their own
carddav server and then ruo or be a TRP
could use that it's just hard to see how
it makes sense
is indicate that that would be something
that the providers and this goes back to
your must versus main language right you
said well you just want this to describe
the interface but if it says the
interface is carddav and then later the
FCC comes along and says well providers
must be compliant with the Rome profile
or whatever it's called now then it
effectively becomes a must and requires
us to do something that's just not a
good doesn't provide a good user
experience are these are these
limitations of card def per se or of K
card / v card I mean my understanding of
card AB is that it's just a vCard server
so I'm assuming the same limitations
apply okay I mean I mean like there's
bird defined you know there's no
standard for visual color ID or patterns
colors etc I mean there's only to be
exceptions to the card / J card right
yeah that's I think your your your point
Jonathan is is that it is it's not the
mechanism but the data that that the
mechanism is transporting yeah unless
you mentioned like the ability to share
share you know yeah but even then the
mechanism allows you to do that it's
just what the how does the server we
know what cards does the server send you
and and as you say that the J card
format as with the X card format as with
the original vCard format is extensible
so adding extensions for things like a
visual representation of the user in
some way is is certainly straightforward
and and yeah I mean you know the
counter-argument for for for saying well
you know providers do that all is do
some providers do some things you know
it's it's yes but that makes a device
proprietary unless it's using some kind
of stand
that multiple multiple ends can can
implement I Paul is waiting in queue let
me we move to hat Paul go ahead I just
wanted to get more clarification on the
question I guess
my understanding is right which might be
wrong right is that right now the
devices the providers use the the
contact list functionality is hosted on
the servers on the on the providers
servers and and the device has some sort
of interface to it
I'm not clear I'm how you're imagining
that working with the Roose Beck would
it mean that would it fit within the
functionality of the ruler would would
the thing that's a rule also have to
have extra functionality in order to
interface with your contact list
especially since you know you don't have
a call when you're trying to use the
contact list to establish a call and you
know if it requires some extra
functionality than that that like blows
the whole idea of the you know a
portable rule that works across multiple
providers and let unless that mechanism
is standardized so the way it works now
as you and implied the the whole contact
list is is is is internal to the
provider and so the way the way you move
contacts from one provider to another is
you request your old provider to send
you a file of your contacts and then you
send that file to your new provider and
he uploads it into his service so the
the what the ROO spec makes that a
little bit better right it just it says
that you do they upload and download
with the ROO you don't have to have it
go from
you to your provider to you know and
then he sends you an email with with a
with a file and then you email that list
here to your new provider at least gets
rid of that part but doesn't do much
more than that
right it's just slightly better than
where we are now the there there it as
there are some equivalents as Adam said
there's some equivalents that some
providers have for handling contacts
among the multiple devices supported by
the same provider so if you know you
have a mobile device and you have a a
fixed device some providers do have
services that allow you sync your
contacts between those that's done again
within the service and and the the card
AB thing would would would give you as
Adam said a subset of what some
providers do you referring to Isaac
Nauta eyes away yes Isaac um I I agree
with what you said pretty much but I
think there's to me there's a little
unclarity still whether we're really
talking about the contact list or if
we're talking about you know as a as a
as a piece of data or or if we're
talking about you know that contact list
feature that the end user uses to search
his contacts and pick somebody and use
one of them to make a call and it makes
a difference because I think implicit in
this although it doesn't say it anywhere
because we don't talk about the user
interface is that with the respect is
that this past this contact list
mechanism is just a way to get the list
of contacts into the root with the
expectation that the ROO somehow or
other you know provides its own user
interface to that contact list for the
user to use for making calls and that
that
mechanism then mean the boundary between
the proprietary part and the non
proprietary part is this transfer
mechanism whether it's whether it's you
know carddav or whether it's you know
upload/download of the list of contacts
you know and but that's that's different
from a from a mechanism that assumes
that there's like maybe a contact list
application on the device that talks to
some server mechanism on the provider
that that provides you know like a web
interface or something to to the
provider she you know that that offers
the the contact list mechanism to the
user my principle here I mean I think
normally an end user nowadays I mean of
course the you know they only transfer a
contact list if they decide to use a
different provider you know so it's
something you do you know like once a
year or something yeah and and so I
think at least what we discussed it
before the mechanism that you used to
you know to transfer you yes you could
requested you know a you know a transfer
of the list but it wasn't real time it
might take weeks to go or you know hours
or something to get it and it was kind
of like a manual process at the provider
and or at least maybe not up a little
bit the you know the download each other
ways which here I mean it certainly is
imagine this is a real time function and
that you know in principle it's just an
optimization you know that if the if
every time you turn your your room on
and it connected to the provider
it might just load the contact list from
the provider and then use it and you can
use card out this to sync it which
probably it's more efficient or it can
dis transfer the whole thing which might
depending how big your list is might
take longer or might not but at the end
of the day once it was into your device
you know all the mechanism for using it
in your device would be local to the
device wouldn't wouldn't depend on an
interface to the provider okay and we
got other people in the queue Paul
you've had okay okay Adam I think you
were next Thanks so I think Paul
actually has a good point but I believe
we can get away sorry Adam Roach
speaking as an individual I think we can
probably get away with just defining the
interface here without having to get
into how the device uses I think like
all the modes of operation Paul
mentioned would be perfectly valid but
what I got up here was actually I wanted
to probe a little bit at what Isaac was
saying around the capabilities of B card
and J card given their extensible
formats and the two examples that he
that I heard him give all this at least
were visual caller ID which I presume is
a picture based approach we like have
contact pictures and then colors which I
presume is categories and both of those
are actually supported by the current
vCard format so I'd be curious if we
could collect what the current
capabilities are used by these systems
and see whether there exists a good
mapping and it might even be worth kind
of doing that analysis in the document
pointing out where things might not be
obvious yeah but I I would be really
surprised to the capabilities given that
it's extensible and I'm looking at the
innn and registry right now and it's
like more than a full page on my browser
of fields and it and put in these things
I would be really surprised if they
weren't covered in some way or another
yeah Isaac
[Music]
yeah I just wanted a couple couple of
things I want to call out you know when
I think of like my iPhone and my Android
phone you know that that's pretty much
what I have to do right I have to export
my contacts from one phone and use use
some service or or some other utility to
import on my other phone I don't really
expect like iCloud and I suspect Apple's
iCloud to work with my Google phone or
my Google contacts to work with my
iPhone so seems pretty equivalent and
standard in the industry to have to
export to a file and import it on
another device on the on the caller ID
the visual caller ID is more than a
picture which is pretty typical and
standard for us it's actually a pattern
of lights and it's something that we do
I don't I I don't think that other
providers do it exactly the same and I
think we and we do actually have a
patent on that so the problem is is that
there aren't really any standards
defined across providers for how some of
those things are done so you kind of end
up with kind of a lowest common
denominator of functionality across
contacts which just doesn't seem ideal
and then I kinda think I agree with what
Paul was saying where it's it seems odd
to say that the provider has to then
provide this type of card day of service
or it's really I think that's up to
whoever the room provider is if they
want to do their own carddav service as
a way to manage contacts across devices
devices that's great but it doesn't
necessarily make sense to say for the
provider that the providers would need
to do that Thanks so I've been I've been
listening to all this and and I think
there's there are a couple things that
occur to me and one is to reinforce the
notion of the difference between the
transport and the data format we're
talking about
a j-card which is extensible and already
has a large list of attributes and then
we're talking about the transport
mechanism for that which is a file of J
cards or a sink of J cards and it does
seem to me that even if you had a set of
features that is you had a set of user
characteristics that were associated
with a contact that was proprietary you
could just use the extension mechanisms
to carry that and you may not that data
may not go to another provider but they
don't have any way of dealing with
anyways because it's a proprietary
mechanism which is fine as long as you
implement the standard stuff it's a
question of whether or not it's a good
idea for the device to have the ability
to manage contacts within itself and
have the ability to obtain contacts from
some service not specified who runs the
service it just says the device that
across the interface a file transfer of
J cards and the carddav interface is
support it and it seems to me that
though both of those are good things to
do it doesn't prohibit you from
extending it it doesn't prohibit you
from saying I don't supply the service
all I do is support the interface across
it so the URI that you provision which
is your card dam server doesn't point to
you points to something else that's all
fine but I think that the that that I
think personally think that it's a good
thing for the ROO to have to support but
both the the upload/download and the and
the sync mechanisms and one more thing
and then then I'll let Adam talk I
actually don't upload and download
contacts anymore or haven't had to do
that in a very long time sync across
services works quite well across almost
every service that I use because they
all use the same standards now so that's
just my experience
Adam Roach you actually covered almost
everything that I've got up here to say
but I want to go ahead and put a fine
point on three specific items the first
is that the J card and and B card format
specifically has ways to register
vendors specific extensions for things
like proprietary features the second is
this the sync text journal like my phone
right now my address book is
predominantly stored on Yahoo because
they have an address book server that I
can use card out with and that thanks to
my other non apple devices with no
problems which is a really good
real-life example of exactly what you're
talking about the third thing was
related to the third thing you said and
I can't remember what it was but it I
pretty much agree with everything that
you just said okay Todd like the one
other thing I've had is if there are
specific contact things that are you
know surly useful for deaf and
hard-of-hearing users that should be
standardized then we should saturd ice
them I mean not oh yeah not as a cup of
this working group but you know take
them to whatever group does card dev and
say hey hey here are some things that
are specifically for deaf and
hard-of-hearing users what's a turd
Iceland yeah if they're not if there is
there's not or something or even if
there are patents you know dude IPR
declaration oh yeah sure sure sure if if
we if the text is clarified to make sure
that it's not an implied that the URI
that's the card dev server or the file
upload download is not specified at who
operates it is there an objection to
leaving the mechanisms as they currently
are defined again
happy to work on wording to make sure
that it's it's clear that that it's not
implying that any particular operator is
running any particular service it's it's
just that the interface itself supports
both a file transfer and um it's you
know it's it's web retrieval right it's
downloaded Jason a large JSON objects
not really a file I see Paul and Isaac
Isaac I was gonna say that this seems
like it could work we would just need to
see that text yeah
see what that looks like before yeah so
thank you right great well we'll
definitely do that Paul I just want to
comment on this that it at least the way
I use this stuff I mean yeah you know my
phone you know I can sync to multiple
places and I mean I can see here the
this configuration is a way to provide a
place to sync to that's it's links to
the provider somehow whether they
implement it or do it by referral but
but like Adam suggested it may be that
the user wants to have his own and so
I'm not sure how it fits into the thing
but I think there ought to be a
mechanism for the fruit for the user to
provide a place to sync to independent
what the provider provides I think
that's an excellent idea and and we
definitely should do that that currently
it's it is part of the the provisioning
but I think that that ought to be
separately provisional because if you
like your contacts coming from Google
instead of your provider then you should
be fully entitled to do exactly that so
that's that's definitely thing to do for
sure
any anything else on on the subject of
contacts
okay so now is the big question of what
do we don't you know what what else is
there if you know we're not ready to
call for last call on the document I
mean we're not and I'm not talking about
that but I would like to know what other
areas of the document people think need
neat work what what where where are
there things that it currently don't
currently believe it is in the state
that it needs to be in and I'll you know
I I know I've kind of sprung this
question so I'm I'm not really asking I
mean if people know things by all means
come to the mic and let's have them now
but this is more of a plea to go back
through the document and bring up areas
that you think need to be discussed that
you don't think are ready to go that can
be small stuff or big stuff but I am you
know we started out with a pretty good
draft we brought a whole bunch of issues
up and we're working on those issues I'd
like to know what other issues people
think they are they that exist in the
document so that we can start thinking
through what what we want to say so
that's as I say it's it's more of a plea
to read the document and send comments
the list of what areas you think need
more work then coming to the mic today
and tell me what what's bad I'll list
them I'm apologize for being late them
possibly mr. discussion I'd rather draft
this morning and I found a number of
occurrences with of the term with the
understanding that and then the protocol
violation and I would like to have the
well the behavior that was intended
spelled out rather than having the
understanding that okay for instance
there was a and there was mentioned that
we don't use media stream tracks and but
it doesn't say what do you mean by that
so that if you instead put them with a
but we are not going to send the MS IDs
and we are going to ignore them on
reception that's fine
I mean if you want to bake the standard
say exactly exactly how you should
behave when you break this knowledge
okay I will take that under advisement
and go look at all those instances in
and try and come up with good worried
you know I may contact you for
suggestions but thank you I yeah that
with the understanding that is usually
not good standards language and I wrote
that so I should you know I shouldn't
have said that
when it comes you'd be done with that
topic yes yes the one thing that comes
to my mind was still this question
that's that we had a discussion for a
while and then we dropped it a couple of
times I think this thing about having
client certificates in order to verify
that the device has been certified by
somebody that's still hanging isn't it I
that very there is no text currently
there there there is provisioning of a
certificate for the purposes of doing
mutual loss which we could drop if
people don't want it but that there
isn't anything the the piece that's
still there is the call info header that
tries to tell you who where this thing
came from yeah I I didn't think that's
what you were talking about here you
were talking about client authentication
there was a yeah I know you had it in
there and it was unclear to people what
it was about I thought I cleared that up
well we answer discussion on the list
yeah I believed what I remembered it had
originally been put in for which I got
confirmation from some other people was
true but which
didn't come through in the spec yeah and
it's uh it was it was intended as a
mechanism by which the vent
manufacturers of devices could get them
certified and then they would get us
assert that they used to prove that
their device had been certified that the
providers could use to screen out
uncertified devices from that you know
disallow them from being connected and
frankly I never believed that mechanism
as written worked and yet III the
providers have a desire for something
like that I don't know a mechanism that
would work I mean obviously we have
things you know like phones you know
that they have certificates you know you
know like Google store and stuff like
that that certify apps that you can load
into your device but the mechanisms for
those don't work in this circumstance
and so I was kind of always personally I
never understood why we had to have it
but the providers wanted it as a safety
mechanism for their network to keep out
untested stuff and so if we're gonna try
to do that the mechanism that's there I
don't think it works for that purpose
and we would need to see if we could
find a different mechanism that did all
right got two more people in the queue
let's see what I can Steve have to say
Isaac you're on yeah I agree I agree
with Paul I think this is definitely a
big concern
something that we definitely do need we
need the ability to protect our systems
from hackers or anyone that might get
their hands on this open source code for
the Roo or VT RP and I I can see ways
that it could work where it's like you
know if if I'm if I the provider in the
one building the Roo I can include my
clients cert which I only have the
private key for and so that I'm the only
one that's able to do that so that when
that client connects to my system I know
that as it has been tested and won't
cause any issues on my system that could
affect my users ability to communicate
so it's absolutely critical that we have
some mechanism so that we aren't just
creating this open door for anyone to
connect into our system which is not
typical I think the example that's been
used as web browsers right and web
browsers are another place that you
might use a client cert so so you know
my bank could do that my bank could say
hey look here here's a client
certificate install this on your browser
and this will ensure that you're the
only one that can access your account it
frankly hasn't been used because it's
it's difficult right from from a user
perspective to have to get a certificate
and understand how to install that and
so I think the example that was given
was that well any you know web browsers
are open source anyone can go get that
code and they can go and connect to any
web server and this is just the same as
that but it's not the same because it's
our communication system or the phone
company for the Deaf and we really have
to protect our system and our users from
any hacker or various actors that might
want to do them harm so it's absolutely
critical that we have
saying I didn't even I had a notice that
had been removed from the latest version
we need to get that back in and we need
to figure out a way that we can make
that work written right now all it says
is during the establishment of a secure
connection with the provider of the room
may be asked by the server for a client
certificate in this case it should
provide the provisioned client
certificate see section 9.2 riders may
reject requests that fail to provide a
recognized certificate that's what it
currently says it is there but it it's
it's it doesn't have its provisioned
into the device and it's a certificate
right the in order in order for that
we'd have to be talking about exactly
who's owning what part of what thing
that that that text is not very clear
about how that works but yeah you're
right you're right so does there I see
that now and I think that the example
that Paul gave previously was almost
something like an app store right like
as as an as an iPhone developer or I
submit my ad to Apple they tested they
verify it works okay and then they make
it available on their App Store for any
user to to download and use on their
phone there was really no other way for
me to distribute an app to iPhone users
without going through the Apple App
Store where they provide that
authentication now I don't it's like I
don't know how that that would work in
our scenario with the room but there
needs to be something like that where
the providers can test and verify that
the clients won't cause any harm to
their system I'm gonna move on to Steve
and then we have Jonathan at the mic and
I'll probably have some stuff to say
hello to go on deceive sorry oh thank
you I was going to change subject so I
was gonna say if there's any other
comments with the regards to this maybe
we should continue at that before I
change subjects okay let's finish this
up and then we'll come back to you
okay all right I guess athletics I just
on the certificate thing I mean the
reason why Apple is able to sign things
in the App Store is they sign the entire
app whereas this you're not uploading
your entire Ruth software to the
provider so the provider is no guarantee
that the Ruth software hasn't been
modified or indeed that somebody hasn't
just extracted a certificate from one
you know piece of Roo software and using
it in their own you know to attack and
you know honestly I feel like saying
that you know you know you can't have
you know the implication that you can't
have a you know open-source
implementation of a roo and point
running on a PC you know that allows it
allowed to connect to the system and
that you know deaf and hard-of-hearing
users can't you know do their own
development of their own endpoint and
make their own enhancements feels like
it's kind of locking down the system
more than I would like
mm-hmm I think you know in general if
you're running a service on the internet
you have to be have some way of
protecting from you know crazy you know
from something you know attacking your
internet and I think the protection here
is you know what you actually have is
you don't know the endpoints offer you
know the person and if the if you have a
user name and password that's attacking
you well you can say we're shutting down
this person because they're not behaving
legitimately they're you know they're
screwing with our system so send so you
know block them out until we figure out
what's going on
yeah that's that's kind of my thinking
that that I don't know a way to protect
a piece of downloadable software from
modification by any number of tools or
extracting the certificate out of that
code and and using that as a way to
protect the other end as from from
malignant software we you basically
can't do that we don't know how to do
that and and that we there just isn't
that just that mechanism just doesn't
work Adam Rhodes I wanted
to put a finer point on it's not just
that we don't know how to do that as we
don't need to do that because we have a
really good proof of existence of a
system that that handles this just fine
mobile phones right I can take my sim
out of my phone and put it in any other
phone without any validation to what the
implementation of that phone has done
you can get like cheap weird phones from
all over the world that do heaven knows
what and as long as I'm able to
authenticate it goes into the system and
it's the same sort of setup right if I
put it my sim into a phone that starts
attacking the network they're gonna turn
off my access and the system is pretty
well protected this doesn't generally
happen but you know in theory it could
and I think that engineering anything
more advanced than that is probably
unnecessary Paul you dropped Isaac
you're up yeah well like a SIM card
would be great right a SIM card provides
a physical hardware ID that allows me to
verify that that is my user so I don't
think that's that's a good equivalent
the type of attack we'd be worried about
would be like a brute-force attack so
let's say I know my ex-girlfriends phone
number and now I can go get the open
source code and I can fairly easily
write a script that can just boot
brute-force attack the system to figure
out what the password for that user is
if I'm just doing a brute-force attack
like that then I don't know who that
user is and I can't necessarily just cut
them off and then but again something
like a SIM card would be a great
solution I just don't know what the
equivalent is for a software app that
doesn't involve an actual device I know
there are like Isom cards on like Google
phones but I don't I think they'll still
depend on a chip or mechanism within the
actual device to make that possible
Thanks Mayer real quick I can answer
that yeah it's in terms of mobile phones
they we do have soft sims where these
are things that can be pushed out that
you don't have to have physical devices
that represent these and they're
basically certificates and so yeah the
answer for how you do this in
software's certificates right you can't
brute-force a search it's your yeah it's
not like you can do this sort of
credential stuffing the you would if you
were validating with passwords and that
part we have right you can grab a client
cert that's okay
correct right it certifies the user but
it's in a way that again can't be it's
not subject to brute forcing or
credential stuff I don't object to
having a client cert that part's fine
but that is a user cert not a device sir
Paul yeah I think maybe you hit most of
it now I don't think we're gonna solve
this here today I think this needs more
discussion on the list and make sure we
come up with something that meets the
needs of the providers I the best thing
I've thought of that that I could
imagine could work here is that the
provisioning server would somehow run a
self-test or something on the device
that satisfy itself that the device was
acceptable before provisioning it or
something like that and then it can
provide the cert but at the end of the
day it would be it I mean it would
probably be a client cert you know and
well again if yeah if you if you have a
sufficiently robust way of doing a
one-time authentication of a user and
you can issue him a cert based on
something that you trust that you know
who you're talking to or you issue that
certain then that cert is an unfortunate
user he has to have the private key in
order to be able to prove that he is
what he is this is a mechanism that's
that's different than what the providers
had originally imagined when
when the stuck was originally written
into the respec if we can determine that
that and because the original one was on
a per application basis if you will you
know and I don't know how to make that
work but if if something like this can
be shown to be to meet the providers
needs then maybe we have a solution all
right I think we just have to discuss it
on the with all right well I'll start
that discussion on the list I agree that
that's probably a good list discussion
rather than doing it here verbally I
will well we'll just do that we'll start
a discussion on the list and see where
where it ends up are there any is there
anything else that people know they want
to do yes Steve is now he wanted to
change the subject so now's a good time
Steve great one question I have I'm not
sure if this has been discussed is with
regards to 9-1-1 and provisioning the
user um this is all from the arrests
respect you know how how does the person
indicate their death and we're able to
provision their home address for use
with 9-1-1 services and are we going to
be passing X Y coordinates to be able to
service their 91 one calls faster okay
so I brian rosen and about as good of an
expert as you'll get on this I've been
heavily involved in all of these
technologies for the last 15 years what
the document currently says is that you
have to be so you have to be compatible
with it with is what with what is
colloquially called I three origination
meaning you suit you conform to RFC 68
81 that's IP emergency calls
that's what next generation 911 is in
the United States and there's equivalent
coming up in other countries there is
provisioning in those services to
support deaf users in a manner that's
much better than it is now I can help
explain what all of those things are but
what this the text currently says that
the the ROO device has to support 68 81
and that means that it can supply an
address or the address can be supplied
by the provider that handles the call on
its way towards the 9-1-1 service it
means that you can support 3-way video
with the bridge at the at the peace app
the 9-1-1 call center
it means that that all three media are
supported all the way through from the
user all the way out to the p7 and if
necessary out to the responders so the
root of that by conforming to 68 81 okay
does does the ROO application allow for
the user to enter their address so that
it can be verified by our 911 services
um that we contract with right well so
you don't currently have any support as
far as I know none of the providers
currently have any support for next gen
9 1 1 you currently use the eye 2
mechanisms which are void mechanisms to
the current inai non 1 system which are
different in every way from how the next
generation 9 1 1 works the text is not
clear and could be made clearer about
whether the device can supply location
and how if it did how it is verified and
I think that that your that that prompts
me to write a note in the notes that
says we should clarify that in the in
the document
as a practical matter although the ITF
doesn't like it the way it's being
deployed the location is supplied by the
provider or the the the network operator
the the the thing that provides the
calling service it would be the VoIP
provider in the case of a VoIP device
rather than the end device the sixty
eighty one implies the end device
supplies location as a practical matter
that the location is being put on by the
service so our our provider on that we
supply XY coordinates to our provider
but they require before they'll use
those XY coordinates that there is a
physical address already assigned to
that that person yeah and they'll only
use the XY coordinates if if that person
has been quote quote validated or
registered with them yeah I I understand
what you're talking about I know all
about these mechanisms so the standards
that are referred to in the current
document support either XY X X Y Z or or
Civic or both and and again we could
clarify in the text whether or not the
device has to be able to be provisioned
with its location or whether it can
supply X Y we can there there's
insufficient text on that subject and I
will I will do that I will fix that okay
because I did do a quick look for 911
perhaps I should have looked for
emergency services and see any mention
of it so yeah doesn't say 9-1-1 it says
emergency services yeah battle thank you
I'm just writing the note about
clarifying that in the text oh yeah yeah
when I make the note it's an emergency
calls yeah yeah yeah yeah that's the
problem some urgency services so why we
we've got the UN that's what we really
use yes your answer
SSS okay but that was a good Steve thank
you for bringing it up that clearly is
something we need to improve and I was
kind of aware of that we also probably
could spill a few words about how how
the current document only describes the
existing system I'm sorry the next
generation 9 1 1 it doesn't really talk
about the existing system the device
doesn't have to do anything for the
existing system so that that doesn't
mean anything but we could say that and
then it would be clear
Isak
go ahead want to clarify on when you say
the device doesn't need to do anything
what it does need to do what we do is we
give we provide the user a way to enter
their address that's pretty typical inai
one one requirement you see on Vonage
and other over-the-top VoIP providers
from what I've seen there I haven't seen
anything in the Roo or the B a TRP so
far that has provided that same ability
for the user to simply enter their
address and/or a standard mechanism to
send that up to the provider so I think
that that's the key piece that's missing
if if you want that provisioned in that
that would be fine typically what almost
every service I know about does for that
is is a web page I mean that is how
vonage does it it's not in the phone
it's not in anything that that is it is
in the inning and any interface it's
literally a web page so if you want
something beyond that I mean I'm happy
to put that in it doesn't isn't the
problem to do that yeah I've definitely
seen it in apps like Google Voice and
others but if it is a web page I think
then it's important to say that okay so
there's at least some way for the user
to get that address in yeah all right
text about that all right
[Music]
just Adam Roach you might want to give
some thought when you do that about
exactly how it's going to interact with
authentication given that users are
authenticated in the system right now by
certificates and you're not going to get
that on the webpage side of things makes
things a little bit more interesting so
yeah we might actually look at
leveraging the sip signaling information
to convey this information to the
carrier in some way okay I was writing
member if there was any register use
cases we used that for and I was about
to go looking but you know just keep
that kind of thing in the back your mind
and see if there's anything a little
more elegant that might be used here I
mean we can send a J card
all right put in call info we have a way
to do that so yeah oh that does bring up
another one yes all ditional data it's a
note to myself you don't know anything
about it but I do okay I'll bring that
subject to also what Mike what's that I
was gonna ask if CalDAV works are these
these are certificates I guess it can
but we'd have to okay well what kind of
Gunnar hi I you mentioned that for the
emergency call you need you will get
video on multi-party view you know we
have a discussion going on for
multi-party real-time text well you need
that as well I think you would all right
maybe I should just draw attention to
what we are starting up in abt core we
have a new draft or a revived old draft
about multi-party real-time text and
that will be discussed tomorrow in a BT
core and hopefully you can join there
and discuss multi-party real-time text
because there is more needed in the
device than just receiving single media
yeah I'm taking notes about that yep
you're right okay dad I just won the
point I did went then look it up
so RFC 64 42 specifically allows the use
of the geolocation header field and
register requests which would be a
pretty cut-and-dried way to handle that
mm-hmm all right does does allow that ha
yeah okay well we actually have the
answer Adam I'll just write it down
there's their security implications in
that but you have to just note it Yeah
right yep
okay well gee this is Steve is Steve
yeah just a quick question Adam which
which RFC did you say was it 64 4 - yeah
I believe that's correct is that they're
not coming up correctly what are you
looking - okay it's just one of the next
or yeah it's it's it's the geolocation
header for Sep okay thank you yep
that's referenced in our document so
there there's a reference to it in in in
the text you can find it anything else
people want to talk about other again
I'm other things that are in that need
to be improved in the doc before we
consider it done this will not be the
last time and we'll ask for that but the
earlier we surface things that we need
to do the happier I'm going to be to get
them done
anything else well for the lack of
people in room this was a very fine
meeting and I appreciate all of you who
most of you are in the u.s. staying up
late and Gunnar what time is it for you
it must be really awful but I appreciate
your participation it's been great
having you on participating in it in the
meeting and I hope we'll be generating a
lot of lifts traffic as a result of all
these discussions which is always what
we want to see and unless there's
anything else I think we're adjourned
whatever it takes