well update him for the proceedings
hello everyone and welcome to sag
welcome back from lunch my name is Roman
Jeanne Leo and I am Ben Caidic and we
should try that not be throwing things
and hitting each other so we got the
blue sheets going around and Roman
already got us the jabber scribe and the
minute taker so we will get started this
is no well he's noted well if you have
not already noted it well not too much
on the agenda today just the usual weird
reports and then the open mic the slides
we have are made as of 119 this
afternoon so 11 minutes ago so if you
have sent something in the last 11
minutes it will not be reflected in
these slides so I guess we should just
page through these slowly and if someone
has further comments that they want to
mention we can just bring those up to
Mike
lamps we get a report for lamps
so I have my co-chair said he would send
this surprised the group is moving along
pretty quickly we have I think three or
four documents with the isg right now we
have a recharter that should be on the
next LH at if that happens then we have
a whole bunch work that will be up for
adoption anything exciting going on for
MLS I'll just see you on Friday
anything you say about the first meeting
of OAuth happened okay
so I can add an OAuth we had the related
TX off both which we're going to talk
about and then there has been talk about
something dumped off 2.1
anything happened in TLS before lunch uh
yeah we there were presentations on some
ongoing working group documents delegate
credentials exported authenticators and
then we had some new work on batch
signing compact II uh since I'm he said
act if you helmet and I just sent the
report they're just good to go so and
then we're gonna be talking about yes
Annihilator today so yeah we had a lot
of talk about external PS case as well
no yes thank you so we had two baths in
the security area we had math math mesh
and we also have TX auth so folks want
to say anything relative to the math
mesh Baath the kind of the summary was
we heard about a broad area of
technologies we heard about one
particular application domain there was
not a lot of excitement about that
particular application domain but we
talked about others and there was
interest in following up on some of the
specific kind of technology issues and
that was the next step coming out of
that loss so TX off do teachers want to
say anything since there was no report
actually did send out a report but
anyway so we had a presentation of all
like protocol which is not
backward-compatible with oauth2 and
addresses a few more use cases and has a
different flow than today's all still
there was agreement over all across the
room about the problems
there's no no agreement on a way forward
yet as you mentioned there's discussion
at the same time about an oath to
rewrite tentatively named their two
point one as well as this O three
this is being hashed out as we speak so
I think there also may be a few side
meanings in this general space did
anyone go to those that is here
look excites I was at a off-site meeting
that mostly disgusts off 2.1 or
continued the discussion of off to that
one from the ORS
first off meeting was it mostly just
discussion or any any good conclusions
well someone volunteered to do some work
but I can't recall the name right now
Aram I could could be but that let him
confirm that's hopefully they remember
that they signed up to do the work okay
so there is a lot of other security work
that's happening across the IETF we have
a scattershot of some of them both in
the working groups in the IRT F in the
IAB
and through liaison activities so if
anyone wants to come up to the mic now
to describe some of that please please
do so I guess when we're making the
slides I put him up here we've got some
some cootie related work going on there
talking about like the autonomic network
infrastructure and the security
protocols and security secure
communications mesh for that and so they
want to use x.509 certificates to
authenticate all the nodes in the sort
of autonomic network and I've been
having a little bit of a back-and-forth
with the authors about how exactly
they're going to use the x.509
certificates because they have some
information that they want to put in the
RFC 82 name field of the certificate and
I'm not I'm having a hard time
convincing myself that this is like
within the spirit of
x.509 so I've I think I've talked to a
few people in person about this but
they've got in addition to like IP
address in string form they have the
sort of name of the acp domain in the
you know domain part of the a 22 name
but then there's some some other stuff
as well including like a arbitrary
subdomain name and a whole form or
extensions and it's it's a little bit
weird to be constructing your own
structured name within the constraints
of the a.22 name at least to me so
anybody who is interested in thinking
about this a bit more I'd be happy to
talk to you at some point not
necessarily now and get a actual
resolution for them because I don't want
to keep holding a discus forever thank
you for the open mic yeah all right so
um
you asked about possible stuff in the
security area so the UT a working group
hasn't met for awhile and there is like
the old stuff to clear up but we had a
couple of a couple of us had a
discussion in a break whether it's time
to do a BCP on deployment experience
from 103 or if it's too soon is there
stuff you know that should get out there
in terms of like that kind of the kind
of stuff that we put in in the BCP for
1.2 that's an open question for the
community yeah I think I'd started
talking to the TLS chairs a little bit
about that and you know there's maybe
some work to do in the space about
updating our recommendations like a
cretin is a PCP 210 195 I don't remember
the RSC 75252 you include to us we're
not three in those recommendations but I
think we and you Chris and Joe and Shawn
you can correct me if I'm wrong but I
think we decided that we will
but more to get a little bit more
deployment experience maybe some more
specific experience with Xero RTT before
we start doing that right that was gonna
be my photo of question whether that's
gonna be the focus maybe it may be it
will be right but anyway I guess the
working group will hibernate for a while
and you know see if some something else
turns up I don't think so but I think
we'll wait for for you guys to tell us
when it's time to wake up and do some
work okay or we could like close and
retire it depending on Bob Moss would
say she consulting you have TMR ID up
there the decision seems to be to move
forward to a working group for TMR d
we're now we're here in the scope of the
other charter of interest to the stag
group would be Graf Whitaker tiem Rd I'm
off and Adam has an interesting spelling
of Whitaker so I suggest you look at the
boss information to get the proper
spelling to find the draft the reason I
mention it is that one of the things
that we have to struggle with is
authenticating these really short
messages previously sent which we hash
and then include the hashes in the auth
message which is then signed so
discussion on what we have created there
the first set of thoughts we have on
that we're really open to other ideas
and thoughts are working this extremely
constrained environment and how to
authenticate 25 byte messages and and to
prove the owner of which actually you a
sent those messages by hashing them and
including them in the much longer auth
message so a bunch of other eyes on that
draft are greatly appreciated the draft
is really rough right now but really
appreciate assistance on that one and
Bob do you know maybe send that to the
email lists as well I will send that to
the sackless yes just a quick note since
you do have NTP up there we did submit
NTS to the is G so hopefully that's
almost done and we have adopted two
additional drafts that are
related to security one on rough time
and one on Chronos so those are security
related items that are going on in the
NTP working group thank you
I also put up there the IAB not program
so just IAB activity for the threat
model discussion I know Stephen or yari
do you want to say anything about that
yah react so there's been some amount of
activity on that so we Stephen I emerged
our draft we're still working on through
the other feedback that we've gotten and
at this idea we had a site meeting 22
people attended and it seems like there
was quite a bit of interest and some set
of people willing to contribute
different aspects of the topic and so
we're cranking away I think and gets the
overall plan is that we will provide
some documentation and rationale for you
know why why are we in this situation
essentially I guess because we've made
some progress in terms of communication
security and now some of the threats our
that we have to worry about are the
remaining ones and that's why the focus
has has changed and you know isn't this
sort of supporting documentation we'd
like to get sort of one pager that that
is you know this is how we would like to
change our see 3552 it's uh at least my
interpretation of the of the situation
but war continues yeah I think that was
my interpretation as well that we if
everything goes well end up with like a
one page update to 3552 for the
broadened scope of things that we have
to think about because we've been doing
so well encrypting everything okay other
security updates from other working
groups inside and outside the idea going
once twice
okay so with that we're gonna open up
the mic line is there anything someone
would like to talk about
we could have had a longer lunch I guess
all right well we're not gonna wait for
them okay going once going twice
anyone want to come up to the mic all
right in that case we're gonna call it
thanks so much
and who wear the blue sheets if you have
the blue sheets please hold them up I
see two clipboards excellent if you have
not signed the blue sheets please find
the people with the blue sheets or come
up to the front
you