back in not the same room smaller room
mr. kiss lucky reminds me that people
should fill this blue sheet out the blue
sheets out so we make sure to get the
right sized room next time it's
searching 20 we're gonna start the
meeting The Cider ops meeting if you're
not here for cider ops you're in the
wrong room for those presenting please
make sure to talk into the mic like this
hold the mic don't use the stand if you
do if it's in the standard you're doing
this I can't see here you either there's
a nice thing in front of the presenters
they can read that instead of doing this
also very nice we have a yep you can
laser point to it like you can see what
I'm pointing at I can't see what I'm
pointing it doesn't work on the LCD it
works over here
we're in cider ops in ietf 106
I am Mauro see and that is care we have
a clicker that works okay we have a
jabber person Natalie or no yes oh okay
well let's see do we have a minutes
taker or another jet and other person
who'd like to type on the keyboard
during the meeting okay perfect we'll
well delay Natalie can take notes
minutes they're called strawberry man is
here yes I'll make my attempt next time
tonight hi there oh the other thing for
the people that are presenting medico
would like you to stand on the pink
square Randy bush pink square you'll see
when you get up here cross fine whatever
it's a parallelogram it's seven parallel
lines five of which are transparent okay
somebody else will got that
I'm sure okay ready Joe it's coming okay
okay okay okay good we'll just move
ahead blue sheets for those who didn't
get them earlier we could pass into the
back there's a note well for the meeting
I'm sure that by this day of the meeting
you've seen this a few times it's in
small print intentionally it doesn't
have all the resources that's further on
okay so today we have six presentations
not counting this one hopefully will be
done quickly with our part those times
are approximate they probably don't add
up to the right time I didn't pay
attention so strat draft statuses
there's some stuff that we have to push
into the editors queue out of working
group last call there's at least two
things I think here yeah yeah maybe a
couple of more the last thing in iest
processing is LTI use cases I think
that's stuck for a long time and I don't
exactly remember why it'll pop out
eventually and the things that are
probably the ones that need to go into
the editors queue are things like OB
egress I think somebody's complained
about that I mean sorry I sent a message
about that a couple the others here at
will as well so we'll hear about those
I'm sure at the mic and afterwards we'll
scrape through the land list and figure
it out okay first person up is Tim
[Music]
almost a square almost
which one is yours called alright so
deprecate rsync why well first off as
you know our sink is used in the RPI so
is another protocol that was invented
here
RDP so the RPI repository Delta protocol
for friends and what I'm proposing here
I I made a draft just in my own name it
doesn't have to stay like that I'm
actually looking for some people I
mentioned to me that they want to
co-author as well but I wanted to get
out so they get something out quickly so
I did that but before going into all of
that a quick reminder why why did we
invent the Delta protocol there you can
talk about this for longer but mainly in
order to run an R sync repository
reliably it's not that easy
and with RDP you can leverage CDMS so
the job becomes a bit more yeah less
challenging I would say and also from
the relying party point of view
most software ends up calling the arcing
binary on a system which may have
different behaviors on different systems
those would be my top reasons why I
would want to get rid of it how well
this might be controversial so it's here
intentionally because I think we should
have discussion about this pragmatically
speaking I propose to keep the rsync
your eyes even though a repository might
not be available at that location and
the reason is that if we update the
certificate profile this can lead to
things be becoming rejected and that
will make deployment much harder there
is some prior art in an XML where
namespaces are HTTP your eyes quite
often and their main
be anything there I don't particularly
like it I think it's ugly but on the
other hand we do need names for things
for debugging and yeah I don't I'm
trying to avoid breaking things and
that's why I'm proposing us so but you
know we can have that discussion also we
could instruct relying parties to prefer
our DP if it's available and well
ultimately phase out our sync
but when well there's a bit of a chicken
and egg problem here I didn't find good
pictures of chicken and eggs maybe I
didn't look well enough but essentially
this is the situation you have many
repositories you have many relying
parties and the relying parties talk to
all the repositories and repositories
will need to support our thing as long
as can only drop support for our sink if
all the relying parties support the
alternative and vice versa our relying
parties can only drop support for our
sinker and all the repositories support
the alternative and I think measurement
should turn into that because if you
look at the wrote there then Randy wrote
a proposal actually that can work but
I'm not sure that we have to tie it on
to that but to repeat what you said
Randy and you can correct me later if
I'm wrong is that well you can start
from the repository side you can say now
you all go support our DP once that's
done and you have the green button right
here right so they all supported and you
could say to our Peas well some of you
support it most of you support it but
please now all start supporting it and
then you can measure with in recession
measurements whether people actually
deploy these new versions and at some
point you can now say ok now the
repositories can phase out parsing but
in my view I'm not sure that this should
be a heavy segment of the document I
think in the eventual document that
final document that you probably not be
there at all in my view because I think
it should just talk about what it
updates but of course this is an
important discussion to have in my view
I think we aim for having everybody move
forward in parallel because I don't see
why that cannot happen meaning that we
would ask relying party software
implementers to it also support RDP even
if not all the repositories already have
it so
but first questions and well this is not
even a working group document so that's
also another question that it might go
to the list so the floor is yours
Jeff Houston
there were many mistakes and bad ideas
in the original work that developed this
and one of them was a sink I actually
think that the problem that we got given
which was the entire x.509 distributed
repository mess and the inability to
sort of smash them all together was was
was a really terrible problem to get
given and opportunistic pool was a
solution clutched out of desperation
rather than a hard design the problem is
actually reliable flooding of
information right and we're doing that
by opportunistic grab in N squared mesh
and it just seems to be wrong and when
you rephrase it as flooding reliable
flooding in you actually look at
protocols like BGP which is actually a
reliable flooding algorithm and if you
think that you don't necessarily have to
do routing information and route objects
bgp is actually an amazing protocol as
many other people have used for many
other
purposes if I tell you something I told
you I never retell you you never have to
ask me again
I've told you it for the life of the
session the whole issue around the way
it gets flooded is actually not a bad
approach and I kind of wonder if we're
going to drop all this stuff about a
sink and replacing it with yet another
opportunistic grab holding algorithm you
have kind of exchanging one model of
anchor for another neither of them flow
and although I might be accused of going
well the perfect shoulds the enemy of
the good here I thought we could do
better and if the abstract problem
really is
I want reliable flooding of what's
inside repositories maybe we should look
further afield than just replacing the
underlying mechanism of this particular
protocol and look at an architectural
sense and go other alternatives we can
piggyback then actually do do reliable
flooding so that when I publish in my
repository it just flows through
everyone else so that's what I would
urge us to think about before simply
just going to this particular solution
because it doesn't change a lot thanks
yeah can only respond to that because
well in my view it's it's quite
interesting to look at BGP as a plotting
protocol for this but I think there will
be many things that need to be figured
out and it's going to be a while before
that's a reality at this moment I think
supporting our sink is impacting people
and it's low-hanging fruit to do that
first of all so in parallel you can look
at alternatives at least that's my my
take on it video photo spherical I
oppose using BGP for flooding this
before
before before I retire I don't know
whether some research group will be
looking into more optimal solutions than
this some problems with arsenic are
known the RDP has been developed as a
probably working solution we do not have
the proof in actual scaled operations I
think I think we need some something
there some document that explains the
roadmap for actually getting forward for
the question of how eggs and poultry are
bred my take is actually actually the
repositories have to move first that
does not preclude getting the
implementation for clients quite
obviously if the road map says the
repositories actually should work on
providing a reliable service before
clients start to rely on them or even
start to do large-scale operational
testing now and yes kind of a fixed a
fixed time schedule I think is not going
to work the schedule has to has to be
conditioned alized
on criteria that say well okay if we
achieve that kind of operational status
on the repository side we we tell we
tell we tell client sites to move
somewhere
I dima from our Kista open source a
relying party project team I like your
idea but I'm wondering whether you have
extreme nose with repository manager so
whether it is it easy for there to
support Delta protocol
well I no longer work for the ripe NCC
but we deployed there uh-huh
and there's some experience there and I
think we're all new software there's an
initial phase of getting it right I
think the tricky part of that protocol
is generating those files reliably but
serving them on the other hand is quite
easy but I agree also at what routing a
said that we should build a operational
experience with running this but some
people have been doing that so
particularly the ripe NCC and Edenic and
others are in the process of developing
and employing as well thank you so oil
information are you our test bed I think
Delta is a watch is walking much better
than I think Wendy Bush are kissing i oj
I don't think Jeff went far enough and I
and I don't think Jeff went far enough
and I have and I have a t-shirt that
says BGP awarding PhD theses since 1994
and I think other bullish males pushed
BGP down our throats when we really
should have considered idrp more
seriously I have also a problem Tim with
the chicken and egg because that is not
the case there is a sequence that gets
you both poultry and dinner
and and do you have a problem with the
sequence I suggested I mean do you have
another sequence which doesn't drop
stuff on the floor oh yes you did the
end I think we may actually mean a very
similar thing what I mean to say is that
I would encourage relying party
implementers to already start supporting
our DP definitely right and and I don't
want to wait until all the repositories
have it right but it doesn't mean we've
done that already
no I think some still need to implement
oh well now haven't we encouraged all
right oh maybe but if we put it in a
document so are you suggesting a
document that only stops at encouraging
them or lays out the whole sequence I'm
into mind about including a sequence I
think is useful during this discussion
and the coming period but if eventually
you have a document that updates the
existing standard documents I'm not sure
that it should still include a road map
but you can have a road map whilst
you're talking about this stuff and
maybe keep it in a document because it's
a convenient place to put it but once it
becomes our of seed and I'm not sure
that a road map is going to get outdated
I'm afraid but maybe you should take
this offline it's not that I finally
oppose it but I don't want to end up
with a document that is going to be out
of date the moment it's published and
you have that risk when you include road
maps in it I'm perfectly happy with
documents that go out of date once
they're successful two minutes left
jokes
nighters NTT OpenBSD I would be
supportive of offering let's call it a
BCP titles using our Seng to distribute
our P key is considered harmful and it
is good if the ITF puts out a signal to
publishers and consumers of the
published information that our Seng is
not the preferred method to disseminate
this data if in an appendix to such a
documents a roadmap is included that may
be beneficial but at least statements
need to be published that we do not like
our sync and we need to state why we
don't like our Seng for this purpose Rob
lost Arkus and Dragon research labs a
couple of comments with a claisen said
they were running out of time first of
all two people who didn't quite get
Tim's comment about why we want to keep
the arson to our eyes um
the problems would definitely basically
have us hashes because we very very
carefully removed all identifying
information from the RPK oh and the only
thing that was left as the authorized if
you take your eyes away to them what you
have is hash it's lots and lots and lots
of hashes which gets kind of confusing
pretty quickly on secondly I slightly
disagree about the marshalling the data
into our DP being difficult actually
it's not yeah we hit limit of this what
four years ago um we had to
reimplementation zuv our see a code that
is because our CA code was in retrospect
designed badly it should have been doing
basically a transactional model to begin
with as soon as you go to a
transactional model this is just you
generated Delta a for every transaction
done it's trivial there are a few
interesting characteristics on the RP
side though in particular when you're
dealing with a very very large
collection like the ripe ncc collection
the validation behavior is different
okay if you've got I'll just use this
poster children uh throwing rocks of
anybody poster children you have a pea
neck as the you know holdouts for the
least efficient possible way of doing
arson
and you have Reitman CC as the early
adopters for a big one of our DP the one
nice thing about the rather strange
think the de pinna cause is you can kind
of do all the crypto in parallel right
fetch it fetch d fetch and the fetch is
so slow that by the time time you're
done fetching you've also done all the
validation with the right model it's a
little stranger than that with the right
model you have to wait wait Rance fir
and process and suck into the database
which unfortunately is slow all of that
data before you can start validating any
of it really and it maybe there's some
efficient way to do it I haven't figured
out yet but to first approximation you
have to eat the whole update apply all
the deltas and unfortunately databases
tend to be bad about doing this quickly
and then you have to do all the
validation is this massive chunk so the
behavior is a little different I think
this protocol is actually pretty much
ready whether or not we are ready to
deprecate our sink is a different issue
but I think this I think this protocol
is mature enough to go sorry Rob are you
saying to adopt it then or adopt it and
just straight during your bless call
that I was not actually expressing a
straightforward opinion about whether or
not we had to just throw our sit got the
airlock at this point in time okay
should we yeah but I guess I'd need to
send out to the list yeah and but thanks
for feedback I think that who else and
yeah also available for offline
discussion about this this week
mr. Asimov think this one no no this one
no this one no I don't know one two
three four five six maybe they came last
minute I didn't we could do that
good work let's see I don't know that I
got them right here
what are they called oh yeah no I didn't
upload those for sure too much going on
don't you
is there when you want to start with we
could do that yeah let's maybe we'll try
that of course now I don't have my chair
slides I have no idea who's next
hold on Oh Randy how about Randy mr.
Bush here's our easy to find Europe and
we'll do uh then we'll do mr. asthma
clear okay so back many many years ago
we drafted this document and essentially
it's transfer of resources between two
registries known asses and IP numbers by
registering the rest of this discussion
we mean ISPs our IRS NIRS etc we're not
going to transfer between two I Anna's
it should be doable and we kind of have
to do it fairly often actually how often
do you do transfers Nathalie often she
says okay and just to get some
terminology
there's the seller and the buyer and the
swing point is the I are at the lowest
point in the hierarchy which the seller
and buyer has a common parent and which
is agreed to act as the agent if this
one doesn't agree their parent could be
the swing point is what subtly mentioned
there and there was actually an internet
draft I'm not sure whether it became an
i or i've seen or not that talked about
parents grandparents acting with
authority I don't remember that that it
didn't make it to RFC yeah I remember
writing it because of this problem but
anyway I'm gonna breeze through this
fairly quickly because the point of this
exercise is really not transfer okay
simple transfer is the seller separates
out the resources and tells the swing
point the swing point without deleting
these resources without the leading this
delegation creates and gives them to the
buying I are okay the swing point
delegates to the buyer and then the
swing point withdrawals from the seller
when agreed okay and Steve Kent said
he's going to write up something I
jokingly called the torn euro protocol
which is they tore a euro bill each of
them has it and when both of them turned
that bill into the swing point when the
swing point receives both halves then it
can withdraw but until then both
delegations are active
because we want make oh this is just a
side you know hey you can have things
where the sellers double indirect you
can have things where the buyers double
indirect you know who cares there's a
problem or that you want make before
break you want both of these active at
the same time because possibly circuits
are moving possibly other administrative
problems are occurring in that transfer
and actual operation of the internet is
depending on both of these being make
before break the point of my story today
is the our IRS have are driven by
underlying data which I'll call stats
files but you know some of them call
them something else some of them have
their authoritative data hidden and the
stats files merely a realization of it
but it makes the difference this is a
sit the problem is these files I believe
in all the RI ours are one-to-one
mappings this resource may only be owned
by one are up one I are at a time which
means break before me okay now there's
no blame seemed like a good idea at the
time
okay and the question is how do we help
the our IRS get out of this position
okay so the our p-a-k-i
structure can do it it's real easy it's
the our IRS have a problem
with these one-to-one mappings okay so
what we have today is not operationally
viable there I was brought to my
attention by an LIRR who actually broke
okay so where do we go with the transfer
document shall we move it forward or not
I don't know and how do we help the are
the our IRS become unstuck from this
problem and I think that's my last slide
I managed to stay on the degenerate
square very good four minutes for
questions Oh Dutch Telecom I seem to
remember that Steve Kent at some point
did draft that allowed some outside of
rpki signalling of something like this
being in process and first of all
criteria for relying parties that wants
to check whether the are PKI certificate
system actually looks reliable quite
obviously include include the criterion
that it looks very suspicious if a
resource is claimed by two parties in
parallel signaling when this is actually
intended and authorized is something
essentially needed there as far as rir
keeping of data
it would seem to be fairly
straightforward to have to have markers
to have a notation on resources
this is outgoing and potentially a time
limit and it would be nice to have that
published so that discriminating relying
parties actually can figure out if they
see strange things in the classic words
of Vince parallelo send code I think uh
problem I think there's a lot of
software tied to those stats files is
the problem a points of a job Snyder's
ntt a point of clarification I would
like to ask you are you talking about
transfers inter area or in Tran re era
we see the problem today in truck RI are
the problem I believe exists inter-rir
and so now I mean having been the first
victim or actually I wasn't a victim I
was very happy with the experience of
transferring between RI ours um it was
made before break so since we're
venturing into the political landscape
anyhow there may be use cases where it
is desirable that the transfer only half
completes and the certificates continue
to coexist in multiple re ours from a
redundancy perspective inter-rir is
probably simpler in the current universe
due to the perverse political situation
yes
and I think this work is very much worth
considering and progressing through this
working group so I'd be interested so
yeah we gotta do something
actually I know what we have to do I
think is helping the our IRS figure out
how to not make not break before make
moving the transfer document is
something we can do at our leisure right
yeah no I'll keep it really sure I think
we should talk about this offline
I read the document I never get scared
of the mechanics that are proposed and I
think we can aim for simpler solutions
and I'm not yet convinced that you need
to signal these things to anybody
looking at the rpi maybe you can
leverage the provisioning protocol let's
have a talk this document it sits in my
memories this document doesn't suggest
that I'm saying I'm not sure that you
need the signaling of the intent to have
a transfer done in the aapki I and if
you do I'm not sure that this is the way
to do it but that's for the sake of time
maybe have the discussion not right here
right now because I don't think there's
time for it
was it long as quick for an attempt at
code I get the nasty idea the RI hours
presented us with an applicability
statement as an internet draft that
pointed to a certain file for
disambiguating potential conflicts in
the rpki it would be very simple I guess
to add in that file another column that
says okay this resource is moving
somewhere this is a nasty comment and I
don't think I don't think it is actually
going to work but it might be actually a
practical way right okay on the break
side for example provisioning protocol
you ask a question to your parent you
say what are my entitlements it tells
you what they are it might be less than
what you have there's no grace period
for example that's one thing you might
consider that you can communicate to a
child that something will be shrunk go
clean up that's one thing you can think
of on the side of initially initiating
all this there's a lot of line processes
involved as well so I'm not sure that
the rpi should be driving this I'm not
even sure that anybody else needs to
know that a thing is going on but if you
do then yes
currently the proposal is to create a
separate certificate with all the
resources that are going to be
transferred on it I'm not sure that
that's the way to do it you can also
invent a signed object that says these
resources are going to be transferred I
would think that's already easier so
just you know we can have more
discussion but that's at the beginning
of it and a quick question for you about
where do we go from here there were lots
of comments that you got and job said
this is
work that this working group can take so
do you want to switch your call on this
I did I think there's two bull bullets
here and I think what we're strongly
agreed on is the second one which is not
pushing a document okay the Straz mob
leave we have your documents now
although if you're a telex thing to
reload okay
max length second one
[Music]
hello everyone my name is Alexander
Asimov I work for Yandex and this will
be a rather quick update thanks about a
spade rats during this year Randy with
fighting with me to make the draft less
ambitious to have clear description
about the procedures that are present in
this draft and these slides is another
tenth that's failed so the cookies not
working try this that's not the right
one but oh it's this thing the other
fullscreen oh yeah sorry son take it
please is an oversimplified description
of the solution without no feelings and
unknowns and so on so there is a drafts
suggest two procedures first procedure
for prefixes that I received from
customers and peers and the second
procedure for prefixes that I received
from providers and for if we are
receiving prefixes from the customers
and peers the only
pair so that may exist in the ice bath
is custom to provide a custom to provide
a custom to provider as you can see CA
here if we detect a single pair that is
provided at a customer or at least it's
not accustomed to provide a source sorry
for ambiguity of these slides its
invalid path the downstream path it may
have both upstream path and downstream
sub path and but each fit is followed
again by an upstream path it's a route
lik so don't look at this light its
listen what about what I'm speaking
about it's very simple and very hard to
describe not in gold but with words and
slides so there were also questions
about deployment process I and it's very
important to bring immediate benefit for
the ice be who will be the first one to
sign first a spay record and a speed
desert because as soon as it signs a
spay record it gives a chance to other
parties to detect mistakes around leaks
so it's very poor to know islands you
know cooperation which just works for
malicious activity it's slightly a
harder process but it's not that hard so
you need to create royal records - so
it's a it's also up to you and your
security also relies on your upstream
providers if you have happy to be t1 you
are not relying to or to anybody so it
uses an is period so this the only thing
that is needed to protect you from
yourself from malicious activity if you
are tired - you rely on your upstream
providers so the change look I hope - it
will not be an additional ambiguity so
it is rather simple
after the suggestions in the mailing
list we changed a spay profile from
players that were customer and provider
to pairs where we have customer and set
of providers to solve Possible's you
musician issues we also added another
state for verification procedure which
is unspecified so we have valid invalid
unspecified it will not be that's useful
at the state of owner adoption but can
give your additional debug opportunities
at the state of middle adoption or high
adoption rate I've added some beautiful
drawings that shows how the state
between valid in validity unknown are
changing I'm sure you if this made the
draft more readable but I hope you
enjoyed it and this enjoyed it and with
good first implementation on top of that
many things goes to yogini become asif
and andre such as ik i hope i pronounced
it rightly
I know that there is another
implementation coming so we're we're
good here so and now action plan please
read the drafts we need your feedback
because we need at least another person
which will start telling me that's the
way I'm writing text ruining the
principle of least astonishment so if
you want to at least work to proceed
quickly please give us feedback help us
to work on the text another on outside
we will receive your feedback work on it
and we'll try to finish working on the
text until the next ITF meeting rain
they also promised that he will work on
archaea protocol and so this is the last
missing part so we will have three
drafts one profile one verification and
a data that is supposed to go together
to the working group Lascaux so that's
all Randy Randy Bush Jai anarchist Randy
promise to do the RPI router protocol
when
um object was clearly designed and
clearly not very significantly changes
they all document progresses I'd agree
and since we have changed their profile
if we have a stable version of object
and secondly I really think the draft
needs some reading by a couple other
people because some of the authors are
in disagreement of its clarity yeah
hands up for this please read the draft
give us feedback it's very important
all right profile drafts in particular
that's what any other one and I left a
comment on the list I wanna eat here so
this is not a big deal but only the
customer is actually needs to be present
only and entity certificates in the
signed object and I would think it would
be good to recommend people that they
don't include anything else because if
you do then you run an unnecessary risk
because of any of those resources are no
longer held by the certificate signing
that ASPA object and the whole ASPA
object become invalid and i think it's
easy to avoid you can just have the one
a yes only and then so yeah yeah thank
you for the comment and thank you for
your previous comments that you
highlighted possible issues with the
pair of provided customer I think the
CAC the text currently says that the
object is valid as long as the customer
a s is in the set that is on the EE
certificate and I would suggest that you
keep that EE certificates small in terms
of resources because you only need to
have that a s that customer s there you
don't need anything else so I wouldn't
include anything else because if you do
that's just a avoidable risk of things
that can break
really do you give up yeah okay
this is my second set of slides and they
are not related to any draft but I
believe they can bring variable
considerations for this working group so
and we will discuss as you see much
length the default behavior normally
when we are speaking about default
behavior or default settings by
expecting that these kind of settings
are working in most of cases and for a
current advocare object roll the default
behavior suggested to be drop invalids
now rejected methods don't accept in
minutes so when route becomes invalid
there are two options first option if
the reason is match in the outer own
sister numbers and the second option is
that the prefix length is bigger than
the length specified in the row object
so as you have already guessed so we
will spend next five minutes discussing
I if max length applicable for with the
default suggestion that such with such
rounds should give it a rejected and it
can a move forward I'm sorry some types
I included yeah there will be another
type us on the next slide so I'm sorry
it's not a thick it's AfriNIC so I've
tried to contact all current reuse to
find out what are their default settings
when people are creating much length
because as you know the the hosted our
creation of rows is the current
so nearly all of them while answering
just seems to think they're looking at
the prefixes detective at the moment and
creating marks length that is equal to
the prefix length look from now but
there are okay but there are a couple of
problems first if we all took the site
of ingress filtering you cannot drop
invalid in case of custom sending your
air black hole from egress site is just
the same so if you are sending a black
hole route you cannot just blindly drop
invalids and it is related to Rudi girls
draft and she is already in line but
there is another issue let's say let's
take a look from the security
perspective from the security
perspective in a perfect world where is
a pacaya is globally deployed we will
have raw and I hope will also have a
spare objects and to stop both malicious
activity and mistakes we don't need max
length and there is another point and it
is more crucial at the state because it
happens at the state of partial adoption
imagine you are the possessor of Network
/ - 23 and you have created rows with
help of some web interface and your
supervisor is a good fellow
and here already using a rotation
procedure but somewhere another guy
makes it typos and he hijacks your
prefix and it's going to be propagated
and there is it's not specific and you
cannot fight it because you first need
to update roles after that you need to
call your action provider okay if you
are using
egress filtering itches a slightly
simpler but again it's it's doesn't
provide it in a way to fight
militias are not malicious but mistakes
rapidly so it's great additional
security risks at the states of partial
adoption until it's already here it's
I've copied it yesterday from NIST and
it says that a half of invalids that are
in the world for correct are consistent
number and incorrect Marsland there are
networks that have already put to this
issue into consideration and some of
them are sitting max length to the L to
the maximum values as it's possible this
way I said yes it turned into to fix
this issue because I was thinking about
this risk a couple of years ago but
recently I've learned from several
players for some of them have very big
names this so they are already hacking
on top of apical cache so the increase
in max length on their side to accept
invalids from their peers and from their
customers and of course it is all
connected what is set by default in
hosted CAS in routing registries I'm not
giving you any kind of solution at the
moment but I'm asking this working group
do you consider this as a problem that
should be taken into account if and if
you think we should work on this issue
let's discuss possible solutions right
again okay there is in my opinion
absolutely no question the correct
default for brewers is a simple row with
max length equal to V traffic's length
that's the basic that's the basic rule
the max length the max length longer
might be something that should be only
available in expert mode
the user interface after after
examination that people have a rough
idea what they are doing may enter at
you and ask you is a co-author of egress
filtering how do you see deployment
process of these draft if the default
policy and drop-in reddits is not
working for the leaves because I'm not I
don't think that the target audience of
this draft is dr. chili con I when I
first saw this draft I said I was
thinking all great so they're stupid
guys will protect themselves from making
mistakes but if if it's not working by
default I'm not thinking they will
deploy it i I have I have to think about
it but kind of I I guess that well okay
if roars if well okay if you if you want
if you want to have to pass to pass
routes that are actually invalid with
Nami I don't well I heard you asked
about yesterday when we talked the day
before yesterday yeah I could have some
more radical thinking about this issue
at the moment I believe that if you flip
the coin and even much length for the
experts instead even the default like is
specified for example by some companies
that already see the risks it might be
flying from the box well if for my own
network for your own network it is quite
it is quite clear over egress
will help me to shortcut stupid
misconfigurations that my colleagues are
doing for customers for customers a kind
of the ingress policy will ensure that I
will not accept invalids they are in
except for the cases where we have a
special agreement and that special
agreement quite certainly you have will
have implications for special handling
on the egress site if there is actually
a egress side yeah but again I really
regret that not all companies in the
poles at Deutsche Telekom and into the
okay okay okay okay I will not least
each company that is at present in this
room but anyway but take into account
the idea that there as far as I
understand the target audience for
egress draft is Leafs
and to make it working at least site you
make you need to make it as simple as
possible the principle keep it simple
stupid is the only way to make it and to
make it work to make it global or not
global even but it is partial doctor not
only by but big players because I'm not
afraid of you I'm afraid of this jeff
has trying to keep this short the max
length stuff is obviously advice to the
global internet at large this is what
the global Internet should be seeing for
these things
the misconfigurations we tend to see
here are often things that you want to
have no longers show up for some scoped
purpose in many cases now the black
holes typically need to go 1a s over
same thing is true in many cases of
various types of te routes no something
that might be a little bit longer than
what you're really good announce to the
world at large the two things that can
be done here is that the parties that
are next to each other that are
cooperating can just simply configure
something into their system that says
that we're willing to ignore the rpki
answer for this because we've otherwise
done validation
we know that this is a valid origin it's
following the paths for my filters and
I'm willing to accept it because it's a
little bit longer the other thing that
could be done is that maybe provide some
sort of hint into the RO objects
themselves for these narrow scopes of
things that it's okay if you are here
but for your more general case of you're
seeing something much longer and trying
to mitigate an attack I think that's a
much harder problem to solve
okay thank you for coming yep job
Snyder's ntt it is quite tricky to at
this stage of the game fiddle with the
semantics of next length because we're
deploying the snowball is rolling down
the hill and for better or for worse
some things kind of are what they are
what they are right now you identified a
specific case black holing for deaths I
brought up a different approach where we
make black hole route requests rely on
less specific routes which then can be
pumped through the original validation
procedure so it may be that for the
black hole use case we don't need to do
anything insider ops but rather
documents enough away of black hole
routing in grow but if there are other
use cases that may still allow this
conversation to continue but I as you
explain things right now I would remove
black hole because there are I think
more feasible more pragmatic so can i
interject guys we're seriously out of
time it'd be great if you take it on the
list thank you small points of order
meets echo jabber room is not reachable
from my laptop anymore so I cannot at
this moment scribe thank you
did you want this one or the other one
first thank you hi folks I'm Deema from
zds and I'm also working for mr.
open-source project for RP Caroline
party so I'm here to report to the
working group I can say if it was about
the update after this informational
document these things is the working
group last call and during the working
group last call we had got some comments
we got some supports and Allah is out we
also made update accordingly especially
by adding double control to reference
IFC 84 16 which you suggested by leaking
out and making some wording improvements
as such as by oleg komarov ski and then
we made a further update because some
reference to the draft has been
partially of the documents okay at the
present we also believe this document is
ready to move forward and the request
for chess actions so next step I'm ready
for actions and I suggest you owe me the
last call we just sorry notice ask that
you email the list to ask otherwise we
will likely forget or at least I will
likely forget so just email us I'd like
to make last call for this thing please
quick quick thank you
I don't see your other slides on this
that's concerning me because I put them
on there oh wait sorry yeah okay it's
Dima again I like to take this
opportunity to brief implementation of
synchronizing rpki in the cache by
distributing cache data in JSON over
HTTP so before I touch upon the very
topic of my presentation lesson review
the rpki cache deployment scenarios as
discounting obviously attitude when they
are ooh another background for the
following discussions as far as I
comprehend as ARP cache deployments in
arif are describing I see a tattoo one
arrow - concurrently could be made that
a lot older dogs have to set up its own
RPC system to do our PTI data
synchronization and verification and RB
k value than the cash is not necessarily
transported around us but between two
intermediate italo's arranged in a
hierarchical scheme last year as my team
was establishing a third party ERP
system is called our pica-x cloud-based
system I will reassure that the
conclusions that I just made in my last
slide was a reasonable and it's
desirable for us to have a tool to
distribute our PK value data cache to
among different organizations over
network the university disease figure
the architects
implemented ways Avista the open source
software is not in service
our Praveen
cache data to some organizations in
China by distributing cache data in JSON
format over HTTP to our servers
deployment in lead hooks of ISP or
ICPs in China so moving along to this
slide I am now presenting our
consideration of the implementations so
Alif all the way of formatting data we
prefer to facilitate data paths for this
violation and applications other than
router origin validation as well as to
take advantage of slum to do local
control and then we choose HTTP l
transport because it's a widely
supported it is with security
enhancement to offer interpreter
protection and it is independent from
protocol than you need so if you are
already familiar with our C 84 16 slum
you would have finally easy to do RP
cache that update by the virtue of slum
filters and some assertions which are
responsible for deleting and adding
cache data items respectively so that's
a reason why we choose JSON as a format
to be in alignment we're still on fire
for mate in other word will slim file to
describe cache data and it's update so
I'd like to reiterate our motivation to
do these so aren't here either over
there why bother to do these on here I
designed excuse me for preventing RP
cache their cache data for routers so
the RTR PDU is bounded to transport
which is difficult to as some extensions
and some applications well which is not
supported RTR cannot read the binary
data offered by RT r and we will also
like to take the adventure of just you
know why API to do business in
correlation and local control because
the Salam file is in JSON format and so
that's the reason why we'll do these so
here is a desire HTTP header for it's
used in transporting cache data so it's
inevitable for us to have got some had
to be her extension to signal what is
piggyback in a message body so the we
look added we can find inside head that
indicates some control information such
as operating model time stem version
information and a Sigler ship which is
the for integrity production and also
about a inside body which is actually a
slim file so our implementation supports
those push and pull model so in pull
model the HP clients need to indicate
whether it wants who are copy or it just
needs an incremental update so that's a
well this is a most important reason of
why I talked about this I think it's
necessary to do stand eyes our bouquet
manager caches invalidation because sync
relation could take place between
different organizations and the Randi
dedicated reserve receiver match in his
provider so and present we have got a
crafter bodies coming soon and I hope
the well be adopted as a working group
item so by the way I will be also
sharing our implementation code at a
chill hub for you guys who have a give
it a try and I also note the CloudFlare
has a made us similar efforts yet in a
slightly different way anyway we'll keep
an open mind to any inflammation details
and
anyway if any in Hawai I interested in
this walk and can contribute to this
let's work together and I hope it
working group will consider whether this
work is it is of our efforts to seek
deny elation thank you
jeff has I'm confused slightly by the
deployment scenario is this attempting
to populate the catio caches that are
supplying inet router to the routers
themselves no this mechanism is designed
for the the catalyst in correlation
among different administrative
organizations so that's a leaves case so
this does not actually catch the routers
themselves you'll have a nothing to the
way the router thank you we actually
ended up with some other format
intermediate for the payload the
validated payload out of the crypto
system and yes such such such a
standardized interface we actually have
three different validators producing the
same stuff quite certainly has some
advantages for scaling scaling the
feeding of many Reuters and well okay
the validated crypto payload as I would
call it quite obviously has also other
potential very interesting uses so I
have one thing to add up as far as I
observed the implementation of
cauliflower and our our t-rex there are
those pride now is private
implementation well both working very
well but I think the community will
benefit if roms are standardized in the
face so that's the motivation thank you
yeah go for it
Oliver you're up run fast I just want to
interject something in the transfer
presentation and make before break issue
um I forgot to give credit where dude
this issue was raised by Nicki alert I
did not invent it it's Nick hello my
name is Alma Boyett I'm from NIST so
today I'm talking about the draft be
trapeze act like validation signaling
which we proposed either last ITF or the
ITF before give you an update so since
the last time we talked about that we
had Burton group adoption call and which
was successful but had some interesting
discussions the first discussion was
that why would we need in why would we
need a new attribute for that there's
already the attributed RFC 80 97 out
there that signals the orator meditation
and it has a long section for reserved
and we just could basically pick a big
on on the reserved field and at pass
validation to that that would work very
fine because the unverified stayed for
us would have the value 0 and RFC 1897
set sees feared as zero on the sending
side and has to be ignored on the
receiving side so that would give us
some backwards compatibility to anyone
who implemented the 1897 furthermore
after the draft got accepted there came
some discussion about
the validating BG speaker another draft
out there that deals with origin
validation on ebgp and has second part
second focus on the operational modes
that can be configured and they came the
part of why don't we merge all these
work together in one thing so we the
whole thing is a little bit more
organized so then you cup from the e6
and I we had some conversation about
that and said okay the his history
basically this this is two sections of
ebgp as well as the operational part
half of that also applies to what we
want to do and the other half the
operational mode could be taken out as
as a BCP so that was what we decided so
far and maybe some input from the
working group would be would be good
especially in regarding to splitting the
validation BGP speak a draft so and then
the remaining portion in the validating
BGP speaker which would mainly deal with
the operational modes and so force would
be put into a BCP or informational draft
because everything that's written there
is actually pretty good so what does
this mean for B to B's neck validation
signaling we we add some additional
language or a little bit more clarifying
language and regarding to ebgp usage and
clarify error handling so the top part
is currently RFC 1897 there you have the
long block of reserved and at the end we
have the validation state and we update
that by using the second to the last
octet for pass validation and we rename
the
while relations state for you it into
origin validation to clarify which
validation state is in which octet
furthermore we we at the validation
state so a lower part where we have zero
for unverified one for valid and two for
not valid that are the egypt lee sec
states that are defined in at least
develop none sell it as the b2b sex
states defined in AD 8205 we went ahead
and did one further thing we in the 1897
the fields are considered lookup resort
and we renamed that into validation
state because it makes much more sense
you signal the validation states so why
not why not calling it like that so
regarding ebgp signaling RFC eighty
ninety seven actually allows you to be
signaling it has some Contessa birding
of volunteer situations we are two
adjacent guesses under the control of
the same administration for example or
the other example what is as a warrants
iteration is basically side or RPG i
which is the link to the b2b to the
draft what i explained before from which
one was called
validating b2b speaker yeah so we
propose the change in this wording to
say implementations must provide a
configuration mechanism to allow the use
of the community in both sending and
receiving and the implementers should
enable the use for this community on ib
tree on all ibgp sessions and short by
default disabled on ebgp sessions to
make it more clear and yeah
then error-handling currently 1897 is
has an indirect error-handling and
they're mainly deals with if the
attribute occurs more than once in the
BGP update currently it says disregard
all instances except the one with Z
largest integer value and that gives a
little bit problem if we have not two
integer values in there so we say okay
if we have more than one instance then
[Music]
disregard all of them and apply the
strategy similar to the attribute
disregard so now some thought so that's
that's changed what we have right now
and I upload it's a document yesterday
it's just take some time read over it
now current the current path is to
update eighty ninety seven to add these
part but the question is where we had so
much more wording and also we change or
we add other things if it wouldn't make
more sense to obsolete 80 97 rather than
update 1897 I think that's something
that should be discussed another thought
currently the draft is b2b techno b2b
segmentation signaling and we definitely
should rename that in path orientation
and origin validation signaling because
the definitely Dean's know there's all
those posed questions job Snyder's NCT
unfortunately I am not entirely sure
you're heading in the right direction by
merging the allegedly called validating
Beach P speaker draft into this I'm not
sure if you're aware of the extreme
controversy that that draft has
generated and absolutely failed to reach
consensus it is very disappointing
you see it resurfaced yet again well
there are tens of comments unaddressed
and with an ITF process it is not the
best quality of work so I think when you
set out to specify extended communities
to signal bgp SEC validation states that
is a lot about goal but then perhaps you
accidentally stepped into something that
doesn't smell as nice and that may drag
down the effort that you set out to
originally accomplish in other words if
you fade share with a draft that was not
well received it will complicate your
original goal and I I hear what you say
the only part of the merging what we do
here is actually that we take the ebgp
signaling into the BGP section it's a
transfer for me to be sick that actually
makes perfectly sense I want and the
other part which we stay completely
clear of of the whole operational mode
and all this kind of stuff nothing of
that is in this draft at all so maybe if
you if I can research for us I
understand where you're coming from but
the cider ops working group does not get
to redefine what transiti means in bgp
attributes that is outside our scope and
a non-transitive extended community will
not in this working group be redefined
as well it's now subtly transitive and
it is a mistake that's in the eight zero
nine seven draft that it suggested that
or perhaps it could be transitive know
that sentence should never have been
there that's a buck in the draft and you
will meet opposition from implementers
and operators if that part of the church
is spray Pence's
[Music]
so this this is a technical issue
because BGP implementations do not
behave that way putting it in a draft
will will will not help okay so I would
recommend to not proceed with the merch
and and proceed with what you originally
set out to do they will make the chances
of success higher okay thanks John
Scudder two things one is personally I
would take no offense that if you
obsoleted eighty eight ninety seven then
just rolled it in that would be fine
with me
the second thing is on your can you wind
back to your error slide yeah that way
that looks like a downgrade attack to me
because if you pick the numerically
highest one that's sort of the least
desirable validation state and that's
going to be less desirable than the lack
of signaling of any validation state
which is what the bottom box does so
that we can take it to the list but that
doesn't seem like a desirable strategy
to me I think we should bring it to the
list because the only problem is what
what I see currently now we have two
validation state in there and let's say
for example we have fun attributes it
says Origin validation invalid and pass
validation valid and the other one says
pass validation invalid and origin
validation valid so now I know I have
the problem do I start
cherry-picking the values out of them
and takes the highest integer value and
I take information of multiple
attributes what I don't know if this is
the right way to go as well or which one
which one do I know choose - I prefer
origin overpass or path of origin so I
think there's definitely some discussion
needed that that's why I said okay the
easiest way in this regard to deal with
that is if I have these problem what I
have to solve somehow if I say okay if I
shouldn't see more than one
Ennio that I mean that's the first thing
why why would I see more than one
attribute in the in the update so but
yeah 90 bushard in Arcis the reason you
should is careful reading of the BGP
spec says that you also have to check
origin as John Scudder said obsolete in
1897 probably is not at all harmful
there is actually a subsequent RFC blah
blah blah clarifications whose number I
cannot quote which throws away a
significant part of 1897 and because it
was ill-advised 1897 is one of a small
number of RFC's which has my name on it
to which I formerly objected in working
group last call and an ITF last call
Jeff has I own an implementation with a
policy engine that has to look at this
stuff you do not want to put these
things both into the same community the
primary reason for this is there's a lot
of if you flip back to the community
description a lot of people that have
policy out there that is matching
against you know basically a scroll
going go go go go one more thank you
there you go there's an awful lot of
people that have policy that says no
match community for three zero zero
bunch of zeros and then number one two
or three and it is done as an exact
match type thing despite the fact that
no it says reserved most people know if
they're doing something slightly smarter
for match purposes might do regular
expressions regular expressions suck for
performance so a lot of people don't do
that
the consequence here is that if you
overload it you know you don't have a
bunch of zeros in the middle in there
anymore and you'll no longer match the
thing you know you'll basically have
an incomparable number and you'll jump
into the wrong spot year policy code so
your suggestions to keep them separate
yes exactly as we had originally yeah
it's an extra as an extra community it's
not a big deal it'd be nice if engines
that work this way you're a victim of
what I like to call magic extended
communities although the validation
procedures you give is an attempt to
choose one out of many because it's
magic
okay actually if I can quickly into jaga
I was myself contemplating whether we do
this as a separate community or not but
I think Jeffress is a really really good
point and you probably want to take this
out you know that I think I think that's
all very very well good points and I
think there's some discussion that has
to be done on the list and that pretty
much also answers your second question
whether you want to obsolete our
existing RFC or not just leave it as is
dr. Montgomery just a quick question I
guess for John's comment as I'm not sure
I understand the threat scenario that if
you're in a position to somehow on the
wire insert a second one of these
communities aren't you equally in a
position just to strip them all and I'm
not sure the vulnerability that you
don't already have if that's your threat
III only want to respond to that if I'm
not taking away from the rest of the
agenda there's no more agenda last three
minutes all yours okay there we go
so still John Scudder yeah I don't want
to try to defend it as an attack even
though I used that word I guess sort of
putting it in more neutral language the
their handling that was prepared
proposed on that slide is sort of less
stringent than what was it that the
you've changed the semantics you've
changed the semantics to something that
will accept routes that were previously
rejected and that made my knee-jerk you
know if you subsequently analyze the you
know the the case and sort of convinced
me that and you know John even though
we're letting in routes that you were
previously gonna drop on the floor it's
okay hey okay but I think that you know
I think Jeff's comment kind of moods the
whole thing so you know we probably
don't need to to dig into it further so
you're gonna do some more work on this
and okay cream make sure I didn't
misunderstand result all right yes yo I
think just one no oh there were two so
there'll be we'll find it and we been a
question of job Snyder's entity a
question about procedure the draft ITF
cider of validating BGP speaker which is
of course anything will validating did
not reach consensus what is the current
status in the working group
see you in Vancouver no I believe the
end result of it was the author's could
go back to try and make something
sensible out of it or we're not moving
it forward anywhere any further so right
now they weren't group doesn't care
about it it I think is the end result
like it's not part of our game plan so
so should we still consider it's a
working group documents I don't know do
we
oh I can kill it I think it's not on the
list right yeah wait wait wait it is
currently a working group document
because we inherited it from cider and
we therefore it was before that it was
an individual submission so it currently
may be a working group documents which
yeah okay yeah we can take that on the
mailing list yeah that's what I want but
not maybe what the offer sponsor I would
say like a please email the list and say
you said ba ba ba ba ba do we kill this
now or that would help Thank You Jimmy
Cooper bye
[Music]
you