are you ready more or less are you ready
to start or we wait we'll start exactly
on time for minutes or do you want to
start or you know I think most of the
people are here so we will get it going
is that okay yeah so thanks all for
joining during lunch so my name is Wayne
Hendrix and I will be co-presenting with
Bryan and Risa we will do also a piece
of the talk so the goal of this
presentation is mainly to talk about 5g
and the impact on the networking side so
5g is much bigger than what we are going
to talk about in general but we try to
focus on this presentation on mainly the
impact on the networking side of what 5g
is about and that's going to be the main
focus of the talk okay just to introduce
5g because 5g means many things to many
people and I typically the way I try to
explain it if you try to summarize it
you see that it can be summarized in
like three big buckets right one is
actually getting more bandwidth to end
subscribers such that we improve the
band to it get more speeds make sure
that video is consumed much faster onto
the network the second thing is kind of
more connectivity so more IOT more
devices which are getting connected to
the network and the third elephant in
the room is kind of industry 24.0 as we
call it which is introducing new concept
like very low latency ultra reliability
and so on and so forth and that has a
rather dramatic impact on how networks
will be built going forward
okay now if you then look if these are
like applications or like use cases
which are all going to become relevant
for a set of people
the second big aspect what we see is
that the way we are implementing some of
those applications or devices which are
actually consuming or actually
delivering some of these services there
is also a big shift right so we used to
things via physical devices they were
all set together it's an appliance
all-in-one if you look going forward on
what's happening with NFV and
virtualization you see that we started
introducing quite a lot of virtual
machines but in the mean time we talked
about micro services we talked about
containers but we already I some people
are talking about function so it's no
longer something which you can
physically touch right so as a result
you see that in order to define and
build the network around these things
you actually have a very heterogeneous
environment to deal with right so that's
the second big thing to take into
account and then of course people want
to introduce things faster wants to make
sure that things happen much more
quickly that it's much more agile and
that's we come into the realm of
programmability automation intent-based
networking and so on and so forth so we
want to make sure that I some of these
services get more I delivered more
quickly like basically the big guys or
the the big web guys are doing is the
introduced services much more quickly
and much more faster into the network
and make sure that I things get consumed
way faster than we used to see a going
forward right if you put this all
together
and trying to build let's say a
framework or an architecture around this
it's kind of a big thing right because
you see that there is lots of changes
lots of things are happening and what we
try to do with it okay I say okay if you
look at all of this environment how do
we deal with all of that right and I
think this is where I template I think
they built important concept from the
early days and and if you look at it we
actually in order to build like a
network infrastructure to support all of
this we believe that is two key
principles which are important to keep
in the back of our minds switch off the
Wi-Fi is that in order to provision
these things in that heterogeneous space
it's important to basically provision it
at the edge and leave the core or the
elements in the middle untouched right
so we always say okay introduce the
service at the edge
and try to build make sure that the the
the elements in the middle are not
touched when you provision new services
right and as a result you actually get a
more easy way of introducing things the
second important thing is actually its
decoupling service from Transport
because that allows us to actually focus
on a certain set of use cases in order
to not boil the ocean and and try to
make sure that we actually do things in
a very easy and and and more agile way
now
if we and and in this presentation when
I talk about on edge I talked about
mainly the data playing I also to a
certain extent or a control plane of the
a router or a device a forwarding device
right so sometimes in 5g we talk about
far edge which is a cloud infrastructure
or an edge which is a cloud
infrastructure here I'm talking about an
edge which is more mainly the data plane
or the control plane aspect of the thing
which is delivering the network right
and as I said from the beginning is that
you see that those workloads are
evolving so we see containerization and
stuff like that so you see that the edge
implementation in a 5g or in a network
going forward it's know something which
you can touch necessarily right so we
have I here are some examples like
physical devices we used to have edge
routers right which are routers built-in
chesties or in pizza boxes you see going
forward that some of these
implementations would happen on the data
center switch which is acting as a
top-of-rack type of thing or you
actually do it on a peering type of
device but an edge can also be like a
virtual thing or in a micro services
architecture it can be like a user brain
function sitting on a server it can be a
virtual switch implemented on a server
or it can actually also be like virtual
switch implemented on a nikkie going
forward so you see that the environment
which we are having available to us in
order to connect all of these things
together is a big I there's there's
quite a lot of variety right the second
big question is and here is there is
Automation is it's where is the X right
we used to build the H in a fairly
central matter but you see that with
this ultra-low latency and this is of
course a use case and given that we are
a finished company we have to have a
finished example you see that if you
distribute the application closer to the
user without distributing the edge you
actually don't achieve anything you
actually introduce bigger latency right
so you see is that the edge itself will
vary depending on the use case as well
so it's no longer something which is
fairly central in a typical deployment
it is something which will be
distributed much deeper into the network
than we used to see right and in some
cases it's even such that it will be
distributed up until the enterprise or
up until the the the site where the
application sits or it can even be
within the enterprise or within a very
close to the to the end consumer now if
you look at the typical network and this
is what the talk is all about so
typically we segment I networks but and
and this is mainly a service provider or
an access provider type of use case use
you segment the network from I typically
access aggregation core and then you
have like I central data centers which
can be let's say
localized data center or private clouds
but you can also see that some people
move to public cloud type of
infrastructure so it can actually be a
very heterogeneous environment plus you
see that going forward you see those
edge clouds also appearing so if you
look there you see that there is much
more distributed clouds and those are
not like a typical data center going for
but they are actually like very small
contained type of server environments
which can be deployed either on Prem or
somewhere deeper into the network than
we used to see right now if you then
make a connotation of where the edge is
you actually see that it's all it's
spread all over the place right and in
order to build a network which is
delivering let's say kpi's
and delivering services and to end with
ultra-low latency but also reliability
where you have to do diverse parts into
the network in order to deliver such a
service or optimize for latency or
optimize for bandwidth or optimize for
whatever type of capability you see that
this is actually a very difficult space
to deal with right so as such if you
look at this in nokia we call this an
fix or so we rebuild a framework around
this in order to build such an
environment and build let's say that
infrastructure in a way that is that is
supporting such a heterogeneous
environment right so when we call this
NFI X which is standing for network
function interconnection because we are
dealing with interconnecting functions
either distributed or central but also
to connect them in a way that you can
connect them to devices which are either
physical elements but also virtual
elements containers or functions right
so it doesn't really matter what it is
about it's basically we want to connect
things seamlessly together but deliver
kpi's and as elise right and if you look
when I change the picture from this to
this what we try to do is build these
boundaries which you typically have that
because if you if you see service
providers building network so they
typically have difficult themes for
aggregation different themes for core
and so on what we try to do here is
build the seamless interconnection
between all of these environments in
order to give that seamless connectivity
between all of these different workloads
right because we will talk about slicing
going forwards right
if you segment all of these things
independently together giving you a
single API to actually connect all of
these workloads together in a very
distributed or very centralized way is
becoming very difficult okay now how
does it build and we are not going to go
to a lot of detail given we only have 45
minutes but actually this is built all
around ITF based definition
which are actually here right so first
of all the way we we look at this as we
use like multi-protocol BGP for a data
plane so we have either a VPN or IP VPN
so we can do both IP or layer 2 or layer
3 services we can we would introduce
segment routing for this and which
flavor depends on the choice of the
operator so this will work with either
an MPLS flavor either supporting over
native and pillars or with IP or with as
our v6 right so and whatever flavor
comes available to us is actually
capable to be working in that framework
we use p7 as a fee to actually make sure
that we have capabilities to define as a
lays and KPIs depending on the use cases
which will be supported there is service
chaining capabilities inside which are
done via D as a C working group and then
of course given that we want to have
this programmable environment we use all
around the yang data model and we use
telemetry to get information from
different devices in order to do like
intent-based networking and go
closed-loop automation so in a nutshell
before I give it to Brian what we are
trying to achieve with NF IX is building
this fabric across those different
boundaries like aggregation core or
whatever workload we see and give you a
single API and the goal of this is to
give the same experience what you get
today when you go on to like a Google or
an AWS or a Microsoft or Alibaba where
you basically have a set of api's you
define your requirements for your
applications and those gets instantiated
into the network and give you a seamless
experience using certain as a lace kpi's
which are relevant for that particular
service all right so this is kind of
giving you a bit of a space how we see
any Vikes and what it I what is a key
enabler going forward to build this very
heterogeneous environment in in the
future
all right thanks a lot wim I'm going to
take a step back now and see what we're
actually trying to all service providers
are actually trying to achieve with 5g
from a business driver perspective so
one of the key things is that 5g is
meant to enable a whole bunch of new
revenue lines although we'd like to
focus on more the technology piece here
in ITF this is really the key focus so
when you look towards how that could be
done or where those business drivers are
coming from you can look to some of
these things on the slide here so for
example there's a huge amount of promise
in things such as smart cities
eHealth consumer experience with
augmented reality and virtual reality
public safety applications connected
vehicles and critical automation and
service providers ultimately want to
play a role in the space because
ultimately all of these spaces are being
increasingly digitized a huge
proliferation of devices in each of
these applications and so this is a
great market for service providers to
expand into from a pure technology
perspective ultimately we're talking
about all the different IOT devices here
all the different connected devices
this can be ultimately made a huge
amount of additional endpoints but it's
also driving additional bandwidth and
some of these have very particular
latency requirements so there's things
happening in the radio network to
actually support those particular SLA s
and so if you use the spectrum in a
certain way you use the radio access in
a certain way you can achieve low
latency or higher bandwidth but this
same case set of capabilities ultimately
needs to be extended across the
transport network to deliver the
end-to-end SLA s that each of these
different business drivers requires so
while we're in this particular
presentation we're not focusing so much
on the radio access I want to spend some
time to think about how we can actually
support those different and distinct SLA
s across of a shared transport
infrastructure just to give one
particular example there so I mentioned
a bunch of industry vertical
applications this is just one to
illustrate it
port is a huge and increasingly complex
environment if you look forward to 2025
for example just looking at some of our
kind of lead use cases here you see over
18,000 oh sorry 18 million containers
going through these ports or a given
port per year
you have several 10k trucks moving
around the environment you have these
environments spanning across tens of
thousands of hectares so a very large
geographical space and ultimately they
want to bring an enormous amount of
technology into these ports to increase
the level of automation and to increase
the order efficiency through these ports
so what could this mean this is you know
broadband connectivity for ship-to-shore
you were actually at the port to the
ship
video surveillance all across the port
itself asset tracking of every
individual can train er
a container so we can actually see its
process and its journey off of the ship
through the container you need to have
low latency video feeds from key points
of the site in the future they want to
have things such as augmented reality
and virtual reality based maintenance of
the different aspects of the site so
they can pull in guys remotely they
don't necessarily have to pull drive
people to every different aspect of a
site we expect to have drones flying
around the site to inspect different
parts of the facility you have
autonomous vehicles moving about all of
these require connectivity and there's a
very high value asset and then also
there are people moving about the site
so we need to know their exact location
and we need to be able to feed all the
necessary information to them so this is
just one particular example you see
there are a couple of ways that this
could be deployed it could be a private
5g environment but the service providers
also look towards this as being
potentially something that could be
offered as a network slice or multiple
network slices off of their
infrastructure as well so
just just one illustration here to show
the the kind of breadth of connectivity
required to support such an application
or such a use case so when we look
towards how we can actually deliver
assure these SLA s across a transport
network we look towards this kind of
closed-loop automation model inside
Nokia we refer to this as insight driven
automation ultimately what is this this
is the ability for for you actually to
automate the instantiation of services
in your network so whim spoke about this
kind of edge to edge provisioning and
then the ability to have kind of network
or application based optimization we
want to have a smart IP fabric this is
really based upon having you know
segment routing based capabilities and
model driven telemetry to be able to
program an extract state from the
program configuration and extract state
from this environment and then on top of
that data that were harvesting from the
network we want to be able to run data
analytics and we see this closed-loop
automation as being really critical
because it's not just about provisioning
a service in such a way that it
satisfies an SLA in one moment in time
it's really about ensuring that SLA is
met throughout the entire lifecycle of
the service or entire lifecycle of the
application so this is a continual
process it's actually running so we can
actually continue to reoptimize some
react based on the latest state of the
network so just a couple of examples of
this so wim spoke before about the edge
to edge connectivity this is one
particular example here we show
connectivity being created between two
data center environments for 4-5 GS so
this is a connectivity between virtual
RAM and virtual core we can build this
up because you know we we can actually
harvest and extract topology information
from the network using things like BGP
LS we know about end points within a BGP
based data center using things like BGP
lu and from a controller perspective we
can actually pull together
at apology view across each of these
distinct and disparate domains and
between those two end points in this
example actually create a traffic
engineered segment erotic tunnel to
enable that productivity so again just
that edge to edge provisioning and kind
of tunneling within so additionally if
there is a if there's a topology change
there we can react to that using the
controller we are doing this in such a
way it's actually going to meet the the
different SLA constraints of the service
right so if you want to have diversity
path diversity between these two
endpoints and that's possible or if we
move towards the next example you want
to move to something a little bit more
complex in this case the SLA
characteristic that we optimize around
will be latency so in this particular
case for example we stay on the red path
initially but if there was something
like an underlying change in the optical
topology maybe your optical transport
network had a reroute then we observed
that the latency changes because we
harvest that information and enrich in
response to that we're going to re
optimize the path from a controller
perspective so this is the type of like
closed loop automation I'm referring to
so such that we can actually continue to
support these SLA s for these different
services throughout their entire
lifecycle and at the outcome of this we
have this we have this in fix fabric
that wim described we have a controller
that's actually enabling and securing
SLA bound services on top of it which
gives us an ability to start to satisfy
these networks licensing requirements
for each of those different applications
and kind of business drivers that I
mentioned at the start and now I'm going
to hand over to Reza who's going to talk
a little bit more from an API
perspective in network slicing hello
everyone it's a good point to go to the
networking I think so far we discussed
how we can create a network which is
consumable without by
Brian mentioned what is the
characteristic of that fabric what are
the use cases and for the last portion
I'm going to tie this together with how
this relates to network slicing how it
relates to us or ATF and how basically
that we can use this logic to create
Network a slicing going forward I start
with an example to make sure that at
least we are on the same page let's say
I have an operator which has transport
it has on the left side is group of
tenants or customers
it has Public Safety Fiat and BMW these
are the customers and on the right hand
side there are a group of application
servers when we talk about end-to-end
network its loss basically we are
referring to the logically isolated
independent Network from left to right
in this example for a take their last
the public safety video surveillance
CCTV we are creating an independent
network from left to the right each of
this network is slices there are various
colors you can think of color as the SLA
of that network a slice for example for
the video surveillance most likely that
the SLA will be the bandwidth 10 Meg or
better for the network a slice green
which is infotainment most likely again
for the customer BMW for the service
infotainment the SLA is 10 Meg for the
blue autonomous driving the SLA most
likely is the latency 5 millisecond or
better so the idea here is we are
creating a group of logically
independent networks from left to right
and this is very important when we talk
about the context and when we are using
in this case for example in the left
side could be your handset could be your
i/o are your tea devices could
your infotainment in the car could be
your gaming console and on the right
side is the application that basically
serves to create each of these and to a
network a slice again I go back to the
last one which the CCTV for the customer
Public Safety let's say I want to create
as an operator I want to create this
into a network a slice what is needed to
be done in the network from very high
level we have to create ran a slice the
meaning of the rangas Ronnie's life
means simply I'm going to create a
context or a personality in my ran
equipment to understand blue green red
Network a slice if I go to my ran I will
see the resources in a practical way it
means a allocation of the radio
interface a scheduling policy profiles
these are basically allocated for each
of these colors by the same token if I
go to my 5g core I'm going to create a
personality or context for each of these
n 2n networking slices now I created ran
I created core now I have to do the
connectivity between them and here the
transport a slice come to the picture
basically transfer a slice is a group of
connectivity with a specific SLA slash
SLO and this is very important to
understand the difference between they
determine ology sometimes this
terminology the is important to be very
clear each of this domain has one
controller but I've run controller I
have transfer controller core controller
and at the very top there is an end to
an Orchestrator as the name suggests
Orchestrator is basically orchestrating
a group of actions a group of logic that
should be incremented in the network the
term a slice here transferred the slice
or ran a slice or chorus slice sometimes
it's called for example transport
transport sub a slice or try
for a slight subnet all are basically
exactly the same different terminology
for one thing there are few observation
from this high-level picture which to me
is very important first end-to-end
network a slice is different from
transfer a slice in the picture is very
clear that a transfer a slice is a
portion of an end-to-end context this is
the first observation the second
observation here is an end to a network
a slice again I pick on the last one
that dark grey enter a network as wise
can have one or more than one transfer a
slice meaning I can have a group of
connections and that one is more than
one so we want to make another
observation here is an end-to-end
network a slice depends on the
application here we are talking about 5g
but this concept is well-suited for
other type of application for a slicing
for example if operator wants to share
the networks or we want to do the DC
interconnect I'm referring to 5g here as
a prime example but keep in mind that
this logic that discussion could be
well-suited for all other applications
so I referring to the last word another
observation about the number the an end
to a network a slice can have other
slices here when you say coton called
other in this picture with other I mean
ran and core for the other application
that might be different so in a summary
and Antoinette regrets Lars has won on
many transfer slices it might have other
slices in the 5g that other a slice
means run and call and the important
aspect here is the only context for the
entrant is at the very top any other
context that you see here they are not
into it
I cannot expect transfer to be an to I
ran to the entrant or core to be into it
so this is basically the important
aspect if I give you an example a
practical example of how this one might
work
let's say for the last video
surveillance let's say Singapore Public
Safety come to sink tile and say I want
to connect all the three TV cameras
inside the city and inside the buses
together it common as sintel to create
an end-to-end logical network for that a
specific application SingTel take that
request basically goes to the RAM
controller create the context for the
rant it should know exactly how many
Roenick admit you know it wants because
it know that how big the city is whether
or not we should create visual Network
function on the ran or not this is the
decision that the RAM controller make at
that point also for the core it goes
that do I need to create a core how many
core I should be created when I said
could miss 5g code do I need to create
any visual Network function for that all
decision will be made by the correct
controller and at the end when the core
and ran are created the transfer will be
connected and end to a network a slice
for the Singapore public safety will be
created will be exposed to that customer
and add there is a at the end that a
slice can be used the last observation
in this picture is a tenant or customer
can have more than one end-to-end
Network espresso you will see BMW has
the tree of them it is possible to do
and these three for a single customer
are completely independent and isolated
and this is basically that the summary
of this slide from the management and
control what do we need to do we
establish the fact that we need n to an
Orchestrator and various controllers
there is an Orchestrator sitting at the
top again depends on the application if
it is not 5g is other that could be
higher system other higher controller
but in this context we have end-to-end
there Orchestrator what does it do it
does three same three jobs automation
monitoring and optimization of the
end-to-end network effects
these are very important aspect because
in most cases we tend to talk about only
the first one we talk about automation
how to create it everything related to
that but at the same time we have to be
really conscious about talking about
monitoring assurance analytic and
closed-loop optimization so the
controller or Orchestrator in this case
in to analyze Network as West controller
performing these three jobs at the same
time it talks to left right and middle
controller ran core transfer controller
to basically achieve the end-to-end is
created for their specific networks lies
the important aspect again here is the
top level it doesn't know that much
about the detail of the network it knows
about the abstraction of the net for
some level of knowledge of the network
but it really delegate all the
intelligence and everything to either of
those controller it doesn't know how
rent is created or what are the
equivalent in the ran or the transfer or
core it just know that how to delegate
all those component at the same time
each of this controller again doing
three things independently automation
monitoring and optimization and if when
it comes to us the middle box transfer
its rise controller is basically
addressing automation of the transferor
slicers monitoring and assurance of the
transferor slices and closed loop closed
loop optimization and these are
happening independently and this is
basically that concept of the delegation
of the responsibility from Orchestrator
each of the controllers you do your job
if something happened try to resolve it
to controller it transport controller
for example which says you create this
connectivity and it doesn't impact the
important aspect here is when
Orchestrator that we just go to the next
was the interfaces that we have the 3gpp
on the left and right in the middle
there is no standard define that
interface we have recently form a new
design team in his working group I'm not
encouraging you to go and take a look
the material that we have their mandate
and the vision that we have that
interface and everything around that
transfer is voice controller and
everything where the logic for the the
receiving the request there and
fulfilling that request is basically
will be addressed one way or another by
that design team is real recently they
have the meeting and not everything is
finalized but this is that my opinion
the right direction that we go coming
back to that interface that I put idea
that interface is abstract that
interface doesn't tell from Orchestrator
to controller go and create a transfer
its life and use RSVP for that tunnel
and use l3 VPN it says just connect
endpoint one two three and as we
mentioned Connect age 1 2 3 2 H 4 & 5 my
SLA is 10 Meg and I want to have a full
secure Network for example that
interface is defining the connectivity
this way transfer us wise controller
receives that is that for the automation
part I have to do something and
basically for monitoring and
optimization I will talk about that in
the next slide but longer story short in
this case we have an Orchestrator
sitting at the top and controllers and
I'm encouraging you to think about I
will give your answer as we go you might
think how the hierarchical controller or
whatever we do at ITF you know fits here
think about it we will get back to the
question in a moment early but I just
want to make sure that at least I
started with the one question that when
we finished we have the answer for that
now I remove everything from this slide
I just keep the transferor ice
controller and every the interface on
top this is the picture that we have if
it comes this is the picture I have
transfer of ice controller in the middle
everything else is removed from that
picture I have a higher system again I
try to be generalizing the concept I
have a higher system in 5g we call it
into a network of ice Orchestrator the
higher system sends a request number one
to create the connectivity again
connectivity in this context
means connect age 1 2 3 2 H 4 and 5 with
SLO 10 Meg or better we again this is
the second question that interface
should not only have this information
but some information about the request
which is correct for example in the
previous example for this the single
public safe there's a customer that
interface one has information about who
is the customer what is the service
services CCTV customer is Singapore
Public Safety and some other information
about that end to a network a slice this
is a second question we don't really
need this information for automation why
we need that one I try to get back to
you at the very end so number one we
receive a request the transfer a slice
controller intelligently is going to
realize that one in the network and this
is basically the whole idea of
connecting this discussion to whatever
Beaman Brian mentioned 10 minutes ago we
receive the request we are going to
realize that in the net for realization
means depends on the network that I have
if it is much lower or pond or optic or
IP the way that I'm creating this or I'm
realizing this connectivity that
transfer a slice it's different but at
the very end number 1 doesn't change if
I implement this connectivity on top of
mantra wave or Path number one is do the
connectivity between h1 h2 h3 2 H 4 & 5
so number 2 basically tie together the
concept that we discussed so far weed
matting the request to any service
tunnel path and fix will be one of those
that we can use and basically number
three we realize that one in the network
depends how we want to do it we are
using that network as the consumable the
resource and we basically we are reusing
the API to create a connectivity I ask
you two questions the first question was
the what why we need some other
information when I want to create a
number one
it should have in addition to endpoints
and SLA and SLO it should have some
other information the answer to that one
is number four in addition to creation
or automation we need to do the
assurance we need to do the monitoring
and close for those we need to have some
information that how this transfers was
basically the connect to the end to a
network a slice which customer is
requesting for that from that aspect you
know using this information basically
helping us to do that the assurance and
the monitoring and optimization of the
transfer slices if I'd recap whatever
you put here we have at the bottom we
have a consumable network resource now
the application that we built on top
basically is going to use that resources
and basically this is the way that we
see the IETF can fit here
number three is exactly whatever IETF
has lots of history on that and doing
number one and two and number four is
basically leveraging everything that is
already here and another question that
might be relevant here sometimes there's
a there's some question of how we do the
for example surface slicing versus how
the fly see how we can make sure the
resources is in the network all is
related to number three the realization
do we need any specific new protocol or
technology to achieve number three at
this point the most likely answer is
NIST is no but as we go forward this is
basically one of the items that we can
think and we can you know address going
forward
so this is end of the presentation for
us I give the stage to we to basically
wrap it up and we have I guess 10 15
minutes to go through a question and
answer thank you very much
yeah to concludes basically I think you
try to see a little bit how we as Nokia
see this world and how networks need to
be built or what are the different
capabilities we need to have in order to
support like 5g type of use cases so and
fix in our viewers is a key building
block or is a key enabler to actually
give you that ubiquitous connectivity
between all of these heterogeneous
workloads which we actually have to deal
with right
and it's actually spans connectivity
across core access I distributed things
because what we are trying to do is
build kind of a fabric to make that
consumption very easy right and do that
in a way that we achieve that where you
can deliver actually as a race and kpi's
and sometimes I refer to an fix as kind
of what as the one tries to do I for
those people familiar with as the one is
trying to do this ubiquitous over the
Internet over the overlay under any
transport but we are trying to do here
is what if you own an infrastructure and
you want to build certain KPIs and
deliver ubiquitous services across those
heterogeneous environment that is what
we are trying to achieve within fix all
right the third bullet which I which I'm
saying is that it's built on all ITF
standards which are actually happening
here the challenge which we have
sometimes it's actually people I don't
really know which pieces fit together
right so we decided that we are going to
write a draft it will be an
informational draft so if people are
interested in contributing I would
welcome them so please contact us after
this talk or something like that because
I think it's important that it's
sometimes I important that we fit the
pieces together because we are using
many building blocks which are built
here right so we're using things from
bears we are using things from spraying
we're using things from net mod with all
the yang definition models which are
delivered or being built in different
working groups neat I need to be
consumed together so we use pieces we
use I so that is different components
from different working groups which we
are leveraging
in order to build this framework right
but none of this is actually very
propriety or very standard so it works
with multi-vendor and actually we have
implementations today in live customers
where we are actually doing this using
those building blocks and then the
second bullet which is here is that in
order to deliver this whole environment
we need to come to a framework where the
network's are consumable through an API
is how I say it right and I always make
the reflection towards what the public
lies proud so guys are doing today if
you see how easy it is consumable their
networks is consumable this is where we
should go towards right so we should
basically with a few point and clicks be
able to instantiate those capabilities
which are your customers demanding and
doing that in a seamless way over that
heterogeneous environment and this is
kind of how we see the implications of
5g and how networks should be built or
the capabilities that should be
delivered going forward to achieve and
to deliver those type of use cases with
that I think we are almost on time and I
don't know whether we have time for
questions or not but we are happy to
have some questions if there are some in
the room but I don't know how it will
work because we don't have mics are
there any questions or hello Cass DP and
CSA so my question is about the join up
between your use cases and what you're
sort of needing from this community and
how do you get a full range of telco
operator requirements into this
community and do you think that the join
up is currently working so what I so the
way we I said the question is is about
how we get requires from operators and
in this community so right so what we do
i from a Nokia point of view is all the
different requirements we get from
operators we try to so that's how we
contribute to draft an IETF and so if we
see that there are third
missing pieces like Raisa mentioned for
transport slicing we believe that is a
missing piece for a service abstraction
to give you that slice and transport
slice controller we build a contribution
into the various working group in order
to contribute and make sure that we
built this open framework to support
this type of thing so basically the
requirements which we see from customers
we bring back to IDF and we try to
contribute and try to make those things
adoptable or change depending on the use
or how IDF sees this adopt based on the
the feedback of the working group here
okay I saw on the slide about how these
slices let you do more than one thing at
the same time on the network or
different comes like Fiat and BMW could
both use the same network and what I'm
struck by is already when I'm at home I
can watch Netflix while at the same time
my Tesla's doing a firmware update
because I have an internet connection I
didn't see any mention of the Internet
in this presentation is this a totally
new thing to replace the Internet No so
this is actually I saw ok so this is a
good good question actually if the
Internet is good enough for that service
we use the internet as a so we use
basically the Internet connectivity
right so it's only when you have
specific requirements which cannot be
met or which are like certain latency
requirements and stuff like that on your
service delivered on X wires that you
actually do or change things so we have
the capability to influence based on
your needs of that specific use case but
if the Internet is good enough there
will be Internet connectivity used for
that particular service so in your
ignorance one of the slides you showed
the round slice and transport slice and
the cost slice yes then you said
essentially the leftmost either ends or
mostly from 3gpp 3G does the run slice
and da and that may be on the core side
then the transport slice you said IDF
can stand I start what exactly IDF can
sterilized is it just the provisioning
of the slice or what
what is the standardization that's left
here whatever we plan to do idea if it's
I encourage you to take a look at their
outcome and the result that we have on
their teaser in troupe for the network
is slicing in the summaries we do want
to first of all define transversal eyes
what is the consensus the definition of
that how it relates to network a slice
this is the first thing the second one
is study a framework to make sure that
we know all the component that we have
to do whether or not there should be a
for example a new NB i to be build this
could be one of the outcome of that
discussion and last but not least to
their address the mapping that I
mentioned if I wanna map that abstract
interface to a specific technology we
are going to have a few use cases and we
basically they show how the mapping
might work in the real world so these
are the the tree the most important
aspect that we want to cover there as we
go forward definitely we need a
contribution from everybody and whether
or not there are some other thing needed
to be done it this is for the future but
at this time we wanted to make sure we
are really focused on couple of saying
we are not basically boiling the ocean
at the same time how relevant that work
is to ITF is a prime the example of
whatever we do and it's very important
to consider that mmm maybe a follow-up
question so when you create a transport
slice what are the parameters that let's
say Phi G system will daily give it to
the transport so let's say you are a
let's see what will be the parameters
I'm just curious
at the high level again this is
something I don't want it is something
that we didn't haven't decided in the
design team but as a general concept the
input that you receive here I want to
connect H 1 2 3 2 H 4 & 5 so a group of
edge that should be connected the SLA an
SLO for that connectivity is what
is the objective that you want to raise
is the latency reliability security and
so on so forth
and some other data which is the use
case dependent in the 5g for example I
mentioned some other information that
helps us not only for automation but for
the other assurance and other aspect is
how this relates to the end-to-end
network a slice which customer is a
single what service is that so these are
very high-level
the detail of that obviously we have to
go through it to make sure that we are
addressing it in a very logical way and
whether or not we need to add other
attributed A's or you know remove it
this is the we have to go through the
process okay thank you okay no problem
okay this is a important from SK key you
so a very nice talk I have a one
question one comment
so you basically you propose intended
based and that talking will be useful
for our net optimizing is it correct yes
so basically you can see a high-level
some policy service level will be
translated into metal label or device
Allegra right so I believe it one of our
core functions is translation so are you
considering how to translate sub
survival policy into low-level policy
are you considering or are you working
for that what is your question how do
you translate policy from between
different devices or so which means it
you know the high level service of level
yes agreement why kind of subjective
level of policy I can def of you if you
look what Raisa was was talking about
actually is an abstracted view right but
you typically see today unfortunately I
redid a lot of work in ITF with respect
to data model standardization but you do
see is that the vendors have not all
implemented that uniformly yet right so
what you need to do is basically even if
we say about intent based networking
what you stiff typically still see is
that you need a device model which is
specific for a specific vendor so as
such what we are doing is we
like these abstract service models which
are being defined like for example even
in IDF EF l2 as an all 3sm being defined
alright as a service model but what you
see is if you have to implement that to
the specific device you sometimes need a
translation layer so we have like device
abstraction capabilities which are
actually mediating towards a specific
device implementing that particular use
case in order to translate for the
specific models which that device
actually has implemented and but so we
have this that is a abstract service
layer and then there is a device type of
model which is actually then implemented
into the device depending on the
capabilities that device has enabled
then maybe women just add I mean that
actually only needs to exist on the edge
itself as we mentioned there so it's
beyond that everything in between is
about how you can assure the the well
the abstract SLA that gets translated
into something meaningful for the
network how you can ensure that in a
closely collimation opener yeah
basically the IDF developer many young
the era models high-level and low-level
the problem is the link to each other
the translation is missing line now so
many people constantly working with it
basically the I to and i7 data security
a function working alone about a member
so we are basically implemented the
policy translator to link high-level
policy into low level so I believe
Network slicing case I think we can
elaborate the previous our work I mean
if there are missing pieces which you
believe need Standardization I think we
are happy to come talk and then see how
we can the other our question is a some
a collaboration with the other standard
apart for example the I to honest F we
are facing the problem is we are using
in security NATO spirit function with
the Sdn for example the problem is ITF
I to an ACEF and Sdn the interface
should be specified the problem is how
to collaborate with other area standard
body so your cases the 3gpp
and airier some standardization and I'd
have some the station has something
called collaborated right so there is my
some actually how to collaborate we are
we're probably running out of time here
but we can take this offline to see what
needs to happen okay thank you thank you
very much we have to stop okay sorry
[Applause]