dang okay yes there we go
so hopefully people can now hear us I
will kind of wait until someone says
they can hear us
hopefully someone could message me and
say that that would be nice also there's
like a 15-second delay however in the
meantime we are very comfy are we very
comfy comfy ready for the joys of comfy
con Oh Eleanor disabled if it's not
meant to be no we are chats permanently
disabled because we like everyone to be
able to another yeah so last time we did
this slack was the the single place
where you can chat this time it's
discord
so I guess welcome everyone if you can
hear me I hope you can yes hundred okay
walk me run to what is a completely
unplanned founder's Q&A session for
comfy con Australia 2020 2021 whichever
year summer 2020 so we're gonna so for
those who don't know we've decided you
know stupidity / eagerness that we're
gonna run this again in yes honey
November 28th to 29th so that's about
five six months away and we thought it
would be good idea to have a nice little
session where people could ask questions
and they could get to know us / ask
questions about the conference so if you
have any questions please write them to
us on Twitter to outcome from Connie you
if you or use the disco channel cybers
events because that's the ones we're
gonna choose hello Yoda you're gonna
come and say hello we have a number of
guests today as well so Yoda and Lulu
are here so
should we start with some of the
questions that were already asked on
Twitter would you do you want to do
questions or do you want to just talk
about what we're gonna do next time are
there any questions that relate to what
we're doing next time
no not thus far that I can say all right
well do you want to give you a little
what we're doing next time it sure I
will I will talk randomly about what
we're gonna do next time so 2020
summarization okay can we have a dog oh
screen can you see the dog oh you're
here is one daughter who doesn't quite
like me because I have a bit or are you
saying 2020 so there is a dog oh yes so
there will be a popper stream set up for
the conference like cheering comfy Khan
which we'll be keeping an eye on one of
our new mascots these two already some
of our mascots but there will be another
one to be announced later know whenever
every popper is a mascot we do also
accept cat mascots mascots
yes we do think you had a chicken last
time as well then make somebody send in
photos are the chickens come back on
I'll just tell you then Lulu come on
summer edition is gonna be exactly the
same as last time it's gonna be the same
time frame so from 12 p.m. ASP credit 8
p.m. EST on the 28th yes and we doing
Saturday in Sunday because the Friday is
not a public horror the conference will
be the same last time you'll have
speakers from all over throwing new
zealand's she looks like she wants to
jump on your lap so many distractions
[Music]
court papers opens 10 20 30 minute talks
we're also accepting we're going to do a
separate workshop screen this year which
is the 30 60 90 or 120 minute long
workshops will also do registration for
those to keep them relatively small so
that workshop people can actually
interact directly with the speaker and
the attendees yes so some examples that
people have been talking about
previously is things like how to begin
programming in rust or how to begin
working with encryption which I think
there's some people who've been asking
for the workshops could be like George's
PI the Raspberry Pi what was it the
printer got you um how do you make the
pin Agassi um basically we're very much
open to any sort of form again in
relation to
[Music]
okay that's fine now it's fixed it's
fixed it's fixed mic is muted yes the
dog is we were having fun too many
dollars which I can't remember that's it
papers workshops cyber or cyber adjacent
so we're really keen to have talks that
are on things like mental health and
recruitment and all those kind of things
like same as last time we've already got
about five to ten papers so far which is
really good but also we're keen to have
the workshops and those things as well
so beginner's guide to ex intermediates
guide to why you know it will probably
be groups of I don't know 20 up to 20 to
30 people working with a single speaker
over a period of time and then they'll
work on that the other thing we're gonna
have this year and they're gonna hate me
for mentioning their names so Benzies
and civilize will also be working on
managing a CTF so the idea is that come
pick on will have caps of fight
competition the way it will be arranged
is we want to make sure that people
don't spend all night working on the
capture the flag because obviously one
of the things we encourages everyone to
go off and do their own thing and get
away from the computer we're still
working it how we're going to do that
but the idea is we're going to get a lot
of challenges put them up people will go
through those challenges and hopefully
we'll have some prizes at the end from
some people as well
brings up an interesting a good point we
are sticking with the idea of no
sponsors for the main conference string
we may consider asking for sponsorship
for prizes but if that happens what
we'll do is the sponsors will send the
prizes directly to the winners and we'll
stay out of the whole situation
essentially we will do match for summer
yeah 2020 Oh get to that hoping that
you'll be able to order it and receive
it before the conference starts unlike
unlike last time bingo bingo is gonna be
a lot of fun I'm really looking forward
to bingo
we're gonna have a few questions in
there which will be easy
yeah we'll have some easy questions and
some harder one so we'll base some of
the bingo questions on the talks and the
people doing those talks and what we
know about them and some other random
things and wipe some prizes with bingo
as well so we'll have a little bit more
to do during the breaks between talks as
well although I think like poppers went
down a lot like fur babies went down
well last it will do fur babies again
yeah definitely we may see if you can
tell the difference between a wallaby in
a kangaroo and a pelican and a bean
chicken so story behind that is we were
driving down the highway today and we
saw something again on the edge of the
road wasn't great I'm like is that a
wallaby or a wombat I know you said is
that a wallaby or a kangaroo it looks
like a hairy Pig yes so again apparently
I can't recognize Australian native
animals which is a bit of a problem
I know some zoologist we could get in
for that game that would be good yeah my
dad's a zoologist if we really need one
yeah we may need a trigger warning on
that segment yes can you can you name
this red kill okay we will go through oh
you have than that okay sorry you asked
yourself what the secret luscious be I
have no idea why you would say that's me
isn't some guy called icd he's real
active in the chats like real active on
that oh that's Sylvia so what is
the secret to a luscious be the secret
to a luscious spirit is just be lazy and
let it grow out pretty much that's it
like I've been grinding this since what
last you know it's it's it's my secret
it's it's the way you're doing in mind
your secret is good genetics good
genetics yes
obviously one from Ben Ben I'm not
answering that question
I'm here for that question
Ben and I have some very good okay next
question
what do you miss most about conferences
and what do you miss the least Jenna I
miss the most is definitely the
networking and hanging out with people
hmm what do I miss the least the fact
that they start them at 9 a.m.
exactly so you know my you know I just I
never get the 9 a.m. started especially
on the second day I mean officially we
chose 12 so that Western Australia you
could join but unofficially it's because
yes yes what do I miss about conferences
I miss catching up with people like I
generally get I miss the whole weight
it's like I generally I'll be honest I
don't go to the talks very often I just
I just go and talk to other people but
it's fun cause like you go to a big
conference like a Bayside's or something
and then everyone who you know from
across the country is in the same place
yeah and so you can catch it with
everyone all at once and then in my case
as a horrible person you can say I'll
catch up with you later and then forget
to do so we still haven't caught up with
the people that you said we were gonna
have yeah I know I'm sorry if you're
watching what would your message be to
students and/or junior security
professionals who may be afraid or
hesitant to submit a talk to comfy Khan
or conferences in general I'd love to
see more of that demographic to giving
this a good so that's from Josh my
message would be just submit something
and we'll probably approve it I think
we've actually got a box on the form
that says if you're a new speaker please
just take this box yeah and it probably
will fit within our criteria for review
although we haven't really got an
official criteria for review let us know
in the comments when you're putting in
your submission let us know if you want
some coaching if you aren't doing
through it because we'd be more than
happy to coach you mentor you provide
feedback even if you don't really
if your topic is interesting submit it
and we can give you feedback on it and
suggest you know if you've got an area
of expertise we can maybe suggest it's
not like an exam or something we're not
gonna be like the only chance to talk to
us is going to be through your your
submission like if you have an idea come
talk to one of the three of us and be
like hey I've got this idea and we'll be
like yeah that's a really good idea
please submit it yeah we will jump top
tip if it's cyber don't ask me don't ask
Andrea yeah yeah she'll probably just
come to me and say hey what is this
sound like but yeah like I encourage
everyone to submit talks because when
you like talking in general when you
when you get further into this cyber
field you have to start talking with
managers you have to start giving
presentations it's not just the
technical stuff and so being able to
communicate effectively is probably one
of the most important skills you can
have because but I think even if you
like because we don't know how many
submissions were gonna get etc just the
experience of submitting for a talk is a
good experience it's the same thing as
applying for jobs and going to
interviews and things like that it's
good to give that first get that first
one out of the way like rip the band-aid
off yeah and then you learn things I
would say while we're on the topic of
submissions one pro tip for submissions
if you submit something that's already
been seen at another talk that will
probably count against you just being
honest we want to seem nice and new and
original things that said nice new
original doesn't mean it has to be well
like peer-reviewed research or something
it could just be some idea you've had
that actually is relevant to everyone
else in the industry yeah it's kind of
if it's on YouTube already probably
won't qualify for what we're looking for
yeah case-by-case basis yeah what a
success look like for Kathy Kohner you
who said that of course he did they are
the most active twitter yes thank you
very much much to one of our moderators
Kirk who has been very helpful and I'm
sure he's volunteering himself to do
something at this point what is
successful I don't know
no one cutting themselves I think my
bones smuggle you know miserable yeah
timely yes but yes yeah I think one of
the big things with comfy Connie's we
are all about accessibility of
information and talk to people who maybe
necessarily don't live in an area where
they can make it to conferences or
they're not able to make it to
conferences for their own personal
reasons and I think success for us is
creating that community and that's
support particularly in a world where a
lot of us work virtually where you don't
necessarily have that like office banter
that you may have had previously and
just general hallway talks in an office
so creating that community for people is
the big kind of success for us yes I
know I told this story to some
moderators and some of the speakers
beforehand but like we got a message
towards the end of comfy cotton in my
April which was thanks very much for I
mention their name but thanks very much
for running a conference it's great that
you had something that people who
normally can't go to conferences could
attend and be a part of unlike there's
there's a number of factors that like
you could be physically unable to attend
a conference because location or you
could all like conferences are really
stressful stressful
not everyone has a conference budget No
so making that really accessible to
everyone and like making it so anyone
can it's like for us the important thing
is sharing the ideas not anything else
like making sure that people can share
their ideas really easily and having a
conference online is really easy to do
that so that's the main thing the other
half of that question is six conferences
and a movie question mark do you want us
to name six conferences or do you think
after six conferences we should produce
a movie on it are we produce
a movie by virtue of having an online in
the first place they can pick on a
documentary we could we could do a
flogging and then do a vlog season about
us making a conference and all the
twists and turns and like room isn't
working oh my god I'm not editing that
what are your self-care routines and has
that changed in the past months I'm
assuming that's for co-ed myself care
routines my horses and my dogs really
they're the ones that keep me sane and
active and together
it hasn't changed that much luckily I
was able to ride my horses all
throughout Kovach because we're in a
pretty secluded place anyway
and we're all that allowed to still go
there so not really I've watched him
home for about 10 years so love being it
loving it
this is yeah it's been actually a really
happy time for me
I've not traveled since last December
which is bizarre because before that I
was traveling every couple of weeks I
it's actually been quite nice to just
sit down and relax and actually have a
self-care program is your suitcase
unpacked it is unpacked my suitcase from
our trip is still in fact I don't think
Wow well you did move so that's Midtown
I was unpacked the week yeah took me
like three weeks but I was also busy
what's your what's myself playing video
games okay
playing video games and running a
conference yes firm for me like sounds a
bit weird or whatever like comfy little
like that sort of thing is kind of my
thing like making sure everyone else is
okay like I like where my friends are
happy and all that kind of stuff so you
know being able to run this and chat and
join in it's kind of my thing
what about you I just watch Netflix and
YouTube just excessive be my skin well
the first time you did it you fell over
yes many times
yes we'll do it again yes what's it
again like this
new parts since they need to go - yeah
there's possible cost the car park with
all the like joins in the concrete was
not no I wasn't it was not a good thing
and yeah I don't think any of our
changes really changed that much in the
past few months
I just don't we just don't go that well
like for us it was annoying that you go
shopping and then there's so many people
that you don't want to go shopping
yeah I just delivery so I'm the delivery
girl but like we like the idea of going
around to a shop and then seeing
everything in the shop and all that kind
of stuff and then you gotta like what
was anyone to like spotlight and
spotlight it's completely packed with
people which is you know there's a
spotlight opening in Canberra top news
is not related to comfy con I'm so ready
for it um what do you sacrifice when
making the time to establish a
conference is it worth it sleeping yes
oh excuse me it's allergies guys I
promise
sleeping yeah sleep and yes it's worth
it I don't think I made that much of a
sacrifice no I don't think we do do that
like really if any everyone was like wow
this is so professionally done honestly
honestly I was working that last two
weeks I think it was more than that but
I think lice we we learnt from other
conferences yes and then we can't have
just emulated them and had an easier job
because we weren't doing it in a
physical location with physical yeah I
think the physical location and the fact
that we didn't handle any merch oh yeah
we didn't have printing we didn't have
shirt t-shirts to give out you didn't
have tickets as badges or vendors or
sponsors apart from our singular sponsor
and a lot of that is where the headache
of event organizing it really comes in
yes yeah so it was mostly purely kind of
these are the paper submissions like
this is having a spreadsheet the running
yeah we have one spreadsheet but
everyone was sort of really good because
when we said like you can have it
whenever you want and you don't have to
go anywhere to do it it just became so
much easier
[Music]
I think the most stressful piece of it
was just the day's itself like they like
I don't know if you guys saw but like I
think we looked really exhausted at the
end there was all the times that you
forgot to press me you oh that was
that's the reason why yeah not that I
just can't use technology
it was just tiring it was retiring it
behind the scenes it was just us which
it won't be the next comfy con which
would be really nice so we were doing
the emceeing and then all the
coordination in the background as well
as the official speakers were ready in
on time and that they were in the other
room you know to practice we could hear
then that they were in the actual
webinar and one says also we have no CFP
we just accepted anyone I mean that's
kind of dirty
yes and though we didn't accept everyone
there was a review process because we
don't was there was that one accepted
for reasons that will not be divulged we
did review everything basically and we
thought like everything was cool like
and I think that's shown from like
nobody said that any particular talk
didn't fit in or they said you know no
talk was particularly relevant like we
had this good breadth and variety of
different things yeah I was so I think
that was probably the best part of
pompey con for me was the the range and
collection of speakers that actually
submitted we had first time speakers and
then we have unique is that you know
very experienced names you recognized
yeah names you don't recognize kind of
thing and they all sort of blended
together nicely yeah it was it was a
really amazing experience actually just
running the CFP and just almost
organically turning it into an amazing
mix of talk so yeah yeah it wasn't it
wasn't too stressful just just think the
other thing was we didn't know if we'd
have enough talks yeah like because we
didn't put a date we didn't put a date
on on the closing of it and then we kind
of had to put a date because we're like
we have no slots left yeah because we
had a whole day because comfortin was
only supposed to be a day yeah I think
it's going to be fraught it was gonna be
the Saturday of that week
and we weren't going to do anything else
and then it became two days and that's
like are we going to extend it to a
third day and I think we had the
beginning sort of a web novice I don't
think we could have lasted through three
days after the second day was really
tiring just being on constantly could
you also ran yet to my side chat panel
as well so not just hosting but there's
also like that yeah actually terms are
probably not gonna do this next yeah
that's what you want earring for yeah
yeah what snacks and drinks are we
having this evening which also leads in
let's just leaves into let's discuss
June yeah so I think we we were
discussing at the time that we had like
was it there's a scotch of rotting yes
and then there's a gin drinking scotch
idea the ones who drink scotch and then
there's up the group of us that drink
gin which I mean I can I be varying
times of the evening yeah we're not
drinking tonight because we have to
drive back to insert major city here so
unfortunately we're not drinking tonight
but feel free to drink yourselves we're
not stuck in we had them we had Red
Rooster other restaurants are available
[Music]
[Laughter]
very different yep
so I think that's all on Twitter right
which team am I on I'm in the gin
section I can't drink scotch show me
that it really just yeah I smell it yeah
white rum yes white rum yeah and this
place from spiced rum and ginger beer
anywhere where is the dog civilized
which dog what are you talking about I
don't know is that we're jumping all on
us
your dog not hasn't arrived yet yes
somewhere over the he might be landing
soon he'll be landing in 15 minutes for
context we're in Sydney because we're
getting a dog
so probably should have opened with that
one actually that's why we're all
together because we're in the same
location baby dog the baby though for
sake I'm sorry
well you're gonna be listening civilized
your face so civilized is running the
entirety of the CTA so any complaint
about the sea no duck shanna exactly
okay see I can drink everything by the
way it's good to know Sylvia I'm gonna
ask the question what's your favorites
Sylvia dad joke does anybody have one
that sticks out there all just terrible
I didn't know I'd have to go back
because there are a few actually during
comfy con that I actually kind of
snorted just golden and I just yeah I
don't remember what he says all my jokes
are amazing I'm falsely Silvio will not
be joining us this time because he's a
he's a prior engagement I don't know I
think he could still do a yeah but like
you want to piss off Carly what do you
mean that's not an excuse it totally be
focused income for the wedding look we
did live streaming yes/no live streaming
[Music]
and like a switch to the wedding will be
in the console and waiting for it to not
collapse yeah that's fair
was there any more questions no unless I
miss them and I'm so sorry if I did I
don't know I see
how is Shanna's garden doing ladies
going really well very very well my
stone fruits uh plus something right now
I'm very pretty um we are constantly
getting lots of rocket and you want to
see my mushrooms
oh you're going mushrooms in your
cupboard a Silvia says which stone
freeze which stone fruits yellow
nectarines white peach yellow peach oh
that's a nice weeks look at the my
dreams they will be showing a pre-cut
top comes with more stone fruits I'm
weirdly fussy with apples I only Fuji
apples is there much room on the
schedule for summer edition so far hi
Caitlin it wasn't Sophia everyone yeah I
think that's um hi you're welcome thank
you
Caitlin I I think that's the only
questions we have thus far please feel
free to throw in other questions all
right is out communication that good
that nobody has any question I think
it's just there's not many people
watching to be honest which is fine yeah
the shade the shade like when I'm in the
shade 13 people watching right now slick
TV hm
well we don't need to do anything else
then we're done yeah somebody else can
run the car finally someone on the
stream is a fun guy
yeah it's Friday afternoon you should
all be drinking stop sorry not
encouraging drink yeah that was the
problem when I started talking about -
you know spiced rum
then you go no this is not good remember
teen me has drunk a lot yeah me too like
a lot yes not like it's just like ah
I'll have a glass and then it's like ah
the bottles opened there's white wine so
it's not gonna last very well are you
working hard doing the wrong kind of
compliance there is no wrong compliance
all compliance is golden game servers
are they gonna be probably will probably
do a survey beforehand to choose which
ones to open up rocket League
rocket League competition I'll get
somebody else maybe if Benzies wants to
run a rocket League competition he is
more than odd there's money to raid
right I was yeah I'd do a destination
charade but unfortunately yeah that's
that becomes the problem of like we
can't be organizing this stuff again
but yeah destiny to raid would be fun
was that civilized and that was that was
hoodie pony and civilized animal
crossing Fight Club I don't know but
maybe maybe in one of the company called
locations we could do some kind of dance
dance you know interlude delegation you
need a game maker to grip all that out
oh yeah that sounds like a box is one
thing we we didn't talk about there is
also a Google Form for volunteers please
volunteer please yeah and you can come
join us and help with everything and
help make the event such a success that
would be awesome
it's not a it's not a huge amount of
work it's literally just a lot of work
because it was just three of us doing it
before volunteering is not mandatory
unless required the term you're looking
for is voluntold
volunteers are there for a number of
things I think I've put up volunteers
for speaker wrangling are you talking to
speakers and making each other in the
right place and their equipment works
moderation on the discord chat MC if
anybody wants to MC or run panels and
then yet other there's an other category
which is like I don't really know what I
want to do but I want to help or if you
think of a role that we haven't
mentioned that you would like to do so
if you're like hey I'm really into X
gaming or something like yeah let us
know and we can see if it's something
that can be kind of worked
MC hacks a lot no Sophia shouldn't see
here's 20 women Silvia you bought the
podcaster what are you doing she just
bought the coax Allah yeah I know that's
what I'm saying it's all the same but
he's gonna be at Mooseheads next weekend
like DJ I've heard family's head chief
clown off some video editing yes video
the thing would be something comfy
it's like crashed my computer so many
times because it's just like chunk of
footage it's not like Nate talks it's
the whole YouTube save it saves it is 8
hours of footage and even though it's
only 720p yeah we'll be doing if we're
using a different hosting service we're
different streaming service next time it
might be bigger yes so the plan is we're
using a stream yard so theoretically
might be bigger yeah better quality so
we're hoping we all have better call
which will have better quality than what
you're seeing right now because I just
looked at it I look like trash yeah it
wasn't linked right quality yeah yeah
yeah yeah like music no yeah I know I
think Bex mentioned last time what would
be cool if we you know if there was any
local bands or something or people in
bands that wanted to our music we'd be
king too you know if you've got music
that you want to share as a an interlude
or something like that we be keen for as
long as you're sharing that content ID
and strike our video yeah exactly that's
that's all ok like yeah but it strikes
the whole video
yeah yeah but if the video is cut then
it's not gonna cut it up anyway that's
the but yes any if and there's anybody
who likes to dabble in video editing or
even just wants to listen to the 8 hours
of footage and find the timestamps of
where the actual video is and it's not
just oh I'll listen to a video and say
if they say the word it was like
listening to an hour the chimes
successive allies I might like to talk
about your idea for kids just feel free
to say yes or no in the nice West yeah
somebody somebody asked for their video
to have no swears because it was being
shown to another audience that yes we're
swearing what's not appropriate so we
just checked to make sure there was no
sorry just a little double check II I
don't know I didn't have a plan of what
to do if we found one but we just needed
to double check oh yeah okay that's fair
oh yeah we can be like Firefly where
they don't actually swear they just have
like other words what's the word Iike
Frank yeah we could have our own like
get farted okay so Dan tells me if
string yard is 720 but better bit right
so we'll look better but it will just be
720 so we'll wait till you can import a
video well why can it like wesker sorry
we'll just run it through OBS or
something and then it yeah yes so if
there are no other questions then it's
[Music]
like has landed I'm a stress eater so
even when I try other things I'm
stressed for them so yeah I think we've
basically covered
so just to end 20th and 20th November 12
lunchtime to 8:00 p.m. at night so it
gives eight hours gap for tops and stuff
same same dinner break this last time
conference workshops CTF volunteers
volunteers please no sponsors again but
sponsors for prizes summer sponsors for
the conference but sponsors for prizes
yeah I think that covers basically good
prizes right like yeah like nobody wants
a water bottle yeah yeah like yeah um
same as previously with like branding
all yeah yeah so we want to stay as
independent as possible yeah yeah like
don't like yes attribution of ideas and
things but like it's not a talk that's
just a sell night yeah yeah so please
submit papers please come along to it
when it's hosted will do another mailing
list of some kind the website I know is
not set up properly I'll get to it can
we showcase products are you selling
them is it open source I guess there's
more the question like my example would
be the Velociraptor talk is something
thing along that nature is perfectly
fine well as well like the Raspberry Pi
one we're showcasing a product in like
you know it's a bit of hardware that you
can like it was only for the souls
project alright it wasn't that yes yeah
yeah we're not we're not you know if
you're coming to us with a nothing that
requires you to enter into a contract
for an extended period of time don't
spend hundreds of thousands of dollars
yes yes because we don't have that money
and I'm sure most people that what's
been having that money on yeah any
anything that's for personal use or
could be used personally open source or
free for personal use things like that
are fine yeah basically if you're unsure
ask oh yeah it's just like send us a
message we're happy to MMS
a contract with certain company no no we
can't we're not going to showcase that
product are we Shanna see I haven't even
mentioned it the name like but what does
being a swear officer involved no he's
saying I swear oh I thought he was well
I'm Terry to be the swear officer he's
not gonna be who's gonna like go around
or like ding-ding-ding people if they
scroll too much I don't think so there
you go is comfy gun this is this is
where you see like how lifted right
brains work yeah
I'll be this fair officer it's fine oh
no that won't be good
Helen you can now be this swear officer
okay please see if you have any control
if you have any other questions feel
free to email us at comfy con au at
gmail.com or just ask questions on the
comfy contest cord link should be in the
youtube video all the Twitter everywhere
else I think that's pretty much
everything we had to say and that was
the only question so if there are any
final somewhat serious questions please
ask them or forever hold your peace
and then we will probably disappear tag
it on some trains I like trains so glad
we didn't go to the train museum we
weren't gonna go try anything do we give
up a segment on flags as well
fun with flags okay I don't see any more
questions thanks for being lovely and go
get dog man yes okay thank you very much
guys he has to clear customs he does
thank you very much everyone