so it turns out that you are all in for
a great treat so I was actually having a
conversation with Jesse a little while
ago I'm getting ready to introduce him
and I was amazed to learn that he is a
former astronaut which is pretty amazing
seven years on the International Space
Station he actually got bored of it so
now he leads a red team and if you
believe all that he's got a lot to tell
us about the spearfishing experience
right so he's gonna tell us about the
real-world trial and errors that he made
building and running a red team and also
why to do things in a very OPSEC safe
way and how to get a foothold with
spearfishing so and of course in the in
the ISS tradition we're gonna start off
with the way we did there you know to
our comrades shot of vodka Cheers good
luck everyone so my talk is called
Purple Haze the spearfishing experience
featuring me so just a little bit about
me if you if we never met before my name
is Jesse doubling I'm on an internal red
team a former consultant I was
consulting for about seven years before
I joined this team this year it's not a
big for consulting firm or accounting
firm I'm not allowed to say the name
right now but I'm based out of Seattle
Washington I'm mostly focused on windows
exploitation purple team advocate really
just I'm in for the collaboration
between red teams and blue teams because
that's really how we all get better
right on the side I do some music
production electronic music play guitar
in a punk band free parking check them
out the cool and I'm just stoked to be
here overall so during this I just want
you to think and take this to heart
during a red team operation treat the
attackers like a real adversary I think
that's important that's how you're going
to learn to figure out how to detect
certain things figure out how to respond
to it properly
if you if you're not doing that you're
not going to get much value from the red
team and then afterwards make sure you
have collaboration so what's the point
of my talk I'm gonna walk through some
of the trial and error I've had as a red
teamer
and also what blue teams have done when
I was consulting and now the blue team I
work with directly pinpoints some areas
that hopefully will help some of you
think a little bit differently from an
attackers mindset tightened security and
to potentially help you foster some new
detection controls and just give you the
blue teamers in the room a glimpse of
how adversaries think and how we're
plotting against you so overall I'm just
going to go over recon some adversarial
OPSEC that we put in place to figure out
if the blue team is catching on to what
we're doing and also dive into malicious
attachments some old stuff some new
stuff hopefully you guys learned
something from it so first with recon
you know we look to see what's publicly
out there who is sub-domain all that
jazz everyone knows that and then we
start trying to craft our spearfishing
campaigns looking for things like job
openings that have the technologies that
your business is using looking up social
media to see if you know your employees
are saying what tools that you have in
your environment anything that we can
really pull together to understand what
your tech stack is and also potentially
craft a campaign to to go against you
also we look for things like services
that might be available though and we
could potentially look for things that
like maybe single off on your external
environment so we could attack that
later and I think the last bullet point
is big one I'm going to show you a
screenshot next in the next slide but
bouncing emails off of domains you can
pull a bunch of good information from
that really what we're using all of this
for the firewall rules looking for the
things in who is in your public
environment
we will create firewall rules for rc2
servers so we could potentially narrow
the scope if you have a third party
sandbox or something like that it won't
be able to pull our payloads and
actually run their sandbox and against
it and so on
I'm looking for those single-factor
authentic
unique to your environment so we can key
in on that and and craft our payloads
further so the left image hopefully you
can see it but that's bouncing an email
off of some random company might be a
real company I don't know but they
actually have the internal domain name
readily available this is more for if
you have SMTP servers like on Prem cloud
services prevent a lot of this and then
you can also see at the bottom it says
PP host comm so that also gives me the
knowledge that your corporation or your
business is using Proofpoint so that'll
help me craft how I'm going to attack
you through through attachments or
whatever it is then the other one is a
pretty old technique but it's still
viable I've used it a ton of times when
I was consulting looking for MS link or
if you're still using a link for some
reason or Skype for business
you can basically send an ntlm
authentication request to that server
and pull back base64 encoded blob that
basically has all of your internal
domain information and also the internal
server name I have a some references
hopefully this the slides will get out
sometime soon that you guys can click
that and look through it more so some
potential areas of detection for this
anyone that's you know mass downloading
externally hosted files to pull metadata
to see what versions your software is
within office or Adobe or anything like
that so we can craft things against that
emails potentially being bounced against
non-existent email accounts that's what
I've showed in that one
this is a lot harder if you if your
business has a lot of clients but if you
know you can potentially whitelist
specific domains and you can crack down
on that a little bit more for maybe a
smaller business and then you know just
brute forcing against single factor off
that that's pretty easily detected a lot
of people still don't detect on that
though I put in a couple points that
I've I've struggled with when I was
doing these assessments you know it
costs more time to the attacker overall
if I can't figure out what your egress
points are from your network from the
publicly available stuff anything that's
registered under your company's name if
if you have a third party or like you're
in a service provider is what's pulled
from from that recon then I'm not going
to be able to change the firewall rules
to narrow down on what can access my
payloads if your environment has
multi-factor all over the place it's
going to be much harder for me to spray
anything I usually try not to do that
anyway because it's too noisy but you
know some people do if employees only
have general job descriptions basically
anything that's not related to your text
sect and that's gonna make it harder for
me to figure out what's in your
environment so I can further do some
tests and against those tools and
potentially get by them and then the
last one wild card emails aren't allowed
so I can't bounce off or you have like a
cloud service for your email you you
won't be able to pull that internal
domain information from those I made a
toolkit for looking up some basic recon
for networking you can follow that if if
you like so the next one I'm running
into adversarial OPSEC testing dropper
malware this is a topic on its own I'm
not going to cover it too much today but
just know that an adversary with that's
dedicated enough will download free
trials of Av get trials of your edr
products and figure out ways around it
you just have to kind of
that in your environment and look for
anomalies but that's just something that
you need to keep in mind and if you want
to talk about this afterwards I'm happy
to I'm just not going to cover it with
this talk so this is a one technique
that I've done and I've figured out was
worked pretty well to figure out if
incident response or the blue team was
on to my campaign I would set up
basically a web server that is not
related to any of my other other c2
infrastructure and whatever payload I'm
sending will basically send a benign web
request to like an image or something
like that
once that image gets pulled or gets
requested then I'll get a text message
this works
twofold because basically I'll get a
text message one if the actual victim
has clicked my link and I know that I'm
about to get a shell or two if there's
multiple requests happening I'm getting
a ton of text messages I'm like oh
the the blue team's probably on me let
me burn down that infrastructure and
start somewhere else I've also seen some
people do unc path injection and pull
and tell MV to hashes over the internet
if you have an SMB outbound I'm gonna
you've probably shouldn't but you I've
seen it like 50 percent of the clients
I've worked at so I just have some
sample code for the text messages for
the red teamers in the room and then
under that for the blue teamers in the
room I actually have the user agents
that office products use it might be
helpful for people that are sandboxing
the payloads or any any of the documents
that they're receiving or if they think
something is malicious you could
potentially use this in in tune your
sandbox a little bit more this is
another technique that I came up with
basically using one-time use tokens so
whenever your payloads if your staging
request out to a server that you know I
own there's a database set up that will
have all the usages of that token if the
token gets requested one time from my
payload then it'll actually serve up the
legit pay
and start the process of downloading and
executing whatever
the flow is if there is more than once
you can set however many times you want
it so to work but if it the token gets
requested more than once then
potentially that it is probably a blue
team so that will redirect to something
benign and then you won't be able the
incident response teams won't be able to
actually pull that down also don't
request my payloads with W get that's
just going to get redirected I've seen
it a lot it's just things that I need to
point out so some areas of potential
detection their office any document
reading process that has outbound
connectivity you know this is kind of a
no-brainer but if some people are knew
that it might be good information any
type of outbound can network
connectivity should be looked at further
there's a chance it's not malicious a
better chance it probably is any
malicious links from non trusted domains
obviously that's a much harder one to
crack down on if you have a big
environment those user agents that I
called out earlier and then this one is
kind of counterintuitive to the first
bullet for my incident response and
defense tips but if there's one of those
campaigns that's more mass phishing that
is has the tokens that are being used
and you want to pull that payload you
could potentially look for those unread
emails click that link download the
payload and analyze it that way and that
kind of goes into the next tip which is
don't do that you're better off just
pulling the payload from one of the
users that already clicked it and
analyzing it that way and that kind of
goes and coincides with that W get
request that I was talking about earlier
this one is just kind of an overarching
one you guys probably hate hearing it
but just assume that adversary knows how
to get around your tools look for things
after you know you're gonna get
low-hanging fruit and unexperienced
attackers but look for things like you
know that guy in finance opening up
PowerShell and executing commands
because
obviously gonna be something that
shouldn't happen or wouldn't happen
normally and then the last one I kind of
touched on it disable your SMB outbound
traffic that's ridiculous
so uh some malicious attachments you
know there's email security and
sandboxing services out there that you
can rely on you can hold on it as a
crutch but I wouldn't make that you know
it's not a silver bullet by any means
you can modify some publicly known
payloads pretty easily and get by them
and I'm gonna run through a couple
things that we do as red teamers so one
this is kind of an older tactic but it
still works wonderfully so I want to
make sure that everyone is aware of it
it's called remote template injection so
the idea behind it is you have a normal
non malicious document and it actually
calls out to an office template that is
hosted on a staging server elsewhere so
basically that template has the
malicious code in it so once the
document is opened it pulls the template
down and then there's a macro in the
document I kind of wrote the steps for
the red teamers if they curious about
doing it you just edit an XML file but
for the blue teamers in the room this
basically it allows docx files which
typically don't have macros in them to
be used as a malicious document so
that'll get by you know quite a few
email filters the other side of this is
when this actually occurs you can take
the template down it depends if you have
the the firewall rules in place but if
you don't you can take the template down
while the email sandbox is doing its
thing against the document and basically
want it once it's making those requests
out you'll see that there's like
third-party sandboxes in like a juror or
AWS
requesting a ton
of times to your server looking for the
template once that dies down it's
usually between five and twenty minutes
you can just Rijos the template because
the sandbox will send that document to
the user the victim whoever you're
targeting and they'll open it and
hopefully by that time you have the
template backup and it'll just pull the
template down and you get that malicious
code execution there's some actually
pretty unique indicators for this for
the the templates being requested by
office products and I just put those
there for the blue teamers as a
reference these slides will be up later
but it's a pretty unique set of requests
that gets sent out once it's pulling
those templates this is you know the
tried and true method everyone knows
about VBA macros it's gone through a
million iterations it's gotten to the
point where you kind of have to hide in
plain sight
Windows Defender is catching on to
basically everything and I assume that
the other AV vendors are going to catch
up eventually but things like WMI
execution is old-school PowerShell
cradles that will get caught most likely
hiding variables and document properties
XML data and then I've just came up with
a method of actually hiding code in
alternative text of images and then the
week I was about to execute Microsoft
put in a new alert that actually says
that it's an off you skated macro so you
can't do that anymore but there's a
really good talk on this at Derby con I
think last year 2018 where they they
talk a lot more about this and it's
definitely a good one to view for for
blue teamers but basically we're doing
things like we're reversing strings just
replacing characters hiding it just
straight in the the normal macro instead
of pulling different properties of the
documents staging the payloads you know
you don't want to put all of your
malicious code in the payload because if
that gets caught then your c2
infrastructure is burned so having that
outside that next step is a good way to
kind of
or some of burning the infrastructure
you set up and took so long to do and
then just executing outside of office
ancestry
this is really it's a pretty well known
way to do things in EDR tools nowadays
all detect on if you're executing as a
child process of like an office product
but as an attacker we always have to
execute outside of office and I put an
example up of just that hiding in plain
sight macro for the blue teamers so you
if you're analyzing something you can
see what is actually occurring here I
cut out the execution side because
that's all public knowledge so this one
is actually something that I came up
with as well but it was based off of a
talk by Stan Hecht at Derby con 2018
this is Excel 4.0 macros for those of
you that don't know is an old language
within Excel that it basically allows
you to hook windows api's and just call
dll's directly through Excel so it's
pretty awesome the method that he showed
off was really more around doing direct
shell code injection but I didn't like
that that much because unless you change
your shell code to execute outside of
the office product it'll execute as a
child process of Excel which will get
caught by an e dr product so I wanted to
do something different and also you know
everything there will give away your C
to infrastructure if that's the case so
I came up with my own attack flow I use
Excel 4.0 as a downloader basically just
calling the Windows DLL URL Mon to
download a file and then you can hybrid
it and actually call a VBA function as
well through Excel 4.0 so you can do
that for execution since in the VBA it
doesn't say auto open it'll get by a lot
of email filters there email filters
aren't really looking for these Excel
4.0 macros yet I also included some of
the the user agents that
get requested when this occurs just so
you guys also know what's going on and
have something to write off of if you if
you can tune your sandboxes so some
points of discovery the first ones
obvious hopefully everyone knows that if
a document has making outbound network
connectivity then there's probably an
issue that probably doesn't happen but
sometimes it does but it's something to
look into at least vba scripts run from
documents you know EER tools nowadays
they they look into these at least you
can flag on them with with a basic set
up but again if it's not like your
accounting guy that is running macros
all day then there's probably some issue
going on some so malicious activity
executing as a child process of office
products if that ever occurs and you
don't have an EDR solution then look
into that that probably shouldn't be
happening either any old format versions
of office documents so dot doc dot XLS
you can actually prevent those from even
being opened in your environment through
GPO so that's an approach you could take
if you don't have like legacy documents
which you know let's let's get to the
21st century now and then the last one I
think is probably the the biggest one
looking for these functions specifically
within the macros the first ones is
shell calm so you can call that seal Sid
and basically execute as a child process
of Explorer instead of instead of the
the office document itself the rest of
them are basically used as downloaders
or other ways of execution the one that
I really wanted to point out was the
active sheet visible equals false I use
this all the time in phishing campaigns
because it's how I sway users to click
something basically what that is doing
is making an image invisible so I'll
just overlay an image on a document that
says hey this is in privacy mode this
isn't protected mode enable content to
view the
document so that'll make somebody that's
not too experienced just click enable
content the image disappears it looks
legit they don't really know what's
going on so that's definitely a bigger
one that I haven't seen too many people
call out and then the others who are
just really around the the hiding in
plain sight aspect of things so for the
incident response tip here sandboxing a
payload on a system that is actually
representative of your domain because we
did all that recon in the first place so
we potentially know your internal domain
name if it's just a third party sandbox
service there's a chance that it's not
connected to your domain and if it's not
then we'll just cut execution right
there and not do anything malicious so
that's a pretty important step I see a
lot of people fail doing that but it's
something that you can you can at least
be cognizant of moving forward and then
the last one this is a really well-known
tool Oh le dump if you don't know that
you should probably look into it it's a
really good blue teaming tool that you
can scrape VBA macros and they also just
made a plugin for Excel 4.0 macros to
see what's actually being executed and
you can scrape that content and actually
do an analysis against it to see if it's
malicious and I just link to did your
Stephens tool that Lu dumped at the
bottom so this last one is pretty new
there's a there's a talk on this
tomorrow so hopefully he goes in more
detail I'm gonna be brief about it
though the the overall concept here is
you can send a meeting event to somebody
and it'll just pop up on their calendar
this was pretty there's there's some big
news about it recently with with
scammers doing it I took it kind of a
next level and did it more as an
adversary where I would just attach like
a WebEx meeting and then say hey you
need a an automated update didn't get
pushed to your box and we need to do a
manual update on your system they've
joined the WebEx and
you just talk them through giving you
mouse and keyboard control download the
payload say hey you're updated
open up the office product or whatever
and say oh yeah the version looks like
it's up-to-date you're good to go if you
have any questions go to your local IT
desk so that works really well and it's
it's kind of a something that hasn't
really been done or I've seen talked
about too much but I've pop shells that
way there's a lot more scammers doing it
with just like random links to something
malicious that say you want a free
iPhone but just ignore that
so some points of discovery for that are
again
meeting meetings originating from non
trusted domains this is going to be much
harder for bigger organizations but if
you know your client base you could
potentially flag on that the other one
is any meetings that appear without an
actual email invite that's an indicator
honestly I don't know a way to go in and
look at that as a red teamer but it's
something to think about and potentially
look at as blue teamers and then as a
tip just get the business to disable
automatic adding of invitations to
calendars because that'll make sure that
they don't get that notification pop-up
that oh I have a meeting in 10 minutes I
have to make sure I join this that
that's really the only tip I have right
now hopefully tomorrow at the coalition
talk he talks a little bit more about it
but yeah so that's it for me this is
actually my first con talk so thank you
so much for your time I appreciate it
and we if if you want to talk a little
bit more afterwards and meet me at the
bar
sorry if I spoiled your OPSEC by saying
where you were working for the past
seven years Space Station thanks very
much and we're gonna be outside for some
Q&A and I think we have a break now as
some Red Team people check in so thank
you
[Music]