hi everyone and thanks so much for
having me I've loved hearing everybody's
presentations and I feel that everybody
has had a little piece of something for
me either to make me feel good about
what introduce does or to make me wonder
in question more about what engineers
does in the misinformation space inter
news is not a news agency intern use is
an international nonprofit that works
through partners in media and tech in
more than 70 countries worldwide to try
to ensure safe access to timely reliable
fact-checked information that can help
people make informed decisions about
their lives participate in their
communities and hold power to account
for the last six or seven years I've
been in charge of responding and the
information space to humanitarian crises
including Ebola in West Africa Guinea
and Liberia the Nepal the Nepal
earthquake the Mediterranean refugee
response hurricane Matthew in Haiti and
then Ebola again in Democratic Republic
of Congo I'm going to share we are
preparing right now or doing our best to
design a response to the corona virus
I'm not going to speak so specifically
as to what that might be as to talk a
little bit about where we come from in
this arc of learning towards designing
for a situation which bears similarity
to other situations we have dealt with
but comes with a new set of
complications that's always the fabulous
thing about these kinds of emergencies
they're always different so we simply
put what we know is that in humanitarian
and public health emergencies
information is that a premium demand is
high in terms of in times of uncertainty
supply may be wiped out in the case of
conflict or natural disaster in the case
of public health emergencies very often
it's more about the supply of
information being controlled or being of
poor quality or being
carotids by rumor misinformation we love
facts the overwhelming amount of work
that we do is with local media partners
in the countries where we work I'm a
journalist by background and so facts
are fundamentally important
we love the international fact-checking
Network we were so happy to see the
launch of it a couple of weeks ago it's
a perfect point of departure for us so
anything that I'm going to say about
facts in my presentation is by no means
suggesting that we don't need them but
into news very much picks up where the
fact checkers leave off and if we don't
have to necessarily do our own
fact-checking that's a wonderful thing
many of our media partners in countries
where we work have existing
relationships with the fact-checking
their networks for instance in in
Indonesia so this is what we like to
think this was the way that things
ideally would be big fat facts and small
skinny rumors what it often feels like
when we get to the ground is this the
kind of situation we might we've
basically been discussing all morning
and we generally think that yes I love
it when people take photographs thank
you
what we generally think of as the first
recourse in this situation is that
that's what we think we should do that's
in fact where we went into the Ebola
crisis in Liberia we went in to do the
typical kind of work that we would do
with journalists in crisis at community
and that is to rally them around put
them together with experts give them
more facts inform them better on the
matter of science and public health they
quickly became acquainted of course with
the public health service information
with which Liberia was bombarded I mean
when you say wall-to-wall it was
literally if you've seen photographs at
that time there wasn't a wall space that
did not have a public health message on
it the messages were few and simple wash
your hands don't touch the don't touch
the bodies use the chlorine water that's
provided for you so
there was no corner of that country that
was untouched by the basic facts of the
health information messages that were
given to people however this is where
the kind of glitch in the machine comes
in some at some point in time it became
clear that there were in Liberia what
people called resistant communities and
for the first time medical
anthropologists were actually called in
to advise w-h-o and others on what this
might be
Engineers experience in crisis after
crisis is that this place here my actual
concern the small voice there is where
the trust factor comes in because
regardless of what the facts are and
whether these and whether individuals or
communities have access to have access
to those facts if there isn't somebody
to address the actual concern which may
or may not be related to the medical
facts not paying attention to my actual
concern breeds typically in communities
a lack of trust in those who are trying
to convey the facts and this may be your
local government your national
government or in the situation kind of
situations where we work a big health
agency and this lack of trust in facts I
think as others have pointed out this
morning can be as dangerous as an
absence of facts so what we find in
these kinds of situations when we go in
to give people facts or fact based
primarily fact-based information is that
we those who are looking to counter
misinformation are focusing on what we
know and there's a kind of inbuilt
assumption there that what we know is
what they need to know and that's
usually the point of departure when we
go to do our very well-intentioned work
we in turn use we don't worry too much
about the what is the source approach
it's labor intensive and we have other
labor intensive work and very small
resources so this business of
identifying the source discrediting
it's a little bit of a whack-a-mole as
far as we're concerned in terms of how
we would use our resources it's a
potentially limited use because there
will always be more sources and
controlling the information or
controlling the message tends to smack
of spin and even in countries where
people you know are not very well
educated or even literate they certainly
do have a good sense of who might be
trying to sell them a message and so
that's where we come back down to the
trust business so when we go into
communities and I have to say that there
is an issue of scale here if we're
looking at misinformation at scale in
need of any given country we would be
seeking to work with the media in that
country that would be independent media
local language media large scale ie in
Thailand the Public Broadcasting
Corporation for instance with whom we
have a relationship preferably when
we're talking about public health
emergencies we would look for the most
vulnerable or most affected populations
and go to their local media a community
radio station which which would be a
powerful potential ally in that
localized information ecosystem so when
we go in there we are looking at OS seus
about the what does it sound like
self-centered using the messenger and
spinning right so what we focus on is
what do people what did people talk
about because what people talk about can
be very very revealing and when we
realized in Liberia that the amount of
factual and fact-based stories that our
journalism partners could get out was
just being completely swamped by the
word on the street on the grapevine
through social media even in the tiniest
village by word of mouth we realized
that that we had to develop a new kind
of programming to deal with that and we
got together with UNICEF who had health
workers going door-to-door in these
affected villages to give them yet again
the facts and the public health service
messages and we asked them to stick
around and just kind
say you know other than Ebola what's up
what's going on
what else he worried about because and
we found amazingly that there was a lot
of information which had that health
worker not stuck around and just kind of
kicked the can around with those people
for a little while a lot of information
that was extremely interesting about
what people's real concerns were that
were not about necessarily what is Ebola
explained germ theory to me but about
schools about government corruption
about roads about trade about food about
voodoo about magic about economics and
we call that Ebola related content now
it's not necessarily Public Health
content but it has a lot of really
interesting implications for how the
response to that crisis will go and how
messaging may be adjusted the message of
Ebola kills for instance was really not
helpful when people started to survive
Ebola it completely undermined the major
Public Health Service message that that
response had relied upon and sewed
mistrust among people who were then like
hey you know we're not we not now not
inclined to believe anything that you
say how do people talk about it what
language do they use and why do they
talk about it is as interesting because
the business of rumor is so rich it's a
revealing of what people's real fears
are fear has been mentioned a lot in the
room today people in unstable or weak
democracies where there are weak health
systems where there's been a civil war
for instance and where there are always
deemed cultural perhaps religious
political reasons why people are
predisposed to believe a rumor that is
much more interesting to us and where
that rumor came from what the agenda was
of the person who sewed the rumor in the
first place if it was deliberate but
when people are asking questions that is
revealing of their fear and it reveals
an information gap what does they really
want to know and if you can meet that
information gap you have a half a chance
of establishing trust with those people
through which you then may start to drip
feed your
facts with a greater certainty that they
are going to actually pick it up because
Trust is everything in this business so
demand-driven localized news so the
fact-checking network is fabulous we
work we use those facts but we need to
localize down to the most affected
communities it's very difficult with the
coronavirus to decide where exactly
those are because everybody seems to be
vulnerable to the info demek but in due
course it may become evident where the
most at-risk communities are you need to
get down there and understand their
localized information ecosystem and try
to work within that to address it for
inter news what is a rumor it can be a
hey did you hear it can be a criticism
they're trying to make money out of this
there's an agenda behind it
a general throwaway comment or is it
true that or I heard that or have you
heard or did you know that kind of peek
behind the secret I'm letting you in on
a secret here which somebody described
brilliantly earlier it's a data point
for inter news a rumor or a conversation
a concern is a data point these come
from Nepal from Haiti and from Greece
respectively these are rumors we call
them rumors as a short turned it sounds
wild like a rumors like a wacky thing
but it's not really it's just it's a
it's a concern of some sort these are
the information services that we bring
we assess local information ecosystems
to understand who the influencers are
because in the chaos of social media in
particular influencers are super
important in local communities and
faraway places they tend to have a
different flavor but it's super
important to have those people on boards
engaging with local media is always
going to be important communication with
communities is a two-way process this is
not messaging which we have already
established is not necessarily helpful
it's always ensuring that wherever you
are delivering some information to
somebody there is a clear path for that
person to speak back to you to ask their
question to express their particular
idiosyncratic little concern and that
you will go away and you will come back
the following week with your with with
the additional information that that
person used which is exactly what we did
in Liberia so the key I would say here
bullet point to the key is to have a
conversation not to do another survey or
assessment so we literally I think the
anthropologists and social scientists
that we work with call it deep hanging
out it is really that kind of shooting
the breeze on the doorstep stuff people
rumor is everywhere people love to talk
about what they heard today because they
do have fear and they want to check it
that's the stuff that we're interested
in so we have teams going out into
communities they may not be into news we
don't have armies of people everywhere
but we might partner with the Red Cross
for instance or UNICEF or people who do
have boots on the ground who are face to
face with many many people and we just
ask them to keep their ears open and
gather and then so we collect all of
these data points open questioning is
very important as opposed to survey
tick-box questioning let the
conversation flow this is what those
data points look like when they're
trapped we don't need to know people's
names we don't need to know where they
came from so data security wise it's
relatively light and we do not pick what
the most important rumors are it's not
about prevalence because it really
doesn't matter if most people believe
that the moon is made of green cheese
but it might matter if somebody believes
that this border is open and they can
cross it when they can't or that it's
safe to bury a body after Ebola those
are going to be dangerous causes of
action so in analyzing this data we look
for we have to make a kind of a
journalistic almost editorial decisions
about which rumors even if small may
lead to endangering behaviors these are
the kinds of places that we go to look
for quotes commentary fact-checking etc
and now we have our fact-checking
Network partners which is wonderful
these are typically the kind of people
who would go to and we produce bulletins
that look we produce bulletins for the
community the bulletins reflect back the
rumor and exactly the way it was
expressed to us in the lingo in the
local
go of the place in Liberia it was called
Deise which is they say which is the
local you know slang for the word on the
street or suck D suck Frei in Haiti what
is said and what is true we create a
bulletin that goes to local media local
influences local content producers
whoever they may go over they may be
Imams and others and then for
humanitarians this is really important
this could be local government it could
be national government it could be these
off this is for service providers
because service providers find it so
fascinating and useful to understand
what people are saying because very
often they're not saying anything
necessarily about the virus itself but
they're saying something about the
quality of service and information that
they're receiving and the level of trust
that they have in it so we have there
there it is the rumor at the top
Anonymous but with a reference to
location here comes the fact that we
have fact-checked somehow with a quote
and then we have a referral here you can
go for more information here you can go
to find somebody who will take action
for you and so this loop needs to
continue we never take data from the
from people without going back to them
with some sorts of answers referrals and
information for follow-up and I assume
because you're standing there my time is
out Thanks
[Applause]