well it's great to be here with you all
today I am a recovering academic not
current academic my PhD and masters are
both in public health but I'm the CEO of
a public health nonprofit we have an
office here in DC New York Atlanta and
San Diego or about 40 people half of
them are public health practitioners and
then the remaining staff are media and
marketing people and what we do every
day is large-scale behavior change
programs for public health we only work
on public health programs and then we do
public health program programs campaigns
and we do a lot of media monitoring we
were founded in 2013 and we basically
anything under the umbrella of health
communication were involved in so we
have people here from the NIH we were
the organization that told the NHS story
about building 10 on the Discovery
Channel and then we also do these these
larger sort of big data programs around
misinformation which is why I'm here
today
it's really nice to be here in a room
full of people who study misinformation
and work in this space that's not often
the case for me normally I'm presenting
to your more classic public health
audience and so there's a lot of
catch-up that the audience has to do to
understand what I'm saying so I'm going
to skip all that catch up today we work
on basically a huge portfolio of public
health programs it's sort of the gamut
as many things as a Health Department
does we're involved in and I'm gonna
jump right to a program that we run
called project vector project vector at
the moment PGP public good projects is
the only organization the United States
that monitors continuously 24 hours a
day seven days a week every day that
year vaccine misinformation so there are
a lot of organizations that do this we
provide it in real time to health
organizations across the country and our
pilot program was established in the
state of New York so we monitor all data
from publicly available media sources so
any social media data we can get our
whole
our hands-on but also television like
broadcast news print so newspapers and
magazines pretty much every website just
anything we can purchase and analyze
using big data techniques which I won't
go into during this talk about which I
will happily talk about my 3:30 workshop
so project vector was set up
specifically for vaccine misinformation
and I'm going to show you how it works
this is a real-time technology
demonstration so we'll see if it
actually functions okay
this is something that public you also
see how many tabs I have open at any
given moment it's it's just like my
apartment I know where everything is but
if you move it a little bit than I've
lost it so this is an example of what we
pull weekly so so how this works is we
have big data mechanisms behind the
scenes here and this is a public website
that requires a password to access to
get a password we have to know who you
are and vet you and that is because
anti-vaxxers are not nice people so I
get the previous panel empathy is where
we need to start but if you've been on
the front lines of this it's not a
friendly debate so it's very different
than being in a one-on-one interaction
in a doctor's office if you're if you're
doing this on a larger scale like a
population scale they find where you
live they find your friends and family
and they attack you so we have to do
precautions on any data sharing that we
do because we always assume an
unfriendly audience is going to get hold
of the data but we do our best to
mitigate that as much as we can we
filter this data according to national
level and then upstate New York and the
rest of New York is there anyone here
from New York City okay few of you so
upstate New York is not New York anymore
and so we like I said every week we we
update this and what we're doing is
we're not focusing on pro-vaccine
information or neutral information
related to vaccines we're interested
specifically in anti vaccination
information and we found some
interesting things through the through
this process one it shifts as the news
cycle shifts so right now anti-vaxxers
are really interested in coronavirus and
then if you zoom in to specific hotspots
in the United States their interest
changes depending upon a particular bill
so everything about the anti vaccination
argument becomes about what's happening
in a particular moment in time as a
public health person I can say this is
one of the things public health is
horrible add is adapting quickly I would
also like to point out that what has
changed over the last 15 years if you
think about it have vaccines gotten less
safe or less effective no the only thing
that's changed and the reason there is a
manufactured debate about vaccines is
because of the proliferation and the
ease of misinformation so I think it's
important if you're on the public health
side of this thing to remember that the
facts haven't changed and this all
happened under our watch so all of the
techniques that we were using 20 years
ago saying that we're gonna double down
and just do those techniques more often
it's probably not gonna be the right
answer because this all happened while
we were doing all of those techniques
and while we're continuing to do them
from 20 years ago
I think we need a really really dramatic
change in our tactics and when I talk to
people who follow this thing closely or
we go to City Council meetings and have
a bunch of people in red shirts show up
and scream at them they agree with me
and I think if you talk to people like
that are on the vaccine expert advisory
panel for CDC they are saying very dire
things things on the scale of a climate
scientists we're behind the eight ball
we don't know what we're doing we need
help we need dramatic changes and
strategies and tactics so we often see
this conflict is this friction between
the measured Public Health approach that
we're trained in school to project and
then the reality of a growing
anti-vaccination movement it is not
plateaued and things are getting worse
and I don't think we can solve this
problem without acknowledging that
things are getting worse every day not
they're not getting better
all of the techniques that we just heard
about and the last panel may or may not
be effective but they're not being
scaled if we found effective solutions
they are not occurring at all on a
national level or even a local level and
that's that's really really clear in the
data here there are a few recurring
themes over and over and over again and
there are a few recurring people over
and over and over again that are
responsible for the overwhelming
majority of
misinformation that people succumb to
and then become anti-vaccination they're
very identifiable they're very loud and
they don't want to be hidden it's what
do we do with them once we find them
that's the real question though that
we're faced with so you feel free if
you're in the audience to sign up for a
project vector right now this is
information that's happening right now
in this week there's a lot of conspiracy
theories about coronavirus as was
mentioned there the thing in Maine right
now is skewing everything so and news
organizations aren't helping
I think news organizations are actually
working really well most the time on the
side of science but in Maine for some
reason probably because it's Maine and
Maine's weird they all the local news
organizations are saying big pharma is
pushing an agenda and it should just get
vaccinated so that's a weird it's it's
kind of hard to predict state-by-state
how this thing goes but I want to show
you some of the things that we learned
doing this project
here are the top authors on Twitter that
create over 60% of all misinformation
about vaccines so it's really easy in
public health to feel like the I can't
figure out what's going on here it feels
like every single day there's new
information I don't know what to do I
don't know how to look to look at them
if they're real easy they want you to
know who they are the question is what
do you do like I said we need effective
techniques and it's not cutting the head
it might be cutting the head off the
snake
off of this Hydra but social media
companies don't want to do that for
probably really good reasons but so what
what techniques do we use as a public
health community and how do we do a lot
better job of getting the public the
silent majority the middle of the
american public middle of that belt that
bell curve activated most people are in
favor of vaccines but they're not doing
anything there is sitting on the
sidelines we haven't given them
something to do and in public health
forums we still talk about it like it's
our job it isn't our job our job is just
if you're a public health organization
or institution your job is to stick to
your facts and probably we're like that
cool Navy looking suit and stand and
read your PowerPoint there's a thing
that the public needs to be given to do
it needs to be activated and if you
think of other movements marriage
equality sexual harassment racism all of
these societal movements all have an
identifiable theme and identifiable
identity and people can join it and feel
like they have equity in it but right
now we're not giving the public any
equity in the vaccine debate if you look
at themes used by the top authors the
top anti-vaxxers on twitter here's what
they talk about and when you can dig
further and further into this like I
said it kind of fluctuates week by week
month by month but this is this tends to
be where they were they land on so a lot
of policy discussions so again this kind
of flies in the face a lot of what you
hear from public health people who don't
track this every day they're actually
like the the individual incessant
attention to every ingredient in a
vaccine is not the largest thing
anti-vaxxers used to argue with you it
might be in a doctor's office but it's
not on the population scale so potential
messaging strategies let's take one
thing I also never hear is us learning
from other movements so the people
Public Health again like where I love us
but we're really siloed we silo
ourselves when is the last time an
epidemiologist talked to a health
communications person in the same office
where they speak different languages and
they don't know how to talk to each
other so now take that on a much larger
scale the vaccine people never talk to
the tobacco control people and the
tobacco control people never talk to the
people who work on sexual and
reproductive health totally different
conferences so now it's even harder to
look outside of this and look at other
movements but here's an example from
counterterrorism the State Department
right here in DC attempted to counter
terrorist propaganda across social media
a few years ago this is relatively
recent and they started with a group
called the Center for Strategic
counterterrorism communications it was a
horrible dismal disaster well documented
by good investigative journalism and the
reason it was a horrible failure was the
State Department used its own accounts
to start arguing with terrorists online
let that sink in for a second it was
amazing and the examples are still there
present it would be like someone who's
recruiting for Isis would get a gif of
an American flag and and the State
Department would say you're wrong
America is the best country on Earth or
I have some screen grabs here we would
insult their English proficiency so this
all fell apart and then what they did
was they switched to the global
engagement center which is what's
running right now and the global
engagement center has a totally
different tactic interestingly enough it
was co-created by a marketing person
from New York rather than it's like
military people at the State Department
so global engagement center which I
received no money from by the way and
instead said actually probably the
majority of people in the world don't
like terrorists
so why don't we just give data and
support to the vast majority of people
and organizations in every country who
deplore terrorism and extremism and
since they've been doing that the amount
of terrorists messaging on social media
has gone down dramatically and it's none
of it has the State Department's logo on
it it's because they started treating
people like partners and stakeholders in
their own lives and and got away from
this viewpoint of we control what
happens when when terrorism pops up I
think we should do that for vaccines and
I don't see that happening very often
there's not a lot of health departments
out there who are bringing in all of the
people locally who are pro science who
can be identified as a potential ally
and arming them with information than
sending them out do also this is from
our data but almost no religions
prohibit vaccines the involvement of the
faith community is almost nil so we need
to do a better job of engaging with the
faith community professional
associations and thought leaders
chiropractors are a huge problem and
nobody's talking about it for some
reason I don't know why maybe it's
because we allow them to wear white lab
coats for some reason and other
countries by the way don't but
chiropractors in a core part of a
chiropractor's training is that your
solutions for your medical problems
shouldn't come from your body not from
the outside so there are two
professional associations that represent
chiropractic in the United States and
one of them is openly against vaccines
on its website and we don't do anything
about it and we also let those
chiropractors walk around in hospitals
giving people medical advice so if you
look for people who are doctors online
who are arguing against vaccines they
are often not a medical doctor or a
public health researcher like myself
they are a chiropractor then you have
social media influencers we don't use
them at all so we try to get we we often
publish our research in peer-reviewed
journals and one of the most common
critiques I get back from editors is it
will be explaining how we mobilized
communities
public health purpose and we use social
media influencers as part of this and
then I'll get I'll get questions back
from a viewer saying explain to me what
social media influencers are and why do
I do those matter I need a lot more
evidence on why you should include this
in your paper or why this is a good
methodology what I would like to say
back to them and what I'll say here is
brands in this year in 2020 are expected
to spend 15 billion dollars on
influencer marketing that is the only
citation that I need we have we can
learn a lot from other sectors brands
are not stupid people who work in
marketing are not stupid they're using
their own research to inform their own
decision making and where their dollars
go and they have a lot more dollars and
more resources than public health has so
I think we have things to learn from
other groups we talk about cross sector
collaboration a lot in public health
that like I said earlier that tends to
stop it
I talked to an epidemiologist and then
mass appeal that was my earlier point
just make it so that people can get
involved
we have no human rights campaign we have
no 350.org we have no one campaign where
where the hell is the campaign that's
pro science it doesn't exist so when
you're thinking about what to do
government can do certain things and
then the rest of society can do other
things and I'm going to show you an
example on the next slide I don't I'm
not personally convinced but I would
love to see data and I know people are
gonna study it is it worth the CDC's
time to go refute things at an
individual level I used to work at CDC I
worked in the center for tobacco control
I worked on CDC's one large campaign the
tips and former smokers campaign it is
really hard work and it is thankless
work and no one likes you so I often
have that quote that survey reported
back to me that 80% of the American
public believe you know trust the CDC
I'm really dubious about that to be
totally honest it's it's often trust in
comparison to other federal agencies
great I don't know if that's a
Inchon that I would want its versus USDA
and CDC I guess I have a vague
understanding of what USDA does so it's
easy because they're in movies and
they're in their cool suits it's it's a
really tough one and and what we see in
the data every day is that there's a lot
of erosion of public trust in
institutions and this is not new
information there's a reason the
administration looks the way that it
does there's a reason the world looks
the way that it looks right now so
relying too much on if you put a
government logo on it people are going
to trust it I think would be a huge
mistake because again that's what we
have been doing for 20 years and this
happened while we were doing that so
look at this this is from today this is
on the CDC's account talking about the
flu vaccine all of the comments are
negative all of the comments are
anti-vaxxers except for maybe one like
one innocent person that just goes to
doses and then everybody else this thing
you're lying you're taking money from
pharma it's just it's this constant
stream of vitriol directed toward the
CDC and I know that the reason I
understand all the biases here but my
point is if you are a member of the
public and and our our response to the
vaccine debate is defer to the CDC then
what someone gets when they go there is
a thread of the CDC is wrong that's a
really really big problem so it can feel
like this right now if you're in the
middle of this whole thing and there's a
in our in our in our own work it feels
like this a lot but I think to go back
to my point I wanted to show you share
you one example from from our work and
then I'll stop this is a flu promotion
campaign funded by Kaiser Permanente so
it's across eight states in the District
of Columbia and it's focused on vacci
traditionally vaccine hesitant
communities communities that are vaccine
hesitant for really damn good reasons
Latin X and african-american communities
so it's not focused on Santa Monica or
Portland so and that's probably why we
were successful what we got here was if
you if you just mobile we had 120 people
who accounted as influential in their
cities that they lived in and so we
selected a social-media influencer based
upon the zip code that they lived in and
who their followers were I have no
concern with who this person is as an
individual I'm concerned about who they
reach and what we found were every
single time one of these people said
here is why I'm personally getting a flu
the flu vaccine this year they had an
average of 500 comments on every single
post that they made and 93% of those
comments were positive so if you
juxtapose that with what the with the
CDC's there is something to learn from
that there we also evaluated this sort
of a case control and we had
statistically significant shifts and
knowledge and attitudes and behaviors
related to vaccination in these
communities as opposed to communities
that didn't receive the intervention so
this again though it's not large enough
scaled it's across eight states but we
need to get it much bigger and I would
love to stop being questioned about the
use of an engaging real human beings and
the work of Public Health so that's it I
think I'm thinking about time thank you
very much