everybody thanks for coming thanks for
organizing this great conference the
talks have been fantastic I've learned
so much I've got a bunch of story ideas
too for follow up so I'm here to talk
about the whole problem of fake news and
fake accusations that the real news is
fake news and how journalists are trying
to deal with that and respond to it it
increased trust to increase the spread
of real information and do whatever we
can to compete against misinformation to
improve the signal-to-noise ratio like
all of us are here to try to do better
it's hard to remember but the term fake
news is fairly recent it isn't something
people used to say there was an analysis
by the Committee to Protect Journalists
recently looking at Trump's tweets they
there are a lot of charts there's so
much data to work with when you look at
his tweets and with this this is a
color-coded analysis of what sorts of
insults he has against the press and so
they used to be you know rich and varied
and about all kinds of things usually
about specific reporters who would
insult and then right up to the election
the red bars are the term fake news and
so he started saying this more often and
now you know most days he tweets about
how were the enemy of the people which
that's in yellow and then a more recent
talking point is calling the press the
opposition party and that's why I going
to increase as the as the election gets
closer so that's just the background
that's what people are hearing and so
what do we do about that how do we fight
that and so what journalists across the
board are trying to do more of is is
show our work so how we know we know why
are we telling you this where did we get
the information and the one of the
workshops this afternoon is on the
transparency project at science news and
they're doing a really good job of this
for adults and for for younger readers
and then you know there's been so much
science on misinformation research you
know academic research all the sorts of
studies we've been hearing about today
so we've report on that as a subject of
of stories of journalism to kind of help
people understand where's the
misinformation coming from why are they
seeing so much of it and then we use
that research to inform our own
presentation of facts
and how we do our headlines especially
is something that we really think about
how can we use the principles of
misinformation research to make sure
we're doing it right and not wrong and
then how do these our principles apply
to coronavirus because we've been you
know scrambling to do that right and to
do all these things as we cover
coronavirus so to show how we do our
work we simply and one of the things
Trump keeps saying is that the news just
makes up sources makes up stories
there's no anonymous sources so we
basically just explained how autonomous
sources are why why do they need to stay
anonymous what's the relationship like
how do we know they're real
we don't just take their word for what
they're saying and then we also well one
of the ways that we try to fight
misinformation is there's so much bad
health and misinformation and so we run
a lot of stories trying to expose
especially things that harm people like
stem-cell clinics and in this story we
this is another sort of showing our work
we have what we call like a did it
section as and this is how we did it
where we say you know we had telephone
scripts internal memos emails we talked
to doctors nurses patient coordinators
this is why this is who spoke on the
record this is who didn't this is why
and then we looked at documents we went
back to the company so basically just
saying again and again we really know
this and it's partly to gain people's
trust so they know they can believe
what's in the article and then it's also
so don't get sued because people like to
see us now that Jeff Bezos owns us and
then another thing we're trying to do is
distinguish between news and opinion and
just label and this is across journalism
you'll see a lot of publications now
sticking the word opinion or the
analysis or a first-person or
perspective at the beginning of a title
especially when it's shared on social
media because it's really hard for
people to know the difference and know
you know that the editorial staff has a
completely different structure from the
news staff and a lot of times they
publish things that I don't think are
true or that literally aren't true but
that they still publish them because
they have a different kind of way of
thinking about how they share
information and then we you know we
cover a lot of the excellent research
that's been done on how
fake news spreads who is spreading it
how quickly it goes to kind of help
readers understand this phenomenon and
then one of the things that's one of the
principles that replicates really well I
think in the in the misinformation
literature is the idea that if you're
going to tell somebody that they're
wrong or that this belief or this idea
is is not true you need to tell them
what is true as you know as quickly as
you can and as closely as you can to
where you debunk the myth and so this
isn't actually my headline it's another
department but this this story did
really well and I think it it set that
up that you know this fat burning heart
zone thing that a lot of people were
buzzing about at the time you've heard
about this it's not true we're going to
tell you what really does work and of
course it's you know pretty simple
there's no secret you have to exercise
and eat less which is too bad and you
know one of the things about the
anti-vaccine movement is it try it as
we've talked about a lot today it tries
to project this idea that it's just a
grassroots movement and all these people
are concerned and shouldn't you be
worried too because all your friends and
neighbors are worried and so there was a
nice study showing look tracking
tracking the money following the money
and yeah there's just two groups this is
Robert F Kennedy jr. and his group is
one and that's where most of the money
comes from so that's really who's
fueling it and that's partly so so
people understand that it's not it's not
a broadly distributed things still most
people know that vaccines are right
there's just a few bad actors who are
really trying to stimulate mistrust and
then you know another another thing with
with misinformation is it really helps
people know not to trust something if
they can be shown why somebody is lying
to you and so this is a we did a big
story about Joseph Mercola and he's
lying to you because he could make a ton
of money making people think that if
they buy his vitamin C supplements that
they can protect themselves from measles
and it's much you know much better than
getting a vaccine so I'm showing that
motivation kind of helps people question
what they're hearing from the anti-tax
movement and so this brings us to
coronavirus this is just a screenshot of
the
the homepage of the Washington Post and
for the past several weeks we've had it
what's called a live blog and that's the
thing up in the corner this live updates
and we this so we keep constantly
updating this with you know as news
comes in from around the world is a
timezone shift where the you know what's
happening in the research where the new
case counts what are the you know new
recommendations and it's been sort of
top of people's minds and we're finding
people are really really interested
that's people are just constantly paying
attention to this and it's a little bit
of a feedback loop because you know if
we put it above the you know digital
fold it's right there in people's faces
if they come to the homepage and the
constant updating makes it get more
attention from Google because news is
breaking and so then people pay more
attention to it so it gets more traffic
and so that that gets more Google
searches to your so it's been this this
constant loop it's legitimately a huge
news story but we have to kind of think
about you know at what when should we
say this is this parts really alarming
this part is just a you know kind of
boring update and you know when there's
something happening that everybody's
paying attention to and there's a lot of
confusion about that's just a perfect
situation for misinformation and so one
of the ways to sort of disarm the disarm
misinformation and help people kind of
cope with the lack of information is to
say what we do and don't know and that's
often really a very effective method
when you're communicating about science
you know people have a lot of questions
it's just super disarming to say well
this is something scientists don't know
yet this is something they want to know
here's a couple ideas but they're not
sure what the answer is they'll figure
it out or if they're hoping to figure it
out and then then you can kind of focus
on what is known and people are a little
less kind of spun up about the the
questions they have like telling people
that there isn't an answer to a question
is the answer to the question in some
situations and so we've done about three
three articles like this and we're doing
them pretty much every week on just
updating what's what's the latest and
the science is moving incredibly fast so
Reuters the other day did a
really nice graphic presentation of just
the scientific literature on coronavirus
and you can see the the kovat 19 you can
see this is just the number of papers
published so it's happening really fast
everybody's trying to get their data out
there sequencing it they're testing drug
candidates they're you know
characterizing it talking about case
studies or clusters and what's nice is
that a lot of the journals have dropped
their paywalls for these it's very it's
it's just everybody's really really
working hard and working fast and trying
to share information and being very
generous with their information but what
that means is there's a lot of stuff
that gets out that turns out to not be
true in this this rush to share and so
this in this graphic the yellow pages
are the papers that aren't peer reviewed
the white ones are and then some of the
black marked through ones or papers have
been withdrawn so there's just it's it's
it's hard to sort out what's real and
what's not legitimately without any bad
actors and this is another chart from
that same analysis looking at the let's
see the the x-axis is the number of
tweets the y-axis is news article links
so you know I like to think the news
article links are more legit in the
tweets who knows and the one outlier is
a paper suggesting that the virus was
related to HIV which it wasn't I think
as far as I could tell it was a legit
just error but that that kind of you
know surprising news spreads really fast
on social media even though it's been
retracted and so we you know as part of
our coverage we've published I imagine
at least a thousand articles by now if
you include that blog post we tried to a
lot of a lot of publications are trying
to equip people to recognize what the
misinformation is and how it's spreading
and why so we cover that and BuzzFeed
News had a really really nice list they
did it they did a great job there were
some of the first to jump on the list of
the disinformation and where did it come
from and how do we know it's false and
just made it really simple for people to
see you know if this is coming around in
your Facebook feed this is what this is
why we know it's not true and it's not
true and here's here's why so this is
this kind of it
equipped readers to quickly tamp down
you know there are social media
connections and share real information
which I love the the study earlier today
showing that that can be really
effective not just for the person who
shared it and maybe not for the person
who shared it originally but for
everybody who's watching the correction
of their acquaintances and they do so in
one of them we've talked about before
the you know there's all these miracle
cure Kaede claims a lot of it from the
anti-vaccine movement there never was a
situation so bad that somebody from the
anti-vaccine movement couldn't show up
and make it a lot worse so this is this
is from BuzzFeed's
list and they they put a red X through
the false things which is just a nice
visual cue of yeah this looks like it's
legitimate it looks like there's
evidence but it's completely wrong the
problem is like reality is really just
as bizarre as the stuff that's made up
so this is true the South Korea spike
like more than two-thirds and I think
now it's like three-quarters of the
cases in South Korea are linked to a
really just sect which is a newspaper
way of saying cult the heads the the
leader decodes the Bible to find
messages of an impending apocalypse
which is so cinematic but it's it's also
true so it's hard for readers to know
what what's legit and what's not so we
try to you know when when there is
something like this it's just so bizarre
but also true then we certainly
certainly cover it and then I mentioned
headlines you know it took journalists a
while to realize that you have to debunk
the myth in the headline you can't just
say you know politician X said Y Z you
have to say politician X falsely claimed
why is he otherwise you're just passing
along this thing that was said it's true
it was said it's just a thing that's not
true so we're trying constantly to say
debunk fringe conspiracy theory doesn't
always work
senator US Senator Tom cotton repeated
the the myth it was in the last slide
that the corona virus was part of a
biosecurity lab and was a weapon that
was released so he
he did that and so instead of just
saying Tom cotton says that the
coronavirus was made in a secret lab in
China we say you know he's repeating it
it's a conspiracy theory it's already
debunked
- just like tamp it down immediately so
that's what we are doing but you know I
think as everybody is said here it's
it's really the platform's you know the
the more they can do the better because
that's that's where it's spreading the
mainstream media for the most part aside
from the you know the like some of the
main coverage of the the anti-vaccine
bills like sometimes you get clusters of
bad luck or reporting but for the most
part where it's really going bananas is
on the platform so if we can all all
find better ways to do what we can as
individuals to to fight misinformation
but you know it's it's really going to
be algorithm solutions for a lot of this
thank you
[Applause]