all right I will be short and sweet I
know we're getting a little tight on
time now so my name is Rhys O'Neill I am
a senior open source analyst for a
company called at no betta we are based
in the McLean area here in Virginia
I support the National Institutes of
Health
and their Ebola studies that we started
in Liberia and are now in the Democratic
Republic of Congo my company is
primarily DoD facing and I had the
really fortunate opportunity to use some
of these really high-powered well-funded
tools in a humanitarian sense and we've
really made a lot of significant
progress in doing so so just before I
get into kind of how we do it we first
started at the tail end of the bull
outbreak in Liberia where the NIH wanted
to do Ebola studies there a series of
studies that went on for about three
years but they were concerned about the
public sentiment around Ebola in general
kind of would people even show up for
these studies are they going to put a
lot of resources and money into a
program that won't have any
participation and therefore a study
that's not successful so we did ground
assessment we use a field team and off
we'll also look into any kind of open
source data we can get from broadcast
print media social media all the way
down to local leaflets that we can find
in communities so we worked there for
three years by the end of it the kind of
public perception of the prevail Ebola
study program was high enough that we
transitioned to the DRC as that outbreak
picked up and I'll get into that in a
little bit so just to give a kind of
overview of how we do it in general were
media analysis but you know that term
media is getting I think a little more
blurry recently especially with a lot of
these new apps popping up but we look
again print broadcast social media and
kind of local media we can get our hands
on we process it by putting in our own
meta data so we have a human curation
that's tied into machine learning that
allows us to really take in a vast
quantity of data and do it rapidly so we
can assign this you know these little
intricacies to what we pull in and that
looks like you know a certain newspaper
article we'll pull a few quotes all the
quotes from that article we assign
source sentiment location and in topic
so over time we build a pretty
comprehensive database that allows us to
see who's saying what how they're saying
it look at specific groups or citizens
pro this or pro that and it really gives
us good insight into who wins certain
individuals that have a lot of power in
the media speak about a certain subject
how that's going to be disseminated and
then reflected by citizens later on we
provide weekly output reports to the NIH
to kind of help their community
engagement teams on the ground know
what's coming making sure they're not
missing certain pieces of information
and knowing kind of when to stay away
from others so really get around some of
those obstacles and working with
communities in the middle of an Ebola
outbreak so this is kind of our platform
that we're able to visualize all this
data by putting all this together we're
able to see both long term trends which
have become invaluable and kind of rapid
reaction pieces so when damaging
misinformation comes out or in the case
of the DRC quite often security threats
pop up we're able to identify them right
away and let our teams on the ground
know this is what you're facing
you know either evacuate the area or be
prepared to talk about this when you
enter these communities and we had a
really significant win in
the DRC that really is also was
supported really well by the software
group at Nevada as well I was able to
working with my field team access
whatsapp channels and the significance
of that was there was primarily
misinformation on Facebook when we first
started in the DRC in February of 2019
but a lot of criticism popped up about
that and those community conversations
where people were kind of speaking
freely and talking about Ebola response
personnel the MSF whu-oh how they wanted
there was a lot of backlash that started
picking up as more attention was paid to
this misinformation on Facebook and
towards a few months later everybody was
really proud of how they had moved away
from the misinformation on Facebook but
we found it actually transferred on to
whatsapp where they were private
channels and no one could really tell
them what to do working with our field
team we're able to access these channels
and sit down and you know watch these
conversations happen in local
communities that don't happen in a
survey they don't happen when you go out
and approach communities and want to
talk about specific subjects so you know
there's posts about everything from the
local soccer team to you know Donald
Trump being the local hero oddly enough
in the DRC and all the way to Ebola
content so we don't just look at Ebola
content in a silo we're seeing what
everyone's talking about the media
across the board and a lot of times we
would see frustrations with the WH o or
MSF as to why people did know
information or that hasn't gotten out
there when they've been broadcasting on
the radio and things like that because
people didn't care there were security
issues going on where many people are
dying in their communities from rebel
attacks that Ebola is not really an
issue you know even other healthcare
issues were more important in time so it
really helped us to give it give context
to what we were looking at and what we
need to do approach when you can't keep
jamming these communication efforts in
the community
that don't want to hear about Ebola
anymore so it really helped us kind of
contextualize that as we went forward so
kind of a snapshot of some of the stuff
we do with misinformation we're able to
identify kind of where this stuff comes
from and track it through the different
media sources so we're cross-referencing
radio to whatsapp to Facebook to local
print and a lot of times where people
keep talking about whatsapp or Facebook
being the source of the misinformation
it's not really true in a lot of cases
where a little further away from you
know highly densely populated areas
where radio stations kind of get some
information about what's going on but
not everything so they get on their
broadcast and they fill in those gaps
and it's from those pieces of
information that aren't quite accurate
but they're close to the other
information that we see a lot of this
kind of rumor mill build and that
information is taken on to whatsapp and
Facebook and it's spread rapidly and so
because we're doing this
cross-referencing as we've kind of
looked back into some of our historical
data we've identified where these
sources are who are the most prominent
ones starting this misinformation and
how to work backwards and approach those
rumors at its source and move on from
there so I have a few case studies just
to really drive home the point I guess
so in June we came across this story on
whatsapp where you know it really gave a
real-world example as to how damaging
misinformation can be especially in the
frontlines of an epidemic or you know
something as tricky as an Ebola outbreak
in a war-torn area so there wasn't a lot
of trust towards international
responders in the first place but the
information was not getting to local
communities as fast as it should or a
lot of communities didn't want to hear
it so there was an ongoing rumor that
once someone died of Ebola the response
teams would harvest their organs and
send them back to the United States for
a multitude of reasons came out of that
strange line but it got so intense that
people were rating the morgues to bring
their family members home so they didn't
lose their organs and they could
actually you know pass on to the
afterlife that they felt appropriate
because their body was intact should the
organs be removed that wouldn't happen
so in this specific example a man his
brother died they he and a few friends
went and took the body out of the morgue
they were chased by the police they
discard the body but they'd all come in
contact with it and then they dispersed
in their communities so now Ebola
contact moving into a community this was
right for a really large spike in Ebola
cases in the DRC and this is something
that we pass on to our response team
saying hey this is something you need to
pay attention to first of all we need to
address this information but be ready
for increased cases as well and because
we don't take this information in a silo
we look at every kind of subject that we
can we've stumbled onto a really in
intricate security situation as well I'm
sure a lot of you have heard about the
insecurity in the area but that
long-term trend analysis we were able to
start to identify when messaging became
a little more aggressive in social media
channels or even on the radio
specifically on the radio that it was
more likely for an imminent attack
whether it be negative messaging to
international responders it's probably
gonna be a treatment center you know
towards the UN they were going after a
UN facility
even though was not always direct
messaging that came out of that and we
started to see that these spikes came
before an attack and then after an
attack they quickly dropped the final
one is one of these events the
misinformation about a multitude of
things that the international
respondents were doing was pretty
strong but the as they moved into
different communities the the messaging
didn't really change whatever they were
saying in Benning City as they moved
into a smaller region and set up another
treatment center they didn't really
adapt to the local narrative to address
kind of local beliefs as much and quite
often we saw issues like this where they
knew communities get all the negativity
from you know operating facilities in
different regions that have kind of a
wider following or are pushing content
in whatsapp or Facebook and so they're
getting a lot of this misinformation
with no real verification and then a
team walking into their community and
setting up a treatment center in the
middle of town led to a lot of
confrontation and this fortunately for
us was quite often shared on whatsapp
there's somewhat of a gentlemen's code
for Congolese two Congolese that they
the rebels will even share or you know
post this flyer saying we're going to be
here in a tomorrow and attack so I don't
really want to injure anybody but we're
definitely going to burn down this
building so please leave and it serves
as a great warning but it gave us a lot
of insight into what resistance in these
communities can lead to and more
importantly how much misinformation can
impact the work people were doing so the
biggest lessons we learned were
identifying these media narratives early
and being prepared going into these
communities to understand the local
perception was vital in both Liberia and
the DRC more specifically the DRC and in
the feedback loop of when community
engagement happens so doing an initial
assessment knowing that these issues are
going to be confrontational and on the
back end after the communion gateman
happens reassessing and saying hey this
was positive this worked here use these
pieces here and it's going to be
different somewhere else but at least we
know how to be successful in one
location
and then understanding the changes over
time like I said we're really useful in
kind of finding out where we needed to
start paying attention and more
importantly for a lot of these NGOs or
groups working in our outbreak response
is knowing where to allocate resources
there's not a ton of money right off the
bat it's got to get really bad to get
the money in there so knowing when to
approach knowing who's important enough
to approach keeping that you know as a
standard really helps people put
resources in the right way and not spend
money in a way that is going to slow
down response mechanisms as it continues
on and I think I went over time and I
apologize so that's all thank you
[Applause]