everyone thanks for the 10 of you who
are around so yes I'm an assistant
professor in the school of computer
science at Virginia Tech and so this
work is with my amazing students this is
part of a larger threat of work where we
are trying to measure misinformation and
conspiracy theories are that are
surfaced by algorithmic search platforms
and this one specifically looks at
finding misinformation on video search
platform that is in our case we looked
at YouTube so nowadays it is fairly
common to see headlines like this how
YouTube is driving people to the darkest
corners of the internet how Google is
directing people to extreme content and
then you see these op-ed that YouTube is
a create radicalize er right and then
you also see YouTube responding by
saying they're reducing conspiracy
theory recommendations are that they are
making conspiracy videos really hard to
find but all these reports and responses
all of these are fairly anecdotal that
is there is not enough hard empirical
statistical evidence to prove any of
these anecdotal stories and and also to
disprove any of these counter responses
so that is what the goal of our study
was in order to verify some of these
adding total claims criticizing YouTube
for surfacing problematic content on its
platform so the question is does
YouTube's search and recommendation
algorithm really surfaces these
problematic content and then what are
the conditions under which it it does
that and the way we did it is by
conducting systematic audits on on
YouTube's algorithm and we picked one
type of problematic content that is
conspiracy theories so these are the
questions that our work answered so very
specific and like some of the other
studies president this morning not that
broad but the first question was looked
at this this question of does the users
demographics let's say their age or
gender and the location from which they
are querying the search engine YouTube
search a video search platform does that
have an effect on the amount of
misinformation that YouTube is reduce
YouTube search and recommendation
algorithm is returning the next question
is the question of watch history so what
happens when the user has watched
some videos let's say all-pro conspiracy
video are all debunking or all neutral
videos what happens under those scenario
does the platform return more or less
misinformation and in the final piece
here is is there any difference across
the topics that is what happens if it's
user researching for vaccine versus
flatter to said effect difference in the
amount of misinformation returned so
this is our entire audit framework and
so I'm gonna briefly go into each of
these steps so the first we started with
selecting a search topics and our goal
here was to make sure that the topics
that we are auditing are these high
impact misinformation search topics and
so that is lots of people have searched
from them so forth and so it has some
high impact impacting several people and
that these topics should also have some
definitive false value right and so how
do we determine that so we went with
Wikipedia and then Wikipedia's list of
conspiracy theories is a human curated
list of a definite false conspiracy
theories so that's was our starting
point and then to figure out whether
some of these theories are have been
affecting lots of people that whether
they are period whether they're popular
or not we went with Google Trends and so
Google Trends we fed these let's say you
feed 9/11 conspiracy theories you you
fix the United States we are only
concerned about what happens in the US
and then we looked at a two years time
span 2016 to 2018 and then YouTube as
our search service of choice and then we
looked at whether there are some form of
trend in the data so here you of course
you see a 9/11 search is going up at
during the September timeline but
overall people are consistently
searching for this topic for two years
we saw the same thing for some other
theories like the moon landing
conspiracy theories you see these
consistent trend lines so doing this is
combining Wikipedia's data and the
Google Trends trend analysis we came up
with five topics for our audit analysis
this was 9/11 conspiracy theories the
vaccine conspiracy theories moon landing
chemtrail conspiracy theories and flat
earth our next step was to select
search queries that present these topics
these myths informative topics and for
that we used two different sources of
data
the first was YouTube's Auto suggestions
so you feed YouTube with some seed query
representing that topic and then collect
the top 10 suggestions that the platform
provides this kind of tells us that we
are focusing on the trending search
queries that's happening in YouTube at
that time and then we also went with
Google Trends and then also collected
for that topic what are the related
queries that people have searched so
again high-impact Karelian query
perennial queries right so combining
both of them formed our set of search
queries for a particular topic that we
then used for conducting our audits
right so we're finally ready to launch
our audits with these two parameters in
place and so our audits essentially
comprised of two sets of experiments
first was a search shorted experiments
this was for auditing their search
algorithm and here the audits were
conducted with brand new Google or
YouTube accounts that is these accounts
were emulating how real people would be
searching the platform and then the
watch audits were conducted with
accounts that had already built some
form of watch history by watching
conspiratorial videos of certain stance
right and then we audited the three
different components of YouTube the
search results component this was for
auditing their social Garthim and for
recommendations we audited the YouTube
and the top five recommendation
algorithm so coming back to our first
research question does age and gender
and geolocation have any effect so for
doing this sort of audits we focused on
four different age groups then the
gender was male female and in order to
do this we created different accounts
which emulated these different personas
right so age or our male or female and
then for geolocation we found what are
the hot and the cold locations right
what do I mean by that these are the
regions which have the highest so hot or
the lowest or low interest in a
particular topic right so and we found
these hot and cold locations by using
these Google's interest over time graph
so the darker locations are these hot
regions lots of interest and the lighter
are these cold region less interest for
that topic so this is this
how it looks for all the topics here so
if you look at flattered that someone on
the hot region that we selected was
Montana a cold region New Jersey and so
on right and so once we had these
regions defined then we created BOTS
to fire these queries from IP addresses
from these locations that's how we are
conducting our audits so this is a
little more detail into our search audit
experiment
lots of the lots of patek see over there
but essentially this is how Ursuline we
created our scripted selenium BOTS which
behave like normal users logged into
YouTube search like normal users and and
then on the back end
there were scripts which were collecting
the results that the that the search
platform was returning for the watch
experiments slightly different so these
were while in the previous one these
were really brand new accounts which in
with no history they were searching but
for watch experiments these accounts had
already built their watch history so
either by watching promoting videos
debunking or neutral and we purposely
made it a little more conservative here
we made the accounts some of the
accounts watch all promoting videos some
watch all debunking and then some watch
all neutral and they watch 20 videos for
four before building up their watch
history and then it was essentially the
same similar selenium bought design it
acted like a like a real user a fire of
the query and our and our platform or
our scripts were collecting what kind of
search results the platform this was
giving and then what kind of
recommendations the the YouTube platform
was giving we also control for noise
this was really important because you
might say that okay the results that
you're seeing is because of certain
noise maybe maybe the the two different
accounts use different browsers or
different kind of times when they were
sending out those queries so your
results are affected by this noise so we
made sure that we control for all these
all these noise variables so all the
accounts were firing queries at the same
time so controlling for the temporal
effects they were all using Firefox this
was again selected on purpose so that we
can avoid the possibility that Chrome
browser would be tracking
these Google accounts that we are using
in our experiment all the searches were
done in incognito mode and they were all
using the same sort of same operating
systems the same infrastructure right so
once we had this entire audit set up it
ran for several days and then we
collected our data and annotated it so
we had overall for this audit collected
56,000 videos 2000 of about 2.3 thousand
of them were unique videos and then we
manually annotated these videos as
either promoting conspiracies are or
they were neutral like just talking
about the you know say 9/11 like
reporting about it but not really
talking about any conspiracy and then
they were debunking some of these
conspiracy theories right so that's how
we annotated and then we did some
statistical comparison tests on this
annotated data right so skipping the
statistical test that we did but you all
might be wondering what's the result of
these these or it's that that's what we
what drove this study in the first place
so let's look at the the first research
question so does demographics age and
gender and us geolocation have any
effect on the amount of misinformation
returned so first good news or bad news
how you already want to take this but
first thing we found that was that for
search audit that's when someone is is a
brand new account brand new Google
account there is no a significant effect
of Democratic Sen geolocation it doesn't
matter what age what gender they belong
where their geolocation is it doesn't
matter they are gonna get same type of
information so there is no significant
difference right so this sort of
disproves some of the initial evidence
that these anecdotal stories had had
said earlier right but things start
getting interesting when we add watch
history to it right so so for the watch
it experiment we found out yes there are
in fact significant effects for certain
combinations of what kind of videos the
accounts are warning watching and then
you know what what type of algorithm
that we are auditing so I'm gonna give
you a quick preview of some of the
results so among all the cases that we
found one overall theme theme was men
were really so accounts which whose
general said as male they were again
recommended
or misinformation videos and then men
who were watching neutral videos they
also ended up with higher recommendation
for probe conspiracy or misinformation
videos so if and this was happening for
especially those two rows that are
marked here the flatter than a vaccine
conspiracy videos and I think this
result is really concerning because
these were users who were drawn to
neutral information that is they were
watching neutral videos and had not yet
developed any sort of strong Crowe
conspiracy belief yet the algorithm the
video you know YouTube's top five
recommendation algorithm I can't really
see the timer eleven minutes left or
eleven minutes okay alright and so right
so which means that it might increase
their these sort of recommendations
might increase their chances of fromming
Pro conspiracy beliefs alright so the
next question was does watch history
watching Pro debunking neutral videos
have any effect perhaps something which
would be most interesting for this
audience is related to health
misinformation so we found that watching
promoting anti vaccine videos actually
resulted in receiving more promoting
anti vaccine videos in the search
results right so compared to those who
watch neutral and debunking and this
aligns with some of those stories that
we have heard before but wait for the
interesting bit in the next part so what
happens for the top five and the up next
recommendation recommended videos right
so what happens for the recommender
algorithm there we found an opposite
effect that is accounts that watched
promoting anti vaccine videos got
recommended more debunking videos right
so it essentially says that YouTube has
gone and changed their they recommender
algorithm but not the search algorithm
and then we looked at another topic like
chemtrails so this this one actually we
found the opposite effect where accounts
that watched videos promoting chemtrails
they got they got recommended more
promoting videos so this tells that
YouTube while they have fixed vaccine
controversies they have not really fixed
chemtrails conspiracy video right so so
it's essentially the third question sort
of I already answered is there any
difference across topics again chemtrail
is a leader in in terms of significantly
more
formative search results compared to all
the other topics same scenario for the
watch experiment as well for 9/11
conspiracy also we found there are
significantly more misinformation in the
up next as well as the top five
recommendations compared to all the
other topics
alright so wrapping up here so what are
the takeaway and contributions of this
work so this through this work we were
able to develop a methodology to audit
search engines for misinformation and
hopefully this method can be adopted for
future audits for other platforms as
well and then we won the first ones to
kind of do the systematic investigation
of the effect of personalization
attributes so by personalization I mean
what's the gender age and the watch
history do they have any real effect on
the way in in the way the algorithm or
the video search platform is is
recommending content and absolutely also
identified these vulnerable populations
for example in our case we found men who
were watching neutral Flattr it's a
videos were recommended more Pro
conspiracy videos so so we kind of this
these audits could also be a mechanism
for finding vulnerable populations who
could be targets for these
misinformation topics and then we were
also statistically able to prove how
YouTube's behavior changes across
different informative topics right so
what are the implications of this
finding right so this this kind of tell
said YouTube's mechanism for handling
this information is more reactive than
proactive so they are reacting and hand
picking topics which have come under the
highlighted by media and popular press
and and their so their strategy is much
more reactive right they are going to
fix vaccine controversies but not really
chemtrails or 9/11 or other
controversies which have not been talked
about by technology critics and media
reports and then even for vaccine
controversy so it's it's more nuanced
than that right so we found that YouTube
while it recommends debunking videos
when someone is searching for anti
vaccine the that the same thing doesn't
happen for its search algorithm there is
a filter bubble which exists in a search
results person who is searching a brand
new account searching for anti vaccine
videos are gonna get search results that
are anti vaccine in the first place so
finally to conclude what we see what I
started with YouTube's claims to reduce
conspiracy theory
recommendations it turns out they still
have a long way to go before they can
claim that they have actually mitigated
the problem of misinformation conspiracy
on their platform that's it thank you
and a daughter 15 minutes and that's
that those are all the questions that I
answered and I'm happy to take any more
questions from the audience if there is
time
[Applause]
so I think there was a paper a couple of
months ago which was also bashed twice
ever like academics that this the paper
doesn't have a good statistical
significance or like it's not done in
the rigorous way so you know so that's
there but I think with this kind of
audit method you could set up an
experiment to test exactly what you're
trying to say with of course with
artificial accounts right so this
doesn't again there's a caveat here
you're not measuring real user behavior
like it's really hard to claim that a
user is only going to search 20 pro
conspiracy videos before they search the
next next video on any topic right but
in order to have at least in a very
conservative world you can make these
measurements by setting these conditions
right so accessing youtubes our
Facebook's algorithm to figure how its
behaving so that's a good question so we
probably have few people in the audience
from the industry so I think in the in
their defense even they don't know how
the the algorithm always works with the
data of the person right the data of the
user so so even if you were to be given
the source code of the algorithm and you
try to go through it you can only answer
so many questions but there is this
factor of users data along with it which
adds this additional complexity which I
think you could only measure through
audits but correct me from the audience
of anybody's from YouTube or Facebook if
I'm not if I miss coding that fact yeah
yeah so he's nodding his head so I'll
take that as a yes
yeah yeah the popularity was one thing
we measured and I don't have the results
I didn't show the results but yes
popularity like number of likes comments
upward all of those did have an effect
yeah but happy to chat more about that
later
yeah thank you
[Applause]