the IPR policy and in contributions that
you should make to the ITF please
familiarize yourself with our policy I
think probably by this point in a week
most of you have already seen this
possibly over a hundred times during
your career here at the ITF for
everybody who thinks they've seen the
note well more than a hundred times
please raise your hand okay keep your
hands raised if you're if it's more than
200 times alright I think we're think
we're well covered for most of you but
for the small number of people who have
not seen it at least a hundred times
please remember to note well in the
event of an IPR emergency please seek a
lawyer do not seek your chairs seek a
lawyer all right so uh thank you for
letting us know yeah well did jeans
today cause tomorrow i gotta with a big
t-shirt joe could you send a note to
knock and see if i can find the media
folks or if you could check in the
jabber room if anybody from me dekho is
there okay I'll try that meet echo colon
okay I was gonna be amazed this voice
recognition stuff has gotten so good
okay so well Joe who is already
volunteered to be our driver scribe is
taking care of that I would also like to
thank Cullen and Alex for having agreed
to take minutes for us today thank you
very much that means our administrivia
is already moving fast because folks
have already volunteered they've
collected your stars and I their stars
and I encourage you later in the week to
collect your own this is our agenda for
today we are going to have some motive a
motive ating requirements from eric
rescorla some additional possible
requirements
industry from philip alan baker a review
of draft barnes acme and from richard
barnes and then discussion the area
director who is just arrived in front of
me may have some questions for the room
I don't have your slides loaded yet but
we'll try and get those done you sent
slides it looked like and so there may
be some questions from the area director
as we finish up is there anybody who
would like to bash this agenda seeing
none I will just follow up with one
reminder this is not a working group
forming buff you will notice that
nowhere on this agenda is there a
charter review or discussion however we
want you to think about the work and how
it fits into the ITF and during the
discussion think about how the ITF could
contribute to this effort if it wanted
to or what other appropriate actions
might be Reverend Laura
the slides but our sailing on to say so
oh I see this is the box and this is the
box like left foot yellow exactly had a
spinner um alright so um I was asked to
talk a little bit about um what we're
trying to achieve with acne so I were
from Mozilla were we're involved in this
effort somehow um so um so what problem
we're trying to solve here on the basic
problem trying to solve is like not
enough TLS on the internet or security
in general but especially not FTL
ossicles outside the main thing you do
for the web so here are current
estimates out of Mozilla Firefox
preliminary that roughly thirty percent
of page loads are over HTTPS and roughly
sixty-five percent of transactions are
on the these numbers are different
because I things like YouTube and Gmail
because gmail is a fantastic number of
transactions on doing Ajax even though
it doesn't like actually change debate
on this number is one hundred percent on
three 110% really but hundred it was a
setup for so um did a lot of reasons why
this numbers in his eyes would like um
but there's a general feeling I think
that one of the big reasons is hard to
get certificates next slide um so I show
the slide a lot um one of my esteemed
colleagues Cullen Jennings was asked to
get a certificate and this is the
transcript of the instant messages that
I'm receiving from him about how
annoying this is so this took him 45
minutes they still didn't have one
helped us it to head over some money so
kind of pissed him off and this guy's
got a PhD in signal processing so you
sure then we'll figure it out um so um
not not good um so everyone knows this
um you know um there's been some work in
this area on you look at them you know
over the past couple years of people
sort of trying to automate this process
so it's more fun um so you look at
universal ssl from uh from cloudflare or
on i guess there's a this I'm spacing on
the name but there's this dumb node
package that does this um so there's
been sort of sir that's all right thank
you um recognition this is a problem
right um
and um so next line um so Missoula along
with eff and san Cisco and Akamai and I
didn't trust and tremor one other person
now I think um has been trying to figure
I'd say about this and on so the
background for this for this Bluff i
think is this new initiative called
let's encrypt that we announced on the
last IETF that aspires to do a new free
transparent automatic CA I'm not gonna
talk about this very much this is
motivation um but the objectives we have
is it should be free it should be
automatic it should be secure
transparent and blah blah blah all these
good things but easy is the biz that
it's like what you should be getting out
of this right um so if it's going to be
easy it's going to have to have
automation that's clear next slide so
what does this mean for a protocol
machinery standpoint is we automation of
all the major operations so that it
reduces the operational costs for us so
we can do this for free and it is the
operational costs for the UM the server
operator so they're incentivized to do
it's not a big pain in the ass that
means the registration has to be has to
be automatic the domain control
validation that is verifying that you
are entailed to operate the domain that
you claim to be entitled to assert for
that's automatic and on something people
often don't realize is that the renewal
is tificate has to be automatic on so
it's really common to see people who
have what a certificate of year ago and
they forget they have to renew on and
then the strictly spira sanitized
inaccessible even though it's accessible
10 minutes ago that's really sucky so
what we want is on a single time
interaction with the ca from the users
perspective where i say i want to
certificate and then their server
continues to function in perpetuity with
no intervention by them whatsoever um
that's what i mean by seamless on the UM
we have some demos our site um there's
nothing particular special too
complicated especially the demos um that
you know you type some crap at the
command line apache and say like I want
the sword and it goes and it just
retrieves it and a few minutes I your
system is running so and then from then
on it she continues to work that's what
you want and finally we wanted to be
flexible on so if cas changed their
policies and practices we'd like to have
a face to fighting chance because it
said that your server will continue to
operate on even under those changes so
say the ca decides for instance that
they
on that require sha-3 certificates on it
really be nice if you didn't have to do
anything to make that work next slide so
here's some examples of the kinds of
challenges that we think that a protocol
does this has to be able to arm you know
encounter to v mq so here's an example
on certificate lifetimes right
certificates now tend to have relatively
long lifetimes year five years ten years
whatever um and we rely on ocsp for
revocation and as low CSP is like good
you're going to have a bad day um so on
right now on I don't believe any major
browser or hard fails oh no CSP ocsp
failures on so on it certificates
revoked on basically all the attacker
has to do is gag the ocsp server and the
browser will continue that's not so
awesome um there's been a lot of talk
about doing on this tough called must
staple um full palm banker's draft on
this about requiring basically you can
get ocsp response and then you can stop
at the TLS handshake and there's a way
to indicate in the certificate that that
better be there or you should fail um
feels like i doing that with hard fail
on by which i mean that if that weren't
there you actually fail you would even
try to use P query um there's also a lot
of talk about shortlist certificates on
what students are stiff achatz which
have a lifetime on the same order bonus
ESP response so you know somewhere
between a couple days to a week or so um
and this will turn into OCS pms staple
there's isomorphism between these um so
like this is like this is a natural fit
for automatic renewal right on if we
have a system which automatically on
goes and gets in just to forget whatever
it needs one on then that's adaptable
but that's adaptable if a CA decide so
you to laterally shrink the lifetime of
the certificate down from like a year to
six months to two week or whatever on
because the server tells you when you
need to assert the ca does and you just
go get so this is an opportunity for CH
we have adapt our policies on with
people who are you know without
requiring the user to go through a
horrible horrible birds um as opposed to
you Daniel lead and it's a hassle so
it's one kind of challenge you'd like to
have this be a result next slide um
another example being you over those um
so right now you know servers typically
support RSA sometimes in support ecdsa
certificates
um so what if we now know CFR G is
defining to curse and let's go do
signatures perhaps over those curves or
Moody's EDD essay or you know last
signatures your post quantum or whatever
right on so the you can't make this
quite a seamless because obviously you
can't preemptively add these things to
your client before you know they exist
but on if you have an automatic
negotiation one thing that can happen is
that basically the ca can add the
capability to issue for these new kinds
of keys and then when you update your
server software it says oh I noticed the
ca can now assume eeeddd SAS I'm going
to get one of those as well on so it's
not quite as nice but you can still do
automatic upgrade something that's the
future you like to have next slide um
the final feature that um again this is
all exemplary I'm not like the sauce
posting exhaustive list but trying to
give you a sense of the kind of things
challenges we think we have to face um
so um delegate issuance so on say you
have a big server farm and um you have I
don't know lots of lots of servers for a
given domain or lots of domains for a
given server boat engine or you have
some Nixon mask thing where you have
like a big server farm that serves
hundreds of the mains on thousands of
servers we'd like some comment we'd like
to know some you know a binary selection
for each one goes which unchanged in a
daily basis um so it's really a pain if
you have to keep revalidate and it
should be really nice if you could
establish control hood of each domain
once and then whenever you want a new
server that stands up and supports a new
subset of the other names you simply say
okay give me a certificate that matches
that exactly um and if you look at the
way actvities done this is a pia it
works obviously there's an
authentication key which is tied to some
class of domains and then you can
request issuance for any subset of that
um so uh that's basically another thing
you like beyond heaven next slide ah
good i should mention one more thing um
first upon my slides um did the other
thing we think this is on it is about
flexibility of validation mechanisms on
so right now c is doing some small some
of them are validation mechanisms it'd
sure be nice to have a system that was
there was flexible about that in
particular in this contest which really
relevant as Dane and so right now you
know if you offer Dane on and you know
there's only a very small fraction of
line
if any which can accept that right on
but I mean the future that might not be
the case but there's a chicken and egg
problem because it's hard use Dane
without getting a backup certificate for
ordinary TLS so one thing that is very
nice about a sort of automatic protocol
is you can simply say you can simply
transition from date from date from you
know Dame + 509 to Dane only in a
gradual way with the automatic system
picking up the slack of basically
automatically recien your certificates
based on your Dean records so that on so
basically this gives you a temporary
bridge while we should get why didn't
deployment so that's particular
relevance context on and again it's a
feat is something you don't we do if you
really have a lot of automation so on
you know my overall message is that that
whatever protocol on is needed here on
is one that is has enough flexibility to
you know let us move forward in a way
that requires minimal user intervention
on as we sort of try to figure out what
kind of policy please early best fit the
internet on in terms of what on our
interest is as far as ITF um or rather
read lots encrypt interest which I'm
sort of like representing today though I
don't work for them um um is we have to
develop this on we understand other
people working this area this is because
some really nice work it'd be great if
we could all use kind of the same stuff
um um you know as usual on you know we
need this anyway so we'll go ahead but
it would great if we could find people
to collaborate with and if there's
nothing interests we'd like to
standardize it Dan Harkins why isn't
test a solution to your problem as turns
out to a partial solution but it doesn't
have any support for the validation
piece it outboards the validation to an
external to external credentials and and
frankly when we looked a test on it also
wasn't convenient for the platforms that
we were interested implementing on sir
Iran Sheva a more requirement request
for requirement in a question world
gardens turns out that in many cases
it's it's more cost effective to use a
commercial CA than to set up your own
internal CA for servers that are not on
the internet yes i would have liked for
this
or a flock of this or whatever to be
usable for internally within enterprises
right so i think i think that actually
on again that's not that's not let the
chris focus but it's not something we
think is bad on the on the i think the
way that servers that s is actually
better suited provide but it's something
that if you look at acne acne can handle
on the assumption hbu populate some
nakal with the keys that were authorized
to ship for certain domains and you'd
have an out of brand agreement with the
CA where you demonstrated that and then
so that you just skip the whole piece
where you did that where you did the
online validation and usually would be
valuable in a protocol like this
definite entity proof mechanism booth
supported that it's just not the highest
party for let's encrypt from Michelle
phone what's about to certificate
transparency yes on that's an orthogonal
question I think on certainly any
protocol we define could be compatible I
would assume we compatible ship your
transparency um but you know we're
talking to finding a protocol on so I
don't think you'd mandate it on in the
protocol specification Michael
Richardson um so I had two questions one
was about things that aren't HTTP I'm
thinking specifically i'm at pop yes and
that stuff particularly for places that
maybe can be made to work where it's all
one all one box it also has a web server
for that same name but the other thing
that actually i think is more import
more interesting important in the walled
garden space is the lights out I Lahm's
those those boxes where we're
essentially train training junior to
mid-level IT people to forever click
through the certificate warning because
this stuff just never has one yes and I
don't know if if that you're thinking if
that is is somehow inscape making it fit
into these right the client-side fit
into that space these are not that on
they're not particularly constrained but
they are really annoying monsters so I
think there's a let's encrypt answer and
a acne and serve either a little
different on I think from let's your
perspective we're not primarily focused
on either those cases initially
um although you know at some point in
the future we might be interested in
doing non-web it's just a web is the
first target on from an acne perspective
I'd be very sad if acne as it came out
could not be extended to handle exactly
the cases you're talking about for other
kinds of non web services and then if
you look at the design there's a sort of
extensible proof mechanism for being
able to prove possession of different
things and so I certainly hope that that
mechanism we flexible enough to support
other things that were not wet on for
the perspective of of Eylau stuff like
that on the like the problem with any
walled garden scenario is is is there a
mechanism for demonstrate what is the
identity you're asserting what is there
mechanist rating control identity and on
certainly if you could tell me what the
mechanism for demonstrating control the
entities in iowa was I could to have a
conversation about what how that would
work but until I figured out I'm kind of
confused so I'm going to cut the line
here remember we're and have a general
discussion after the full set of slides
but no no that means the people who are
in mind okay then Daniel you have that
JJ hi Daniel can't Gilmore so I just
wanted to point out that it actually
isn't completely orthogonal to
certificate transparency particularly in
the section that you talked about
ramping down the time for the
certificates one of the things that ocsp
lets you do is you have fewer certs in
the log and then you have regular ocsp
update yes if we're talking about
ramping down to shortlist certs and
we're logging everything then the log
balloons inside that's absolutely true
on on so actually been a nitride about
this a little bit on and I think I think
I suggested to bend that perhaps it'd be
nice if CT with log key identity pairs
route in logging certificates um for
precisely that for precisely this reason
um Oh fantastic follows a better wife um
so but I'm just just generally um um
you're quite right yeah obviously CT
will not scale well if you have to like
issues because every 22 minutes yeah
yeah I mean like I think actually that's
just one of those things you put on the
requirements at pile and just trust as
if we're going to come back we'll have
an answer so next slide please so i'm
still home baker and with comodo I've
spoken to some of the industry partners
but we've not really got into a long
discussion with it so I'm talk so when I
was talking from experience here it's
it's confined to komodo but I only speak
of a promoter but i think is probably
the same for most other large cas so
where we are now is we actually have
tools that make automation of
certificate issue possible and raise
reasonably straightforward so we have
standards-based sitting at the
enrollment we've got easy to use and
they're not the same thing they're two
completely separate paths we would like
these two things to be one now why do we
want to go from our proprietary
standards to the to a standard sorry
proprietary schemes to a standards-based
one next slide well the answer is that
plugins just don't deliver at the moment
to use our automated schemes you have to
put a plug-in in your server and the
administrative costs of the plug-in is
vastly greater than the time saved in
cut and pasting a csr and yes I know
that it I know that it's a 45 minutes
for current well you know what putting a
plug-in into your web server is a lot
more than 45 minutes and I'm the problem
with plugins is you can't test them
because yeah one plug-in works too is a
combinatorial problem at three well so
you just can't test the interactions I
want to go to a standards-based
mechanism because that's the only way
that I can automate this scheme in a way
that makes things actually easier for my
customer rather than harder next slide
so looking at our looking from our
position as an established CA what we
want that's common with the alexan crypt
manifesto is we want frictionless
usability so like I posited in prison
proof email no absolutely no unnecessary
user effort the user should not need to
do anything differently when setting up
a secure website to setting up a regular
website unless some additional
information is required from the user
and we definitely want though
short-lived certs a killer for us would
be no any new SN 1 here from my prom to
view the Canon of SN 1 schema has closed
we have burned all our asn.1 compiler
tools we don't want any new stuff we
want Jason and the reason for that I'll
come to that little bit later but it
makes it possible to solve all the
additional requirements that I'm going
to come to without making the base spec
to too complicated we also want whatever
I mean Acme in some ways is going to be
the first Jason based security spec we
would like whatever tropes that Acme
introduces in producing a protocol to be
tropes that we can use on other security
protocols without having the how we're
going to use JSON discussion coming up
every time we also need to interrupt
with existing back-end systems and we
have hardware security modules and
lockdown systems that expect to see a
CSR for proof of possession so that's
one place where we want to see a
maintaining compatibility with existing
sn1 but we don't want to see any new sn1
structures appear next slide so looking
at it from our point of view specific
requirements we obviously want a choice
of CA there and we also want a way of
charging the customer and we also want
to support all our p kicks based
products I for me it's not going to be a
very exciting move to move
just my TLS customers with DV
certificates to a new enrollment
protocol it's only really going to be
interesting to me is if I can move all
my cust of this to all my customers for
all their needs so that if they choose
to have six TV sets and then upgrade to
EV then that's possible for them we want
to do TLS and we also want to do s mine
we actually have a large number three
quarter of a million s mindsets paid
which shocked the heck out of me when I
found that out but it turns out to be
what we have also so one thing that this
means that you can't assume the issue is
the issue of the certificate is going to
happen immediately if you're doing
extended validation or organizational
validation you're going to start the the
attempt to register and then other
information is going to have to come in
out of bound and so it's not going to be
a run this tool once and then you're
done there's going to have to be some
delay and some ability to pick up
certificates after the fact but actually
that's not all that difficult different
from the certificate renewal problem
which also has to be solved and
obviously we need to have the ability to
add in those additional criteria for the
validation for EV etc oh and
private-label certs are also quite big
that we have quite a lot of certs that
don't appear in TLS our public CA is at
all so next side another bigger industry
specific requirements probably have more
impact on the model is we use local
registration authorities for a lot of
certificate issues if you're a large
organization like say a heel at Packard
or whatever you're going to want to have
part of your CA infrastructure deployed
inside the enterprise and the actual
certificate issue is taking place on CA
back end but you've got a lot of local
control so we want to have an ACME model
that allows us to provide an enterprise
with the local control of a local
Registration Authority while still
chaining up to
a back-end CN with all the tier 5
security etc that of prophecy a can
provide we also not to be able o so it
was one thing that might have a long
term is obviously one cases this is
going to be the device talking Acme
protocol to the LRA it's also possible
that they may be talking another Jason
based protocol that is higher level and
it might be that the way you want to
configure that in the cloud is when a
new web server comes up or a new mail
server comes up it might be saying hey I
want to do X I want to do these
protocols you give me all the stuff that
I need to do my job and I'll go and do
it and you might have a protocol of that
type of which certificate registration
is only one small fraction there will be
a massive amplification of Acme rather
than just the base acting protocol we
want to be able to have provide
customers with management tools so they
can see all the certificates that they
have subscribed for that are currently
active and we can see oh yeah there's a
device there 666 example.com we've got a
certificate for it what's it doing you
know and in some cases you might want
private key information to be traveling
from the LRA to the device I'll explain
the reason for that on the list they're
a bit complicated here okay some
technical points we've got that there's
a record the certificate authority
authorization record which is an
existing RFC there are hooks in that it
was designed to be expandable where
you're trying to discover where is my CA
what CA should i register under CA
records might be one way that we can do
it and paul hoffman when we're
discussing the CAA record he in he
actually proposed using dns name for
identifying the ca for this very purpose
and i think that was a very good
extension of CIA record we don't
necessarily need to go to
market with an ACME specification day
one that supports every feature provided
that we don't have bits in the code that
nailed down and exclude particular
applications one of the nice things
about Jason is you can add in slots as
required provided you've not made some
brain-dead assumption in the system so
for example don't assume that when
you're making these requests of the ca
or the server or whatever don't assume
that the key that the server is going to
use is going to be the same key that so
the key that the service is going to use
for TLS is going to be the same ski that
they're going to be used for subscribing
for certificates and authenticating that
request you probably want those to be
different actually so next slide and one
thing that I have to rate this isn't our
IPR but when you're designing the
validation protocol will need to be
sensitive to the fact that there are
quite a few cas out there that have read
have patents pending or issued that
cover methods are validating DV certs
and I know that you know our scheme took
us a long time to work out because we
were dancing around I all this i PR I
don't have that all that I PR in my head
sorry I would have to do quite a bit of
research to work out who owns what and
so on but when we're designing this
protocol we should not assume that
there's going to be just one way of
validating the cert because if we if we
do that then we'll end up being sued up
the ass and that's it sir questions gosh
I answered all your questions
okay let's bring Richard up and well
he's coming up a quick question who
hasn't signed the blue sheet oh my
goodness gracious over here you people
I'm going to deputize you to find the
other people after Olaf is holding it up
please raise your hand again which box
Joyce diamond
so my name is richard barnes i worked
for mozilla and I've been helping out
with drafting the spec for the letter
code projects which we're trying to
generalize out that projects be this
general acne protocol next slide please
so the idea is you know you you install
some piece of software is going to do
all the acne magic and auto configure
server with the cert and all that but
what really happens under the sheets
when we do the protocol here so i
thought it was helpful and oak what yeah
yeah so if you're not your laptop's out
what you all do you love the URL at the
top you can see this form on your laptop
but the idea here is I thought it was
helpful to look at what an existing free
cert issuance process looks like so this
is a web form from whoa sign of Chinese
CA that is offers a free ssl cert
service and they collect a bunch of
different information here so you have
to tell them the domain name and
whatever else you want to go in the
certificates they have like duration
fields and things like that they have a
couple of different ways you can verify
that you control the domain you can
provision a file on your web server I
think they'll do the email style
verification as well you have to provide
them a CSR to show that you own the
private key that you want corresponding
the cert you want you provide them a
contact an email address and a password
so that you can prove that you are your
you know you are the guy who requested
this cert and verified it possession of
the domain when you go to pick up the
cert from them they also have a CAPTCHA
and a subscriber agreement which it
turns out is required by the ca browser
for them if you want to be a CA so this
is sort of an example of the sorts of
things that we probably want to capture
in the acting protocol right these are
the sorts of information that the the
web server or the thing requesting a
cert is going to need to provide to the
CA in order for the CA to be able to
issue a certificate so next slide this
is a diagram out of the out of the act
nice back of sort of how the acne
protocol reflects these pieces of
information I'm sorry the green is so
bright might be a little hard to read
but the idea is we have three basic
types of object with one kind of sub
object we talk in terms of registrations
authorizations and certificates so
registrations cover the Who am I
the identity the contact information the
authentic the credentials that you're
going to use to to access the acne
service so that's where we have contact
information and authentication and the
subscriber agreement concept so
registration is you when you first show
up at an acting server you register you
go to the new registration endpoint you
get a registration and then you head
over to the new authorization endpoint
at that point you say I would like to
prove that I own example.com you put in
the domain name you want and you do this
authorization process acne then has a
challenging response sort of protocol
for verifying domain control and it's
extensible to support bunch of different
a few different types of ways to do that
domain validation I use domains here as
an aside we use domains in the slides
here but the way the protocol structured
there's it's an ed there's a typed up
for the identifier structure has a type
and a value so you can currently define
type as domain name but you in principle
the protocol could support other types
of identifier is like phone numbers or
mac addresses or whatever the CA can
validate you'd need different challenge
types to verify possession of those
identifiers but in principle the
protocol is extensible in that way so
you go through this challenge and
response thing to prove you own the
domain name and then you can hop over
this new cert endpoint and drop your CSR
in and get a cert if once you proved
you're authorized the reason for the
separations we've got here is twofold um
the separation between authorizations
and certificates you might note that
authorizations look sort of like
certificates in that they're set there a
statement by the CA that we the CA
believes that you are authorized to act
for this domain name but the reason we
separated those from certificates is to
support some of the use cases Ecker
called out in his slides where you might
want to have a data center where you've
got hundreds of different servers
serving different combinations of sands
and you want to verify you wanna prove
ownership of each of those the domains
that the servers are recovering once and
then be able to issue a bunch of
different combinations issue
certificates with a bunch of different
combinations of those those names so the
idea is you do the authorization to
prove that you
control each name and then you can issue
certificates with any combination of the
names that you control the separation
between registration and authorization
was to try and separate things that are
generally regarded as public from things
that are generally regarded as private
in particular and let's encrypt we're
going to try and publish all of the
authorizations and certificates and sort
of as transparent certificate
transparency mode and but we didn't want
to have to publish all the contact
information we were getting three people
because for obvious sort of spam and
privacy reasons that also lets us it
opens up the door for acne to support
sort of user management models maybe
groups and things like that adds an
additional level flexibility so that's
the overall architecture of how the
protocol hangs together I've got some
examples of concrete protocol messages
on the subsequent slides the whole
protocol runs in JSON messages over HTTP
all the messages from the client to the
server from the subscriber to the CA are
signed with a key pair that key pair
acts as the account identifier for the
the entity replying for certificates in
the document without an account key pair
so with registration we begin by
associating contact information and
agreement with some terms with that key
pair so that is initiates the user into
the into the ca's management system and
the CA just says yes sure I've got this
next slide when the once you've
registered and have sort of said this is
my public key and Who I am you can then
sign requests to authenticate to be
authorized for a domain with that key
pair so this the message on the left
here says is the subscriber saying I
would like to request authorization for
example org for that domain name and the
signature by the account key pair vine
associates this authorization request
with that entity that's requesting it
now here's where it gets kind of
interesting so the subscriber says I
would like to prove control of example
organ the server responds with an
authorization object so it has a status
we have sort of pending valid invalids
sort of status as you would expect it
echoes back the identifier and the key
that's that were requested and then it
actually issues a set of challenges it
says the service says okay if you want
to prove that you own example org here's
how I require you to do it next slide
please so like I said acne has an
extensible set of challenge type so each
challenge message has a type thing that
says here is the mechanism you should
use to to prove your control of this
domain I think there's two or three in
the document right now obviously
especially as if additional identifier
types are added you will need different
types of challenge but then the other
fields and the challenge say here's some
properties of the URI is how you respond
to the challenge and then the token is
the the stuff you're supposed to
provision so simple HTTPS asks you to go
provision of files of a given path on a
web server and then the response says
here's how you go check that I fulfilled
that challenge yeah Ellis connects me
over HTTPS is the only way Dacian
message you are thinking about or could
it also be DNS paste I believe in the
document right now we have simple HTTPS
a one mechanism it's based on server
name indication in TLS and a DNS based
mechanism okay um obviously if people
have other ideas for for ways that a
third party could validate that another
party owns a domain name yeah we're open
and it may be also that there's sort of
pre validation cases can be handled with
different challenge challenge types as
well so yeah the flow is you know you
get this challenge in the authorization
method and then you post this response
back to the URI that's in the challenge
so you respond to a challenge specific
you are on and I sort of leave out a
step there but once you once you've
completed this and the the servers has
gone off and verified to the domain
control the client can pull that
authorization URL it got and look for
that authorization to turn green to turn
from pending
and then it knows it's bent is that the
ca considers it authorized for example
calm next slide please so now the client
knows that authorized for example.com it
can go ask for a certificate this is
pretty minimal Eve generates a PK cs10
CSR sends a link to the authorization
that the client believes authorizes a
certificate signs it to prove you know
that it's bound to his authorized
account key and sends it up to the
server and the server sends back the
certificate if he agrees and sends back
an error code if not yeah suppose I have
web servants and I get to owned for a
half hour by a hacker and now I found
out about it I clean up the server but
now he already has a certificate for my
server for the next three years instead
anyway i don't i don't know for me to
know about it or or something yeah i
move units are for this i mean i mean
this is this is the same problem any
convention CA has there's no difference
here all the answers are things like CT
and replication or calling adam Langley
i'm ninety google so we've just had a
whole bunch of sites discovering you
shouldn't allow users to register user
names like administrator if you provide
them email access i'm also going to have
a bunch of sites realizing they
shouldn't allow users to register the
name dot well-known can we require like
a weird content type on this thing or
something that is going to be less
error-prone yeah so there's there's a
bunch of really technical discussions to
be had around the specifics of the
validation nekkid against i'll leave it
yeah i'm just trying to capture the
overall architecture here yeah just I I
think this will be one of the places
where we could get cab forum to be
involved so that I would like to have a
definitive list of email addresses that
boneheads don't allow common garden
people to get and should be something
like this for that there is not an email
validation mechanism in the document
right now maybe we should add one maybe
now
it's worth noting the cab form has been
working on tightening down their list of
validation mechanisms so this will
probably require some coordination with
them in terms of making sure that
whatever gets the pod remember we do
have a whole discussion section so just
clarifying questions at this point
please just very short domain names
change ownership which would be good to
have a mechanism that allows for
creating greater a domain name is
authorized and potentially all writing
documentation yeah I think the thing
that's it's a really important point
that this is validates at a point in
time and it may be useful to have some
sort of reauthorization or scoping of
authorization so force revalidation yeah
next slide yes this is just summary of
the overall process you know you sign up
for your new registration if the ca
requires some sort of subscriber
agreement it sends back the URL you
indicate your agreement then you request
authorization for your domain the ca
sends back challenges you respond to the
challenges and then you poll to see to
see if your authorization is valid and
then once your valid you issue a
certificate so try to sort of make it as
minimal as possible within the set of
use cases we wanted to require we wanted
to support so any further clarifying
questions on the protocol as we have it
today dan harkens again is there a way
in this workflow to for the ca to
specify what type of public key to for
decline to generate and CSR to support
like I was talking about ecdsa or at DSA
or something like that so can he say
make a key with the p34 we looked a
curve or something like that right there
there's a couple mechanisms that I think
we kicked around we were drawn we were
drawing this up and I don't think either
of them is reflected in the current
draft it seems like it would be
desirable to have the ca be able to
express basically the policies for what
it will issue so covering key lengths
key algorithms key and extensions it
might allow or not allow
we had thought about there's sort of two
approaches to getting to that you could
do it at the certificate request stage
as by returning arrow types or someone
requests something that you don't like
or you could have some sort of policy
publication mechanism as as an adjunct
to the existing queries you've got here
I don't think there's anything in the
document right now to do that but it
would probably be a good thing to add
other questions all right thanks okay
folks so we have about 15 minutes for
discussion now and there are two topics
the first of those two topics is really
around the work do people find this work
and the scope that's been presented here
interesting so far are there other use
cases they want to bring up at this time
well so this is for discussion I'm not
asking for a hum so this is the moment
when if you want to talk about the the
scope of the work etc you would get up
Alex my over I absolutely love this this
is very much needed in the industry
because all the providers to deal with a
lot of certificates it's a big hassle
and there's a real real need for that
hi Nick Sullivan cloudflare so I have a
question about this that is a little bit
about the scope of this document itself
on acne is why was the decision may made
to make the account key the
authentication mechanism for getting
certificates the main question I have
about this is is that if you do have a
wide deployment and a lot of sort of
cloud instances that you're spinning up
you have to send this very sensitive
account key to each one of these
machines in order to get a machine from
it yeah absolutely um so the assumption
was quite the contrary so maybe we've
messed this up but the idea was exactly
to address that use case and the idea
was that when the Machine spin up they
would send their public keys to whatever
box intermediated the UM the CSRs
through the box that we've had the
account key and that would ask for and
that would ask for approval so if
there's some I mean the idea was
precisely to precisely to avoid the
problem you're talking about so maybe
it's bungled but that's the idea so if
that's not working properly then we'd
like to fix it Phil hung back yeah I
think maybe what we should do is to
split the protocol into two and have an
ACME direct and an acne lra and describe
the two separately because connecting up
directly to the CA is one set of use
cases connecting up through some
intermediary I think is a different set
of issues and we probably want to
separate that out and separate protocol
so back might please
given that why don't we just aggregate
everybody the front Mike please yeah I I
think the battery's dead it's turned on
but it's dead anyway Justin richer and
my question for tuefel for all three
proposals so far is that I will very
strongly get behind anybody that makes
me never have to write a csr ever again
and 2 i'd really like to see something
that us adopt an approach that will also
work for applications that just need a
bear key pair that don't need a CA and
assigning chain and all of this other
stuff we're seeing a lot of applications
that get by with publishing a JW k at an
https qri for example and that's that's
kind of a hack but it works yeah but
this would actually let me potentially
distribute it and things like that so
this is Joe channeling yon from the
gabba room are there people in this
session who would really like wild cards
what are their use cases oh wait sorry
yeah wondering how people generally feel
about support for issuing wild card DV
certs and Acme are there people in the
session would really like wild cards
what are the use cases we've heard from
a few people for whom that wouldn't work
for example randomly generated domain
names on the fly go ahead and max fauna
and i was thinking about this work and
actually then it seems to me beside the
fact that most most of the format that
is chosen kind of duplicates the work
that we've been doing in a PK x working
group a long time ago with CMC so
managing the certificate life cycles
with CMS but besides the format which is
not very important one thing that i
wanted to point out is that and one of
the biggest problem that we are always
faced in the ca world was discovering
services and this is something that we
started to tackle a little bit in the PK
x but I
working group and died and it's
something that he deep I think pointed
out when using the dns records but it's
something that I think we should focus a
lot more because it's the biggest
problem when I want to have look for
which CA I want to get my services from
and how to discover the different
services provided and maybe looking at
the fact that there might be Federation
of types of CAS that I want the services
from but I don't care which one I want I
want the services from so like some kind
of Federation the concept of feather a
federated cas that's an interesting
point but I let me let me up level that
a little bit what I'm hearing is support
for flexibility in the ca and support
for discovery mechanism or primary
Elliot Thank You Elliot layer three
quick comments and a question comment
number one it answered your question I
think this is a very important problem
I'm at number two I think it's a very
nicely constrained solution and comment
number three is keep on going and
question is have a various CA vendors
shunt risk well certainly let's encrypt
is shown interest then I believe that
phil has shown some interest we have
something George moccasin I panic so I
have a small number of comments in like
sense to make without attempting to
objectify any one individual what I
believe I heard on entry was please
preserve my bread business model and
that concerns me because there are
qualities in the currency a business
model that i actually think we do not
wish to preserve so i just want to make
that observation the second observation
i wanted to make is intermediaries are
somewhat concerning to me I understand
the CA are a split but in effect we
partly here because some intermediaries
acted badly and issued certs we don't
think should have existed so there are
qualities and intermediaries that make
me extremely uncomfortable okay a third
comment slightly to one side I am very
very concerned about the traction behind
day I want deign to succeed and there's
a limited amount of clue
the universe and if we divide the clue
into this room in the dining room before
Dane is complete we won't get Dane I
need Dane modules in browsers I need
Dane modules in systems Dane is very
important and one of the reasons Dane is
important is because it gets rid of the
see a business model which is one of the
main goals so I'm slightly concerned
about aspects of this project having
said which I think it's a really cute
model hey that's that let that let the
let the record state that 52 minutes
into an hour buff were already concerned
about a crisis of success which i think
is rather quick work on it our long and
non working group forming above it's the
question we shouldn't do this because it
might disrupt the Dane business model ok
so uh let's let's close the the line
after ecker because I have another
question to ask the room but Richard so
three quick points on the question of
separation where there's a need for an
explicit delegated model or two
different flavors delegated and direct I
think it would be worth looking at the
question of whether acne could be used
and sort of back to back fashion where
an end client does certain flavor of
acne with the CA and then the ca does
are with the RA and then the RA does
another flavor of acne with the CI if I
think that it may just be a profiling
exercise to look at what you need in
each of those cases second on the
question of wildcards I will say that's
among the top questions I've gotten from
people since I've been involved in
what's encrypt projects so it's probably
something when working group is going to
want to take a look at and consider
whether the different what validation
methods might be appropriate to that and
what the security considerations should
be around the issuance of wildcards
ultimately is probably going to come
down to operational decisions by cas
using this interface but it's worth to
think at least having some discussion in
the working group and the last point on
Dane I actually think this is a
supportive technology for Dane in the
sense that it has the potential to
interact really well and be a use case
for DNS SEC in the sense of using DNS
signatures to prove possession of a
domain and signatures over objects you
might put in the dns to prove your
control of a domain to provide a higher
degree of authentication into the as a
basis for issuance of certificates as i
pointed out i think this can also
provide a sort of a bridge today by
lowering the costs of certificates it
effectively removes the extra costs that
you have would have to incur to support
legacy browsers if you also do dave mark
nottingham Akamai but not wearing the
Akamai let's encrypt hat this is good i
think this is important i agree with the
previous speakers from an HTTP
perspective i suspect i have issue with
some of the ways it uses HTTP and i'm
willing to help improve that because i
would cry with joy if we could get one
RFC that uses HTTP well out of the IETF
that would be fantastic ever yeah but I
would love to what webdav isn't your
friend them's fightin words and rush
he's not here to protect you yeah but
occurs right behind you and his wife was
that he that's always something to worry
about isn't it um I'm not gonna go in to
Dane I I strongly disagree with what my
former esteemed colleague said about the
relationship here but I think that we
don't have enough time to talk about
that okay so I assume he still has
seemed esteemed just not a former
colleague of all right
welcome back to telecom I'd like to
economic a switch is providing zip
connect one-on-one I ppb exists with
certificates which is a huge hassle
today but I think it's quite possible
they're using HTTP certificates so it
shouldn't be a problem Erika scroll
amazon yeah um I guess I guess I'm a
little confused by a book by the heat
but I hate from from my esteemed on
former colleague um um I mean this
certainly isn't about impacting the see
a business model is about the fact that
the browser browser and other clients
accept certificates and nothing else and
this is about allowing people to talk to
those browsers securely as much as
possible on as far as on as far as Dane
goes on honestly I think that the
analysis that was offered there's
actually put you backwards um so on that
the problem with dane now as people can
tell you is that there is it we have a
standard collective action problem which
is to say that because there are no
clients are set except dane there's no
value in an offering dane are
practically no clients and because
there's no and because because
practically no one offers damn there's
no incentive for the clients to
accepting and so um what one of the Acme
and in general automatic issuance offers
the possibility to break that log jam by
giving you a valuable reason to detain
even nobody accepts it to use for to use
as a stronger form of issuance and also
to allow you to deploy it in certificate
while only some small fraction of people
accept Dane in the rest except
certificates so as Richard said this is
a bridge universal day deployment and in
fact back to the only scenario I've ever
understood where you could get browser
based in deployment on from 0 to 100
almond or any plausible scenario so
quite the contrary I think if you want
if you like getting you should be
excited about on universal automatic
issuance not happy okay so I know the
area director was going to send me some
questions to ask and I never got them so
i'm going to ask some different
questions almost certainly and then turn
the microphone to him for the the last
thing how many people in the room are
either have currently read the draft or
intend to after having seen today's
presentations and that's good forgive
the bad language so shocked i have the
vapors now how how many people in the
room are either already on the Acme
mailing list or intend to join it after
today's presentations alright how many
people in the room currently believe
that this is so complete and baked they
don't need to help Michael Richardson
and Jeff Houston were the only hands I
saw oh no there's one more in the corner
so there are three very trusting people
and the rest of you think there's some
work to do here otherwise I assume
you're not reading the drafts and doing
the joining the mailing list okay so I
think what I'm hearing I'm going to risk
the next 22 hums this is not a working
group forming buff so this is just the
sense of the room how many of you think
that there's work here for the ITF
please hum now
how many people think there is no work
here for the ITF please on that okay
that was funny but I need to ask the hum
again because the laughter over wrote it
if you think there's no work here for
the ITF please come now okay one one
person near a microphone something okay
so the last words will go to our
esteemed area director to see what
questions he would have had me ask that
weren't those those were good I guess I
I only have one further question I guess
so I think the plan here is that there
seems to be people willing to do this it
seems I think there should be agreement
there's nothing to be done and so I
guess a question is whether we should
just go ahead and do it from former you
know get start getting people writing a
charter maybe not in the next week's put
in the next month or two or whether we
should have another buff before we do
that so how many how many people would
be so I what I want to know is our
people okay with that plan so it so if
the plan the plan is to let's say with
the plan to just go ahead and form a
working group do the charger on the
charging on the list and so on in a
month or two I'm very much in favor of
that plan okay so if you want to call it
Adam Langley google so so the ITF does
have a tendency to take things and take
a really long time and then come up with
something that's slightly different from
what used in practice so the reason why
i hummed against having the IETF to do
something here was that I hope let's
encrypts like spit out of working CA
shortly and then if the IETF were to
standardize something that wasn't what
they were using and wasn't what the
world was using which is quite possible
that would be quite a sad outcome there
behind you so I guess at what time we
have we just hit our time ok so the mic
line is closed and so so speaking
visually plastic creeper my
understanding listen Chris posture is is
that we intend to spit something out
prior to ITF standardization and would
hope to harmonize the IETF as long as it
was not to radically different insanely
cell which I understand is not the best
outcome in the world on but we'd also
don't think
and we should be more than pleased to
people just adopt it whatever the hell
we get ok so we're bracket euro is it
very quick yeah quickly skimming the
drafts it looks close enough to baked if
we don't need a working group this can
be nuttin as an 80 sponsor draft with
all the comments that you can get it
about the point on a list I don't think
I agree ok and so ok ok so I want you to
home now if you think just going ahead
and forming a roping group in a couple
of months is a reasonable thing so if
you think that's a reasonable plan home
now if you think that's not a reasonable
plan please on that okay so I guess
we'll do the rest of this thank you
thanks very much everybody go get some
cookies so do you know where to take the
blue sheets ok take the blue sheets over
to the registration desk and given to
secretary thank you very much up thank
you thanks fellas so who you if this
does go ahead I would like to come
fortunately I was
you