focus
this is there anything not going to be
here it's not the last chance to use you
everybody else will be locked in for the
next hour okay so you have a short
meeting today so go ahead and stay
because social so you're sure the night
guys so this is a no go inside
enforcing this man so nice sounds
terrible I'm agenda today we
some chairs besides commands
I'm documents said to it still here ok
good tell you about that goddess so
there is going to be a talk on the
evaluation guidelines / characterization
guidelines is a case maybe I can
benefits and quick Chicago status so the
recommendations graph draft is the one
thing that we've been pretty close to
finishing up now over the iesg ballots
are green and I believe Martin is
working with the general with Lee Davies
right on making sure his comments are
all 10 kills
what is lost turkey matters to me so I'm
not sure if you got also the last email
from him like or the last week or you
just send this to me in private okay
maybe you have to tell chickadee may say
that give me something is happening
address 37 to everybody's what i can i
will call seeing it so 11 arrested so in
case it's very nearly done in national
should win for sure so we have a bunch
of any working group items now and a lot
of them seem to be ready for a last call
and
things that I think we want to do today
we will
just trying to get a sense of how you
should do this son of glass cause we got
the five things cute up there and I
think the natural ability to do them in
would certainly not sighs in parallel by
the time it'd be like the Next Iron Chef
meeting before the day with last call's
so we have say overlap in the last calls
between one or two documents at a time
but I think the natural way that they
would be the evaluation guidelines the
ekend benefits probably fq
implementation in the two algorithms and
thicken to last calls on each disease
have some questions inputs on the last
call process will overload you and you
know at the same time
for people to sign up to review each one
of these like one or two people for each
document that can commit to giving us a
good solid last call with you oh he
wanted all review BF q implementation
since you're an author that doesn't help
much change so 20 said it crack that's
10 weeks we should actually work time
yeah assuming that two weeks is uh you
know the time it takes to collect up all
the comments and close well that's what
I hear in v6 outside for enrolling in
class falls okay we'll try to anyway you
so let's let's go down the list yeah so
let's let's go down the list and try and
find a couple of names for each document
so is the ECM benefits one first time a
list you gotta keep your valuation
counts okay so can we get somebody to
tell us that the willing to review this
so they can be so easy to benefit for
you your community I don't
so you up here I'll do okay I'll be
great thanks Andrea okay so how about
evaluation guidelines some are going to
commit to looking at that and taking
making a detailed review and setting
some comments Jim how about you
great okay perfect so how about the yeah
the fq implementation with any then
shred
engine okay good anybody else rescue
implementation that we can count on no
okay that might be okay so how about the
pie algorithm I hope at least getting
you know send the other authors we're
going to review that Bob great Stewart
perfect okay so ask yukata is since you
mentioned it when the ones on the wrist
stuff includes a little bit more
feedback a little bit more scrubbing and
work in my opinion for the last call it
but certainly you don't have to wait
until last call to provide comments so
create any of us for pie and cuddle
perfect
ok
so I think this is good now you have
your names are occluded and and we will
use that against you so I just public
shaming on the mailing list for not
getting reviews and I guess the good
news is that i saw if you have all the
documents in the last few weeks in
preparation for the media I think it's
one of the best sets of documents among
all the working groups here they're
quite readable and since we didn't
really invent anything in the working
group it's very easy to review them
because you're you're looking at
descriptions of stuff that's been done
rather than trying to find holes in new
things that we're doing and look for
changes and improvements
do I take us to the next slide so once
we've been talking about adopting was
the docsis pie drafters been sort of way
positive feedback about it on the
narrowest and we think that may be
enough because that's about all the
feedback that we've been weighing on
anything and well it's it's useful to
the IETF to describe you know what was
done in the docsis spec and I believe
that it's implements the PI draft
basically and we should be able to sort
of move it around in in parallel and I
guess since we haven't seen anyone on
the mailing list tell us that those
would be a terrible idea to document and
it has been some positive support unless
some jumps up here today and tells us
not to do it I think we're going to
adopt that as a working group draft zone
your feedback on that before we do it
okay pop somebody's afraid to speak up
okay so Richard Richard thinks we should
go through the whole process so let's
just to 100 if you think we should not
adopt this draft she's home now silence
okay so we will adopt that and hopefully
we can you ask all that one quickly as
well and add it to the pile of documents
for trying to finish up
and I think that's our last side right
so on to the characterization guidelines
okay so this is about an update on the
Aiken characterization guidelines draft
next we have had some feedback at the
ITF in Honolulu and also we've got under
version 0 we've got some feedback and
full review from Alfred then some
comments on the version 1 from Wolfram
and then we submitted the version to
just the 9th march two revisions are
submitted one and two based on this
feedbacks that we've brought in the idea
so they're mainly editorial work and
minor fixes but the main thing is that
that we provided more clarity in the
definition of the end-to-end metrics
that are being defined in the draft so
they are right now they come up with a
definition what what is good good put
what is loss what is Jeter so and they
they are citing other rfcs and also that
we have more clarity on how to report
the data related to the end-to-end
metric the evaluation of the end-to-end
metrics also previously the way that the
draft was written it was like that that
there are there were a lot of mosques
that if you want to test a confusion you
must do this what we must do that so we
kind of gave a little
more liberally to the testers to
actually come up with their own
scenarios and being more of a guideline
rather than an evaluation sheet and also
there was one thing that in the last
site if we talked about it was there
about how to actually quantify different
congestion levels so here we kind of try
to come up with a more precise
classification of different congestion
levels for testing and also there is an
encouragement in the draft on to try to
gather a cue level metrics the data
related to the cue level metrics
whenever it's possible so so if if you
have a hardware that that gives you the
you know the queue size and you can get
it from the hardware and if its impact
on the aqm mechanism itself is
negligible then drag the draft
encourages of collecting those data as
or number of easy n marks or whatever's
in the middle boxes so whenever whenever
it's possible then it kind of has the
new draft it kind of has this mindset of
real-life test testing things on a real
system previously it was written more
with the mindset of simulation based
things so next so with regards to the
metrics and and their data measurements
we defined a set of metrics that needs
that their data needs to be collected so
previously it was the draft was saying
that you actually can choose what
metrics you want to report on so right
now the way it's written is that it
actually says that you should actually
report the maximum number of metrics
that you can record them and they are
relevant to the context of the
evaluation and to the scenario that you
evaluating so the maximum number is like
a maximum maximal istic approach but
it's not necessarily all metrics it
depends on the context of the evaluation
and also that the evaluations should be
based on on the end-to-end metrics it's
good to gather the data related to the Q
level metrics but the main the layout of
the evaluations should be based on the
gathering data from the end to end point
of view and also based on the RFC's how
to measure the packet loss in the system
so we've got two metals on how to
measure the packet loss whether you
assume that the packet would arrive
within a certain delay bound based on
the RFC 2680 and if it doesn't then you
assume that it's lost or based on the
RFC 2544 you actually can't all the
packets sent then you can't all the non
duplicated packets received and then you
measure what was lost then the
definitions of good put one day one way
delay and jitter they already embedded
into the text and we came up with
recommendations on how so that does sort
of time intervals if you're going to
report good food over time how are you
going to do it different people may
measure good food / different time
intervals so here it provides certain
recommendations for example every
multiple RTT you need to report a good
put but then it suggests that you pick a
minimum
an RTT or higher to actually as a
measurement interval for the delay
samples it's preferable to do it on a
per packet pair or per packet if you can
actually have a very fine grain
distribution of delay or or at minimum
10 samples per RTT and all these things
are that Esther goes through should
should be a must be disclosed and should
be exactly same for all the evaluations
that that a specific tester is doing for
that for the for the comparison of
different economic assets next please
then with the network scenarios we in
the previous idea we had this discussion
now we have incorporated that into a
draft that you should investigate both
asymmetric and symmetric link scenarios
where you go the asymmetric link
scenarios it should investigate the
bi-directional traffic first it looks at
a scenario when you have the viaduct by
bi-directional traffic when you have an
acre on only one direction you may also
want to look at a more complex scenario
where
two instances of a QM on both directions
and then you want to also look at the
impact as the TCP Act drops by a QM how
is it going to affect the TCPS clocking
mechanism and also when testing you
should use the maximum buffer size which
is identical across all the tests so
just to provide some sort of coherence
and we've also come up with some form of
recommendation for it for a traffic mix
but it's changing from a must or
recommendation and as a minimal set of
traffic mix that that one can use but
the test I could come up with a more
complex set of traffic mixed scenarios a
very more critical part of that is to
how to define different condition levels
and rule in the last scientific provided
a Lincoln and a paper we try to read it
it was highly complex mathematically and
it actually was very difficult to
translate it into something that is
quantifiable under every link so we came
up with so previously it was uses it was
using a certain packet loss ratio
assuming that if you have had a drop
tail queue so it would have translated
to certain level of congestion we change
that into we actually infer that packet
loss into a formula from from a Morris
paper scalable TCP congestion control
that which actually gives you how many
number of flows on a surfing path would
drop tail cuteness would give you a
certain packet loss ratio that doesn't
mean that you actually have that
Atlas on the link but it actually gives
you how the condition never would be
well if you have a qm it's going to
change the congestion level anyhow and
that's actually what we want to test is
that is it is able to bring down the
condition on the link so previously was
really actually very high percentage
ratios for defining what is mild with
what is medium and what is what is heavy
congestion sure we would reduce it 10
times less so to make it more realistic
in the version number two and next week
and at last so there was also another
talk about that asian should support is
yen so in the current version at the
Achaeans should support this in all
equipment and the testers must discuss
and describe the support of ECM in the
in the end the proposal that they are
testing that's all
any comments questions concerns
aggregates safe that paper I referred to
you was a bit too heavy the packet loss
levels can I suggest using us you've
reduced them to more realistic levels
but maybe a slightly wider spread of
them would be with wire like you've got
point 1.51 to see maybe going to you
notice a point Oh 5.1 1.5% or something
like that the kiss if you have the link
that is like a 100 millisecond base are
two key and 10 mb you know that's very
classic scenario and a PDP of offering
then you're gonna have like around 18 19
flows for a heavy congestion which which
makes sense actually and for a mild
congestion you would have around for
flows and that is actually compatible to
what we have in mind for that is
specific link scenario but with the
previous selling that was like higher
have like 19 flows were actually a mild
condition which would never be a mild
condition on a 10mb link you there
another michigan RTT so it will be just
you know very small condition window
fluctuations I don't know we have to
pick a number anyways so but yeah and
those are it was reasonable but this is
actually just like a guideline so you
were actually half that test and you
have a different tests angle if you're
testing on differently no loss rates of
different number of flows but it's just
for wise a guideline of how to do
so I one comment yeah I didn't think
about it I saw you last night that we
should be careful that this is the
guidelines and recommendations on
evaluating the algorithms or not on
designing the algorithms right so the
aqm should support ecn I don't know if
that's what you want to say that we want
to say that you know the tests and
evaluations of a qm should enable ACN
and provide the results yes but I mean
the design i should probably have this
and you know because the play that was
the dominant side support is trying to
go to the RFC every cube right now on
designing algorithms great was I can
volunteer to read through and see our
and how that and learning capacity tweak
to separate out the evaluation criteria
from the recommendations to the
designers yeah I don't think it's a big
deal but and bilson sank like um I just
apologize i'm not entirely after hadn't
reviewed the whole thing i was just
looking through it to find out like how
many flows you'd be looking at I know it
like home gateway was mentioned then 17
flows was considered a large number but
you know what about evaluating this like
a core router or somewhere where we're
seeing 100,000 flows or is that is their
scope of this is it is targeted to a
specific domain that is this whatever
flows should be general i think but i
haven't actually sit down what google a
tutorial 100
what a generous but it would be but to
recommend a general-purpose algorithm
you'd want to see if it works in the
different cases or what the different
parameterization so that wasn't about
algorithms but more about different
condition levels and you know what is
the condition level is kind of fuzzy
definition so it could translate it into
good things we have to kind of come up
with a way or how to you know produce
rather like a fuzzy kind of mild medium
and heavy condition levels so I mean I
don't know how bad this can go away but
I mean if you have a reference or
anything that help we are very happy to
incorporate that so they actually the
tester to choose the number of flows
that for their case and apply these
guidelines make a livin Katims honest
own mind I've just looked on the traffic
try to figure out how many of us are
using in and you do this correctly that
you define your congestion level as like
the the amount applause would see if you
would be use a prop like you instead in
the same scenario basically but that's
really confusing for me it's like good
because like for me ms you save it
correctly the congestion error depends
on the a community results and so this
is saying it doesn't really go well in
my head so why don't you just remove it
why don't you just say like we have
heavy load we use a large number of
flows and you just make up a number
because it actually it's not that
important which number we have it's just
a large number and then we have a medium
number we have a small number yeah so
now really time an example would life to
be you want to test the neck
different ranges of number of flaws yeah
but they should say th name over a
different number of ranges of flaws and
thats arranged you should apply and the
minimum of tests you should do instead
using two flows pipe flows and underflow
so I don't know some of the same number
sex makes things much easier Michael
Abramson so uh I've seen some specs from
typical more powerful wrong and they're
to expect or like a call for a few
thousand floats and then at season so I
that puts somewhat of an opera ball I
think we at least need to do this is
about more like an axis lost in the
queue now the ones i'm not sure if you
have everybody's under that any loss yes
let me know if our picture of light it's
gonna do a lot yes sir so and this is a
very typical use case for so longer than
one night so i think it should be
evaluated
she's mostly my unless the time melrose
metrics which actually touches on a lot
of the same issues is there space in our
agenda that should be presented Blair
just a guy's body it's a safari but
because it was actually a lot of overlap
between stuff that I've been working
group is doing in this specific document
yeah i think the IP p.m. stuff is a
little more tightly defined this is the
recommendation stop it's not as tight of
a specification so maybe we need to add
some links to I ppm material from the
precise description 00 i go to air
weapons little documents sure our
internal ide on here hat on actually we
the point owl and ask if their review
you're doing of this document is also a
PMD review because this I don't know if
the script caught this but this
desperately need to be in Europe
okay I was wondering why I had seen one
of those grow up okay yeah so so there's
I don't think we necessarily need to
define all of these metrics with the
regular that we've defined for example
2280 I think that would probably for
just these evaluations guidelines that
would probably be a waste of effort I do
think that we need to have sort of wider
review of the front outside the aqm room
on the fact that you are sort of
defining new performance metrics and if
those performance metrics won't be used
not to make operational decisions but
instead but I think it would be another
way of saying we're defining what some
tests and things that you might look at
in trying to come up with performance
metrics would be but I think what's your
opinion it'd be I think where crew for
some defining specific metrics in a way
that I peed I Emily impulse at the graph
he actually uses that yeah yeah so the
basic loss and blossom to lay stuff is
is straight to my young but just looking
at at and I have taken a quick look at
the past you know I should probably sit
down and finish reading the draft and
then come lookin submitter with your
Brian so can I Brian's name to the list
of review on this one
co-manager I actually prefer the
conditional admission in this is often
the benefit I mean itself as in the
Ingraham would be tails I mean just
given numbers are hopefully before mind
you for any three boot and the buffer
size and stuff the thing is that is not
independent of the buffer back the
bottle sizes in the formula so dependent
of the actual age yeah it's like there
is not you are the kind of party
so hi I'm Alan Morton and I've got my
benchmarking methodology co-chairs had
on at the moment I tried there to
stimulate some review from the other
benchmarking with folks by sharing my
review with them and so far it hasn't
been successful but there's a I would
say there's as much overlap between this
work and I ppm is there is with
benchmarking methodology so maybe we can
try one more time to get some folks from
BMW G to this as well up there to
comment I would make it which is on the
previous slide if you wouldn't mind just
put them back their West Briton thank
you yes yes traffic mix so at least for
the for the UDP stateless stuff we have
an RF seeing the number escapes me but
it's the i mix genome which can help
here this this provides repeatability if
you use different mixes we think it's at
least it's our best shot of a beautiful
but but the answer is when you test when
you test with more than one packet size
repeatability between test labs it's a
little goes it goes overrides just
something to keep in mind
me again and I just want to explain
further what I meant sir first of all
what I like about this document it
that's very clear and very focused and I
think it's really useful for people who
want to do something so I also regarding
to the IP p.m. stuff it should be in
line with IVA p.m. but it shouldn't make
this couple this document more
complicated it should stay as it is so
that's that's a nice period and so that
was also why I made this proposal
because the congestion level is the term
itself is very confusing to me because
you calculated based on drop ship and
then we applied the menu you get a
number of flows you apply this number
flows using a different ATM and get a
different loss right out of it which
other people will again see as a
congestion lever and so that's just it
just makes I understand what it is but
it's really it's a weird term to me and
I also don't think that is needed so of
course i'm using over different vendors
today products using the same number of
flows relieved to what you call
different projections efforts because
all the thing it doesn't matter to have
always the same tradition ever it's okay
if you just test a small number of laws
and be remember flows and a maximum Bo
feels so the idea behind this was that
if you've got tester a antecessor be
testing two different accurate and using
number of clothes and different links
then we wanted to actually be using the
same number of floors you put the grabs
in front of each other and start
comparing so that's why I was certain
you know net for a start a netbook
network had characteristics so so
basically what we saw like if you have
to have a scenario you have the a
certain dinnae you have a sudden bang
castrate you have placed a jumbo certain
records so you have 100 milliseconds and
to end today 10m bit link and then you
calculate your numbers of floats and
that's in this case 10 now you take the
same and you have different scenario you
have a similar bandwidth so the number
you broke i could a disguising but like
half half the bandwidth so it's five
instead of 10 yes what is important is
that you compare the algorithms in these
scenarios like you have 10 megabits per
second half your 10 mega a second
hundred meetings and 10 flows and then
you can play all the apms and then the
next scenario it doesn't actually matter
if you have five or ten flows but you
have to have the same number of flows
and that's why I just say pick a number
which is okay for all sinners just
absolutely number flows on a certain
links would translate to something
condition levels and you know like why
is important to have the same condition
if it's just like you live in the medium
congestion if it's not a perfect set
exactly the same position but but that
wouldn't be mild that's the point is
that certain number of flows maybe mind
I'm certain link but not mild and
another is that you're trying to come up
with the formula that gives you that
number actually want and the end is to
cover in the use cases so if you even so
you have a large link and you only have
two flows for like or you have that
Smalling and you have hundred flows and
that's very heavy congestion let's
review q's case if you really can have a
link where you have found it flows then
you should test it I don't care about
the congestion never because the
congestion has influenced by the ATM I
care about the scenario yet and I want
to hear what they could do actually we
could keep the formula but just scrap
the congestion level definitions but
keeping the formula that's one thing i
find the term are you confusing but i
was done i think that's more complicated
and it needs to be just have to pick
numbers I don't care about it and you'll
agree again I don't care about the name
of it but something of that sort of form
which takes some of the dimensions out
of the problem so if you get something
comparable is is quite important because
say I've got a scenario with the
bandwidth is ten terabits a second and
the rtt is four milliseconds and I want
to forget figure out whether an IQ in
that worked in that situation somewhat
comparable to another situation where we
hit say I don't know 100 gigs and then a
minoral a second 30 tea right you can't
actually make it at some kind of
comparison based on what happened with
this condition label my metric because
it's a relative measurement within the
within the new apprentice of a scenario
but the number of flows you require for
those two scenarios is radically
different right yeah for the team taylor
scenario i mean you know I know so seven
million employers is kind of going to be
kind of something that's going to be
required to get it the context right
don't you really need to have that
number
to be able to actually come up with it
on a teen turbit link of course you do
yes oh that's right that's what I'm
saying when I was whether at a serious
problem is you go to the large
dimensionality space you are simplified
and I will suggest that being one of the
primers you have a pic is the na- for
shear rate that is the aggregate
bandwidth divided by the number of rows
I guess with these ways said it but but
but that is the commander is from
something to be held constant because
that's the parameter that the users care
about as you scale the system all right
so if you buy put your limbs you can
watch more channels at once as a snack
the record i agree to it so this is good
feedback thing really incorporate those
parts i think it's just a few parts in
the draft and probably ask for the
working group let's go yeah and we have
plenty of people who are all review list
which of that in everyone's name as they
came to the microphone
no talk about the next direction so go
first sup my neighborhood and okay so I
time to read this quickly through again
and some of the terminology here is a
little bit different for it in the ATM
guidelines recommendation
recommendations guy who's vcp will talk
we just top-rated beginning is it worth
trying to align this and not talk about
switches but talk about network devices
and to use the same definition for a qm
because you have a kind of more fuzzy
definition and there are things in here
that we could make changes to how can we
make comments it wouldn't group think
that's helpful personally I think that's
hopeful then I'm up for review of that
to do that consistency in our output is
important I think ok
anything else you will talk about okay I
guess we'll be going to talk about it
ekin here I'll started the pink box away
from the top we're from the camera ok
I'm going to talk about and eckin or eca
I'm right and I need to be professor at
the very beginning and Michael gave me
the job of doing the last editing
uploading and I managed to mess up the
upload procedure by uploading me a new
version of the individual submission
round in the working group 1 and nobody
told me any different until after the
deadline had passed and the ID tracker
will now be changed to not let you do
such a stupid thing because of the
people don't as well this hey ed should
spin the archive and then we have to
conquer do it releases to to make sure
it is replaced by the right one and all
sorts of silly stuff and finally
admitted the right version and I already
took this version which is version wrong
to respond to comments provided by the
working group and a powerful one so when
you talk about this now purpose though
the draft is to present a vision for why
people should be using ECM if you think
this is the wrong popular t you think
which will do something different then
you need to speak up because the perps
this document is to preserve our vision
please use easier if I as the key
benefits and it could potentially
identify the pitfalls that was the
second comment we got from West and it
closest to think again because talking
about the profiles in a document which
is effectively a manifesto for saying
turn on ECM seems to be able to put
contradictory this document still
approaching the RFC series trying to say
gzzz em neither based approach book
describing current pitfalls appeared to
be maybe not the right language version
2 that tries to avoid the word pitfalls
without removing those sessions have
talked about the bad things that can go
on it just changes the language now
challenges which email address exactly
it uses the real challenges yes
y direction so and this is mostly a
rewrite this is 0-1 to eat better than
the text here representing us today
because we think it's now ready for
wider review in particular where we are
able to review 02 not 01 the new version
we've uploaded what were the two
versions the second version because the
second version and has this word change
it just avoids using pitfalls at all
goes back to the original words we have
and I think this is pretty much good for
comments throwing websites I tell you
what was in it okay then this dust in it
this is where we let the pitfalls
because if a person every move and which
may potentially confuse people is I move
the bleach your little box requirements
earlier in the document then because I
put it with deployment issues because I
thought this was a deployment thing that
you should tell people not to bleat
cheese here so I do put it at the end
where we talked Brett mechanisms okay
everything else the conclusions no
issues
geez we didn't call it we think this is
ready to go quick and get the school and
Brian's going to do a review of it and
working group last call yes I will okay
all right i mean my name is already on
the list so i figured i might as well
get up so high Brian channel I have a
question about sort of the scope of the
challenges I guess for my coloring
pitfalls anymore how crazy and in
paranoid do you want the challenges to
be I want the challenges to be
motivating the use of ECM this is a
statement to people that we should be
using it yet it's not a certain problems
of going away the ITF 11 working on it
in fact I intend to write drafts about
TCM to make it better or to make it work
effectively which i think is a little
bit of that challenge but Sir concrete
example if a challenge to ecn deployment
is that turning on ecn may cause welders
that are doing equal cost multipath
routing based on hashing the toss bite
to break tcp anyhow is that a you sleep
the look on your face is Iraq
tcp any guest is already broken because
after I tweeted something about the talk
I gave an ICC orgy I got called out in
Twitter about breaking the internet for
telling people to turn it on but it a
good for you TCB anycast when you're
bleaching or when you're copying the
boss fight so many things are wrong with
not that I can't even start acting on
the top of washing on the toss by
evening there is equipment that does
that he put something so the point is
the point that I'm making is that if
we're talking about okay well we're
thinking about all the problems and
repeating people at this document there
are people in the community who will say
ECM is broken because queasy feeling
that I want to do what I saw once or I
have some broken equipment or I had a
bad idea and I'm continuing to do the
bad idea I don't know that we want to
put that in there but if this is
supposed to be the one stop shop where's
the line I don't think we should talk
about whether we see I was good st2
honestly anything else either look that
is already broken and stuff this broken
is broken and then it needs to be gonna
be fixed I think you agree we don't want
to get the room since about yeah sure
that's my opinion
hendra McGregor um as far as we know we
haven't got had a consensus call or any
kind of convention discussion on the
question of is the position of ECG and
marking is equivalent to drop correct
and what do we want to do about trying
to make things that we have to hire a
TCM deployable now that seems to be a
challenge for this document in some
respect but I'm not sure how it applies
okay and it's okay it's a challenge in
getting ECM correct and i think that is
still a work in progress so yes we do
have to choose it and we've made some
recommendations in VA qm recommendations
for things that might need to change the
things that might need more research on
some of these avicii unrelated and if we
if people believe us and they start
turning it on we better get on finish
these things as well and we could decide
not to publish this because we believe
we have to do all the work first and
then you can work up the motivation for
actually doing the work that precise
question is one of the reasons why none
of the documents or implementations
about either coddled or if you cuddle
say anything about it they probably
should but without kind of resolving
that question there's no way of deciding
what
hmm doesn't know what to be done yeah
sure I I can't so sorry I got your
perspective on that and let you know
that this isn't supposed to be spec for
you seeing that modifying you know
anything about you see end it's about
explaining the people arrive they might
want to use it so it would be the wrong
place actually if we had guidance about
that to stuff it but it might be a good
thing to mention in the Challenger
section i would encourage people to turn
out and talk about yeah yeah okay like
there is this the place where we
starting the challenges stuff to me that
this this is an information of document
but well well you gave a nice to make it
work but yeah yeah but we can talk about
listen this is fun making a computer
different topics I can you per se so I
should have probably brought up this
earlier but I haven't been here to last
meeting sir and there is a section
saying benefits when do mock you see an
earlier various yeah which I don't be
the end of thing between botany see an
earlier you don't understand how you can
walk earlier no did I understand i don't
know ken how you can get benefits for me
and because so my understanding is if
you map you can earlier you will just
reduce your condition into earlier and
so the other flow who gets a later draw
we're just use all the capacity and we
will not be able to get any of the
capacity which is might be beneficial
for the operation of network probably
not but it's definitely not beneficial
for the one who's using easy
you're near a microphone so recession
the illusion eh i think we are benefit
and i think i think we could we could
try to do read them but maybe they could
be done in in academic papers and
research and we could go that way and
that's making this section a little bit
shorter and that's a thing for this
working group to decide oh but Briscoe I
guess the thing Curren presented in ICT
RJ was a way to mark ii CN earlier and
not lose lose out to drop so it just
needs leg embellishing rather than
moving to say that you can't just do
that naively
okay remember this is a manifesto
document not a technical specs so we we
should probably be able to sort swallow
in this room by KO talking and as an
example if you feed a DC TCP and their
Reno flow both of which support ecn
enter an f qk l modified to do PCN
instead of trop they'll balance our
Kevin what if Q Cole yes but you are
already in the marking right now we're
all of the values long as the menu comes
from if Q but in this particular case
the coral is going to balance it is
going to the site on the right marketing
rate that each flow wants to get to
where the accused feels it should be now
I mean you value about that's the right
thing to do it but this world to happen
your came with benefits in two cases I
believe needs two different cues I
mature if this is meant by this take I
don't think that's what you meant I
think two different cues in my
terminology of scheduling yeah and yeah
Lots intricately tied with performance
we're just talking about and the other
ways that you used to complete a
different contraction control for the
ecn enabled through and that needs also
some kind of agreement sanitization
between what between the ATM and the
system because both need to know that
they have to do something different and
I don't think that's something we have
right now so I'm not sure if it should
go into this document
I mean I would happy people think about
it but i'm not sure if go on this w no I
want this conversation is good Oh matter
your size everyone wants it okay so it's
been said that this is not supposed to
be a specification the specification
exists and recommends for now to mark
rail would otherwise drop and I think we
should not changed out our proposed to
change that in despair and remove any
text that says anything about possibly
marketing area that's level email grant
will take care that we should talk about
what mark when we should what would
otherwise drop means not when an ad I'm
would otherwise drop regarding the salon
chair on it yeah well we can just
explain this I think because this is a
common misconception that it's the same
as a drop tail rotor the same as an AQ m
the region maybe okay I agree I I would
still like to see like a side remark if
you changed this spec saying not you
have not have to do the same like rub
anymore if you change it and you change
also the congestion control you can have
additional benefits just making work
somewhere that you know there's more
coming up which might be interested in
something that that would be I think
that would be nice because if people
read this they say okay that's basically
all stopping you but what's the real
benefit okay and when we just try one
second longer poker and is it a new
benefit or is it a greater benefit only
because the benefits we already outlined
in some top-level describing the
different ways you can benefit I believe
what you're saying actually is a good
thing and I've got research also in this
space but it actually just increases the
benefit in those particular cases
the the of the whole system if you have
a different aqm and the different
congestion control then there's a new
benefit that might be doable because
today's congenital needs a certain
amount of buffering trachea which I've
utilization and if you want to have
higher education and no delay you might
need to change those but that's like
this I'm not sure that might not belong
it okay then so the low delays is better
realized because you can make a lot
alike you right okay I don't we will do
what with the text yep where we leave
this pit I'll start off your scent I
mean I agreed to review it and so if I
have an idea where we can it like one
sentence I were just so welcome work for
trying to do the structural changes here
that are useful I will any other topics
because I'm will happily consider them
doesn't look like it okay so that means
that we need rep three and then I will
assert that ref 3 contains all the
feedback which we want to put into this
and therefore that version should get a
reviewer or I go to we can get lost call
it will go looking real class call thank
you
so Andrew you just want to say briefly
status on cuddle no slide straight no
show slides and uses micro sis closer
the car will draft we have at this point
we have a number of known editorial
changes that need to be made a whole
bunch of reference that's and a few
other such things but in its current
form its kind of reading for review
understanding that there are some known
editorial issues stick particularly
references and when those are resolved
we believe it'll we're ready for a score
so if you go to insert a link if you
poignant now that's that's perfectly
fine and it won't be too long like all
the handful of weeks before we have a
new version that will have the editorial
issues we already know about resolved
and that should be you know ready for
serious Rudy okay quick does that mean
okay that wasn't trying to add something
the experiences section if he can frame
more information there as well everybody
has any data that they can provide to us
driving the experience section that will
be fantastic there okay Martha lesson I
i have i have some reservations about
the behave
that happens when it enters this drop
mode the part of the square root I've
seen strange things and I can share them
off run and we can have a discussion
about it but I think about black tab
more justification about this part not
the problem the first choice but to
repeated dropping the idea the idea with
this document is to document coral as as
it was originally published in his here
out there in the wild rather than do
further development on it now all right
you further algorithm development is a
good thing but and we'd certainly like
to know about that and probably publish
it would also be nice to know how that
happy can observe that same behavior in
if you coddle for and I don't want to
grab get in the way of the process here
of documenting what stairs I think
that's a very good thing to do so I
think it might have a sexual or maybe I
suggest you re we're already on the
future work in you know other research
because it certainly mentions in many
places and document some some other
things that could be poked into and
maybe that's just a candidate for that
yes west-east we could do that and just
you know you
there was a mile i wrote reviewing
cuddle on the list that i think you
promise to answer at some point maybe
two years ago now i set it to kathy
nichols and fan and no one ever answered
it and then you said you have its green
carnal dragoness and this does anything
else that's all we have for today thank
you for coming and participating and we
worked a to all the rest call reviews
and I've know that everybody who has
been under naik to be wealthy of us that
there's another joke
daily
you