good afternoon happy Wednesday afternoon
to you this is the grow leading at IETF
92 if you think you're in a different
meeting you should leave if you'd like
to stay for grow that's great too we're
gonna get started in just a minute
there's blue sheets going around please
take the time to sign the blue sheets do
it three times so we get a bigger room
next time no don't just once is fine we
have four presentations a little bit
update about current drafts and things
in progress and then ever to be able to
go home well I mean back to wherever you
were before here all right this oh sorry
that's the note well slide it's an eye
chart intentionally I'm sure you've seen
it several times I changed one word in
there you have to go find it so anybody
else have anything to add to the agenda
going once going twice okay good um
quick draft status we have four actually
I think there's six things that are
currently flying around in mid process
the filtering threats was updated in
February I think actually maybe yeah
februari the air-handling document I
think actually Rob you sent a update for
this in recently or is it yeah not the
November but like in last week or two or
no oh gee we
okay right uh so i should also said
earlier on we need to pick up somebody
take notes and a jabber scribe one to
note taker Jared No okay great we got no
ticker in a jabber scribe perhaps 00
cherokee javascript great excellent all
right so backing up again we have draft
status we owe Peter putted last call in
for the growing threats last night the
air-handling document was refreshed by
Rob and he's looking to get last called
and out the door hopefully after this
meeting provided there's no substantial
comments I'm like today the route leak
problem definition shriram had an update
but we can half ago and he's going to
say a bunch stuff about it a little bit
later today thanks then there's some
expired stuff grow bgp shut i think that
this might actually be waiting on
something from the chairs i have to talk
to the authors and unless there's one of
them around the grow RP sale via also
expired and so did the leak attack no
help b.tech note bgp sec no help that
expired in favor of shrooms draft i
believe so unless somebody wants to
argue about that we'll leave that one go
next there's a two that are in
processing the route policy
considerations is in iesg processing
don't remember what the extech exact
status for that is and then the route
server operations it's in the editor q
so it should pop out as an RFC at some
point in time and then we have a bunch
of presentations
alright so there's a the same stories
last time there's the pink box okay stay
in the pink box talk to Mike do you want
to present yeah okay it's going to be
harder for you to be in the box and also
present but oh I can move then I'll stay
into the box
push a button on the things it doesn't
work
ok and should i use this yeah so my name
is Jackie O Hara from aunt Edie and I
this is an introduction of the BGP dump
to which I developed this is the tool to
read the real dump so the motivation is
that the we are saving route routing
table in route of use project and right
NECC mainly and there is saved as a file
so this is the new tool to read those
routing tables it is a beneficial if we
analyze those full routing table to the
health health check and or the molded in
the future round table shape so as an
ISP I belong to that is all I wanted to
know that how we are doing by comparing
the BGP route and also I in doing so I
wanted to modify something so that so I
developed it from the scratch so this is
the kind of you know but the rube dump
files how we save them like the this is
the Kota and target AS is called a rod
monitor or the target is a busy Pacifica
is called Rob monitor and we call it as
appear in the ripp file
so there is a DS list of existing tools
but I created a new one yes and it meets
a goal I succeeded the support the GDP
so that we can read the right sorry
right real file as well in using this
tool so what's good in this is just this
is the simple example of the simple
display and we can we have a partial
compatible mode with the zip it up the
community and local prefer those are not
yet shown but briefly it is compatible
right now and we can show the display we
can show the pier table and Poppaea
routing table and palkia statistics like
how much how not what number of routes
is contained in each pier and what is
the distribution of the prefix length
like the of course the / 24 is the most
biggest one that has the distribution
and also I wanted to know how much next
stop it includes and mostly they are one
but sometimes depending on the
configuration some files includes up to
200 next stops in India rip file so this
is the speed like if we just visit cut
this is the lower bound
we're gonna take 30 seconds if we are
using leopard am pasa it's gonna for
four hundred thirty seconds if we are
using lip BZP done it's going to be 150
seconds and hours 90 seconds so a little
bit advantage in the speed so i created
the diff option which is kind of like a
unified if like if we specify two peers
and if the route is the prefix is only
found in the left beer then it's going
to be minus sign and if perfect's is
only the right side then it's going to
be plus and but when we see this i'll
show you the next question come up we'll
be there yeah we don't have these prefix
in the left pier but should short I mean
should shoulder length prefix covers
this range so that it locked up in the
left side left hands pier there is no
region T to this prefix range know those
kind of in order to answer those kind of
questions we're gonna need a long as
much such so I created I my tool can
construct the routing table using
publish yeah and like if we are
specifying pier 19 and look up for one
address then it's going to be like this
and we can help we can specify as a file
like
the file contains the full address then
look up one by one then some of the
prophets address is not found in the
relative so what we can do is now we can
compare the rich ability if the
left-hand side Pierre actually blocks
the readability all mode we can consult
so I extended the marks like if the plus
is appear then it is reachable but it's
only in the right Pierre kind of like
that and if the prefix is in left and
have not found in the right side then
it's going to be this is the greater
done right this time is shown and after
that may be partial route can be found
then it's going to be using the right
parenthesis so it is yes it is I thought
that the right parenthesis is directing
to the right in not not edgy like so
it's a gent gently right you know I
don't I don't know her stay but so this
is the example so if we are comparing
our isp and another region this prefix
is only in the level 3 but we have some
partial routes so this is the how we can
see
and using that feature and just ignoring
the partial route and filtering the
missing missing route like the left side
left hand side is our route and right
hand is older other peers that is
existing in this file so the this is to
compare the entity's route with each of
other ISPs rod that is what I wanted to
do and these are the missing in the
entity the prefix missing in the MTT
routing table like the there was kind of
60 peers in the file some of them were
empty but the 38 of those peers have
this perfect but the entity doesn't have
so it might be a kind of you know
difference in for protein table and if i
if we unique by the organization name
this is the ranking of the organization
name like the first one is the sum
taiwan network and the next is the
proximity from romania i confirmed those
two prefixes or the organization is can
be found in the global routing table of
the entity but somehow in the Oregon's
route view is not having a DA
rods so even in one isp there would be
some kind of versions and if we were
focusing on the route few organs
throughout the routing table then
there's a difference between the global
entity routing table and Oregon's route
views entity routing table so I didn't
check about the third but for the fourth
this is kind of eye catching so the I
ask talented entity operators to track
down why's that we don't have this time
warner cable's profits it is confirmed
that in also in the global routing table
some of the profits is not there so the
we are asking and also the Sun as for
the voxel t in from Romania some of the
asian network doesn't have a reach
ability to the voxel t even though the
NTDs global routing table have it
because they set the community tag which
that means do not advertise in asia so
i'm wondering this is not the original
intention of that vogue city itself to
set these tags not to provide a rich
ability to that rgr network so we might
need to contact the boxes these
operators about this
and there are some other nice features
like if we are concerning about the
number of roads in the full routing
table we can have easily we can show the
number of routes in many rebel files
like if we are specifying multiple files
then it's going to be shown like this
one line per rip file so that and
timestamp is the first one and this is
the pa1 disappear to disappear three so
that we can easily create this kind of
figure like this is a ph 0 this is a PR
1 and so on no and this is another
example of the analysis we we compare
the two rib files from a different time
and for that the same pier we compare
the difference of the distribution in
prefix length so the like in from August
12 and to august 13 / 16 is decreased 47
x 47 and / 23 increase in 66 this is
like that and yeah this is another from
August 13 to August 14 the / 24 is
increased in 500 and we can we can which
is arbitrary time range like it's
depending on what real values
so that we this is the one week range
including those two days so there is one
thing I'm concerned creating these kind
of figures because it depending on the
PID is the same for the same PR identity
I mean the if the entity is a pier 19 in
the previous filed and in the next file
the entity is also the pier 19 but
sometimes the pier is changing this is
the implementation issue of the quagga I
think but if we are searching for entity
in the file for ya this is the output
from the three rave files one is the
2020 and PR 20 and pier 21 is the entity
but sometimes 21 22 19 20 so in this
case it's going to be more harder to
create those minor features and as a
discussion the first line is the the
same the pier number is changing and in
doing the full route rolling table you
know I run into some philosophical
question like what is the BGP routing
table even in one isp there is a version
of depending on the area or region so
maybe the common set of the a mini
version of the is from the ISP or the
among the ISPs might be interesting I
thought in the random thought and I'm
thinking that we can evaluate the isps
quality of routing by comparing the bcp
for a relevant table but I don't know
how exactly like just differing two rods
would make you run into some detail a
specific case debugging so I don't know
what is the we can say this is good what
this is but for this kind of thing and I
think the this tool is already
contributing in some sense like we
triggered us for our specific debugging
for specific routes from the out of this
tool so that I think the tool is already
10 official I think features to be added
is like really regular expression in a
spa and also regular expression possibly
on next ops this is suggested by mr.
John camp and also i heard that the
marching is passed n and also matching
in community tag is a is not supported
by one rod evanda like I I thought
someone was saying drinker but I don't
remember these these kind of it feels
might be contributing helpful I think
and also we're going to need a neighbor
resolution using team camry is providing
the dns interface for the name
resolution of aes number so i might be
using this one so this is the last slide
vcp dump is developed from the scratch &
duck that can be used to compare the
reach ability of the two routing table
using the longest marching feature and
I'm open to the feedback please use our
oh I haven't told you that the it is
already in the keypad so you can use
from now on thanks do we have any
questions comments
hi Colin Petrie ripe ncc the issue that
you mentioned with the pure index
entries varying over time and you
suggest that perhaps that's a kwaka a
bug and i I don't I don't probably bug
but yeah well my understanding of it is
that depending on whether or not of here
is actually up although other viewers
have been configured they get insert the
the numbering india and the dump files
is always sequential so if a peer is
down or one who's been removed then it's
going to reorder itself were you seeing
this in situations where the same number
of peers were always in the index table
were you seeing the pier move around
with the same set of peers I didn't
check but I believe the number of peers
are increasing or decreasing when the ID
is changing right yeah so yeah I think I
think what you explained is the what is
happening I think yes
all right thank you for your
presentation think Rob you're next
Thanks don't move outside the box
getting told to get back in my box I'm
quite used to that I think I'll get some
slides so I'm going to talk a little bit
little bit about this draft which is the
operational requirements for error
handling and I thought I'd start with a
bit of history because I I actually
wrote this draft in 2010 so and in 2011
it got published it was I took it to IDR
in the first meeting there in it then
went in to grow spilling Crow since the
idea was to try and put forward some
operational requirements for changes in
PHP error handling since then we've kind
of talked through a bunch those
requirements we've talked through a lot
in IDR we've reached a point of
consensus around the set of drafts their
solutions but still we haven't managed
to entirely finish off the requirements
draft and partially that's me and
partially that's that's the fact that
there's been a lot of debate and
especially some of the debate has been
around implementation issues from people
for comment I she build build the
features so next slide please I think
that the key ideas there in this draft
have been stable for for a long time
they're really around defining a set of
errors that can be defined as
non-critical so we don't we don't tell
how the session we do something to
handle instead some things that are
still going some errors that still
happen and we want to tear down the
session because there's no way to
recover from it and defining error
handling that sits between for both of
those different approaches one being the
things like treatise with drawer and
then the other being how to reset a
session with the least hit hit to
actually carrying traffic over it when
we've also been through a working group
last call we went into ITF last call for
this and one of the feedbacks was the
document wasn't very clear so I see
since then have also done a complete
rewrite of the document to make it a lot
clearer and it kind of suffered somewhat
from we had a bunch of ideas and then we
wrote those down and then they had got
added to and taken away and the document
it wasn't necessarily easily consumable
anymore the main clarifications were
mainly
thanks to Bruno I think which is around
defining more clearly where the
different scopes of errors that we we
had we're around is it an attribute
error is a message level error as a
session level error and then I've so
taken those and linked them back to the
two kinds of error handling behaviors
which are the non-critical and critical
ones that we we had before next slide
please the other thing that we added in
later revisions was there's some debate
around what should an operator do when
you have a really long lived error that
you can't really do anything about
especially when it's remote to you do
you just live with and especially when
that's also a critical error so the
session is continually being torn down
so we've added into two different
potential solutions that there seems
like there's some operational support
for from the various discussions one is
the longleaf equation restart which was
called persistence before and then the
other is a method of last resort where
it is possible to say I know that there
is a problem on this session I can't do
anything about it and I would like like
it to stay up as a as a knob to be used
in emergencies such that you can at
least retain some form of connectivity
when something can't be filtered next
slide please so I think I've addressed
all the comments that there were further
06 version in the or 7 version there's
one my editorial set of changes that
need to be made as I said before we've
been through working great last call on
this I think there's consensus here if I
were to call it could sense based on the
fact that no one really shouts in more
which which is that was really the big
problem before so the lack of shouting
I'm assuming is people being happier out
than people not caring anymore and if
that's not the case then i would like to
be corrected i would really like to
publish this work because five years ago
i started this work and i think we've
actually we've deployed it in our
network we've we've learned a bit about
it it's in most major implementations
stuff that's come from this work so and
it seems kind of broken to me that we
have solutions published without the
requirements which kind of motivated
them necessarily reaching the same level
of maturity so if you don't think this
should be published then I would really
like its shell to be now if you think
this should be problems I'd also like
you to shout when does it last call so
that we can we can progress it so I
think this is some good output for this
working
there's been a lot of input to this
document from a lot of different people
I think it'd be useful to useful to
record them raise our hands Oh who's
actually read the latest draft so it's
not yeah I think let's go to the list
and and I'm guessing that's probably
ready to publish but we have to go
through the list and I will have a potty
in Prague if we do right you're all
invited we probably need to find a few
reviewers just to go make sure that it
goes through before we do last call yeah
um because it has had a major revision
and not many people re-reviewed exciting
they agreed with the original one and
the organs probably better yeah yeah
Joel yay glee um yeah I mean I think
we'll probably try and get some early
feedback from well I shouldn't say early
because it should have been about two
years ago but I early feedback from the
routing a DS when you get when you get
to the point of calling it a working
group last call so that we can get
square with the other sort of
communities of interest on this that's
my only thought go perfect well I'm
shepherding the ID I'll document so I'll
also go to people who made comments
there and see if they've got a complete
list yeah and I expect you to do the
routing area review on your own document
to but you know we will cross this
bridge when we get to it but I don't
think it will be a huge problem it's
just we have some work to do there
thanks I think yeah it will probably put
it out for last call and see make sure
some people review it for last call and
go from there thank you magic thanks
Europe go for ya I was going to do the
other one but I'm toggling through the
screen so okay so let's go so this talk
is about doing some time stamping with
in BGP so this is a work that we started
in idea so the first version was
presented in Toronto and I was
presenting yesterday some updates but
I'm pretty convinced that I at least
some part of this work is really kind of
operations of of PGP so some it's it's
really important to present it here also
so what is the problem that we are
targeting to solve today we are sending
some paths within the BGP control planes
and sometimes we have our propagating
are propagated quite quickly sometimes
not and we don't have any machinery that
is able to monitor this kind of
performance of the BGP control plane so
what we are trying to do here is to
provide some kind of time stamping
within the BGP control plane and let so
we are creating sort of time stamp
vector with in BGP so if I'm positioning
at some PT speaker that is receiving
something I'm able to receive all the
information about what has been the
propagation time at each bgp speaker so
next slide please so why it is important
today for I think the most important
reason is bgp back propagation is really
important for convergence it about you
don't agree
it depends on shore service for example
if you have some will chicas VPN you
need to send something to be able to
join the tree and you need to be able to
send it very quickly this is a well of a
use case as you have some layer free VPN
and you are relying on convergence
because you at least your essay is not
too much critical so you can rely on it
your bgp update must not take at least
hours or minutes to be received by the
receiver node don't smile it's happening
so we are clearly facing some issue in
operational networker life at large
scale with bgp propagation time so it
sounds really important for us to to be
able to monetize it's becoming more and
more critical because we are more and
more services that are using bgp so we
are before we have we had only internet
then we add a layer free VPN now we are
doing layer to VPN VPN multicast VPN
using bgp and from an operational point
of view as operator we would need to be
able to mix all of them in the same
boxes for capex reason an optimal cost
optimization so it's really important to
to ensure that by mixing this all is
still working fine because all the
different services as have different
priorities on a critical some are less
critical so we need some tool to be able
to monitor is so the good behavior of
the control plane next slide solve the
requirements so we need something to be
able to monitor performance in term of i
would say orchestration i will need
something that is really simple I don't
need I don't want to establish multiple
session to each bgp pier and then try to
correlate information by
okay i know my topology I know that this
is a first-half effectiveness is a
second one so this one need to receive
the information first and via ye it's
really complex its complex within an IAS
and if you want to do it in in TI es
nada it's even more complex so what I
want is ok I'm triggering some pub at
the point of a network and i want to
receive the informations at some
different point of listening and then
being able to analyze what's happening
in the past propagation so a single
point of listening is something that is
sounds really important the other point
is I need to as i said be able to gather
information about what is happening in
between so at each bgp speaker and for
sure we need a solution that is quite
accurate in terms of being able to
measure of this time Tempe next slide so
the solution what we sow so shall you
are currently proposing inner in idea is
based on a new bgp attribute which is
called bgp time stamp which is simply a
vector so each PGP speaker that will
receive the path and we send it to to
some other bgp speaker will add some
information about when it received this
information and when this send operation
has been done or so to the next pgpr to
the net bzip speaker so as you look at
the diagram here so for example see one
is sending a bgp update for specific
prefix it's adding some bgp timestamp
information and then each speaker in
between so originator on the listening
point we'll add a subsequent information
within a witch in the vector next slide
please so for sure the scope we are
targeting is not to timestamp everything
ah at least in my opinion this is not
necessary
we already had some internal machinery
to try to measure office bgp propagation
time within a live network without using
such extension but two-bit complex
butter okay okay we have something that
is currently working and what we see
that by using some pubs so I'm sending
some prefixes sometimes so I'm sending
withdrawing Sam Dean withdrawing from
different point of the network and we
are doing some sampling and it's
providing already practical information
so we want social solution is retarget
to to be done on some very specific
prefixes that really a send on which one
and something sounds too to be a good
solution for for the measurement so next
slide so for sure we want something that
is the go to run into a yes because for
example in our use case with owning
multiple a a season we want to be able
to multiply propagation time between
aces we considered some kind of my if i
don't know if i can say with security
issue but sometimes you may issue are
talking to a partner for example you
don't want to expose your internal
topology on your internal time stamp so
we are providing some ability to drop
the timestamp information or aggregate
the information to say okay the time
stamp with in my network is just the
entry point and the last point on you
are hiding something all that is in
between so since something that we are
currently considering so depending of
the use case it's useful or not this is
something that we can we can discuss
next slide please so the next step so at
least as a service provider wishing that
is this is something that is really
necessary to be able to monitor his
performance in term of solution we are
proposing a solution
is it a good solution or not service is
something that we can we can discuss it
maybe some some pros and cons so we are
clearly welcoming your feedback about
this an interim of work the question is
do we still need to continue this work
on idea only do we need to own at least
maybe the problem statement and
requirements in this working loop and
split with solution and encouraging
maybe in idea personally I don't care so
this can be discussed
Doug Montgomery so are you proposing to
timestamp things upon receipt or upon
best path selection and transmit receive
and transmission today both we started
with only receiving an intern toe we had
some comments that doing it also in the
selling process is useful so we added
actually I think it's the only place
that it's useful or at least you know a
route could sit in your ribbon for weeks
until it's selected as best bad I agree
with you but as I mentioned the target
is really to have some kind of POD
prefixes so when they will be received
and automatically selected as the best
path and exported you see see the
questions any other feedback
did he present this an idea already yes
well first time in Toronto and yesterday
also for you including your data and
posted your dates so it's only for probe
prefixes this is what I'm targeting but
we can discuss I'm open do you see a
really interest to do it for example for
all your prophecies well not all but
some that are actual praefectus sure why
not you can you can do it maybe that's
an interesting question I mean it works
with book right so you're just proposing
an attribute that if you've dropped it
in a path that was for a real prefix it
would do its thing
will you well okay for the
production prefixes actually what you
would be looking at how old all those
are you don't want you don't want the
production prefixes flipping around all
the time and this and demonstrating and
demonstrating how well you are doing the
conversions okay and I think we need to
probably talk offline about it and
decide on our way forward and so we will
talk to you okay sure thang said it
right
I'm straight am from list so the problem
definition document in Honolulu be
presented a individual draft version of
it and subsequent to that in grow its
it's been accepted as a working group /
draft so the this is the work working
group group dropped version next slide
please so compared to the previous
version the diffs are we have added two
new types of route leaks and that was
based on comments that we received in
the hallway in Honolulu from and ray as
well as Brian Dixon essentially they
thought that the previously the five
types of route lakes that that that we
we did the classification earlier we put
it in five different categories or types
they thought that it would be more
complete if we looked at some other work
and and thought about that and and and
see if that that list is complete or
something could still be added and we
have also added several relevant new
references next like this so we had
types 1 through 5 which I talked about
and described in Honolulu and since then
56 and 57 odd new again motivated by
comments from Andrea and Brian type 6 we
can I guess go to the next slide this is
my last slide just to give you what is
new in the in the new version of the
draft type 6 is a leak of provided
prefixes to peer so this is this happens
when an offending a a sleeker prefix
routes learned from its parameter
provider to lack to a lateral peer and
type 7 is a leak of peer prefixes to a
provider so typically the the prefix has
originated from a customer cone goes to
an ISP and the ISP gives it to appear
and then that
here shouldn't be transmitting it upward
toward towards the provider so so so
these two types have been added and just
like we had real real world the incident
examples for each of the previous five
types there are such examples for these
as well so type 6 what Jarrod Mar chops
where he sees three ISPs in a sequence
in the a s path so some of those are
type 6 kind of leaks and type 7 if you
take for example the dodo Telstra
example the prefixes that a whole bunch
of thousands or hundreds of thousands of
prefixes that dodo passed on to Telstra
they included not only the prefixes that
we had learnt from providers but also
from from peers so so so that I believe
like makes it reasonably look good in
terms of classification based on all the
real world incidents that that we have
been able to cat a cat log and and look
at over the last several years and so if
you have I mean I'm sure there can be
other definitions of route leaks leaks
which are not included here but we
thought that these are critical they
have made news every now and then and so
so based on that we have this this
classification for now and if you have
feedback that to add to this or I'll
make any improvements in the draft its
most welcome
Jen ago I read the draft and I'm kind of
surprised to see certain the type tool
you referring to stealing the internet
presentation because and at the same
time you saying that as the highest pass
is not modified I think what was
particular interest in quincy stealing's
internet def canto that there i can we
defied is passed to make sure that is on
the path to the victim could not see the
announced I oh I mean the okay so time
to is Miss more specifics skate again
you churn with more specific presence
right so I think if you are referring to
DEFCON I talk ah yeah you probably
should say that I espouses modified it
probably is a different type of league
because the sub prefix is modified you
are saying the a s path is modified yeah
in that particular case which was
described in def con tal attacker
modified LastPass make sure that other
network could not see the announcement
so did I don't think there s was in
circuit has deleted right I mean no es
was in no new no different no es was
inserted or deleted they inserted the
ISS which are on the path between the
attacker and the victim yeah that is
Oh video actually I think I think
the path the maliciously ejected
announcement was manufactured now if the
if the actual prefix that's being
announced changes this is not leaking of
a route that somewhere it is actually
many it's actually manufactured and well
okay that it actually copies parts and
modifies parts of announcements that are
there mm-hmm does not really match my
definition of League ok so our intention
was to to see if yeah I mean that could
be malicious leagues and if if you if a
malicious t equal to happen you could
modify you could pretend that the
whatever come in here you could you
could change this up prefix to a sub
prefix so it could be intentional just
to make the traffic flow through your a
as in which case in which case the
traffic does indeed go through the a s
so it has the same effect as a regular
leak with a full prefix so so you could
have you could have intentional or
malicious leaks and that's where that's
where the sub prefix at the type to
comes in and then we talked about the
prefix hijacks right where that the
reverse path to the legitimate
destination is still available as so
there again there have been like
examples like Bell dress and Iceland
where the whole the prefix with the
whole path was leaked not so not sure it
was hijacked but then in China Telecom
as well so it was if you don't want to
call it you can call it the real
accidentally maybe but it's not clear
that that's what happened though right
in at least the Iceland in the china
telecom cases the routes were simply
like squeezed out the wrong hole right
they were just leaked through there was
no Riya rigea nation they just paddled
on ok so he was filtering on both sides
what's the full pathways present all the
believe so yeah I need to refer somebody
in here knows more about this that would
be great if they would stand up and say
something to contradict what I said but
I'm pretty sure they just leaked out due
to poor provider filters yeah I guess
here I think you are saying in the draft
that you are not trying to list all of
the league's types did you yeah it was
not our intention to try and capture
everything that somebody may think of as
a route leak but we looked at a whole
bunch of incidents in if you look in the
references there are maybe approaching
30 references which which talk about
different types of incidents that have
been called route leaks and so we looked
at all those and then we try to come up
with categories that that describe those
my comment is it's going to be better if
we can list all the roof leaks in the
drop right so yeah kind of just not
trying to list all the types or as we
know it kind of thing is all right I
think but just not trying to explore
Dennis all is you know we were at least
yeah we didn't deliberately exclude
anything we just thought that the what's
being talked about as out leaks in the
press etc that that's that's what we
went by Doug Doug Montgomery
on the show I understood the last
comment so trying to make sure we list
all leaks will guarantee that we will
present a new version each time we come
here but so the taxonomy was devised to
look at various characteristics of
incidents you could choose different
characteristics so if you wanted to
differentiate things that we call type
to the ones where you know there doesn't
appear to be path modification I mean
that's another taxonomy another
dimension in which you could separate
those two so there's more specific sort
of leakages and then more specifically
kaijus with path modification so if if
that seems to form a useful class
distinction one could talk about doing
I also think there is a purpose to just
building a functional taxonomy of many
of these but not saying that it covers
everything you could possibly call
rudely because I think that's an
infinite set of things so yesterday we
presented the the mitigation detection
mitigation draft in IDR and so so the
solution that we had we were able to
extend it to tau clicks of type 6 and 7
as well so that's that's the status of
the things please do let us know I mean
if I mean if you have some if you feel
strongly about any of these
classification put it will please send
us a message for posting an email on the
list and we'll be happy to discuss that
way thank you thank you so looks like
that's all we have for today and this I
ETF we will see you in Prague I believe
so thank you
you