I'm in status so we have pretty much to
working group documents and another one
which is not on the slide so the first
document the GRE empty document we just
requested publication so Ted was our ad
and it went on his plate but the working
group is changing hands to Brian so we
also briefed Brian now that like it's on
his plate now okay so that it's going to
start moving soon with ad evaluation and
the other document is like the ipv6 GRE
document which got adopted since the
last meeting so it's gone through like
two rubs already and it's been actively
discussed and so Ron is going to present
like the updates and see whether working
group thinks so as you see doesn't
that's pretty tight and so keep your
questions to a minimum pretty much so
like keep it shot and then other stuff
we can discuss on the mailing list so
let Fred get started okay so uh excuse
me so any agenda bashing so anybody has
issues with the agenda or okay cool Fred
go-ahead run one
ok
okay extra so what we see about tunnels
is that encapsulation headers always
consume data bytes so that breaks the
1500 everywhere assumption that seems to
be prevalent in the internet today and
it's exacerbated by tunnels within
tunnels where we have you infer the
levels of encapsulation tunnels perform
link adaptation per RFC 2460 when the MT
was in fits efficient so link adaptation
is a way in which a box can break up a
packet into pieces that will fit across
the link and be reassembled at the far
side next chart I'm so uphold the 1500
everywhere assumption one strategy a
tunnel fingers could employ is that it
could say anything smaller than twelve
eighty minus in caps we can send without
fragment and because it's guaranteed to
fit within the 1280 bite minimum to you
you anything larger than 1500 bytes we
can send without fragmenting because
posts that send packets larger than 1500
are really supposed to be doing RC 4821
in other words sensing that those
packets are getting through without
being dropped by a black hole anything
in the middle zone though that's larger
than twelve eighty minus and caps and
less than 1500 might have to use
fragmentation to get them through and
probe to see whether fragmentation is
still necessary so if fragmentation is
needed though it'd be nice if we could
somehow tell the original source that
hey your tunnels fragment and it'd be
nice if you get back off and either
limit the size of the package you send
or do the fragmentation yourself and
this is what I'm calling an advisory
packet too big next chart so what is an
advisory packet too big when the tunnel
has to fragment it can send a packet too
big with a size that's smaller than 1280
subject to rate limiting it can then
either discard the payload packet and
treat the packet the big as a loss
indication or you can fragment the
delivery packet and treat the packet the
big message as an advisory indication so
when a source gets this packet too big
message that's that's lists a size
smaller than 1280 the RFC says it must
include a fragment header in future
packets but it need not reduce the size
of the packets it sends below 1280 and
that's per RFC 2460
unfortunately not all sources do this
and also sources that don't do it are
non-compliant so the source could
instead of doing that reduce the size of
the packets it sends to a size smaller
than twelve eighty or it could fragment
future packets that are no larger than
1,500 so the tunneling you just English
doesn't have to fragment so that's
that's the results of what an advisory
packet too big how's the source to do
next chart the tunnel ingress options
when a source sends an atomic fragment
an ipv6 packet no larger than 1500 with
a fragment header but with more
fragments set to zero in ossett set to
zero the tunnel English can either
fragment the payload packet into two
packets then encapsulate and send both
and they'll be reassembled by the final
destination which is required to
reassemble 1500 or it can perform tunnel
fragmentation on the payload and
encapsulate and send both fragments and
separate delivery packets and these
fragments will be reassemble at the
tunnel egress but the ingress needs to
know that the reassemble the egress can
be assembled as much for example it
needs to know that there's at least a 2
K by minimum mr you on that side or it
can encapsulate the payload packet then
fragment the delivery packet and these
fragments will again be reassembled by
the tunneling ingress next chart so for
non iqp encapsulations we might have for
example I IP GRE Ethernet encapsulation
where Ethan that needs to see 15 18
bites and there is no such as a package
the big message in that environment so
that means that the egress must be able
to reassemble at least 1518 plus and
caps and that fragmentation can't be
avoided in all cases so that we might
also actually need sizes larger than 15
18 for some I triple AAA coatings
Ethernet within Ethernet caps caps
elations is another grey area next chart
so documents of interest we have this
draft templin sticks me on link adapt
which is talking about the advisory
packet t big messages draft templin
arrow link and arrow men also the
interior GRE ipv6 document and draft
Herbert gue and that's my lightning
delivery of this talk on advisory packet
two big messages questions
okay there's no question so what's your
goal Fred it is like do you intend to
ready wanna work on us you want to work
on this here or like what's the goal I'd
like to bring it into this group or
discussion and i think i can take it to
the mailing list and try to generate
some discussion on it sounds good thanks
ok thank you rom ok second lightning
present second lightning presentation um
we were working on a draft a couple
months ago that talked about gip v6
payload over GRE and GRE over ipv6 and
somebody pointed out that there's no
standard for either so we decided to
remedy that next slide so we wrote a
draft last IETF it was adopted as a
working group item we got lots of
conversation on the mailing list between
these two I etfs from Fred Joe told Lucy
and Tom Herbert and we had a few changes
which are summarized in the next two
slides first is checksum text when the
delivery protocol is ipv6 the GRE
ingress should set the checksum present
field 20 the GRE egress router must
accept the value of either 0 or 1 and if
the GRE egress receives a value of one
it must use that information to
calculate length however it's not used
required to use it to calculate packet
integrity the next change next slide had
to do with the MTU and it is basically
what you do when you're in a situation
where fragmentation might be required
when the GRE ingress receives an ipv6
payload whose length is less than or
equal to the GMT you the GRE ingress
must not fragment the payload or deliver
delivery packets that means if you don't
need to pay to fragment you must not now
when the GRE ingress receives an ipv6
payload whose length is greater than the
GM to you it means fragmentation has to
happen and the GMT you is greater than
or equal to 1280 Arquette's the GRE
ingress mount router
must discard the payload send an ICMP
PTP back to the origin and let's say
whoops those bullets bullet shouldn't be
there and the MTU field should be set to
the GM to you so what a thing is in that
nominal case where the the gmt you the
MTU across the tunnel is greater than
1280 drop the packet send an ICMP ptb
back to the source next slide and when
you need to fragment and the gmt you is
less than 1,200 then you have a choice
by default you drop the packet and send
an ICMP packet back to the source
however you have a configuration option
that is on the ingress that says rather
than doing that I'm going to fragment
the delivery up encapsulate the payload
in a single GRE header and fragment the
delivery header the default behavior is
to drop the packet and send an ICMP back
to the source the non default behavior
is to fragment the delivery header next
slide so it's a painfully short draft
all of six or eight pages lots of
discussion we'd like to ask for a
working group last call but we have lots
of comments Eric so Eric not mark so did
I read your slide your previous slide
correctly that you said the default is
to throw those packets away even though
they're perfectly valid pockets yes the
default is to discard them and send an
ICMP back the host will ignore that
because it's less than twelve eighty yes
um so that's no service that's true now
the question I mean I don't have a
problem with the knob i have a problem
of the default setting but yeah i see
that's what we're arguing about which is
which is the most likely serrio i'm
thinking that it's such an odd situation
to have a gmt you less than twelve
eighty that maybe you won't want to
think about what's going on but maybe if
it's not so odd the default
configuration is backwards and it should
be the other way well yeah I think it
because you basically are telling the
hose that me is to provide of the tunnel
I'm screwed up that I'm telling you that
I'm screwed up right because my gmt you
is is too low right okay and you're
supposed to tell yourself not tell the
host because the hose can't really do
anything about it I'd be perfectly happy
just happy to switch which the Fate
behavior is the default looking at her
input from the working group just tell
me which and I'll make it happen I'd
like a few people to come to the mic and
tell me which to do I had another one
which what you might have any draft so
the GRE checksum is only for the GRE
header right so how its defined I mean
the question is really about pseudo
header checksum for other things one of
the distinction between I seen Peavy 49
MP v6 is that nobody we include a pseudo
header checksum to deal with bit
corruption in an outer ipv6 delivery
header all right are you doing the same
thing here and would it make sense
because it might be incompatible with
our people due tre over ipv6 today I
would be surprised if no one has already
implemented if no one has what I I
despite people have already implemented
GRE over ipv6 but I don't know no hats
but the GRE chick some contains the
chicken of the path header and the
payload yeah my question is really about
pseudo header versus not and it might be
that that train sailed many years ago
which is fine hi Tom Herbert I do have a
question about the checks and would you
mind from would you might keep it into
them sorry yeah squirt I had a question
about the checksum can go back to that
slide for a second so we had a
discussion on the mailing list and I
thought the conclusion was that if the
checksum is present that the receiver
must validate it and that doesn't seem
to be what you're saying okay well
actually Suresh is the guy who answered
that so I'll let him speak for himself
um I think we should put that in I think
we should have a present okay we'll make
that change okay thank you oh let's run
so for the GMT you I think it would be a
violation y pues expects if you didn't
provide a 1280 empty for a v6 link so
you have to ensure that I think I'm
sorry could you repeat that please it
would violate the IPC expects if you
cannot provide a link layer that offers
1280 empty you larger so I think you
have to ensure that so I'm checking you
know Eric's co calculates it you're not
with regards to the fragmentations 2473
has quite a lot of text on that are you
could you ensure that you are reasonably
in line with that so we don't create two
different ways of fragment thing you
know after an inner payloads here and
thirdly there are many implementations
of you know I 36 GRE you can we also do
some work to ensure that we're not
creating an aspect here that is you know
not interoperable with the existing
implementations okay I'll answer all
three so it sounds like we have two
action items first is to switch the
default on what we do when the gmt you
is small second is to say yes we will if
you receive a checksum you must use it
to verify integrity now the third as for
existing implementations yes there are
existing implementations and they do
what the draft currently says the
default is to discard the packet so yeah
we have a choice of doing what existing
implementations do or do the right thing
so I think you define that gmt you has
to be larger equal or larger than 1280
which you know might imply outro
fragmentation here and to the chairs I
think we would appreciate if you lost
call this or at least notified 6 my list
as well when this goes through thank you
I mean if there's a knob there Eric Nam
marc ian if there's a knob there and
basically saying your existing
implementations might not have that knob
and basically be hard-coded he have it
be in setting one right well the adverse
it the existing implementations have the
knob it's just the default value that
we're arguing okay yeah then that's sort
of like throw that they'll be easy for
people to adjust their implementations
yeah so what we'll say is the default
value should be to fragment that
delivery okay okay so we will make those
actually it comes to two changes
changing the default value and arm
checking the check zone I'll submit the
draft and then we'll ask for a working
group last call and also simultaneous
last call and sex man all done thanks
next victim please
that's it
so no
hi my name is Tom Herbert and going to
the pink penalty box we do that's like a
thing also in a box magic box step out
of the box and it moves it rejected so
I'm going to try to do another lightning
talk this is generic UDP encapsulation
it's a protocol kind of what it says
next slide please so basically what
we're trying to do here is a generic
extensible flexible and capsulation
mechanism and this actually came out of
network virtualization however we did
realize that we could expand that and
basically have a kind of a general
protocol next slide so generic UDP
encapsulations its roots lie in GRE
protocol looks a lot like it jiri
obviously well established while
deployed very simple so we like that in
large deployments unfortunately we've
kind of hit a wall with GRE basically
it's really difficult to extend so we
found a way to extend it by somewhat
overloading the texan feel and the
sequence number fail in the key ID field
but that's about it and even if we add
at new fields on the edges middle boxes
that need to do d parsing wouldn't
understand these new fields basically
because the GRE header length is
computed by interpreting the field bits
so GU kind of you can think of as a
successor to GRE or potential successor
and in it we try to keep the same model
of simplicity and extensibility we want
opportunities to extend the protocol so
that's a big part of this and why we're
at it add a few improvements you know
that you might have wish we had in GRE
next slide so this kind of a list of the
features as I mentioned will use flag
fields much like Jerry so if bit set it
refers to a field we had a header length
this is the thing that allows
middleboxes to basically basically skip
over unknown fields to do deep parsing
the next header is indicated by IP
protocol instead of ethertype we found a
few interesting uses for that and also
saving those eight bits from the ether
types actually worth it in the header
this is fundamental UDP encapsulation so
it's much like the other you team
capsule ations so we kind of get ecmp
for free there we have a concept of data
messages and control messages security
is a big part of this so we actually
define a security field kind of optional
but this is used to authenticate headers
in certain environments yeah checksum we
have a checksum like jury although this
is kind of the improved checksum so it
includes the pseudo header and its UDP
light so that the checksum is only over
the header and this solves problem and
switches where they don't want to
compute the full package checksum but
still want to have some sort of checks
them over the header hardly hardware
friendliness was considered obviously
GRE is hardware friendly by the fact
it's deployed and they're saying things
that parse it so we're kind of hopeful
that that will continue and as I
mentioned we have support for network
virtualization it's like so I won't go
into too much detail over the gue
headers but we have the normal version
and header length protocol next field c
bit indicates whether it's a control
message or data message and then 16 bits
of flags and this last flag is actually
kind of special it allows us to extend
the flags field so that we're not
limited to 16 bits we can actually
extend that to another 32 bits so
conceptually we do this over and over
again and have as many bits as you want
so it is you know trying to think a
little bit forward hopefully we won't
wind up with hundreds of flags but it
allows for that next play UDP so as I
mentioned we can use a source port for
entropy much like other European
consolations UDP checksum very similar
to the MPLS over UDP over UDP
same provisions however since we do have
the ability to add a header checksum
within the encapsulation that may
mitigate certain circumstances where we
wish we could turn on the texan but we
can't because of the switch
compatibility next lane so primary goo
header so I have some detail here as I
mentioned there the header length to
allow skipping over a product protocol
see type field serves two purposes
either it's an IP protocol or control
type and that's distinguished by the sea
sea but next slide so just kind of an
overview of the headers I already
mentioned that next slide more on the
undersea bit next slide please so I will
mention about the flags this is kind of
an important part of the extensibility
and one of the things are very careful
about the flags is to make sure that we
have forward compatibility and one of
the rules about the flags is if a flag
bit is set and the D capsule later does
not understand that flag bit packet is
dropped so this solves a lot of problems
where if we want to add a flag safer the
checksum receiver gets that and doesn't
understand that instead of just ignoring
it in organic cut some which would be a
bad thing it will actually drop the
packet so there is an assumption here of
the ability to either synchronize or
configure these things upfront and so
you can kind of skip the next three
slides so this is some more detail on
the flags in the fields and what we're
trying to accomplish there so the
protocol is designed to be extensible
and in fact we have already defined five
extensions virtual virtual network
identifier is for network virtualization
this is really the only thing we found
specific to network virtualization is
that it needs this 32-bit identifier
security field as I mentioned this is
designed to allow either security cookie
potentially a secure hash over the
header
it is kind of a multi length field to
allow some expansion in the future
header checksum I already mentioned
remote checksum offload is a little
optimization this is based on the fact
that there's already a large deployment
of network interface cards Nick's
basically that support UDP fix them off
load but wouldn't necessarily understand
how to support something like goo so
there's a little trick where we can
actually leverage these you debase UDP
support of the outer checksum to offload
the inner checksum tunnel fragmentation
I think Fred actually alluded to this we
actually came up with a design to do a
tunnel fragmentation this is kind of
kind of has some improvements over IP
fragmentation so for instance we can do
a 32-bit identification instead of
16-bit identification so that's kind of
promising there are a number of
potential possibilities here and I think
this is like a normal what are the value
value here we're trying to make sure
that anything added is is generic as
possible and in fact some of these
fields like a virtual network identifier
security field can be fine in such a way
that can be reused so for instance
security we could have a 64-bit field
but you could use different algorithms
for that and we don't have to specify
specify that upfront in the definition
of the security field so it's kind of
like repurposing the GRE key ID we can
extend that model to some other fields
next slide private David data Regent so
this is another feature that we added
kind of to enhance Giri model a little
bit this allows after the last leg and
before the payload if there is space and
they're determined by the header length
this can be arbitrary private data that
is inserted by the sender and understood
by the receiver so it can be a community
structure we have one case where people
are putting tlv is in there whatever and
says it's fine so that's kind of kind of
neat next slide the status
so we have three primary drafts plus a
few that describes some of the
extensions the goo draft is the base
draft and that describes pretty much the
protocol as is the network
virtualization draft is specific or the
MBO is specific to the network
virtualization extensions and we have a
security draft describing the field we
have a port assignment this is now an
upstream Linux so you can test it out if
you wish we actually support IP IP / goo
GRE over go SI t / go so one of the
reasons why i want to come today
actually had a question basically wick
working group should we consider this to
be on so i think that's one of my
fundamental question we have a dap f
asked for adoption in NV 03 and that's
going pretty well but unlike some of the
other protocols in NV 03 this is really
intended to be a generic encapsulation
protocol that supports network
virtualization as opposed to a network
virtualization protocol okay so our
thoughts so yeah well well Carlos una
gang no had questions that did you
attend that the this put words put off
on tuesday when we were discussing this
from the privacy point of view this idea
of hiding information press and a spud
puff yeah yes I was there and yes I do
believe this could easily kind of be
contort it to do transport encapsulation
also so before that we only consider the
tunnel encapsulation this is very
similar to spot and in fact I think
there are some things we do need that
spud mentioned like that magic number to
allow middleboxes 22 I positively
identify that this is actually
encapsulation so can parse it so I think
that would be a good addition but if you
kind of peel back the onion these become
very very similar at some point if not
if not the same for instance one other
thing we need here is probably dtls the
original security draft to ipsec but i
think dtls is
much more compelling with the UDP based
protocols we probably have that in which
case the packets would probably almost
look identical you couldn't tell the
difference between the tunnel and a
transport encapsulation if they're the
payloads both encrypted all you have is
some sort of encapsulation header I
don't know if that was your question but
well yeah yeah wait is he what what what
those are because definitely there's a
lot of relationship or overlap or
coordination mention in the pod that
there's kind of parallel efforts here
and a lot of this comes back to UDP
encapsulation there's a lot of
commonalities and we should try to
leverage that ok thanks yes basic oh yes
I can my question is am I don't know if
you did you define a tunnel
establishment procedure no there's the
control plane is considered higher layer
this is only describing a data plane the
same thing in theory people did so but
they are going to try to establish their
control comment lining command line
interface you can on creativity so can
create a retail but I'm not sure how do
you do with the good so what is a good
idea to define the the tunnel
establishment procedure in the industry
itself I see so in one in one sense it's
similar to GRE so I can figure both ends
of a tunnel and provide the parameters
and then I can talk GRE between them
there's other interesting use cases so
for instance I think threads not here
but we have talked about the possibility
that arrow would actually use GU as the
underlay encapsulation and then the
management of the tunnels would be arrow
and from that point of view we consider
kind of arrow or in the case of n via
three network virtualization to be the
user of the encapsulation and the
control plane is deferred to that layer
so there's a clear separation here
between data plane and control plane so
that so I don't think we
really planning on that I think it
actually makes sense to have the
separation keep this has just
encapsulation properties of
encapsulation and then above that but
then people who want to use it they come
up they have this problem right how do i
establish so then everybody will come up
with a different protocol so it's not a
problem like I said I mean we already
have GRE we've lived without having a
control plane for GRE it is not
established in every I'm almost a rotor
vendor I think they support command line
interface for that so what I would
anticipate what happen is there will be
another layer either arrow or some
generic tunneling kind of control layer
network virtualization maybe we should I
didn't afterward so what happening we
have to get to that too so I went to the
draft but he said like he had like
extensibility issues with GRE right like
it's not clearly defined what do you
want to extend the GRE that was
difficult i can give you the precise
example and why we actually invented
this at Google was response to our
attempts to turn up network
virtualization so network virtualization
we needed a protocol and one requirement
that we had that wasn't satisfied by any
existing protocols the exelon or envy
GRE was we needed a security token so we
needed to prevent some mechanism prevent
any spoofing basically and guarantee the
integrity of the virtual network
identifier problem was if the virtual
network identifier became corrupted
packets could go to the wrong tenant
this is a serious breach of kind of our
first requirement Network fertilization
so we have to add have to add something
GRE is the most common I'm probably most
commonly deployed encapsulation we would
like to extend that but jury besides the
key ID really doesn't have any usable
fields that we could put the security in
we could try to hack it and overload
some of those fields but pretty quickly
even even if we manage to do that well
we still would like a header checksum so
GRE check some very
it's just the payload doesn't even have
a pseudo pseudo header checksum so can
we have a header checksum that was
actually one of the suggestions from the
fragmentation and tunneling problem so
you start to go down that path and
realize wow you know if if we're going
to create a new protocol let's make sure
it's extensible and you know hopefully
last 30 years and we can predict we can
even meet the requirements in the future
we can't predict for something like this
security I think is a big one security
is only going to get tighter and tighter
in the data center so we're going to
need more and more opportunities okay so
a lot of Cutlass next and then sorry I
put myself in McGee Juan Carlos swing
again no hat the there's two aspects to
it one isn't the network or the virtual
network identifier and then there's also
the privacy so my comment goes more to
towards the privacy and I want to get to
your question to what working group
should this be and there's several
efforts right now going on on the
privacy like we're running this this
market restaurant on my station
experiment layer two but then there's
also drafts for ipv6 address privacy
settings then we're talking about while
doing this and I p but layer 34 but also
we have talks with w3c on the higher
layers seems to me that we actually
require quite a bit of coordination and
make sure that we do the right thing
when it comes to privacy features and
i'm not sure what this point in time one
one single group can answer a question
we just talked about this this but the
overlap with spot and the you know the
fact that there's there could be some
overlap or or relations or need to
coordinate let's say between the two so
I agree with that um in some sense it
would have been nice if we could have
put this into either IP options or ipv6
extension headers but then we run into
the common problem against which support
for these and so I know Eric probably
has feeling about this too but one one
thing about an encapsulation header in
theory we can solve problems like that
right so we could never extend IP
options because
just don't support it but we could start
to put this stuff in encapsulation
headers i'm not i'm not advocating that
I think it's a slippery slope so we
definitely need a lot of diligence about
where we put these things in this case
the security actually is tightly
associated with a virtual network
identifier so I'd like those to be
logically together that they are wanting
the same I cannot accept the virtual
network identifier without the security
saying it's it's valid so that's that
there was a tight coupling to those and
there may be alternatives but this was
actually pretty simple but interpreted
on the same you ensure the trust
relationship with it with the network or
there's some authentication to the to
the actual network because then if you
are binding the two then you need to
have the mechanism to also make sure
that the network is trustworthy the
network to be able to parse to them so
middle yeah so rule is middleboxes may
inspect the headers they do not have to
understand all of the bits they should
not drop it if they don't understand
something they can inspect it however
they really can't change it and security
probably prevents that because security
Zhen nan so if they change the bits
it'll break the security but we do allow
for middleboxes Parsis if somebody wants
a firewall based on the virtual
networking identifier which is almost I
mean pretty much guaranteed to happen
then yes they can do things like that ok
thank you ok cool not much so I think
that on the extensibility thing unless
I'm mistaken but I thought that the
reason to have the header length is not
only for the middle boxes it's also so
that you can potentially send a packet
with some new stuff in it and the D
capsule ater can basically d capsulate
it and sort of silent ignore whatever it
didn't understand right which we can't
do it with GRE on on the D caps later
yeah i mean it can say i know about flag
one two three and that's all I know
about so i can actually parsed out and d
capsulated the fact that the
encapsulated
encapsulator included oh it's over there
included flag for right the D capsulated
can skip that isn't that the default
behavior here no it's it's the exact
opposite if the D capsule later gets
it's like that it doesn't understand it
must drop the packet and the reason for
that is the forward compatibility
problem and I think we're seeing this in
VX land another instance is a router
alert so if I add something like a
security field and that's a new field
and I send that to someone who doesn't
understand that field it makes no sense
to ignore that you're basically ignoring
a security field so if you look at the
extensions we've added I don't I haven't
seen one yet that would make sense to
ignore their there may be some but for
the most part you know if we had
something in checksum or if we had
something like remote checksum offload
that is supposed to modify the packet to
fix up the checksum we really can't
ignore that we certainly couldn't ignore
fragmentation because this is not no
longer a packet that can be received by
the host so there may be alternatives
and we can take it offline but even GRE
had some semblance that some of the
flags had can't be ignored and some can
be i'm not sure how successful that was
in fury yeah I wonder whether we want
the flexibility of having some sort of
ignore if you don't know about them but
and but we can take it offline se
because but I would I would really love
if somebody gave a good use case there
are four for the ignore flight problem I
do realize that this is in some sense
contrary to a lot of precedent GRE was
it was a different one in that that have
mandatory flags well it you note on that
would be great it's some level I mean
I'm reflecting saying and this is this
reflection but it's sort of the inverse
of today today the middle boxes will
drop everything they don't understand or
many metal boxes have that behavior
because they think they know everything
whether we told them to behave that way
or not but but and the endpoints are
sort of more liberal than what they
accept and this is sort of the opposite
but ha I don't
fine man okay thanks um so I have a use
case like for this like it's incremental
deployment but let's not talk about it
right like so we need to first figure
out like that this is going to go right
so what is the status of this at envy or
three so because I don't see anything in
the tracker that does not auction call
or anything so so we are in a coffer
working group adoption that's been going
on about a week so we're halfway through
so far all three of the proposals have
not had any negative feedback okay so
and and I did mention to Benson so I
suggested this I said we have three
drafts what is the appropriate place and
he said to ask in the area guys okay um
so Brian have you had a chance to take a
look at this draft okay okay so I think
of Eddie Brian yeah so um so I think
it's like what while discussing this in
the entire email English so let's try to
get a discussion going on the mailing
list to see if it like belongs here but
if any or three is willing to take up
the work we can just like last call it
here like all over suggesting for the
GRE raft so if there's like another
place where it fits and nowhere else
very fixed right if there's not nor the
working group that wants this other than
your three it makes sense to leave it in
NV 0 3 and we can just do review here so
that's one way to go forward right okay
so i probably i would like to keep them
a separate separate dress because i like
the modularity definition right Brian
Haberman as your newly ordained
shepherding ad or less than 24 hours so
yeah
there I guess there are two aspect here
that I will make sure we keep in track
the first one is and forgive me for
having coming here late because i'm
actually chairing the working group
somewhere else the routing area is
hosting a design team to try and figure
out all these data encapsulation
mechanisms ok i just make sure that
we're we're on board with that one and
i'm on that committee good good i don't
i don't want I don't want dairy to go
running off doing yet another data
encapsulation mechanism and have those
guys go what are you doing but as long
as you're involved I'm fine men and that
let somebody here know what's going on
the second thing is is that I think at a
minimum you want to have people here
review it so if envio 3 wants to adopt
all three of them then as things go
forward I would expect to see a you know
a kind of a dual working group last call
in both int area and in MV 0 3 having
not seen these three are they I mean
I've assumed the second to our envio
three specific and the first one they
really only the env 01 the a third one
is actually generic its security for the
encapsulation okay but date but they all
need to go together right or I believe
so security is optional however i
believe it's it's kind of court at least
of everything that I'm thinking oh let
me channel Stephen Farrell security is
never optional down
that's fine dear David black wearing a
transport area working group hat and
trying to make walked up here with the
sort of a explanation sort of where
transport is and I think overriding
concern is that probably ought to be one
focal area for this work and right now i
guess i guess i glued what i thought i
heard brian say that the routing folks
appeared of appear to be leading the
charge there I mean I've talked Tom
about this draft a few times I've seen
seen seen em vo three I think envio
three is going going to adopt all of
these over and transport I think we're
going to we're going to care somewhat
about the use of UDP but and
particularly have we have the GRE and
UDP draft which we're making we're we're
making progress on I think this is this
is ok to go forward if you've got guts
something generic but I'd hate to go see
things things getting worked on in
different ways in different areas my
sense right now is that is a routing is
in the lead I'm happy happy to have
things stay that way for a while yeah
thanks to Eric so yeah so I agree with
that I think the thing that we can if
there are other use cases that are not
tied to any or three right it might make
sense discuss those use cases here right
because you can't really discuss them
over there right and you know I don't
know if I mean some of them you already
covered but if people come up with
additional ones that might be one other
thing is that that would be closer here
than in NV 0 3 I don't know what do you
mean by use cases so what I want if the
fortune cookie option all right
something else in the pocket okay not
use cases of the protocol but additions
yeah external or overriding uses yes yes
that's what I'm not yet okay that makes
sense so there are a series of drafts so
for instance the fragmentation option
is probably of less interest and via
three but seems like it'd be more
interesting here and yeah that's a good
point particularly if we talk if we're
talking about other aspects of
fragmentation here in tunnels right
there might be down here click I don't
know yeah my inclination is and correct
me if I'm wrong to start with the basic
three and then move to the rest yeah
thank you okay so thank you very much
Tom so so what we'll do is we'll take
the discussion on the list and talk to
the envy or three chairs and the routing
and cat design team head that's Eric
over there so so since David black
doesn't want it in tsv for now so let's
so let's get started from there and see
where we want to take this okay thank
you then we yes I'm here okay so so it's
my fault I didn't apply the time sauce
for the me cool for some reason
so here I think maybe I'm not as a
really they me good people but I
have to make a shorter presentation so
what if today is we have the
architecture work working group draft
between the FCA Turk you so ted has
approved in this week and we also have
the mpv d id agree would have been
presented a couple times we are thinking
we are going to have a working class
call after this meeting and also we have
the DCP support MPD extension that has
been presented in dhcp working group i
think they call comments we are updating
and after the update we are going to
have last call together and also the NDP
extension also been presenting in the
sixth man working group you also got a
comment and we are the update together
and also does these three draft will be
we are going to issue a working girl at
school before next 90 meeting and the
first one is a
you mean a TI document so we plan to how
rewrite this document to up adapt to the
mpv d architectures so we would like to
have the major contributor to walk
homeless and the chair we are
coordinating the offline people about
this work and the third one is a problem
formalism liaison work so the Miffy
walk-in cooler has an interest to what
countries live since last I team meeting
and we got some of the volunteers and we
are thinking we probably as one with a
candidate proposal from itm to work on
this problem we are talking with a TS
about what we are going to do links
that's it thank you
the topic the topic is fierce ipv6
options for the discovery of 46 48 lat
ipv6 prefixes and the four six four
isolates provide ipv4 connectivity
across ipv6 network using translation
technology and the you know translation
process plus C let's master discover the
pill I said the translation ipv6 prefix
salite and bending to the destination IP
v4 dress into the discovered ipv6
prefixes to get to the destination ipv6
address and for the multi papi lights
scenario the front of you lights help me
help different ipv6 prefixes in this way
a pill traffic can be attract attracted
to the crack 30 light so our work
proposes a deer's ap ways with six based
the measure the further pill pill I said
ipv6 prefix the discovery and the
solution I will show a la finger first a
lusty light and here's a few a6 server
interaction the see light request to the
polite prefix least the option in tears
ap way six requests and then that use a
few a6 server probations the pill I've
said translation ipv6 perfectly stop by
the option and then Inga Inga lista
adoptee lights ipv6 prefix and well more
polite Oh ipv4 prefix a testers are all
contenido and the steel IT recorded the
pill I decided translation ipv6 prefixes
in Neutron in the translation process
all the delights must select the correct
a polite according to the provision the
prefix list and the destination ipv4
address
oh the correct ipv6 the prefix it can be
selected by the longest match first to
you next and there are two options
define first either Oh prefect T life
prefix the least option it is a
container option for well more of July
to prefix the option and it is
compatible with single colitis if there
is only one prefixing the prefix lista
and honor to define the option is a
tealight prefix it is encapsulated in
the unity ID prefix Lister and the HP
light v6 prefix counting a sole option
in the English on the polite ipv6 prefix
and the corresponding one more IP with
ipv4 presa are all listed next and
comments are welcomed and I will I
wonder which which working to replace it
is a fit for the draft okay so just to
provide everybody some background for 64
X slide is a transition technology that
has got done by v6 ops and v6 ops is not
charged to do protocol look okay and
it's a dhcp option but dat working group
like doesn't do options for other people
it reviews the options at some point
when people do protocols and so that's
why there's like no natural fit for this
work so that's why we are considering
this in interior so just some background
so not any comments okay I think we'll
just take this up on the list and see if
you want to adopt it here or not okay
thank you Eric
I thought this rectangle was sorry shake
of the shape of the rectangles off in
the realignment so I decided to come up
come up with a long title so it was
brought to my awareness that we run into
these various things that I decided to
call intentionally partially partition
links or mouthful and in exactly this
one slide you can go to the actual slide
and I'm trying to investigate this stuff
and I'm basically standing up here
saying if you have some clues to impart
on me or you want to help with this
stuff let me know right but i'm planning
to sort of gather some stuff into some
internet draft but i haven't started it
yet but i just wanted I got this
opportunity to send this advertisement
or whatever request for help so these
links are they look to IP as a link in
that they have a subnet prefix but
they're intentionally not uniformly
forwarding packets at layer 2 right and
we've seen it so typically the way they
used is that hose can talk two routers
and vice versa but hoes cannot talk to
host and we've seen at least two
examples of this or I've seen two
examples of this there's a split horizon
case that's used for dsl were basically
that the host can chat with each other
described in some dsl forum report and
there's private vlans that people deploy
to sort of conserve on connectivity
address space whatever there is a
solution but they there's very little
little written down how to deal with the
stuff in the general case as far as I
know sort of howdy how do you configure
things and what works and what doesn't
we have a solution for the specific
cases split-horizon that deals like with
dad right but I don't you haven't seen
anything that says how do you do it do
you arpan ND for the general case
particular how do you do dad for the
more general case I don't think that
that that that proxy dad thing
necessarily works for the more general
case which is there in private vlans
because a pack at the v you have these
things that are what is it called I
think it's called community vlans where
some house can talk to each other and
they conducted the router there's some
other things that are somewhat related
which is some filtering in RFC 4562
which isn't really partitioning the
layer to link it's really as saying I'm
going to play with the ARP table sends
on filtering to get some isolation
behavior and I think at least when I
started thinking about this stuff that
felt like that was a different thing but
because it's not partitioning things at
layer 2 so that you have any loosely in
part here I'm grateful two very quick
things one of them is you should add
cable modem to the list ok it behaves
much in the same way it's glitter Eisen
right it split horizon yeah you
basically each connection to a
subscriber as a separate channel and so
the subscribers can't talk to each other
except through the CMT s so it behaves a
lot like DSL ok well different so ed add
that to your list the other thing is
that we've touched on this kind of thing
a number of times before you mention one
duplicate address detection that was
raised by the broadband forum unisex ops
and that's where that came from another
one is really ancient history frame
relay where you have circuits underneath
but it looks like a non broad nvm a non
project has multiple access network and
in ospf we wound up with failure case we
had to replace it with point mulund
interface which is essentially a bundle
of circuits so these are these ones at
least it looks today to the attachment
at least to the host it looks like a
broadcast medium yes understood ah but
so it's related but I yeah it's a little
different
you can actually see the circuit we're
well on a CMT s or a beer as you can
tell that there is a channel underneath
yeah you if you're actually on the beer
ads or the CMT else so at any rate yeah
we do have some history there you might
want to take a look at transfer and I'm
inserting androgenic oh between Stewart
and Dave thanks Stewart sure sure I have
a question this also sounds familiar
sounds similar to another case if I'm
sitting in a coffee house with the Wi-Fi
access I can't communicate with the
person sitting next to me even though
we're on the same access point would
that be another case profits this model
so it's so there's two pieces there i
think there's the l2 behavior right i ne
but then there's a separate thing that
doesn't mean that you can't communicate
with TCP because that's is as far as i
can tell sort of at a ACL policy
question on the actual router right what
these technologies do is that they force
the host to talk through the router and
then on the router you can have it i
believe a policy saying oh this hose can
talk at layer 3 or i will run them
through this far wall and see whether
they can talk and there might be
deployments where people say now hosts
should never talk right so there's two
pieces there that it's the l2 behavior
that that basically fundamentally
restricts communication and then there's
potentially l3 policies that further
restrict things but the implications for
things like neighbor discovery doubt
whatever are is due to the the l2
behavior okay well my two observations
are in many of the cases where this
happens it seems like the people running
the network don't want the communication
to happen maybe for misguided reasons
they don't be blamed for getting a virus
on my pc so they want to avoid the
liability my second observation is if
you do want the devices to communicate
that seems like a Miss configuration
because at least in my mind that the
notion of a subnet the useful property
of a subnet is everything on the subnet
is reachable by up and everything that
doesn't match when you use the subnet
mask has to go through your default
gateway and if you really want to treat
this as a series of point-to-point links
then don't make it look like a broadcast
domain if it doesn't behave like that so
that it seems like yeah with a pure
architectural hat I would agree but the
part of the reason these things were
created was to save at least ipv4
address space right so it is a bit of a
hack but it's out there and we should at
least make sure I want to do enough of
an exercise to make sure that ipv6 works
on them as well as ipv4 getting online
at one that loss and I think that
requires that a writing down how I be
before works here as well yes okay so
speaking for android york yankees has
almost any professionally done hotel
event Wi-Fi is another example this
scenario private VLAN nearly if not all
Wi-Fi vendors allowed to prohibit the
communication to in clients and then he
says something okay i replace my
previous comment with your comment is
true it i may want to save ND cash in a
network with 10,000 host and i may want
to force host to communicate via roll
through so yeah we're supposed to
communicate via Ralph okay save the
indie cash yep so speaking for myself
now it was just like to say our seas
3069 which is ipv4 for doing something
similar so you might want to reference
that third and fourth now 3069 30 06 90
k thanksgiving dip dip it work there's a
there's been a confusing multihoming
discussion in envio three that might
result in a in the converse of the use
case in your second bullet where if the
if an essence are the l2 domain is is is
hooked into the virtualization domain by
more by more than one
what are effectively routers although
they may not be you can get in situation
in which you want the host talk to each
other but you do not want something
coming out of the virtualization domain
by one interface going going going back
in I don't know where this is going as
discussion I think is in has been a big
has been a bit confusing to date okay I
didn't quite understand that one but ok
find out ah just as fine a photo read
out of time so feel free to stay here
and listen but if you want to go I'll
understand thanks Dave favor I would
suggest you do a compare and contrast I
gather you're talking about what you
would put into a document a lot of the
things that you're talking about are
similar in some ways to the multi-link
submodel that's used by men a autocom
6lowpan etc there's a couple differences
like the word intentionally as opposed
to you know inherently by physics and
whether you are and trying to preclude
communication between hosts or whether
you kind of like to allow it if you
could if you could and so compare and
contrast because a lot of the same
issues are there and whether you want to
address them or not may differ and so I
would reference the multi-link subnet
model and the six lo pans style
solutions to that for where you want to
get arrested for the issues and ways to
potentially get around it should you
want to and it sounds like you're
specifically trying to target the case
where you want to preclude it rather
than get around it at least precluded l2
right but yes I did look at mobilink you
kinda precluded at layer 2 and get
around at layer 3 then it's just a
multi-link subnet pneus and the existing
techniques used by things like 6lowpan
applicable I don't think it's identical
but yes however so juan carlos zuniga I
also happen to participate in NATO to
that one there's a group they're called
omnirom task group in one of the issues
that we're trying to do is this network
abstraction model for 480 to
technologies and definitely one of the
issues that we've been trying to
coordinate we don't we are not at any
stage yet but some talks that we've been
having Brian Harman was part of it is
how do we present 802 technologies to
higher layers because of the issues that
Stewart just mentioned like it's well
known that some Wi-Fi interfaces you
know even though it's a multicast or
broadcast domain then then you only have
point-to-point communication because of
artificial things that will make you get
to that to the Gateway and this is
especially true for the mobile now with
that we are having this mixed notes of
you know like 3G or 4G sand and wife ice
and so on so so I just wanted to voice
that there is this group and I triple
eight oh two dot one that is trying to
see how we can best serve IP from the
lower layer point of view okay we don't
have an idea yet we know there are
several flavors out there but it'll be
interesting if ever we need something
out of fatal to or any coordination or
any flag or any thing well there's
there's no sorry yes sir some get some
sort of digestible document that
describes a bit what they're trying to
do and think about something they go
read well in fact the only document that
it really gets into this specific point
because it's not the only thing that
only run does right but for this
specific point we had a discussion about
the the net x the logical interface that
this an outdated draft that is being
hanging there in the metrics the group
for for a few you next logical interface
and and it was trying to describe how to
how to at the time was for for IP flow
mobility and how we can basically
present the same behavior from a Wi-Fi
and point-to-point PPP 3g interface
point of view to IP so that r.i.p
wouldn't get confused but but still you
know that we were thinking about
evolving that document into something
more actual and wider than just cellular
okay but we can drop it and do something
else if that's it yeah go look at it
okay thanks thanks a lot folks and thank
you very much for your five minutes
overtime so thank you very much and have
a nice evening enjoy your evening
I will
so what do you want
you