if you have kind of thoughts
additionally the place where feedback
would be good is there's different
styles with which to present the final
kind of schema whether it's down to how
you want to see kind of spacing how do
you want to see you know types defined
versus natively kind of embedding kind
of classes if you have strong feelings
about kind of either of those be great
to put on a list Kathleen Moriarty so
from past experience I would love to see
if we can get a couple of volunteers who
might go through and comb the UML versus
the schema so that we reduce the errata
that gets filed later so maybe the
chairs could um try to get a couple of
volunteers anyone so would anyone here
be willing to do that so and what just
it entails just making sure everything
matches up between so I'm sorry so we
have how many oh great good so we have
three thank you because it's it's so
easy to miss stuff and we had a slew of
them on the first one it's just much
easier if we can thank you yeah I mean
the other thing that would help in
addition to the UML and the XML is that
we've been trying to keep keep a
changelog going about what's different I
know we're not very good about that I
mean I find things aren't we missing all
the time so if in you and out of that
pass if you could take a look at that
that would be greatly appreciated future
implementers well thank you can ask ke
Glen question about um I assume there
are tools that can help too or is it
more than that just making sure that XML
matches the EML scheme when we say uml I
mean I think we have used uml light so
I'm not sure how much the tools will
help us here so i think i'm saying how
about some you tools that will take the
UML and compared to the schema and i was
making the comment that will use uml
light a little bit i'm not sure house
tricky worried especially the way we
represented in the text i actually don't
know how we'd extracted someone someone
has a piece of tech that i can extract
that ask yarn I'm all ears that'd be
great actually mmm
I've been really exciting actually all
right next slide I just want to talk
about some of these issues in depth now
so the mailing list has been really
active in the last day or two on this
particular issue so we talked about this
about a year and a half ago about the
fact that the software type the IDF
software type which is a way to just
describe an application or a piece of
kind of software whether it's saying hey
I got my data from this piece of
software or this piece of software was
targeted we have this data type to
explain that we went back and forth
about a year ago just about switz was
kind of mentioned we said punt at that
time in Honolulu we said we had a lot of
different options at this point we
really do have to decide and so the four
options it leads to four options I think
we have our use oval you swig don't do
anything just say that's someone else
someone else is going to do that with
additional data or the last approach is
to support multiple techniques to
include one and two and use something
like the IDF sei extension or the Edam
kind of draft just to put in an eye on a
registry things like one and two and
potentially other things and then have a
blob to represent what that raw format
would be so we have a number of things
said kind of on the mailing list are
there other things to add to set
conversation do have a feel for which
option is preferred but the list looked
like he was leaning towards for no one
said anything positive about 12 or three
having all the feedback it was okay o
plus fund that one I think yeah but de
vuelta my plus one on for as well
because I I think um type of identifies
and the registers might change all the
time so you don't want to be you know
corner yourself by yeah so this is Sean
trainer so I think I kind of took the
bait on this one right so for me I like
it this way like ophelie is like kind of
like some of the de facto standard rate
and it's used there's a thousands of
maybe hundreds of thousands maybe
correct me it seemed
really weird to force everybody to go to
sweat right when i first started looking
at slid it was maybe a little confusing
whether you had the pain to get a number
that would be bad for open source people
so that didn't seem to make first i
didn't seem to make sense so if we pics
wit and we make everybody switch from
oval that seems weird right then we
could come up with a mapping scheme is
that what we really want to do I don't
know and then don't define it all seems
like kind of not really doing anything
it seems like maybe supporting both
seems like the way to go and I don't
think you really need to begin MTI here
I think it's whatever because the idea
is can you get a free identifiers and
then is the database that you're going
to go look at actually available they
both are so great we're covered Kathleen
Moriarty contributor so I also agree
that that's a fine answer because as
Alexei said it will change over time
groups can choose what they want to use
and we don't spend a year arguing about
this yes and the last ones with the hat
on yeah yeah Dave altameyer again I
agree with everything that was said at
the mic here I like for because we can
incorporate you know the other options
into into four and it provides the
flexibility and extensibility that will
likely need overtime so so so i mean i
get i tend to support for is the right
answer so a bit of a pulling that thread
a little bit if you guys remember what
we did with the enum draft which is to
say yes it's really hard to have
enumerated references but as it turns
out if we're going to create the i enter
registry and create an XML format that's
probably useful across the ITF for folks
that are on an XML representation and
maybe others will even use the I at a
registry as well so talking kind of with
sockem and i'm looking at how to adam
that the get theirs is there because
benefits of the working group to take
the this kind of thinking to implement
option for for software type and to
create a very very short draft in the
light it kind of in the same vein as the
Edam draft for this as well and this
would be useful to sac
what a second's perspective yeah edda
montville yeah it's useful for soccer it
will be and there's just no question so
yeah you need help with that I'll help
you with that yeah I think I mean what
why don't we put that together allows
you to credit this manga say again how
about you to quit the small draft I
didn't understand it this new small
draft swim brand-new and I yeah we'll
work on it ok ok we'd already been kind
of thinking that this would not would be
the right answer very much like the enum
draft I mean kind of short and straight
forward in eldidd just one a day of all
tomorrow one clarifying question are we
talking about creating another I in a
table for software or are we talking
about adding entries to the eye on the
table that has been created under the
email draft as an example I was thinking
different I'm sorry Adam our kuleana I
home I could see it going either way so
let's talk about it and make a decision
and then move forward like Terry we can
talk about it after this yeah that makes
sense and go to the list and all that
yes absolutely all that I mean those
present the option cause and cons of
making you one using something different
but John field also agrees with number
four open enables open and forward
compatibility ok so we're tipping for is
there anyone that wants to speak up
about 12 or three or a present five all
right
for I mean that's conserve some
religions on this one yeah I mean I
think four is the answer so Adam and I
will work to get a draft a skeleton
draft that will reference will create a
separate extension for i/o def software
type also you have a different name
space and in addition we will bring the
list the conversation about you know
reuse the eye on a reg traded crayton
uin register okay 1001 question
regarding number four I guess the
current mechanics like enim or I will
excite both of them can be used as well
what we have to have when you drop I use
it or any you are going talk about it at
least but why we have and add any reason
to create a new draft on that and
because what extensibility we are using
iron on table both of the inner and also
either they're both of them are using
that I am table for the extension and
this is a chance for us to the
extensions are so I don't appoint to use
to have a new draft on that if you have
a reason for that I want to hear that so
the way I would answer that is that I
guess I think it goes back to the
conversation of do we need a new I enter
cable or not because right now in IDF
SEI and Edom each one of the different
classes that are defined the class of
themselves aren't the problem it's what
I in a registry they're bound to so if
it turns out that we can reuse one of
the ini registries that gab who'd
actually make sense to reference one of
those are the ones I think if it turns
out that that's not the case then you
know we should kind of may need to get
of a new draft I think then the question
is assuming we do all that are then we
comfortable with whatever is the name
that's assigned to kind of all of those
whether it's in the SE iron table
tomorrow from my understanding the
regardless of whether we decide to
create a new eye on a table or use the
existing ones we're going to have to
write a draft to instruct Diana to do
some work so a new draft will be
required no matter what these are true
that because we have a specific into
recoil and also expert review so you can
have experts with you we can just change
the end table i guess that my understand
each other or not is it expert review
for SEL don't turn a little over one in
a month where I guess is it yes okay I
think we should take a look at the
options and why don't we kind of stereo
stare at it again
and you can make sure that that's part
of the conversation so that will be the
purpose of paper going in the transit so
yeah I mean there is no reason to create
in your draft and there is nothing
absolute read basically but I'll image
package so um looks like we're going
with option for and then we need a
little bit of discussion or some you
know if you want to discuss privately
and then circulate in the mailing list
your ideas that would be good make sense
ok moving on to the next issue so this
is about specifying related dns and we
have these options on the mailing list
as well and so the thinking here is that
we want right now we have a series of
classes for lack of a better term that
we describe a records so we can describe
domain names and kind of IP addresses
but all the other things that we can do
can with dns are not described all the
different kind of record types and so
there is this desire to represent some
of that information and so there is a
stub in the data model for related dns
we have all the xml isms of how you
represent those things the problem that
what we don't have is what is the actual
representation of the difference of the
other the different dns fields and we
kind of talked about it i think we
initially started it's actually not
listed here is that just use dig output
as a blob and kind of put it in there
that honestly was a good answer and so
we need to think about a little bit more
also not in this was sorry it actually
is option two it was include comma
separated values and in Honolulu we
talked a little bit more where Paul said
I have a JSON draft why don't we use the
JSON draft then with them there was
further discussion on the list about hey
why don't we just punt on this the same
way we would have punted on the last and
say it's additional data it's someone
else's problem and then there's the
possibility that no one has taken up
work on is someone could actually XML
eyes the JSON draft were kind of come up
with a representation for all the
different dns types so either way I
think we need to decide I think two
things we need to decide whether we
still want to do this or we're going to
get a pun on this outright or can we
want to adopt one of these I guess that
punch on on it is honestly option three
do we want to implement one one two or
four
where does anyone else have anything to
add to the discussion on the mailing
list the feedback to date what kind of
was there was not consensus the one
thing that folks said about the juice on
drafted which is actually complete as
its JSON and so that's a little kludgy
to bring you to an XML with some of the
some of the feedback feelings are strong
feelings sorry about that folks Uzi be
strong feeling so um Shawn Turner no
strong feelings here the only thing
about referring to the other draft is
trying to figure out what the status is
so is it anyway it's experimental right
now that is one of the one of the
concert yeah that yeah I'm not loving
that well Jason looking group just
closed and all off on my got some cycles
I don't know whether you want to take
take this option I mean the other thing
with the JSON is we could I mean there's
blob and where we could define this
transformation because again it's not
that complicated so we're standards
track and that's experimental that's
exactly that's exactly right yeah so
okay and then the second thing is does
anybody actually think that number for
one defining related does anybody not
think that creating the XML for DNS is
not the correct way we just don't want
to do the work I sense that it is a
little bit of that I mean if there's a
lot of head nodding I just is there
anybody who thinks that's not the case
Kathleen Moriarty I'm an agreement and
I've been you know inserts where you
know they show me what they're doing I
used to do this stuff I don't anymore
and DNS is huge for them right they rely
on lookups and sharing pics you know
data that you can't find anymore because
the who is information is gone and dns
lookups are gone but they still need to
show the history of attack profile so
you know you can't just leave in the dns
and or an entry and then expect that the
data is going to be transitioned around
because it could be gone right so you
need it in the incident data that goes
with the exchange yes Kristen so
christmassy oh so let's just to find
that yes okay I'll work on the defining
dns records in in XML and I'll foisted
on you fair enough we have a volunteer
you'll preempted my question you know
thank you perfect okay any other
comments unrelated do this I think we
have this one resolved okay next slide
please oh yeah so this is another one
that's in the tracker and the origin of
this is cross walking I think actually
in this case it was standard on the
incident reporting one of the things
that one of the things that that's cut
we wanted to capture is what is the
cause of the incident and so I think the
question of put on the table is 50 70
bits doesn't do it sei does it through I
owed f dash SEI can the weakness class
if the need is specifying the cause of
an incident is that weakness class from
the SEI drafts efficient does anyone
want to see something different and so
again the weakness class I mean talk is
going to correct me here I mean that
again is a pointer would be a pointer to
an external registry that would be a
dictionary of kind of weaknesses I think
other options would include trying to
define our own dictionary it's why i
framed it that way yeah I think you
might divide a compelling argument for
reusing other dictionaries is a good
idea if you can do that by the way for
this kind of pointer I guess not only a
CA but also animal draft would be useful
maybe that could be more useful for the
enemy to attack same projects I never
drafted for the pointer to that
identifier
GW has identify years so maybe CW could
be used to be there by annum draft
rather than AC I guess okay well cwe
through email yeah other thoughts so
that's that's an
option why don't we put it on the list
and see whether there's any kind of
feelings one way our kind of the other
but I what I hear is no excitement you
define your own dictionary which i think
is a very good idea it's a question of
what's the right way to point2 points to
someone else's dictionary okay do you
have a sort of proposal in your mind how
this might look like or is it still need
a bit of thought I think it requires a
little thought I mean I think our talk
is right i mean we should in part of
this kind of comes down to what do we
want to say in 50 70 yes I think it's
difficult what we want to say point back
to i def SEI that creates its own set of
kind of that's that's one kind of path
the other way to say it is not
references at all and someone just drops
the the sei reference through additional
data and then I think the third option
is to potentially drop the you know
something through the e nom draft as a
way I mean I think part of it comes it
comes down to if we acknowledge its that
talking about weaknesses is the thing
that's of concern do we want to just say
yes SE I can handle it if you want it
pulled in or to be one is explicitly
with if you 70 this reference we know
that this is important go to this place
to read about I mean it's a little bit
of a kind of a design approach about how
we fold in honestly the all the great
thinking that the sei ask that was
missed in the draft okay a suggestion
can you create three examples of the
three things you yeah and post it to the
mailing list and just let people before
you do more work than that yeah good
that was not as much as I was going to
do yeah Sam make sense tascam Christian
I think you have a lot of insight but on
the other hand other end of the
discussion that draft and I only speak
trust would be ready a large document so
that's not so easy to read it is
possible to split some content so that
guidance raft we could cater to that
would be able to write some content of
this I guess so you think we have to
write more texture on us understand
sorry I mean some contents this kind
consideration could go to the guidance
draft as well because guy that could be
a existing for that reason I guess right
maybe a fourth option right up
okay I can do that further thoughts on
that okay so i just wanted to point out
something didn't make this Lodge and
this is this is my fault i got in
various feedback from folks that have
looked at the looked at the text and
they gave different feedback i put it on
the mailing list and so this morning so
i can make it to the slide so i just
wanted to kind of point it out but you
can read the details on the mailing list
first one of its a feedback was i have
to share tens or hundreds of thousands
of a particular indicator think big long
text file of IP addresses I'm not all
that excited the feedback was you know
they weren't all that excited to wrap
each individual IP address with all the
XML and they said wouldn't it be really
great if we had one big tag that I could
drop my big long list of IP address in
IP addresses in and so the thing I was
sharing just was just honestly a lot lot
more kind of simple and so I think what
I was saying something on the order of
bulk observables so bulk observables
going to say what's what what is there
one per row of on the list and we would
support get some subset of the
observables we currently have was one
bit of feedback the other bit of
feedback was the counter right now only
counts particular rates actual measured
rates it would be really nice to also
convey things like peak rates or average
rates and actually might be kind of
others that can of worms so that was one
bit of feedback and then there is this
notion of right now we can describe the
observed protocol but the observed
protocol number like the tcp port may
not actually be associated with what's
actually using that port so if Iran HTTP
on you know 830 71 I might there's a way
to say i ran a 371 tcp but there's no
way to say that that was HTTP so is
there some way to represent that where
the three bits of feedback I got
privately sounds that maybe you should
create a trick items for them and I I
will I will do exactly that good ok so
there's those things that's all I have
in terms of the formalism I will say you
know the text needs work more help on
the text please editorial things please
well the list of outstanding issues is
much shorter this time then it wasn't
whole which is a good sign retrying so I
think we we should strive to do a
working group last call for Prague
Graham we can talk offline about you
know maybe we'll pick a date in early
April to start the process and um do you
have any changes outstanding I'm and
turn to remember do you have an
unpublished version of the draft that
you would like to I do there's a few
editorial things I've already caught all
right okay well wish that Alan okay
we'll talk after the meeting okay ah
yeah earlier about twenty cents in this
case yeah I guess let's do
implementation report on when somebody
came up to me and asked you know where
the new presentation is going to be I
said up to this one anyway let's switch
the loss topic good morning busy the
skinny on odo so on our way will present
an hour my link division reports so next
are pleased so today's agenda is an
Aurora to an updatable information guide
wine in section 7 an update on some
implementations such as changes of the
stators of an hour subscribe and
implementations so next I'll freeze
okay this is a red wines that now the
one three four five weeks down the
roster etfs and hours so now I rabies
anomalous dot p.m. is in today's topics
and then our 80s and that are updated
status so next I'll freeze okay this
rested on our update we're doing an hour
three masses so I'll degree with an open
source of module between PI sins and I
did the Parsis and I detective documents
and the developer but the design of the
rabies normal shape and is designed for
word as simple as possible so na sono
are three I know maybe I know this M is
misspelled pi b ib is a generator when a
Python code is an and it can be also
generated in such modules formality of x
SD button are generated module tend to
be inherited now complexity of excess
see so little bit the complex and a
little bit they are easy to use so they
oppose a create a scratch and during a
person edge it's an idea and I XML
covers so an i describe that I
dysfunction and in section 7.2 so next
I'll place it is also a famous module
who are taking an IO day when I xml file
and I I would appear missing is also spa
jewelry to empower and the developer is
no se young from Ray Isaac baby and
personalize it and I with the document
as before so now I wouldn't rape and it
also pop icon's employed in preferences
and I described see section 7.3 ok next
please so this is today's again the key
topics and update or implementations or
example so on and six SDK I explained
any Ross IIT as an equal role and that
this was an hour other implementations
and according to venice art postcards at
develop now and six sdk today and a
popular tickets open source so we are
not change the portion from another
implementation to open source
implementations and of course on
we also envision the opportunities that
is enough community support software for
example in vwz at this moment when our
maybe another section with draft it was
rough getting a degree the plan to
support currently is a support these
tools on are repeating on our equine so
Isaiah a crime reporting tool name is an
e crisp maybe he's an available as a
anomaly study to wanna use an idea on
maybe Annie may be due to nature way p
GG this is our precinct so they are
certain are reporting combating I ODF
second Thank You Now Jessie marathi and
I introduce a saint Otis me to Anna dak
me cigarette ash navigate thank you very
much and maybe I know it I know Ariana
Guetta informations from an IP GG and of
course we will share this kind of
information to another steak with such
as the panels is an odd one draft this
section is also known and necessary
wanna and also an array Isaac is an hour
research and education network and Isaac
means that maybe an hour yo showing I
know she sent our conceptions and they
also supported on our we know I odf
tools this is also another werster on
our research after the community
software so in such case of a community
service software maybe we I need help to
an i gather information and it is very
helpful to you home at Marion Greece
thank you very much it's just one or my
today topics oh yeah this is a summer
easily and uh what I did again on the
base of these and other varieties and
updating I'd 1990 months and I
envisioned ability signal equities not
so calm I suppose
hi Shawn Turner um great this is awesome
i love having this Kosta as people can
know where to go and go get stuff the
only the only thing I would caution you
about is fine never close the document
waiting for everyone to give you input
at some point you have to say about 12
of these or six let's move on and
publisher we have they went out again
into shock for me probably it doesn't
know that this guy get you a ready
furthermore presentation and I think we
can hear you either this is somebody's
robbing you know so i see so amazing she
will be distributed in prison so you
want this
but if you got Eric i just described a
downslide
don't annoy me you can unmute yourself
now hi hi guys
can you guys hear me yes we can okay
great thank you so I've not done this
particular remote meeting tool before so
I'm not 100-percent sharable you guys
control the slides or do I do that Oh
will will control the slides yes okay so
I'll just I'll just ask for next slide
at the at the appropriate time okay so i
guess i'm not should we get started
right now yes good good okay all right
thank you guys so here today to talk
about the Rollie draft resource oriented
light weight indicator exchange i have
approximately 10 slides and
approximately 10 minutes so we'll go
through pretty quickly on i think
probably the best approach is to kind of
run through the content it's simply a
quick overview and introduction for
members of the team is the group who
perhaps have not looked at the draft
it's been out there for a while and
really this is just kind of to to bring
it to the fore so next slide please okay
well yeah yeah you guys can can click
forward we're going to talk about what
is the rolly draft and at a very high
level what motivated it so the idea here
is that a while back I had the
opportunity to work on a POC
implementation we're essentially setting
up a proof-of-concept consortium to
exchange information using i/o death and
rid the learnings that came out of that
experience kind of lead to the rolly
draft it was really an opportunity to
have another way to do things intended
to supplement or to complement what we
already have and I think fills a need
that we may not currently be addressing
next slide please okay so in short
rowley is a restful approach to sharing
cybersecurity information and the idea
is in a nutshell very simple way to
interpret this is that I created what is
essentially an atom feed binding for i/o
def and rid and the concept was to
enable people to do a loser coupling so
that information could be exchanged more
dynamically and to do that in a way that
was a symmetric in the adoption we'll
talk a little bit about that as I go
forward but I think one of the concepts
and the current interchange capabilities
is that it is a peer-to-peer message
based approach rather than something
that is more asymmetric and perhaps more
restful in that we can do things more
dynamically without as much
infrastructure as a precondition next
slide a little bit
delay on the slides that's why it was
your pause here ok so the high-level
goals high level goals of the draft were
to make it easier to do simple sharing
the notion that anyone with a feed
reader can participate anyone with an
HTTP client can publish the idea was
that it would reduce the need for
operational coordination between the
parties that are doing the sharing on
the notion also was to leverage existing
identity management investments so
obviously a lot of investment is gone in
over the last number of years and
building out identity management
infrastructure everything from sam'l 20
off to and everything in between um I
think we have something of a disconnect
in that the authentication and
authorization of existing message based
interactions has the notion of identity
of the parties rather than identity of
the individuals that are representing
those parties I think I think that's
something that perhaps is a gap that we
could close another idea here is that we
can avoid a heavier requirements for
distributed policy enforcement the
notion that once a message is exchanged
that we're relying on distributed policy
enforcement I've imagined an iodophor
rid message that has been a sent in
response to a query enforcement
mechanisms have to occur and will occur
at the destination the approach enrollee
was to emphasize enforcement that the
source essentially resulting in an
elusive coupling between the parties
also a lack of a requirements avoid a
requirement for a lot of state
management on the side of the provider
improving the scalability of the
provider really nothing that's Noom here
this is really a an attempt to adopt the
approach taken by essentially the rest
of the web which is that you want to be
as stateless as possible I in your
interactions and again we're talking
about
transport related state maintaining
session state information at the
transport layer for interactions between
the peers we want to minimize that
overhead state management next slide
please okay so i probably spoken ahead
of my slides i do that a lot that's okay
saves us time on the slides basically on
when i did this in the POC
implementation that i had the chance to
work on i realized that there was a
non-privileged trivial investment needed
to participate regardless of the
specific role that the party was going
to be fulfilling if you're playing the
role of purely a consumer and not a
publisher you needed to build much of
the same infrastructure that a publisher
would build using an approach as
described enrolling would allow for a
more asymmetric deployment there's
nothing wrong with having symmetry
except that it makes it a little bit
harder to get on board from the point of
view of the the larger community when we
think about sharing at very large scale
the goal was that for many use cases for
many participant roles being able to do
an identity-based authorization and
participating via a restful feed would
be sufficient and appropriate for those
use cases it doesn't exclude other uses
it's more supplementing and enabling
participation for those that don't have
all of the infrastructure necessary for
the distributed state management next
slide please
okay so some use case examples that God
just go through this is real quick this
is kind of the the nuts and bolts try to
ground some of what i've said in
realistic tangible use cases imagine a
case where there's a red query the the
burden to actually do the compute task
in really responding to the query falls
on the provider it falls on the server
who's serving that response whereas what
I think we see in other examples of a
big data data crunching problem is that
we put the burden of consuming the feed
on the client so it kind of reverses
things in a sense that if I want a
specific let's say complicated query
could be any number of elements in the
predicate that the task of actually
sorting through that could fall to the
client rather than to the server it's
simply another option to have in the
case of a red report on the use case
that we stumbled into when we were doing
the POC work was that doing the
distributed transactional integrity made
things a little bit challenging in terms
of maintaining State on the server um
with a more restful style the server
typically does not maintain application
state and as a result did improve
scalability next slide please yeah and
in many cases here by the way that we
talked about in the rolly draft that the
payload can be either rid containing I o
def or I o def alone either one of those
would be supportable on some business
use cases the idea here is to support
broad sharing so imagine a government
agency sharing indicator repository
broadly with citizens in the private
sector the notion of a internet
accessible repository that followed
something like the Rollie draft would
enable people to to explore and discover
in that repository and effectively
obtain what was needed with less
investment on the client side a second
use case the private sector organization
publishing intelligence feed to a
subscribing
I think that's a use case that's well
handled today but would not be excluded
by Rowley it would simply be also
supported on private sector organization
accepting incident reports from partners
and customers again I like this one
because it enables broad participation
the ability to be able to do an HTTP
POST is all that's required you don't
need to have a full infrastructure of
state management on the client side next
slide please so a little bit on the
relationship to existing RFC's as I said
this is complementary to the existing
RFC's the idea is to leverage immediate
which is commonly done in restful
implementations we make use of that HTTP
media type header on any other
representations besides Adam and XML are
possible but that's what I chose to do
in that first double zero draft the use
of existing HTTP return codes would I
think be sufficient to enable clients to
interoperate between the existing
endpoint and any new endpoints that were
introduced next like this
so a summary wrapping up basically the
notion is that I personally kind of view
the cyber security challenge as an
asymmetric conflict attributes that I
attribute to a an attacker generally
loosely coupled collaboration patterns
with a high degree of technical agility
really looking at an environment with
continuous evolution and adaptability of
the tactics and methods um my approach
to this I concluded that the message
based architectures function optimally
when deployed and operated in a
symmetric fashion and i was looking to
complement that with an asymmetric
approach that would hopefully enable the
economics and the scalability that are
needed in order to enable sharing
between people who couldn't participate
today loose coupling and a uniform
interface of use of content type
negotiation is a is a well-proven
pattern when we look at other systems
that have adopted a restful style I
think that's it I think our next slide
is just for discussion so I'm happy to
take any questions that anyone can have
my school's um got this guy know the
name of mal and he'd be sitting out
there and he'd be interested in seeing
how many things he can host you to fill
up your database or maybe he would say
well can I do this query to Tommy's
Nadia for server for generating the
response to me um so that nobody else
can find out what's happening on the
asymmetric as you say thats attack
vector can be using attacked me against
what you propose here how would you
address that and mitigate those
operations okay a good question i assume
i don't have to repeat the question i
think the the short answers one thing I
kind of skipped over in the in the
presentation was the assumption that we
would leverage existing identity
management infrastructures existing
situations today as I said using things
like a sam'l assertion to
authenticate yourself or in the case of
an interactive end user something like
OS to authentication token the idea is
that the endpoint is still protected
right unless you can have multiple
levels of access and of course some
information might be completely public
other information is not public and
requires privileged access I would
assume that the the end user the client
who is going to make that access whether
it's supposed to get is still going to
be subjected to standard authentication
and authorization techniques okay thank
you okay other questions Kathleen
Moriarty so this is I guess with no hat
on for this just an observation when I
walked around a floor last year with
products rest was the most commonly used
interface people weren't using rowley
may not be aware of it but this
interface is used very commonly on
internal networks to do these exchanges
and it seems to be the one that's taking
off the most that I can observe so Thank
You Kathleen that that's good to know i
enjoy the the data point from the real
world i think the issue is that this is
a real opportunity that basically people
are generally using lightweight HTTP
restful approach and of course i think
that immediately implies they need to
standardize it in order to achieve
interoperability and i'll just clarify
to i didn't do a study i just walked
around a particular conference or
whatever vendors showed up there that
was the majority mm-hmm sometimes the
best kind of study is walking around how
does Shawn Turner it's just kind of a
general comment um I went to nanog in
February and like six of the 24
presentations were about d das and some
of the complaints where the stuff is too
hard to use the existing things are
really too hard to use so anything that
makes it easier for the operators to
actually be able to report this thing up
is really good and I think that they
kind of get how to do restful things and
people kind of understand how to do that
so this I think
a really great idea mmm Thank You Sean
yeah I mean to add to that comment the
idea that the the restful approach can
get you started perhaps think of it like
the you know the the big toe in the
water or you know whatever analogy you
want to use whatever metaphor it enables
you to begin participating in the
sharing and build up over time on it's
very likely at least i thought you know
in my experience in the PSC it was very
likely that some people some
organizations participating in a sharing
network in a consortium start out by
being read only and then eventually kind
of move up the food chain and become
full-fledged members on so again another
opportunity to leverage the investment
we've already got in the existing
representation formats and be able to
use those in a wide variety of use cases
that we perhaps wouldn't address
otherwise okay so i don't know if you
guys have seen this but my screen just
went on standby hopefully that hasn't
caused the problem we can still see okay
very good okay any
the comments questions often thank you
for your presentation will try to push
on your dog you know to progress your
document after we've done the 50 70 base
but in the meantime if you have any
updates make them and also try to get
application area review of you know the
way you use rest okay thank you very
much I'm until I can find people but
I'll try okay one last comment is that
this is obviously a ten-minute segment
so it's hard to cover all of these cases
I'd encourage people to take a look at
the first couple of sections of the
draft I do in the draft try to lay out
some of the rationale um I tend to do
that you know many years doing
architecture work I I feel compelled to
lay out the rationale as to how we got
to this point so I'd appreciate feedback
on on those sections in particular the
obviously the technical nitty-gritty of
the details of the binding is open for
discussion and we'd probably have many
more discussions over that I think
really the motivation and the rationale
is is probably the appropriate focus for
now okay so this is the end of our
agenda any other business any other
questions announcements related to mile
yeah okay ah well thank you for coming
and you have present I'm not sure how
much time yes you have an hour and eight
minute before your lunch Joey okay thank
you yes so there are two questions when
it will be deposited
drop this off