all right we're going to
started welcome to NV 03 the second
session today we have a shorter agenda
we've got one hour we have two
presentations they are on a similar
topic which is Oh am in overlays so
hopefully the two together can encourage
a good discussion afterward if we have
extra time which our agenda has I think
20 minutes for we'll have some open
discussion that we would like to focus
on any questions around the data plane
adoptions so we'll have time for that if
no one has anything to say on it we can
talk about other things or break up a
few minutes early so jumping through
real fast the intro slides first of all
as always this is an ietf meeting so
anything you say here is a contribution
to the ITF the note well describes what
that means in more detail so please be
sure to be familiar with it we have blue
sheets which have been started to be
passed around it's going to be obviously
in a room this size it's going to be
tricky to get it everywhere so I
appreciate it people can help each other
out passing it around without too much
distraction we do want to get everyone's
name on it if possible we have John and
ignis just as on Monday are taking notes
here today so thank you both and we are
presenting these through WebEx so if you
want to watch them on your screen or
you're listening remotely you can see
them there today like I said shorter
agenda one hour long we're going to hear
first from Eric nordmark and then from
Diego Garcia about some oam options and
so i'll take one moment to see if anyone
here wants to bash the agenda and
nobody's complaining so I think Eric we
can get started
well you can stand there I'm supposed to
stand here how it is one that we're
going to be on video right Fiona Mike
there is a second camera out of that
particularly when you don't remember
what you wrote on the slide because you
did the slides like a week ago and like
I don't know what's back there but so um
trace rod for overlays go to the next
slide so there's three pieces here and
this is not an exclusion of anything
else we might be doing whether I am
right but this might actually be a
useful tool in the OEM toolbox so keep
that in mind as we think about you know
different different forms of OM one of
my observations has been the traceroute
on the internet today tells me a bunch
of stuff that maybe I shouldn't be
allowed to see but actually do you see
them maybe for historical reasons or
maybe because it's actually useful right
and what s with you as we do you overlay
networks we might actually lose some of
this visibility by design as opposed to
buy policy and this is actually not that
that hard to change right we have
actually prototype stuff for vehicle on
a dusty stuff so so this is sort of the
typical path that you could see this was
sitting at work it looks similar from
home I have no idea what these routers
are so why is this useful one might ask
well because I can take this stuff and
put it in a trouble ticket all right and
I can send it off to our IT department
and they can go figure it's the problem
on our end or is it as they go out to
the ISP or is it somewhere else making
forward the stuff along and if I have a
temporary outage you know this is sort
of the only way you can feed some useful
information in other than saying I can't
get there from here right so I think
that being able to take this stuff and
say I can send this off this is what I
saw at 9am this morning and someone can
figure out well was there something
wrong on this particular router at that
point in time as opposed to having to
look
we're right so that's the the the
high-level thing so today there isn't
much policy to enable people to block
here in fin isp wants to hide ur
topology from this from IP trace route
they sort of have to either tunnel
things which they do with mpls and
whatever I clearly can't see everything
I can't see the whatever optical trunks
that are used underneath and whatever
right mpls there's a bunch of things I
can't see but I can see if they're a bit
I could see more than a binary didn't
get there and they could filter things
out if they weren't as well not send any
ice in peace next oh I have the clicker
so when we come to tunnels the IETF if
you go look at it we have actually
developed two different tunnel models
one is called the pipe model and the
other one is called a uniform model this
has been done both for diffserv as well
as for TTL and the pipe model is the one
that's commonly destroyed or most
commonly used for for env3 that means
that the env II actually puts on a fixed
TTL that's configured in the outer
header and then on eager so you just
throw that away oh that's all right oh
yeah it doesn't really matter we can do
them in this order to burn ok and and
with a uniform model and you basically
are counting the TTL across the whole
path under layin and overlaid together
and the behavior there is that the the
ingress nve will set the outer TTL to be
the inner or the original TTL minus one
and likewise sort of copying in the
other direction and decrementing on the
egress so these two behaviors are
described but people might mostly think
about the the pipe model so so some of
the issues that I could show up that are
particular to to overlay networks and in
particular also to overlay networks
carrying l2 your Ethernet frames is that
when you when you have a
a a DX land type network well if I'm
going from one host to another they're
on the same subnet or the simple case of
them being on the same subnet one idea
ping and traceroute I see nothing
because the packets don't go anywhere
there are no IP hops involved at all
right and yeah the ARP request may or
may not timeout depends whether you are
propagating ARP information in the
control plane or sort of doing flooding
and whatever but in order to see
something you actually need some access
to the ingress and the e so if I can you
know get access to that thing whether
it's a virtual switch or whether it's a
physical switch I would actually need to
do several things one is check whether
the underlay has an issue by doing a
ping or trace route but I also have to
go check some set of tables that map my
overlay traffic to the underlay and
describe how their scent right whether
it's mappings from from vlans to the NI
IDs whether it's some sort of flooding
tables or whatever MAC address to remote
IP address of the nve right I need to go
inspect all of those things and then I
can tell it's this thing actually well
that might not be sufficient because I'm
not likely certain that the packet even
reaches that nve and that's very hard to
tell because it's effectively in l2
service and you know you can't really
there's no widely available tools to
tell that from a host so if I don't have
that that access to their me the only
trouble ticket I can generate you saying
it didn't work right and here's the IP
address i tried to get there so we have
those two models so so i guess it
doesn't say that so basically this means
that i can actually get disability
underlay if i actually use the uniform
tunnel model because now i seen p errors
TTL exceeded that treasure our users
will be sent from everyone along the
path everybody will uniform the
decrement ppl the ingress and egress and
me included but
not sufficient there's one more piece we
need it's about how we handle i simpiy
errors and this is an area we played in
before not for the TTL exceeded but for
other things so the idea is that so
these desizing p errors sent by the
underlay routers will be sent back to
the source of that IP packet all right
standard ICMP or IP forwarding behavior
and that's the ingress mV so the ingress
mb gets these IP packets are sorry gets
these i simpiy errors and it can go look
inside and say oh this is a DX lon
whatever envio 3m cap packet that was in
error I can go extract where needed
actually come from and send it back
basically deliver an ICP error that
makes sense for the original host so if
you have to look at an example of how
this would behave is and it's there's
one special piece here which we haven't
done before which has to do with mac
addresses and mike headers but first one
the host censored and packed with the
TTL of two it gets encapsulated and as
part of that the TTL gets decremented to
one and then it comes to the first
underlay router the decrement and checks
TTL and says this expired right and it
sends back the the number three here is
the shape of that I see the error it has
the envio three whatever VX town header
in there and whatever it had inside
which is a mac and IP header and then
when that packet comes back to the
ingress MBE it can form the icing Pierre
at the bottom that makes sense for the
original host and i don't know if i put
examples of what this stuff looks i have
some example so that's that's all there
is to it right well there is another one
which is you probably don't want this
uniform TTL for all packets so the host
here says I'm on the same subnet as this
destination host there could be some
protocols that assume something about
TTL like TTL doesn't occur man if I send
it with TTL one and gets there because
we're on the same
map that would break if you applied this
uniform model all the time there could
be other ones that use TTL 255 and check
out the receiver same thing right so you
have to do some ingress selection or you
have to do some selection at ingress to
figure out am I going to use the pipe
model or the uniform model for this and
you could do that in any way you please
write it could be based on and here's
where it sort of you the policy norm
comes in saying should I do this for
this customer is it for this port this
particular originating IP mac address
maybe i have some dedicated trace
infrastructure that i run in the overlay
for this right you can do anything you
want something if you want to do it at a
granularity where a host can do it that
is also running running other traffic
you want something in the packet to
select this and there's two things that
you can easily tweak in the packet and
that you can set in the linux trace
route one of them is the dscp or toss
white and the other one is the UDP
source port that you use so you can
actually set up some things on the
ingress and be saying okay this customer
is authorized to do this right I will
going to say that this customer can if
it uses this DCP value or whatever or
the CDP source port I'm going to give
those packets the uniform TTL processing
model and there's some difference is
that some trade-offs in graph between
that in terms of entropy and whatever I
think I have just one slight love so I
think I'll go through that one before
questions but and the the second piece
is if I want the behavior on the on the
egress I have to have some way I'm
instructing the egress on a per packet
basis what TTL behavior do you want and
the easiest way of doing this stuff we
played around with different ones but
this is one is actually getting one bit
in the in the B header that says please
apply uniform TTL behavior at the
and note that there's been discussions
about sort of OEM bits with slightly
different semantics just a fly that it's
not the same right the OEM bit that's
been discussed is this is an oem frame
that should not be delivered to the
unhold that's not the behavior we want
here we just want the this TTL behavior
oh yeah there was one you can do this
whether i simpiy errors you can do it
with our agenda packet too big for
instance you can actually use it as a
way of detecting that I think my
underlay should be configured to be able
to carry the encapsulated packets but
maybe it's misconfigured we've seen
customers actually do this right and and
it's hard to find out well if not that
hard you send a small ping packet things
work they run TCP and it doesn't tcp
times up because TCP sounds full-size
back at well now you have to figure out
okay what should i look for right and
you know other sort of unreachable
whatever so in via con me prototype the
stuff we found a bit at least at the
time wasn't being used for something
else then of its that's still the case
with all the VX lon proposals but and
and it basically says here's the D
capsule aiding behavior that's all that
bit the semantics of that bit and there
are some things that might surprise
people when you do this so the first one
is your underlay and overlay are
actually diff different addressing
realms right and you could think of this
as separate verbs or whatever but like
you know your customer has net 10 right
well you can actually run n bo3 or VX
down whatever where the underlay use is
not 10 as well it's perfectly valid
because it's l2 or l3 they don't meet
anywhere well when you do this and
that's not the example but when you do
this the trace our output is going to
show the underlay and overlay IP
addresses so you better know that when
you enable this thing don't think that
you can ping those those underlay
addresses is any useful way right but
there might even be the same addresses
that you're using your overlay inverse K
right so as long as you know that okay I
can do it over later a drop which sees
whatever overlay part of my path I can
do this combined trade route that sees
both and if I take both of them and put
them in the trouble ticket someone can
actually figure out what's going on the
other surprises what you see as you have
different IP versions this notion I'm
getting and underlay ICMP error and
generating an overlay I CPR means taking
IP addresses that are in the underlay
and showing them overlay well that works
well if it's v4 486 / before because I
can fit 32 bits in 128 which is what
this example shows that basically these
six ICMP errors that have 96 bits of
leading zeros or whatever it's something
doesn't really matter what it is it's
just something that provides useful
information for the guy who's gonna look
at the trouble ticket and I think that's
it hey well I guess the other thing is I
think that this is a useful tool right
and and it might be something that
people should consider but as they look
at different encapsulations so questions
or comments David black um I mean we lay
something that I think was said uh
rather strongly at the sputters food
bought this morning dscp is not a
sitting in mechanism please don't use of
this actually I actually think that your
most common case you actually don't need
anything in the protocol which is that
if you're using a virtual switch that's
co-located on the same box with your
traffic source that can be set up by
that can be set up but set up via via
other means there there there some
interesting possibilities on
thinking I had figure out how to make
that one work yeah that's only one of
the cases right but also you do need if
you want to do this at the granularity
of a mac address or an IP address right
basically dedicate one of those in the
overlay for doing the trays it means
that you sort of have to request people
to allocate one of those for you right
the whoever controls the address space
for the overlay has to do that and by
putting something in market in the
packet of some form you are avoiding
requesting that your complexity I think
I think keep looking because said this
this is not a good use dscp your
discussion of how UDP effects ecmp I
think is I think it's fatal to use of
the two usually use the UDP source port
because all you need is one is is one
one arm of a four-way ecmp to be out end
and the OEM will never see it and the
the trace my goal is to find the traffic
doesn't yeah butBut tracer actually
varies destination ports as well so if
you can't necessarily pick a particular
on if you do that right but but because
of the varying destination ports if as
long as that's included in me if you can
gosh if you can get a trace for our tool
that's prepared to keep retrying with a
whole bunch of different ports and tell
you which ones working which one which
ones didn't you might have occluded
something's wrong with libby with with
each with ECT cmp down there on the
other thing is just a warning which
we've had in the context of the endcap
discussion for routing which is watch
out for nested in cap sooner or later
you're going to run out of payload size
and ICMP and not be able to rebuild what
you want to rebuild without state in the
end ve on the way back yes we have 512
or five 776 bytes to play with but this
yes sorry share on the line
I think what you're doing is a nice hack
was really architecture it wrong because
you're you're violating all the layers
you just be thought a minute later to
you're just going to uniform on my model
this is absolutely wrong well there's a
rag no but there is a question about
what is the purpose of layers right and
one of them is providing some superb
structure that underneath that doesn't
mean that the abstraction should get in
the way of the ability this is a one hop
and early whatever you wanted to you
sorry overlay it's a one hop over late
whatever you want to do is one hung over
but this applies even when I have a
combination of overlay and underlay hot
saree the same thing I'm being able to
say these packets are marked with arcing
a disability to the underlay if you had
terminated the little match the layer 2
and I've done an IT inside the excellent
of that I agree but this is wrong okay
Sean opinion really yeah i was going to
actually say something similar to him
like if you go to slide 7 right do I
have slide number Pedro this is an old
gun one from them so you talk about the
nbe encapsulating the packet of the TTL
decrement so that's really not true
right because the enemy if it's a layer
2 and EE it doesn't decrement the TTL at
all correct that's one of the behaviors
in terms of providing this despite this
this uniform ppl model write that as n
cap and decap countless hops there as
well in addition to the underlay all
right be good and the reason I picked
that one is that it seems useful to
showing all parts of the path so if it
won't work if it's a non IP packet if
you're transporting well how would you
mark the non IP packets right that
clearly you can't find an IP header
there to go do anything with so you'll
just need you have to do that the pipe
model for non IP packets but last time I
checked ninety-nine point nine percent
of the packets that we carry here r.i.p
but but but it doesn't break those right
the key thing that still works still
works yeah I know that this is different
because people are used to thinking in
layers and that's useful for some things
all right but that doesn't mean if you
make it significantly harder to see
what's going on and and as a result
making it operationally difficult to
deal with these networks I think you
know we should pause write and think is
that really what we want right every
night yeah the general thinking tends to
be that you let the lower layers take
care of themselves and then you have
someone that can query each lee yes very
and I can see cases running jwhite the
comp in sa correlations assuming the but
it is somewhat hard I think because I
can see running a you know even if I
take in some of the failures I've seen
right even if I was running BFD doing
continuous monitoring of my underlie
path making sure that that one didn't
fail I still have configuration issues
when this stuff fails because the
mapping from l2 into the tunnel right is
somehow misconfigured work whether it's
you know sort of the port come of eel on
TV and I or some the flood list or
whatever I used to do right that stuff
is misconfigured and those things the
underlay OEM doesn't help I really need
to connect the button and the overlay
one by itself doesn't tell me anything
either and failed and I don't have a
good way of connecting the dots all
right so if if you had your end hosts
sending out some kind of messages that
looked like the data they would go
through the same data part and they
would discover where the problem is
right there would just be dropped on the
force on all right it'll get dropped
somewhere and because it's not received
you will know I know that they
disappeared somewhere else I could tell
that it's not working but I can't tell
where it's not working so you're
I mean what you mentioned was that
concerned about the place where the
mapping takes place from l to r us to
l-3 and that mapping takes place at the
english point and egress right but he
grace and so you would know but but as
she start complex more complex
topologies right you might end up with
multiple sort of chained and Bo three
tunnels ain't going through some routers
that route between them whatever and
then it actually gets hotter as well yes
I could I could give some idea about at
in the overlay did it get to this router
that you know you did get over the first
tunnel right I can tell that from the
overlake high throw but I then sort of
so now I know which tunnel forgot debug
any on so just a quick note we this
conversation we move on to our question
and the limit it to the people that are
currently standing just so that the next
speaker isn't as well yeah so just
follow the steam come quick yeah if so
that the only so my biggest concern with
this would be the scalability issues
because let's say you have a medium dm's
using the underlay each of those million
VMS tries to start doing things like
trace route that underly needs to
respond to and you know how do you
control something like that how do I
control the festivities today in an IP
network I don't know some you turn it
off i Baca lies in peace now bark all
treasure I
I can do it from home today I can do it
from here I can do it from work icmp I
mean Tracy artworks in IP and the
routers don't fall over in the internet
and there's plenty of people that I'm
sure I dossing it right now as well
right so i don't know if that's any
worse but that's hi Tom Herbert so on
one of your earlier slides you mentioned
these two models the pipe model versus
the uniform GTL model yep so my question
is should we actually consider the
uniform tunnel model as kind of the
operational model and the example will
give i think is david's example if i
have 2 n bees are co-located with a host
with the VMS TTL was relevant in that
case if they set a TTL of one that's one
single tunnel so therefore the packets
will go however if my bm's introduce a
routing loop in the overlay then
theoretically i can go through n squared
hops in the underlay just to just have
one packet eventually run out of TTL so
i'm wondering if this is like a problem
that you might want to address here but
i don't think we can change it because
there are protocols like ipv6 neighbor
discovery right that you know that run
between hosts that are in the same
subnet and they assume something about
tikyo and the fact that we are building
basically remote bridges using is this
overlay technology that has to for those
packets to still work it has to be
default to being apart model that's it
so for a layer to network that might be
true but for layer 3 we're referring
customer just a default route the TTL
could actually correspond to the
underlay yes if you're not if you're not
if you're not carrying l2 service over
the env3 network yes that's correct so
I'm just saying maybe this is is that
number 13 in the
hey yeah i think that that's a good
discussion to have right which is which
is separable from the how does this
behave for for l2 right sorry shower on
the value again so i want to give you
one alternative solution which is
architectural you're correct so you can
do for example a internet link trace
route or linked race and then that can
trigger a idea trace route at the NB and
then you can breathe reply the results
that's our cadet very correct e well
that's a different way of doing things
it's not a tool that people are used to
today and then again learning yes and
you want you want to twist the
architecture and destroy all
architecture soundness so that people
are not know what is the purpose of art
where we should take this to the bar but
the purpose of architecture is not
something that it's a way of organizing
our thoughts and having ways of creating
obstructions it's not a way to forbid
thing people from from solving is
architectes avail for reading people to
do things insane things it is a way of
keeping everything sound and you know
working in all different conditions and
situations so we should we should
continue this conversation but not right
now there is one more question in the
back and i think we missed you as sort
of a punishment for sitting in the back
of the room since the mic on the mics
was not on our visa in the previous
session equipment what do you so i
wanted to add a couple more surprises we
that's Darrell Italy we've had a yeah
Darrell Bluett sorry we had a lot of
experience with deployments with trace
rot in hell three overlays and a couple
of the gotchas that we found in the in
the operational internet ours are often
times we get much less than 500 bytes of
data back like so in the cross AF tray
tea time expired coming back to the end
we get not enough are you still seeing
the only eight bytes of the of the
transfer coming a lot of errors because
we fixed that was added to Rada
requirements in 1995 I understand that
this sometimes we did that because
apparently all right but I'm not
pointing fingers because it's almost
every vendor as a few you know as a as a
device out there that does that what we
found impaired interesting is that when
we do cross i have often times we don't
get the enough information back to
determine the actual you know IP address
that we need to pass back to the bus
back to the host okay so that's that's
an additional supply it's very good i
was assuming that that had gone away
yeah and then the second surprise well I
mean you know that windows and stuff
doesn't use UDP for this and it's a real
struggle when the tracer line itself
doesn't understand the cross they have
information you're passing back so a lot
of times you get stars and stars and
stars we really wish you could get
better information back to your to your
users and then I think the other thing
is that there was a lot of comments
about about performance and stuff in
here we've shown and implementations
that are doing this that do a small cash
just for trace route on the on the
encapsulator d caps later that handles
this functions and if it it's just a
small buffer and if it overflows because
too many people are doing it then the
people get more stars than they would
have gotten otherwise but it hasn't
impacted the env performance on the on
the control plane are you saying that
they remember that trace for cuts well
data you have to identify the traceroute
that's coming from the host right and
you know when you get packets back to n
ve where to send that where to send the
the traceroute back and sell three that
i'm talking about no not when you get
the whole payload right yes if you only
are getting eight eight bytes back sure
all right exactly so i got to figure out
a way to have this but what I'm assuring
you is the hacks can be done without
compromising the performance of the than
B and the final the final thing that
I'll mention is that the chip doesn't
matter okay okay that's you so thank you
make sure
diego you can use this to hi so well
what we're presenting is a bit
complementary to what derek has been
doing it's a oam from the MV e to the MV
and to do a bit of data but yeah so
basically the idea is to to have the
capability of doing traceroute and doe
am from MV 12v and some of the things
that we wanted to cover with the generic
overlay was having you know yeah the
first point what eric mentioned that in
the existing ping and traceroute does
not work very well for overlays for the
reasons explained before and but some of
the things you want to verify is yes how
do I find information from the underlay
how to find information from the path
that the packets are taking how do i
verify the behavior of the network when
there's ecmp and multiple paths of the
cmp in the way and how do I deal with
the consistency of the control and data
plan a beta plane programming especially
when we're talking about an env that
might be in a co-located with the server
in the hypervisor but the controller
might be an open flow controller or some
external controller you have to have
some way of ensuring that that data path
that you believe in BGP is one thing has
it been reflected down to two to the
forwarding plane have some way of doing
continuity checks for verification some
fault isolation as well and performance
in terms of delay and packet loss
measurements so in terms of the
requirements for the overlay framework
what we wanted to do is have the the
overlay endpoint should be able to send
them some form of frame that is follows
the same data path and reaches the
incest and reaches the end and ve but at
the same time somehow doesn't get
accidentally leaked to the vm because or
to the end device that is behind the end
II I think you know while it might be
acceptable in some production
environments where every so often euro
am packet actually reaches the the vm
that you were trying to target we're
trying to avoid that as much as possible
and then by that means it's the the end
point should be able to differentiate
what's annoying packet and what's not so
that it can parse it appropriately and
reply back to the originator so we have
some information and and the idea is
that we are able to achieve OEM for both
applications in the layer 2 and layer 3
overlays we're seeing that the MV 0 3 is
moving to supporting not just layer 2
but towards also virtual distributed
virtual routing environment so you know
trying to build a the OEM in a way that
supports both mechanisms and and again
the other part is the fact that we could
have some capability for doing trace
paths maybe not necessarily from the
client endpoint and in fact we're not
looking at it from the client endpoint
but rather from a central management
system or the env itself as a network
administrator I'm able to look at how I
am going to be able to find the path
that the packets are following find if
there's one dead link in a nice EMP
bundle or in an EMP fabric how do I find
that particularly that is being
troublesome and sometimes you could
forward packets based on purely on you
can try from an MV e to another MV using
ping or some direct under late test but
you're still not fully verifying that
your VX lat encapsulated packets are
making it through that indeed the
endpoint is properly configured and and
part of what we're doing also with this
framework is the ideas that to support
multiple overlake technology so you know
not just VX land but MV GRE mpls over
GRE mpls over UDP and some of the
upcoming and capsule ations are being
proposed as well so I mean try to be
generic so that we can I mean not not be
the universal panacea but have having
some way of having something that is
covering the different use cases that MV
0 3 is
looking at so in terms of the packet
that we were proposing is I mean having
this is very similar or similar to what
was being done and in some of the m LSP
trade routes and LSP om that was
previously specified in mpls and we we
were looking compared to what was
presented some time ago in in a previous
ITF meeting in terms of versions we
added we actually added a version a
header to the packet itself so we could
support multiple evolving formats for
the packet and you'll notice that there
are timestamps and sequence numbers very
early on in the packet and this is to as
much as possible have the capability of
doing hardware time time stamping in the
platforms that will eventually support
it we tried not to do the timestamps stl
these randomly in the packet but rather
in a fixed position so that if a
hardware implementation could
potentially timestamp it directly and
not have to look at it and punted to to
a control plane to a supervisor so and
then what we are is the sum tlv formats
for the type of encapsulation that we're
trying to 20 a.m. and optional tlv is to
identify the end system that so if we're
trying to figure out what's going on
with a destination MAC address so there
are two parts of the draft one is
verifying the tunnel from a from an env2
and vso from beat up to v tip and the
other one is ok also once i get to this
nation can i try to find certain
information about a particular endpoint
a particular host that i'm trying to
reach and i might not be having the the
visibility to get there and so in terms
of the overlay ping in terms of how do
we originate and detect this so in
packet the idea was to have use some
form of router alert bit in the VX lan
heather and i'm not particularly set on
it being one particular bit we had a
proposal and we have a draft
implementation based on that but you
know there's been on the excellent GBE
there's its own OEM bit being defined we
could
coexist with that bit and just use it
you know look at the interpretation of
how the bid would be used and mpls over
GRE or mpls of your DP we could do a
router alert label that would keep
things clean in that encapsulation and
in the inner Heather encapsulation here
is where it gets a bit trickier or a bit
different for everything that's tunneled
to tunnel verification Soviet up to
vetem verification and the idea is to
actually have a full V explain
compatible frame so it has to be at
least an ethernet header and we were
looking at doing actually an IP plus UDP
headers as well but the echo request and
should have a destination MAC address
that's like a well-known neck address
that we can trap and we can prevent in
case this OEM packet arrives to an MV
that doesn't know how to interpret the
router alert bit then we don't want that
packet to be forwarded to the end host
so we don't want to have it we don't
want to cause that packet to be flooded
or so on so we're trying to use one of
the slow protocols MAC addresses so that
we can actually trap it and the same
thing with the IP address if there's any
chance that this packet would be routed
you know we're using at 127 00 sedo or
you know a local host address so we
don't send the packet accidentally to
anyone and this would allow us to
properly identify the packet as the
destined to that to the v-dub itself so
we can get an idea of how trap it and
send packet send a response back to the
host and and in terms of a layer three
overlay the encapsulation would be
similar except we wouldn't be adding
that additional inner ethernet header
with a mac address reserved from iono
and so yeah in terms of again the the
packet information we had a couple of
cope you know call side dress is
specifying the router alert bit in NV
GRE and VX lamb and
we had the mac address as being
requested and we have the validate the
control plane and data plane the echo
reply with the return code so this is
the encapsulation for the reply the same
idea again a similar mecha dress similar
destination IP address and so on and we
would have different return codes in the
packet so that we can able to look at
what the different possibilities of
errors the different error types
different error codes were so the type
of request that we're looking at in the
moment it's basically an echo request
and an echo reply the echo request could
also be used to do to perform a trace
route as well and we'll see how that
worked and the reply mode there will be
a no reply so we can specify the type of
reply that we want and we could specify
do not reply mode so meaning we're just
sending probes that somehow the receiver
will keep statistics will measure like
they have a sequence number so you can
measure gaps in the sequence number to
determine random packet loss or estimate
packet loss and or you could do a reply
via a routed ipv4 packet or ipv6 packet
back so not encapsulated into VX lan
just routed back to original to the
originator or you could reply by the
overlay segment in the return path by
other is the return tunnel if they
return tunnel is available so sometimes
this is having the possibility of having
to reply mode gives you the chance that
maybe your outgoing tunnel is working
but they repeat the response tunnel is
failing so you can send the response to
come back through and through a routed
infrastructure and not tunneled so you
can see ok I'm seeing that my
unidirectional path is working with my
return path it's the one that's failing
so having that possibility opens up some
you know wait it slightly more
interesting troubleshooting options and
then yeah we have a couple of return
calls as well and for the path traced
procedure I mean the idea is to be able
to send the echo request with outer TTL
again this is originated from the Vita
or the VN ve so we have the rec control
over the TTL we're not doing layer
crossing there but we would be setting
the outer TTL to a particular value and
we're able to send
I get back and forth and for every
increment we could also randomly or
sequentially increment the source UDP
port so that you can exercise a certain
number of hash hash is for your ecmp
fabric I don't guarantee that we're
going to discover every possibility CMP
path but if the user could request that
for every TTL increment I send 16
different UDP values and then I
increment once i send 16 more values and
so on so you can get a good idea of
sweeping the underlay and and the
response for the TTL expires there would
be again dependent on part of the ICMP
response it's interesting to see the the
point mentioned before that yes people
are there are some implementations out
there still replying with only 8 bits so
8 bytes so we have to see you know how
much information can we confirm 8 bytes
if the 512 bytes or 500 and so bites
were available that's you know it's easy
to determine the whole thing but with
only eight bytes we'll have to see how
we can do that but there's short of also
requiring the intermediate transient
transit notes to implement a some
version of this OEM which potentially
they could do in later steps the relying
on the ICMP time exceeded message it's
whatever we can have today and and
basically in terms of a the other part
is no not just verifying the tunnels but
verifying the end systems and what we
specified there were a couple of
different TLDs where we request to ping
or to verify the forwarding tables for a
particular MAC address IP address Mac IP
combination or just a row packet that we
specify as a certain number of bytes so
in that case the idea is that we are
able to look up against the layer two
tables or the routing tables of the end
and ve and we are able to get a response
of whether that mac address exists at
all in the end ve that we send the
request to and and again we have a
couple of requests but yeah basically
the next steps are you know looking
forward to comments and feedbacks we
already got some comments on the mailing
list and in person today but we're
so we're looking at working at that they
share on the value brother this is
another architecture a wrong proposal
I'll tell you why why do you even need
that OEM power relay overlays an
adaptation layer you are not going to
forward based on overlay just put an
overlay the excellent header ten-forward
this packet you cannot it's like they
say I want an oem for eater type this is
a tap tation layer react the excellent
at encapsulates your your l2 header into
an IP packet that's it why do you need
an oem for the overlay I mean there's
some pretty much it what do you want to
detect in the overlay in the VX lab what
do what error do you want to detect in
the VX line is the tunnel working at all
or yeah what tunnel that is not VX nine
is not the tunnel the tunnel is IP I'm
not sure I follow I mean you cannot
forward the packet based on the
excellent hitter so so so when I was
standing up there and and you said that
this is wrong like I guess I didn't
quite understand what this was but as
far as I can tell what you're arguing is
that everything that has to do with the
uniform model is wrong yes because the
uniform models has something about TTL
behavior and you're arguing as far as i
can tell that that is architectural e
incorrect impure whatever and we've had
standards doing this stuff for mpls for
ipv4 or ipv6 for a number of things for
four decades put it this way why can't
what can you do hear that you cannot do
with ethernet OEM and IPO IPO am that we
have what can you do here extra that's
extra to that I mean with easily
whatever you want to do here you can do
it with ethernet oh yeah for the overlay
and for with I do em for the underlay
this this is why you 10 M because an NDE
might encapsulate to one or more two or
more nvs on the other end
and while it's encapsulating to it it
wants to test to see if this
encapsulation path is up and if it goes
down it wants to switch that's why you
need Oh am packets to be originated by
the NP and say not originated by angry
you can originate by Utley so you just
want to test it check the mapping from
the basically you want to check the
correct VX line header is added that's
what you want so yeah but you can do it
your test you're testing the path from
the encapsulating MV e to the d capsule
eating at me and the packets are being
originated there so you can have a you
can do it when you can do it the
property the IP joining I think we
should probably this is a specific
should specific discussion we should
have there's a fundamental here around
who gets to do troubleshooting if it's
the attendance system keeps fading in
and out tenant system or just the n ve
owner I think maybe we should start from
the point of view of what we want to
facilitate and then talk about the
architecture so to them to that line I
have a couple of common terrorists a
couple of comments about this um first
of all having done a lot of over the
internet overlay troubleshooting over
the last six seven years I'll tell you
that it's absolutely essential that you
use the same UDP destination port that
are using for data packets when you try
and decide if something's alive or not
and you're paying because very many
times will be a middle box is blocking
some port but not another and you know
it is a little trouble so we are we are
using exactly the same UDP port does
misread the slides no there's there's an
inner UDP port inside transported all
the way inside the overlay that could be
but the outer V X lon is definitely the
same we're not we're not touching that
second point is is that I I have to
congratulate you of using a union of
every idea when it comes to
troubleshooting but I will say this is
that one of the other problems with
operationally is that if the tool that
you're trying to troubleshoot with is
okay and somehow it so complicated that
wasn't implemented probably you're
really stuck and so I encourage you to
find a very simple small subset of this
get some operational feedback and then
add to it over over time yeah so that's
the other thing that we were looking at
after some of the conversations we have
these days was to split it into one
thing that's verifying purely the
tunnels and the other is and systems but
just less common yeah a clarifying
question Eric nordmark so you said you
have you so you have this rather alert
or OEM bit so is that does it have
exactly the same semantics is in the GP
draft how do you know and I as far as I
read from the GP draft I could
understand the ideas that is a packet I
mean it would it means it gets punted to
control plane and in particular in the
DB drive it means that it never gets
forwarded to the understand right that's
not the semantics yeah so that's that's
my ID I don't want that packet to be
forwarded the the thing is I cannot
guarantee that it will happen for non
impure VX land it will not happen for
non router alert bits aware
implementation so the Sharona myself I i
I'm actually but I'm sorry I'm actually
going to cut the conversation on this
topic it seems like there's a lot of
good conversation that's happened and a
lot more that we need so we'll we'll get
together with a few of you after this
session to chat more about what the next
step would look like but everyone should
please read these drafts and comment on
the mailing list so thank you thank you
so we have and I'm sorry I am really
sorry to cut that conversation short but
we have about 10 minutes a little less
than that left before we're supposed to
be done here and I wanted to make sure
there was a chance for some open
discussion of the data plane adoption
that is in process right now if no one
has comments on it we could break up
early if you have any comments questions
or whatever this is a chance to to speak
about it for a few minutes it just as a
reminder we are in the process of
adopting we have three calls for
adoption out right now for the VX line
GPE
for goo and for the why am I forgetting
the name of the last one genève geneve
where's Jesse he can yeah I call it
janea we need a pronounced asian guy but
I and do we pronounce it in French I
mean there's like beer the beer of
working group that's pronounced in
German right so oh yeah then this boot
as well so I guess sort of the sort of
balance between industry in there i
clarify i think it would be good if we
could the ideal thing would be if we
could come up with one encapsulation
right but I don't not sure that how that
were I can happen and even if we do we
still have things that is getting
deployed out there like the basic the
advanced off so i don't know if it's
useful to think about whether the
participants here and sort of wearing a
combination on the IDF hat and they're
sort of we're deploying there's anyhow
hat which you know happens out in the
real world sort of our amenable to
thinking about other ways that we could
we could prune things down a bit and not
end up with sort of these three
potentially being deployed plus whatever
things are out there existing and one
thing that might help with our stuff is
is sort of looking at the the
encapsulations considerations thing and
there are some thoughts about
extensibility there's many things about
how to encode extensibility in the
pocket so that we can make it make it a
bit more future proof if people want to
build hardware that can use the
extensibility mechanisms which you know
the encapsulation the design team that
was looking at this stuff actually came
up with some good things that we wrote
down would seem to sort of point out
that unconstrained kill these are
actually very hard to deal with in
hardware sure with the encapsulations
all of them
the abilities that we can skip the whole
thing right we can pass over these
extensions but if you in the future say
well there's some security extensions
that are useful I should be it would be
useful to be able to have the hardware
actually parse and insert and actually
do something is all about so and if
people I don't know if people have
already looked at that stuff and say
here's something that would make me
tweak my encapsulation and if people are
willing to do that we might be able to
get fewer of them I mean I don't have a
problem with the working of adopting
these things instead of refining them
but I'm thinking about what is the world
going to look like three years from now
right are we go or five years from now
or whatever how many of these things are
going to be deployed out there that's
that's my real concern and I want to
make sure that the IDF is part of this
conversation as opposed to being
completely sidelined because people
deploy whatever they want and we don't
get the benefit of sort of the
additional review and sort of broader
thinking in their yard yeah thank you so
I just to respond I guess I see this as
a present process if it works well we
want to adopt and document things that
are going to be deployed and or are
deployed now at some point we could do
more than that we could maybe come up
with a one of them that we think is is
going to be the you know must implement
standard or perhaps there's a way to
combine ideas or whatever i'm not going
to you know prejudice what the outcome
would be but i think trying to balance
out this recognizing the people are
going to deploy things and we need to
document it on one hand versus it'd be
nice to kind of come together more
coherently and help the community on the
other i think that's a i agree with your
point i think that's a path we're going
to try to walk any other
so actually I this Jesse Mesa might
default on one specific point to Eric
made not so much on the general process
just as far as the engine trans kill
these things so I actually happen to
know I think five implementation subnet
at this point in commercials of
switching silicon in the multi target
range including person kill these so I
just want to kind of challenge the
conventional idea for a little bit
stalker yeah sure on context seem so it
it seems like we give up on one
encapsulation because there's a new one
new encoding or encapsulation every
every few weeks or months but at least
have a defined mechanism to negotiate
which encapsulation is used by the two
NV is that will be a start and one small
comment to Eric and the OEM the other
one about race route is overlays
inherently support multihoming so that I
think any address in advance so there
may be multiple ways to get to the same
the only one but let's yeah let's keep
the conversation on Mike if we can so to
add to Sharon's comment Dino this is
dino sorry in the list working group we
added an encapsulation type format to
the mapping database and right now its
enumerated seven different
encapsulations and growing so just let
you know that the mapping database could
tell you what v-type address to use as
well as would encapsulation so it's a
form of negotiation not back and forth
just what I will support and you pick
one of the ones that you would
encapsulate it yeah so just sort of add
to that that means that the control
plane has multiple data plane options as
a requirement right this is elan go for
mental i think i want to make the same
comment that I made at the virtual
interim as well now trying to come up
with one single encapsulation format
that's a standard from my ETF is not
going to help the industry because you
already have many different and you're
going to create one more that the
industry may or may not put up creating
more problems than solving it where it
might be useful is in the TL vs we're
still it's an early stage where it's
possible there where the IETF can come
and define some some tea LVS that are
useful for maybe future hardware to
parse it has a request saying and so
this is a good time to start but have
that conversation and define some tlv
that could be adopted as a standard
within the IETF just to clarify you mean
maybe using the same T LVS across
different protocols that's that's
correct so if you look at the tlv format
at least between two different protocols
i can see that it follows exactly the
same format so you can always go and
standardize the tlv even though the
outer encapsulation that carries the TL
vs might be different you can still
sanitize tlv former that could be useful
in future and it could I mean you you
can get interoperability as well you can
make it work make them work together and
also you can make the hardware that
parses it to interpret it correctly
consistently across the encapsulations
and so will thank you I will take the
two people are standing here and and
then we'll but I have to close the ques
because we actually really do have to
quit on time today the plenary isn't
here next but before we go on Tom who
has the blue sheets and and more
importantly if you haven't signed the
blue sheets please find them and do so
sorry good Tom hard work so I just
wanted to comment on that so one thing
we are doing in goo is actually defining
several extensions so we have a
fragmentation extension coming up with a
header checksum and a few others
security is actually very important and
I think most of those could be generic
so for instance if you wanted to apply
those to tlv right now they're in flag
field so we can actually somehow
separate out the base encapsulation from
how you extend the protocol and say that
for instance DLP's is one mechanism flag
fields would be another but the content
of those may be either the same or very
similar and that could be a common
another common point Eric not my call so
quick response to longer that yeah I
think that's a good idea to think about
different things that are common in
terms of I guess not necessarily till
the encoding but the actual payload and
its semantics right and a it ties in
very well with one of the observations
that was made in the end caps design
team which is that the times when we had
defined these sort of extensions and
having actually use done right they sort
of have become useless but it can get
implemented in hardware or the middle
boxes just drop it on the floor or
whatever right so maybe there's some
sweet spot whether it's some security
cookie or something that people might
want where they want sort of better and
protection in this packet infection that
we could we can sort of say okay here's
a starting point let's pick this one and
only define whatever how big it is right
and that if that helps sort of get
across the hump that we have some
hardware support for something that we
can get into Nick's and switches right
and then we can see well the extent it
needs to be next but maybe they're just
doesn't software but there we can that
might actually help in terms of ensuring
that this is likely TB be useful down
the road right extensibility becomes
thank thank you for the comments
everyone obviously we have actually the
starts at the beginning of some good
conversations here on these two topics
so please don't lose the energy let's
take this to the mailing list and the
hall pay and I appreciate it we'll see
everybody soon will will announce an
interim meeting at some point another
virtual interim meeting and and you'll
see some of the details on the mailing
list so thank you and I see one blue
sheet coming up here if you haven't
signed it signed it please come up to
the front and sign it there's another
one over there all right thank you
everyone
just one of them on the clipboard
you