elliptic comic man or input from the
larger community so I would encourage
people to use that as well up there look
yes when it becomes a draft so basically
there's a section of that wiki that
tracks both working group gang models
and individual unique models there's two
tables there is a separate section that
lets people go on and announced their
intent or desire to create a gang model
and solicit input from the community so
I would encourage everybody to take a
look at it and use it as much as you can
okay any other questions or comments
before we move on okay oh the slides
have been uploaded but they may not
appear yet the because the tool takes
time but all the slides have been
uploaded they just may not appear online
yet because some of them would just
uploaded about 10 minutes ago okay
okay let me open the next slides okay
look II you're actually up without
slides so look at is next talking about
four four four seven bits oh look II
know doesn't work you just did something
to the to the projector as you walk past
it this works okay did actually not so
well good morning I'm surprises so many
people in this room 15 years to the to
the day actually well did it to the
meeting there we go about 15 years ago
that's what we first introduced the LFC
4447 which was the time called it was
still called civilized oh we haven't
actually we didn't give a cop's at one
at a time was called rock martini
actually and and then we we created a
working group called sea oats and that
then was renamed to pwe three and then I
guess he was a name to pals now and
that's when I first actually I met
Stewart shortly after that on a big
argument about two bits the feckin embed
that can bit exactly actually I can
probably say what happened then at this
point it's been 15 years there was a
typo in in the in the header and so we
basically reverse the effect on him back
in bits in the pw free header they
control word and that call you know it
was no reason the particular reason and
so Stewart actually found that
tenancy he was the ascii also questioned
why do you would you reverse this bit
that we couldn't quite explain it that
was the problem is that there was a typo
in the header but the problem is as soon
as nobody notice a type of document and
by the time Stewart product the problem
everybody had implemented it that way
already so there was no has no good
reason to change it anyway so this at
this time so what I did in in in the
past there's been to two revisions
actually of this RFC 4447 biss the first
one I took all the rat as we over the
past 15 years and you know they were
accepted there was a lot you know many
small technical problems mostly text and
you know clarifications and things of
that and I included that in the document
and then we just took an overpass at it
and we basically at this point you know
it's this talking has been around for a
long time it we just wanted to get a
refresh to include the errata and a
movie to proposed standards or whatever
the next step is we I believe that right
now it's it's ready for you know it's
last call we're not trying to include
one of the things that I wanted to do in
this document I didn't want to change
anything radically like text or or
include over references to what has been
done put after the document or anything
like that it's just a very simple fix
for for the errata and and you know kind
of update to the current temp later like
EF so so that I think there's one thing
they came up on the list there was the
order of the effect 129 theories and the
question was there was there's one
implementation that sends it in the
order that is in the picture in the
draft and there's a number of limitation
ascendant in a random order and the
particular document does not require any
order
you know it doesn't say it has to be
norther there is a way FTL these is
opposed because you should be able to
send them in any order you want unless
somebody specifically says there is a
good reason to send in a specific order
and so so I don't really feel like we
need to add a piece of text that says
you know you can send in any order
because that's implied it doesn't say
you have to send it in order so we
should be fine with that and in your
comments yeah clarifying question in a
router that you looked at the fixed in
next release a router as well as the
there are several classifications for a
rattle is reject there's accept which
obviously you do have to do but there's
also authors to look at when the
document is update updated did you pick
those up as well yes I looked at all of
those there were there were some that
were not you only have to look at them
but the commitment is that we were is
that the authors will look at the ones
that the 80s classified as look at in
next release as well as the ones that
were pretty right right I went through
all the full errata they weren't
accepted there was nothing over there
not accept I don't know they accepted
state I'm not sure who's making sure
because a lot of people don't well you
know no no no it was it was the state
was always held for next that's a yes
look I did all of the held for next
revision good good there was nothing
that was not you know there was wrong or
anything like that I can remember it was
it was fine now the other thing is did
you go through all of the updated by
documents and see if any of that needed
to be propagated into it updated by well
so rfcs get updated my other rfcs when
you do a revision you should look at
those updates and move them into the
main body of the text by one way or
another so that because otherwise the
update trail is lost and people don't
necessarily know what edits they need to
make right that's one okay so there was
a there was no update to it was ok so
there's the one thing that comes to mind
is there will control world negotiation
yes a pact where it was not as clearly
as specified in this particular graph as
it was in the next there's a number out
of see you know 2,000 Andy so no this is
not let me get back you can read about
the tracker you can't have the tracker
that says whether it was updated by
anything let's not do yeah that's not
the last one no that's not the last one
a 21 right you see the update in this
there you should incorporate that those
updates into the body of the text okay
I'd either directly or by reference or
ever you want to do it otherwise all
that information is lost and people
don't know everyone is we could do a
reference on this I'm not doing klein
into putting this into text because some
of those are fairly extensive well we'll
have to just look and see on a
case-by-case basis otherwise the
integrity of the document isn't right
okay I mean okay so so let me ask you a
question here of them what does out of
season learning about which number it is
is the VCC be sorry the control protocol
negotiation which really kind of updates
whole session which we can include those
updates and obsolete that our see with
the new one that will come out I think
that's probably the right thing to do
because that's just you know it's breezy
to do I just have to put it that texting
there was not intention initially whom
this document because we didn't want to
change you know why don't you do that
well you've got to say that delete the
paragraph delete the section or we have
delete delete body the section and say
the method of doing this is described in
RFC whatever yes okay but here's the
problem is this document is is well
established the procedure in these
documents will establish this is ready
for you know proposed standard or
standard trac right those are have
ceased
they updated like the control world
updates and so forth that is not exactly
the same status so we need to go through
each one on a case-by-case basis and see
because that line will not be that line
of updates will not be present in the
new RFC right right right okay so we
need to make sure that the reader of the
new RFC Rosa where by reading that
document or reading another document of
the work that is presented in the update
text okay so so okay but this still
gives me a dilemma because you did the
control board negotiation procedure that
this is describing that is not in this
document right and it is not the same
status level of implementation or
anywhere than it is in in this
particular in fact I believe that the
may not be any implementations of that
that on what is in this document so i
can't really include that text in this
document and claim that this is we we
did with moving should look at the top
line but we do need to deal with the
updates as well as the Arab sure we'll
we'll deal with that just we need to
figure out how to best you know I
referencing them maybe or something like
that so we don't we don't have to do
something that causes the document to
linger yet them over and over 10 or 15
years okay so any any other points
another updated points has anything else
anybody wants to bring up i vas word for
this 10 minutes because usually we don't
have enough time and I want to kind of
added a conclusion and discussion to to
move this forward we have all the time
in the world today sorry we pirate we're
going to hijack another hour hour and a
half or something rather the end of this
year we have lots of time yeah exactly
Eric yeah I one comment on me Eric gray
at ericsson I have one comment on the
the thing you were talking about with
the order of the tles or and and it
seems to me that there's sort of a proof
of concept that there's some confusion
over this
and it you could you could argue that
because we don't say it has to be in
this order right we are implying that it
can be in any order but it's equally
true that if it's shown in a specific
order it's implied that that's the older
you might be consp ecting it and so I
think it might be useful to put in it
these these may appear in any order in
the document on the other point you're
just talking about the updates I
completely agree with chairs on that I
mean minimally after all things are
considered you have to at least put a
paragraph in there and says you know
please also review the following rfcs
which have updated this that's sure yeah
okay so about to order they come and I
have is that earlier in the draft there
is actually a set of TL VZ with the
picture that has to be in order and it
says this has to be in the order it
explicitly says that so the rest I mean
people yes can assume the next one has
to be in order or not I mean it's kind
of a clarification point we can you know
I can I don't have a problem to add some
text I i we could add a text that says
did you know this don't necessarily have
to be in order or something like that
but as you know the interpretation is
that they should be in order and the
text doesn't say in that section it has
to be in order so I think that would be
extremely useful clarification because
one of the things that people tend to
forget is the one you have a make in an
RFC there's an implicit must behind that
which is that you say it may appear in
any order that means somebody must
accept it in anywhere right right so
any more comments okay great any more
questions or comments felucca okay thank
you lucas let me put the next
presentation up that is yes it is
just move it a little bit to the left
this that's fine thanks okay lowa could
you use electro so there is a directive
what your name please and lo Anderson
that is it directly from the secretariat
that you should make the speakers keep
within the box on the floor because
there is a camera that it actually I'm
running so please Thank You Louis though
if you come up to speak please stand in
the pink box pink box here and remember
that very well does that yes okay so I'm
going to talk about Mac withdraw
signaling these are the co-authors so
brief history we started with this
effort was started in 2011 and it was
first presented in l2vpn then it went
little bit dormant there wasn't
sufficient interest in the l2vpn group
the service providers were requesting
this feature so I picked it up and
presented in pw III in pw3 we went
pretty far discussions and there was a
lot of acceptance and all that in 88 ITF
88 we did a detail protocol presentation
and was well received but at the end
almost towards the end there was a I
think the chairs ND malice and other
people suggested that we should really
take it to l2vpn working group so again
we took it back to l2vpn working group
because original mac withdraw signaling
for dynamic pseudowire were actually
done in l2vpn working group so we took
it to l2vpn working group since already
in the last stages in pw3 we did allah
call and I think then the group split we
had some more comments and so we are
this is an update on with the comments
next slide please so the as we as you
guys know Mac withdraw signaling is
actually it's an optimization to
mitigate the black holes during pseudo I
switch over it's already done for
dynamic slower as I said this is this is
to do it over the static pseudo wires so
this this mechanism actually is clone
from the dynamic match because signaling
for which is already defined in the 4762
and pseudo as status signaling was
actually taken from the pseudo I status
signaling actually shows how you can do
the status TV or any kind of signaling
on the OEM channels so we took that
scheme from there so yeah here is just a
brief graphical display on where it is
used a little bit of animation here you
want to click yeah so if you have a
fault if it's empty you is dual home to
p1 and p2 and if the primary pseudowire
is on going to the p1 and you if you had
a fault you the mech you need to the
empty use which is over to the standby
pseudowire and more click and since this
is a static sort of wire you need to do
a signaling of mac we draw one more
click and so this is how it progresses
MTU sends the mac withdraw signal over
the static pseudowire has described in
this draft which then gets propagated to
all of the remote pease the whole idea
there is to so that yeah the whole idea
there is that all those remote p is p 6
5 4 3 2 who were sending the traffic for
stations behind the MTU they were they
those remote piece did not know anything
about the pseudowire going down on P
between mt u and P 1 so they were they
had learned the MAC addresses that sent
that was sending the traffic to the PE
one so they would continue to send
traffic to p1 we want now to let them
know that now that you can send the
traffic for two for them to you through
the PE 2 so you need to send this Mac
withdraw that's the utility of this
feature okay so that the Wi-Fi on the
static pseudowire so the this mpls-tp
you know as is taking hold especially in
the access networks and thats a static
provisioning LSPs and that's doubt tails
with the static provisioning of the
pseudo wires so this nessa see it's this
om signaling for the statics of the wire
next so the coming back to the central
topic here the response to the comments
the you know these comments were quite
comprehensive and Stuart provided those
who Thank You Stuart so that I have not
addressed all the comments but I had
taken the most of the the general bigger
comments the first concern was that
magnet rho signaling on ldp was actually
you know ldp uses the tcp so there's a
guaranteed delivery reliable
acknowledged in order and this one since
this is not using tcp it says it's over
the static pseudowire so how do you
guarantee the delivery and so the the
comet is correct we do have the sequence
number acknowledgment and three retries
so it's a kind of a best-effort scheme
it is true that yes you can if the
network is congested or lossy you can
lose that and
and you may not you may not get the mac
video signal so I do I can't remember
what the new text says but does it
explain clearly to reviewers that it is
a best-effort scheme because yes the
dangerous this question will get raised
yes three other times between now and
IRS I actually added a paragraph because
you made that comment i said yes i will
and i added yeah i made it very very
clear that this is a best-effort scheme
it's an optimization scheme and there
are others other mechanisms by which the
node will relearn so if you have a
bidirectional unicast frame exchange
going on then you will learn and the
second is the you know the aging timer
sorry share on the very so a question
what's the difference within this and
this RFC 73 61 and also there was an EVP
nmac withdrawal also what's the
difference with that one so the IRA 7361
is an optimization the opted for the in
the 73 61 that the scheme there is that
if you if we go back to the previous
badger that graph here the in 73 61 says
that the p1 should send the Mac we draw
oh yeah instead of having the P to send
Omega door to every the p1 sends the Mac
we draw with a specific list of mac
addresses so that you don't have to
flush all the mac addresses from the
other but here you flush everything yeah
so this one this is 444 I mean this is a
map withdraw signaling or you know 4762
this is what it says that you do it on
the stair then the one you just
activated so that's the difference and
then if you can also had some mic with
Rob I don't think that there's is or
anything different they're there you
know bgp based mac video signaling yeah
EVP n is bgp ways yeah and this is LT
today this is al dpa no this is static
static on the way not even earlier no
not even ldp but your drug says LD fever
started League inning no no the the
scheme is derived the Mac we draw
signaling scheme the mac Lee's tlv is
derived from the LDP based mac
withdrawal we didn't define a new tlv
okay but this is done on the static
pseudowire on in band om channel so we
in band om shan so you're defining in
you oh yeah yeah new ACH type yeah yeah
yes it's not it's in the traffickers
yeah and actually the last lectures we
are asking for new OEM channel type you
see school I should make that clear do
well there well you know it says the
static over static pseudowire there is
no ldp in bed yes yeah okay the couple
of like oh yes so you know the general
scheme is that you will relearn with the
you know bi-directional uniform unicast
for him exchange and obviously you have
the mac address aging usually the
default time is 300 seconds so if you
know in the verse trick worst case
scenario you would have a black hole in
45 minutes another point is that you
don't want to actually keep retrying
forever because the utility are the
benefits of mac withdraw signaling to
flush mac addresses the case you know as
the time goes by so you know it's it's a
very small window you want to do the
flush and you know carry on the next
slide please so the other comment was
you know what if you are using the big
mac and you know if that list is too big
there is no fragmentation and you know
how do you handle all that so you know
the response is actually there are a
couple of ways you can handle that one
is that it is a sequence number based so
you eat you can treat a concise you know
you can break up the list and you send
frame by frame with whatever the list it
can accommodate in the MTU and it's it
each one is individually that
individually with the sequence number
the other thing is that if it's too big
you just use an empty metal it anyway so
I should share on the body so how does
the p2 now know there's a failure on the
other link the prairies a pseudo has
started signaling also sospeter really
doesn't have to know that there was a
failure between MTU and PE 1 and then
why if it doesn't know then why she
asked for a mac with raw p2 doesn't ask
for it empty you sends the mac we draw
to the PE 2 and their PE 2 then forwards
that to everybody else so this packet
that is just showing is sent from the
MTU yeah that's from theatre no not from
p2 p2 forwards also the MTU so this or
why it starts from Mt you yes not from
here to know empty you is you know thus
the hierarchical vpls you right in the
hierarchy we pls you have the it's not a
multi-segment pseudowire this is in the
hierarchical vpls you know you have an
MTU that talks to the Pease and the peas
it yeah so the empty you would send it
over the pseudo wise let's go back ok so
the MTU sends it over a pseudowire which
terminates at p2 yeah exactly and then
the p2 takes this message yeah puts it
on another pseudowire there are going to
the vpls instance yes same thing with
the pseudo our status signaling and all
that yeah yeah ok yeah so those you who
are standing in the back could you find
seats there are some open seats up here
we don't want to keep the door block
yeah it's a great thank this is uh this
this is very common yeah hey I can
explain you more offline if you want ok
I will go back to the comments yeah so
you handle the you know the MTU exit by
the empty list or break break down the
list
into multiple videos okay the second the
next slide please yeah sorry there was a
yeah the concern is how do you handle
the out of order again this is not a
reliable delivery but we do have a
sequence numbers so what we have stated
in the draft is that if you have a out
of order so if you have a lower sequence
number arrive later than the higher
sequence number you you actually ignore
that and but you do a kit so the highest
sequence number takes the presidency so
now when that happens if you ignore that
list you will you will not flush the
subset of the MAC addresses which again
is fine because then you know if you did
the means those mac addresses they would
be relearned anyway by other mechanism
so so it's not a calamity that you lost
a subset of mac addresses next time the
fixed three yeah we do the three retries
actually I can you go back I did not
talk about the sequence number rap there
is an RFC 4385 we do do sequence number
in the control word and this RFC 4385
actually describes how do you handle
that how do you detect a wrap and and
how do you handle it the overflow so
I'll go to the next slide I ok so yes we
have 33 retries comment oh the fixed
interval so the yeah the original draft
said that you know if you if you don't
receive that if the sender doesn't
receive the ACK yeah you say you know
you resend after 1 second interval 3
fixed intervals and the comment was that
you know in case of scaled configuration
you
there may be many pseudo was doing this
and you cannot guarantee that everything
so I think the better thing and I have
changed the text is that you can do the
exponential back up it's an
implementation choice but it's a
suggestion that if you were to that do
apply some jitter then you know you have
a better chance of resending it and
getting an act back next slide scene so
yeah I mean we had the that was very
good comments very comprehensive there
was a lot of other comments also i want
to address them all here but it made the
truck better and i think we feel that we
have it's now in a much better shape so
next slide please yes so I think you
know we have asked for a new channel
type x 28 and we feel that we should
give go for the last call again comments
yes I again two more question for I
don't like the name OEM I think we
should change it to something else you
call it OEM this is not really OEM the
pseudo I status also calls it over here
yeah yes it's consistent SRAM sorry it's
consistent with previous error yes it's
possible Rock debacles box if i compare
our seas okay um if you feel strongly
enough about it I suggest that you put
your comment on the list in there and
see if you get any positive reaction ok
this is really controlling us as you
know yeah it's not doing any it will go
to send a comment changer hail either be
right before or during last call it will
be addressed according to g process sure
second thing is this only withdrawal or
is it chemically used to move the mac to
a different suit or no it's only for
withdraw its only coach yeah it would be
mean this is kind of an imperfect
solution intended to provide some
optimization if it was a movement it
need to be it will have to show where to
move to and all that stuff and and the
sender doesn't know where it should move
to like for instance in this case then p
2 would have to know which sort of our
phase and what that should have our
coincides on the other remote Pease
right here this is just saying hey plus
this make it unknown it will get
broadcasted and it will relearn the one
the whole idea here is that don't keep
sending it to the old paths because all
path has gone down you're not going to
it not going to go so that's the whole
idea okay great thank you thank you
macho and the the chairs are in
agreement that it's ready for last call
so that will be starting soon after the
ietf I had excellent and just before we
move on to the next talk who has not yet
signed the blue sheets I see some lot of
hands up so whoever has the blue sheets
please start them circulating again so
we can get them around to everybody okay
alright so I am NOT Carlos or Prasad yep
yes oh ok ok ok trafford early for those
of you just for everybody's knowledge
for those of you who plan to present in
any working group in any room this week
there is this muneco system that the
IETF is now using in and I think every
one of the rooms now to to broadcast
what's happening in the IETF and and
recorded as well and there's a little
camera in every room and by standing in
the pink box that's marked on the carpet
that guarantees that you're in the range
of the camera so that anyone who's
watching out in the web or watching the
recording at some point in the future
can actually see who's speaking so
that's the reason why there's a pink box
on the carpet that's so now you all know
well that's all very well it's fortunate
that in this particular slot I don't
need to do my usual thing of pointing at
the slides and explaining one line or
the other was showing how packets are
moving around so we should pride some
feedback about this restraint on
speakers ok the next slide please and
I'm not either the and we and this was
presented in BFE yesterday next slide
please it should be moving let me see
hello
here we go okay um so what not what this
is about is about defining the behavior
of spfd on the VC cv channel for a
signaled and prostatic pseudo wires and
uncle slightly unconventionally it
covers both are the l2tp case as well as
the over and mpls PSN case so 55 58 5
covers this but we don't very often talk
about it in this in this working group
so we're interested in l2tp signal
pseudo wires static pseudo wires and a
future revision of the draft we'll talk
about ldp signaled suitor wires but it's
not in the current version of the text
plan is to reuse the encapsulation
protocol procedures of 5885 and to
define the additional the additional
work changes that are needed to support
spfd we will need a new cv we need new
cv types to support as be a sink SD spfd
echo is not in scope now we had this
discussion the last time this was
presented it's in the records and the
authors will take a look at the the echo
issue spfd provides v CC v base fault
detection only and VC's other fault
detection status signaling is out to
scope next slide please so the the next
thing that we need that we need to
design as part of this is the the the
mechanism for getting the spfd
discriminators will either use
provisioned discriminators or use the
the alert mechanism that's currently
being proposed in the seamless PSD alert
draft and l2tp when that's used for
advertisements there is a draft that
describes how we add that to lttp
encapsulation where the is your a call
we can either send BFD natively or we
can send it in UDP IP where it's going
in UDP ap it will go so as it does today
except that the sbf d UDP destination
port will be used so that's actually
really just cookie cutter stuff where l
two SS for l2tp or the pseudowire ACH
encapsulation mechanism is used we will
have to request new iono types to
identify that it's spfd being carriage
next slide please the initiator
operations are we need to new cv types
for the operation for the operation
option one uses some reserve bits in the
existing parameter defined by RFC 5885
option two uses some bits from the VCC v
extended cv parameter tlv defined in RFC
71 89 for the reflector operation we the
the proposal is to run this exactly as
described in the base BFD seamless
specification the capability selection
and this is something that I think we
need to discuss in this room for a
little bit there's a question of what is
the order of preference between s BF d
and b FD and i understand that you can
have both of them can currently working
as well so the the question that the
authors posed in their original slides
was can they be independent I
order of preference someone who worked
in this work quite a long time I would
be worried about that because I would
like to make sure that every time two
systems come up every time I provision
some systems the behavior is exactly as
I expect so I'm guessing we may end up
with all three cases one the other or
both Greg moreschi Erickson actually I
would compare SB of d to our icmp and
LSP pink so not really be of D because
it's a functionality of echo request
echo reply and that's more like I see in
peeping in LSP being right but we're
going to have to but the the two
signaled pseudowire pas or whatever you
call the LG TV 11 sort of not remember
how they will have to have a common
agreement whether they are going to run
just the FD spfd as well as BF d or just
spfd because they could decide that you
want to run s50 all three possible cases
exist right but at the same time when we
advertising capability where advertising
icmp paying an LS beeping so
and email sighs have a comment as a
participant rather than as a chair my
own personal druthers is that we as a
working group just make a choice for one
being the default one of the three cases
I don't key I don't have any particular
opinion as to which one should be the
default but I would like to see a
default so that it's so if if people
just naively bring up systems without
provisioning this it'll work yeah I
absolutely agree that there needs to be
one default but I suspect there are
really three cases and not to as people
have bought yes I have a question to the
previous slide where there's a reference
to a CH encapsulation at previous slide
so in case of a CH encapsulation ah
there is no IP address to return to so
how reflector will identify the source
of s BFD echo request and return because
the idea of SB FD is that reflector
doesn't create any state associated with
a session there is always suitable
statement is unconditionally going to be
pseudowire state because pseudo wiser
was bi-directional so you all will know
who your peter is ok so basically no you
wasn't you I think you you can say that
you always know that if you get
something of this type of this vfp of
spfd type on a pseudowire then you take
the appropriate actions and send them
back on the the the other of us part of
the pseudowire because sooner wise
always bidirectional great ok I'm not
quite sure what happens and maybe
someone maybe I've just forgotten what
happens if you have a
point-to-multipoint sudo why do you
always have a return channel there I
really can't remember no no so we do
need to figure out whether this is a
flick
yeah 22 that case yeah the only thing
that you really know is that there's
probably an AP return channel of this
but that's not all you know well I don't
know there may not be any in a.m. PST
PST or may not be anything that's true
so we do need to have some comment in
here on that either limiting the
applicability or solving the problem yep
okay next slide next slide so I think it
would be really useful if people can put
some of the comments that they've made
onto the list we could if we can have a
list discussion on this the authors are
keen to close off the open items and to
submit a new revision and they're going
to ask for this to be adopted by the
working group given the existence of
spfd I think the working group does need
an opinion on it and don't need to
specify a solution for using that type
of OEM technology ok ok any questions
yep I'll opium from javi well question
to you the intermission the unipro we
are a Salida you seems there to use a
another consider the RDP based arrow to
VPN so they stick it that it means the
RDP based art will review not taking
into account in this draft you hang on
watch don't use RSVP signaling there's
no definition of an RSVP single suit or
is it knock knock one that I've knows so
so I don't see why we need to have any
discussion about RSVP here none are not
are asleep you are deep you our old EP i
reduce you yeah when not it so they plan
to provide some text i think if you go
beyond earlier on in here yeah yeah mpls
ldp signal zeros are not considered in
this revision the bracket future i
understand that to mean that there will
be an ldp
body of text written before this work is
fully completed so we will need an ldp
solution and hence you know my question
about how do we pick one if we're signal
if we're negotiating this because if
you're running ldp you will have to have
the default negotiation mechanism
working so i think it's just that they
didn't put the text in rather than
there's no intention to do it and I
think we have no no choice but to solve
its Institute to document the design for
use in an ODP signaled environment I'm
sorry I misheard that you said I know
any other questions from the very just a
clarification question these runs over
the l2tp has a control packet and data
package runs over the data package right
another control so the signaling
configuration runs over the control
plane and the identification that this
is an oam spfd itself runs on their data
there's a bit in the l2tp header that is
this is l am ok so it has exactly the
same exact same as their concept but
they've just dodged it in a completely
different way en w'en down from poway
just a clarification is this a drop
litter purpose is to replace that
original easily at the FD no I don't
think so I mean BF BFD exists anyway and
i can't see as ever deprecating it in
any immediate term done time frame so
this is to enhance BFD but i am
presumably when you want to introduce
some measure of scaling that you might
not easily achieve with BF diva BFD has
got some useful properties anyway yeah I
agree
but I said about the sense that it can
also be used to empieza to the wire so I
think we have now we have a two options
for the PFD VCC be so which should we
use sorry i'm not sure but he wants to
know this me two options yeah the in
spfd he's looking for guidelines I think
it depends on what you're trying to to
achieve yes so so I think his point is
if the draft should go into oh right the
draft should discuss under what
circumstance yes that yeah that the
applicability of the work would be a
useful section to act yes I yes exactly
here ha totally like every booster I
supported it in some crap equipment so
the answer is I don't know the answer
that question but I asked the author's
where shouldn't you have a or b and they
said no i might want to run a and B so
and I didn't pursue it but like they
tell me they need to run a and B we need
to figure out how to have get both ends
running in the same mode a B or am to be
okay feel free do you know the questions
for Stewart okay thank you stop being a
ghost and just before we move on does
anyone need a blue sheet yep Eric could
you pass it over to that side the room
okay hello yo B from javi this topic
that used to discuss the design for our
two week in a young model okay I see a
nice life okay they see you the history
revealed in the Honolulu IETF 491 so we
present the are tweaking a young
configuration a model in the past
working group then after the meeting we
received a positive response from the
several experts to cooperation to define
the young for review so because of the
working group I used to change it so
this draft is also moved to the past
working group together the appropriate
working group to go on to discussion
okay so we have a meeting to discuss the
design for the earth who we being young
so according to the operation so that we
said have a design team for arrow to
Whitney Young so this is from a sciphone
santoshi show and a commensal so and
also that we go on to welcome more
members and a cooperation from the
industry we hope to add the beginning to
negotiate the common models for our to
Virginia so that we can finish the young
walk annotated consists concern concerns
as a beginning okay next okay so the
design team we discussed the scope of
the arrow to VPN because in the past ten
years are to review the very popular and
the all kinds of our VPN solution have
been proposed here so this goal we try
to define that what to design by this
team and the water not will be designed
by this team so the first day you
discover you the common comments for the
are to live here so that means that no
matter our DP based pvp based or the
state high capacity so we have some
common configuration this included the
art will be P instance and the
attachment has secured under the
silverware this is the basic components
of the air to whip you so that the
common configuration and operation will
be defined under the the young on the
different types of the eric who live
here because the different era to live
here different types of the air to VPN
there may be different configuration and
is the operation Peter so this included
the RDP based repeatable us and VP RS
and the PGP based the bleep ers and the
PDP auto-discovery based we be ours and
also that is a state hehe p SS and the
static of a PRS so this is the the haps
of the art will appear will be taking
into account so now the one remaining
usual use the CCC that means the
security cross connect because this is a
user to some extent use the different
from the common reference model of air
to VPN but in fact there are several
implementation so we will discuss later
this you use as a vendor specific young
model or try to defend in the working
group okay yes young definition we will
take into account the configuration data
and the operation data and in the RPC
and the notification so that a user
completed the young definition for the
models not a universe cope I think that
the art will appear because the number
of the types of the art will appear so I
think this we can be a future draft so
and also that uses some
work related with the arrow to VPN or
the silverware is real that means that
the OEM they have the VCC VPN and the
trees and also that I'm pr's tpo em for
civil aware especially regarding a
related with the performance monitoring
so this Walker will not be taking into
account by this team so this work we
will leave to the OEM experts to do the
young model work yeah okay next okay and
also when we prayed until the worker in
the past working group but in fact the
art will appear has much relations with
other work so we will do some the during
that the cause of the desire we will do
the liaison work this included the lay
down with the best working group because
the PDP based vp RS and the PCPD
auto-discovery based the Riviera's will
be taking into account so the liaison
work will be done between the past
working group under the best working
group and also that using the last
meeting stillwater reminders that they
are to repeal the existing are to VP
amoeba so this will win design the young
model so we try to keep consistency with
existing RTP amoeba ok and this is the
design work plan so the first we will
discuss the architecture design because
we firstly we try to defend the
architecture of the air tubes in young
models so we try to finish this work in
the middle of the May this year so this
will define this is using the work I
include sakova definition and also the
component division because this is
because we try to do you truly divided
the art we be a young model design walk
into the different apart so there is a
they say user into account this included
the common component and also the
different there may be different
aircraft for the different art Olivia
young model so this is the tool hire two
walks we'll be taking into account into
this face after the face so we will
prepare the plan for the concrete data
model design so the concrete data model
design included a common component under
me under the super Civic pass of the
different types of the air to Vivian's
so I think this is we try to pro whole
the initial draft before the next idea
of a meeting but according to the pasta
experiments so the work is a very
challenging so that we will propel the
work plan after the first phase
architecture design so that a disgusted
in the working group to see if it can
comply with the charter of the air to
pass a working group ok next one ok so
this is the working a measure that has
been discussed in the design team so
that we will meet every two weeks to
discuss the design of the art will begin
young models ok I think that this is a
meeting time has been determined any
commerce this is being run from comcast
of a question for the scope of work so I
see you cover a bgp based v pw vpls like
to understand like will index scope we
also cover ugp based v pw s service so
going to point yeah ok so the question
is are you covered under the spec in RFC
47 61 or are you cover also 6624 i think
that should be covered because yesterday
we also discussed the
please review SS yeah it's really cover
okay yeah I will we come as Comcast we
use the bgp signode v pw s so i
definitely want to make sure like this
big add to the scope sorry okay thank
you get yeah can we go back to the
working methods one of the things i'd
like to see as part of the working
methods is that you update the wikis
that we made reference to at the
beginning of the meeting I know that is
there's quite a few drafts one drafts on
there and I'm not sure which ones
overlap it looks like there's some
redundancy because some of them are
listed is l2vpn and some were listed as
pals but if you could reconcile those as
a result of though the work and the
working methods I appreciate it okay
yeah okay definite okay I think of data
we will that in the beginning / that a
user some days the young model
coordination what a message that has
been proposed that you know I ATF we
will comply with this method okay to
earn our were walking okay that's one
okay so I saying this so you finished so
I hope that we get more comments to help
her to help us to defend your models
effectively yeah I so would you like to
part its way we need service providers
to participate in this activity because
they are the one who are using these
models right it would be really nice if
service providers join this effort yeah
I comcast we are like we are heavily
like investing like looking at netcom
from the young so definitely i'm going
to have someone from our like Devon teen
participate
iftikhar infinera now in the scope
question for the scope is at the service
level aspect of l2 service example a
diff like manipulation active vlans for
example or entrance you know in the
context of LG are they in the scope of
this one or not ok I missed this part in
fact the univer last the meeting the day
proper the similar opinion so that I
used because there for the VP ours for
the some the pws there are some special
contribution regarding the AC attacher
security so that especially for repairs
there's a lot of the villa operations so
this is the this Walker will be defined
this unit is your model yeah yeah Nick
del regno verizon a couple things one be
happy to help out with the definition
source engine email join the list the
second is don't think we should include
vinterberg vendor implementations vendor
specific implementations like ccc in our
definitions we should be in the business
of writing Hank models for the RFC's
that we produce okay Greg mesquite
ericsson I think that it's okay to have
containers where their specific
implementation details can go but yang
model that standardized should be a
common set of functions and emails this
actually takes me back to a little bit
of history that i can tell you all back
in the 90s here in the IETF I chair the
working group where we did in a SP lib
for frame relay services and there was
also in the ATM working group at that
time we also did a very similar ATM nib
for ATM services in there in each of
those nibs
we did have a vendor-neutral
cross-connect table so so I suggest that
you might just want to take a look at
those two noobs as examples of what you
can do for a vendor-neutral cross
connect okay okay thank you okay any
other questions or comments before we
move on okay and we'll come to our last
presentation for the day which means we
are running right on time in terms of
finishing up in an hour and a half
although we do have the full two and a
half hour slot it turns out ok let me
just start these up and Mohamed take it
away episode my name is mommy hookah
death and and presenting this draft on
behalf of all theaters so the precise
will be sure because you this working
group and the pharma group that did
already done the work to identify the
problem space and the gap analysis that
we are addressing in this draft so in
the next life pieces as you see in there
are RFC 74 39 it won't fight what are
the missing pieces in so that we we can
deploy ipv6 enabled impetus network and
in that in that in that excellent
analysis deified that the only piece
which which which is still missing is
our RFC 66 74 in which the identified
the even identified the section that
need to be to be fixed and handed so
that we can have something which is a
address family in
why we have it right now ipv4 specific
so this draft is trying to fix this void
I did pride so exactly two simple
updates as you can see in the next slide
please so the first one is just an
update to the BGP another I attribute
that is don't define it in that section
so in the current version of the RFC the
PIAA this is all the uncoated for octet
and the new what we are suggesting here
is that you have JP address encoded to
cover and ipv6 so there will be some
text to explain in the draft and the
next up Update is ready to add to the
signal if our signal part in order to
add to to be sure to use analytics
others as a source and a target so the
drug is suggesting to define a new type
which would be an able to include 128
bits rather than the one that is today
only capable to go to d 2 230 it's so
there will be a the river section that
we need to be updated in the in the RC
60s 74 just to say that's so as you can
see them in the next slide please it
this drop is it just feeling something
with that has been unified in general
this RFC the fixes are for me not
controversial are fake reward so we are
presenting here this work you have to
seek for more feedback for you and
cyclist and so that we can move this
document for world so intersection our
modem campus very nice work this is a
quite useful so so thank you very much
for doing the work are there any
questions comments anything at all
okay thank you very much and with that
you haven't explained adult right yes
that brings us to the end of pals so
thank you all very much for coming and
we'll see you next time Oh whoever has
the the other blue sheets please bring
them up to the front of the room yes
around some oh I see them no this cheeto
and the other one I just saw someone
hold it up it's done it's back there
thank you very much I think the finish
dr. pol can be adopted and this
afternoon
we can go and do some stock thank you oh
that's funny
well I see the sooner we are you may see
if you are so you Natasha the EC au se
idea ok so these are the VP are you mean
to thank you
okay okay the most important thanks
ok
so you're playing is everybody cool so
after you send an email to
whatever
right
you