okay so he was playing was actually
session
yeah good afternoon good afternoon good
afternoon Brian a working group
and you know I if you got lost I find
this to be very surprising but you never
know so this is prissy working group
meeting this is obviously under the
traditional note well this is the
proposed agenda so status of the last
calls that we have done and it was a
request for mapping and I haven't earned
any slides or anything about mapping
okay and if there's any discussion about
the lucid the buff that just happened
any suggested changes to the agenda okay
so here's the status of our current
darkness sorry
well I can tell you somewhere published
one document the problem statement like
a couple of years ago framework is in
our theater sku and we have two
documents in publication requested and
very well 12 okay well anyway thank you
yeah framework as is is done the and we
have Peter was prepared a few slides on
the the last two documents I think what
we have met new ler Miller that as
submitted is a shepherd review but then
a nickname the shepherd doesn't sent
this is right up so that's one missing I
guess from the process point of view
and so
this is Barry your ad has a question is
there anything related to lucid or other
things of that nature that makes you
want me to hold up on these or you just
want me to charge ahead and process them
next week I think we have discussed that
in length in the frame about the
framework and the idea was essentially
we add some text that says you know be
careful and and the same is true with
these two document okay cut right that's
what I thought I just wanted to make
sure yeah so yeah joe please get me a
Joe is not around anyway we'll deal with
it so this is what Peter prepared Peter
sent Andre and I since he's not here and
that's my fault I didn't prepare a
channeling audio from him that I should
have but so I'll do with the slides so
framework done a proof for fabrication a
registry is done the code points the
table are done and Peter where is the
reviewing the table to make sure that
all the cool points are okay and then
we'll send its ok then they will this
will trigger the the arts editor to
publish so you may get it in a few days
sasol Prebys I think you're cool yeah so
basically a relative little disc has
changed since Honolulu the username
profile got split into two for
case-insensitive case insensitive and
then basically the document was brought
in sync with the framework changes and
dates but for the most part I've well it
is it is done we believe it's ready for
working group for I TFS Cole I was just
talking to Barry I think what we'll ask
for a couple of apps Directorate
reviewers for this that's probably one
way of getting you know more of yours
nickname somewhat similar updated and
from the other address working group
last call feedback and ready to go for
ITF last call xmpp this has been X MPP
sweat 2061 22 this is referring to these
is has been working group last call in
the too well in the XP XMPP working
group and then in you know
simultaneously in pracy and we think
it's going ready for ITF last call
however this is done on the XMPP side so
it's more for your information I guess
so I just I have a question on this
there is some comments a question I
think my general question is the ad okay
and is anything missing for you apart
from I think the Shepherd right up right
up and
okay mapping someone requested I don't
have your slides to UF slice or just to
talk sorry I don't have a try okay in
this time I'd like to make sure the
markings documents next step according
it is I here according to the discussion
in IT 90s the mappings document where
moved to working group last call after
framework document I Kevlar score is
done so but I'm very sorry ah I had not
realized too I i had not finished it to
revise the mappings document and so the
map current status is current status of
the mappings document is expired so I'm
I'm revising the mappings document to
quit greatest framework document we need
to synchronize all those so I'm going to
I'm going to submit the document until
re a proof so I'd like to ask shares
whether the working group schedule I
wrote the submission a submission so
I'm I'm going to submit the mappings
document as soon as possible and I
direct this year your comment to proceed
was to me was the mapping document a
working group document yeah ah ok oh
yeah that's been expired that's why I'm
not seeing it Aaron okay so it go so
we're we're waiting for having you a new
version yeah synchronize with use the
framework yeah ok ok thanks Peter
saint-andre regarding sasal prep this we
received quite a bit of feedback a long
time ago from people like Nico Williams
and perhaps you could ask them for a
sanity check at this time
andrew sullivan on the mapping document
on this is maybe anticipating a little
bit too much the next agenda item but
you know we just heard in the in the
lucid Boff suggestion that one of the
directions that we could end up going if
we don't have a lot of we know how if we
don't have success with a property is
essentially a significant mapping
document probably a significant bit of
advice now I'm not sure whether it's the
same mapping and that is what's not
clear to me so I I mean I don't actually
have an opinion on which way to go but
it seems to me that one of the things
you could ask yourself is whether it
would be better to see how that proceeds
in order to proceed with the mapping
document or to publish this and then do
another one later well we my I guess my
personal point is that not thing as with
I DNA mapping is pretty important for
most of the customers of you know
priests priests II so and then right now
we have a rough idea of maybe something
that may we may work with Unicode so it
looks like to be more appropriate to
have a full package of pc that could
people could do and then rev it because
I don't know mrs. Peake Resnick I mean I
think the more important point is I'm
guessing it's very likely that the
mapping kind of stuff we would do to
deal with the lucid issues even if we
get to that point are going to be very
different from the kind of mapping
that's being described as sort of a more
general here's the kinds of things you
could do mapping wise um they're dealing
with very different looking problem
spaces I think they will of if we go
down that path and lucid I think they
will end up converging but I think marks
right there's
the utility enough of the current
mapping document that we should probably
go ship it and do a rev if they converge
and in the the Jeffers someone said you
know we could probably do some similar
to what PC framework says which is a bit
of you know heads up of you know warning
right so I'm again this is andrew I i
I'm fine with all of that i'm not i
actually just don't have an opinion but
i'm i'm conscious of what i think it was
chris said in the multiple versions is
maybe a problem so just just a thing to
consider
okay um well we're a good segue to the
other so this the next item on yes
getdata a DJ from John cleansing so Mike
it seems to me that if we are going to
publish mapping now it better contain
very strong and receipt warnings and
another channel is mike i think that
view is consistent with that with fat PT
saying so what will i think we will
review when the doc the new version
comes out of the document and see you
know altogether if you need to do
something more or less depending segue
to the placeholder of will do we need in
proceeded to think about you see this is
or what what happens in a couple of
years the last two hours we know what
but what would happen but maybe 11
question to the ideas is especially the
right own to to start this this you know
preview see the work or not or doesn't
matter
sorry before that can I ask an ignorant
question for somebody who had a conflict
is there one sentence or one paragraph
summary of lucid well I think you look I
think you laugh is indicative but which
is sort of suspected but okay well the
ones yeah i guess the summary and so
Andrew went through the the issues and
then proposed five possible directions
we could take to deal with them the
issue of course is how to deal with new
characters that come that changes in the
character set from Unicode that that
break the situation that we expect and
we looked at the five directions and
added a sixth and then took a hum and as
I was as I remember it the direction
that we decided was best was to try to
work with the Unicode people to come up
with a new property on characters or a
new set of properties on characters that
we could synthesize a our prop a derived
property from that would help us and or
create an NF I normalization format for
IETF that again well for identify as
whatever that would come up that that
would that would have to be something
we'd have to work out with Unicode as
well and that the back the back up of
that is to say well we have to put
warnings about where you might have
problems and I don't think we decided
and the other the similar one of
warnings was how did what did we call it
and one lane bundling and blood bundling
of the situation bundling and blocking
blocking certain characters bundling
certain characters education ready
protocol they where we would do this
work is was left up in the air and
that's what these guys up front are
asking us now this is andrew i think the
only thing that i would add to that is
it it wasn't clear at least to me but
that could just be that my brain is i
think i think it shriveled a couple
hours ago on that that we have an
understanding of what kind of property
exactly it would be so there is a
potentially very serious problem that we
know we've got something that we want to
describe but we don't know what it what
that description is and we could wander
around in the dark for a very long time
the the one thing that that did leave me
feeling a little sad at the end of that
discussion was that people seem to agree
that there was a property or maybe
several that we needed to describe and
then i thought about well look at the
tremendous energy and you know output
that happened in this working group how
we managed to get everything going and
that worries me a little bit because if
if we don't get the engagement from the
people who are going to consume this in
order to sort of figure out and hammer
out exactly how we're going to how we're
going to work on that i don't think
we'll get the property I think we'll end
up with you know just a lot of
speculation and and then we won't
because my sorry to ramble here I
haven't formulated this very well my my
interactions with people who are active
in Unicode suggests to me that there are
people who are sympathetic to the idea
that we need I mean there are people who
are not sympathetic but then there are
people who are sympathetic to the idea
that maybe we need a property or two
here but they want us to describe
something that is clear distinct
distinguishable and and sort of
algorithmic and that means that we've
got to do quite
to work some of this may have security
implications and I don't know if we're
getting the the pollination across the
area that maybe we need for that so that
that's really the only thing that I
would I would raise this Pete again I'm
much more bushy tail than andrew is so
let me see if I can lay out why quickly
first of all the end of the session I
heard a lot of people say well the work
that we would invest at least the
upfront work we even invest in trying to
work with the Unicode consortium and get
them what that property means is pretty
much equivalent to the work we would
invest to try and come up with a set of
warnings or bundling rules and
everything else that goes with the other
choice so it's not wasted work in either
event and and some of it is agree I
agree hard but that that works going to
have to be done one way or the other the
other but that I'm a little more saying
when than Andrew about is with regard to
the Unicode consortium simply because I
think the work that we have to do here
is not stuff that we sorry guys one
meeting place is not stuff that we can
possibly do on our own right figuring
out what that property is and what is
even plausible to do is something that
is going to be an interactive process
with Unicode that we're going to have to
say is this a distinguishable thing that
you could come up with and part of
figuring out what it is that we're
missing is going to be part of that
conversation I think that conversation
is worth having one way or the other um
and I'm going to lose the thread here
because my brain is about as mushy as
Andrews um the oh the other thing that
he said was we're gonna have to get the
people who are wanting to use the
profiles again involved in this
conversation I think that's actually um
only marginally true if it's true at all
um I think we went through the process
and decided
at the particular compromise we made
okay these are characters that are
distinguishable within script and
therefore you know and have
distinguishable properties and therefore
okay to use as identifiers so we made a
category error we didn't get what we
thought we wanted but I don't think we
have to go through the process of asking
all those implementers again what they
want I think we have to figure out with
the unicode consortium whether we can
actually instantiate what we thought we
wanted with properties that they could
provide so I'm not clear that we
actually have to go back and redo all
the work that we did here I don't even
think we have to do very much of it I'll
push back on the penultimate thing that
you said that so getting getting anybody
else involved in this getting the
consumers of this stuff involved is a
non-starter agree with that no one
except a handful of people want to have
anything to do with this kind of sausage
even if they want to eat the sausage but
we have here a specific instance of
something that breaks our assumptions
and makes us want to do this the
ultimate properties we want is well this
is this character that's safe to use an
identifier is but that's too generic the
trouble is that the next time Unicode
changes something they may change a
different aspect of things that causes
the characters to be unsafe to combine
with other characters and identifiers
and so this may be an iterative process
getting either getting different
properties or getting the same property
applied differently in the future when
Unicode 7.2 or eight point 0 or whatever
comes out and that's the part that I
worry about no oh I've just I'm
really bad in this planning of this
meeting but I forgot to ask a secretary
or any describe so it would
and given that we're starting a
discussion we would like to get it you
know somewhat in some place any
volunteer for scribing at least when
starting from now please listen to the
mp3 later thanks um sure right and I can
probably remember to how to write down
what I say Jim shot so this is a
question for I guess barrier Andrew how
wet percentage of what this property
needs to be do we currently think we
actually understand and know how to
write down what are I was going to say
that as a consumer of this information
as a consumer of these rules maybe I can
express ladakh sorry as a consumer of
these rules I can express at least the
particular use case that I am looking at
and it may actually turn in to a way of
describing this property this mythical
property that we're talking about which
is the idea that when I go out and I
fetch a public key for a particular
email address and I get back a public
key that has a slightly different
identifiers on it than what the user
input how do I compare those two strings
to differentiate a situation where it's
a substitution attack vs just a
different way of expressing the same
piece of information and the example
that came up in between sessions was the
two different ways of typing in
the city Zurich where one uses a normal
you and the other one has a you with two
dots over it and presumably a human
would assume that both of those are
equivalent but a computer would not so
if a user types in Zurich with or
without the dots over the you presumably
it should match something now when we're
talking about a property maybe that is a
good way of describing it precisely
because if we compare this to how when
we do a search and again I'm an American
all I speak english so i'm going to use
examples from english you have the
option of searching for a word where you
preserve the case or you don't preserve
the case and i'm starting to think that
that's the type of property that we need
for these identifiers where you can
conduct a search and you look for
equivalent representations of the same
character but don't necessarily match
alternate characters that look similar
but are actually different and that is a
situation where the you with the dots
over it versus the you are actually
different and if you have this property
that is expressed programmatically then
you can conduct the search first for the
exact normalized string that was
provided and if you get a match return
it if you don't get a match you can also
write the protocol spec such that the
server would presumably conduct a second
search where this property is disabled
or turned on or what however you want to
express it would locate the possibility
of an equivalent match and be able to
suggest hey did you really mean Zurich
with the two dots over the you and then
the
mua can say is this what you really
meant user can click ok and it can
update the email address field or not
and to me that almost seems like an
expression of uppercase versus lowercase
but I'm looking at it very naively and
the more we talk about it the more it
sounds like we almost need to involve
the folks at the UTC precisely because
they're the ones that have stockpiled
all of the people who are intelligent
about these issues with how many
hundreds of different languages that are
represented by Unicode I don't think the
IETF has people who speak all of those
different languages and understand the
various properties of all those
different scripts but that's basically
where I came to I guess the only other
thing I'd close out my long-winded
ramble with is by saying that when I'm
developing a system I need to be
cognizant of a situation that me and
Pete talked about where some systems may
want to allow a situation where you have
two users one that spells Erick with the
regular you and one with the dots over
it and some systems may want to make
those mutually exclusive where you could
have one but not the other you can do
either one but you can't have both
because of the confusion factor and
that's where the security aspect gets
into it and I was of the opinion that
you wouldn't want to have both of those
accounts on the same system just because
a user could type in one variation of
that name and end up sending a sensitive
message to a completely different
account which is not the desired outcome
from a security perspective Pete was
arguing that there are a lot of people
who would want those to be two distinct
accounts and would get upset if they
couldn't make that distinction so it's
just something to be cognizant of and
how we express this problem needs to be
aware of that
Andrew Sullivan and I will channel
myself first and then John when I was in
high school I was in a band and we had
among other things a song called I hate
Motley Crue the lyrics of which were I
hate Motley Crue I hate the dots above
the you and I didn't know that lo these
many insider this is gonna be chilly
that I'm the Holy anyway on so to my
response to Jim's question do we
understand this is essentially giraffe
handlebar bicycle no we don't know John
had something a little bit more saying
which is essentially depends on what you
mean by we and understand so I think
that that's fundamentally what the what
the work of that we would need to do
under loose it is on that's not why I
got up here though I got up here to
respond to two berries remark which was
if you Nico changes this again stuff
could could shift on us again I I think
we want to be very careful here um
único didn't actually change anything
they had a system that just didn't work
the way we thought it did and what they
did is they added a code point under a
set of conventions and principles that
we did not fully grasp now there is
reason to suppose that no English
speaker of sufficient technical
background could have read the
definitions in the unicode standard
prior to 70 and understand that but it
appears now in retrospect that there was
a fairly consistent set of principles
going on there and maybe it was just a
bug in the in the way it was written
down finally to channel something else
that John was saying which is on a
different topic the Zurich case doesn't
involve lucid issue and is very
a fundamental to what is supposed
to be doing so it's it's really quite
quite a different case in particular
normalization won't help with that
either but it turns into a very tricky
language sensitive problem and the
language sensitive problem is something
that I think we're not doing here are
not doing in lucid thing clarify in what
Andrew just said I i did this is Barry I
did not mean that unicode had changed
something or that it was their fault but
what I meant to say is that in the
future there might be some other aspect
of how they make decisions that we were
equally unaware of now that would trip
us up this is pete and i think i'm going
to continue to disagree with barry on
this one the whole idea of actually
having a communication with the unicode
consortium and getting them to come up
with a property that we mutually
understand to be the thing we're working
on it's certainly possible that we screw
it up again and we don't understand what
they mean and that we end up with a new
set of characters that do something very
different but we've really lowered the
odds if this communication goes on
mutually and channel and bearing says
yep yep yep yep yep and and just to
follow up on what John said tuladhar
which i think is an important point the
the what i would call compatibility
matching the sort of search stuff really
is sort of independent of what pracy is
doing and what the lucid problem is
about it's certainly something that
needs to be dealt with and and we can
have a long discussion about you know
what kinds of things we do for those
sort of fuzzy matching rules which is a
whole big complicated problem and some
of them you'll want to solve in in your
implementation and something you really
want but play see the the kind of
property that we're talking about is
strictly if you want to use these things
purely as identifiers without fuzzy
matching that you want all of the false
positives to go away
and once we get into the fuzzy matching
stuff we've got a whole different
problem so we do want to separate that
out we're working on the property for
identifier that are not going to be used
in fuzzy matching Stewart cheshire a
quick thing comment things that we
should remember I think some of the
people in the room know this but
probably not everybody we need to be
very careful not to apply our own
intuition two languages we're going to
understand and luda was saying something
that we all do we assume that the oh
with or without the little dots on top
is ought to be the same letter because
to us as English speakers and like you
I'm only fluent in English I can read
and write passable French and German and
hindi and gujarati but I don't know any
right to left scripts and I don't know
Japanese or Chinese so I've got limited
personal experience and to me the little
dots on the letter are just like crumbs
on the page a little bit of dirt I'd
brush them away because they don't
matter but to other people they're
really important and we need to not make
the mistakes if people in another
culture were having this discussion
about English and I'll just use this as
an analogies they might say that letter
L and the L with a line through it well
they're kind of the same thing but
they'll be the line to it is a tee and
to us to map those as the same
identifier would be crazy and polish has
an L with a line in it except that L is
slanted and it's pronounced like a W and
that's not a tea or an L so our
intuition that it's obvious that
uppercase and lowercase a are the same
thing is a very dangerous intuition to
carry on to other scripts I was just
going to say I think you made an
important point and it made me realize
that what this problem really is isn't
understanding the specific languages
because we have matching rules that are
specific to a script already the problem
is that we're building systems that cut
cross-language and locale boundaries
where we've got us users talking to
people in Europe that speak a completely
different language and like you pointed
out have their solid Oregon have very
different ideas about what should match
and what shouldn't and that's where the
problem lies because a u.s. user may not
understand the distinction between two
characters that a European user would
and how do we come up with rules that we
can apply to be as safe as possible so
that at least when we get it wrong we
can point to the standard and say well
that's what they said we should do
so you said is done right okay I'm not
sure there's a clear conclusion but it
was a placeholder in case we had a here
you know work item for a preseason last
item I would like to talk to is
something that has been has been
discussed a bit during the working group
lunch today was so one of the
deliverables of this working group so
these are below here let me see if I can
improve the okay so so we've done that
we've got that we've done some of those
then there was an idea of guidelines for
people to you know help doing profiles
or not doing profiles and stuff and that
document hasn't been started so are we
going to do it they're closed the
working group or do or wait until
further profiles come in or something so
there were some support in the working
group chair lunch to get the guidelines
for people but that we would require
some people to write the document so if
we don't have anybody to write a
document so we're gonna bail yeah do you
do you honestly think this is very do
you honestly think that there's enough
energy here to do something like that
right this is a SL the floor that's a
possibility though what what Aleksei
just said not unless people come in and
help so if you can scare up enough
people to
and reactivate things and I'm happy to
let the working group go in that
direction the on the profiles I I think
what's more like that probably not going
to get profiles coming in tomorrow right
they're probably going to come in a
while later if they do so I be more
happy to charter up a new working group
to do the profiles that come in later
but on the advice document whatever yeah
if you can scare up enough people to get
some energy go for it otherwise I don't
see doing it in the current working
group will work okay so it's kind of the
last call for people if you want to
author such document you know please
start and contact you know but we need
an editor at least so if if you don't
raise your end soon then we may have no
more working group we may shut down the
working group right any other comment
before close okay thank you very much
Peter saint-andre the best way to work
on the advice document might be might be
to provide advice through expert reviews
of profiles and learn what the topics
are that would need to be covered so I
guess that's by way of saying that we
should wait on doing that too until we
have more experience with the existing
profiles and the new ones that are
requested I know some people that are
getting free that there would be very
good for doing so maybe I'd like to lay
via the document maybe we can we can we
be Japanese can as a Asia well i am
paper weekend provides some good
feedback for that but for a whole
structure we are not good at writing the
wrong document to win research if people
can move forward to it we can have
certain if it happy tising
freely decidedly she I'm sorry I chairs
a theater cross nice place and combine
human
it is not okay what was collected take a
train
you