Oh little should change that
triack stem
nothing is happening I mean this being
doesn't even react
maybe we can just dump let's see what
the secretary anyway Oh
yeah oh actually no it's on horse
we're some troubles with the projector
the last it crapped out so how does it
work you man because they were purchased
yet a man so they were projecting an
event get it yeah yeah i know i mean i
i'm not there before the first star yeah
i think it's a project
presentation oh yeah so um they were
replacing the rear tire just going to do
that like six minutes anytime so so I
took to see the last night he said
before getting somebody a movie
somebody please deposit right now
yes but me ideas right till this thing
we'll see
hey
so trying to say that exhalation that's
what i wouldnt in predicting from my
pantech so list
your computer seems to like it
yeah you can get likes it so
yeah there we go thank you
I think we need to connect it to normal
soon
you have to do that in the you got to do
that over there right don't close that
we just run through that right now
look like one ble Pacific next one
yeah this is do this okay welcome to the
ETA in the right place unless you've
sort of remaining here from the previous
session that I was quite entertaining so
I listened while we have a relatively
short agenda today so if you're good you
get to go home early still next slide
this for those who may not be a wise is
UTA flts or dog and our agenda is we're
going to spend a couple of minutes on on
them status update and and and a young
russian but not too much so since we met
last we have actually graduated progress
will progress the couple of regiments we
have our first document published
analysis or since 74 57 used to be eg a
FF draft is all done the TLS draft had
been at the disappearing left is some
it's in the editors q a couple minutes
left to do but it's that will soon that
gets sorted make some people and draft
is I
Georgia it is DQ we will actually have
him back 11 that but we expect that to
be problematic looking at is to talk to
us about mmm we are the Nexus TLS and
identity check procedures through email
alexa alexa up your that can just to
summarize the status that document them
right so i just posted 0 2 as you asked
which finish unterminated sentence x I'm
but the may change in 01 was splitting
instead of you know having requirements
and no different type of actors like
mail user client writers on ce
certificate authorities cetera in one
section I split them in two separate
sections and this actually caught one
error and I think I made the
requirements more consistent so I was a
bit skeptical before I did this but I
think it actually improves the document
and I think at this point it's stable
and should be ready for working with
Roscoe okay so let's get a quick
sensitive
read this draft okay so many of you guys
say anything about your having been real
draft on the money list it's something
we could just sort of pipe up in the
list say yes I read it it looks okay see
that I issue allocated blast coil in the
next couple of weeks but we really have
to get one or two more yes I whether it
looks okay reviews it doesn't you don't
actually have to find folks with the
bouquet because even if any doesn't mean
you have to find any fault with it it's
just okay is to say that you read it and
think it's it's done so actually pretty
good shape so I turn though the world
over to Chris I asked to remind
everybody that when representing you're
standing up front you're supposed to
stand in paint books on before
exactly fitting with the controls okay I
think we have microphone now okay i did
a revision of the draft it's now a
working group draft so so this is just
the overview of what's in the draft for
people who are part of our spectators
and haven't read it and if you haven't
read it yet I'd really like you to read
it because I want to get this done
relatively soon but this is the overview
of what's in the draft basically it's a
set of things with the intent of
improving confidentiality for the link
between the mail user agent and the
server this is not about mpa mkay relay
that's that's out of scope for this
document so this is the basic overview
moving on the changes I made to this
revision I i believe technical contents
largely complete we renamed the privacy
assurance to confidentiality assurance
and based on Russ's review I need to do
a little more wordsmithing about that
because that is the correct terminology
for what this is providing and Irene a
privacy assurance to no privacy
insurance as I did no confidentiality
assurance because I think that looks
better other words the sniffing it's now
a working group draft and I fold it in a
bunch of review comments from my
co-author Keith so to do I need to fall
fold in the comments that Russ made i
just i read all of them so i'll just
make them yell unless there are further
comments on that on those topics and i
need to add an explicit reference to the
pls bcp so those are the two items that
I definitely have and I'm a mitt and I'm
also inclined do a pass over to see if
it can improve readability and
approachability of the draft a little
bit moving on to the next slide so the
old issues so one of the open issues I
have an item to go gather deployment
data on port 465 versus 587 and I
haven't had time to gather that data yet
so basically right now the document is
recommending port 465 over 587 the
recommendation that ends up in the final
document should be backed by what's
actually deployed and I want to
understand the relative deployment of
port 465 versus 587 because yo if we go
with port 465 there are there are
process issues that make that that are
challenging so if if it's the case that
port five days at every isp that offers
port 465 also offers port 587 then I
think we should just go with port 587 to
avoid the process difficulties but we
need to gather that data so it does
anybody have cycles to gather data on
like significant ISPs and clients
support for these ports guessing not I
guess that stays on my plate and they'll
try to get it done as soon as possible
the next open issue this is one that
came up in a discussion Keith and I were
having and i wanted to i take this this
is a really interesting one for for the
group to discuss there's a design
trade-off in here where the current
spect the way it's written if you have a
no confidentiality assurance account set
up and it's not using TLS on that on
those connections and then suddenly the
server says wait a minute I'm now
offering TLS there is a model that the
current approach would I will try to use
TLS if it uses it if it can use it even
though the cert doesn't verify it will
it will latch on TLS so that it will
keep using TLS so the idea is you get
confidential yo if if the site wasn't
using TLS and then starts offering it
but without a valid sir it'll at least
get the passive protection so that's how
the current drafts written the downside
to this approach is there's an obvious
denial of service attack of your Joe asp
with no ssl and i insert a man middle
and say hey I'm offering SSL now
I want you to latch it on and then the
quiet latches it on and now you can't
connect your ISP anymore so there's a
denial of service attack against the
client with the model that's currently
in the draft the other approach is sorry
if the certain if the certain doesn't
validate we can't latch on SSL and so
we'll just do it in the clear yeah well
you're you're all your data will go in
the clear on that no confidentiality
assurance connections so that would
solve that one denial of service attack
but you lose you lose passive
confidentiality protection so I would
like input from the working group on
which of these two approaches they like
better as I think this is a really
interesting question
I would like to do that now we go to
face to face time like this year's me
yeah let's let you but yo get some
shorter distance was stated in please
lugar Leveson was gained considered for
detecting the presence of an ssl
certificate on a particular port and was
there any consideration about possibly
updating the auto configuration scheme
for indicating that a TLS certificate
should be available and should be
required so that you can have start TLS
trippin okay so right now well right now
this doesn't have very much very many
references to Dane so there is a yo if
you have a Dane validated certificate
that's not Pete expel dated that's
supported in the current in the current
document I've had some open issues for a
while where I where if someone
contributes text I'd be I'd be
interested in possibly filling that text
in so for the service setup part of the
document I've got I I explain how to use
the existing SRV set up to do a count
set up and there
there is a way to extend that to
leverage Dane and if somebody added
provided text for me to add to the
document to do that I would most likely
be supportive of adding that text
independent IDs but but yeah that's
independent of this particular problem
that i'm raising so anyway if you have
if you want more dean support in the
document submit text to the lists of
what you would like added to the
document so the idea of using gain was
to detect when the certificate was
changed to avoid this denial of service
problem once the certificate has been
pinned to the imap connection in h st s
fashion the other idea was indicating
that TLS was mandatory in the SRV record
somehow so my email account setup works
as you look at the SRV record only once
and you don't generally don't look at it
again so these so that's why the HST s
style account indicator is in the
protocol with with this draft it's not
you know it's dead done in the protocol
the same way it's done in HD hit p but
you know map to the email model so no
we're not where I I did not think of
doing a chest es approach in using the
DNS cuz I know and I mean the main
reason I don't think that's very
interesting is right now it's hard it's
very hard to get your hands on dnf sec
in a deployment so you know I certainly
have I can't like I cannot write DNS
software i cannot get access to servers
to test it on sorry
in my head I'm thinking through the
scenario of if you can stipulate in DNS
system that a server supports TLS then a
client should presumably only connect to
the line how do you write have you read
the draft no no I would I please do read
the draft and you know and section 8 has
the discussion of the SRV yellow account
setup model in the draft and it has some
discussion of advertising SSL in there
and the documented references also has
discussion of that so occasionally that
see if it meets your needs and if not it
yo let let's see some suggestions for
text improve the document I appreciate
that thanks David lump under stand on
your answer I don't think they can
currently indicate that there must be a
zazzle available I think it can only
refer to the certificate to be used and
authenticate that but that's that's a
bit that's missing from Dana and I think
that needs to be added so I kind of
support the question and I think someone
wants to go today and at that as a
separate capability but it's not there
as far as in hell yeah I'm generally
keeping that I so far generally kept
this very loosely coupled the Dane I
think what's in here is mostly
complementary to what day is doing yeah
acute oh yeah I like I learnt gained in
principle although I think that without
bnsf basically you just create a
different set of security holes and so
it
getting dns i deployed is pretty to be
quite difficult or slow at least I think
I guess you know my feeling is if we get
a reliable indication from the server
that it now supports pls and will
continue to do so then it's reasonable
to trust that and reliable means that
it's coming over a TLS encrypted and
authenticated connection with a
certificate that we trust and that we
have we sort of trust axiomatically and
the question I have is how do we know
when that's good enough for that purpose
and I don't know that I have the answer
because they're this sort of lots of
little corner cases there but what's
your thinking about that well I mean I I
think that case is not controversial yo
if if you can validate the server cert
and the search says I support pls with
cert validation in the session you latch
it on your done I think that's already
covered at the current test the part
that I i think is open to change is the
part where okay I I've been talking to
the account there's there's been no TLS
at all all of a sudden see ok I can now
do TLS with the server and the server I
can't very validate the sir the cert
doesn't validate but I can get an
encrypted cut so that I have at least
passive confidentiality and then the
server says by the way I I am do I am
offering TLS but not offering cert valid
certs and I'm doing this indefinitely so
the question is when that scenario
happens should the client latch on and
insist on TLS in the future even though
the cert doesn't validate or should the
client just use it for that
session and then the next time if
there's no TLS sorry you get no
confidentiality those are the two
options I think it's a really
interesting question I'm not sure we'll
actually that's what you should do yeah
this is Peter's naked so validated the
search I think it's the opportunistic
case and the answer is next time you
arrive wherever because you can't tell
who you've been talking to the next time
you arrive if it's clear text only and
TLS is not available maybe you were
talking to something bad actor last
already got the TLS i will just continue
to do the opportunistic though of if the
TOS is available use it not don't don't
latch because you don't know who the bad
actor in this play is that clear text I
or the TLS die it could be a denial of
service attack by inserting TLS during
the session that you saw it well I you
know that's the argument for that side
so I'll make the argument for the other
approach the other coach is I yo if my
service provider can't you know for some
reason can try sir but he can get TLS on
the server I would rather have passive
confidentiality than in the clear and
you know an active attacker can always
get me so so that's fine and so I'd
actually you know and in the case where
active attacker starts yo pretending to
be the sober and saying I want you to I
want you to turn on TLS and require it
I'm actually okay with a dial of service
attack because the customer will call
the isp and say why don't i have writer
hype i have any confidentiality all of a
sudden and so i write the pressure on
the ISPs too young to roll out proper
encryption that that introduces so
that's that's sort of the the trade up
so keep more again I think one of the
things that occurs to me I think app
insert is a trusted certain that it's
axiomatic Lee trusted just as much as
one from a trusted signed by trusted CA
yeah i think if you get a latch
declaration from the server that says we
support this feature from a pin search
that you should trust that equally as
you trust one whatever i think if you
don't have that but the pincer is
something that's explicit configuration
so just because he's seen a server
advertise a cert before doesn't mean a
thing and you should you should
basically it's always fine to try to
negotiate TLS but it's not fine to trust
whatever that server says it's an
indication in the future and the thing
that concerns me is maybe you have bad
actors that advertise this feature and
that's basically done as a way to get
people to turn this feature off in their
user agents and that I think that's kind
of what happens when people don't
understand it's like well let's just
revert to the
behavior because it will probably be
there supported in the user agent and it
doesn't cause the support calls so one
way or another I think that's what tends
to happen so I'd rather I would actually
own balance rather not trust it I also
think it's simpler that way it's easy to
describe in a way that's likely be
implemented correctly you're on chef
thought and so first of all and you use
the term passive security you don't get
passive security if in fact you trust
the certificate and on the other hand
unfortunately you can get an incorrect
certificate from mid boxes so not just
active men in the middle attackers which
on balance I think would mean that if
for example if you normally deploy your
client behind the coffee shop access
point or an airport access point you're
vulnerable to this kind of so-called
attack so unfortunately you cannot latch
in these cases the question maybe it's
just that you wish I mean if you will
feel good terrace even if it doesn't
write a bit you still can decrypt this
is but don't latch don't change anything
there's a question of do we want to buy
a to latch on encryption without
authentication so you know passive
production yo yo and what I'm hearing so
far is no we don't want a way to do that
in this in this instance
if that's the rough consensus what I say
you do / to mystically you clicked
opportunistically but you don't play
with their lunches in this case that's
what I'm yeah okay stupor and so yeah
it's tricky go I I mean would it make
sense to latch for a short period he was
so in the case where you have a provider
who has a sensor or something like that
right and your pattern is priority that
you're going to pick up mail every day
or something maybe at least people piece
of email yes yell varies from every
every few days to every five minutes all
right well so it's put it in Super Bowl
that i only talk to every week or
something then it's probably okay to not
much but you need any weddings or
whatever it is you want a photo op you
may as well do that from that case but
if you if you like just for a day that's
a or something then you don't fall prey
to the coffee shop if you pick up your
mail before a large kind of expires
right on the denial of services that
just prefer day when I'd say I'm not
sure it works but really investing can
wait but i don't think i could write
that in a dog even in a way that i think
would be implemented well that's costly
because it's just actually be something
like you'd be recommending a lunchtime
today or something for for subside
services so do you want
they can start formulating I'm question
froze yeah let's hear what keith has to
say I say I think the main danger of the
thing that you want is you want to
upgrade to confidentiality when you can
but you also want to minimize the number
of support calls that result from this
neck admit so that's the trade off a few
like that anything that's kind of hard
for support people to predict like
here's the timer going off on this
laptop or whatever I feel like that
actually makes a support situation worse
and yeah I would lean against it for
that reason so that's permalink so the
on either hand I you know I kind of
quite a few my servers that do have
certificates that are verifying that are
okay well well the thing I remember I'm
mua holy so MTA relay it's a completely
different in every message stories but
Tiger is pop servers and submitting
services she does it there's quite a
bunch of those that don't have good
service as far as i understand i'm not
aware of that as a major problem i would
if there is data on your submission I
map and pop servers with invalid certs I
would like to see that data because my
understanding is that is generally the
certs are fine on all three of those and
this is actually surprising the nation's
get some producers who then this is
surprising because submission servers
there's actually zero require
in any of our published standards to
validate the cert in any way which is
why the things I want to fix David I
mean I thought it was a bit more coming
but if it's less common than I think
maybe not watching it's probably the
right so it feels like been been going
back shedding this so okay let me try
the hum question so the the first prom
will be if you believe we should upgrade
but we should latch passive defense only
when we see TLS but can't validate the
sir so yes you and the second will be
the opposite of weed we don't latch
passionately TLS those ones where both a
rival any more information yeah end of
their adoption okay so the first column
which is upgrade from those security to
pass a defense their businesses laughs
it off reactions are that's big leche
and we can do ok so the lap shock option
option I'm going to come slightly
because because I was proposing in your
hangar sir left actually I'm in charge
so now hon if do not want to lunch
and education here
the best against infection land no
discharges you mentioned HST s yes
there's models of that you know similar
model there's a section on using cell
signed cert in conjunction with hsps and
RFC 6 7 97 which basically says you got
to distribute route certs to your users
boxes because we kill the connection if
it's unauthenticated okay i'll go read
that text and add and see if if there's
something i can pick up and adapt as
part of this change the same time just
finishing the loop on the hum to be
clear anybody who thinks we're totally
broken and things are really bad if we
choose that don't latch option speak up
right now it's not a preference but
we're really broken if we do it that way
but thank you for asking that question
and I forgot to ask it I just okay
moving down I this is question I want to
ask so the mandatory implements cipher
in the I'm at base spec is our essay rc4
sha-1 120 this is mandatory to implement
for interoperability the current text i
have in this draft says you know we're
not changing that it's mandatory to
implement but you can turn it off by
default
in I should I be stronger about getting
about changing that as in should I say
ok the I maps back has now changed that
cipher suite is no longer mandatory to
implement the Nana Tori to implement fri
map is now the tls 12 cipher the bcp
recommends Shawn Turner yes updated
please ah Alexei I want to hear what you
have to say this yes implementations are
using standard libraries so they use
whatever is bundled so although an app
doesn't recommend using TLS 1.2 I assume
a lot of clients and so as actually do
in practice so I don't see a problem
with updating this is very bottom line
is what this really means is advice to
the library maintainer well it's
actually because it's in the imap stack
it advice to imap implementers when
selecting which library and version to
you yes i'm not i'm not sure i need
given the comments i got caramel site
like i'll just change it ok the next
bullet is a improved document
organization actually their question yet
so I'm just I'm up don't you run till
date those three to be the same ok so
submission
not have a mandatory to implement i
believe so it inherits what's in the TLS
one to base back as it's mandatory to
implement and i believe that i'm not
sure what pop3 does I I don't remember I
don't know I just I just make all the
free the same so you could actually want
me to explicitly update all three
documents to set a mandatory to
implement to what the bcp sets this is
people a recommendation from the
security folk is the other choice is to
go in the other direction and say you
dereference whatever TLS says to be
that's what you want to do and so they
get out of line now specifically and say
what's man for you it is written over
there don't look over there does that
make sense I meant actually activities
to say it's mandatory with this
particular cipher suite you want to
reference the you Toby CPM and that will
get updated as it goes well you're not
specified ok actually Saudi so what I
want to do is make an update to expect
deleting the mandatory to impress i
implement cipher from there
spec and replacing it with the current
of reference to the current PCP yeah I'm
job will be if I could that's okay if I
see something about the first bullet
sure can we finish this section so I'm
analytical ability quizzes kind of
Indian Chris I think that the the spec
of the requirement for the MTI on 1.2 in
the email deep specs is its TLS RSA with
aes-128 cbc shop what the Utah PCP draft
says GCM should we make those two the
same yeah yeah I was good it was on my
to do on the previous scientist his
reference the BCT properly house
assistant Coakley textual reference to
disappear yes good hey so we closed out
for that one I moved back to work post
five yeah editor has as sufficient
advice and and will execute gmail yahoo
AOL comcast do support port 465 hotmail
does not and I think that as we go as
you scale that I think you're going to
find more less the same thing the
majority of providers do support for 65
years balls everybody 587 oh yeah I
think I think I think you're going to
discover that all in the drug the
majority of people support for 65 it's
going to be considerable pain by the
minority but this up for the Civil maroc
minority don't so these so you're saying
the data is that anybody who has
465 also has 587 yes with start TLS yes
if that is what you're saying that
suggests data supports a a change in the
draft yo and so one of the reasons the
draft has written the current way is its
kind of architectural II Queen to say yo
for imap pop and submit we prefer the
separate court because that's deployed
but what we're going to have to what I'm
going to have to change to is prime F
and pop we prefer the separate port
because if you survey the providers the
separate court I'm f and pop that yo
anytime my map start TLS and pop star
TLS are available two separate court is
also available but the other is not true
you can find providers with a separate
court but not start healing what and
significant you know but if the opposite
is true of SMD p suggestion then then
then it makes the spec more more
complicated to write number strictly
don't although that is a tiny survey
that's probably that's food with the
majority of mailboxes in this content so
it's sort of it it's an interesting it's
interesting setup written yeah I'm going
to try to do a slightly bigger survey
but I really appreciate that and if you
if you know somebody who might be able
to get me data on a slightly bigger data
set I really appreciate the past my more
abilities if they have but they have the
lying around okay great thank you very
much
I think there were more reasons besides
just deployment that a separate court
seemed to make more sense and I say that
is the the inventor of stock pls but I
don't necessarily recall what they were
i feel like the issue with a separate
quarters originally if you try to sort
of do opportunistic upgrades you've got
some vulnerabilities there but is long
as you have things latched then I think
the separate port is actually better so
i think the desirable end state is that
we use the separate board for these
things and we eventually deprecated use
of the of the unencrypted board so
either why i would like to avoid
declaring the desirable in state to be
you start us for a submission yeah
there's some controversy because i heard
both sides i'm relatively neutral on
this point I although I actually do feel
fairly strongly about the text in the
current document that says we should
register port 465 as a port that has
dual use in the wild and I know the
registry folks won't like that
but but I I'm a believer in reality / /
process so steam from a big piece issue
and yeah I'm back to mandatory to
implement all right sorry I'm not
entirely remembering what the be speed
the generic PCP says but I think it has
like a few because we're talking about
TLS in the board it has some
recommendations but also says there's
these other side / suites that are still
only two or if you're in this situation
you might want to do that catering for
like you know the job environment which
have the short diffie-hellman values and
so on right I think in this case we
don't we don't have to be so constrained
so I think you can say here you can
study weapons if it's not quite to say
pointed the bcp you want to say 22 bcp
and use the propeller beside for sweets
is the miniature right i saw a
discussion about that on another draft
and so I was going to prefer to the
cipher suites in this section are the
part of the mandatory to implement but I
think in this case you can kind of tie
it down very very tightly for right for
these programs so Alexi said it's 73 you
can pick one I think it's you think you
can't do here Polly ok did you know who
says I'm you know that the future oceans
and
he's gonna make those distinctions or
have those so it makes sense since for
simplicity is key reference to the
reference when we update to disappear
yeah neither have we don't necessarily
grant you so the bcp doesn't have some
things that are probably not ideal we
probably don't want to have those coming
in here if it's feasible to let up so
you're exactly what we're doing we use I
don't really care of it you know just
point out the best bits of the bcp not
that the ones you have to live it so I
keep working I feel like the thing with
the cipher suites is if you tie this to
some external document that can change
then you might actually break in or
ability when that set of cipher Suites
changes and you'll have skew between one
implementation and other about which
things they implement so I actually
think that the time unit you're going to
have a binding of those things you
should bind to a specific document not
to you know like a bcp number or
something like that and even though we
realize these recommendations will
change over time that has to be
propagated back to the application
protocol specs yeah I must buy anything
that really matters the way we do
references the reference will point to a
specific RFC not the bcp general yeah
okay yes this has been very helpful so
okay any more on the first three bullets
I am oh you got one
saw something move yeah so I will not
just to add about the start TLS versus
the register port and whether it's which
one of them and better adorable
distraction so whatever case matures in
the end I just think that it needs to be
written in the document in what sequence
the client should do these things and
the server should do things because
otherwise we'll just add more ability
problems to whatever we have my hair
already just the general engineering
thing thank you yeah what I may try to
do on that is to write the text for both
which of course involves the sequencing
text and then we'll see how much we hate
that text and if we want to actually go
for that yo tune towards one
okay moving on to the fourth bullet
there has been some controversy on the
list about document or court
organization and clearly and so I mean I
by the way the documents currently
structured is I came up with a set of yo
yo there are a set of ideas that all
move towards the same goal I wrote them
roughly in the order I thought of thug
and then I tried to and then I moved
from around to try to eliminate forward
references so that's the current
document organization I will not pretend
that as an algorithm to get an ideally
readable document so I am open to
suggestions on reordering sections in
the document and restructuring it to try
to make it clearer my request on this
topic is that the as that the term bcp
not be used as part of this discussion
I'm okaying various organizations but i
don't but i don't think bcp is a
constructive categorization mechanism
partly because you can talk to two
different IETF people and get two
different thoughts on what should go in
and bcp and what shouldn't so I'd like
to have this discussion at the level of
can we put this section before a disc
session and one of the things I wanted
to point out
Russ actually made some suggestions on
reordering sections that I thought made
sense to me and I'll just do them so
anyway I wanted to invite suggestions to
improve the organization it did anyone
want to have additional comments on that
topic or shall we just continue
discussing that on the list just because
would a choice of any male in this
discussion so so looking at business
that dokument tries to the bdcp remember
others who might waste and discarding
the plug-in today
about to go bad I personally find it
interesting if somebody would comment on
them describe about the draft saying
this is how it is done in election today
may not represent the best compact
package all right and that's a separate
thing that's a completely enslaved
somebody has information out there about
the employment experience high hopes
high security interesting to get that
some of that down on paper that's not
what you're trying to do right yeah so
good so I am this documents focused on
the MUA to server Hawks you know pop
IMAP and submission only but the MTA
relay hot too hot model is different and
is very different and broken and there's
some sort of de facto agreements
happening out there right now in the
wild but you know I can tell you my
involvement with service providers as a
mail server engineer is that yo service
providers are having to wire up special
one-to-one agreements for certificate
validation right now because the
standard there is nothing written down
that's clear enough about how to
validate certs and if you do write
something you have to write well you can
validate this way which is secure but a
lot of sites don't do that so you have
to validate it this way which is not
secured properly and so the current
practice is there is no
Oh active attacker protection for MTA
MTA Hawks right now when hit bottom line
except ones that have been specifically
configured interesting for tough
congenital okay yeah they've had a
description of that
draft out on its Witt has UTA in the
title it's an individual submission I
think Friedel is the author and that's
trying to start it start to work on the
MP a 2 MP a hump in so he I gave him
some feedback on that and you know
hopefully that's something that can come
into this group as a separate working
item soon ok so that was I think the end
of my slides although they just went
black oh yeah I'm working group specific
document text suggestions I'm open to
anything you know that now is the time
to get them done because the technical
content is yo other than the issues we
just discussed pretty you know pretty
close to done so any other topics on
this document actually when asked could
we have yours run
how about concussion or any version of
the draft okay let's do that so I'm I
would very much like to see a couple and
somebody who volunteered to reminisce
just to even if it's just to say then
it's okay or it's looking to event that
I can somebody went in to get a cup of
mojitos to commit to doing this slide
back to the first screen passes the
tests I tell pj you may may be simple
today to talk about helps us for them
David anytime shrim is going to end I'm
gonna volunteer last time they do it so
i actually did read it I sense
email yet Chris can you explain maybe
you know I'm completely forgetting
someone explain it well but say a client
latches on 1.1 and the TLS 1.2 so the
server says hey I'd you can put one and
only in it Clyde latches the surrogates
upgrading because 1.2 when does the
client when is it able to upgrade to 1.2
ok so with the latching model yeah well
first so that there isn't a one point
where unlatched yeah I didn't see Nolan
implement in here right yeah suppose you
have 10 laps but the 10 latch needs is
the server has made a commitment to
support TLS 10 or later that's what the
latch means ok so i skipped that part
okay sorry so as soon as the server so
what happens if when 10 gets we find out
that groups that's not so hot anymore we
want to get rid of back and they want to
update to like 1.3 or whatever and don't
do anything it's below whatever version
so so there's a 12 latch right right now
and when 13 comes out we can go see what
the relapse but the client so book for
the clients and so basic
what happens if there's if the if the
server says I'm offering 12 and I want
you to lash it then the client will lash
it I assuming it successfully negotiates
12 invalidates the sir no no I'm just
going through my head that I want to
review the job to make sure that that's
clear because I want to make sure that
as we get newer versions that it's like
oh that's what I'm yes yeah I'm of
course you know deep in the implementing
and I've been doing emails and since you
know the the late 80s so I am yo I have
no pretend that this is the clearest
document it could be so I right now I'm
quite open to clarity improvement
honestly when I read it I was like it's
pretty good I mean like it's kind of on
point it was clear there were some
questions that you had in the back of us
should we put this out do all that I was
like man it seems like more work for you
so we should try to keep it easier on
the document offers this is people make
the same coin which organs I don't
remember but does the client have the
option to say I don't accept one of
laches cuz I don't know it was screwed
up right I think the idea is is they're
going to come a point where we write a
bcp that says deal us you're always hose
you should not use it anymore it's as
bad as using bad bogan crypto
and Clarence should say I don't watch or
10 even if you tell me to is that it is
a possibility in what you're ready well
I mean cert certainly if a DCP says
don't use 10 then then when you've set
the 10 laps whatever meat is actually
negotiate 12 that's what the lash would
need in that case because that because
the latch is defined as one or later now
I'm making an assumption here that we
won't release a subsequent TLS version
that's worse than the previous version I
hate that assumption is correct
otherwise the design is Rob right or the
other thing is that you know TLS Forks
in such a way that the version numbers
are no longer linear but there's some
other facility besides TLS that you
might want to start using and then
everything is latched Els will sort of
need to walk back up and do something
else and we're not necessarily planning
for that I mean that's why there's a
registry of tags so we actually I think
we did plan for that because you can
define you new latch tags in future yeah
this area envisioning is the server
supports 1.3 and then somewhere down the
line some other technology becomes
favored and I mean with the clients of
all rushed 13 and we'd have to define
the latches in such a way that it's like
you know X Y Z 1 point 0 and actually
greater than or equal to TLS 1.3 yeah
I um have on this I think it's about
right so tons like um lots of inputs are
all emotion and i get home version as
soon as possible some reviews about this
coolness so we have a commitment for
review from david did we have a
commitment for review social alone oh
absolutely thanks i really appreciate
the reviews and i'm going to i'm going
to start trying to chase down quiet
authors mail client authors and get them
to review that we weren't so if anybody
has contacts at their company with mail
client authors i would appreciate
comments from them because there's
always the problem in the email space of
most of the specs or written by server
event yo server engineers and the plan
so i intend you no input from client
engineers it's hard to find so any help
in getting that input i really
appreciate us at the end of a agenda we
have connect um as you can all see
yourself
approaching the you can sorta see me
under the light at the end of the tunnel
for this working group is that chocolate
there is one item that we haven't
progressed and that's some sort of
general advice of opportunistic sir cage
for TLS it's cooler out of conversation
with Stephen I don't know if you can
speak to this topic Stephen but is that
cool to any of us that we even know what
the problem is and have to formulate
anything I was so but some things that
they understand that any kind of general
they realize
elastic security forgive us and feel
that way comes or describe that problem
well feel free to do so but I have to
have to have seen some for somebody to
come in a limpet to us and what right
drafts about Service over security to
chase somebody round to do that after
that we're not seeing each other on to
work for local group if you smoke that
molecular should take on now's the time
to go home and try to sort of pen to
paper and suggest work in the final
drafts this is a black time so this is
Pete just the organizational stuff since
we've been talking before the meeting so
I'm stepping down as a wednesday
normally I would just transfer stuff
over to Barry since I don't have a
replacement but where the process of
doing a little bit of iesg
reorganization one of the things we did
was make it possible to have a directors
that are not in the area be responsible
for the group I think it's still useful
to have this is an absurd a regular
because we want to encourage
applications people to be looking at
this that it's for them
it sounds like Stephen is running to be
the irresponsible I am irresponsible
area director for the working group
going forward so lightly at the next
week when a little shuffle those on
Stephen will end up with his name on the
data tracker for the responsible AED and
there is a word document and publication
requested which magically become siemens
problem instead of mon-sol
reconfirmation formation by wednesday of
ever will see if I'm very motivated in
these next day or barrier one of us will
do the ad evaluation point it will get
it unstuck you know goal in the process
so then we question the comments about
that bad that's pretty much what we're
planning at this point there could
always be changes but that's what were
thinking honest most of us have any
shoes our boy runs I believe
maybe 50 break that was actually better
use space
directly trying to specify
actually
interesting
I think this is for making sure that
contaminates come fix insecurity or
groups Bethel at which
Thomas
rustle up those from Cass guys
you