[Music]
I'm here I can 66 in Montreal Canada
with members of the 2020 nominating
committee or NomCom jason ascii ola
jacobson and him and Ashcraft j can you
explain the role that i'm come yeah the
NomCom has a very important role within
the i cant ecosystem many nonprofit
organizations have a concept of a
nominating committee but the way i can
does its NomCom is very different than a
typical nominating committee and it's
reflective of the multi-stakeholder
model and the practices and the
importance that of things that are
happening here at ICANN so all all
members are all parts of the community
within i can g NSO c so a lack the ASO
technical even the CAC has it has a
option to participate within the NomCom
so our entire committee consists of over
20 members who get together and meet
face to face four times over the course
of the year to recruit new candidates
for open leadership positions do
candidate assessment work and then make
our final selections and present them to
the community at the 2020 AGM Olli what
are the board positions I need to be
filled by the 2020 comm this year there
is two positions for the ICANN board and
one position for the PTI board Jay how
was the 2020 timeline different than
2019 and how is that new timeline
advantageous yes so there's a major
difference with the timeline this year
historically the NomCom application
window has opened in January and closed
at the end of March this year we're
changing the application window said
that it will open in mid December and it
will close in mid-february the reason
why we're doing this is it will allow us
to come to I can 67 and begin our
candidate assessment work
face to face which provides much higher
quality work and and allows the
committee to be much more effective one
of the other benefits of moving the
timeline up is that we'll also be able
to do full committee interviews of
candidates for gns Ola
in CC NSO which is a new thing that the
NomCom is doing this year historically
only the deep dive teams a team of two
or three members have have interviewed
candidates for those positions Damon
what are the other leadership positions
and why do they offer great
opportunities to get involved sure the
other leadership positions include two
for the at-large Advisory Committee or a
lack and those are there's one position
out of a two for a North American
candidate and one position out of a two
for a European candidate in addition to
that we also have a position on the
generic name supporting organization or
gns oh and also a position for the CC
NSO or country code name supporting
organization and those are those
positions are very important because I
can is a bottom-up model and so a lot of
the positions within the a lack the CC
NSO and the G NSO are helping to develop
built the policies or comment on the
policies and give guidance for the
overall organization and for the board
to consider Olli can you tell us what
the NAM comes work on transparency
accountability and the ongoing efforts
to be in the forefront sure so starting
a few years ago the NomCom has been
publishing progress reports what's new
this year that will also do publish our
operational procedures and voting
documents so that everything that we do
apart from information about the
candidates of course which is
confidential will be available to the
public and also blog posts and various
updates of that of that nature
J considering how diverse the ICANN
community is what is being done to
ensure a diverse pool of candidates we
took a number of measures on the NomCom
to ensure that we do have a diverse pool
of candidates last year the NomCom
started partnering with multiple global
and regional computing firms and this
year we're going to continue that
practice so in the process of selecting
those firms currently this will allow us
to target regions that have historically
been underrepresented in leadership
positions within I can we also in
general have a high level of diversity
within the NomCom itself and we ask our
members on the committee to go and
recruit people for the open leadership
positions through their networks so just
from that first year we get
a lot of exposure globally and helps
drive diversity well gentlemen thank you
for joining me today and talking about
the 2020 NomCom thank you
[Music]