hi I'm Takashi this is a short abstract
video for this work
non-interactive real marriage nivik is
the protocol to improve validity of some
statement without revealing anything
beyond its validity in a non-attractive
way
we require music to satisfy completeness
soundness and their knowledge property
it is easy to see that lyrics for
non-trivial languages are impossible in
the playing model so we have to rely on
some track and set up in this work we
focus analytics for qma with classical
verification here qma is the content
version of NP or M A or we are witness
and verification can be condemned even
though we consider such content
languages we require that the
verification can be done graphically
which is a highly non-trivial property
the ultimate goal is to construct
classically verifiable lyrics for qma in
the common reference string model
so first there's only a heuristic
contraction and no known construction
from standard assumptions thus existing
Works rely on stronger setup models than
the common referencing model the
motivation of this work is to find new
trade-offs among assumptions security
and models for classically Revival
musics for qma
in this verb we give three constructions
of classical review fire genetics for
qma with incomparable features I will
explain them one by one
the first contraction is in the content
secret parameter model in this model the
drafted party first sends a Content
proven key and classical verification
key to the further and verifier
respectively after the setup the program
non-interactively generate a classical
proof we proved that our contraction
32-5 both statistical soundness and
statistical view knowledge without
assuming any assumption not that this is
a variant of the navic by broadband and
griddle or where the proven key is
classical but the proof is content
the second construction only requires
the traffic fit app to generate your
common reference string but the fire has
to send some instant independent Quantum
information to the pluriver as a setup
after this setup the prerection
non-interactively generated classical
proof we show that our contraction has a
dual mode property under the LW
assumption that it there are two
computational indistinguishable modes
one is The Binding mode where it started
to find such statistical soundness and
the computational zero knowledge and the
other is the hiding mode where it
satisfied the computational was handlers
and the statistical knowledge
not that the mother and assumption are
exactly the same as those of Kola danger
Vedic and gen where they constructed
lyrics with computational soundness and
the computation of their knowledge
they left it open to make either of them
statistical and we solve this open
problem
the third contraction is in the Bell
pair model where the proverb and
verifier share entanglement as a setup
the better pair model is often regarded
as a Quantum analog of the common
reference string model
our construction satisfied computational
soundness and computational the marriage
in the content random worker model this
answers an open question of brother
banter and the guerrillo who asked if we
can contract nivex for qma in the very
pair model
this is a comparison table among
constructions of classical liver fiber
netix for qma for more detail please
attend my talk at aviacrypt thanks