hi I'm anxious and I'm briefly introduce
our new paper Compact and typically
select the opening skill publicly
encryption schemes this is join work
with judging Pine
and in the PK setting we have a receiver
and a receiver have a publicly and
secret key the send we have a lot of
centers and they can use the public key
to increase the message with some
Randomness and then send a cyber text to
the receiver
we consider setting that now to send us
Randomness and message will be revealed
to some anniversary and because the
adversary get the message and Randomness
it can completely break the security of
the cyber attacks uh we say a cyber text
is open it is Randomness and message are
both revealed
so now some server texts are open and we
will ask how about the unopened cyber
text to the unopened subtext remain
secure
and the sender select open security
consider such setting or shorten it so
security
in the SEO security the adversary gets a
bunch of Chinese sub attacks and it can
also open some of the child in sub
attacks the so security requires that
the unopened Child Services remains
secure so security is a very practical
notion for example sometimes the
sender's computer may be crafted by some
hacker and the hacker can get all the
information about the sender including
messages and the renderness or the
sender can use some maybe use some
insecure Randomness generator and the
rosary can recover the such insecure
randomness
The Selective open security has been
studied for a long time and it can date
back to the 1999
um there are two flavors of iso security
notion indistinguished ability base and
Social Security and the simulation based
as Social Security or shortlist same as
so Security in this work we just focus
on the same so security
in terms of that the same as of security
is strictly stronger than the standard
pke security notion like the indcca
and it's highly contribute to achieved
same as so security because there's a
dilemma if we want to in you want to
prove security we we should invest some
problem instance into the Cyber text but
if we embed the instance to the Cyber
text then we can open the server text
because we do not have the randomness
and for example one way one may wonder
if we can use the hybrid argument plus
an idcc to achieve the same as of
security
this such hybrid argument doesn't work
because if we want to use the hybrid
argument to switch the charge ciphertext
to random then we can open the Cyber
text
and of course there's a true solution to
deal with such problems we just guess
which cyber test will not be open by the
adversary but this solution is not very
good because there's some value
probability
since the reduction may get strong and
it leads to some non-ti security
so we ask can we have SIM socc scheme
with high security the answer is yes but
it's not very satisfactory
um some group based same Associates with
Thai security they have a long time tax
or long public key
long public key means that the group at
the number of group elements in the
public key is not a constant it depends
on the length of the message
and long cyber text similarly
the drawbacks that the non-compact pke
they have a very high uh very high
communication overhead
so in this one we want to solve this
problem can we have a SIM socc scheme
such that they actually achieves the
Thai security compact publicly and
compact subjects at the same time and we
find this problem is very hard and we
want to relax some requirements
how about in the random Oracle model can
we have such steam in a random Oracle
model
our paper give a positive answer to this
question we propose three direct
constructions in the genetic
construction they are all compact
entirely same SOC skill in the random
Oracle model
um there are some techniques used in our
paper but I'm not going to introduce
them there and our full talk will be
given in the Thursday morning and thank
you for attention we also thank vanity
Wagner for his helpful comments