I'm Andrew Morgan and this is the short
video abstract version of my Asia Crypt
2022 presentation on concurrently
composable non-interactive secure
computation
non-interactive secure computation or
nisk refers to two-party secure
computation with minimal round
complexity that is two single message
rounds where only one party the receiver
receives the output from a protocol
we focus on fully malicious security
where intuitively an adversary with full
control over one of the parties even
having the ability to deviate
arbitrarily from the protocol should
learn nothing about the honest party's
input besides what they could infer from
the output of the computation we
formalize this as simulation-based
security where an adversary's view of
the real execution of the protocol
should be indistinguishable from the
review of an idealized execution where
messages are simulated independently of
inputs while a trusted third-party
computes the functionality
in fact nisk with malicious Security in
the play model is well known from
standard assumptions though we note that
a relaxation to Super polynomial time
simulation is required to circumvent a
classical impossibility result and
Achieve security with fewer than four
rounds
in our work however we investigate the
achievability of stronger Notions of
security specifically to intuitive
desert rather that are not provided by
classical definitions of
simulation-based security are
composability or a guaranteed at
security of a composition of protocols
can be based on the security of its
components and concurrency a guaranteed
that security of a protocol still holds
when many instances can be run
concurrently and an adversary might try
to adaptively use the views of certain
instances to break others
the first notion of security to consider
and provide both guarantees is the
universal composability or UC framework
introduced by kinety in 2001 which
requires security against an environment
able to invoke many instances of a
protocol and control Communications and
interactions of multiple corrupted
parties in those instances
furthermore there exists an analog of
super polynomial time simulation for UC
security known as angel-based or
oracle-aded UC security that preserves
both the composability and concurrency
guarantees specifically it allows the
simulator and environment both access to
a super polynomial helper Oracle or
Angel but otherwise restricts them to
polynomial time
of course since UC security is strictly
stronger than Standalone security it has
historically been far more difficult to
prove the existence of UC secure
computation protocols and especially of
ground efficient UC secure protocols
while the theoretical minimum of two
rounds was achieved for Standalone
Security even prior to our results
the best known protocols for
concurrently secure two-party
computation even table and composability
run in two simultaneous broadcast rounds
and would thus require three single
message rounds and the best known UC
secure protocol runs in a large
unspecified constant number of rounds
thus the question has remained open can
we achieve concurrently composable
non-interactive or two-round secure
computation with malicious SPS Security
in the plane model our work answers this
question in the affirmative we construct
and prove the security of nisk with
Oracle aided UC Security based on two
underlying assumptions
a standalone SPS secure nisk protocol
which we augment to achieve UC security
by using a non-interactive tag-based
commitment scheme which satisfies CCA
security a strengthened notion of hiding
analogous to chosen ciphertext security
for encryption
in my full talk I'll focus on presenting
our main serum our construction of a UC
secure nisk protocol And discussing at a
high level how does sub-components
combine to achieve the strengthened
notion of security
additionally I'll discuss the
requirement of non-interactive CCA
secure commitments which are thus far
known only based in relatively complex
assumptions and highlight our second key
result which demonstrates that in fact
non-interactive CCA secure commitments
can be constructed based on uc's secure
nisk hence showing that these
commitments are both sufficient and
necessary for UC secure nisk or in other
words to the assumptions for a
construction are essentially minimal
while details of the construction
improve of the second result are out of
scope for my talk I'll conclude by
noting that they along with the complete
construction and proof of the Mis
protocol can be found in our paper