hi everyone and Welcome to our video
abstract about decryption failures and
the fujizaki okamoto transformation
this was joint work with Andreas ruizing
and Christian Mayans we were motivated
by taking another look at how post
Quantum key encapsulation mechanisms
were built during the standardization
process for post Quantum secure crypto
what all of these key encapsulation
approaches had in common was that they
shared the same recipe how to turn
passively Secure Public key encryption
into actively secure key encapsulation
mechanism
this recipe by now is quite well known
it's the fujizaki okamoto transformation
that was recently Revisited at TCC in
2017.
and the revisiting happened to allow for
um public encryption schemes where
decryption sometimes fail which can
happen for example for letters or
code-based schemes and the revisiting
also considered different rejection
methods
meaning methods of how to deal with
ciphertexts that do not look well formed
one approach is to Simply during the
encapsulation answer with a dedicated
rejection symbol like bottom the other
approach is to hide and that the
ciphertext was not accepted by replying
with an absolute random value
of course by now the Fuji Zaki okamoto
transform has also been Revisited in the
quantum random Oracle model because we
are now interested in post Quantum
secure schemes
and if you take a look at the Quantum
random Oracle Model results we've seen
so far there are some things that at
least we found kind of intriguing
the first thing is that while random
Oracle Model results are kind of
agnostic to the rejection method meaning
regardless of whether you return bottom
or absolute random value
the security bound does not change
in the quantum random Oracle model
implicitly rejecting variance had vastly
better security bounds than explicitly
rejecting variance
another thing we found kind of
surprising was that all security bounds
so far contained a grover-like search
term that was relative to Delta the
error probability even though it is not
clear how an attacker could do a full
Quantum search because
a decryption failure usually depends on
the secret key to which the attacker has
no access
so all in all we were wondering whether
the bounce we've seen so far might be
sub-optimal
a more interesting
part of our observations probably is
that we encountered an applicability
issue
by that I mean that the definition of
the error probability data that we
require for our security proofs does not
match the estimations of data that were
given for concrete schemes like Khyber
and I'll be talking a bit more about
this in the full talk
so what this work does is that it aims
to deal with all of these weird things
and problems to achieve more optimal
bounds and also to give a security proof
that is actually applicable to the
estimations of data we have seen so far
and on the way we also pick up some cool
new Quran techniques that allow you to
lift certain types of random Oracle
model proofs into the queue run
the technical side we were faced with a
problem that we had two existing
techniques and extractable Quantum
random Oracle model simulator and the
so-called one-way to hide in Lemma but
naively they cannot be combined in the
way we want it to combine them so we
opened the black boxes and proved a new
one-way to hiding Lemma for the
extractable quantum random Oracle model
in addition when we wanted to
characterize the behavior of public key
encryption schemes with decryption
errors under the randomization we needed
query lower bounds for a task that is
related to search but is not exactly
search it's the task of finding input
output values of the random Oracle that
evaluate to large values under some
predicate function
so we generalized some proof techniques
to improve that square lower bonds
if this sort of teaser made you curious
then I recommend you come to our talk
and we will be given by Caspian
hervemance here you can see when and
where it will take place thanks