hi everyone this is Nan Wang from the
Australian National University
we are going to present our paper flash
proofs efficient zero knowledge
arguments of range and polynomial
evaluation on the 6th December in Asia
Crypt 2022
flashproofs are three round Sigma
protocols and the discrete logarithm
assumption with a transparent setup
they do not require any pairing
operations
foreign
first we'll present a new type of zero
knowledge range argument
we devise a new variant of the bit
decomposition approach to prove that a
committed value is in the range between
0 and the two power n minus 1.
our range argument is tailored to
confidential transactions on blockchain
platforms
it achieves n to the power of two-thirds
sublinear efficiency in communication
and verification
the major breakthrough is that verifying
our range argument consumes a comparable
amount of gas costs to that of the most
efficient Zeke snark without resorting
to any trusted setup on ethereum
our argument also supports the
aggregation of multiple Arguments for
further Improvement in efficiency
the table at the bottom shows the proof
size and the verification gas costs on
ethereum for a 32-bit and a 64-bit range
respectively
second we will introduce a new zero
knowledge argument of a polynomial
evaluation
the argument aims to prove a public
polynomial relation between two
committed values
we provide two zero knowledge protocols
which are optimized for lower and higher
degree polynomials respectively our
protocols build on the work of buyer and
growth
to the best of our knowledge our
argument can instantiate the most
communication efficient membership
argument in the discrete logarithm
setting among those not requiring
trusted setups
it also supports the aggregation of
multiple arguments sharing the same
inputs
the table illustrates an efficiency
comparison of bg13 and our two arguments
for lower and higher degree polynomials
it can be observed that our arguments
achieves a non-trivial Improvement
improving verification and proof size
if you're interested in our work please
come and watch our presentation on 6th
December thank you