hi I'm Leo I'm going to talk about the
summary of our work functional
encryption with secure key listing
this is a joint work with field Channel
our question is whether we can copy
protect or delete data
it is easy to copy classical digital
information as much as you want
moreover it is hard to prove that we
delete classical information
however if we consider Quantum
information the situation is completely
different
in general it is impossible to copy
Quantum state by the no cloning theorem
in addition we could prove that Quantum
information is deleted by the
uncertainty principle
there are many unconable cryptographic
Primitives or cryptographic Primitives
with flat by the deletion by using those
Quantum properties
in this work we focus on functional
encryption
in functional encryption we can generate
a functional dedication key where a
function f is hardwired
when we receive a cipherfects of the
plaintix X we can compute f of x by the
functional education t
the question in this work is whether we
can copy protect or delete functional
decoration keys by making those keys
Quantum States
we propose the notion of functional
encryption with City key listing
in this printable a functional decision
key is quantum state
and we also generate a verification key
for each decryption key
we can delete a functional decision key
and the generator certificate for
deletion
if the certificate is varied then we can
guarantee that the functional education
key was deleted
after the deletion we can no longer
decrypt hypothetists
we also proposed a stronger motion
single decrypter functional encryption
in this primitive a functional
definition key is quantum State as a fee
with secular key listing
the difference is that we do not have a
deletion process and the copying key is
prevented
even if we try to generate two entangled
Quantum States
from a functional reduction key one of
them does not have the decryption
capability
in this work we present a bounded
Collision resistance secret key Fe with
secure key adhesync scheme based on
Boundary functions
foreign
scheme based on indistinguishability
obfuscation and one-way functions
please attend my talk or read our paper
for detail
thank you for watching this video