hello everyone
this is a short video abstract of my
Azure Crypt 2022 paper General
properties of quantum beat commitments
from China university
The Story begins with since our world is
quantum we can ask the following
motivating question
can we base unconditional Quantum
cryptography solely built on principles
of quantum mechanics
Stephen Wiesner might be the first
person to explore this possibility
back in early 1970s he first studied
Quantum money
inspired by wisner's idea two Primitives
ending with different Fates were
intensively started in early days of
quantum crypto
the first plaintiff is quantum key
distribution
Burnett and blessed and independently
Earth
have proposed two slightly different
protocols both of them can be shown
unconditionally secure
the second primitive is quantum bit
commitment
there are many purpose schemes however
all of them will finally broken
the security of qpc is finally settled
in Middle 90s males and independently
law and child finally prove that Quantum
beat commitment is impossible
with a big blow to ambitious researchers
in Quantum crypto since then a qpc seems
dead
in a subsequent two decades there was
little progress towards QBC until
recently a QBC revives but in 55 human
sense
let it be compromised to introduce
computational hardness study
computational QBC
this is ironically in contrast to the
original motivation of starting Quantum
crypto unconditionally
however this is actually the starting
point of this work
specifically this work proposed to base
Quantum crypto on computational QBC or
is to querying the complexity theoretic
objects
there are similar exciting and somewhat
surprising results are obtained towards
this research Direction in this and its
follow-up work
now let me go into some detail
seeing from the complexity theoretical
perspective computational qpc induces
two clean and simple to State complexity
theoretic objects that turn out to be
equivalent
the first object is a pair of
efficiently generated Quantum states
that are computationally
indistinguishable but statistically
distinguishable it is called EFI in a
follow-up work
the second object can be viewed as a
computational navigation of one month's
theorem we just call it a woman
we propose to study computational QBC or
equivalently EFI or woman at the basic
complexity assumption in medical script
based on the following reasons
first
prior and this work show that
computational qpc is both sufficient and
necessary for several important
Primitives including Quantum material
knowledge and Quantum oblivious transfer
and more recently work extend results
are further along this line of research
second
EFI has a classical counterpart that is
well know equivalent to Runway functions
third QBC or EFI or woman is weaker than
two other candidate complexity
assumptions in medical Crypt namely a
Quantum secure one with functions and
the pseudo random Quantum States
fourth our study indicates that
definitions of computational qpc or EFI
or women are quite robust
several interesting equivalences among
different variants of them can be
established
in this last picture we summarize
equivalences we have established in this
work a represented by this red and
orange allows
this picture also summarizes our current
knowledge towards exploring basic
complexity assumption in medical Crypt
that's all what I want to say thanks for
your listening