my name is shreyan Duman I'm a PhD
student at Royal University program and
in this short video abstract I'm going
to talk about you on our work on group
action based key encapsulation and
non-attactive key exchange in the
quantum random molecular model and this
is a joint work with Dominic Cartman
Ikea Sabrina kunzuela Jonas
so what is a non-attective key exchange
we have Alice and Bob and they have a
secret and public keys and they exchange
their public keys and besides exchanging
their public key says no interaction and
they can compute a shared key and if you
have a key exchange it's G to the a b
and the different key exchange is
passively secure uh under the under the
decisional DVM and assumption which
states that g to the a given G to the a
g to the B and G to the a b
there's a computationally indecentable
from G to the a g to the b g to the U
for a b and U uniformly render from set
P where p is a prime order of the group
now there's a slight variant of the VM
and key exchange called HTTP hammer and
here the shared key G to the a b is
additionally hashed using hash function
h
also here we include the public keys
and interestingly this is actually
actively secure under the strong CDH
assumption and the render molecular
model and what does a strong CDH
essential state
it states that it's difficult to compute
G to the a b given G to the A and G to
the B and additional access to an oracle
the social Oracle which
decides about G to the G1 exponentiated
by a equals G2
so in the quantum world we don't have
the VM and key exchange anymore at least
not the classical one
because discrete logarithms are
efficiently computable by large quantum
computers
and for lattices and codes it's an open
research question to build efficient
making
but from misogyny-based cryptography
like Seaside we have a candidate for
Quantum assistant Nike
and in our work we take the more
abstract view of group actions of the
group action framework
and what is a group action
it's a group G and set X together with a
map
and the map apps from G and X to X and
we have some additional conditions which
I'm going to talk about more in the full
version of The Talk
so in our title we said we studied in
the quantum random work model so what's
the random Quantum random molecular
model
well if you want to study the quantum
resistance or scheme Sentry and the
render Markle model
then we have to assume
actually access to to Quantum access to
the hash function because a quantum
computer can compute the hash function
locally and then
do superposition queries
so
this is actually then the right model to
study a Quantum resistance or schemes
and the the right extension of the
random molecule model
so now let us talk what we do in our
work so we have the group action based
uh HD family key exchange here
and what we do is we prove that the
active security of the scheme and the
qram
using the cloud group action Quantum
strong CDH assumption
and
show that such an assumption is
necessary
and we show how to weaken the Assumption
by alternative constructions for example
using training or key confirmation and
we prove also the corresponding cap
secure
so this is the last slide of this short
video abstract I look forward to see at
the full version of The Talk