I request everybody to please have a
seat
it gives me great pleasure to invite you
to the first invited Talk of the
conference the talk will be by Gian guo
on evolution of cryptanalysis security
updates on shatri and AES hashing about
our speaker Gian guo is currently a
faculty member at the nanyang
Technological University in Singapore
he's been working on symmetrical
cryptography dedicatedly and has
published over a 40 papers with iacr
since 2007. he co-designed several
symmetric key Primitives
including the lightweight block Cipher
led the lightweight hash function Photon
and continuously provides updated
security evaluations to important
symmetric key designs such as shattu
shatri and AES
he serves the research Community
actively
as general co-chair of FSC 2013 Asia
trip 2021 a member of the iscr board of
directors since 2020 a member of the
Asia Crypt steering committee since 2017
and a PC member of multiple iacr
conferences and workshops he has also
co-founded the Asian workshop on
symmetric e cryptography in 2011. let's
all welcome our speaker
thanks for the introduction and thanks
for the invitation
it's my honor to present uh talk here
so today I will present a topic on
evolution of group analysis security
updates on shastri and say Yes hashing
so I have to acknowledge all my
collaborators on these two topics uh
they are my ex PhD supervisors
colleagues
[Music]
poster
students and Friends
so today I will try to give the talk in
five parts first I will give the
introduction on hash function and clip
analysis
then I will move to developments of
copper analysis
followed by the security status of AES
and AES hashing then I will summarize
so first of all I will I have to
emphasize that the talk is educational
so uh
so I tend to give the talk to General
audience including people outside of the
symmetric key fields
so you will not contain too much
technical details but to cover the most
updated security status
on the fields
so starting with the definition of a
harsh function hash function is a
function mapping a b string of arbitrary
runs to a fixed lens digest so usually
we use H to denote the function and N to
denote the size of Digest
that core security has to offer
Collision resistance premature
resistance and second primage resistance
Collision resistance refers to the
property that it should be
computationally difficult to find two
different message such that the digests
are the same
so the key here is that there's no
restriction on the selection of either
message
the attacker there are people who want
to analyze it has the full degree of
freedom to choose x and x Prime
the second security is premature
resistance
so given the target key it is
computationally difficult to find a
message X such that the digest of X is T
and second primage resistance is very
related to premature resistance
rather than the digest the attacker is
given a message
and that goal is to find another message
such that the digests are the same
it has many significant applications so
um for example digital signature we can
use the hash and sign approach to
generate the signature password storage
usually comes with a sort together with
the password before the hashing
checksum so this is used quite often for
large buyer downloading so to ensure you
have a correct fire download that's
usually what we do is uh to check the
checksum against the one provided if
they are consistent then it's very
likely that
the file is correctly downloaded and
message authentication codes
in the way of hashing of a key and
message such as hmac and Mac
so shashri was triggered by the
triggered by the Broken of xiaowang in
2005 by a Chinese researcher sharing
Wang and her team
then nice to organize the discharge
competition in 2008 or October 64
submission received
2009 July 14 selected for Round 2
2010 December 5 selected for round three
and
2012 October ketchup was announced as a
winner
beside a group of people from Belgium
actually here is here
uh it's three years later the ketchak
was formally standardized as jashree
it has four major digest sizes two to
four two five six three eight four and
five one two
and later on two extendable digest sizes
are added they are named sha Shake one
two eight and
it has a very different design strategy
from xiaowan and shot two
consists of 24 rounds and the diner also
proposed a kangaroo 12 with 12 rounds I
will come back to this later
so another major instance of a hashing
is what we call AES hashing so AES
fashion is a hash function designed from
AES
that because AES was so widely used it
will cause a marginal additional cost
to implement a hash function if the AES
itself is already implemented
so uh about AES so it was the successor
of BS
and there was there was the attack by
mass reason so I think it's also here
I saw him yesterday at least
uh so niece they organized that this AES
competition in 2019 uh 1998 June 15
submission received at the next year
August 5 selected for round two
thousand topper Rhino was announced the
wind designed by Zhong and Vincent and
the year after it was formerly
standardized the AES supports three
different Keys one two eight one nine
two and two five six
yeah uses the white chess strategy to
resist differential group analysis
because differential group analysis and
linear group analysis what a major group
analysis technique invented
before aesmt was the major threat to Des
and the number of rounds are 10 12 14
respectively for the three different
variants of keys it can be converted to
Hash function by modes such as Davis
Mayer so this is one example so if we
use the message as the key and hash the
previous training Value Plus the key
again we'll get the updated training and
this will be the compression function
so
as we know group analysis is the major
uh energy consuming I mean human power
consuming parts
in the hawk
symmetrically design cycle
it will take lots of time uh
and actually lots of design parameters
depends on the group analysis results
so now it serves as two to trade off
between the Simplicity efficiency and
security for designs to run numbers okay
so meaning that if usually the design is
iterative with this similar wrong
function repeated several times
when we have more rounds it means we
have a larger security margin but uh
lower efficiency if we have lesser
rounds we will have higher efficiency
but lesser security margin so Cooper
analysis methods is trying to make the
best trade-off between the security and
the efficiency so that we get an
efficient one yet not broken yeah
the major group analysis method
developed in the past two decades
includes differential group analysis
linear code analysis integral analysis
and meets in the middle attacks for more
attacks Cube attack Etc
so take differential crop analysis as an
example The major portion of
differential group analysis is to
find a good differential path
good means high probability yeah and
evolved from
hence
finding differential paths by hands and
people believe that the broken of Shawan
was actually done by hand in 2005.
and after that the people will write a
dedicated program to search for
differential passes according to their
experiences
like for lower number of rounds what are
the good good ones and try to propagate
to a larger number of rounds
starting from 2011 people started to
utilize set like servers
from 2019
machine learning also found its
application in trip analysis so the
problem is that so we are given inputs
out output differences and the number of
rounds we want to attack
then people have to find the
intermediate differences so that the
overall differential
probability is high or Optimum
so the approaches are before we have all
the tools is mainly about human
experiences
to narrow down that such space so for
example we know for low number of rounds
two or three we know how to do it by
hand
and if we have to build
larger number of Brands differential
parts we repeat them or we build try to
add additional rounds on top of the
shorter differential passes yeah
we also have the meet in the middle
approach meaning that if we have two
shorter differential passes we try to
connect them by matching the inputs and
the outputs of the past two passes yeah
so that's what we have done for many
many years so people we find useful
tools like set and machine learning
so in 2011
set like servers were introduced to
Cooper analysis one of the issue is that
it's difficult to predict the serving
time meaning that uh
the only thing we can do now is to try
and see whether it give us the results
if it doesn't
we don't know whether
is not solvable
in real time or the model has itself has
some problem yeah
so either yes or no
machine learning is similarly so we're
constrained by the Practical from
complexity meaning that once we have the
model fixed
uh
we have to we have to train the model in
Practical time
if that model cannot be done in
Practical time we cannot be sure whether
the model is working or not yeah so uh
yes both have this uh
function of practical complexity
so for a set like servers it's hard to
achieve optimality for any uh so it's
it's hard to achieve optimality for any
equip analysis attacks which are usually
tunable by virus parameters so sort like
set like servers are here to help for
better optimization here I list a simple
example so if we have a list of
constraints
um with inequalities
and we Define an objective function
either we want to minimize something or
meaning maximize something
so this is a very a simple example of
milp
we can directly input this into this MIB
server
and you'll be able to Output us the
Optimum or sub optimal solution so in
this case it's one two and the objective
is three which is maximum yeah
so for group analysis we can actually
convert all the constraints into
inequalities like this and fit into the
server once the server give us some
solution then it means a solution to
that group analysis results yeah
so for example the differential path
search the constraints are simply we
have to make sure that differences
intermediate differences are compatible
in each round
so they they they form a complete and
compatible differential path and the
optimal goal is the overall probability
which is dependent on the choices of the
intermediate differences okay
who is uh okay with content computer in
light we also consider the group
analysis
under condenser thing there are two
major algorithms available which are
different from the classical ones so the
Growers Grover algorithm which is also
called the quantum search algorithm
it takes the square roots and time
versus n in the classical computer to do
the boot for search yeah so that's the
immediate impact of this is that the
security strengths of rock cybers is
half
so 128 bit key becomes insufficient
because uh 2 to the 64 is very close to
a practical time
and second premature and premature
resistance of hash function is also
halved yeah because of this book for
search
another algorithm useful for us is the
assignments algorithm so if the function
f is periodic
means that FX is FX plus b for all X in
the domain so it costs polynomial time
to find that period P yeah
so the immediate application of the
global algorithm is is application to
content Collision finding so
traditionally content attack in
classical setting it will cost per stay
time which is square roots of the search
space yeah
and this can be done simply by selecting
to the above the N different values and
store the digest in the hash table
and
roughly with a probability about half we
will be able to find the repeated Digest
we do the same for Content setting
except that that's now we only need to
store 2 to the N over 3 because now the
search is uh done by Grover which can be
done in square roots of the such space
so if you have 2 to the anniversary
values available in the space and the
entire space is 2 to the end and the
ratio will be due to the two n over
three and the time to do a search in
this ratio is simply two to another two
and over three yeah so the overall time
complexity for Collision finding in
content setting is 2 to the anniversary
uh so means that if the digest size is
120 a bit it only offers two to the 42.7
security
which is insufficient yeah
another impact on differential based
Collision attack is that uh
at the lowest useful probability
uh changes from 2 to the N over 2 from
the classical setting to to the negative
2N over 3 in the content setting because
with this probability we only need to do
the search in time to do the anniversary
in order to find one colliding pair
so in content setting there are
potentially much larger such space
and uh
also potentially result in longer
attacked rounds yeah
so with all this in mind meaning that
the developments of the group analysis
method from the traditional ones to the
server added ones and in the setting of
a classical and
Quantum will look at the security of a
shot three and AES hashing
social 3 was
following the sponge Construction
the design is simple so the internal
internal function is a permutation as
and it starts with the initial value so
top Parts R Beats is Chord rate at each
registration are bits of message is
added to the states at the beginning
and this was fit into the permutation f
and this was repeated until all the
message bits was processed
then it goes to the squeezing phase
which outputs a bit at the issue
iteration and here you get sufficient
many bits needed
so shashri there are four major
four major instances
but they share the same permutation as
meaning that's uh
uh the only difference between the four
instances are the parameters R and C
okay
it can be organized in in in a cube uh
five times five times 64 cubed uh it has
24 rounds each round consists of five
steps and out of the five there are only
one non-linear operation
first step is called Sita which adds the
parity of two columns into the current
bits
so there was the notation of a column
parity kernel means that if all the
parity of the columns are zero then this
forms in the CB kernel and he has some
special property because in this case
Theta becomes the identity yeah means
you
who does nothing
and we have the role which is the lane
level rotation so we have a five by five
25 rows and each row rotates by a a
defense value of offset by according to
speech table
find step is the permutation of the lens
according to this formula so you need
that we just Shuffle the position of the
lanes
and Kai is the only non-linear operation
which is Sim which is a simple circuit
design okay
so uh we have a value here to go through
the navigation and together with the
next value go to the ends operation and
add this value adds pizza so that's the
updates uh the speeds so this applies to
every bit we can see easily see that the
algebraic degree of chi is 2 because
there's only one non-gate and the
inverse that it has algebraic to grade 3
which is a very low compared to AES
Yota is adding a constant round
dependent constant to the states
so this is to destroy the symmetry
so overall we can see that the Yota
destroy the Symmetry and it does nothing
else so in our differential attack we
can simply ignore this one
the first three are linear operations
and the chi is the non-linear part so we
can actually combine the first three
operations to form a big linear
operation
the overall attack framework is
something look like this
so uh there are there are two
foreign
actually tries to connect the
connect the initial value to the the
input difference here so we call it
connector
so the parts we can control is the rates
because the message is added here so we
can choose the correct the message we
wanted so to change the value to what we
want uh really
but this version capacity it speaks to
zero so there's no way for us to change
it so the value is zero that
defense is also zero so uh
there's nothing we can do here so we
only miss we only have the degree of
freedom of this R Beats try to connect
it to uh
the data in here after a few rounds so
there's a series of developments worked
on this
uh in FSC
2013 and the connector was one round and
in Euro Cup 2017 we tried to
uh expand it to two rounds by having a
fully linealized
rounds means that here we will have a
layer of all Xboxes active and try to
linealize it Legalize It means that we
try to fix a
uh some values of the Xbox so that the
Xbox
becomes a linear operation yeah
and set crypto 2007 17 we extended this
to a partial three round connector means
that uh we cannot fully control all the
all the defenses but part of them we can
do so that we leave some of them to be
probabilistic matching this data as in
and the rest are by the connector yeah
okay so the result was uh
the result was a
at the very beginning only three runs
shot three five one two and four rounds
shot three three a four can be done and
only three round version chapter three
one five one two can be done practically
uh in 2017 we extended this to uh five
rounds practical attacks on Shake one to
eight and Charles 324
and later in a general version of this
paper of this two paper we also extended
the Practical Xiao 3256 Collision
without to be practical yeah
yeah so that's the original idea without
that set okay
so as we can see here uh we actually
involve three parts of the attack the
first part is to come up with a good
differential pass with high probability
the second part is to come up with the
connector which also offers sufficient
number of solutions for this
differential parts
and the overall goal is to have an
Optimum complexity so
three parts are done are done
independently before and they were
searched by dedicated programs and so we
can see each part can be replaced by a
set like solver yeah
so we did that
and combine all these steps together to
achieve Global Optimum
so what we got to uh six rounds attacks
in content and classical setting so uh
weird
present this paper
I think that this is the last talk of
today
on this portion
how this was done
right
so that's about Xiao SRI so on AES
there are 10 12 14 rounds of AES
respectively for three different key
instances and the wrong function looks
like this it consists of four operations
first is the sub byte which replaces
each byte by the substitution of s-box
of its value followed by the shift row
so you shift left us cyclically by
zero one two and three positions Mr
column operates on the columns so yeah
multiply and MDS Matrix with the column
and update it and finally we have the
add key so which is the one key and this
is the key schedule for aes128 okay
so the major Collision attack on AES
hashing is by the rebound attack
it also involved the high probability
differentials yeah
so the idea is that if we have two high
differential uh
high probability differential you can
chop the entire Cipher into three
portion
so uh the first one is what we call fpw
backwards
and the last question is f
FW forward and the middle portion so uh
what we want is that
the probability force in this F the
first and last portion are high so that
when it comes to the boot for search
scattered stage it will cost less time
and we
we want the fbin to connect this two
portion and offer enough number of
candidates for the Brute Force stage
yeah
and this rebound attack was introduced
in FSC 2009 by Mendo at all and that
first application was to uh
whiteboard and Lane
a true Lane was removed by this attack
yeah
and he relies on high probability
differentials of these two portions so
you can see that where the set set like
servers come to play
the constraint is simply the middle have
to match in the state and key it in use
through the F in portion
and the overall goal of optimization is
the overall complexity means that
uh the overall which is uh which is
highly determined by the probability of
the first and last portion
so the Collision attack on NAS hashing
uh in the classical setting uh is
reaching seven rounds with complexity
two to the 56 so in order to for in
order for us to have Collision first of
all we have to satisfy the condition
that the input difference and the output
difference is possible to cancel each
other
yeah so you can see the pattern in data
B and the pattern in Delta C are the
same only only then it will be possible
to generate Collision
and then
the dotted line is what we have for f in
the middle portion yeah the middle
portion we should be able to solve it by
utilizing the degree of freedom from the
key
and out of that the first two and a half
rounds is the F in yeah so in the real
attack after the inbound phase he
actually propagates backwards in this
way
so the probability we are calculating
here is simply
we have a missed column of four to one
here so here is one to four that's which
probability one so we don't pay anything
so it's just here four to one
similarly uh the last round we have this
uh
we have this for free because there's no
more mixed column yeah so the only
probability we have to pay is here and
the price that this and this has to
match yeah so we have three bytes
condition here and four bytes condition
here so in total seven byte con
condition which is a 2 to the 56 yeah
foreign
using the original method because
previously the two steps were done also
independently meaning that
the high probability differential of the
forwards and backwards portion are
searched independently and the matching
was done in the Second Step so although
each each step you might reach the
optimum but globally you know may not be
the optimal yeah so after we actually
consider the two steps in one and put
them into a one server
then be able to give us this uh
this uh new results together with the
chain relation algorithm
and in the content setting as I
mentioned in the content setting for
Collision we can go for the probability
as low as 2 to the 2N over three
uh
we are able to extend this attack to
eight rounds so again in order for us to
have Collision we have to ensure that
the patent which is the
which is uh eight bytes active here and
outputs are the same yeah so they are
possible to cancel each other
and
we are able to solve a very big inbound
space which covers five rounds here so
uh
from here to here we cross nothing
because uh it is one to four yeah and
because
it is one to four yeah so in the end the
only price we have to pay is this one
matching this one here
and it costs 2 to the 34 in content
setting so we can see uh in content
setting
in content setting this is a very low
complexity so in if online computer
comes to reality this might be the first
targets we can actually Implement and
carry out the
findings
so overall uh
for AES hashing classically we can reach
seven rounds and in content setting we
can reach eight rounds in total
there are 10 Rounds so the security
margin is uh is becoming small yeah
so in summary in summary a
we've seen some developments of Coupe
analysis method from the transitional
methods
to the ones by dedicated such programs
to the ones aided by set like servers
and now starting from 2019 we see group
analysis method aided by Machine
learning so the idea is to mimic the
differential based key recovery attack
by Machine yeah so we first train the
machine to distinguish the reduce the
round to its hyperbility differential
from random ones means that as long as
we know there's a high differential
probability covering the entire portion
of the attacker Cipher
the machine should be able to detect it
yeah by
by calculating or
calculating or
calculating the number of output
differences satisfying this High
differential property High differential
high probability differential yeah
and then to launch the key recovery
attack utilizing such differentials so
uh
these two steps were done by hands
people and now it can be mimicked by
by uh machine yeah the first attempt was
done by God at crypto 2019
with the application to Simon and the
second attempt was uh by
uh my team I guess you have heard the
talk Yesterday by Jensen
with all the details so it was the first
time achieving a complexity which is a
a better than man-made attacks so
Simon was actually analyzed quite
intensively since the since the proposal
was made public in 2014
and uh
it was uh actually unexpected that the
machine can actually do better than what
we did because uh we have accumulated
like Decades of experience on
differential based key recovery attacks
yeah
however okay however the limitation of
machine learning is that it's limited by
practical complexity
meaning that uh when the model gives you
results that means the model is working
and give you results and the result
should be right
if it doesn't give you the results
there will be
two possibility either
the model is wrong
or the model simply takes too long to
Output the results yeah
by other experiences so far
the application of machine learning
based group analysis is capable to apply
to very short block size block ciphers
so Simon has the the major
targets we tried here are 32 bits block
size yeah which is very small once it
scares up to 64 or 128 the model becomes
very very slow and takes too much memory
to to do the training and it won't be
able to Output us the uh results in
Practical time
another difficulty is that there's
currently no theoretical treatments of
this machine learning based coupon
analysis so for human right for
traditional differential group analysis
we can do projection yeah
so if we can carry out the Practical key
recovery attack based on differential
uh then we can do a projection by adding
up the number of rounds because we know
adding this much of rounds the
differential probability will drop by
this much this is predictable yeah
and the complexity of the final key
recovery will also scale up accordingly
however in machine learning there's no
such thing okay
because we have to ensure we get a
distinguisher before we can do key
recovery and we can only guarantee us to
get a distinguisher by the result the
Practical results so far yeah
when the when the block size get up or
the number of rounds scare up the the
machine is no longer able to distinguish
the the Target and the render Oracle we
are not able to tell whether this is due
to our limited amount of resources or
due to the fact that it becomes
indistinguishable yeah
so uh a practical
so as theoretical model to treat this
machine learning is in Urgent needs so
that we can try to scale up the text to
larger block sizes and larger number of
prongs
in conclusion
so so far Collision attacks of charge 3
is up to six rounds
so there are lots of possibility margin
left
because the structure in total have 24
rounds but we are only attacking 25
percent leaving 75 percent as the
security margin so maybe kangaroo 12 is
a good idea
because uh
it has only 12 rounds means uh it can be
twice as fast as strawberry
and still we have 50 percent security
margin left
for AES we can do up to seven or eight
rounds in classical and content setting
is still usable because we have 20 30
percent security margin but in content
setting it becomes very risky to use uh
AES in hashing modes because
it has 128 bits block size offering
maximum 2 to the anniversary which is 2
to the 40 to the 43 Collision resistance
in in theory yeah but even there's no
attack
I guess
very soon we'll be able to see boot for
such uh on 128 bits solution yeah
so it's not a vital it's not a divisible
so to resist content attacks
people should really think about rock
ciphers with a larger box size
such as 256 yeah
so what to expect from future
developments of group analysis we really
want to have a deeper look at the core
algorithms under the server and machine
learning
so uh
so for both as I mentioned for both uh
server based and machine learning based
group analysis the bottleneck is that
we are limited by practical time
practical resources
and
when the model doesn't outputs us
anything we don't know whether it is due
to the model
or due to the fact that it becomes
invisible to attack yeah so uh
we really want to figure out uh
how to project this so that we can scale
up our algorithms and the text to uh
to a larger space yeah and another
reason is to uh having this it is
possible for us to select according to
the performance of the underlying server
or machine learning
the best strategy to model the attack
yeah so that's uh you actually reduce
the Practical shopping time yeah
yeah that's my thought thank you
any questions
thank you for that nice talk to the the
Collision search on the hash function
and yes my question is you mentioned
that uh break content I mean that the
classical and the quantum setting what
what's the difference I mean that I
interpret the
that when you search
you will use classical searching over
global search that is the difference
what is difference
yeah
okay that is you're using Global search
so
how do you assume that the complexity of
global search
does critical searching is very simple
right yeah
so how can you estimate the complexity
of global soil yeah so the current
Grover search complexity is assumed to
be the square root of the such space
okay so of course I don't have a Content
computer I cannot enjoy it practically
but that's the everybody
I can understand that this is a
theoretical yeah that's theoretical yeah
okay so another question maybe I can
challenge later this is possible to
Break by Quantum machine learning
Quantum machine learning yes
yes right what
okay so there are two things uh which is
uh constraining us from using machine
learning for coupon analysis one is time
the other is memory I think the most
constraints resources is the memory so
far because to train a very large Rock
Cipher
uh especially with 64 or even 128 bits
block Cyprus the amount of data
increased exponentially
so it becomes impossible for the Machine
model to accommodate so many data in
memory yeah
however for
time I think we can use up a
supercomputer to paralyze all the
computations okay
so
yeah in that sense I think it's
difficult especially uh given that the
quantum memory is much harder to achieve
than classical memory yeah
thank you
any more questions
all right let's thank the speaker again