hello everyone this is toy Elio today
I'm going to talk about large Precision
homomorphic sign evaluation using few TV
it's a joint work with Daniella
michancho and you report account
so for some background information uh
we in this paper we use a functional or
programmable bootstrapping what that
means is that it basically we can
evaluate an arbitrary Mega cyclic
function basis for free while also
performing some bootstrapping over
elderbs affects this is first introduced
in dm15 and it has two constraints the
first one is that it requires the next
cyclic function uh exactly basically
means that for some input X and zq you
need to satisfy that f of x equals to
negative of f of x plus Q over T you can
see this is a relatively strong
restriction and the second restrictions
that they can only evaluate functions
for messages app to keep this a
precision and usually case equal to 506.
uh basically the runtime exponential is
exponential in the in the number of bits
so for more than five or six bits the
runtime will be relatively impractical
and there are two uh bootstrapping
methods discussed in the paper the first
one is few uh introducing dm15 it can
efficiently support uh arbitrary Secrets
but the bootstrapping key size is
relatively large and the second method
is tfvg it it's introduced in cgg i60
and provides better runtime performance
for small Secrets like binary ternary
and the shopping key size is much
smaller to see MP top 21 for detail
comparison and see uh this new paper for
third method uh this is comes after our
previous published so it's not included
in people
in this paper we use a functional
bootstrapping as a black box so any of
these methods will work for us
and the main result of this work is that
we added some uh new powerful tools to
the kvg a few
skips and and
the mentors are the following the first
one is large Precision comparisons and
one comparison first because comparisons
are widely used in ml vaccine inference
or DPC training and data science and
comparisons are also considered hard to
be used uh via homophic encryption
as you know the current runtime
exponential with the number of bits and
we want them to make the runtime linear
scaling
and second tool we provide is the logic
Precision arbitrary function evaluation
Now it only supports negative cyclic
function and supports only small
precision
we have implemented our schemes and the
implementations open sourced and open
fhg and passive libraries
let me conclude this abstract talk by
describe our very very high level idea
and is that our first observations that
the comparison is equivalent to assigned
valuation so to compare A and B we just
need to find the sign of a minus B
and the psy evolution is equivalent to
Computing the most significant bits and
the Computing the MSP is the central
part of UTV
to evaluated for large Precision our
method is to remove the large number of
stitches gradually
for example we have this 18 bits we
first removed the last six bits and then
remove the central six bit the metal
sticks bits and then we have only six
bits left we can use a few per shopping
to directly extract the most significant
however uh directly remove these bits by
things like emotional switching is not
acceptable because there are they will
introduce some errors to know what
technique what is exact the technique we
used and introduced in the paper uh
please come to the flue talk it will be
on Tuesday December 6th uh five to
five twenty five and um it will be uh
GMT plus eight uh time zone uh thank you
for listening