and our talk we'll present new
algorithms and Analysis for the problem
of some preserving encryption this is
Joint work between myself and Dr Scott
yellick
the problem of some preserving
encryption and creating some preserving
encryption schemes was first introduced
by to Jake at all in 2019.
the idea is you want to encrypt vectors
so that they have the same sum so you
start with a vector of integers and you
want to encrypt it also as a vector of
integers but with the same sum as the
original vector in addition to
preserving the sum we'll also typically
have a bound on the components of the
vector so both the plain text and the
cipher text each point in the vector is
going to be bounded between 0 and a
component bound of d
tajik at all presented this problem
along with an application so the
application was the problem of thumbnail
preserving encryption the idea is that
you want to encrypt an image so that the
thumbnail of the image is preserved so
both the original image and the
encrypted image have the same thumbnail
the thumbnail is created by dividing an
image into B by B blocks of pixels each
block of pixels is replaced by a single
Pixel whose value is the mean of the
original pixels in the block
so if we take each block in the image
and we imply some preserving encryption
scheme so we encrypt each block with
some preserving encryption then each
block in the original image and the
encrypted image will have the same thumb
sum thus the same mean and we'll end up
with both an original image and an
encrypted image that have the exact same
thumbnail in addition to preserving the
sum we'll also bound each pixel between
0 and 255.
tajik at all present this problem and an
encryption scheme
the idea is that we're going to again we
start from a vector of integers you're
going to shuffle this Vector of integers
until we get a random shuffling
then we're going to pair adjacent points
in the vector to create a perfect
matching so we're just going to pair
points that are next to each other to
create a perfect matching
then independently for each pair in the
matching we're going to replace it
uniformly at random from one of the
valid pairs of integers that we could
replace it with so we're going to look
at all pairs of integers with the same
sum and that respect to the component
bound and we're going to choose
uniformly at random leave from each of
these pairs of points all right so we
look at all pairs with the same sum and
we choose uniformly at random
if you repeat this algorithm enough
times you'll end up with some preserving
encryption scheme
in our talk we'll go into more detail in
the background of this problem and
previous work and we'll present our work
our results
so we we give three main results the
first is a formal mixing time bound so
essentially an upper bound on the number
of times we need to repeat the algorithm
given by tajik at all so how many times
do we need to repeat this how many times
is sufficient we give an upper bound on
that this formal proof uses a path
coupling technique with which we'll also
discuss at a high level in The Talk
in addition we'll present two algorithms
for ranking and unranking
um these integers with a given sum so
these are practical algorithms that we
can use we can take the rank and unrank
algorithms and combine them in a rank in
Cipher unranked approach
um to come up with new some preserving
encryption schemes in addition we'll
give performance results comparing
um all three of these algorithms both
the shuffling based algorithm and the
rank in Cipher unrank