hello everybody my name is Barbara and I
am a PhD student at the Technical
University of darmstadt and in this
video I want to give you an overview of
our paper Nostradamus ghost Phantom
which analyzes the Nostradamus attack on
hash functions and the quantum setting
this paper is a joint work together with
Mike fishlein and mod support
in case you liked this video and want to
know more about our paper I would like
to invite you to hear my talk at Asia
group and yeah of course to read our
paper
I will provide all the relevant
informations on my last slide
probably you have here the name
Nostradamus before
Nostradamus was a well-known pharmacist
of the 16th century who published poems
in order to predict the future
we could call this approach somehow
secure since it requires real magic to
write believable poems about future
events and it's hard to pretend to be a
Nostradamus or in other words to be a
Nostradamus attacker if you are a
non-musician
in 2006 cats and Kuno introduced the
modern Nostradamus who uses cryptography
instead of poetry for his predictions
and for them furthermore Carlton and
Kuno analyzed the effort of a
non-magician to be a modern Nostradamus
attacker
So This Modern Nostradamus wants to
prove his prior knowledge about a
specific specific event with the help of
a hash function
for example he wants to predict the
numbers of the lottery draw next
Saturday
this would happen like this
before the lottery draw he commits to a
hash value by Target and says hey
I know the lottery numbers but I cannot
tell you which numbers because then you
could see the lottery
and um yeah we don't want this but what
I can tell you is the hash value of my
prediction which I would send you after
the lottery draw and hey you don't need
to try to guess the lottery numbers
based on this hash value by Target
because I add a secret signature M to my
prediction to avoid this
and afterwards he publishes a document
containing the correct prediction as
well as his signature and having this
hash value by Target
of course this picture of a modern
Nostradamus is just something to keep in
mind to have an intuition
nonetheless this is a desirable security
property for a hash function that this
can only happen if someone knows a
lottery numbers
and there's some assumptions we can
specify the effort of Kelsey and kuna's
rosadamus attack
which is a generic attack this means
that the adversary do not exploit any
concrete details of the Hedge function
our contribution is the development of a
Nostradamus attack in the quantum
setting which is a generic attack as
well and shows that the time complexity
can be reduced significantly if the
quantum adversary is allowed to use
crowbar's algorithm
you can see it here
The Factor before n
changes from two over three to three
over seven
moreover we give a lower Bound for the
quantum Nostradamus attack by using a
result of Leo and xandri which proves
that our attack is essentially optimal
and this is what you can expect from a
Target Asia group first I will explain
our Quantum attack and then I will show
you the proof idea of the lower bones
and as promised you can hit find here on
my last Slide the link to the full
version of our paper
and also another link where you can find
our kisket experiments for more
information please look into our paper
my talk at Asia Crypt will be at the 7th
of December at 5 30 PM in Taiwanese time
thank you for the attention and maybe
see you then again