in other words what does it mean to make
a digital signature or a digital proof
vanish
so the way we think about this is with
uh
the way we think about this is making
the soundness of the proof or the
soundness of the signature disappear
so consider Alice who signed something
at time T is equal to zero uh and we
wanted a signature to uh the sound up to
time P but then after time P it
shouldn't be sound uh verifier looking
at the signature wouldn't be convinced
that it's analysis so this also gives us
the notion of liability if someone sees
the signature After Time t uh Alice
could possibly claim that she never
signed
that could have been made by someone who
had no knowledge of her privacy
right
so how do we do this uh the underlying
technique behind all of our
constructions is to allow for signatures
to be forged through a slow computation
and similarly proofs can be sure uh
words like that so here we have a forger
who uh does a long sequential
computation of these steps and finally
produces the Forger and uh to any
distinguishers seeing the real signature
by Alice and the port signature uh
uh all of this requires some notion of
time
so someone uh is getting a signature
should know if it was made within the
past time or not and it's hard to time
stamp every single signature it's
magnetically possible so without like a
global block or anything so what we use
instead are beacons so consider like a
global Beacon over here which emits uh
some bits of Randomness every uh uh
Delta steps or time over here uh and
this Randomness is unpredictable
uncontrollable
so uh beacons have been made using
Randomness from stock prices blockchain
block hashes and distributed protocols
with multiple parties like the events
so how would a solution with a beacon
look like uh if uh say the beacon value
B was emitted at Time Zero uh and we
want the signature or proof for whatever
was created to expire at time P after
the beginning was released uh so here
say I'll sign something after the beacon
was released this signing algorithm that
Alice uses would specify the beacon
value
in the protocol and similarly
and uh once time T is reached regardless
of when exactly Alice made her signature
the soundness would be lost over there
right uh so without a timestamping
mechanism or a global clock we can uh
use beacons to uh make significance
come on
yeah so the rest of the stock I'll go
over some applications or short-lived
proofs and short-lived signatures and uh
then go over construction which is
verifiable delay functions as a key tool
and a briefly go over there
okay so uh in denial so when uh email
servers exchange emails they sign out to
authenticate them so this is required
for security and it's only really needed
during Transit so when the second server
receives the email and verifies the
signature it's no longer but these
signatures do last forever and
undesirable side effect of this is that
they can be used to validate
so here's like a picture of a uh a
famous Wikileaks in 2016 where all of
the emails were actually kept their
Google Furniture
um
uh the main thing is identified
um so this is not uh at the intended use
of these signatures and um this problem
is
one solution he suggested was uh Google
would like periodically release their
signing keys so uh Republic and so any
signatures
um
one uh so shortened signatures are like
a natural solution problem where uh when
uh investor wants to send an email they
sign it with a short uh it'll be valid
uh over here uh you can show the
signature after thank you to the whole
world anyone could have made it
and with this the advantage here is that
uh the signer no longer has to do any
actions like releasing their key they
can keep one key they don't have this or
anything if you like your private key
you can keep
it uh if it certainly proves
the rewarding system so uh suppose
someone makes a vote
and The Ballot Box gives them their
proof that they their vote was included
correctly right an undesirable side
effect of this is that this proof can be
used to get like
that and it's like a receipt of what
they did so e-boarding systems want to
have a receipts
uh
the proof lasts for a few minutes while
they're in the ballot group and after
that uh
it doesn't function
so uh there have been other lots of
related work on this area
I just needed verifier groups or proofs
that make sense to one verifier but no
one else
it makes sense
uh time signatures
we can solve the inverse problems
as signatures are like locked Central
Time
where we want signatures to be valid
uh
actions from the sign or third party to
for uh
proof of worker knowledge also solves a
problem where uh if someone either knows
a witness to a proof or uh did a long
time but they used to work and it's
paralyzable and not really a notion of
time
uh so just a quick note on formalizing
uh sure so when the rest of stock I'll
stick with short little truth and so in
formalizing them they have like a
approved algorithm and a verify
algorithm additionally we have a forge
algorithm and all of these things
and completely set the two uh
uh the portability the forging time
should be just overwritten uh in this
inducibility means that the proof is
generated by imperative report
and this business you know this uh
and uh we need a new notion of soundness
for key soundness where you can expect
that uh can produce groups in time
listening but after time T this
extraction guarantee is lost
so all the constructions will be
translated
uh we have four translations
uh and uh
for a vdf a function that takes a fixed
number of sequential steps to compute uh
but once this application is done it's
easy to convince a verifier that the
computation was done correctly
uh
so here an example or repeat its current
PDFs where the input is an element in a
group
and the output is
and the fastest
uh but once these sets are done you they
can generate a proof that producers are
verified that Y is indeed
uh so um
the security property
it's hard to convince it verifier
without spending time
okay so the most straightforward
construction to get effective to the
specific or the whatever you want to
prove and
here uh if you have a relational
input X which is W that's one branch of
the or and the other branches the media
taking the beacon value is
completeness because an honest viewer
can ignore the vdf branch and just
satisfy the relationship
and a forger who doesn't know the
witness and I have to satisfy the PDF
Branch by actually Computing the vdf
and uh since the PDF takes these steps
to do you get
also proven distinguishably and
soundness
note here that only one person has to
compute the vdf output and proof on the
beacon value and everybody can use their
Y and pi to forge groups on uh any
relation
thank you
and so this stronger notion of
portability we're calling reusable
forageability where the first quarter uh
additionally produces an advice that
helps make more fun
so here uh this is really good in
practice because one long computation
uh can help uh generate multiple chords
and the more versions there are
uh it enhances
uh where there are the main Construction
so just to establishment you have a
sigma protocol for relation r with uh
input x uh and uh the first step of the
signal protocol a uh gets a challenge C
and since
and uh signal protocols have a simulate
function where uh
without knowing the witness you can
simulate a realistic
all right
but so uh how do we make a sigma
protocol
so the first step over here
C1 and
and uh what we're going to do is use and
what we're going to do is
uh use C1 as a challenge for the
relationship
and CPU as the challenge because
right so why does the inclusion is that
the forger and the viewer will each beat
on different branches of this sand and
uh and honestly
so the forger can simulate the
relationship but then they'll have
problems
and the honest viewer can cheat on the
relation Grant by sorry on the video
so that's the intuition
because of the protocol just want to
note here that the input of the video
clarifier is
so we don't get reusable
right so to get
the design a new type of detail
s
which are similar figures except that
the output y isn't revealed
uh you have again it's very videos
but you just give a proof that you know
why you don't have to go right and to
verify that you do know yeah
uh the neat thing here is that this
could actually be represented as an
efficient Sigma protocol with foreign
of uh the relationship
yes
and just like some more competitions you
can simulate one uh one branch and
honestly
uh so the Uber can simulate the ztb
effect without actually
and they just uh they can run the signal
or their relationships
but the forger since they don't know the
witness they'll have to simulate the
relations branch and then uh honestly
completely
foreign
uh and uh just briefly going over the
implementation we use vespowski vdfs
which with rsa2048 groups which are
pretty large but even with that the
overhead for transforming signal
protocol into a short-term protocol is
pretty low it's only by half a kilobyte
for the tubes and even less than that
RSA signatures and the clear time
overhead is 120 milliseconds not that
much and much lower signature uh so just
wanted to highlight here that these
transitions are practical and uh
right so with that I'd like to conclude
and if you have any questions thank you
any questions
[Music]
I have one
how fine
um how fine grain can you control the
the period
at the time yeah that theory depend on
the beacon
uh it's actually dependent on the vdf so
here our vdf is y is equal to X bar 2
per T and it takes exactly three steps
so the Practical time would depend on
the proving Hardware uh and all that but
uh the vdfs are becoming very
standardized
like a specific Asics to compute this so
it's likely that it won't get any faster
Beyond a point like there will be fast
Hardware that does it really fast so
we'll have to that'll probably be the
Benchmark for the actual physical time
that it takes but yeah this number of
theoretical steps is fixed but the
hardware depends
other questions ready
hi thanks for your talk uh so I just
have a quick question so are there any
technical difficulties when extending
from signal protocols to multi-round
protocols
yeah we haven't thought about that but
yeah that would be interesting because
um for us uh if they can be composed
like a uh if they have a composition
available I think it would be easy to do
so that might be underlying uh thing you
can always try to compose with the video
and the original signal protocol so
that's something that will come down to
that okay thanks yeah that's interesting
okay so let's thank the speaker again
the second talk in this session is uh
rotatable
rotatable zero knowledge sets
post compromise secure
auditable dictionaries with the
application to key transparency
and the speaker is uh Li golden
please go ahead
hello everyone I'm Eli and I'm going to
be talking about rotatable zero
knowledge sets uh this is Joint work
between Zoom NYU and Microsoft research
uh with Brian Chen you have any notice
ishagosh myself
Antonio marcedon and Marianne burmell
uh our motivation is for end-to-end
encrypted communication systems whereby
parties want to communicate securely
with each other but all messages must
pass through some untrusted server this
is typically done using public key
encryption but the problem is that users
need some way to agree on each other's
public keys uh if for example the user
were to host a database of public keys
if for example the server were to host a
database of public Keys uh then this
could lead to man in the middle attacks
whereby the server could respond with a
compromised public key
uh to prevent this the most common
solution is to use security codes
whereby users will send each other
directly a QR code that can be used to
verify that the public key returned by
the server is in fact correct this is
TDS and requires manual verification and
so it can be audited can be automated
with something called a key transparency
system otherwise known as an audible
dictionary
uh in a key transparency system the
server will provide a commitment comp to
the database of public keys and whenever
a public key is queried the server will
in addition to the public key uh provide
a proof pie that the given identity
public key pair is in fact in the
committed database uh note that we also
require a uniqueness property that is
for every identity there should be at
most one public key that can be proved
to be stored in the database
uh then as long as all users agree on
the commitment men in the middle attacks
can be detected by users verifying that
their public key is stored correctly
the database may also update and perhaps
frequently as users update their public
keys and we would not necessarily want
user staff to check that they're
publicly is stored correctly for each
commitment
so uh every time the server updates the
commitment it will also produce a proof
pie that the update has been done
consistently which can be independently
audited not by the users themselves both
by some trusted third parties and this
increases the efficiency as users no
longer need to check that their public
use
correct every single update
uh by default this does not preserve
privacy that is the proofs May leak
information about the database but there
are privacy preserving solutions for key
transparency namely uh conics and
seamless as examples I will be focusing
on seamless since that is what our
contribution builds off of
um seamless
achieves keep private key transparency
using a primitive that they call append
only zero knowledge sets and append only
zero knowledge set or azks is
essentially a key transparency system
but for generalized databases for any
label value pairs the consistency
property that the proofs verify is that
the database is a pendant that is the
proof uh the update proof shows that uh
no database entries have been either
deleted or changed
uh the proofs in ezekiel's are privacy
preserving that is there zero knowledge
um the proofs uh both query and update
prints reveal no more information than
necessary
and it turns out that to achieve azks
the construction in the seamless paper
uh really requires some sort of uh
secret key public key primitive that is
the database the server storing the
database will also have some secret key
that they will use to hide the data and
there will be a published public key
that will be used to verify the proofs
uh note that seamless and neither is
conics or any existing key transparency
system that decides post compromise
security that is if the secret key is
revealed during say commitment one
um then for all label value pairs
including those added in later
generations uh privacy will still be
lost
our contribution is to add post
compromise security to keep private
transparency systems uh in particular we
Define a new primitive called the
rotatable zero knowledge set which is
the same as a pandemic zero knowledge
set with an addition of a rotate
operation which will change the public
key and provide a proof that the
rotation has been done correctly
um the idea is that even if the old
secret key is compromised all label
value pairs under the new Pro private
key will maintain private
uh let me Begin by talking about a basic
construction of the transparency systems
uh without the Privacy guarantee and
I'll show that how seamless extends on
this to add privacy and then our
contribution on top of that
uh so the basic contribution is that the
commitment to the database will be the
root of some sparse Merkle tree where
for every label value pair in the
database uh there will be a leaf
corresponding to the value at the index
at the point indexed by the tree path
um corresponding to its label
uh then a label value pair can be proven
to be stored in the commitment just by
giving the Merkel open
note that this does not maintain privacy
as if for example the Merkel opening
contains some other Leaf some adjacent
Leaf then it will reveal the fact that
the corresponding adjacent label value
pair is stored in the database
uh to add some privacy onto this the
first thing seamless does is replaces
the value stored at the leaf with a
commitment to the values uh this then
does hide the privacy of the values uh
and in fact
um and so now the new opening uh for the
commitment will be the Merkel the Merkel
opening as well as an opening for the uh
at least the commitment on the leaf so
uh but note that this still does not
achieve total privacy uh since if there
is an adjacent Leaf it will reveal the
fact that the adjacent label is stored
in the database for some value even
though it doesn't leak the value itself
uh so we know that we need to so the
first approach the approach that
seamlessly use is to replace the label
indexing the leaf uh with some other
value associated with the label note
that this could not be deterministic as
then it will leak too much information
about the label
um but we may hope that okay what if we
replace this path with say a commitment
to the label
um this is getting close uh this does
preserve the privacy but the problem is
now we lose the uniqueness property that
is uh for one label there may be two
commitments that correspond to that
label and so therefore uh as if there
are two commitments there may be two
values stored in the database uh
corresponding to the same commitment
um which would be a problem
uh but so we know that we want some
Randomness uh in this path uh but we
need also uniqueness so the uh correct
approach it turns out is to use
something like a PRS
um which will
will guarantee that there is only one
prf output for each label
um but we'll still maintain the privacy
of the label itself
uh the problem here uh the problem with
just using a prf directly is that there
is no way for verifiers to tell that the
Merkel opening in fact corresponds to
the label that is there is no way to
associate the output of the prf on a
label with its input so the key trick
that seamless uses is to index instead
with the vrf with a vrf replied to label
or a verifiable random function
intuitively vrf is just a prf where you
can prove that an output corresponds
with the template
more formally a vrf is a triplet of
algorithms Egen query and verify where
key gen outputs a secret key public key
pair
query uh takes in a secret key and some
input and gives an output and a proof Pi
here I'm going to call the output of the
vrf the Box containing X for visual
reasons
and finally uh verify we'll take in the
public key and then put an output and a
proof and output 0 1. to security
properties we require are uniqueness
that verify should output one if and
only if Y is in fact the Box containing
X and pseudor Randomness that is the Box
containing X should look random as long
as the secret key is not revealed note
that pseudoranomis should still hold
even if query proofs or some other
inputs are given
so to add key rotation onto seamless we
are going to do the simplest possible
thing which is we will come up with a
new secret key in public key and
completely rebuild the Merkle tree from
scratch
uh this works since new label value
pairs are going to be under some new
really new secret public key pair
um but it remains to be shown to prove
that this rotation is done consistently
without revealing information about the
database
uh what this boils down to is that we
have two sets of vrf outputs and we need
some way to prove that they come from
the same set of inputs
uh and so to do this what we do is we
Define a new primitive called a
rotatable vrs uh which will have this
property that you can produce these
rotation proofs and we'll show how to
construct it
uh more formally a rotatable vrs will be
a vrf with two additional algorithms
rotate and verotate rotate we'll take in
a secret key as well as some set of
inputs uh produce a new secret key
public key pair as well as a proof of
rotation
and verote we'll take in two public keys
and two sets of outputs under the
corresponding public keys and output 0
or 1.
uh intuitively we want verito to succeed
if and only if for each eye a y i in
response to say the blue box containing
x i and y i Prime corresponds to the
green box containing x i
uh and also we want to model post
compromise security uh that is the green
box contain ax should be pseudorandom
even given the old secret key
um to model more formally our security
we're going to strengthen the security
of the underlying vrs and build up on
top of that just because the stronger
security requirements on vref will make
it easier to add more complicated
definitions or more advanced definitions
uh we're going to strengthen uniqueness
and extractability condition which I
will not talk in detail about here
and we're also going to strengthen the
pseudorandoms requirement for vs do a
zero knowledge condition that is the
proofs for the vrf should be simulatable
uh even if the output of the vrf is
replaced with the output of a truly
random function
then to Define rotatable vrf security
we're just going to combine this post
compromised security property into the
zero knowledge requirement
more formally we're going to model zero
knowledge as a different as the idea
that a real and ideal game are
indistinguishable and in the real world
we can imagine some Alice interacting
with a server hosting a vrf as follows
Alice will receive a public key at the
beginning and can make any number of
queries to the vrf Alice may ask also
that the server prove that some correct
input output pairs of the Vera are in
fact correct and may ask for rotation
proofs where Alice will pass in some set
of inputs and the server will provide
the new public key as well as a proof
that the rotation was correct
um note that implicitly the server will
also receive the vrf outputs on both the
old public key and the new public key
and finally to model post compromise
Security will allow us to make
corruption queries which will return the
old see we'll return the currency
uh in addition we also uh model some
idealized object or perhaps a random
Oracle or near a group and we'll allow
us to make queries to the idealized
option
uh to Define zero knowledge um zero
knowledge will state that this world is
indistinguishable from the world where
all these oracles are replaced with the
simulator even when the vrf outputs are
all replaced with the outputs of a truly
random function indexed by the public
key
uh note that to model that rotate proofs
uh do not reveal anything about the
inputs uh we require that the rotate
proofs be simulatable only given the vrf
outputs under both the old new and old
public keys
uh to make this possible the simulator
has three capabilities first it can
control the initialization of the public
key
it has full control over the idealized
object that is it can program the random
Oracle and finally whenever a corrupt
query is made the simulator will gain
access to all queries made to the random
function
uh this is to model the idea that once
the secret key is revealed the viewf
should no longer be pseudo-random
uh before I get to our construction I'll
give a brief preliminary on ddh doubles
a ddh tuple is a four Tuple of group
elements GH G to the ahda where the last
two elements are the first two elements
raised to the same exponent
uh Tom Peterson in 93 show how to give a
zero knowledge proof that a given Tuple
is a ddh tuple and this can be made
non-interactive with the CIA Shamir
transform
um our construction for rotatable vrfs
will be based on a standardized
construction of vrs push forward by both
seamless and nist this is an efficient
uh and simple construction and our
addition will be also simple so this
really is useful for practical purposes
um
in this simple standardized construction
uh there will be a random Oracle F from
the message space to some group as well
as a group generator little G
and how the construction will work is
that Keygen will sample you secret key
uniformly at random and the public key
will be equal to G raised to the power
of the C
then the vrf output on some input X will
be the random Oracle applied text raised
to the power of the secret
to give a query proof to give a proof
that some given output corresponds to
its input all that will be necessary is
to give a proof that g f of x p k y is a
ddh double
why does this work well if this is a ddh
tuple and the public key is equal to T
to the secret key then that definitely
means that the output y will be equal to
f of x to the s k which is exactly the
same as saying that Y is the vrf applied
to X
um this is satisfies all of your uh
requirements and is satisfies both
uniqueness and pseudo Randomness and it
works totally
to add on to this we then Define uh the
rotate algorithm uh to Simply sample the
new secret key in public key uniformly
at random that is the secret key will be
sampled uniformly at random and the
public key will be accepted to the SK
just as before
we will model this for purposes of the
proof
um by saying that the new secret key
will be the old secret key to times some
randomized exponent a uh and the reason
that this is nice is because this means
that the new public key will be equal to
the old public key raised to the a oh
but this is exactly the same as just
sampling the secret key uniformly at
random
then to provide a rotate proof all that
we do is provide a proof that the public
key uh as well as the first output and
the second public key and the second
output is a ddh tuple and why does this
work well if the first output is the
output of the vrf under the first secret
key that is if y equals f of x the s k
uh and just the second public key is the
first public erase the a the DK Prime
equals DK to the a then that means that
y Prime must be y to the a which is the
same thing as the random Oracle raise
the secret key times x but since the new
secret key is the old secret key times a
this is exactly the same as saying that
y Prime is the vrf apply to X under the
new secret key
and ignoring rotations under the ddh
assumption and programmable random
Oracle model
um this vrf is zero knowledge that's by
zero knowledge
um and the idea behind this proof uh is
that you can program the random Oracle
so that the randomized output Y is
equals f of x to the S10 so once we know
the randomized output and the secret key
we can choose f of x so that this all
works out
um but the problem is that this proof
approach no longer works once we bring
in rotations
and the reason for this is that if we
say publish to public Keys PK and PK
Prime
we are going to informationally
theoretically commit to two secrets
then after we publish these public Keys
we may get some input x queried to the
random function and so we'll get some
uniformly at random chosen Y and Y Prime
and we're going to need f of x to
satisfy both the equation f of x to the
s k equals y and f of x the s k Prime
equals y Prime
since the public key information
theoretically commits the secret key
and X is going to be chosen after the
public keys are chosen these equations
may be impossible to satisfy uh just by
programming the random Oracle so what
does this mean this means that the proof
approach for the standardized vrf does
not apply when we're dealing with
rotations but that doesn't necessarily
mean at least set in time and we tried
for a bit and we could not find anything
uh so what we managed to do is we show
that this uh rotatable verif is in fact
zero knowledge under a stronger
idealized model namely generic group
model
uh and Chief's generic crew model our
policies are given access to a random
Oracle exp modeling group exponentiation
as well as an addition Oracle star which
takes uh two outputs of the EXP Oracle
and multiplies them uh as if it were
actually group exponentiation
uh importantly we allow our simulator to
program the generic group just as it
could a random Oracle
uh the key trick is that in the generic
group model giving out the public key
does not necessarily commit to its
discrete block
that is we don't need to Define discrete
logs until a corruption happens
and as when a corruption happens all
queries are revealed uh to the simulator
this means that we can choose the secret
keys after we choose after we find out
the uniformly random Y and Y plan
uh now I'll go through a little bit more
formally what exactly the simulator do
when keeping track of the generic group
uh so we can think of this exp Oracle as
really a table of group elements in
discrete logs where each group element
query corresponds to some value tracked
by the distinguisher Alice
um so what our simulator do the key
trick is that we'll replace the discrete
logs um with a uniformly random number
with polynomials and some special uh
variables and in particular discrete
logs um will be stored this way for
group elements that do not come from the
EXP Oracle like the output of the random
Oracle and the public Keys themselves
um so the variables uh that we will use
is we will set that the output of the
random Oracle will always have discrete
log of variable corresponding to its
input that is the output of the random
Oracle f of x the group element
corresponding to that we'll have
discrete log a variable B of x
and similarly we will create new
variables for each of the A's from the
rotation proofs and in particular pki
will have discrete log the product of A1
through AI
then once we have set the public keys
and random oracles to have these
discrete logs we can make sure that the
output of the CRF has corresponding
discrete logs that is the output of the
vrf under some public key and some input
should be equal should have discrete log
equal to the product of the discrete log
of the public key and the discrete log
of the random Oracle of that input
we can then Define all other addition
queries made by distinguisher to be
consistent with what we set the discrete
logs to be for these other variables
then when a corrupt query is made we
will simply replace each of these AIS
with a unit value chosen uniformly at
random
uh and this and then we will return that
the secret key that has been corrupted
will just be the discrete log of the
current public key
and what this guarantees is that the
viewer that the output y um that is
supposed to correspond to vrf of the
secret key on X will be equal to f of x
to the SK for all SK and X
the key idea here is that
um the degree of these polynomials only
increases on rotation
and since the only issue that could
occur really is that um
sampling these AIS induces the Collision
on the polynomials and since the
polynomials are have found a degree the
schwarzipalama tells us that a collision
will happen with negligible probability
and so this works
um so in conclusion uh using this
generic group model uh polynomial
programming Technique we show that
rotatable vrfs satisfy zero knowledge a
rotatable vrs then give us Post
compromise secure auditable dictionaries
in particular RZ chaos as we Define it
there are many additional subtleties and
small improvements in both parts so for
more details read our paper feel free to
come talk to me afterwards
thank you
questions
hey uh have you thought about like uh
how this would work for pairing based
prf
starting base
stir UPS um kind of use the same
construction as a VR after the pairing
group and then you know kind of verify
with the pairing
I have not thought about it at all but
come talk to me afterwards and you can
discuss yeah
okay then let's thank the speaker again
okay the final thought in this session
is uh buy online
foreign
protocol for relations in CNF the
speaker is gonji and then
okay are you ready
yeah I'm really can hear me please
proceed yes we can hear
okay there's an alarming started
uh thank you for attending this talk at
least today I would like to
I would like to present my paper dng
Sigma
a deity based stigma protocol for
relations in CF other co-authors are
General light
[Music]
the presentation will count the
following aspects the background and the
motivation
then the contributions of this paper
after that I will introduce the main
idea of the construction
so let me introduce the backgrounds and
show you what problem we have studied
and why we studied
Sigma Protocols are popular and widely
used as a building block in many
cryptographic protocols
given a binary and the polynomial time
relation and an instance X Y belonging
to R the sigma protocol is run between
the proof and the verify in three steps
a commitment a challenge and a response
are sent intent by the approval and the
verifier where the challenge is randomly
picked by the verifier
finally the verify checks whether the
transcript is valid or not
Sigma protocols have been designed to
prove kinds of relations among these
relations K Auto and partial knowledge
is well studied
as early as 1994 Karama dang and the
Shoemaker showed a general method in
2015 gross and the covenants show how to
achieve local Mystic communication when
k equals 1
very recently a 10 gram and fair
achieved local domestic communication
for General K and N in the discrete log
region setting
a relation about K Auto and passion
knowledge can be expressed in this jump
to normal formula and we call it
complete kdlf relations since the number
of the crosses is a binomial coefficient
Kom
it's natural to consider some extensions
the first one is to reduce the number of
Clauses and we call such relations in
complete kdnf relations
the second one is to reverse the symbol
or logic end and logic or and then we
get a relation in conjunction normal
formula so because such relations K C
and F relations
our paper may be focuses on KCF
relations in the discrete logarithm
setting
relations expressed in CNF are an
important correction of relations in
practice for example many Access Control
policies are naturally set in CNF and
they have been discussed in some AB
skins
in addition the instance of the case
site program expressed in CNF
we also provide a potential application
here
a
startup company wants to shoot investors
a business plan which is about building
at least a shopping mall in every key
neighboring blocks
the startup company also wants to show
it in a general knowledge way in order
to avoid the exact business load map
being leaked you can find the relation
is also in CNF
to the best of our knowledge we find the
following schemes working for KCF
relations
the first one is proposed by chroma
Adair here we call it CDs 94 however it
may lead to Super polynomial
communication costs
the second one is
the second one is a cyclicity program
proposed by ABR
but it is designed for and not an actual
technological and it seems impossible to
transfer the cyclicity program into a
standard Sigma protocol so it loses some
advantages of Sigma protocols for
example lowest organisms error by Design
high efficiency and more flexibility
therefore a course a question is
arranged naturally
is it possible to construct a more
efficient stigma protocol for KCF
relations
our paper gives an affirmative answer to
this question in the discrete logarithm
setting
next we are going to introduce
contributions on this paper
the contributions of this paper are
listed as follows first of all we
formally Define the partial knowledge of
KCF relations
we also propose a construction in the
discrete logarithm setting by
transferring the KCF relations to direct
it a cyclic graphics
that's why we call our method the AG
Sigma protocol
secondly we apply our dhg Sigma
protocols to construct similar protocols
for incomplete kdf relations due to the
time limitation we will not talk the
details here
finally we Pro we provide an
implementation based on elliptic curve
groups
it assures that when proving the example
relations in our experiments and
combined with cs94 the our dhg stigma
protocols say saves more than 95
communication cost and more than 90
percent running time
here is our theoretical compressor to
same time here I only pick the
conversion about KCF relations you can
see that the communication cost of our
skin is Big O and minus K element in
group G and the Big O absolute V
elements in group t p star
note that big red denotes the vertices
of the graphic in our dhg Sigma protocol
a discussion on upper bound of the
number of the vertices shows that the
size of our solution is smaller actually
is much smaller than that of CDs 94
which implies our skin enjoys a better
performance
here are the experimental results we
firstly issued experimental results when
k equals 4 the region the ratio shows
how much communication cost and the
running time our skin saves is clear
that there is a remarkable Improvement
list fingers are the experiment
experimental result about different
values okay according to this
experimental result we can draw such a
conclusion that when combined with CTS
94 our skin achieves a remarkable
performance Improvement on proving KCF
relations no matter from the view of
communication costs or running time
next let me introduce the main idea of
our Construction
here is a format definition or KCM
relations in short every cross contains
K different statements with logic or
then we combine these Clauses with logic
end
a valid business statement pair for such
relation requires that every Clause
contains at least a true statement
in other words for every cross among the
case statements the prover knows at
least one weakness of them
then we are going to introduce two
building blocks the first one is the is
an algorithm KCF to JG as the name
implies the algorithm is to transfer a
KCF relation to a daisy
there are two properties of the dag
output by this algorithm the properties
guarantees the correctness of our skin
firstly every node in some parts maps to
a statement in some corresponding Clause
secondly the number of passes with
length k equals to equals the number of
across
we take relation R1 for example it
contains four Clauses and each Clause
has three statements
finger 5 shows a simple idea to transfer
the relation R1 and you can find that
there are four passes and each path maps
to a clause in R1
in finger 6 we introduce three kinds of
states with respect to the in degree and
auto degree of the nose and they are
denoted as a b and e we can merge those
nodes which represent the same statement
and have the same state as a result is
clear that finger 6 contains less nodes
than finger five
but the simple operation show in finger
sticks cannot work for some relations
for example we present another relation
R2 combined with R1 R2 has one more
cross here we marked it in red
using the same method of finger 6 we get
a result in finger seven and the Clause
marked in red is transferred to the path
with dotted lines more exactly the path
is A4 B3 and E1
then you can find that lay is a Crossing
in finger seven more exactly there is a
Crossing in node B3
then you can find other new passes
for example A4 B3 and E2
which should maps to across Sigma 2
Sigma 3 and sigma 4. however we cannot
find such clause in relation R2
therefore the number of passes in finger
seven is not equal to the numbers or
Clauses or relation R2 then it's
contradictory to the properties we
mentioned before
a solution is shown in finger 8. more
exactly the node P3 is divided into two
nodes b31 and p32
the example tests us that the tig output
by kcf2 dag should not contain any
closings
in fact the algorithm KCF to JG is
simple and only contains three steps
preparing node merging pre-physics and
emerging substance
for the details of algorithm please
refer to our paper here we take the
relation R2 for example and show how the
algorithm works finger 9 shows the first
step more exactly for each cross in R2
we generate a path then in finger 10 we
show how we merge prefixes here note A51
and the node A52 emerged into one node
A5 similarly if node A4 1 and node a42
are merged into node A4
Finger Eleven and finger tail show how
to merge subsets similarly node E11
E12 and e13 emerge into node E1 after
that the surface of the node B21 and the
node B22 are the same in other words the
surfaces are not node E1 then we can
merge node B21 and the node B22 into
node B2 finally we get a dag and we can
check that the dag satisfies properties
we want
here is the upbound of the number of
vertices
we can know one item is the binomial
coefficient D divided by 2 o n
note that in the original expression our
KCF relation the number of statements
can be K times number where number
denotes the number of crosses the
maximum of the number is the binomial
coefficient K Over N therefore the
theory implies that our method can
achieve a good Improvement
we also provide another method to
analyze the upper Bound in our full
paper maybe it's easier for you to
understand
first we prepare two same stamp graphics
the dance of the passes in the sub
Graphics is K divided by two lists
and the number of the passes in each sub
graphy is the binomial coefficient K
divided by 2 of n
then for each cross we divide the cross
into two parts for each parts
we find the corresponding path in the
corresponding subgraphy and we add an
arrow between the two parts is
finally we remove those passes with
length K divided by two we can track
that the dang satisfy the properties we
defined before and is easier to get that
the number of vertices is K times the
binomial efficient okay divided by 2 o n
which is similar to the result in our
theorem you can find that in some cases
the result in our theory is a title
bound
next to introduce another building block
is a sigma protocol for One auto okay
partial knowledge in the discrete
logarithm the relation is shown in
equation 3 in short the pover knows at
least one discrete logarithm of them
then we record the chameleon mode of the
snow Sigma protocol note that in the
standard model the approval in this
first step picks a random number R and
computes the commitment using r
is different in the chameleon mode
what exactly the plural in the first
steps
caused us the simulator to generate the
commitment in other words besides a
random number are the proverb also
computes the commitment using another
random challenge C pi
here is our Sigma protocol for One auto
K partial knowledge based on Snow's
Sigma protocol the main idea is that for
each statement we compute the hash value
of its commitment and the hash value is
a challenge for the next statement such
that we can call the simulator to
generate the commitment for the next
statement
one of the advantages is that the
approver only needs to send one
commitment of the case statements to the
verify in other words we only need to
send A1 to the verifier therefore we can
reduce the communication cost a lot
finally we show our dhg Sigma protocol
in the discrete logarithm using the
about two building blocks here is the
KCF relation in the discrete logarithm
setting
and our TIG Sigma has two steps the
first step is to run the algorithm KCF
to Dag and get a dag
we can know that the dense of each path
in the dag is K so the second step for
each this kind of step is that for each
path in the dag we run a proving
algorithm which is similar to that of
one out of K partial knowledge
yeah
there are some differences between our
skin and the protocol for one other okay
passion knowledge in the One auto okay
partial knowledge the relation is
translated to into one pass is the
landscape
the hash function only takes one
commitment as input as the corresponding
node has only one arrow pointing to it
however it becomes a bit complicated in
the KCF relations
we're taking the relation R1 for example
and its corresponding dag issue here
we can find that there are two arrows
pointing to node B2 then using the same
method we can know that the challenge
for node B2 will be influenced by two
commitments in other words it will be
influenced by the commitment of node A3
and the node A4
so the hash function takes as input
the commitment of node A3 and node A4
finally in our paper we proved that the
dhg sigma protocol provides
computational knowledge soundness and is
special hvjk
for the communication complexity we
prove that it depends on the number of
the vertices of the Dag
and we show that front view of the
communication complexity our skin is
better than CDs 94.
here are some references of this
presentation
that's all for my presentation thank you
thanks for the talk
any questions
[Music]
okay so uh it looks at uh
when you're when you're a protocol is
turned into a non-interactive using a
heuristics
it looks like it looks like very similar
to the to the one that you introduced in
the body part of your torque which is uh
a single a cyclicity programming
approach
do you how do you compare
those two uh approaches
with respect to the non-interactive case
uh yes exactly our method is similar to
the cyclicity program uh in fact we
compare combat it with our method in the
in our papers and the cyclicity program
is designed for non-inactive Journal
knowledge and we try to
convert it into a standard Sigma
protocol however we fed so that we
propose the dag Sigma protocol
okay
okay thank you very much
any other comments questions
then let's thank the speakers and all
speakers in this session thanks
thank you very much