yeah
or focusing recession the first topics
Universal link signature in the standard
model by Pedro Branco Nico dot ring
Sarah one and sterawin poke please
okay hello good morning and thanks for
coming to this very early session
um I'm Stella and I'm presented in a
joint work with Peter Bronco and Nico
dudling and our paper is called
Universal ring signatures in the
standard model
um to explain I will first get into
water ring signatures
okay
so ring signatures are just regular
signatures where instead of using one
key and signing and verification you use
a whole ring of keys and what you get
from this is anonymity and unfortability
so if you have a verifying signature you
want to be sure that somebody in this
ring has signed it but you should not be
able to tell who exactly so this is the
anonymity part
where it's used nowadays this is used a
lot in cryptocurrencies but today we
want to go back to its first use case
which was whistleblowing and the whole
idea here is with this ring you can
basically hide yourself in a crowd and
it will not be clear who exactly
um said something
so governments don't really like
whistleblowers and they want to protect
themselves against it so
um what is the setup for whistleblowing
basically an employee wants to leak some
data to a journalist and the whole
reason why we want signatures here at
all is for authenticity so the
journalist wants to be sure that the
leak that they receive is from somebody
who actually has access to this type of
data and it's not from a Reddit troll
who's just making things up
so how is this done we assume that the
employee already has the public
verification key for example for an RSA
digital signature and in a first step
they will pick people among which they
want to be anonymous they choose their
keys and they make a key ring
in a second step they use this ring to
sign their leak and they use a ring
signature to do this so they can be
anonymous but the journalists are sure
that somebody from those people for
example everybody working in the same
department
has actually signed this and the data is
authentic
but we can never have nice things so
it's not really so easy nowadays because
well
we don't just have RSA so there's a lot
of different schemes in place
and not for all of them is it clear
whether there are ring signatures or not
and especially if you have to use
different uh key signatures
keys from different signature schemes
because maybe not everybody in your
department is using RSA
it's not quite clear there are some
previous results which do this for some
types of schemes but there is no result
yet that shows that for every type of
scheme you can do this
so a clever government might have the
idea oh okay maybe if these signatures
they all allow for ring signatures we
just forbid all of them
and we wanted to ask ourselves if this
is actually possible and if there remain
any schemes that you can use which do
not allow to be used in such an
unlimited ring
and our result says
no
no there is no
some terms and conditions to apply and
we will get to this in our talk today
so
our proof is constructive so we actually
give a new primitive called Universal
ring signatures which solve precisely
this problem
so
um if you get different keys from any
type of signing schemes we allow you to
make a ring and then a ring signature
from it
and the Syntax for this is as follows we
do not have a key generation because the
key generation needs to be inherited
from the underlying signature skills
like we want this to be fully compatible
with already published keys
and
otherwise we only include an additional
list of schemes that are allowed so this
is really the only change so basically a
verifying signature is now the signature
that verifies for one of these keys
under one of these schemes
so
there is a very very obvious solution to
this which uses a trusted setup or the
random Oracle model
and
we don't want to do this the question is
why don't we do this
would be so easy
so for the CRS you have to note that
whistleblowing is not a trusted scenario
so whoever is used in the anonymity ring
might later claim they do not trust the
CRS used
because this is kind of like an
adversial setting where people get
included without them agreeing
so this is bad and for the random Oracle
the problem is that it needs to be
instantiated in practice and we show in
our paper that there are some potential
soundness issues with this
so it is the standard model then why is
this paper Worthy
let's get into the challenge
so
um we have two properties first
unfortability essentially what happens
here is the adversary gets some ring of
honest keys
they can corrupt some keys they can ask
for some signatures and also ring
signatures and in the end essentially
they do have to provide us with a porch
that is a verifying signature a very
fine ring signature for just another
strings for just honest keys in the ring
and
since we know that we cannot change
anything in the keys and we cannot
really put any additional setup things
um the only thing we realize that we can
base unforgeability on is
unfortunatability of the underlying
schemes
and therefore from this Forge we must be
able to
extract the signature for one of the
underlying schemes okay let's keep that
in mind
on the other hand we have anonymity
where also the adversary gets some
honest keys
and they can then pick two of these keys
and we will sign with one of them and
they have to guess which one signed
and what we note here is that what they
get here
um it's very much shaped like what we
get in their Forge
so if the adversary here would be able
to also extract the signature from Sigma
star that would be very very bad because
then they could infer which of the
people actually signed
so they must not be able to extract
and now the question is really how can
the reduction in unforgeability get an
edge over the anonymity adversary
without changing anything in the key
structure or putting other additional
elements because that's how it is
usually done in pre-existing ring
signatures
so
let's recap we need to hide a signature
somewhere where only the reduction can
find it
and we found two different ways to do
this
one way is we give the reduction more
runtime and then we use complexity
leveraging but this is not the most
elegant solution
and so the second thing we did is we did
find a way to give the reduction some
more information and then use witness
encryption based on it we will give a
bit more information about both of these
constructions in this talk but first a
little bit of a comparison
so there are these two previous works
they do give ring signatures for a
couple of
signature schemes but they assume a
certain structure on them and also they
are not in the standard model
our complexity leveraging scheme
has the downside that we need the
signatures to be super polynomial and
secure so this is not truly Universal in
that sense so that's why we decided to
fix it with this witness encryption
Construction
however there are Forest results is only
linear in the size of the Ring
and we do Boost this by making a special
witness encryption using IO
and there is another caveat that we have
to note so we do have to lower our
anonymity guarantee a little bit
so normally you're anonymous as I told
you before where you have to have two
honest keys and in this case we need a
fixed higher number of keys usually this
will be three or four honest keys in a
ring for achieving anonymity
okay
so let's get into the first solution
with complexity leveraging this is more
of a warm-up it's pretty standard so
um
given a key and a message that you want
to sign what we said is we want to be
able to extract signature in the end so
let's first make a regular signature
and then we want to hide the signature
and we decided to hide the signature in
a commitment
and we use a keyless commitment so that
we can forego this changing of the keys
and the Assumption here is really that
this commitment can be broken in some
super polynomial time T but the
signature schemes cannot
and additionally we add a Navy probe to
show that everything is done correctly
and this constitutes the ring signature
this is
unfortable
simply by these assumptions so if the
adversary could make a forge we could
extract in time
a team from it an underlying signature
which
violates the unforgeability that is
assumed
so this is an unfortable scheme for
anonymity we do a bit of a standard
trick so instead of doing this whole
commitment once we do it twice and then
also provide an or in the media proof
and then we can basically switch
the fulfilled statement from one side to
the other and swap the signatures that I
used around
so that's also very
clever
and there is one problem here which is
the size if you look closely here
there's a really really really long or
statement that says this must be a true
for the first key and the first scheme
or the second key and the first scheme
or the seventh key and the 13th scheme
and so forth so this will blow up really
really badly and there is gladly a trick
for this from the literature which uses
somewhere perfectly binding hashing and
we will omit this here for time reasons
and the only thing that Still Remains is
that we do not like the super polynomial
assumption
so how can we fix that
so as I said this commitment thing was
really used because we didn't need a key
and what we thought was a good
replacement would be witness encryption
because there you can use a statement as
a key that can be inferred from The
Ring signature without changing keys
and this can help us drop this uh super
polynomial assumption
and
what are we using as a statement oh no
first okay witness encryption
encrypt to a statement and then it
decrypts to witness for this statement
if you have a correct witness then you
get back what was encrypted if there is
no correct witness namely if the
statement is false then you get CPA
security just as an overview
so
yes
um in this uh challenge that I showed
you before with these two uh different
experiments we noticed that there is
just one little little bit where we do
have some
um degree of freedom for the reduction
and that is the choice of this
Randomness here
um really everything else is kind of
fixed in handing out the keys
but this we can do
so what do we do with it
basically normally you would have some
independently chosen keys but we make a
second mode where we have some mail form
Keys you can think of this for now that
you have some general key that would
help you
um
to use instead of all of these Keys you
can just use this one General key
what is this General key in our qas it
is a prf key which is used to make the
seeds for the signing keys
so we're using this one degree where we
have Randomness really to choose
so
this is naturally a lot more sparse like
for normal independently chosen teeth it
is very unlikely that such a prf key
exists that we can make all of their
randomnesses from it
and so these are indistinguishable
website awareness these two
distributions but they are also far
apart
and there is a witness
for us having chosen a malformed key
uh distribution namely this prf key
so we basically have everything we need
for witness encryption
to do it a little bit more specifically
so here you can see uh for standard Keys
we have all these randomnesses so
actually learn them and for malformed
Keys we have them as a prf of 1p and
their index
and
what we note now
um we think about what precisely to pick
as a statement so basically we only want
to use these malform keys where we want
the reduction to extract so in
unfortability and there the reduction
can control all but one key so one key
they have to get from the underlying
unfortability experiment
um
so naturally we just choose the
statement the statement is a ring of
keys and it is in the language if all
but one of the keys are malformed in
this way
so
um what does now hold in the anonymity
like we already made sure in
unforgeability that we can extract but
in anonymity what happens so the
adversary must use T honest keys
um in RT anonymity this is potentially
more than two this is where this comes
from
so
um basically for them to succeed in
opening the witness encryption they need
that at least T minus one of them
because they can choose their small male
form but they cannot choose the honest
ones to be essentially malformed and
then
um we show that this is unlikely
by looking at the Min entropy
so the main entropy of the malformed
keys is always going to just be Lambda
because we really only choose this one
key but then on the other hand since for
standard keys they are all independently
chosen we have the number of keys times
the lowest entropy of each of these key
generation schemes
as a lower bound on the entropy so if we
pick T big enough then this will be
considerably bigger
so what do we need to pick
so we can assume for a secure scheme
that people would accept that this
amount of entropy in the key generation
is roughly in the order of the security
parameter and so here for example if
it's half the amount of bits as the
security parameter so like out of every
two bits of Randomness you get one bit
of entropy in the key
then uh ts4 is sufficient and we think
that this will be a reasonable
assumption for a lot of schemes
so to put it together basically we
dropped the commitment and put a witness
encryption there
but everything else stays as it was
before
and unfortability now holds
as I just explained because the
reduction can get one key from the
underlying Challenge from
the unfoldibility of the underlying
scheme and the rest that picks malformed
and then they can extract and anonymity
it will take honest keys and as we just
discussed then it's very unlikely that
the adversary can extract
foreign
the size
namely here the statements in the
witness encryption they are very very
long because they include all of the
Rings so
um I will quickly give you an overview
of how we will fix this
so instead of using one outputting one
long witness encryption for all of the
keys we split it into smaller witness
encryptions for where we just say oh
this key is now from this key is
malformed
and we sign we hide in them shares
um which we pick such that a random
um number gets out of the secret sharing
if we get enough of them
decrypted
and we use this basically as a one-time
pad encryption of the message that we
want to transmit and now what we notice
that a large part of this we can create
via a program instead of sending all of
these single ones we give a program that
essentially has
some information in a hash stored about
the
um
keys and then you will input one of the
keys and it will verify yeah this is the
set probably and then it gives you the
corresponding ciphertext instead of you
getting all the ciphertext so this is
what we do to reduce the size and this
is where we need to use IO then
okay so as an overview we have shown
today that ring signature is accessed
for any type of signing schemes and also
for using multiple types of signing
schemes together
and we do not need collaboration of any
kind we've given three constructions one
with the complexity leveraging and two
with correlated Keys one of them is
linear in size the other one needs to
use IO
and
thank you for listening this talk are
there any questions
okay
any questions
thank you for the great talk uh I didn't
see why you don't want to use uh London
Morocco model what I find something
issue means that it's a theoretical
uh in theoretical sense so if there is
some uh artificial scheme that uh if we
instantiate random Morocco with their
hash function then it may be uh in
insecure so what do you mean by yeah
yeah it's pretty much in that sense so
we show that for
um a secure signature scheme we can
embed like an obfuscated circuit that
will give you a ring signature and then
this would have to be
um
still secure
in the random Oracle model if we had a
proof there but it is not
okay thanks
a question
no
yeah
I just uh super question what is the
assumption that frequency encryption
exists sorry but what is the Assumption
weakness encryption exists
what assumption foreign
[Music]
I think we just assumed that witness
encryption exists I know that it exists
from IO but potentially it could exist
from less than IO so this is why we
distinguish between these two cases
I assume that are you all right
yeah your first team also assumed are
you all right yeah the third scheme
assumes IO directly and for the second
scheme it is not clear whether we need i
o to have witness encryption
and we just know it's sufficient so we
wanted to make the distinction if
witness encryption becomes easier
at some point
okay
[Music]
yeah
thanks speaker again
next stop is
the next stop is uh
uh the ability brain signatures by
you're a customer Julian Ross Jian you
and
seriously
all right are you ready
I think Julia will talk
okay uh thanks for the introduction
um yeah this is the talk about the other
okamoto partial live line signatures
team we visited
um this is Joint work with you young
loss and Xiao
microphone doesn't seem to be working
that well
um
yeah so in this team in this work we
talk about uh partially blind signatures
so first I want to explain to you what
those are
um so in a partially blind signature
scheme we have a signer here denoted by
a scroll and the user here denoted by
unicorn and the signer has a secret key
and the user knows the corresponding
public key and also a message that he
wants signed by the signer and they also
agree on a shared information info so
this could be for example a monetary
value that we assigned to the message
signature pair or also it could be an
expiration date for the message
signature pair
and we consider three move partially
blind signatures so uh here there are
three messages that are being sent back
and forth between the signer and the
user and in the end the user learns a
signature on the message
that he has
to motivate the security properties that
we want from this let's look at a
potential application
so uh in the case of electronic cash the
signer will be the bank
and then the users are people who have
bank accounts and who might want to
withdraw money that they can then spend
somewhere
um so in this case we have some users
who have withdrawn one dollar and two
users have withdrawn five dollars and
now if one of the five dollar users
spends their money we want that the bank
cannot tell which is the person who
bought something
um and more formally this means we have
the partial blindness so here we want to
protect an honest user against a
malicious signer and the malicious
signer will be allowed to choose the
public key two messages and attack info
to attack
and then the user chooses a bit which
will determine uh when he uses which
message so when they interact twice the
user will want use one of the messages
in one interaction and the other message
in the other interaction
and
um in the end the user will either
output both message signature pairs if
both interactions were successful or it
will output an error symbol if at least
one of the interactions was unsuccessful
and these values are given to the signer
and the signer has then to determine
which of the messages was used in which
of the interactions
on the other hand of course for
electronic cash we would want that if a
user withdrew some money uh he cannot
spend more or he cannot use different
coins than what he got
so uh here the user again has two fives
and one one
and we would for example not want that
this user can somehow output three fives
in the end
um so for this we want one more
unfortunatability
so here we protect an owner signer
against a malicious user and uh here
again the signer will output a public
key for the user to use
and then the user gets to interact with
the signer multiple times so uh also for
multiple tags that he chooses so here
for a green tag uh red tag
a blue tag
and again for the green tag for example
and now if he has interacted for some
tag L times
uh the user will win the game if he
manages to Output more than L message
signature pairs for this tag
so here the user would win for example
if he manages for the green tag to
Output L plus one message signature
pairs
in this work we consider a partially
blind signature scheme by Avon okabuto
this is an efficient discrete logarithm
based scheme
and it has been a very influential work
because it's an inspiration for other
schemes that use a similar technique the
all-proof technique so examples of other
schemes that uses or proof technique are
esteemed by others this is a fully blind
signature scheme uh the anonymous
Prudential slide scheme and also a very
recent lattice based scheme called Blind
ore
and especially the proof strategy from
the original work is of interest for
other similar scheme that also uses or
proof technique
so in this work we were looking at the
proof for the one more unfortunatability
and we found a gap in the proof and we
mended that Gap while achieving similar
bounds in terms of reduction loss as the
original work
so let's look at how the scheme works
so um it is a scheme that's based on
groups so discrete logarithm so we have
a secret key which is an exponent
um and the public key is a group
generator raised to that exponent
and um then there's a second part to the
key in the you know manner of speaking
which is
um this set which is a hash of the
shared information info so recall this
could be something like the monetary
value so we would hash
for example one dollar
and um
what's going to happen is on the sinus
side
there's an or proof that the signer
knows either this secret key X or the
discrete logarithm of this attack key
set
and this is done in a very similar way
to
um snow signatures for example or blind
snore signatures so there's these two
initial equivalents that are sent as a
kind of commitment
and then
the user will blind these group elements
into other group elements and hash them
along with the message and the info
to then blind into a challenge value e
that he sends over to the signer
and the signer does send the author of
computation to respond with this two
components the orange component
corresponding to a proof of dialogue
knowledge of the X and the green
component corresponding to a proof of
dialogue knowledge of the set
um
and then the user can again line these
values to obtain the actual signature
so the signature is going to consist of
these four exponents
the verification works like this so
um
in the verification we just add together
this Omega and Delta value and check
that is equal to the hash of these group
elements that can be computed from the
signature along with a message and the
info and you don't need to remember the
the details about which exponents are
here you can just think of if you're
familiar with snow signatures that this
is an or proof of two small signatures
so now I'm going to talk a bit about the
approved strategy so the basic idea is
that the reduction can either simulate
the signing using this uh actual secret
key X and extract the discrete logarithm
of Z so it will program a random all
code so that actually the discrete login
challenge is embedded there
or it could use the discrete logarithm
offset Again by programming the random
Oracle
to generate signatures and then try to
extract the discrete logarithm of the
public key so the secret key X
um in a bit more detail
the reduction first is going to pick a
secret key X
or pick the D log set
so it chooses which one it will use
and then in the next step it will run
the adversary once
um to obtain L plus one message
signature pairs from the adversary and
then it will reprogram the random Oracle
after a specific point
and then it will run the adversary
another time
so this time it will use the same random
coins for the adversary and also
um all the random choices it makes
itself during signing will be the same
the only thing that changes is really
the way it responds to these random
Oracle queries
and then it will hold to get the other
key from the signatures that the
adversary outputs so um
this other key will then be the solution
to the discrete logarithm problem
and uh the most difficult part in the
proof is this analysis of why we
actually get this other key with a
reasonable probability
and this is also where the Gap in the
original proof occurs
so let's look into why this is difficult
to see that we can actually get the
other key so what happens in the proof
is we use the forking technique
um
and the forking technique means we
respond differently to the hash values
but to the hash queries in the second
round
so we pick a place in the um
in the hash queries where there was a
signature before
and now starting from that point
uh different hash response will be given
to Hash queries in the second round
from that uh
there will hopefully be two signatures
that can then be used to compute at
least one of the witnesses that was used
to generate the signature
but with an all-proof so what happens is
either
because we change the hash value and we
know there's these two components that
need to add up together to get the hash
value so either the orange component
changes in which case
um from the two signatures at this
forking point we can get this discrete
logarithm X of the public key or the
other thing that can happen is that this
green component changes and in this case
we would get the discrete logarithm
offset of this hash uh hash of
information info
so as a reduction however what's going
on is the reduction has this secret key
which I've formally denoted in purple
so the reduction will also potentially
receive different queries uh as a
challenge in the signing sessions and so
it will also need to respond in a
different way so the reductions behavior
in a sense also Forks so the reduction
will Fork According to which secret key
it has so it will fork in this purple
line
but it's once from the adversary that
the adversary will actually fork in the
blue line so it will actually reveal
this other key that the reduction does
not have
and
um
so here we have sort of a difference in
behavior of the reduction and the
adversary and we need to argue that
this difference uh will occur often
enough
so now I'm going to stiff skip some
technical details and uh we'll get into
a more abstract
a matter of speaking
so
um yeah let me explain this graph so we
can uh kind of think of these
hash Vector with like hash response
vectors as a graph so uh the vertices in
the graph are the vectors of hash values
that we give as a response
and the edges will exist like for each
um index at which we could Fork there
will be such a graph and there's an edge
between two of these vectors if they
fall from each other at this point
and you can also see that depending on
which witness the reduction uses to
simulate actually we get two graphs
and these graphs are not necessarily the
same so they might be different
and
um what the reduction does essentially
is it samples one of the edges from this
graph so it samples two vectors that
fork from each other at a specific point
so in the original work
um they came up with a clever primitive
which is or like a clever technical tool
which is uh these triangles
and triangles here consist of two sides
and a base so the base is a special type
of edge in this graph which has very
nice properties
but it is hard to find for the reduction
it's very unlikely that the reduction
was Sample such a base
um
but it is more likely that the reduction
will sample a side of a triangle and
sides have potentially less nice
properties but they are likely to sample
and so the goal is to somehow transfer
the nice properties that we get from the
basis uh to the sides
so
um you can imagine these spaces
uh to to explain kind of what this
special property is
um
they are hash vectors that don't cause
the
adversary to ask different questions
during the signing so for both of the uh
for both of these um
two uh hash vectors at the end of the
base the queries that the adversary
makes during signing will actually be
the same
and this can be used to achieve nice
properties in the base
so the key property of a triangle is
that if we do not get the nice witness
so the witness that the reduction needs
from both of the sides then actually we
can also not get it from the base
so if both of the sites are marked red
so they are bad for the reduction then
also the base must be bad
in turn this however means that if the
base is good of the triangle so the base
yields the nice witness actually at
least one of the sites must also yield
this nice witness so this is kind of
this transferring property
and now we get to uh the Gap in the
original work which is this claim
um which is that if four over five of
the triangle sides yield a bad witness
then three out of five of the triangle
bases also yield the bad witness and so
uh here's a little drawing as an example
so we can see here there's eight out of
10 of the triangle sides that are marked
red and this implies that actually three
out of five of the triangle bases are
also migrate
um
however you can see here that in this
example the triangles are all disjoint
and uh this is where it becomes tricky
because actually if they are
um sharing
components the triangles then
um
this claim does not hold anymore so here
you can see we have some triangles again
and
um
five out of six of the triangle sides
are migrated but actually half of the
triangle bases are not so here this
claim does not hold anymore
so what we need to do is to find some
different argument for y actually we
have enough good triangle sites in such
a case
and so let's go back to this graph that
we saw earlier
so here let's save we just like make the
Assumption maybe this happens on the X
side that there's this kind of triangle
base that is applied in a lot of
triangles with uh bad sides
to this bad base
um then actually we identify a set of
such triangle bases
that have a lot of corresponding
triangle tops so our part in a lot of
triangles on both of the sides so there
is exists some kind of inefficient
mapping
that transports us to this parallel
universe where we actually use the other
witness to simulate and in this case uh
this triangle base will be good because
there it yields the witness that we
actually want
and now we remember kind of okay if a
triangle base is good then actually
at least one of the triangle sides of
each of the triangles that it
participates in must also be good so now
we get some blue uh triangle sites here
uh on this other side so uh this gives
us some probability that we will
actually succeed
as a reduction
uh but we're not quite done yet so the
other thing that can happen is that
triangle is somehow share sides and the
problematic case here is that if they
share the sites that are good so we know
they have one good site but they might
share that good side with another
triangle which in the end would mean
that it's less likely for us to actually
as a reduction find uh that good side
so here we have as an example this image
where again
um 8 out of 10 of the triangle sites are
bad but actually the triangle bases have
a very different distribution so here
four of six of the triangle bases are
good despite most of the triangle sides
being bad
and so we somehow need to deal with this
case as well and basically we can find a
combinatorial argument
uh for why this cannot happen so you
might see here that there is somehow a
triangle base missing
that would be red
because uh this like dotted line
is not in the picture
and so basically what we argue is that
this case where the dotted line is
missing which would then actually give
us potentially a good triangle base on
the other side this cannot happen too
often
and now I'm going to summarize uh what
happened
so uh the original scheme by other
Camuto is an efficient partially blind
signature scheme
we mended some gaps that we found in the
proof
while still achieving a similar
reduction loss to the original work
unfortunate unfortunately this reduction
loss means that there's only a small
number of signing sessions that can be
open in parallel but this is actually
kind of inherent to this type of scheme
because there's this Ros attack
um on schemes of this type like online
snow signatures it works as well
um so this is uh this is an attack that
works when there's many signing sessions
open at the same time
and so an open question would be are
there schemes that maybe use this
technique
that allow for polynomial number of
signing sessions to be open at the same
time so this would mean that we need to
somehow overcome this loss which is
related to the number of signing
sessions
and one candidate for such a steam could
be this uh partial this fully blind
signature scheme by other
um which is believed to be immune
against this attack and uh shown to be
polynomially secure in the algebraic
group model but we do not yet have a
proof of polynomial security
um
in without the algebraic group model
so this concludes my talk uh I thank you
for your attention
and I'd be happy to take your questions
so uh I am the original inventor
and I have to say thanks so much for
analyzing that uh very complicated proof
in that depth and finding the bug in the
very deep point
and uh one uh one of my question is that
uh okay in the open questions you point
out that uh still that scheme is only
um or a secure only for a very small
number of signing but for these days
there are some bootstrapping uh
um Paradigm do you think that there is a
possibility that this one fits to that
boost bootstrapping Paradigm to upgrade
its security
um yeah so we actually were thinking
that this might work for the scheme
because it has this so I know these
bootstrapping techniques for these
schemes based on linear functions and I
think this scheme might fit into this
linear function thing
um but of course the the
um this this puts I think they puts
every technique would need to be adapted
but I think it is possible that it might
fit into this linear function uh
Paradigm somehow and then be able to be
bootstrapped
great thanks a lot
thanks for the question
it's nice to do again
next talk is online so I hope uh speaker
will show up
uh yes okay uh the next stop is
analysis of algebraic group model which
uh by Jonathan Katz Kong
in talk
and can you see this on my screen
yes yes okay cool thanks thanks for the
introduction
um yeah so this is a Channel with
Channel cards and Tonga so the title is
my voice okay
your slides are not in presentation View
yeah
it's a readable or not
that's better
okay
okay the title of the talk is an
analysis of the algebraic group model
so
oh
sorry give me a second
okay here's a plan so first I will talk
a little bit about the background
um
what is the general group model and
algebraic group model and then I will
present our main result which is our
analysis of the AGM model
um the group is the cryptography receive
a lot of attention since the beginning
of publicly cryptography so we have a
beautiful TV Hyman protocol I got my
encryption Shino signatures yeah and the
security of this photographical schemes
and curricular Protocols are based on
the Honey's assumptions
so which is relative to a group
right so we are following the approval
security
um approach so if
the underlying assumption
hold holds then
the designer scheme is secure
so even we do not make a ex seeing the
expression we must know that the
hardness assumption relative to uh
um a group so we use a conclude the
encoding
we often we do not like like make the
encoding explicit
so group encoding so here is a injective
map from Z sub P to zero one L so here L
is the lens
we can consider the trigger encoding
which is a binary integer and we
consider this addition
right we use this ID
and in the textbook right when we have a
learn cryptography we often said D log a
d log assumption is believed to be hard
but here we this is under the concluding
encoding so here
the underlying for example this is taken
from the textbook for example has an
inner textbook right
if um this is a subgroup of zq star and
the operator is the multiplication
so we can believe D log assumption is is
hard
and we know that
in some encoding for example the
retriever encoding D log is not a hard
it actually is drivable
so
um encoding the matter
um more background is that we in this
talk we will consider security cameras
okay so we follow the the famous epilera
Rockaway Style
and in a game so here is a famous
d-logger game
so we have a game and this is advisory
right and we have encoding advisory is
given like two group elements and
anniversary is supposed to figure out
um the D log
okay and I believe everyone knows it's
this game right and based on the game we
can Define the event that it would win
again
so then we can Define the winning
probability
based on the security camera we can
Define security reductions right we say
again H imply the game G
so that means we can actually
develop a reduction r
so
here
anniversary a
you got
break this game right this a here we can
use a
to construct
um another algorithm B
okay to pick and break this uh this game
right so this is actually also in the
textbook
so
um we can
um this is a security reduction
okay
so now this topic is about a
algebraic group model and a general
group model
so the reason is that when we talk about
the concluding encoding many things are
not unknown if for example we do not
know any unconditional hardness can be
established
in the uh with respect to any concluded
encoding
so shop back to like 19
1997 so it should developed the
following model
so here we have the game right and in
the game we have the adversary
so now the game advisory can make a
like Argo query to obtain the encoding
so here either a or the game can make a
like Curry eggs here is from z p we know
that the encoding is Sigma is zp
map to zero one right zero
okay so we can make this kind of query
this query called a labeling query
foreign
Sigma over X
there's another second type of interface
it's called a group operation in
interface so here we submitted two like
a group of elements or encoding
to the Oracle and Oracle will check
okay if these conditions satisfied
if this encode this group element is a
encoding of X and SGA is the encoding of
Y then we can add these two like X and Y
we obtain Z and then we send the sigma
over Z as the response
if this is not satisfied we then the
Oracle will return a part
so this is the the sugar model
sugars
General group model
and the malware has a different version
in this talk we mainly focus on shook
and the cool thing is that in the sugar
model we can establish a absolute low
bonds right you can in the in the shoes
paper so for example I got low balance
CDH and then many like hardness
absolutely hardness can be established
unconditionally
okay so this is one way to respect the
the power of the algorithm we consider
only consider generic algorithms so
later
so people consider algebraic algorithms
in a in a crypto 2018 paper
so we call the F okay our paper fko 18
paper so algebraic group model was
introduced
so here this is the game and this
adversary advisory will start with a
page set of elements group elements then
this advisory can produce like a new
group of elements for example here is a
sigma y
and this new group of elements is
produced along with the must be along
with the
representation here I'm using R1 to R
sub k
right
and this new group element
is based on
existing group elements in this space
set
okay remember so new group element can
be produced but will be based on
the group elements
in in the page set
and apparently this person can increase
right but the algebraic algorithm can
produce more and more new group elements
okay
and this model this agent model received
a lot of attention and like you can
check like many many like research
papers appeared in in crypto your crypto
GCC it's about this uh it's based on
this
this 2018 paper
okay
so in this AGM model
so the orders
the fkl 18 paper the order that also
show uh but claim they can show a
technical limit
so basically generic reduction
um
between games
between games in the agent model
implies
the reduction
generic reduction in the TGM model
okay so how to understand this
so so so let's say the game age
implies the kmg in the agent model
right and they they can say they say
these were implied
is H
MH implies is G in the TJ model
um
data says if H is hard
if H is hard in the GM then this game G
is also hard in the GM
right it's kind of like a lifting a
living Lemma
yeah and these Lemma actually
essentially used in their fko paper and
also in many follow-up pairs
um
that's the ATM model
so they have a a way to produce new
Global elements and they have uh they
claim they can show a pilemma okay
in our paper
we basically we we do a security
analysis of this model and we identify
um some issues
with the ATM model
um
for example
as I said new group elements right
there's the intuition okay new group
elements can be produced
but
these new group elements must be
produced
through like um the value that group
operations
and in their paper this is their
intuition the only way to produce
um for uh algebraic algorithm to produce
new group elements is this is through
like a value group operation
based on known in the business based on
known group elements right because
remember right in the previous slide so
here this is unknown
it's the known group elements
okay the only way for algebraic
algorithm to produce a new group element
is through like a group operator
through a valid collaboration to and
based on known government then you can
get a new government along with the
representation
so that's the that's the inclusion
and we we said we found like um these
are their intuition and their actual
definition there's a mismatch
and we can construct
um
we can derive new group elements
but using non-group operation
okay we didn't use like Google operation
we are still able to produce a new
government
but it was like a validator
uh representation so here this is our
example
so here we consider like retriever
encoding right remember here the the
base
here
the non-government is a is a one right
we consider this group okay another
group of operator is addition
so here we in a line two we were using
like nine group operations remember
when we talk about the trivial encoding
the group operation the value
collaboration is addition
okay remember right in many slides back
right it's addition but here we didn't
use a Very Good Vibration we were using
like multiplication which which is a
non-corporation we are still we are
still able to get a good uh element
right s is actually
s is equivalent it's in a zp right
and also this second is
the representation it's a value
representation okay right so how to
understand this we can add up
there's a number of like ones one one is
the best right we can obtain this group
element
okay
but you guys can
can follow what I said okay so the the I
just I mean that more detailing okay you
don't find in the paper but I want to
claim that we can have a alternative way
based on
a non-cooperation we are still able to
produce something like um uh a valid
element along with a valuable
representation but in the fkr paper
their intuition is to produce value the
group element along with the value that
representation in there the only way
is to use group operation and here we
show our account example we were using
like an angle vibration
okay
there are other issues okay
so
um
our second result is that we find their
key Lemma there's a big issue in the
Asian paper
the big issue is about you guys remember
the
this is their key calmer in 2018 paper
they claim they can show this uh
basically asset so
reduction between games in the agent
model can be
re implied the reduction in the TGM
model right
and we show this Lemma
in some scenarios the name I will not
hold
so we have a theorem so here more
extremely we show a account example okay
right so we call the BT is a binary
encoding game
and here we show this this theorem here
uh game G is the the counter example
game we design okay and each is a well
known like a deluxe right
and we show that
um
we show like three items okay so so let
me try to say age is hard in the TGM in
Showbox ggm right so we already know
that this is written in the super
1997 paper okay so this part is easy
okay
so the third item is that we can show
that
the
the kimchi
kmg is is this right it's BG game
chemji is easy
okay all right in the next slide I will
try to show that
so and finally we can show that
these will hold
we put like three items together
this is a this contradicts to the The
Dilemma in the fkr 18 paper
right remember in the label right so
says this is a assume this and assume H
is the typical it's hard in the ggm and
the NG is hard right but now in our
theorem we show that g is easy okay
that's a contribution
thank you
okay
so yeah so this second item is is done
19 paper has a result
and then yeah now we I I'm trying to say
a little bit about this thread item
right so this is the the game G we
design okay it's kind of a circle right
so if you draw pictures
we have this uh game this is BG game
okay this is adversary it's a
the encoding okay right
so
so here I I I wonder like uh go through
these details uh one by one just believe
me this is a rewriting of this uh
pseudocode okay
so
a is given like group elements capital x
capital uis right and then adversary a
is supposed to produce another
government let's say Z Prime
that was a win the game
in the BG game right if Z Prime is equal
to to Z right Z is here this is a
Capital C is a group element including
of the literacy
right so back to the previous Slide the
third item says basically says the game
G is easy so this game is easy in the
show model
right
kmg is used in the supermodel
so that means that Advantage a can win
the game with good probability right so
how can a win the figure out win the
game so a must produce some like a good
looking Z Prime right so how to do that
so A in a sugar model right so this is
known capital x is including of one
right
and the uis
right UI is supposed to uh encoding of Z
sub I letter Z sub I so now advisory a
I've seen this inputs input and filter
aware tests
if x equal to UI or not okay
right that was a contest right because
yeah this Oracle is given
so if they are equal
then the corresponding Z little Z are I
is designed it is it's a one it's a one
okay otherwise this is the I
is beta0
okay so edible a make anemia like a path
of this uis
and elevator a can recover all the I's
right all the eyes
okay so once adversary a can recover all
they are Z1 little Z1 little D2
little Z sub l
and then I'll go to a in a true model is
able to combine this
together and this piece together will
form a group element and the design is
Define this as the capital Z Prime
so this capital Z Prime group element is
a
you you magically kind of like it's able
to glue this zero one piece later zero
one little Z2 until a little CL together
can get a guru element
okay this is allowed in the initial
model
in this way another a is able to obtain
a group element Z Prime and ZZ Prime
must be equal to Z
okay remember this Z it's um we take the
opposite thing right we pass
decompose this is a group element into
like uh be the screen right Z1 Z2 ZL
so
so put it like in summary this a is able
to win the game the PG game
with the probability one
okay so that means BG game
PG
this game is easy
right so in that way I'll throw the item
has been proven
so this third item is proven G is easy
BG game is easy okay the second item is
proven right so now the remaining is
that we need to prove this this first
item
okay
the first item remember H is the D log G
is a new game BG game
okay in order to like um prove
age implies
T right
so as we said before we need to develop
a reduction right if there's a adversary
a
can break this g game
then we can construct another game
another episode P right based on
reduction
this p is able to break the H game right
so how to do so here's a reduction
right remember H3 is a d log
so the Box
the reduction so we have a this is the D
log right we are given like two group
elements capital x capital Z is supposed
to like recover like a leader Z right
so how to do
remember uh
the first item here is the algebraic
like
it's a a reduction in the AGM model
right
so now
this a is the algebraic algorithm
so this a break the PG game right so a
is supposed to return this is a group
element along with this like
representation
okay
so I'm using the fkr 18 model
right so algebraic algorithm a
is able to if everybody a win a PG game
a is able to produce a good valid
government along with the representation
I'm using X reader x0 leader X1 until
later x l
so
and then this a must
this condition must be satisfied
right
so now the reduction are
okay based on this outputs right capital
Z Prime and also the derivative
reduction R is able to uh
return a value
okay and then this value actually can be
defined as Z okay right
so
okay so the more details like like as
presented in on a screen so basically we
are able to uh develop a reduction okay
by using our algebraic uh uh attacker a
right this add a title A is able to
produce uh
a value equivalent Z Prime along with
the reubenation
uh maybe it's uh we are a bit behind
schedule so can you wrap up your talk oh
okay
I saw that I have I have okay yeah yeah
okay thank you so yeah that's actually
this is the last slide okay so in this
uh then we try to summarize so in this
zero we proved like we had a three steps
right and then
we prove that here
so the take-home message is that we in
our paper we give the analysis of the
AGM model and yeah they are key Lema
um does not hold in certain scenarios
okay so yeah so
obviously like Urban question is can we
fix the agent model right can we have a
restricted like a type of like
um
put some like conditions so that can we
fix their key level
okay thanks and the paper can be found
on the ePrint okay so yeah
any questions
foreign
and Paris in Hope
okay
um hi so today I'm going to be talking
about
um the instantiability of classical
random Oracle model encryption
transforms and so
uh first just some background on uh what
we're going to be talking about so
first the random Oracle model is an
idealized model and
um
So Random oracles uh output a random
value when queried so they have some
dice
and they also have consistent outputs
for the same inputs so
there's some scroll to write down the
outputs and it can only be evaluated on
in a black box way so
he won't tell you what he's doing
and so of course this does not exist in
the real world but proving a scheme is
secure in the random Oracle model shows
security against black box attacks which
can be useful
So instantiating Random oracles means
replacing them with a real function in a
way that allows the scheme to maintain
security so in practice random oracles
are instantiated with hash functions
like shot 256.
but unfortunately some
unsubstantiability results exist in
general so if a scheme is uninstantiable
then it means that it's secure in a
random Oracle model but there is no
standard model functions that can
replace the random oracles and allow the
student to maintain security
so in this paper we provide two
instantiations
for uh celebrated random Oracle model
Inception transforms so the first is low
exponent RSA OE oaep which is due to
belarian Rogue in 1994 and so this
transform takes a chapter function so in
this case RSA two random oracles and
upgrades that into an IND CCA to public
key encryption scheme so that's
indistinguishability under adaptive
chosen ciphertext attacks
and so this was uh standardized in pkcs
in 2002.
and the second transform we consider is
the fujisati yokomoto encryption
transform
which takes a one-way CPA public key
encryption scheme a private key
encryption scheme and again two random
oracles and upgrades that again into an
IND cca2 public key encryption scheme
and so this is used with modifications
in many of nist's post Quantum the
encapsulation mechanisms
in the competition
so I'm sure everybody knows this but
just to make sure that we're all on the
same page I wanted to go over the
security game for IND cca2 security
because it will be our goal in both
cases so first of all of course the
Challenger selects a random bit B and
samples the public key and the secret
key sending the public key to the
adversary who has access to a decryption
Oracle and based on that information
they select two messages m0 and M1
and the Challenger encrypts M sub B
corresponding to the random bit B to
create the challenge ciphertext D star
which is in turn sent back to the
adversary who again has access to a
decryption Oracle which of course does
not allow the decryption of the
challenge ciphertext and based on all
this information they try to guess which
bit the uh is so if it's one or zero
and if they guess correctly then they
win
and so we say a scheme is indcca to
secure if all polynomial time
adversaries have negligible Advantage
where the advantage is the probability
of being correct Beyond random guessing
Okay so now we're going to just look at
the preview of the result our result for
oaep and then we're going to go back and
Define all of the things mentioned in
the preview that haven't been defined
yet
so
here is the schematic for RSA oaep
and again we have the trapdoor function
which is RSA there at the bottom and two
random oracles and our input plain text
message with some zero padding and some
random salt
so these are put through the hash
functions the random oracles and xored
all together
and then concatenated and then run
through RSA so the details uh will
become clear later
um so this scheme is uh with random
oracles is idcca2 secure so
we proved that low exponent RSA oap is
secure in the standard model
with the following instantiations so for
the random Oracle G
first we have uh it's going to be a
composition of many Primitives and
around the whole thing is
indistinguishability obfuscation
then we start with a puncturable
pseudorandom function
followed by an extremely lossy function
followed by a pseudorandom generator
followed by a pairwise independent hash
and that will be the instantiation for G
and H
is a bit uh it is a universal hardcore
function
and the final thing we need is that we
require RSA to be sort of exponentially
one way which is
reasonable
so first uh we're going to Define all of
the things I just mentioned
so one of the most important things in
the construction is extremely lossy
functions which is a notion due to
xandry and so if you're familiar with
lossy functions it is similar in that we
have a key generation algorithm for
injective keys and then you can see on
the left side the injective mode is
exactly what it sounds like it induces
an injective function
and
like regular lossy functions we have a
lossy key generation function which
induces a non-injective function but the
difference between regular lossy
functions and extremely lossy functions
is that the key generation for the
velocity Keys is adversary dependent so
the key the velocity key generation
algorithm will actually take input that
depends on the adversary's run time
so if the polynomial time adversary runs
in say time t
then velocity is generated such that it
takes time t plus one to find a
collision in the Elf image so
this means that this will only these two
modes of operation will only be
indistinguishable to adversaries with
runtime t or less
but because T is a polynomial
running taking time t plus one to find a
collision is also a polynomial so this
means that the lossy mode image size can
be polynomial which is the big
difference between regular velocity
functions and extremely lossy functions
the polynomial image size
and zandry also provides a standard
model construction
based on the exponential ddh assumption
and the next thing is
indistinguishability obfuscation
so
this is just in fact two circuits C1 and
C2 have the same input output Behavior
and the same size for their circuit
description then I O of C1 and IO fc2
are computationally indistinguishable
and again there exists standard model
constructions
and the next thing we use which is not
actually a part of our construction for
the random oracles but is an important
part of the proof is point function
obfuscation uh with auxiliary input so
here we have a point function with input
point x and so that just means that
if the point function is evaluated on X
it will return one and if it's evaluated
on any other point in the domain it will
return by
and having auxiliary information means
that we have this Z which is jointly
sampled with the input point x from some
unpredictable distribution
and unpredictable distribution here we
mean that if the adversary is given the
auxiliary information Z
then they can only output x with
negligible probability
and our security goal for this type of
obfuscation is that given the auxiliary
information
a polynomial time adversary cannot
distinguish between the obfuscation of a
point function PX with input point x or
pu or a random U
so a real versus random input 0.8 can't
distinguish with um
Advantage greater than negligible
and
so taking this another step further we
actually use multi-bit Point function
obfus station which is uh very similar
except we have an input point and an
output point so instead of outputting
one on the unique input point it outputs
a multi-bit string y
and again we have our auxiliary
information Zed which is jointly sampled
with X and Y
from an unpredictable distribution
and the unpredictable distribution
definition is the same in that a is only
given the auxiliary information Z and is
only required to find X and it has to be
able to do that with negligible
probability
and again the security goal is that
given the auxiliary information the
adversary cannot distinguish between
the obfuscation of a point function with
input point x and output point Y and the
obfuscation of a point function with
input point x and output Point U for a
random U so now it's real versus random
output Point instead of input point
so the next tool we use in the
construction is a puncturable
pseudorandom function so this type of
pseudorandom function is uh it has a key
generation algorithm like normal and
it has when evaluated on a regular key
it just behaves like a pseudorandom
function
but you also have the ability to
puncture a key which means that when you
evaluate using the puncture key
it will evaluate like normal as long as
you're evaluating evaluating it on a
point x that is not punctured so here
you can see that if X is not equal to X
Prime where X Prime
is the location of the puncture then it
will evaluate like a normal PRS but if
you do try to evaluate it on the
puncture point it will just return bot
and the security guarantee for pprfs is
that given X Prime and the key punctured
at X Prime the adversary can't
distinguish between the output of the
prf on the non-punctured key at X and a
random point
and again we have standard model
constructions for
for this primitive
okay so next I'm going to talk about the
oaep half of the result
and there's a few properties we require
for our low exponent RSA oap proof and
the first two are
um properties of RSA and they're not
additional assumptions so the first one
is called second input extractability or
Sie and this says that given the RSA
function Black Box access to the RSA
function and some output Point RSA of x
and some portion of x
then there exists an efficient extractor
that can recover the entirety of x
and
the next thing is common inputs
extractability which says that again
given Black Box access to the RSA
function two image points RSA of X and
RSA of Y then there exists an efficient
extractor that can recover X and Y only
if some portion of both pre-images are
equal so if some portion of X and Y are
equal then it can recover the entirety
of X and Y
and finally as I mentioned before we
also require that RSA is
sub-exponentially one way
so again here we have the schematic for
RSA oap the two random oracles and the
trapdoor function and the final result
being IND cca2 secured and at the bottom
is the written out version where of the
final ciphertext where you can see the
xores and the inputs are and um
okay so this is what we saw before the
construction for the
um random Oracle G and so surrounding
all of these Primitives we have
indistinguishability obfus station
then first in the composition is
puncturable pseudorandom function
then we have an extremely lossy function
or an elf
and then a pseudorandom generator and
lastly a pairwise independent hash
so G is instantiated as I just said and
H is instantiated as a sub exponentially
secure Universal hardcore function which
can be constructed from standard model
Primitives uh from different inputs
obfuscation with pprx with short
auxiliary information
Okay so
the
we can uh
prove our instantiation if again we have
H as universal hardcore function G is
the composition
RSA sub exponentially one way and
finally that there exists multi-bit
Point function obfuscation with
auxiliary information for specific
sub-exponentially unpredictable
distributions
so
this final thing is needed again for the
proof and not the construction
so for the proof idea I'm just going to
go through the sequence of hybrids at a
very coarse grain level so recall the
indcca2 game so the starting point is we
have
the adversary is given the public key
which contains
this key for the hash G and so here I've
admitted the prg and the pairwise hash
just for clarity and so a has the
ability to compute this function
and a the adversary is also given the
challenge ciphertext
and we use stars to denote things that
involve the challenge ciphertext
okay so the first step of the the game
chain is we have that the challenge type
for text is unchanged and we change the
hash key for G
so we have done two things in this
change the first is that we have
punctured the puncturable pseudorandom
key at R star which is the randomness
used in oaep
and we've also introduced the mbaipo and
this MBE IPO has input point R star and
output Point Z star
so this change actually makes these two
versions of kg
um have the same input output Behavior
and the purpose of the MBA appeal here
is in part
um to hide the puncture point and it has
another purpose that we will see later
and since these two versions have the
same input output Behavior we can
determine that this change is
indistinguishable from the previous game
based on the security of i o
and so for the next game the this time
the construction for the hash stays the
same and we change the challenge
ciphertext
so in particular the output of the
function the hash function G is now just
changed to random so you can see before
it was like G of R star it but now it's
just random
and this change is undetectable by the
adversary because of the security of
punctual pseudorandom functions
and in the next game this time the town
of ciphertext is unchanged and we're
going to change the construction in the
public key for G
this time the elf is switched from
injective mode to extremely lossy mode
and of course this is indistinguishable
to the adversary because of the
indistinguishability of injective and
lossy mode else
so this
allows us to do something in the next
game it that
takes advantage of the polynomial image
size of elves
so in the next game we actually have the
decryption Oracle that the adversaries
have access to being simulated with only
the public key and in particular without
the secret key and this is done by
utilizing the two properties of RSA I
mentioned earlier second inputs
extractability and common inputs
extractability and the polynomial image
size for Elf so we can actually
exhaustively search and iterate over the
entire Elf image to decrypt
so in this final step
we change the description of G
and we have it so that the mbaipo
changes the output Point instead of
having Z Star being the output point
where Z star is in the challenge
ciphertext as you can see highlighted in
red now it's actually just independently
random Zed Bar
and because of the challenge that
protects is unchanged this z bar has is
completely independent of the challenge
ciphertext
and this is undetectable because of the
security of MBA IPOs the adversaries
should not be able to find the output
point so they won't be able to tell if
you've changed the output point
so the important part of this last step
is that Z star in the challenge site for
text is now random and independent of
the public key given to the adversary so
there's no information about Zed star in
the public key
which means that it's independently
random being xored with the message so
we have that the message is hidden by
the security of the one-time pad
so that was the overview for
our OA EP result for low exponent RSA
and next for fo we have
this is the schematic for the Fujisaki
yokomoto encryption transform
and the ingredients are first a one-way
CPA public key encryption scheme
then a symmetric key encryption scheme
again we have two random oracles G and H
and here H is acting as encrypt with
hash
so it is the random coins for the
encryption so we have R coming in being
his input Rand the randomness and it is
also the acting as sort of the plain
text for the public key encryption and
in it's also acting as the random coins
for the encryption through its hash
and the result is that this whole scheme
is IND cca2 secure
and it's used by as I mentioned before
the selection for this post Quantum
standardization for uh key encapsulation
mechanisms
but unfortunately this instantiation
that I will present is not post Quantum
secure because else the construction
provided for elves by xandry uses the
ddh assumption
so we've prove instantiation actually
for a slightly tweaked version of the fo
transform in particular the r Randomness
is additionally used as input for the
symmetric key encryption scheme where it
is not in the original
so
using this version We instantiate G as
the exact same thing as we did for oaep
in particular we have again
IO
and then we have a punctured
pseudorandom function followed by an
extremely lossy function followed by a
prg followed by a pairwise independent
hash
and we have
H being instantiated just as a pairwise
independent hash
and the base
uh public key encryption scheme is lost
the encryption
and
The Base secret key encryption is
authenticated encryption and again like
for RSA oap result we also need there to
exist
um MBA IPO for specific distributions
specific and predictable distributions
and so I won't go through the proof just
because uh time constraints but I wanted
to mention that we prove this result in
two steps
so following the observation of Paul
finds it out so the
fo scheme operates a base one-way CPA
scheme into an indcca to secure scheme
so this can be broken into two steps
first we start with the one-way
CPA scheme and then upgrade that into a
one-way PCA scheme where one way PCA is
one way under plain text checking
attacks
which is a it's a non-standard security
assumption
and it's between these two things so
then the next step is upgrading from
one-way PCA to IND cc82
okay
so in summary we provide
we so uh we provide full instantiations
of IND dca2 standard model
instantiations
for low exponent RSA
oaep and a tweaked version of the
fujisakiakamoto encryption transforms
and these two
have been long long these two
instantiations have been long-standing
open problems and
we provide
instantiation so
both of these instantiations use this
construction of
i o hash function prg elf and a
functionable pseudonym function
and in the paper we also provide
standard model constructions for mbaipo
the multi-bit point function obfuscation
with auxiliary info based on RSA and
elves
so
uh some open problems are to create a
version that is post Quantum secure and
another one is to find a way to abstract
the properties we need from this
composition of five things into some
uh
just simple descriptor for the
properties required
and you can see the paper for more
details about everything in particular
about the fo proof and the Ambi appeal
constructions so thank you
thank you
okay although we are just a weekly
behind schedule but do you have any
short question
of
thank you that's a great result
um can you comment a little bit on the
um second infant extractability and
common input extractability of RSA
specifically together with assuming
exponential hardness of RSA like it's I
think it's slide 18.
foreign
about these assumptions I'm not so
familiar with them
yeah um the first two things are
um not assumptions they could be shown
with the coppersmith algorithm and the
sub-exponentially one-way requirement is
an assumption but uh It is believed by
some people to be true about RSA but it
is um still an assumption all right
thanks
foreign
so some