welcome to this session on the fully on
a homomorphic encryption
so the first book will be on the paper
uh the status is a special linearly
homographic encryption on Z over 2 to
the KZ
and the speaker will be I that occur
so either flow is yours
hey thanks for the introduction
um so yeah I'm gonna tell you about a
scheme that we developed which is called
threshold linearly homomorphic
encryption where the message space is
set in which is a KZ and this is Joint
work with Ian castanos and Fabian again
so I'll stop by uh explaining how high
level what threshold public key
encryption is so the idea is it's just a
public key encryption scheme where the
secret decryption key is
um shared According to some decryption
policy among various decryption servers
and as any public key encryption scheme
the public key is public and so anyone
can encrypt a message M with this public
encryption key
to produce a cyber text domain
so this architect here is the red m
M and then in thresholds uh public key
encryption we have a partial decryption
where each server is going to use their
partial decryption key in order to
compute partial decryption shares
and in order to recover the initial
plain text
um
we have another final decryption
protocol which is public so anyone can
perform this and if you have
um a number of Cipher texts from Secret
Keys which
um
satisfy the decryption policy so we'll
say they're part of the qualified set
then combining these ciphertexts will
allow you to recover the message and if
the secret keys don't satisfy the policy
the
the decryption will return an empty set
not an error it should be an empty sense
if we want this threshold public key
encryption scheme to further be linearly
homomorphic
um I mean this means that one should
also be able to perform
um
by by performing operations on the
ciphertext you can perform linear
operations on the underlying plaintexts
so we have two efficient algorithms uh
one which given the Cyber text of M and
a side text decrypting to M Star you can
produce nervous ciphertext which will
decrypt to M plus n star
and uh algorithm called evalscal which
takes uh ciphertext which decrypts to m
a scalar Alpha
and produces a new ciphertext which will
decrypt to Alpha science and stuff
and uh linearly homomorphic public I
mean threshold public key encryption on
Z over G to the KZ is basically above
but where the message space is Z over G
to the KZ
so we can encrypt any message modulo t
to the K and the interesting thing here
is that these um homomorphic operations
I can't hear you anymore
oh okay
I can hear
can you hear me yes okay great
so the the interesting thing uh about
having
um
an encryption modular due to the KZ here
is that the um
homomorphic operations that we do on the
ciphertext under the hood on the
plaintext they're performed modulo two
to the k
okay and so why is this interesting
um so there are various applications but
I'm going to just describe one of them
uh how this can be applied to
multi-party computation modularity to
decay
so
briefly uh the idea of a secure
multi-party computation is that we have
like various parties here we have four
um they all have secret inputs say X1 X2
X3 and X4 and they all want to compute a
function of their common of all of their
inputs put together but they don't trust
the other parties and they don't want to
reveal their secret inputs to the other
parties
so one way of doing this would be having
a trusted party like this Angel here
um
and all the parties send their secret
inputs to this person that they all
trust The Trusted person
computes the result of the function and
sends it back to everyone
but of course in real life angels are
kind of hard to come across
and so uh the idea of secure multi-party
computation is achieving the same goal
but without a twisted party so all the
participants should keep their secret
inputs secret but at the end of the day
they all want the result of this
function on their private empaths
um and there's been a lot of interest
recently I mean fairly recently for um
uh multi-party computation modulo two to
Decay and this is mainly because uh on
standard CPUs integral arithmetic is
performed modulo two to the K so for
instance 32 or 64-bit chips
um and if we have secure multi
computation multi-party computation
modulator due to the K we mirror this
design and it means uh that one has a
simplified implementation of these MPC
protocols
we don't need to perform modular
arithmetic or compensate for modular
reductions
and it also means that programmers
they're implementing these protocols can
use optimizations for CPUs directly
and so how does one go about building a
multi-party computation
modulo 2 to Decay well there's a kind of
common blueprint which is used to build
maliciously secure multi-party
computation protocols it divides the
process in two phases so we have a
pre-processing phase which is
offline so this means the participants
can do it without knowing the inputs
that they're going to use for their
computation or even the function that
they're going to compute
um and it's slow
um and the idea is to compute
many shares of triplets of the form a b
a b where A and B are random in Z over 2
to the KZ and these triplets are then
going to be used to speed up the fast
online phase and they're basically used
as masks during this um this protocol
and so this online phase is fast and
information theoretically secure
um
so we'd like a way to improve the slow
phase the pre-processing phase because
the online phase is already very
efficient
um techniques that were used in the past
um are notably oblivious transfer which
was used in SPD z2k to create these
triples
um
so oblivious transfer yields a fast
solution but the bandwidth of
consumption is quite High
and then in overdrive 2K they use
somewhat homomorphic encryption so this
does improve the bandwidth consumption
but the actual protocol itself is quite
complex and so implementing it um for
developers is quite hard and there's
more risks of things of there being
mistakes
um and then another solution which is uh
much closer to what I'm going to talk
about is uh one by
well in that they develop in Monza
um which uses linearly homomorphic
encryption modulo to to Decay to produce
this raw material
and in particular the scheme that they
use is the israeliver encryption skin
uh which is linearly homomorphic and has
a message based of Z over 2 to the KZ
which is great
but there's no known threshold
decryption
um for this scheme
uh and in well under standard
assumptions and in particular this means
uh the in Monza they only have a
two-party MPC protocol and
um
because each party has their own secret
and public key instead of sharing the
decryption key
um they need to use zero knowledge
proofs to prove to the parties that the
other party that what they're doing is
correct and so obviously these zero
knowledge proofs have a negative impact
on bandwidth and so the efficiency gains
that one would have expected uh compared
to say speed is 2K and not as big as we
would like
and so in our work what we do
um is we create a
threshold linearly homomorphic
encryption scheme with a message they
said over to to the ksaid which is
exactly
um what we need to
fill this Gap and
efficiently produce these triples
and save on Van rope
so I'll um
first kind of give an abstract view of
the
tools that we use
um to build our construction and how we
build our scheme from from these
abstract tools and later on I'll explain
briefly how we realize this framework
from class groups
so the framework is quite similar to
that of Casino from ctrsa 2015. we have
a cyclic Group G of order s times 2 to
the K where the gcd of s and 2 to the K
is one
we have a subgroup of G called f
which is the 2 to the K which is 2 to
the K roots of unity of G
and is avoided to the k
and there also exists an efficient
algorithm for computing discrete
logarithms in F so it means Computing x
given F to the power x
um and finally we have another Group H
which is uh the subgroup of two to the K
powers of G and is of a known order s
and it holds that g is isomorphic to a
direct product of F and H and and
finally even though we don't know the
order of s
I mean the order s which is the order of
H and hence the order of G is also
unknown we do know an upper bound s
tilde phase
and the security assumption that we use
in this framework is a hard subgroup
membership assumption which essentially
states that F1
um samples a random element from the
subgroup H or a random element from the
subgroup page multiplied by the
generator F raised to the power some
invertible elements modulo 2 to the k
then both elements should be
computationally indistinguishable
foreign
and so to build a
public key encryption scheme funds that
over to the KZ from this uh the scheme
is fairly simple it looks like
El gamma in the exponent uh so we we
sample the secret key from a
distribution uh which is close to
uniform which induces a distribution
close to uniform over h
um and the public key is just the
generator of H raised to the power of
the secret key
um to encrypt a message M instead over
to the KZ
we sample a random element R in this
distribution DH
um and then we compute uh first cycle
text element which is
H to the power R and the second in the
second part of the ciphertext we encode
the message in the exponent of the
generator F and
um we mask this with the public key
raised to the power R and the ciphertext
is both elements C1 and C2
um finally to decrypt uh one multiplies
the second part of the component C2 by
C1 raised to the power minus s k
and this should be equal if this is a
correct ciphertext to F to the power M
um and so here we check if the mess if
the resulting capital M is in the
subgroup f
if not
um then the ciphertext is badly formed
and we the ciphertex have rejected and
if so we return
the discrete logarithm in base F of
capital M which as I mentioned earlier
is efficiently computable
um and so it's quite easy to see that
this scheme is also linearly homomorphic
in order to
add plain texts which are underlying to
ciphertext you just multiply the two
ciphertexts component wise and then
re-randomize the resulting ciphertext
and similarly to perform scalar
multiplication wonders raises each
ciphertext component
to the power of the scalar Alpha and
then re-randomizes the resulting
ciphertext
um for security I'm basically uh going
to follow a kind of game based approach
um
so I'm going to perform little changes
to the original encryption scheme which
um I'm going to justify are noticeable
to anyone who's looking at the
scheme from an outsider's perspective
who doesn't know the secret key
um
and um
[Music]
and then I'll get to a point where the
message is statistically hidden um and
since
if we have a simulated game a simulated
like encryption scheme where the message
is statistically hidden and that's
indistinguishable from the real scheme
um then we'll be convinced that the real
encryption scheme is secure
um so the first change that we do from
our original encryption scheme is
instead of sampling the secret key from
a distribution uh
which
induces a uniform distribution over H
we're going to sample it from a
distribution which is close to uniform
modulo s times 2 to the K and so induces
a distribution
uniform over G
and because uh the order of H divides
the order of g s divides s times 2 to
the K this changes a noticeable given
only the public key and the rest of the
scheme
um
the next change we do is purely
conceptual so we compute C2 in a
different way instead of computing the
second part of the ciphertext as F to
the power M times PK to the power R
we're going to compute it as F to the
power M times C1 to the power SK but
these are actually exactly the same
they're just computed in a different way
because
C1 is H to the power R and P K is K to
the power s k so p k to the power R and
C1 to the power SK are the same thing
the final change we do is
um we sample an extra element u in Z
over 2 to the K in the invertables of Z
over 2 to the KZ and we multiply the
first part of the ciphertext
um H which was H to the R by F to the
power U
H and so now we can notice that uh
the first part of the ciphertext in our
in our previous game and the first part
of the slave takes now
are um
so basically the two elements that one
tries to distinguish in uh the hs72k
problem
and so if there's hsm2k assumption holds
uh
which we assume it does we're ensured
that this change is indistinguishable
so now uh we're in this like final
simulation game which we've established
is like indistinguishable from the real
encryption scheme and here we can see
that the information it can potentially
be leaked on the message is contained in
C2 which is f to the power M plus u
times s k times b k to the power R I've
just Rewritten this by developing C1
and so an unbounded adversary would at
most uh be able to deduce from this uh
the value of M plus u times s k modulo 2
to the power k
um and here the secret K the secret key
SK was sampled from a distribution which
was close to uniform modulo s times 2 to
the K so even though the value of SK is
information theoretically fixed modulo s
because of the public key which reveals
H to the power SK
the value of SK remains close to uniform
modulo 2 to the K because s and 2 to the
K are Co Prime
and 2 to the K divides the order of
T
um so we have SK which is close to
uniform modulo 2K here we have U which
is chosen to be invertible modulo 2K and
so the product of U times SK
um is uh close to uniform modulus UK and
so perfectly oops masks are on our
message or statistic emasks our message
M and this is what we wanted to prove
security
um and finally uh to make this scheme uh
not to obtain a threshold decryption for
our scheme uh we just noticed that the
decryption key SK is
only used in decryption for explanation
to this secret key in the group of a
known order h
and so we use
um linear integer secret sharing uh to
share the decryption key over the
integers and um so our resulting scheme
allows any access structure for the
decryption policy and in particular
threshold decryption
um and so how do we realize this
abstract framework from class groups
well we start from uh the original CL
framework
um in their framework they provide us
very similar abstraction the main
difference being that the subgroup F
which encodes messages is of prime order
queue
in their work they have two class groups
uh one with the fundament of with the
fundamental discriminant Delta K which
is set to minus P times Q at p and Q at
Prime and
um
the class group of non-maximal order of
discriminant minus P times Q cubed
in this setting we can
create a subjection between the class
group of the maximal order and the
cluster of the non-max sorry the class
group of the non-maximal order in the
class group
none and the Maxwell order
um and whose kernel is um
of order q and we're going to set the
subgroup F to be
um the this kernel of order q and it
would be great if we could just plug Q
equals 2 to the k
um and get our resulting scheme
I mean setting
um but that unfortunately doesn't work
for various reasons but the main problem
is that um
if you know the factorization of the
discriminant which is the case uh in the
original CL you can compute square roots
and you can decide if elements are
squares and if that's the case uh the
hardness assumption hsm2k doesn't hold
at all it's completely broken
so we need to
um have a setting where Computing square
roots is hard and so that means that the
factorization of the discriminant cannot
be known and so we build our
discriminant from an RSA integer n
foreign
but we can't choose any n we have to be
careful in particular if we looking into
the geosphere Associated to class groups
um
one can see that some Genera can leak
information on discrete logarithms
and so we have to carefully select the
discriminants and hence uh the RSA
integer n which will allow us to
securely work with the group of squares
of the class group
um okay last but not least performance
so we did do an implementation in our um
paper but since then uh
have implemented a
library from scratch in CNC plus plus
called bicycle which improves our
timings so I'm providing these better
timings
um
so yeah as you can see
decryption is
for like a message Space 2 to the 64 and
128 bits of security our decryption is
only like 40 milliseconds which is uh
very efficient so yeah that's basically
it thank you very much for your
attention and uh if you have any
questions I'd be
happy to try and answer them
or maybe there's not much time for
questions because I went over time
please
hi uh can you hear me
hello
okay
um I guess you can hear me uh
okay thanks uh okay hi uh I'm sorry Elio
today I'm gonna present large Precision
homomorphic sign evaluation using a few
TV sheep bootstrapping this is a short
work with Daniela michancho and Yuri
polakov
let me start by some background
information so uh what's functional or
programmable bootstrapping basically
means that we can evaluate in a cyclic
function uh through lookup table for
free while also performing some
bootstrapping over some LTE server texts
this is first introduced in dm15
and it has two requirements or two
constraints the first one is that it
requires the function to be next cyclic
and what does it mean by next cyclic
basically means that for an input in zq
the function needs to to satisfy that f
of x equals to negative of f of x plus
qr2
the second constraint is that it can
only evaluate functions over messages
with Optical bits of precision and
usually K is equal to 5 or 6. the reason
is that uh its runtime is exponential in
the number of bits and um for the number
of bits Beyond 506 the runtime will
become quite impractical
and we will use this notation for uh
bootstrapping so basically we use boot
for some function f over X and it will
output the
ciphertext that's encrypting f of x for
some neglect click function f from DP to
zq and this p and Q can be different but
for Simplicity you may assume that P and
Q are the same number
there are two uh bootstrapping methods
available now and uh the the first one
is a few introduced in dm15 it
efficiently supports arbitrary Secrets
but the constructing key size is
relatively large and the second is tfhe
introduced in ctgi 16 it provides a
better runtime performance for small
Secrets like like binary or ternary
secret and the bootstrapping key size is
much smaller
please CMP uh 21 for a more detailed
comparison
and we use this functional bootstrapping
methods as a black box so either of the
two work for us uh it's the same state
serves the exact same uh functionality
there's another bootstrapping method
that's recently developed and can be
applied as well but it's not included in
this work but because the the paper is
published before the new method is
proposed
uh so the main results of our work so at
a very high level we uh introduced some
new tools uh to this a few TVG line of
work to make the schemes more powerful
more specifically first we introduce
some large Precision comparisons so why
comparisons uh comparisons are widely
used in machine learning like in CN
inference or DTC training and then and
the data science
and comparisons are usually considered
hard for SVG schemes and privacy
preserving ml or DS is an essential case
for Fe
currently the runtime for uh for uh this
is exponential with the bits of
precision and we want to make the
runtime linear scale
the second tool is more General and more
powerful we provide the way to do a
large Precision arbitrary function
evaluation
as mentioned before now it only supports
phonak a cyclic function and only small
supports for small precision
uh we have implemented our schemes and
the implementation is open source in
open fvg and Palestine libraries
so let's start from some high level
ideas
one of the one observation we have is
that the comparison is equivalent to
sign evaluation
to compare two two numbers A and B we
just need to find the sine of a minus B
and another observation is that the sign
evaluation is equivalent to Computing
the most significant bits
Computing the most significant bit is
the central part of you or TV cheap
bootstrapping but as mentioned that it
only supports for up to say k bits
therefore our uh key technique is that
we try to remove the large number of
stitches gradually
for example if you take a look at this
18-bit number we just remove the last
six bits and then remove the middle six
bits we have only six bits left we can
uh we can perform some few or TV cheaper
strapping to extract the most
significant bits
foreign so uh to do large Precision
comparison we first used a floor
function first to run down the last K
bits so if we have this 12-bit number we
just make the last six that's zeros and
then we divide this result uh by
teaching the K where to the case equal
to 6 here using module switching and
this will make this topic number into a
six bit number
we cannot directly use module switching
to round down the original uh six bit uh
12-bit number because a module switching
is performing a rounding instead of
flooring which will cause errors for
some values near the boundary
and then we repeat this procedure for
each digit as mentioned before after
there are at most like keep bits left we
can perform a regular fuse shopping to
extract the most significant bit
this one question remains is that the
flow function is not necessary so how
can we evaluate it
so let me ask a question what is really
a flow function a flow function is
basically would give you a number and
you make the last case at zero
uh so we achieved this functionality by
invoking the function of the functional
bootstrapping twice for uh with two
different Mega cyclic functions
we first clear the most significant bit
of the last K bits so for a and the
number from B1 to PN uh the last qubits
are from here to here and we just clear
the most significant bits of the elastic
at last cables
we cleared this up by using the
following function you can double check
that this is indeed Mega cyclic so this
can be achieved by evoking one
functional bootstrapping with this
function
and then we clear the the rest of the K
minus one bits I.E the bits here uh and
we achieve this by using the second
function here and again you can double
check this is indeed a mega cyclic
uh this is our pseudo code uh as
mentioned before for the floor function
we first use the F0 to remove the most
significant bit of the last key bits and
then we used F1 to remove the last
Cayman swamp bits and we we process this
uh we use this floor function digit by
digit until we have only log qubits I.E
the K bits left and then we can use the
original few or TVG bootstrapping to
extract the most significant bit
uh now let's talk about a uh the more
General Tool uh the arbitrary function
evaluation let's start with some small
context module uh the the first
constraint we need to get rid of is that
the view or TV cheat bootstrapping will
require the input function to be next I
click
so uh can we make the function arbitrary
like remove the mega satellite property
requirements uh similar to the flow
function we can use two functions to
achieve this functionality we first
remove the most significant bits of the
input
sorry
and then for the rest of the bits we'll
be able to evaluate an arbitrary
function upon because and uh after
removing the most significant bit we can
just use a mega secular function to with
KPS to represent a an arbitrary function
with K minus one bits
but then how about the most significant
bits
uh we it turns out that we
met with modulus from Q to the 2 to 2q
then it will introduce a random most
significant bit to the input so
basically with a uh km cable input we
will raise the modulus to uh Q from Q to
q and then the input will become K plus
1 bits and then we remove this redundant
random bit and then we can perform a
Nega cyclic function uh an arbitrary
function evaluation
using the original view or TVG plus
dropping uh here's a pseudo code this is
a function we use to remove the most
significant bits again you can you can
check that this is indeed negative
cyclic and uh for the function for the
input function we'll use a like a
circular function to represent it but
since the most significant bit is clear
to zero one of the branches will not be
used at all
and here we first remove the one bit and
then we evaluate this aperture function
uh on the input
uh so now let's talk about how can we
make this uh the small Precision into
large precision
we did this first by uh breaking a large
Precision ciphertext into several small
separate texts
this is done through uh what we call a
ciphertext decomposition or homorphic
digital decomposition
this can be achieved by calling the
large Precision sign evaluation as I
mentioned before and we just need to
collect the bits removed if you recall
that in the large Precision PSI
evaluation we need to remove kbits at a
time we just need to collect the cables
that we have end up with several small
server texts that each encrypting kits
of message
this essentially has the same cost as
the large Precision sign validation
then we can evaluate each small
ciphertext sequential using a change
shape method or three ship method both
of these methods are for first
introduced in gbe21
the change for the chinship method uh as
you can see uh is like a chain so if we
first use uh some uh a few functional
bootstrapping to evaluate c0 and we will
get a results out this carrying result
will be processed with the second input
and uh and together it will be evaluated
using the second uh function of
bootstrapping and sequentially we'll get
some results
but this this method is relatively
restrictive because not all functions
can be expressed in this way
so they have the second method which is
the three method uh the three methods
basically saying that um for for first
input instead of outputting a uh LW
subtext it outputs some lookup table and
this lookup table will be used to
evaluate the second server text and so
on and so forth uh this is much more
General and much more powerful all of
the functions can be expressed in this
way uh but the catches that at the wrong
time will be much worse than the first
method
but to sum up using The Cypher text
decomposition uh we can use these two
methods to to achieve arbitrary function
evaluation over large precision
there are two uh concurrent and
independent Works uh both of the pro
approaches uh use the observation that
uh negative one times negative m equals
to M and the extraction of most
significant bits using few TV cheaper
shopping
uh both of these results both of these
algorithms use uh multiplication and
requires at least uh two bootstrapping
invocations
trot21 uses a BFE like multiplication
and KS 21 uses a GSW like modification
and the rule on the details we refer the
audience to the those two papers to find
out the details uh but our approach does
not require any multiplication and can
be instantiated using only addition and
futility per circuit
here's an uh
is asymptotic comparisons as you can see
the noise growth our noise growth has is
the smallest and also we only we we have
uh at less number of bootstrapping call
invocations compared to ks21 and the
same compared to clot21
uh now let's talk about the experimental
result in applications
we have implemented our algorithms in
Palisade and openfg libraries
and we evaluate the large Precision
comparison of for precision ranging from
five bits to 21 bits
uh the result is a single thread and
with TV cheaper shopping using G plus
plus 9.3.0
uh here's the results I will not go into
detail of all of them but as you can see
the the runtime basically scales
linearly with a number of bits we have
also implemented the arbitrary function
evaluation uh just to prove that it
indeed works for only small precision
we have also applied our techniques to
have a site activation function over T56
slots by using cks few tfvg scheme
switching technique
more generally one can use our large
Precision comparison to perform an
encrypted Branch evaluation
uh
there's another important line of work
that uses cpts to to perform uh
comparisons and those results are all
based on uh polynomial approximation of
the sine function and I would like to uh
at a very high level compared to those
two lines of work but the detailed
comparison of course uh may may benefit
from a more detailed survey paper
uh so for state of the art success based
comparisons uh it takes roughly 30
seconds to compare for uh 64k slots
where our method is uh six seconds for
one slot so if the number of comparisons
needed is very small our method will be
faster
also our method is easily paralyzable uh
while cks supports only limited
parallelization which means that if we
have multiple cores that even if the
number of comparisons are larger our
method may still be uh preferred
thank you uh another point is that
higher Precision of cks method like 50
bits can be very hard to support because
the log queue can easily exist the lock
use the Cyber text modulus for CTS
schemes can easily see like 30 000 and
this will also cause for ring Dimension
to grow which will cause the performance
to be much worse also uh to perform like
a 50-bit a Precision comparison the
scaling factor of ckks also needs to be
increased from 64 64 bits to 128 bits
which will further reduce the
performance according to our our
Benchmark using Palisade it can be as as
bad as like eight times slower
and of course our methods much simpler
to implement and use and if multiple
invocations of sign evaluations needed
cks based method needs push dropping in
between which will further reduce the
runtime while hours do not
uh there are of course some challenges
and uh and potential promising and
interesting future directions the
map.net here for the runtime is the tfec
or a few functional bootstrapping each
comparison has to be done separately
there's no CRT packing support and
performance can be improved only by
parallelization and like using multiple
threats and or gpu-like parallelization
so one very interesting uh question uh
that can be asked is that can we develop
other methods for functionable shopping
with data efficiency
and can we leverage pgb or BFE
bootstrapping for this
uh let me finish today's talk uh by with
some conclusions and remarks
so first in this work uh for the a few
TVG line of work we have we have
provided so far the most efficient large
Precision comparison and more generally
large Precision arbitrary function
evaluation
and moreover this methods can algorithm
can be uh combined with cks one can use
sticky gas for polynomial functioning
valuation and use our algorithms for
non-polynomial function evaluation like
comparisons or like activation functions
and so on
uh of course this will need some uh some
switch some switching technique between
cks and few and this can be done from
using cqs few TVG scheme switching
technique first introducing Camilla
paper and later improved in Texas
and open Refugee is planning to include
this scheme switching technique uh
switching scheme a scheme switching
feature in version 1.1 so after this is
published or one can simply use the and
and as mentioned that our organism and
also CTS are both included in open fhg r
d which means that if this feature is
public one can simply use the open fishy
library to perform what I mentioned
above to incorporate our algorithm with
the cks
foreign
references and that's pretty much it for
my today's talk thank you all very much
and I'm open to take questions
all the questions from the audience so
online
no I don't I don't see any questions
okay so let's thank the speaker again
thank you
is in person do we have the speaker
ah excellent
Facebook
so the next talk is on the eval round
algorithm in ckks bootstrapping and the
talk will be given by
Kim
thank you for introducing my name is
Sarah Kim and I'm going to introduce our
paper over around algorithm means the
kks bootstrapping
so let me start by giving a brief
overview of this talk
the main topic is the kks which is a
representative form of increasing skin
which is widely known for its ability to
deal with real numbers
CK capable as bootstrapping is later
suggests operation which recovers
modulus of cyber text so it can be
evaluated orbital arbitrary times
our problem of this cks bootstrapping is
it is an operational recovering those
cyber text modulus but it consumes
modulus at the same time
what I missed is that uh
it is another big combination of
addition and multiplication so it
consumes modulus and it directly
determines
how many evaluation depths are left
after another after bootstrapping
so
we are focusing on reducing such model
as consumption by proposing a simple yet
effective variant of cks bootstrapping
which consumes less modulus modulus and
which can be implemented with
with a negligible cost on the existing
Convention of disturbing algorithm
implementation
the contents will be given as follows
I'll start by a giving up background
focusing on this modulus consumption of
kkks
and our as our algorithm is constructed
tightly on the combination of the
describing algorithm are spent some time
on reviewing the conventional algorithm
and I introduced the evil round
algorithm
in this talk I'm I'm focusing on the
delivering higher level ideas so please
check details on our paper
uh I'll not explained the whole concept
of homework being Christian but
homophone in Christian scheme can be
characterized
with three operations namely encryption
decryption and a method to
evaluate or desired function on homo
frequency on the Cyber text
so
let me look close
in the case of ckks
ckks provides three spaces message plain
text and cyber text
with encoding and encryption
so focusing on the plain text under on
the Cyber text these are constructed on
the wrong non-problem called rlwe so the
ckks can utilize its homophic structure
which is constructed on the polynomial
where the finite field coefficients
with this RW problem
the increasion of the plain text is
given as the equation below
on focusing on the message and plan text
the encoding and decoding map is defined
by discrete period transfer it is
natural to define the map by this since
they are polynomials and vectors and one
more thing on the cks is that the
message are complex vectors and plain
texts are integer polynomials so we have
to scaling up to encode the message and
scale down to decode the plain text
so in short the encoding and decoding
map is given as the below
one problem arises from the scaling up
it is the
size of encrypted plain text is growing
by each multiplications
in brief
suppose the plain text one is scaled up
by scale factor one
Delta one and plain text 2 is scared by
Delta 2 then the simple multiplicated
result will be scaled by Delta 1
multiplicate by Theta 2. so
if we nightly execute the important
evaluation circuit the size of the
encrypted plain text will grow
exponentially
actually main feature of the kkks is
dealing with
dealing with the size of being prepared
plain text efficiently it supports the
operation of rescaling to maintain the
size of encrypted plain text which is an
operation of dividing the Cyber text
modulus and the encrypted plain text at
the same time
so
rescaling
deals with the site so encrypted plain
text in exchange of consuming modulus
and the amount of motivates consumed is
exactly the same
as the encrypted plain text has scaled
down
it is open uh visualized by the diagram
on the right side
so we have
some plain text of size M1 and we have
another plain text of size M2
then the multiplicated result wave size
of M1 verticulate by
M2 and we just cut out the lsbs by
rescaling and the cutout or amount is
equals to the modulus consumption
such rescaling is a brilliant way to
deal with this
the size of encrypted plain text but
still there is a challenge
the challenge of all these kkks s is
that through evaluating the circuit
the Cyber tester will eventually
eventually run out the Cyber text model
so it can be
cannot be evaluated any further
so put the strapping is later suggests
to recover the Cyber text mode list
so we just
bootstrap the
cyber text at the bottom modulus and
continue the evaluating
cyber text
so it completes the cks at the fully
homophobic inflation scheme
the problem we are focusing on this CK
case bootstrapping is that
it consumes modulus
actually boost the first step of
bootstrapping is projecting to the
higher modulus so it is its modulus is
already recovered
but
we have to adjust the value of
protected cyber text to the original
message so
it consumes modulus from then so
after boost disrupting the Cyber test
modulus way goes down from the Fresh
modulus
and the
size of the
cyber text modulus after bootstrap
directly determines the possible
evaluation depth
till another bootstrap
so we'll go and uh
within the conventional approach
trapping algorithm
the input and desired output of
bootstrap can be defined as shown
so input is the Cyber text which is
encrypting a
these are the plain text
but it is on the bottom of the list
we desire on put to strap output to be
on
on other cyber text which is
encrypting the same plain text
you're going to ignoring the encryption
error
but on the greater ring
of Greater cyber test modulus
so the conventional to striping
algorithms is proposed with four steps
namely mode rates clip slot even more
than slot coiff so I'll go on briefly
explaining each steps
the fourth step of Mod race is just
projection
note that sector cyber text or bottom
alerts is also an element of higher
modulus so
we just regard it as an another modulus
on the
ring of higher modulus
recalling the definition of decryption
we can know that the
decrypted plain text of uh huh
motivated cyber text is somewhat
deteriorated with a q0i term
so the problem becomes to remove this
super plus Q 0i term
from to the
um
from the deteriorated subtext and
recover the original play encrypted
plain text
the following steps choose with it but
there is a problem that we want to
manipulate the confidence plain text
directly but we have only methods for
manipulating in creating messages
is also known as Dot and
the
operations deals with encrypted message
are playing homographic operations
but
we can think of sending those
coefficients to slots
by applying homework inquiry
so
recalling the definition of encoding
this is a linear map so we can just homo
frequently evaluate this
so after sending those questions to
slots we just don't deal with the PT
Plus Q 0i term by
holding evaluation and
uh
we covered the space by
applying inverse of the cut saw
so on the following step
we apply homorphing operation on PT Plus
Q 0i
to compute the original encrypted plain
text by applying modular reduction
this modular reduction is
simply approximated by sine function so
it is not hard to operate approximate
this function and there have have been
various approaches to
uh enhance this
but Arena covered those approaches as
because our suggestion can be applied on
any of the implementations on eBay mode
so I'm going to explain even around the
algorithm
the construction will be around the
algorithm is consisted of two minor
modifications on the conventional good
strapping algorithm
the first modification is on the cluster
start step
by alternating it to us
its variant
which is Computing in precise result
in exchange of consuming less modulus
by changing the step of coffee slot to
capture slash sharp we get an RNs wizard
but on the following modification of
alternating even more to even round
we can deal with the error effectively
so we'll look how can we how can it be
done
the first modification is uh
quarter slot which is don't can be done
by just or adjusting parameter
in detail we use lower scale factors to
scale up
Less on including idfp metrics
so looking on the coil of the slot which
is an homographic matrix multiplication
so
it is an inner product with encoded
diagonals and rotated plain texts
so I while I want to point to point out
is that
it is including such diagonals
by adjusting its scale factors we can
adjust its valid beats or Precision of
the identity coefficients so
by using lower scale factor we can
expect the imprecise result
but at the same time
because the rescaling consumes modulus
as much as the scale factor
scaled down
we consume less modulus
which is an
desired behavior of our algorithm
so after taking advantage of consuming
less modulus we have to deal with such
error
by alternating around
eBay round is an
uh systematically it is a homographic
evaluation of motor bounding and it can
be formally defined by
identity subtracted by either mode
so simply defining by this equation
hence uh since
revelation of modular reduction
the identity minus eBay mode is
mapping to the value to the closest
multiple of the
wanted integer
so
applying around
can completely alternate the existing
step and the proof is given as below
so
the
left side is the
step two three four of the convention of
the strapping algorithm
and we utilize the homorphic structure
of the slotcraft and even audience quite
slow so
if we rewrite the eBay mode by either by
identity minus around the identity can
be evaluated separately with either
round so we
get the equation of identity minus event
bootstrap is the same
compute the same result from the
conventional one
although the
even around the stack computes the same
result of the conventional one
there is an advantage of that
everyone is much more stable to the
input error
so
it can be directly seen that
as the input
changes
the modular reduction
the result of modular reduction changes
changes directly but
motor rounding does not so
it is much more stable to the input
error so we can take
advantages and Advantage from the
stability to consume less modulus
uh by applying the algorithm described
so far
we evaluated as on the table
we
developed our own ckks code to test the
algorithm on
practical parameters
so we give the size of message and bit
size of modulus with
practical means
but we
[Music]
maintaining the Precision we
obtained less modulus consensus by 84
bits so it is sufficient amount to
increase evaluation deaths after the
bootstrap
it becomes more and more effective when
it is applied on the parameters with
heavy root strap circuits so the
evaluation originally related evaluation
depth is small
the great advantage of this algorithm is
that it
does not require such assumption or
effort to evaluate
or Implement so it is
it is easy to upgrade on the original
Bluetooth strappinger algorithm and it
is super superior to the existing one
uh
what I want to point out is that
the hard thing is to set the scale
factor of course to slot as this
determines
the how much error on the equipment shop
step is occurred but the firm
setting on the scale factor will be
described on the paper
so
summing up we have
implemented
so
we have suggested on
normal algorithm or conventional
bootstrap
nowhere variant of commissioner
bootstrap to consume less modulus and
okay
is to implement on the conventional
bootstrap implementation
thank you for listening
are there any questions
thank you for your presentation I have a
question about either everyone so can
you show or gain the definition will be
very round so
[Music]
oh
okay this is the second question anyway
so what I don't know is that I don't
know about the role of identity function
so so if I change the identity function
by or some don't present don't present
in functions such as some ultimate pgme
in kks so you know that this is just uh
change the the index of the question
then do you think it happens the same
effects uh as the identity dungeon
what do you think about that
I think there will be no problem on
changing such functions but
if
if you are talking about the uh
programmable Bluetooth strapping yeah
well just just the alternative so so you
you utilize the river around the S on uh
identity binders eBay mode so so then we
can redefine some such functions such as
uh automobile
mode so be be based on you function and
we can upload the function into the the
parenthesis and and the the obtain or
new new education and and so so the left
left side is is replaced I left the
identity function is replaced by some
alternative and and the right side is
some good station is awkward but but I
can I think uh the the effect
so so what I know what I want to know is
there is some differences between or
what I what I uh 13 and and your your or
yeah good works
[Music]
so
uh
as I understand your question is to
comparing Pro
your question that this work is what
other uh
instance of programmable bootstrapping
am I right
uh uh
I I think I I didn't focus on Justice
I didn't function is it's just my
thinking about just don't don't
preserving function so so it just uh uh
do that thing so so some some function I
think the same same work because they
just uh filter the room so so there's no
no or error error or application so I
think I can change so I did function to
some some boom printing function so
let's just also there are some famous
functions in CK case skks so so also
alsoever pigeon so so I I just curious
about there are some some of possibility
to optimize this is your your ideas
yes uh I think
I also think that applying such
technique on the eBay round is also
available same as the combination of
bootstrapping
so
if around can be applied to the program
I will put the struggle yeah
wow okay thank you
any other question from the audience
there was a question online yeah so let
me let me get it
[Music]
okay so it's a question by uh Hilda Vito
Lima Pereira
please could you comment more about the
column bootstrap bits Precision on Slide
22. if we start with scaling 2 to the 60
which is the final precision
foreign
addition to the question which is then
starting with small scaling Factor what
is the final precision
[Music]
uh I I'm not remembering the exact value
but it is much higher than the
conventional bootstrapping one it is
natural because uh
on this diagram we only
dealt with aerobical creative slash
sharp but actually there is some run
okay
existing rounding or quarter slot
and
and there is a polynomial evaluation
error on motor reduction so the blue
grab is not exactly
evaluated by
even mode
so even round defined by the identity
minus symbolt mode is not the is exactly
the same to the given rat graph so
uh
the
bootstrap priest will be somehow a
little higher
to the proposed
current proposed evaluation
I think we can sing a speaker again
the next book is a an online talk
hello
[Music]
we can hear you but we don't see your
slides yet
yeah okay let me try again
[Music]
wow
I'm not sure maybe you could stop this
sharing that is going on already I don't
know if this is blocking me somehow
yeah just a second
thank you
[Music]
foreign
you know
oh we can see your slides are you still
here these lights okay and we can hear
you excellent okay sorry for the
technical problems yeah sure no problem
so okay so the the last talk of this
session will be on the paper titled
final faster fhc instantiated with
Andrew and lwe and the talk will be
given by uh Hilder Pereira uh hilders
thank you very much for an introduction
so this paper is a joint to work with
Charlotte
please if there is any problem uh you
just
tell me you can turn on your microphone
and tell me okay
um so
the starting point here is
essentially comparison between these two
heart problems the rlwe the ring
learning reverse and the end true
problem right so the ring learning
reverse is very famous and it's used to
construct basically most of the fully
homomorphic encryption schemes that we
have and what the rlwe allow us to do is
to sample pairs of polynomials from a
polynomial ring so we can Define this
integer polynomials with degree bounded
by some parameter n and then we can
sample pairs of polynomials where
this second element here has a hidden
structure it actually hides the secret s
but they look uh uniformly random right
if we don't know s
but we have a c kind of similar problem
the entry problem that also allow us to
hide a small polynomial into another
element of this ring so another
polynomial and this is
we are yeah so we were stuck on the
first slide okay thank you
so now we can see the second slide okay
if I do this is it moving
uh no yes
there seems to be some delay
so now we're on the ring lwe and then
two problems later
yes okay thank you
so I was just saying that the end true
kind of give us the same we can
construct this polynomial
um b a ring element that hides this is
more secret and at the same time it
looks random but the difference is that
for the rlwe we need a pair of ring
elements while for DN true we just have
one polynomial right
so if we could somehow
um
it looks like these lights are stuck
again
okay so if we could somehow replace the
the rlw problem by the entry problem
uh
in the the fhc schemes
we should like the intuition is that we
would be able to use half of the memory
and half of the server text because of
instead of working with pairs of
polynomials we would work with a single
polynomial
um these these slides are not passing
right
we are still on the slide number three
yeah
I mean this is not good
okay I will just try one thing please
let me just do this
you are not seeing it no
[Music]
Hilder do you see how to solve the
problem or no I'm sorry I'm trying to
share but
I click on share and it's not sharing
otherwise we I I've been told that uh
you you gave us a prerequisite video so
in in the worst case we can uh just uh
yeah maybe it's better I'm sorry about
this yeah sure that that happened son
and uh so yeah I will stay online after
this we can answer the questions at
least if people have any questions yeah
okay so let's let's do this
foreign
[Music]
true and lwv this is a joint work with
Charlotte Bonte ileashinku chongyong
Park and Professor Nigel smart
so most fhe schemes are based on the
ring learning refers problem
this problem allow us to sample pairs of
polynomials from a polynomial ring so a
ring with integer polynomials with
degree is smaller than some parameter n
and although this pair of polynomials
hide the secret value s they look random
but actually there is another problem
defined over polynomial Rings which is
well known it's the entry problem and
with this problem we can hide a secret
polynomial f
into one single polynomial that also
looks random
so
you can see that the N true
allows us to use one single polynomial
instead of a pair of polynomials so if
we could somehow replace the iwv problem
by the entry problem in this fhe schemes
the intuition is that we should be able
to use half of the memory and maybe half
of the running time
and actually
this observation
has already been used in the past so
some authors try to construct fhe
schemes using the entry problem for
example there was this scheme Yash that
was more efficient than the than the
corresponding ilw based schemes at the
time
but the problem is that the ciphertext
modulus this parameter queue
that these schemes based on the intro
used were super polynomial in n
while the first intro ciphers they used
like intro encryption uh into Crypt they
used very small
uh values of Q just linearing in
and it turns out that the entry problem
is insecure when Q is too big in
comparison to n
now we understand well
why this is the case so before we
essentially just knew this ski recovery
attacks which have a Time exponential in
N but there are new attacks called
sublets attacks that whose hardness
depends very strongly on Q so the
situation is the following when Q is
linearing and the sublets attacks are
more expensive than the key recovery
attacks and then because the curricular
attack is already exponential time then
true problem is very hard
but as we increase Q the sublets attacks
becomes easier and easier and
at this point if Q is exponential in the
end in the sublets attack becomes
polynomial so if you have an attack that
runs in polynomial time this means that
n true problem is very easy
so the sublets attack has become easier
is easier at some so at some point it
costs essentially the same as the key
recovery attack and this point is called
the fatigue point
so
new uh results especially this paper
while auduca and pardon
computed the Point as n to the
power of two and a half essentially
so if we choose parameters with Q larger
than this we are in this version which
is known as overstretched and in this
version the entry problem is not as hard
as we want
because of the sublets attacks so when
we use the intro problem to instantiate
our schemes we have to restrict
ourselves to this version here
So Below the fatigue point
so the first contribution of the paper
is constructing a scheme that looks like
the GSW scheme
but it's based on the untrue and because
of this it has a faster external product
so the external products the main
operation of this type of schemes this
is GSW schemes
and then we use this NGS to bootstrap a
scheme that is based on the intro and
then because this scheme is based on N
true and NGS is also based on intro this
means that we are between fhe based only
on the entry problem
and with parameters below the fatigue
point
and also we use NGS to bootstrap a LW
based scheme and when we do this this
combination of lwe and then true give us
a bootstrapping that is 28 percent uh
faster than tfhe's bootstrapping and
uses about half of the memory that tfhe
uses
so now you explain a little about our
scheme NGS
so this secret is just the small
polynomial from the entry problem
and then we Define two types of Cipher
texts a scalar ciphertext which is just
a polynomial so we have a name through
sample and we add the message is scaled
by some integer Factor Delta
and the vector Cipher text
is composed by essentially a vector of
this uh scalar a ciphertext here but
this Delta instead of a single Delta now
is a vector with powers of some value B
right so we have a vector of n true
samples and then the message is
multiplied by the vector of powers of
some base we can choose this base B here
and then L is log of Q in this base B
so in the original GSW scheme
this instead of this Vector here what we
have is a matrix like this so you can
see that here we have l l again so 2
times L of rows and two columns right so
2 times L times two this means that we
have 4 times L elements and here we just
have Arrow elements
then to run an external product we just
have to take this the scalar ciphertext
we decompose it into a vector of L
entries and we multiply it by a vector
ciphertext right so this is just an
inner product so the external products
is an operation between a scalar and a
vector ciphertext and it costs just L
multiplications on this polynomial ring
so when we compare with with the GSW
scheme we have this the descaler server
text now is just one polynomial instead
of two
and the full Cipher text in our case is
a vector with L polynomials while doing
GSW it's a matrix with four times L
polynomials and then the external
product is just an inner product in our
case so it just costs L polynomial
multiplications but with the GSW scheme
the external product is a vector matrix
multiplication and then it costs 4 times
L polynomial multiplications
now we will explain how we use the NGS
to orbiting fastbootstrappings
so we used the framework from View and
tfhe which which is essentially this so
we start with an lwe encryption
of some message and with some large
noise e and we want to obtain an LW
encryption of the same message but with
a small noise so what tfhe and
essentially fuel does is this we have a
main Loop using external products and
this so this is evaluated with the GSW
because the jsw implements the external
products and in this main Loop we are
essentially running the linear part of
the decryption of this scheme in the
exponent of this monomial X so what we
will be thinking is m
I scaled message M plus some noise here
in the exponent and this is encrypted
under the ring lwe instead of the lwe
and then there is a extraction which
takes this M from the exponent and puts
it in the coefficient and also keeps
switching so that we go from the rlwe
back to the lwe again and then this
gives us LW encryption of the same
message M but now this noise e doesn't
exist anymore we just have a new noise e
Prime which is a smaller than the
original noise so this is how tfhe does
it
well we already have the external
products with the NGS so we can run this
part
but when we do this we are between
a monomial encrypting this same value
but encrypted under n true instead of
rlwe
and then
this means that we need somehow to
extract and key switch
for in true now right
and also if we want everything to be
based on the entry problem then we need
a new scheme based on the untrue instead
of the lwe
so we'll start with this we show how we
constructed the base scheme based on the
intro so we used this Matrix entry
problem which is
kind of the corresponding of the
lwe for the rlwe right this is in true
without the ring so what this MN truth
says is that if you have a random a
small Norm Matrix G and a small Norm
Matrix F you take the inverse of f in
with pi by 3 then you get this Matrix C
that looks random just like for the
polynomial case right
well but if you take the ciphertext to
be a matrix then to decrypt you have to
multiply by The Matrix F and we don't
want the decryption to be a matrix
matrix multiplication because this is
too complicated we want the decryption
to be simple so just an inner product a
vector vector multiplication right so
what we do is instead of considering the
whole Matrix C we just take the first
row of c and we use these as the cipher
text right and if you check it the first
row of C is actually the The Matrix G
times the first column of the inverse of
f right so now we have a vector of
Dimension n and then to decrypt now we
just encrypt the message in the first
entry of this Vector C so to decrypt we
just need to multiply by the First
Column of this Matrix F instead of by F
right so if they find this a small F
here is the First Column of f the
description is just this inner product c
times f
and then because this is just a inner
product we can compute it in the
exponent of X using the external
products of the NGS
scheme
so now uh the bootstrapping goes like
this we start with an encryption of some
message M under this Vector small F and
then we use an external products to
multiply this this Vector ciphertext
this by um
by this secret Vector F here so what we
will be telling is this monomial uh and
in the exponent of it we get the error
plus the scaled message right and this
is a normal entry encryption so it's
encrypted under this polynomial F and
belongs to this polynomial ring
and then we run the extraction
essentially in the same way as tfhe so
this eliminates this e here removes this
noise e that we had in the original
ciphertext and brings M from the
exponent to the coefficient here
and
then we propose a key switching for n
true Cipher texts right because this is
encrypted under Andrew
and
we apply this uh key switching to go
back from an encryption of Dimension
capital n two Dimension small n and also
to switch the key from this polynomial F
to the vector F that we had in the
beginning so the output has this has
exactly the same format as the input so
it's an encryption of the same message
but with a smaller noise right and then
we can set all the parameters below the
fatigue point
so now we have
um
fhe with fastbootstrapping based only on
the intro problem right so we start with
an intro encryption of some message M
with large noise e we use the external
products and we get an entry encryption
of this monomial with the message plus
some noise in the exponent and we have
the extraction and key switching which
give us an intro encryption of this same
message M again but with a smaller noise
e Prime
we also use the NGS to bootstrap a skin
based on the lwe so when we have a
scheme based on the lwe just like in few
or in the in tfhe the ciphertexts have
this form so to encrypt the message M
under secret key s we sample this
uniform
Vector a and then we compute this
integer b as the inner product of this
uniform a times the secret s we add some
noise in this scaled message right all
of this module Q
so to decrypt essentially you have to
take this public a multiply by S this is
an inner product just just before and
subtract from B so this we can already
do using the external products of NGS
right then we obtain an encryption of
this monomial B minus a times s which is
an encryption of the scaled message plus
some noise and all of this encrypted
under the secret polynomial F of the
entry problem
so
this means that we already have this
first step of the the bootstrapping
framework right we can start with LW
encryption of some message M with large
noise e we run the external products
using NGS and we get an entry encryption
of this power of x
now
uh to go back to lwe
we proposed a key switching that
switched from the end through to the LW
problem so we run the extraction as
before this give us an entry encryption
of M and removes this e and then we run
this new intro to lwe key switching to
switch from an encryption of M under N2
to an encryption of M under the lwe
problem and this closes the loop and
completes the bootstrapping procedure
so now we are going to see the Practical
results
we implemented everything in C plus and
this implementation is publicly
available so you can go to this git wrap
repository and download it and install
and play with it
and because we mainly wanted to compare
with tfhe which is the state of the art
for
binary circuits
we used the same fft Library as tfhe key
and then we compiled our code with the
same compilation flags as tfhe
and we try to use similar parameters as
the ones used in tfhe
so
we we have two is two fhe uh schemes now
we have one that is based on and true
that we call M and true here and one
that is based on the lwv right and then
we bootstrap both of them using NGS
which is based on true so these are the
parameters for these base schemes
so the dimension of the ciphertext that
we want to bootstrap with and true is
800 and with lwv is 610. so for tfhe
they use lwe ciphertexts and then the
dimension is about 600 as well
and for the NGS the degree of the
polynomials that we have in the
polynomial ring is always 2 to the 10.
in our case and what changes essentially
is the decomposition base from one case
to the other and for tfhe this Dimension
here is also 2 to the ten so this means
that RTF our ffts the Fourier transforms
are over the same Dimension as in tfhe
right so they are really comparable
and we have to
to remark that this value n here
this tells how many external products we
have to run so the thing is for MN true
we see that we have 800 this is much
more than in the lwe case so even if our
each of our external products is cheaper
than in the fhe because you have to run
much more of them at the end our end MN
true scheme is slower than the tfhe but
for the LW case because the number of
external products is similar to the tfhe
case and each external product is
cheaper than our lwe within true is
faster than in tfhe
so when we run tfhe in our experiments
we got that each bootstrapping takes
around six uh 66 milliseconds
and then for our MN true we got 92 so
this is
kind of similar same order of magnitude
but it's lower right but our combination
of lwv and in true runs the bootstrap in
48 milliseconds
and we can see here that that's the main
reason because the number of ffts is uh
much smaller in our case so essentially
what we got is that if we check here the
bootstrapping key and the key switching
key they are much smaller than in tfhe
so the key material that we need is
about uh half of what the fhe needs and
the bootstrap in time is about 28 faster
so to conclude we proposed an fhe scheme
based on in true with parameters that
lie uh below the fatigue point so
outside of this stretched regime
and so this brings back into FH it's the
game and we hope that this result will
bring more attention of the academic
community so that people can do further
researcher on Andrew based fhe
and maybe improve the efficience of our
scheme or create new schemes based on
intro
and well we proposed this a scheme that
looks like jsw but is based on N2 so we
called it NGS and it has a smaller
Cipher texts and faster homework
multiplication when compared to the rlw
based GSW so
we hope that this NGS will also be
useful for other applications so
essentially where GSW is used maybe we
can use NGS instead
and finally we proposed this uh
uh fhe scheme mixing and true and lwe
and we saw that this runs faster than
tfhe
so that's all if you have any questions
or comment please feel free to contact
me
thank you all
okay so we are running late and uh the
attendees from the other room are
starving in front of the footer so if if
there is a quick question we can take it
but otherwise I suggest we do it offline
any quick question
okay so let's thank uh Hilda again
thank you very much
the vegetarian options are I mean there
are more vegetarian options