so my name is Maxwell
um
I have the pleasure to to share this
session so this is the first one on
practical cryptography uh there will be
three talks in this session and the
first one is on some preserving
encryption and two could be given by by
Sarah I see online sorry can you hear us
yes I can perfect so you can start
whenever you want all right well thank
you so welcome everyone
um so I'm going to talk about new
algorithms and Analysis for some
preserving encryption and this is Joint
work with Scott yellick
uh so I'm going to start by introducing
the problem of some preserving
encryption
um so the idea is we're going to create
an encryption scheme where the
ciphertext and plain texts are both
going to be integer vectors and they're
going to have the same sum so if we sum
up all the points in the vector for the
plain text and the cipher text they're
both going to have the same sum in
addition each of the components of the
vector are typically going to be bounded
between 0 and some maximum of D and this
problem was introduced by tajik at all
in 2019 and they looked at a particular
application of some preserving
encryption specifically thumbnail
preserving encryption so the idea is you
want to create a encryption scheme where
the thumbnail of the original image and
the encrypted image are the same so
we'll create that just to go over we
create the thumbnail by dividing an
image into B by B blocks of pixels and
then we're going to replace each block
by the mean pixel values the average of
all the pixel values within the block to
create a smaller image so if we take
each each of these same blocks and we
apply some preserving encryption to the
blocks then the sum of the pixels in the
original image and the encrypted image
will be the same thus the amino be the
same and we've preserved the thumbnail
between the original image and the
encrypted image
all right so I'm going to give a little
background on this problem and and then
discuss our new algorithms uh so you can
think of some preserving encryption as
it's a special type of format preserving
encryption and there's been a lot of
work on format preserving encryption it
was originally studied by Brightwell and
Smith in 97.
uh it was formally defined and analyzed
by Bellaire uh riston part Rockaway and
speakers and 09 and they used a rank and
Cipher unrank construction which I'll
talk about uh further examples of that
here today
and again it's widely studied uh and
even standardized
so to Jake at all introduced
um this idea of some preserving
encryption as I said before and they
focused on the problem of creating a
thumbnail encryption scheme
okay so I I mentioned that this idea of
rank and Cipher unrank is going to be
important so let me just uh review that
real quickly in case you haven't seen it
um so the idea is we're going to start
with a plain text then we're going to
apply a rank algorithm so we're going to
rank each possible plain text between 0
and N minus one where n is going to be
the total number of possible plain texts
so we first start by ranking it then we
have an integer and we can apply a
standard Cipher to get another integer
right this is our encrypted integer and
then we apply an unranked algorithm to
get back to a ciphertext and this is a
standard technique in format preserving
encryption
so did you get all um realize that we
could use this approach um in for the
problem of some preserving encryption um
and so they proposed um this idea of
representing a string
um or sorry representing a vector as a
string of ones and zeros so this is the
stars and bars construction from
combinatorics if you've seen that before
um so we're basically going to uh for if
let's say look at our example the first
number is five we're going to replace
that with five ones and then a zero so
the zeros are going to serve as our
separators
um so we'll have one less zero than
there are points in our vector
um and then our second number is three
we would have three ones followed by our
separator and then our final one
um so if we uh represent our vectors of
integers um as binary strings in this
fashion
um then this is a regular language and
there's some known techniques we can use
um to to turn this into an encryption
scheme however
um this uh has high time complexity and
it's it's relatively impractical in this
situation
however uh tiju got all realized that if
we do this with just vectors that have
two points so if we just have a link two
then this is pretty straightforward and
you know if you've got some downtime
during the next break between talks you
could work out how we could rank uh
vectors of length two and with a fixed
sum
uh and so they use this idea to create
as some preserving encryption scheme
and it actually can be thought of as a
Markov chain and so I'm going to talk a
little bit more about it from the Markov
chain perspective in a little bit so I'm
going to present their algorithm
um not exactly how they presented it but
um as a Markov chain which they they did
realize they did um point out that this
is a Markov chain so the idea is they're
going to repeat this algorithm in
multiple rounds so they're going to
start again you're starting
from the vector of integers and they're
going to randomly Shuffle Shuffle those
points all right so you randomly Shuffle
the points and then we're going to pair
adjacent points to get a perfect
matching all right randomly shuffled
pair adjacent points to get a perfect
matching and then now within our
matching we have pairs of points and we
just I just mentioned that we could rank
in Cipher unrank these points and so
we're going to replace
um using this Rank and Cipher unrank
approach we're going to replace each
pair of integers uniformly at random
from all the possible valid choices
right so we have to preserve the sum and
we have to preserve that component bound
all right so for each pair in our
matching we're going to replace
uniformly at random
um from the possible choices and then we
get another Vector that's going to have
the same sum and respect those component
bounds
all right so so
um
today our results
um we give the first proof bounding the
mixing time of the tajik add-all
algorithm
um so you know the natural question you
might ask uh when presented with an
algorithm like this is how many rounds
is sufficient right how many times do we
have to repeat this
um so we're going to we give the first
formal bound on the mixing time and in
addition we give two uh practical Rank
and unranked algorithms that we can use
for some preserving encryption
and we also create prototype
implementations uh with performance
comparisons comparing these three
different algorithms all right so so in
the rest of my talk today I'm going to
go over briefly our mixing time bound
and some of the proof techniques behind
it and then I'll present uh the two rank
um well I'll describe at a high level
the rank and unrank algorithms and then
show you briefly the uh performance
comparisons
okay um so we're going to ask this
question for for the mixing time bound
of how many times do we need to repeat
this algorithm
um and I'll give a heuristic algorithms
for what secure um choices round choices
would be uh but no formal proof and so
that's what I what I'm going to present
today
um and they tested performance with a
thousand three thousand and five
thousand rounds
uh just to formalize I'm going to talk
about the mixing time
um and here the mixing time is going to
be
um the amount of time until the
difference between the distribution at
time T and the stationary distribution
is less than Epsilon all right so we're
going to parameterize this by Epsilon
all right um and we show that if n is
the vector length D is the component
bound and S is the fixed sum then the
mixing time
um is upper bounded by n log of the
minimum of DN 2s and one over Epsilon
all right so how do we do this well
we're going to use a half cup we use a
path coupling technique due to Dyer and
green hill and 98 and this is a standard
technique in the Markov chain community
so before I I'm going to kind of give
you a high level
um view of what the proof looks like and
before I jump into that though let me
just kind of tell you a little bit about
the techniques that we use um I know I'm
sure not everyone's familiar with them
um so we we use path coupling which kind
of followed on to coupling so the idea
of coupling is we're going to simulate
um two processes X and Y and each of
them if we view it in isolation it looks
just like that Markov chain
um and so we're going to simulate these
processes until they agree and once they
agree they stay together and it turns
out
um if we can bound
um if we can bound how long it takes
before
um these processes agree this is called
the coupling time
um and this will give us a bound on the
mixing time so we can use the coupling
time to bound the mixing time
and how we do this is we generally show
that at each step of the Markov chain
the distance between the two chains is
getting closer in expectation so the
expected distance between the two chains
X and Y is decreasing
um and here um we're going to use the
Manhattan distance
all right so in coupling again we want
to show that the expected change over
one step um from any arbitrary pair of
configurations so we have to we have to
show that this happens for any two
configurations in our state space any
two possible you know vectors
um path coupling makes this process a
lot easier because we can just look at a
restricted set of pairs of
configurations all right so we don't
have to look at all pairs we can just
look at a subset and in this particular
case we're going to choose to only look
at pairs that differ on exactly two
points so every single other pair in the
vector is this every single you know X
and Y match on every single other point
except for Just Two
um and so we only have to look at these
special vectors that only differ on
these two points
uh and just to kind of give you an idea
why this works um if we can um we show
that you can find between any arbitrary
pairs of configurations you can find
Paris
um that are in this special set right
that only differ on two points uh and so
the expected change in distance between
any two arbitrary configurations is
bounded by the sum of the expected
changes between those special Pairs and
so we can use those to get a bound
um to get to get our bound overall
okay so so just to give you an idea how
this works um so again we're using the
Manhattan distance uh and we're looking
at vectors that just differ on two
points so um right so here there's again
X and Y agree on every everything else
except for these two special points and
we want to show that after a single step
of the Markov chain the expected change
in distance is going to right the
distance is going to decrease
all right so so just to remember our
Markov chain right it starts by randomly
randomly shuffling the points um and
then it pairs adjacent points so if
after our random shuffling if these two
points that differ if these happen to be
adjacent
right
um then uh we our distance decreases to
zero right that we can choose the same
um pairs of new pairs of points in each
of our chain X and Y and the distance
decreases to zero so this is the good
case right this is this is going to
solve everything
the downside though is that if these
pairs of points right if these match
with other
points
um then it's much trickier and one of
the things that makes this really tricky
is that now if we look at the two chains
X and Y the sums are going to be
different
and so that means that in many cases the
number of possible Right remember we're
choosing uniform formally at random from
all the possible ways to replace these
points and so they're going to have a
different number of choices which means
that we're going to move to the
different
um the different the different choices
with different probabilities in the two
chains it turns out we can still show
that the expected change in distance
that we can come up with a coupling
right so we come up with a coupling and
we show
um that we can all the distance will
always
um stay the same or decrease but it's
quite tricky and there's a lot of
details that I'm hiding so I'm not going
to go into those details but that that's
what makes it
interesting I guess or tricky is that
part
um all right
okay so I told you we had kind of two
types of results one was this mixing
time um bound and the other one was the
rank insight for unring
okay so we have two algorithms um for
ranking and unranking and I'm going to
talk about the first one just a little
more quickly because it's not quite as
as um interesting
um so the first uh algorithm for ranking
um is going to rank the vectors uh
directly using lexographical order and
here we're going to build on algorithms
for unranking that were developed by
Stein for use in random sampling so it
was trying to do something different and
he gave an algorithm for unranking
according to lexicographical order and
we came up with added on to that one for
ranking
um the this algorithm is going to rely
uh heavily on a table which we can
pre-compute and that's going to store so
every point in the table and S is going
to store the number of vectors of
LinkedIn with some s and the table all
entries across the table will have the
same component found
and with this pre-computed information
uh we can rank according to
lexographical order and I'll if you're
if you're interested in the details you
can take a look at the paper
um the other ranking algorithm
um is based on what's called we well we
call recursive block order and I as far
as we know this is is not an ordering
that has been been used before and so uh
to describe this order so if you want to
order
um two vectors according to recursive
black order
um you're going to look you're going to
divide the vector in half and you're
going to look at the left sum and the
right sum and if the left sum is smaller
it's going to have smaller it's going to
be smaller in the order
if the left sum is greater it's going to
be later in the order and if they're
equal and this is where the recursive
part comes in if the sum the left sums
are equal well then we're going to we're
going to take a look and work it's how
the vectors relate depends recursively
on how the left half relates to the the
right half according to recursive block
order
all right and so here's an example so
this is different than likes a graphical
order again we're looking at we're going
to split the vector in half and we're
comparing the left sums to see where it
falls and if they're equal then we
repeat
all right if we want to rank according
to recursive block order and I'm going
to go through this a little bit quickly
um but uh so if we want to come up with
a ranking based on this ordering we need
to determine if we have a particular
configuration we need to determine how
many configurations are smaller in the
order
all right
um and so there's basically three
different ways that a configuration can
be smaller in the order and so we need
to count how many there are in order to
rank uh and so we can do this using a
combination of recursion and the table
values that are stored um so if we look
at this first the piece in yellow right
the number that have a smaller left sum
well we can count this up using
table values
uh the second one if they have an equal
left sum but Exile is less than yl right
then we need to determine the rank of x
l and then for each of those right every
for everything that's smaller in rank
the number of configurations there are
right we multiply the number of ways
there are to fill in the right half
um and then to get that final piece in
green um we're going to take the rank of
the right hand side and if we add these
three things up we get the rank of a
configuration and and you can take that
recurrence and turn it into an ad it's
pretty straightforward to go from there
to an algorithm
the nice thing about recursive uh block
order is if you see here we're only
looking at
um when we make recursive calls we're
dividing in half each time so we
actually only need to see two Lo we only
need to compute to log in rows of that
table versus lexicographical order so we
need much fewer rows which is going to
give us some performance improvements
foreign
so both of these algorithms rely on this
c table and so I'm just going to
describe quickly we come up with two
different ways to fill this table and
the first one is similar to what Stein
does but in fact um we so he doesn't
frame it as dynamic programming which is
what I'm doing here but it essentially
is the same technique for filling the
table we actually use a cumulative sum
instead of storing the C values directly
because it leads to some improvements in
the algorithm
um and so you can come up with a
recurrence for this table
um you the idea here um is we're going
to look at the very first uh Vector the
very first point in our Vector
um and so if it starts with zero we can
count those recursively as shown on the
slide
um and if it starts with some number
that's greater than zero right so if it
starts with something that's greater
than zero then we can just look at the
number of configurations within points
and some one less
and then we take each of those and we
add one and that gives us something
right that gives us something in the
original C of n s
however um we're gonna in some cases
we're going to be over counting here
because adding 1 to the first point in
the vector might take us above our
component bound and so that's where this
third term comes in
I mentioned that in the last right in
the um in our second uh ranking
algorithm uh we only need to look at log
n rows of the table or two log n at most
log n if it's a power of two
um and but our you know the the dynamic
programming version of filling the table
actually you would need to fill out all
all rows right and so you wouldn't get
that that Improvement so we also can
fill the table uh using generating
functions as well and that allows us to
only fill the rows that we need and we
can take advantage of the fact that we
only need those log n rows of the table
right so in addition to the the mixing
time bound and the ranking algorithms we
did prototype implementations uh and
compared the running time of these three
different algorithms I'm not going to go
over uh the the sliding you know that
the numbers are up there
um I will say that uh for the specific
example of thumbnail preserving
encryption it seems like the ranking
algorithms aren't going to get us an
improvement uh but again which algorithm
is better is going to depend on your
particular sources of ND and S uh and as
we get to larger values of n the ranking
Solutions uh have struggle because we
have to pre-compute this table and that
table starts to get really large
all right so in summary I showed you
um boy basically I hand waved a lot um a
proof of the bounding the mixing time of
the at all algorithm
um and I showed you or we gave two
practical Rank and unranked algorithms
for some preserving encryption one based
on lexographical order and the other
based on this new recursive block order
and uh we created prototype
implementations with performance
comparisons
that's it thank you
foreign
speaker
commit maybe online I don't know
so maybe so I saw celery as one of the
application uh what is preserved in that
case
sorry I saw in one of his slide that
salaries was one of the application
um so what do you preserve in that case
so the sum of the salaries
oh yeah that we're preserving this time
yeah so all of our work preserves the
sun I think you could definitely
possibly generalize some of these
methods if there was a a different
um parameter that you wanted to uh
preserve uh but we only looked at some
preserving a lot of the ranking
algorithms are very specific to the song
assume that someone new joined the
company
and so in that case so the sum will
change but then you can deduce the
salary of that person
is that correct
so assume that someone new join a
company oh yeah there's some would
change you would have to yeah
and just the last question so is there a
plan to make a product of what you
presented
not as far as I know I would love it if
there was but okay
so thank you
okay so we can move to the to the next
talk thank you Sarah
um so next talk will be on the Elizabeth
string Cipher and the torque will be
given by uh by orl
foreign
which from now on I will call ATT and
which is a tool used in a fully
automatic encryption to solve the
problem caused by the extension ratio
when you're doing the fhe you have to
deal with a huge equivalent ratio so
this is a illustration of it
so if you want to send some data on on
the network and you have a small plan
text the corresponding type attack is
going to be huge
um
so um we are going to try to use uh what
comes with fhe to uh to reduce this so
on the screen you have a usual setup of
fhe
where someone is trying to send some
data to a server to do some computation
but doesn't want to Revenge them
on the server is going to compute a
modifically on them but once again uh
sending this data requires a lot of
bandwidth so what we would like to do
instead is use another crypto system
much later with a small extension ratio
and then since the server can compute
whatever you want it can also decrypt
the this small cycle text to obtain the
the frequency encryption it would have
other without that and then compute
whatever you want but to do so you need
to have you need it needs to have the
secret key
of the new schema so we also have to do
one uh sending in Freedom of encryption
at uh at the setup which contains a
secret key
so several HH schemes have appeared over
the year
uh and they are trying to optimize their
own different criteria the main three
being the the economy in terms of
countries uh in itself
and the other two being the latency and
the circuit and nobody really agrees on
which one is the best so the latency is
the time you have to wait uh to uh
to to go from a small symmetric scheme
so my gray box here to a red one on the
server
on the passion that is called
transferring
so it's the time that it takes to uh to
translator only one bit
and it makes sense when you use packing
in FH here which is the ability to store
several message in a single Cipher text
so we wanted to uh we
and we have to introduce a new scheme
called Elizabeth
which will be here on the schema but the
main idea that we want to introduce is
that it doesn't really make sense to
compare all these scheme uh in terms of
I don't see our throughput sorry
so in the current state of the art
scheme are designed to optimize some
aspect of the hhe so some aspect of the
transfer in time
and then the comparison are done as this
team were Standalone and we don't we
don't think it makes sense in fhc since
uh it's within the site of the fact that
in fhc we want to compute something with
output of the ht's camera
so what we did instead was to start by
thinking in terms of use case what we
want to do once we have transferred and
then design a scheme that will be
optimal for that kind of use case
so uh to evaluate an HTT scheme with the
use case we need a use case
and we choose a one that is a very
common in uh in fhc and it's machine
learning
so it comes with its own set of
constraints
first off in machine learning we want to
use as many bits as possible because
neural networks usually work with 32 or
64 bits input
and then we want to be able to compute
fast because when you do machine
learning you don't want to wait a long
time to have an answer and what you're
trying to compute
and then fht come with its own set of
constraints so we choose to use a tfhe
that is a state of the art computer
system for your memory
and in tfat you don't have the ability
to pack messages so that was something
that we knew we would like to deal with
the gfhe is useful when you want to do
modular editions on the evaluation of
negative tables that use uh lookup
tables in which the second half of the
values are the opposite of the first
half
another missing item on my side is that
in tfhe you cannot store very large
messages uh in a single Circle text so
we knew that we would have to to work
with a few bits so the trade-off was to
use 4-bit messages that was the best we
could do to have a small crypto system a
faster system to evaluate
while storing as many bits as possible
you know tfhe type of text
and for the first evaluation we uh we
made it so that the operator system will
be easy to evaluate and multiple thread
at the same time
and regarding the consummator because
the tfhe uh we just chose to call them a
toolbox inside of a constraints and we
use them to design the scheme
okay so now let's dive into a horror or
scanner is done so it's called Elizabeth
and it's uh
sold as a successor for crypto system
called Philip which has all uh state of
the art HH scheme is biased uh is based
on the filter permutation introduced by
ship so the idea is that when you want
to generate a key stream
you start from an internal State and
then you do some computation over it but
when you do so in sat you add some noise
in the output and if you do it too too
much at some point your your kitchen
will be so noisy that you won't be able
to use it anymore
with the filter permit data padding you
start from an internet State and you
apply a key stream generator function
and you will always use the the same
function on the same internal state so
the bit that you produce will always
contain a fixed amount of noise
so are we going to do that by adapting
the feature parameter padding to the
group heater parameter as a group inter
parameter padding so we start from a key
register and using a public prng we are
going to choose a subset in it on the
shuffle it and then add some modernized
in it
so all of this operations are now is
less because choosing a subset I'm
Shuffling it it's not fhc just moving
box around
so at this point nothing is noisier in
what we did
and then we are going to apply a filter
function and only in the feature
function will be a noise to a ciphertext
so uh in the end Elizabeth is a entirely
defined by its filter so here it is
I do realize there's a lot of slides so
we're going to break it up the first
thing you have to notice is that there's
only three different things uh on this
you have five inputs or equivalent to X5
modular editions and the eight boxes S12
S8 that are negative Equitable and that
are computed through through a bootstrap
in a homographically
and these lookup tables are the costic
part of the operation
luckily the first four can be a computed
separately because you don't need the
output of a trend to compute yourself so
you can do that in a first step by trade
then you have an addition because you
have to wait and synchronize but the the
next four can also be done separately in
Traditions Trading so in the end to a
computer it is a
this box you only have to pay for two
bootstraps and you can compute eight of
them and it is just a part of the full
filter and the actual filter is the
tissue version then 12 times in parallel
so the the entire filter of exhibit
consists in 96
bootstraps but you only pay for for two
of them sounds to a community thread
so now let's have a look at our use case
so this is a neural network that uh we
uh we used for the use case which is
rather small I think I was told so by
people that do understand what the
machine learning is
uh and what this does it's uh
classifying
um pictures of classes
and believe it or not but this picture
is actually to a high def to be used in
fhe because it uses eight bits of Gray
and we can only use three the Y3 are not
far even so uh is a bad kind of stuff
for bits messages it's because uh to
enable first computation with jfhe you
need to set the machine different bits
to zero so we can only write in the the
three uh next bits
so by doing so the the neural network uh
lose a bit of accuracy so it can only
answer quite clear 97 or no 90 of the
time
but uh it's a it's okay for us so
because uh we know that with FH here we
are going to lose a bit of accuracy
so
no regarding the timing of Elizabeth
uh it has been designed to be
to use less constraining uh parameters
than any use case that it could be
useful so actually in this table I'm
only interested in these three values so
if you use Elizabeth with the optimal
parameters it's going to be a
so if you don't see efficient so the
timing doesn't mean much because it
depends on what computer or otherwise
you're going to use
uh but what you can see is that if you
use Elizabeth with the use case then the
time I uh the timing are multiplied by a
factor five and it comes from the fact
that the parameters of the use case uh
yes of the use case are going to be much
bigger than the parameters of Elizabeth
uh and uh for every different set of
parameters that you want to use in
effect here you have to send another key
to the server so you could choose to uh
use Elizabeth as a plug-and-player with
the system and turn missing to the
server and then determine they are going
to be a bit bigger but you could also
choose to send the its own set of
parameters for either that and gain some
time
so if you just do an intern that is an
evaluation of the neural network in fhe
without hhe it's going to takes five
seconds and if you use Elizabeth with
the parameters of the neural network is
going to be a much larger but once again
it can be a much reduced if you use the
parameters for example 30 firms and the
one from the neural network
and in terms of efficiency bandwidth
wise Elizabeth
is a
we will reduce the bandwidth youth uh
since the very first influence
and if you choose to use the two set of
parameters uh it's going to take a bit
more influences so around 2000 in front
years but it only takes 40 hours and so
it's not much in a SAT time
so friends there what do we want to do
well first off we would like to be able
to transfer much bigger message at the
same time because with forbids we have
seen that there's not much that we can
do
we also think that uh we should look at
that from the machine learning point of
view so without even using cryptography
or can we do a better neural networks
that are
easier to evaluate with a fhe
on the left three we should look for
more relevant use case because once
again we think it's uh it doesn't make
sense to consider Itachi without a use
case but we also think that we need to
find use case that are relevant to uh to
hhe so we chose to to use teacher's case
because fmnist is a very common data set
in machine learning but maybe it's not
what you want to do when you use akt and
we think that people that do understand
what is machine learning should look
into hht and find a
relevant challenge that will help
compare feature schemes
thank you very much for your for your
attention and sharing this channel I'd
be happy to answer
it doesn't drop out okay
the questions
remarks
online do you have questions
um so he told us that uh Elizabeth was
the successor of Philip yes that's the
main difference between the two ciphers
Philippe work in one bit messages on the
with Elizabeth we are able to encrypt
the four bits at a time so that the main
difference between Philip and Elizabeth
on the training between isibetan Master
hhe schemes with the ability to work on
4 bit messages
just one bit messages and there are some
other activities things that work with
several bit messages but then the output
are in a infinite field rather than a
Z16 so it's less easier to do any
computation on them after a while
okay thank you
Okay so we've done no more questions
let's thank the speaker
thank you very much
Google
so next talk is some related key
Boomerang attacks on AES
hello
so
hello everyone let's get started
so as you can see here this table
summarizer existing attack again a year
1992 and note that here by click not
really an effect it's not improves it's
not desert with a complete look on the
display and
the current met time complexity on
Attack on Route is total
176 for a relatively Boomerang of
pericope and hobartovic and
in this book we found a new related
time complexity in two to three people
come lower than the Batman attack
so
here is the boomerang attack in the lab
is a random attack
and in the right is our type
going by here is that means no different
and
we have our attack has the probability
is two to minus 108 instead of two to
minus 110 is a bit better but it's
almost the same probability
here is a zoom and map input of blood
attack
so in our type we have the modeling by
zombies attack doesn't mean we know much
more information than the type of
protocol and combative
and since the rest of this talk I will
need balance in detail how we found the
attack
so anyone here knows a boomerang attack
before raise your hand okay
of
and first the study here it's the
different will be combined or not
so I will land in a basic form of
boomerang distinguisher had an attacker
as the art staff for about ingression
and decreasing cycle so first the
attacker picked the big one at random
and ask for the Cyber text C1
and secondly he composed Vito as by
adding a different answer and get the
psychotic C2
and after that he completely free and C4
by adding the different than fat to C1
and C2
and next he obtains the corresponding
Atlantic P3 and E4
and finally he asked he checked it be
free and before he differ by the same
different answer or not
and
we will keep answer combat more often
than a random permutation we will have a
distinguisher
and
false the artists didn't know approach
the stifle e defined into two parts
P0 and E1 and we miss the good
difference so for its path and
puzzle
input different and style it was the
outputation data with high probability B
and over e0 and the mileage with the
high property Q over E1 and we need the
then the expected property is P Square Q
Square which the asymptoms that's
crucial are independent but
think directly this Essence does not
allow it correct and
who had
in 2011 movie shows up the boomerang
never come back and the problem comes
from the assistant
that's my dependent may exist so
to handle the dependency that money and
propose a sandwich attack now disciple
divide into three parts instead of two
parts is zero and you want to stay here
but we have a new middle pass em and the
em with high property and now the
expected probability is distance Square
building square and uh
and
so how we can compose the property of em
PTY 2018
table that reduce the problem of
computing the property of the numerous
to to the one of computing it over its
exploit and
so
VCT mode here is the number of solutions
as boomerang come back
mystery framework this computes the
property of Boomerang distinguisher with
a considering the dependency
and
to search for the move around attack we
typically use some automatic tune also
because the boomerang distinguisher and
sit there and use MLP model to study
this level speak to aspects the belcy
blue and Sasaki use an IOP model to
direct research for the women around
this ticket user on the hip but this
works only rigid em plus only one rail
and recently the land and introduced a
set of table to calculate the
probability
and they use an IOP CP and other
approach to search for the boom language
industry on skinny and now what is based
on this book
so
this technical had to understand the
notation view in the definition
to surface the boomerang characteristic
to serve as a woman listening leader you
need to be able to compose the property
of the boomerang characteristic
visiting not enough so we need to mask
the different cell table we need a chart
three table here we have the UBC pays
for the upper basicity lbcp for the
lower obesity and obesity
and
so when given a boomerang characteristic
how to propose the volatility last
Boomerang Twitter
life
many people like the property of
assistance but how we can Comfort the
property of transition for one
particular Expo that's gives a different
suitable
so here we give an characteristics
on three well
and we need to compose the variety of
this Boomer characteristics that's the
woman
returns
what we need to do here is that
look at where the we have
for sale
and
we will address
so this is where they are the input of
the output in the upper of the lower
Trail
best value
and after that we looked at some light
tables yet
input and the outputation uh
zero and
lead to
one another particulars
let's look here
the input as output of the cells
and for the input of the lower are
substitution and the output of the lower
shell has
Etc
and it correspond to the ebcc guys so
you can compute the probability of UBC
statistics
model to serve for the chances
[Music]
and
that makes some new variable for the
known variable
variable
and add some new content to new
variables for the function of three
variables and let us I think there are
some the best content for the select the
table to know which table are you in the
computation of the property
how many
people are important language
[Music]
department
is very generous so we want to use model
to
write a yes to apply the ASAP but first
why is
one of the most I'm just gonna hold them
in the world so
block style has the one
it can be used to Magic of four times
to have the four operators
to our routing Supply should go and
follow the steps a lot well there are
three versions of ESP 128 a year 192 and
8. so 100
and
our model is robust we use a app 1992f
an example because you have a look
wasn't
so here is
so
uh
but this password and
the problem here is that statistical in
non-linear and cannot control solution
and between such a loud thing and we
need a new model
so
what we will add into new model
to handle the non-linear Keys as well we
use related feed conditional
and not slightly a small chain on the
distinguisher may lead to a better
attack so we want to really resource the
attack not only possible distinguisher
and
actually you cannot control the this one
on the thing because if we start the
different for most input and output of
an output then it rejects the possible
value and we look at the
and
for our time
so
this one as though
as opposal
so pause the new model we
new variables
to know what's this one is the distance
by the variable if there are variables
belongs to the best variable if it can
be zero and type variable is the
difference is known and S if the reason
is bad to us that type of value
and we are doing some pressing the
profiles monthly and S and
well there are some problems for the
known variable in the case as a plus
like with when we search for the
uh differential characteristics on a yes
many of them are impossible because
the linear relations in the
other system of a person this right yes
so
actually one yeah
so what
who will be
this time when with our solution and we
take it the solution is satisfies the
content or not so we're having some lazy
content to our model
that's done
yeah
and
than just
so how to compose the probability the
property is depends on the Travel
variables for absolute
the upper and the lower terms of input
and outputation
is the best
variable and infected we found in my
possible okay and we need to compose the
social foreign
possible probability
and we work both on includes the
value the probability
five binary variable and 33
and we also add a
function to answer that the probability
is greater than total minus
and
for the objective function we want to
optimize the complexity object but I
have to conclude so we can use an
approximation
so what's them faster to the complexity
here in our opinion if the vectors type
of the Blendtec and the property of the
Mysteries so we will maximize the this
function for the
or the optical function
actually our model is very slow and we
impossible to serve as a better part so
we need to reject the first way by
reject the
number of accidents so
yes statistics
so we found a better attack and
sometimes
and
so we use the same lowercase
that's cause
it's a better friend
help
and that's the reason why the small
chain is the may lead to a better type
finally I will summarize our football a
new advice
to build with non-linear Keys as well
and without a need to effect again 298
1992 it's comparables 3252 I'm lower
than the 10 members of the equipment
over two weeks and we also recovery on
AES 266
and defense
a little more detail
how people are yes
and every
so
puzzle advancements or any questions
[Music]
okay so then oh
can I ask is this possible to apply your
Technique to as128 or other AES based
Cipher
because that was the question so
actually our model is
but for a year 1990 yes so it's it's
very slow and you don't know how to
reset the suspective files
they're not values but they are in order
to improve this model because
okay so let's thanks the speaker and all
the speaker of this session
foreign
[Music]
and you can see
foreign foreign
[Music]
foreign
each other
[Music]
so how do I
okay hello it's time to start uh welcome
to the session
um this is a session for zero knowledge
one
and then we have three talks here
during this session
okay we start with uh should leave zero
knowledge proofs and signatures by ARA
Saloon
thank you for the introduction uh so
this is Joint work
this is Joint work with Joseph Bono and
Jeremy Clark
so imagine you signed something on a
piece of paper with disappearing ink
um whatever you signed would vanish
after some time right you could write a
proof on a paper with disappearing ink
and showed someone that it could vanish
before they show it to someone else so
the goal of our work is to emulate this