in this work we designed two new types
of Primitives called short-lived zero
knowledge proofs and short-lived
signatures
imagine you signed something on a piece
of paper with disappearing ink whatever
you signed would vanish after some time
what's the cryptographic equivalent of
this in other words what does it mean to
make a digital signature vanish
one way to do this is to have the
signature lose its soundness over time
say Alice sign something at time 0
up to time T we want her signature to be
sound but after time T the signature
should no longer be convincing
this gives us a notion of deniability
too that is after time T Alex could
claimed that anyone could have made this
unsound signature without her private
key
so how do we achieve this
we allow signatures to be forged after
some time
that is there's a forger here who can
perform a slow computation that takes
time T and finally produces a forgery
Alice's real signature and this forgery
should be indistinguishable
and anyone should be able to create a
forgery for any key and any message
all of this requires a notion of time we
don't have a global clock but we need to
tell we need some way to tell how fresh
a signature is that is if it was made
within time T upon receiving the
signature or not
and we do this using beacons
we assume all parties in our protocols
have access to a beacon that
periodically emits Randomness here in
this diagram we have a beacon that emits
256 bits of Randomness every Delta time
uh beacons have been constructed using
Randomness from stock prices blockchain
block hashes and from distributed
multi-party protocols like drank
in our paper we described three
applications of our New Primitives for
short-lived signatures we use them in
deniable messaging emails and in in
validating email leaks
short-lived zero knowledge groups can be
used in electronic voting systems to get
an interesting property called receipt
freeness
we construct short Loop proofs and
signatures by transforming generic nizik
and sigma protocols into their
short-lived variations
are proofs in our in our paper we have
four Transformations for proofs and two
more for signatures and they each have
different complexities and properties
our constructions all use verifiable
delay functions as a key tool
a vdf is a function that takes a fixed
number of sequential steps to compute
but once this computation is done it's
easy for other parties to verify that it
was done correctly these are the eval
and verify functions respectively
in our work we formalize the notion of
re-randomizable PDFs and we Define and
construct zero knowledge vdfs uh which
are vdfs where y isn't revealed but the
verifier is given a proof convincing
them that the prover has indeed computed
why or has knowledge of why
these variants of vdfs will give us
interesting properties for our shortly
proofs and signatures
one such property is the notion of
reusable forageability
here forging something with a beacon
value produces an extra advice string
and this advice string can help speed up
further forgeries under that Beacon this
enhances deniability as every Beacon
value now requires just one long
computation that helps produce forgeries
for all other keys and statements for
that Beacon value
when formalizing shortlist proofs we
need a new notion of soundness which we
call T soundness
T soundness stipulates that you should
be able to extract a witness from a
prover that produces proofs in time less
than T since the beacon was submitted
but after time T has passed we lose this
guarantee about witness extraction
and note that the time here starts when
the beacon value is given not when the
input statement or message is designed
we Implement our constructions using
bezelowski vdfs using the rsa2048 group
our constructions are actually quite
practical adding just about half a
kilobyte of size overhead to our Sigma
proof versions
our construction using ZK vdfs notably
has reusable forgeability and induces a
fraction of a second overhead for the
proverb 120 milliseconds here we design
more efficient constructions particular
to signatures and Implement them on RSA
signatures to get similarly low
overheads for poorer time and the size
of the signatures