time for snacks welcome everybody I'm
Hamza abusala this work is done jointly
with geography and Karen Klein
I'll start up by talking about light
client blockchain with striping as a
problem then Define snacks succinct an
interactive arguments of chain knowledge
and then show you how to construct
snacks from proof of sequential work
schemes and then show you how to use
snacks to to solve the problem of
bootstrapping generically
in like client blockchain protocols you
have a full node proof analyze client
Miner and approver stores the entirety
of the blockchain the light client has
minimal information about the chain says
Genesis block the protocol will be
required to satisfy a few properties
that the effort of the verifier is
sublinear the communication is sublinear
and the protocol isn't interactive if it
additionally satisfies the approvers
effort is sublinear and there are no set
of assumptions then that's even better
our protocol achieves all of these
properties
in a bootstrapping protocol the very
fire having the the Genesis block here
b0
after potentially took a reading a bunch
of proofs from different provers its
ultimate goal is to Output a commitment
to the stable prefix of the blockchain
this is powerful if the approva ends up
having the commitment to the same prefix
of the blockchain it can also
become a full node Miner itself but also
it can verify different statements about
transactions in the blockchain so in
this example I'm having two blockchains
Bitcoin and chia Bitcoin a proof of work
blockchain Chia proof of space
blockchain and we have our bootstrapped
verifier then each any approver can do
statements about say the ith block and
in Bitcoin and the jth Block in in Gia
by opening the respective blogs and
providing their respective proofs
so having a commitment to to the
blockchain is is a powerful uh it's a
powerful tool solutions to this problem
exist you have snarks generic Solutions
you have none interactive proofs of
proofs of work you have fly client some
limitations of this work exist either
they have some setup assumptions or
limited applicability apply for proof of
work blockchains but not for proof of
space blockchains for example or limited
usefulness some of them do not even have
the notion of a commitment but more
interestingly a fly client and any Papa
they work in a model where you have
multiple proofers assuming one of them
is honest this is the only case where
the verifier has any guarantees if the
vampire is talking to to a malicious
prover there are no guarantees
whatsoever
in this work we Define a classical proof
system that underlies bootstrapping and
some other light client protocols
we construct snacks from graph labeling
professional work scheme and the web we
unify and generalize these schemes and
provide a new one
and we we show how to use these snacks
to generically solve the problem of
bootstrapping the advantage of our work
is it provides classical soundness
guarantees you have classical soundness
measurable guarantees for the verifier
that reads malicious proof
the work is simple generic and modular
and it allows for exchange of ideas
between the theory of proof of signature
work schemes and unlike client
blockchain applications
in one slide the way we we do our
construction we assume that we have a
blockchain so this is the underlying
graph of a blockchain it has a simple
path but it could have additional edges
in this case these dotted edges
and if you have the graph the underlying
graph of a proof of sequential work
scheme I'm giving an example here for
scheme that I will show in the in the
paper and in the presentation then we
can show how to intertwine the
computation of the proof of the
blockchain and
and the proof of sequential work scheme
by absorbing the blockchain computation
into that of the proof of sequential
work scheme such that we derive
guarantees on the blockchain from the
sequential guarantees on the proof
sequential Works key
this is in in picture like you have two
graphs so you define one one augmented
graph and you show how to label the
graph and utilize the proof of verifier
of the proof of sequential work scheme
to build approver verifier for the the
snack success and interactive argument
of general knowledge if you're
interested in like client applications
like bootstrapping or in proof of
sequential work schemes then hopefully
see you in the full talk thank you