thank you so much for coming here it
means a lot to all of us it was really
really great to be able to make this
happen and be able to see friends and
people that we've been with for years
and uh i just
i'm just it's kind of a bit overwhelming
to have this many of you in this room
um there's too many people i don't know
how many of you are now all of a sudden
claustrophobic
after the past few years i've got that
feeling a little bit a couple of quick
announcements first and foremost
um we already said welcome we're glad
you're here i want to point out this
shirt
um we don't have goons uh at in any of
the way west wild west hack fest
conferences because goons honestly scare
the hell out of me i don't know if
anybody has that vibe uh but if you see
someone wearing this shirt there's
someone that can help you
uh if you have a question you want to
get to the right place if you have
medical assistance that's needed please
look out for somebody wearing one of
these shirts and they can help you out
also
it's ridiculous how many people have
these shirts right now our staff
helped out this conference and get it
set up has just been amazing can i get a
round of applause for everybody that's
been setting all of this up
so and if you see something suspicious
something weird just let us know um
there's no reason to go in and confront
people and turn it into a scene but let
us
talk to the people who can actually
handle that i would appreciate that i'm
also going to talk a little bit about
code of conduct if you go and look on
our website we do have a code of conduct
the first year that we did this my code
of conduct was don't be a jerk
and if you don't know what being a jerk
is if you're coming up to me or like i
want specific details on what qualifies
being a jerk
don't come
um if you're that
confused over what being an is
you shouldn't be here you shouldn't be
around people
all right she said jerk now you're
yeah we're escalating we're
escalating we're escalating um but
here's the deal we can disagree with
each other folks
we don't have to make it a personal
argument we don't have to escalate it to
the point where we hate each other we
can have disagreements
you know about should there be four
layers the stevens model or are there
seven layers in the osi model taste
grace less filling all of that
um also if someone isn't interested take
the
leave them alone
right okay this isn't this isn't okay
it's a freaking pretty com
once again if you're coming to
conferences looking for love you're
probably in the wrong place
um
so please be nice to each other that's
that's all i'm gonna ask i'm also gonna
let you know um if there is a conflict
between people at this conference i'm
going to ask both people to leave
and i'm not doing that because i'm being
an a-hole or just you know
if we have a conflict at the conference
between two individuals i am not going
to try to figure out who's right and
who's wrong i'm going to ask both
politely to leave the conference because
you know of situations where people
might come back and take it out on the
rest of the people at the conference
just going to say let's just de-escalate
we don't need to pick sides on these
types of things a reminder we have yoga
with christine tomorrow from 7 45 to 8
30.
so please check out the schedule for
that and then on friday we're doing a
run i have no idea how far we're going
to run
some will go further than others
some may make it to mexico
not come back and that's okay
if you're making a choice the yoga class
does not leave the site right yoga class
is not it's not that if you're if you're
running that you're doing yoga wrong
like that's not that's not the way it's
supposed to be
if you sign up for one of our workshops
person and you cannot make it
please let us know because there is a
wait list for our workshops we have a
lot of really cool workshops uh going on
um a cancellation uh my my brother from
another mother jonathan ham um is not
feeling well and he made the right
decision somebody applauded
that guy is sick
or they applaud it too soon they're like
i should have heard the rest of that and
he made the smart decision
he didn't feel good
and he is not
to be presenting
i'm gonna say this if you're not feeling
well
be like jonathan
you know don't come downstairs and cough
all over us no we don't we don't need
that so he unfortunately will not be
here if you can send him well wishes on
twitter i'm sure he won't read them uh
because he's he's smart and he stays off
of twitter
um
nathan sweeney will be presenting 2 p.m
to 2 50.
i believe that nathan's taking over
jonathan's slot is that correct
um and he's got this talk which i have
to see
shortcuts through the minds of mariah
how bad could it be
i'm guessing bad
tomorrow night we're going to be doing a
live production bhis talking about the
news um from seven until eight uh so
we'll be
and talking about the news so that
should be a lot of fun and i wanted to
call out our mcs uh we have rey is here
where's bibi
um bibi king is around here somewhere
can't miss him um i've got this write up
of rey i've known ray forever
uh he's been one of the people who was
facilitators he was permanently at the
sands institute he took tons of classes
um he actually i think was
one of the divisions of the sands
institute for a while
he was a dean okay so he was literally
freaking college uh
and
my one of my favorites that i've ever
keep the audio
air every time i touch it
on your left
so
i'm gonna hold this up
we're gonna keep this going um
we were playing around a while ago
and we were talking about the dmca we
were talking about music and how they if
you're sharing music
you could get like the record companies
to come after you we devised a scheme so
what ray did is he burnt all of his
music onto a hard drive for me and he
gave it to me as his backup service
and periodically i had to validate the
backups and we thought that that would
be a good way of getting around um
the riaa and everything that they were
doing with music so uh but ray is one of
the legitimate completely legitimate we
were hoping we would get sued i don't if
you self report on youtube there are no
penalties if you sell report on youtube
so hi youtube welcome this conference
has nothing to do with hacking
um so he's going to be the emcee of one
of the tracks and then bb king is going
to be the emcee of one of the other
tracks i don't think he's here right now
but bibi is one of the uh one of the
earliest and one of the earliest pen
testers at bhis
and he's just an absolute great friend
um both these guys are just great so
please you know hang out and get a
chance to talk to them and get them a
beer now tonight we've got doc is
presenting
and one of the things i really like
about doc is he actually is in the field
doing this stuff so he's got some great
war stories
about all kinds of horrible things so
security isn't what you do i'm going to
be a little bit curious on what that is
he said he wrote it just for this
presentation for this presentation
tonight and then he winked at me i don't
know what that means
i'll find out um following that we have
a panel discussion um a whole bunch of
people are going to be up here talking
about computer security and then to
close it out uh where's john bevers
um john bevers the man behind the
curtain he's been working really hard as
part of our capture the flag we've
developed augmented reality and john is
the mastermind behind that if you saw
the battleships in the next room that
are all cardboard cut out not cardboard
they're actually cut out and plywood um
we've been working with some augmented
reality stuff
so please please please uh check that
out so with that once again i want to
say thank you so much for being here and
getting this close to each other which
is a little bit unnerving i don't have
time to go through and say thanks to
absolutely everybody that made this
happen i'll try to come up with a list
later it's like the oscars i've gone too
long and i need to be shut up so with
that everyone can you please give a warm
round of applause for doc
who's kicking it off officially there
you go
thank you
let me grab my
that was totally unnecessary and it just
i feel like it raised the bar right
there for me so please know
if you clap when i go do my job
i'm just gonna have to go to your office
and clap when you do your job right
you like that don't you yeah
all right i'm gonna try something here
and see if i can actually make this
microphone work
hi everybody how's everybody doing today
in san diego woohoo wow
really excited about that i really am i
mean just with covent not that i just to
get out of my office basement which is
just you know the basement of my home
that i put a computer in it it with a
table and now it's an office right you
all know what i'm talking about we've
all been doing that my my office now so
i'm doc blackburn um as as john said
i've been i've been doing i've done a
lot of different things over a lot of
different years
and so when somebody asked me what i do
for a living i actually i
i don't know i talk i talk for a living
which isn't a bad job to have
but
i am going to say some things here
just to kick off this conference
here in san diego here we are all
in person again
we're all excited to get back to doing
you know our jobs
in person security
and i am going to start this conference
by telling you at a security conference
that security
is not your job
it's not what you do folks
i'm sorry
and i'm going to spend most of this hour
together well it's supposed to be an
hour and then and then zelda tells me
it's 50 minutes it's like well
last year i had an hour and i only took
45. you know how you know how budgets
are if you don't use the whole budget
they take it away from you and so now
they're like oh well you can do it in
50. well
you're killing me here you're killing me
velda but we're going to have a very
very uncomfortable conversation here
and the conversation
is going to be around
one question
and one question only
are we secure
so let's start with a thought exercise
on that
when i give presentations
in case any of you have attended my
presentations before
you know that if you sit in the front
row
you're going to get wet you're going to
get picked on all
right thank you so much for sitting in
the front row here folks
we're going to do some a thought
exercise for you
let's say so we made eye contact so i'm
going to
did yep
you did it you did it i'm so you didn't
mean to maybe but
let's say
i i'm your boss you've been working for
me for a while okay and i come up to you
one day and say hey what's your name
patricia
so
are we secure
no okay you're fired that was easy good
yeah
she's being honest
i just fired patricia what's your name
daniel daniel daniel are we secure of
course yes okay all right
well he learned because he talked to
patricia she's walking out the door it's
like yes we are secure
now
i i as the boss i got the answer i was
looking for right obviously because when
patricia said no
i fired her
so now
and i forgot your name already
daniel
daniel said yes we are secure now what
did i as the boss hear not
not what did daniel say
but what did i hear as the boss
that where what so go ahead you're safe
we're safe which means no
no hacks no breach right
daniel i remembered your name this time
two times the charm
is that what you meant to tell me can
you tell me
can you tell me that we'll never be
breached
no of course no of course not
then why did you say that we're secure
so now what happens what's that
that's what that's what the boss wants
to hear but then what happens
is daniel
is the first one out the door he gets
unceremoniously fired
when we get breached
and then i hi uh who with the
diamondbacks hat all right diamondbacks
fan i love that the d-backs
your name all right craig
that'll be easy to remember that's one
of my brother's names all right so craig
daniel just got fired and now i ask you
i hire you and i ask you are we secure
he's got a deer in the headlights look
camera on him here you should see his
face here it's like wow
are we secure
i don't know i don't know who that's a
great answer
no you just you're not you're just
parroting what patricia said you want to
get fired don't you yeah
yes is the wrong answer
because we can't guarantee it right
no
is the wrong answer because the boss
doesn't want to hear that
and you
you call yourself security
now when i say that some of you right
now you're thinking well you don't
understand though there's so much more
to it just saying it's like but there's
but
yeah i know some of you are feeling that
way right now it's uncomfortable right
well some others of you
are probably like preach it brother
you are giving us the word this is the
word this is what i'm talking about well
just wait folks those that
yeah
you don't know what the answer is do you
if any of you know it blurt it out
please because i haven't figured it out
yet all right
not yet
now
i'm sure some of you say well wait a
minute doc
so you're either in one camp or you're
in the other or all of you others are
like wow doc blackburn's already blown
through three memes on the first slide
of its presentation
it's like yeah
you know why not
pictures are easy to find on the
internet use google right and my brother
the reason that i put this picture up
is my brother the other day and all the
stories i'm gonna tell are true
my brother i had a conversation with him
about a month ago and he said he said
you know you're like sheldon cooper
and i asked him i said
what's a sheldon cooper and apparently
apparently my asking that question made
me more of a sheldon cooper
i don't know
i just found pictures i saw some lady
yelling and some other person with hands
in the air you know and oh by the way
since we're dealing with all of these
memes i know
today is a special special day right
it's the it's the anniversary of
battlestar galactica right
and so all i'm going to say is
yeah okay
all right let's go let's back to the
question here so are we secure we know
that no isn't the right answer yes isn't
the right answer
and so we deflect we
let's say let's say
you pull
an answer out of your butt
that gets you out of the boss's office
and now you're back in the hallway
slowly
glad i
got through that
well now here's the thing you're no
longer relevant in your organization
if you aren't going to be able to answer
this question to the boss so
my question to you is
is it
really the right question to ask
can any of you say
that you will never be sick again in
your life can anybody say that we take
vitamins apparently we're doing yoga
tomorrow which sounds like a lot of fun
we're going to do some running
we take care of our bodies
but nobody here can say you will never
ever again be sick can anybody say that
just checking just making sure everybody
you say you'll never be sick again yeah
liar
no
no we can't say that right one out of
what 200 or 150 and we can't be wrong
right
so
what's the problem that we're dealing
with here
the problem is
is when the boss asked you the question
it was their expectation
as to what the answer would be it was a
matter of breach or no breach
and that's the metric right
yes i'm seeing some faces they're like
it is
the boss thinks that this is the metric
for you doing your job right
now
what that does is it puts us in a very
uncomfortable position
because
we
are based on this metric
we are being paid
so nothing bad happens to the
organization doesn't that feel like a
mob boss sort of proposal right there
it'd be a shame if something happened to
your stuff
they're paying us so nothing bad happens
to our organization is that the right
way
to have our jobs be viewed
because that's how the boss sees us
right now unless we change the
expectation now some of you may say well
blah blah blah you know we do the we do
what the company across the street is
doing
right you ever you ever run across a new
problem
and you ask i have literally been in a
position where i've had a boss ask me
as i was working for a research hospital
we had of affiliate hospitals
and my boss who was
had the title of director of security
said
well what are they doing across the
street what's children's hospital doing
as if children's hospital had any idea
what the they were doing
sorry
right
come on
now now we're preaching it
yeah we're gonna do what they're doing
as if they had some sort of a plan in
place
somebody over there was like i don't
know
put a firewall in front of it right the
firewalls are magic they make us secure
so
let's take things a step further now
security
is getting in the way
of the business
the business does not exist
to secure it
i don't care whether or not you have
security in your job title
the business doesn't exist for us to
secure it
the network
doesn't exist for us to make sure nobody
ever gets in i actually i have i have a
friend who
one day he he um uh he calls me up he's
like hey he knew knew what he did for a
living
and he said hey so doc you know you're
students you teach them all the stuff
and what we want what i've got here is i
created this network
and it just has
for fun and and i want to see
if somebody could break into it do you
want you want to give that
network address to your students and see
if they can break in
and i said sure
and i asked them
what does the network do
what do you mean
i said what does the network do what did
you make it for
he said well no i just was putting it
together it just it does nothing i said
congratulations you made something that
doesn't exist it's not real
because all of our networks are designed
to do some sort of a job and when we put
security in place
that causes that network to no longer do
the thing that it's supposed to do
we're wrong right all of a sudden we're
wrong
for
not allowing them to do this thing now
this particular picture i know it's a
very it's a very thought-provoking
picture right a friend of mine was
skiing in chile and
and he took a picture of that and he
sent it to me he's like doc that i think
that sums up he's a security guy as well
so that sums up our our job right there
i said yeah pretty much that's that's it
totally now it the problem is even worse
than that
because
we
they want us to secure the network
but we don't get to spend all of the
money to secure the network right
right because every dollar
you spend
on security reduces the value of that
asset by one dollar is my microphone
cutting in oh it sounds like it is yeah
stay away from metal stay away from mel
stay away from metal i i feel like uh
howard
howard and better call saul or oh chuck
chuck that's it's chocolate
everything everything else
all right
it's working it's working now maybe
maybe
they're just penning me in maybe i just
have to stay here but they can't go too
far back they said i get feedback if i
go back here
which is hilarious which means i don't
get to see my own slides you know i'm
flying blind over here i i when when you
see the slide i see it too
for the first time
now
my
mommy
remember all these stories are true my
mommy gives me a crisp 100 bill
every year for christmas yeah it's nice
i got my 100 dollar bill awesome
some years i spend it on
material things one year i bought a base
used and i actually i was flying from
denver to chicago
and i'm holding that base in its case
and walking down the the road in um um
on the plane
and this guy with this purple hair goes
oh you can just throw yours on top of
mine there
look i see this guitar case up there i
was like okay nice i throw it up there
and and uh
figure well if i put my bass guitar on
top of his guitar i'm also sitting the
same row with him yeah i don't know i
don't know if that's the etiquette if
that's you know
if i'm allowed to do that but i sat next
to him
and we're silent for a few seconds i
said
i bet you're somebody and he smiled and
he said yeah i'm jim pedreck the
founding member of survivor was like
yeah the guy that wrote the eye of the
tiger in all of 30 special songs i know
for anybody here who's not taking heart
medication or or other sorts of vitamins
for your daily health you don't have any
idea the things that i just said
he was important at one point he signed
my base when he got to chicago midway he
signed my base for me so it made it
special that was a special 100
but this last christmas
i decided you know what i want to
the crisp 100 bill that my mommy gives
me
has special meaning too
because my mom gave it to me
so i decided i'm going to protect this
i'm not going to spend it it's an
heirloom i'm going to keep that
so
i need a special place to keep it
i go down to target yeah i know they got
breached i still shop there i go down to
target and
what was nice is he started seeing those
people in your class
you the the what i like seeing
is breach happens i don't like seeing
breach happened all right i mean i do
it's called job security but i i don't
like seeing breaches happen but when the
breach happens what i do like to see is
students showing up in my classroom uh
for those companies like at least at
least they're turning things around at
least they're starting to do the right
things now
but i go to target and i look on the
shelf it's like hmm there's there's this
safe a fireproof safe and that's a small
one it's like that's perfect i could put
my 100 bill in this safe and and some
other things as well some important
papers and so i said this is perfect i
take it to the register put it on the
belt the cashier rings it up and says
100 please i said yes and i give
them
oh
the 100
that i was going to protect in the safe
folks we don't get to spend all of the
money protecting the assets because the
asset would be worth zero at that point
i can't spend one hundred dollars
protecting one hundred dollars
because
then it's worth nothing
it's worth nothing at all
so we don't get to spend all of the
money
also speaking of money
insecurity
we're seen
as a cost center
what does that mean we're seen as a cost
center it's going back to a few slides
here we pay the money so i mean
we pay security money so nothing bad
happens to our stuff
and even worse than that
we also get labeled as the department of
no
whatever you do do not ask security
because they'll tell you no right
so what do they do they take the manager
takes their purchasing card and just
here just just buy it just buy it
don't tell security about
which is about the worst possible
condition we could be in
at that research institute that was
working for we had a we had a new
researcher come in um
i'll leave names out of this but let's
just say this particular principal
investigator we poached them from johns
hopkins university it's like yes you've
got a big gun here millions of dollars
of funding
and i at the time i was supporting uh
that area of the the research
institution and and she comes to me one
day she says so doc you're you're you're
the person that helps me with my i.t
stuff right and i said yeah sure what do
you need and she said here let me show
you and we go to her office to her her
wet lab and for those that know and
research a wet lab that's a heck of a
lot more important than dry lab the
difference between the two is a wet lab
is a lab that has a sink yes
that's what the researchers want is a
lab with a sink and yes that's as an
actual thing and she had a bunch of it
it was actually her wet lab area was
about the size of this room
and when it comes to research dollars
that's huge
and she took me over to one of the
cabinets and she opens it up and there's
servers and blinking lights and cables
and switches and and all sorts of stuff
and she's like i need to
and i didn't let her finish her
statement i i closed it
and i said
i was never here
and i walked right out the door
that's shadow i.t right where they bring
in the i.t yet if something was to
happen to that
the university would be in trouble
it wouldn't be so and so researcher you
know had stuff in a cabinet that they
didn't tell anybody about this stuff and
so you know that's not the headline it
was the university had a breach
and so here we are dealing with this
this uh these things that we don't even
know about
because either it's allowed it's like
why was that allowed she brought
millions of dollars of research funding
in so of course it was allowed
she was making the business better
remember we support the business
so those are the types of things that
we're dealing with everybody to get in
the picture here we we've got a problem
keith palmgren
summed it up best
when he said that when security gets in
the way of the mission security is wrong
not the mission
we cannot do anything
that gets in the way of what we're doing
in our
the business
in their job now
keith being a good friend of mine he he
he also let me know that he said once
he said now doc i'm not saying
that i'm batman
he says but you've never seen both of us
in the same room have you
and so of course then i screenshotted
him and i put him in a batman costume
hearings and now his son apparently his
adult son is a huge man a batman fan and
so uh
this is apparently uh his adult son's uh
uh wallpaper on his cell phone now i was
like that's kind of cool but the point
is
that we cannot do things that don't
support the mission we cannot do things
that get in the way of the mission we're
wrong in those cases
so
let's circle back to the original
question of are we secure
now we got hired to do a job we got
hired so the organization wouldn't
become breached right
and now we know
we've discussed this we have lots of
reasons why
we cannot be secure we know that which
means that eventually
you will get pwned you're gonna get
breached it's just a matter of time
we don't get to spend all the money
we don't get to
take this network offline
it's easy to secure systems right um you
just
turn them off and bury them in concrete
it was a um
they say you know if you bury the
computer and concrete in the lead case
thing and is off and all of that it's
probably secure but even then we're not
so sure yeah but then it's unusable
and so we don't get to do that so
eventually you're going to get breached
it's going to happen
does anybody want to argue that point
with me at this
point everybody good
yeah i've i've beat you into submission
that well excellent
nice
yeah which means
eventually we get breached
now
let's say it doesn't happen this year
congratulations
you did your job you we didn't get
breached right does that mean we did our
job this year
this means our number wasn't up at that
time right
so
what happens when we don't get breached
everything's good we we get raises we
get bonuses
oh no we must have spent too much money
on security which is just it is a
neurotic a neurotic way of looking at
things
we paid you
to make sure that we don't get breached
so when we don't get breached i must
have paid you too much money to do that
so they cut our budget right
because we're known as a cost center oh
well here's a place that we can cut
money
because security is excessive
until it's not
so let's cut their budget
and then let's say congratulations you
just went through another year and you
didn't get breached
what do they do to cut your budget again
and then another year until finally bam
now we're breached all right
and then they unceremoniously fire our
butts
and then the
the cruelest cruelest joke of them all
is they hire new people
to come in to do the same job that we
were doing and what do they do with
those new people they give them money
they give them resources they give them
anything that they need we see it all of
the time we were talking about target a
little bit ago yeah target is a prime
exam now i am not picking on target
specifically just insert company name
here
but a company gets free she's like oh
well we should do better and so they
hire people they bring in resources they
do lots of different things and guess
what
don't feel too bad for yourself when
that happens
because guess what's going to happen to
the new shiny face people that come in
is the same thing's going to happen to
them
it's just going to repeat that cycle
over and over again
now
i need to introduce
um
a fictional character
this fictional character is evil doc oh
he's scared
i'm sorry i put this picture up i didn't
give anybody trigger warnings or
anything so let's censor that there we
go
now
evil doctor is a fictional character
because there's law enforcement law
enforcement in the room all right so i'm
evil doc you know does lots of things
he's a fictional character good doc me
i wouldn't admit to any of those things
but let's talk about
good versus evil
here
now
what is the job of good
we we come in to work 9 a.m monday
morning we spend eight hours do having
meetings writing reports you know
checking on the logs the firewall rules
well whatever whatever your job is fill
in the blank there
and so you're going about your day
and then you go home
you get you get sick you have to go home
you take vacations
at 5 00 pm you call a day we have to
sleep at some point
does evil ever sleep
does evil stop well some evil might so
like yeah well
some evil will sleep and then other evil
takes
takes over in their place yeah then some
we have to protect our networks 24 7.
but it's worse than that
i took
a posting
from the uh job site monster.com
and i just i i edited it for brevity for
brevity it's the one on the left by the
way i edited it for brevity
and i put it on the slide and this is
only a little
of what that job posting said for
security administrator
do you see a disconnect
between what we have to do
and what they do
they just they they're going to pull in
our systems and and monetize it right
then they're done
that's it it's not a fair fight in fact
i like to call security our jobs
i like to call it the hockey model
because who's who's my hockey fans here
the nhl stanley cup playoffs just
started what's your team
avalanche go abs absolutely i'm from
denver so there we go that's real
canadian canadians are they even in it
no okay
the caps what's that
lightning woo
kraken wild yeah awesome
i'm not a hockey fan at all sorry folks
i i could barely name five nhl players
and that's the truth why did i br i just
set you guys up didn't i
why did i mention hockey oh here's the
thing my son
my son plays hockey
i'm a fan of my son so therefore
i watch hockey right
now when my son was small
he was he was actually he was a very
good player a very strong skater
and i noticed something about what the
coaches would do with the kids that were
strong skaters when they were small
where would they put the strong skaters
they put them on offense
for those who
now i got some i from the corners of the
room i got some people who were hockey
fans the rest of you you know how the
game hockey's played right it's that
game on the ice and the fishbowl thing
and they they skate around and all that
with that so there's sticks and that
puck thingy and now i've just exhausted
all the information i know about hockey
right there
now they put the best skaters in offense
why
because those offensive players as
strong skaters they could skate past the
defender
they only need to be slightly faster
than the defender and they win
the whole idea is they get by that
defense so they can take a shot on net
without the defender there right i know
in baseball it's totally this is just
weird stuff think soccer you know think
soccer yeah it's kind of like that all
right
now
and yes this this actually the the boy
in orange and white there with the puck
you can see that low puck thingy uh is
uh
he's a strong skater
these kids are i believe they're nine
and ten years old in this picture and he
was a strong skater and so he would
skate past the defender you could see
his
the his stick and the puck is just
inches
beyond the defensive player but he's won
already
because he gets to take the shot now
but i had noticed i had noticed
something as he got older as he grew up
got bigger stronger their level of play
became more sophisticated
the coaches did something different
they took those best skaters
and they took them off of offense and
where did they put them
they put them on
there's only three different positions
in hockey right come on just start
thinking through it here they put him on
defense
why
because in the game of hockey
the defenseman
and now you see that these two in the uh
toward the top of the slide here they're
the defending players
they are
anticipating
what the offense does
they mirror
the offensive players actions
and they redirect that offensive player
away from what the offensive player is
trying to do
okay what's the point
they're doing all of that while
skating backwards
it's hard to see in this picture but
those two uh now this is high school
hockey right here these kids are about
uh 16 17 years old 17 18 here um though
you can't see the action but those those
two players are actually skating
backwards while
mirroring everybody else who's skating
forwards
now
tv and movies
have lied to you folks
yeah i know what
yes they've lied to you
because do you know what tv and movies
have told you for generations
who's in the net
the fat kid that can't skate right
they lied to you do you know who the
best skater is in the team
the goalie themselves does this kid look
fat does he look slow they're the best
skaters out there now this has nothing
to do with the presentation at this
point i'm just bragging about my son
that's my son in net there
12 months ago why thank you thank you
12 months ago this time i was in st
louis watching him
defend
against the this was in the national
championships and he was in that
well thank you
and not not that i'm proud of him or
anything right you've got more pictures
and stuff it was really neat to see him
play for a national championship but now
going back to that skating uh i know for
a fact
that along with the coaches on the team
along with the goalie coaches they have
for the organization
these players these goalies have their
own private skating coaches i know i
write the checks for that
yeah they're the best skaters out there
they're the ultimate defender and he
actually has three other coaches on top
of that a private coach for positioning
a private coach for the psychology of
the game of private coach for game
situations that's just the stuff that
they go through but the reason that i
mention this at all
is
insecurity
that's us we're skating backwards folks
we're the defense skating backwards
now
how are we skating backwards so far
we've discussed many of these things
does anybody have
i got a question for you
does anybody here have unlimited time
and resources to fix everything
in security anybody have unlimited time
and resources
darn i always wish that somebody would
raise their hand because i want a job
application from you yeah it doesn't
exist right
we're constrained by time and money
also
we
have to
within hockey the offense
the offense only needs to find one way
one way to get past the defense right
what must the defense do to be
successful
in stopping the attacker
they have to
they have to find and fix all of the
ways right
yeah they have to be right every single
time
and do the right things
now
does an attacker
need to follow
your organization's policies in
attacking you
no they don't need to do that
do can we
can we break policy can you break
company policy defending your network
no that's not allowed
does the attacker
need to follow your compliance
regulations
i don't know
a single business today i just cannot
name one that doesn't have some sort of
compliance regulation that they have to
follow right does the attacker have to
follow that
no
does the attacker even need to follow
the law in attacking you oh that's silly
they've already broken the law they're
trying to break into our systems can we
break the law in defending our networks
no
you guys get the idea here right and
there's just some things that just don't
even have solutions
people make bad passwords people make
bad decisions there's shadow i.t and you
know there's nothing puts the sh in it
like shadow i.t does right and there's
there's
ways around you all are congratulations
going to be here learning for most of
the classes most of the tracks you guys
are doing here you're going to be
learning how to get around all of the
defenses right
so
we
cannot
we cannot
secure our systems
and i know that makes many of you angry
go go back to our original thoughts now
and start putting all of this together
so
what
are we actually doing
if security is not our job
what do we do
and this is the interactive part just go
ahead and blurt it out just say it
we reduce risk okay yeah the the boss
here's blah blah blah
we need more money for something right
we reduce or yes we reduce risk what's
that
process it's a pr a process you intrigue
me
what process is this
it's a closed loop kind of process so
you just
yeah i had a slide for that yeah
we learn about attacks and learn ways to
prevent them and if if you were my
employee and i was your boss i fell
asleep halfway through that sentence but
that's that's a halfway decent answer go
ahead
keep the company off the dark web
what exactly is the dark web wow
what's that
where they sell information cool oh i've
got some money let's remember i've got
that 100 let's go get some info
um
these aren't wrong answers they're not
bad answers
we defend
okay great i i like i like that answer
too
we're here to check a box i love that
one
what's your name
carlos everybody give carlos a hand
there we're here to check a box
speaking of box checking carlos tony
sager is right behind you of cis
the ultimate chat box checker right
i i'm sorry i'm sorry you know that i
he's a rock star of mine by the way and
so then and the way that i show
affection towards somebody is to pick on
them so um now i
no those are all noble answers
what i'm gonna do is take all of those
answers that you guys gave
i'm gonna smush them together and make
it sound smart okay
we're managing our levels of insecurity
that's that is what we're doing isn't it
that covers all of those answers
what does that mean
well
for one
our boss doesn't understand our job
is your job title insecurity manager
it should be right
it's a
security is in our job title go ahead i
said that builds that bill that builds
confidence doesn't it i am an insecurity
manager
but it is what we do
right
let's talk about this for a second what
does that mean
well
first
we need to
acknowledge that security
just isn't our job
and i think we're all there right now
right
but what we need to do
is acknowledge that i mean internalize
it
you're managing your organization's
insecurities
but security is in your job title
we need to change the way
the organization sees our jobs
so let's talk about these just a little
bit here
first
we have to take away the expectation
that our role in the organization is an
expense
i can stand in front of a room full of
executives just like this
and i can talk about security without
even saying the word security
and i can get them all riled up they're
like yeah that's the stuff
by saying
simply
what we're going to do here is we are
going to build repeatable processes that
yield dependable results yeah
well isn't that security
isn't that security
if you can build
repeatable processes
and the outcome is dependable
that to me is the definition of security
but
it's an important reframing
of the conversation
because what have i just done
i've aligned myself with the business
i've aligned myself as a strategic
partner
in the business
by reframing what our job is
we can also do a better job
of
defining with our organization how
we
spend money
to protect money
i am going to spend a little bit of
money
to save a lot more money
i know i know that all of you in this
room know this
i'm going to ask you the question
what have you done
what have you done in your business
to explain that to them
are you giving them the right reports
on what the activities are that you're
actually doing
because the businesses if you're not
communicating that to them they're just
seeing it as oh i don't know we pay the
magic wizard behind the curtain money
and the the magic wizard pulls the
levers
what lovers did they pull
does anybody here have
a safe place on the internet where you
don't get attacked anybody have a
visible ip address out on the internet
that doesn't ever get attacked
are we
communicating to leadership
how often we do get attacked
are we telling them how often it happens
how many punches we're blocking
my son as a goalie
he's got a stat
for the goalies i was like yes there's
there's goals against
okay
but what other metric are goalies
measured against not just how many goals
they let in
but how many they stopped
are you
communicating to the right people
in your organization in the right way
to tell them how many shots you've
stopped
are you actually doing that
because guess what the boss thinks
is going on when you don't give them
those that information
they think it's a big fat goose egg
right i think it is oh well we got we
got pwned three times yeah we were
attacked thousands of times
well
we need to show them that value we're
not doing that we're not showing them
somebody had mentioned decreasing
liability early on and yes absolutely
that was one of the punch lines i had
thank you the checks in the mail whoever
had said that i forgot who it was yeah
now
one of the ways that we can do this is
randy martini of virginia tech he says
he's he's been a cisso or whatever his
job he's got multiple
roles
he's been a ciso for a large
organization for longer than most people
have held a job
and he was asked one day i was there
when he was asked this like randy
how
when all of these other cisos are being
fired after breaches when uh all of
these people are let go you know even
the target says the cso for target they
got canned after the that breach
randy was asked
how do you
continue to do this and stay in your job
and he said simply
never waste a breach
what does that mean never waste a breach
well there's a few different ways of
looking at this for one
if your
organization
gets compromised microphone went out
again i was doing all the right things
they had me trained and all of a sudden
i lost it
when your organization gets compromised
there's hard questions
that are going to be asked of you and
what are these answers to these
questions well that's too late
one of the things that i did at that
research university i'm going to go back
to them
for this particular example
is this research since they were dealing
with uh hipaa data hipaa the health
information uh health uh uh insurance
portability and accountability act blah
blah
and so every single time because i knew
that the associate vice chancellor in
charge of they were our hipaa security
officer i knew that they were
checking for all of the hipaa breaches
you know that every single time one came
in ocr fined somebody because he wanted
to stay out of jail you know you know
you could go to jail by not following
hipaa heat he decided he didn't want to
go to jail that was just that thing
about him you know and so he would watch
those reports
so what would i do
every single one of those reports
when they came in
i would read that report i would look at
what the findings were in that
corrective action plan these are the
things that a corrective action plan in
this particular case is this is the
you're supposed to be doing that you
didn't do and therefore we're going to
find you and so i would look at that and
i would ask if
ocr i'm sorry office for civil rights
yes hipaa data is a civil rights privacy
issue i would ask
as us an organization like us
if ocr came in and didn't audit how
would we do and so by the time he opened
up that report
he knew what the answer would be for us
that's an example of never wasting a
breach whatever your industry is i just
gave you an example for hipaa but
whether it's let's say you're a large
retail organization target gets pwns
what did you guys say anything about
that other than oh sucks to be target
did you actually inform your
organization well you know if that
happened to us
that we'd be okay in these areas but you
know we could we need help over here
are you doing those things
and that's all about you know we reduce
the threat we reduce the vulnerability
blah blah blah i really don't have much
to say about that slide what i want to
do is i want to
get to
the crux of the problem
i have just spent 50 minutes
framing a problem
and i am not going to give you an answer
for it i'm sorry
but i do have a solution
don't start plotting yet
i do have
a solution first an acknowledgement
what is the risk appetite of the
organization do you understand your
organization's risk appetite is it
actually written down is it codified in
policy or is it just the boss thinks
that we're always going to be secure
that's a good place to start great
because there's bruce schneier i'm sure
most of you know who he is he he says
there's no point in just thinking that
this this wave of selflessness is going
to happen one day where everybody agrees
on what risk is you need to know
who the
people in leadership positions in your
organization what they think of risk
and
you must answer to that
also
we need to start speaking in their
language
now
here is the solution
that isn't going to fix the problem
today because
the problem is not fixable by us that's
the whole reason why i did not
give you guys a solution
this is unsolvable
by the people in this room
leadership
needs to do something
they don't know that they need to do
something
if leadership needs to do something and
they don't know it
whose fault is that
it's it's not leadership's fault
it's ours because guess what
when you get compromised i don't know
who it says i'm gonna address that side
of the room
when you get compromised are they gonna
say my bad and fire themselves
no
it's our problem it's our problem to
solve
so
what do we do
first this is the first step
congratulations for
being here
for this last 53 minutes here
a few minutes i'm gonna stop talking you
know i'm the quiet one in my family yeah
i really am this is my outlet i actually
get to talk uninterrupted you know you
guys have kids you know right you know
we have to change the way
that we view our jobs
that's step number one
when we change how we view our jobs
when we stop calling ourselves security
and we start acknowledging
that security isn't our job
we can start changing our minds about
how we see our job and then
when you make that change in how you
think about your job
you change
the way you talk about your job
and then when you change the way you
talk about your job
you will start to this is not something
that we flip a switch and now we're good
we're going to change how others
perceive our jobs
remember it starts with us
we change how we think about our job
which then will change our language
and then the business starts seeing us
as a strategic partner
where we are supporting
what it is that we're actually doing in
the business and then only then
can we be invited to that table
and actually have a say
in how our organization is protected
and most importantly
changing the perceptions of leadership
that security isn't what we do
we're managing our levels of insecurity
but it all starts with us it's up to us
to change this
leadership isn't going like bruce
schneier said it just isn't going to
happen
we have to change that all right
now i'm hoping i'm hoping because i've
over the last
few years i've gotten to this point
and it's how i've done my job going
forward i got tell you it's a wonderful
place to be i sleep well at night
when i
reframed how i see my job
i hope
that this starts the first step on the
journey for many of you
and as an
that we can change
our organization's security for the
better
so thank you for your time folks i hope
you have a wonderful conference and in
just a moment here we're going to have i
was the warm-up act for hal pomerantz
and his motley crew all right so thank
you so much i appreciate your time