hello everyone hello
welcome to california um i love this
idea that now that you're in california
and you've been here for a little bit
you are obligated to both do yoga and
eat avocado toast i don't know nobody
did yoga it sound like avocado toast to
anyone maybe look at that a ton of hands
went up that's fantastic yeah okay
that's good yeah perfect
it is cool
and strange to be back in person doing
these sorts of things i don't know if
anybody else is kind of feeling that way
and it's it's weird seeing you all again
because you know i know a handful of you
but i almost don't recognize people
without their zoom backgrounds that's
been very strange also i don't know how
many of you have been playing the game
but
taller or shorter than you thought they
were has anybody been playing that
i usually get the yeah i'm shorter than
i thought it was yeah that's usually
mine that's which is fair um so hello to
all of you in person hello to you on the
stream everyone that's watching live
sorry you can't be here but again it's
great that we have both options for
folks who can't make it here in person
for all sorts of reasons so i'm glad we
get to do all that
big thanks to the wild west hack and
fest team for having me here today and
for setting all this up and everything
this is and i don't know if all of you
share this opinion but this is one of my
favorite conferences bar none i find
that this audience and the speakers that
come to these
and just how accessible everything is in
wild west hackfest so hopefully you all
feel that way as well but i always
recommend for folks who are especially
starting out wild was hack invest is
great so tell people who don't know
about this place about this place
um
cool let's go ahead and get started
um today
we're presenting on what is attack
coverage anyway the breadth and depth
analysis with atomic red team that'd be
fun so
you all heard the spiel about me i'm
adam meshinshi i'm the director of open
source programs at red canary so you can
think of me as kind of the head of
product over all the open source stuff
which is very fun
my background is in privacy encryption
adversary simulation emulation you can
have fisticuffs over those two words and
what they mean together later it'd be
fun um
but
my soul is a product manager under the
hood i i do have a technical background
i know enough code to be dangerous i
write a little i'm not good at it but
it's fine gets the job done um but
really
with all my love of purple teaming and
the kind of stuff that i want to promote
open source in particular go wild west
hacking fest tool shed which is very
neat you shall check that out as well if
you weren't planning on it
my big goal is to be an enabler right i
want to enable people to do whatever
they should be doing for example if
there's an open source program or
project that has a maintainers team and
they want to just be maintainers and not
have to worry about all the crazy stuff
or come to conferences and talk about
their project and they just want to do
maintainery things great i want to
enable them to do that if there are
contributors to an open source program
and they want to come do this sort of
stuff i want to enable them to do that
those are all the things that have
wrapped up in my role
um okay
so let's get started
apologies in advance we are talking
about mitre attack it's in the title you
all knew it was coming but obligatory
slide yes you're going to be hearing
about miter attack probably a billion
times in the next few days um so if this
is the first time you're hearing about
it cool we're going to have some
explanation about that um
and it's only a matter of time as you
all know till every vendor on the planet
is talking about mitre attack to you if
you haven't heard that already and then
you know the clock is ticking down for
when your family brings it up at
thanksgiving and that should be
interesting too
so yes we're talking about mitre attack
today sorry in advance but it's gonna be
good
this talk is kind of an interesting one
for some of you who run the conference
scene this might sound a little familiar
um this is actually the the end of a
trilogy of talks that all kind of had
the similar title
the first one we did was a one about
coverage this project when it was just
getting kicked off but it was really
about a way to structure
internships in cyber security for folks
who are looking to spin up those kind of
programs it was done under the lens of
this project and that was a lot of fun
to be able to create a talk like that it
was called a two topic talk it was very
tricky to create and have those threads
interleaved but it was fun and again
thanks to all of us hack and fest for
letting me experiment and to talk in
that way
we then give a 15 minute update to this
project at attack con my colleague brian
donahue gave that talk brian lives very
close to attack khan and i live very far
away from attack khan so we just kind of
obligated him he did a great job thanks
to brian for doing that
um and today
we're going to wrap up the trilogy
kind of so it'll be fun
some definitions before we move too far
for those of you who do not know what
atomic red team is
um atomic red team is this open source
library of
threat
examples
that are aligned to mitre attack
technique ids that's what it is
and one of the common misconceptions
about atomic red team is that it's
software it is not software it's a
library of examples i'm going to
mention this a few times but
just keep that in mind as we talk about
things it's a library of examples that
are aligned to miter attack
um
now mitre attack that thing is a matrix
of
adversary ethics and techniques and
procedures
and it's a knowledge base of those
things that have specific ids so for
example
system time discovery is
t 11 24 something like that and
everything is aligned in that way
so for those of you who don't know what
mitre attack is this is just the tldr on
that
a friend of mine jeff mcjunkin also
calls mitre attack a game of minesweeper
for adversaries which is an analogy that
i love you know in this grid of
adversarial things that a
offensive individual could do
these are the kinds of minds that a
given adversary might trip over as they
try out different ttps if you will
and so they're also the idea that
as a blue team as a defender you can
design tripwires around certain
adversary behaviors that you want to
make sure that you can detect and again
it's kind of just a cool lens by which
to think about mitre attack so to
visualize it a different way
again on the left here we have
just a snapshot of the miter attack
matrix you know under discovery there's
account discovery and there's sub
techniques accordingly there and then on
the right there's a bit of yaml
regardless of how you feel about yaml
atomic red team is aligned to yaml
with the goal being that we have this
library of tests yaml format and it was
though created by red canary the
organization
it is maintained
almost exclusively by the community
the community are the ones who add tests
to it and maintain it
of the maintainers team for the open
source project only one of them is a red
canary staffer and so again this is an
entirely community driven initiative to
create this library and have it provide
value and it is mapped one for one with
these miter attack ids which creates
some odd scenarios if you have an
example for a given technique id
but it also kind of applies to another
one well where should it go and the
maintainers help assign those things and
sometimes you just duplicate it and put
both places because that's where it
should go
so anyway
just another view about what atomic red
team is
what's cool about atomic red team just
by nature of it being an open source
project it has a lot of value to other
organizations so for example if you're
an organization designing emulation
plans
well those things can actually just be
atomic red team atomic tests under the
hood and that's what we've seen so for
example
miters adversary emulation plans those
things are if you look at them a lot of
them are just atomic red team tests
another one cites community threats a
lot of those tests that are developed
those come from atomic red team which is
very very cool
red canary's threat detection report all
the examples provided in that thing
atomic red team tests
now i mentioned earlier atomic red team
is not software but you need software to
run the tests all these examples right
there's execution frameworks that do
that many of them are open source so
invoke atomic atomic test harnesses
atomic operator caldera if you've ever
heard of these things these are the
software that run atomics and atomic
tests not atomic red team itself so it's
just a really subtle distinction as you
try to research this and
get started with it
and then finally commercial products
also use atomic red team they've
implemented this open source project
into their frameworks whether they be
execution defensive or otherwise so we
mentioned scythe prelude operator is
another one attack iq
lima charlie also has some atomic red
team integration from a defensive
perspective snap attack who did some
speaking at attack con they also have
this whole thing that uses atomic red
team so you'll see this all over the
place
but the goal of atomics and these atomic
tests is library of examples in my mind
it's to solve
the now what problem
and i think many of you who have to deal
with or get to deal with threat intel
profiles and the like um bump into this
right you get a threat intelligence
report neat
thank you for describing this threat
actor and the behaviors that they've
done oh look mitre attack ids this is
super useful cool but but but but
there's no examples of the ways that the
threat actor actually did it what was
the command that the threat actually
actually used i want to know that too
right i want to build detections around
that thing
and so to fill that gap
well now that you've given me some vague
information now what
atomic red team can answer that question
for you
because it has examples that you can
utilize for the now what if you see
technique 1 two three four but you don't
have any example about how to execute
that or what it looks like or anything
the atomic red team is here to help so
that's the goal
atomics provide that actionable baseline
for you to use this threat and tell and
actually build detections on it or use
it in your red teaming as an example
so hopefully that makes sense
and of course if you start to learn
about these atomic tests well you can
learn and grow you could say oh
that's a cool test but i could modify
that slightly to do something a little
more interesting
some last things
atomic red team the spec in the way that
that project works that library is added
to by design was to have the barrier to
entry be low
we want strangers on the internet to add
tests to atomic red team it is really
important that people can do that
quickly and easily all of you could add
tests to atomic red team whether they
are you're adding a test or you're
adding a typo or whatever changing
fixing a typo not adding a typo please
um regardless
we want folks to be able to contribute
to this that's the goal you shouldn't
have to have
two decades in threat intelligence to
build that tests out for atomic red team
we want that barrier to entry to be low
consequently there's some side effects
to that decision which we'll talk about
in a bit such as defining success and
failure gets kind of weird but again
we'll talk about that in a little bit
but again atomic red team they're atomic
tests both like
uppercase and lowercase a atomic test
one thing
they're not an adversary emulation plan
not software
okay enough definitions we're like what
15 minutes in and we haven't even got to
the meat of this presentation
problem number one
what is coverage in the context of
atomic red team and mitre attack
this is the coverage part of the talk
the first problem we encounter when we
talk about coverage is how do you define
coverage
kind of a weird question but actually
when you think about it it gets a little
complex as it turns out so
the naive approach to coverage
well there's this grid of
ids
do you have tests for each id if yes
that thing is covered when easy solved
right um
that is breadth coverage generally
speaking that's a simple one
there's x amount of tests
there's
x amount of technique ids what are those
numbers done
um
cool
and then you can break that down by
platform and platform in the miter
attack concept is kind of where you're
doing the test so windows mac linux
infrastructure as a service containers
the like there so you can break those
things down that's pretty easy
but what about depth
depth coverage is a little trickier to
define because it can mean all sorts of
things if you depending on which way you
want to slice it
um how well does a group of tests cover
a technique how do you quantify that
how do you conceptualize that how do you
automate that kind of question away how
difficult
are tests to execute again how do you
figure that out how do you do the maths
to figure that out um and then what
about a concept that the atomic red team
has that miter attack does not
sub platforms well infrastructure as a
service is a platform in mitre attack
neat
but
aws
and azure are both infrastructure as a
service but the way you think about the
techniques in those things is wildly
different and the examples you would
provide for both of those things is
entirely different so we have to think
about that sort of thing a little
differently
so again we had to conceptualize what
coverage was
now
oh yeah you can't there's no way you can
read that the galaxy brain text on this
slide i think i actually found what i
had written there originally when i was
generating this and it's something along
the lines of
let's see so there's count techniques
breakdown by platform and then the one
is uh
create a rubric for defining difficulty
to execute a test based on a number of
criteria which can be duplicated by any
human with said rubric or via script
preferably in python because go is too
hard to set up an environment in and to
develop and really who wants to use
something like ruby or rust these days
because it's probably just trendy and i
could probably get made fun of them if i
tried to write any code in them now you
wouldn't make jokes at me because you're
all really good audience i'm just saying
it's reasonable concern you know
thank goodness i kept that text
somewhere i'd never be able to figure it
out anyway moving on
problem number b
okay if we define coverage who's going
to actually help us fix the coverage
problem that we might define
um
yeah that's a tricky one and the way and
we alluded this earlier um
is you need to find resources to do that
but open source projects you know a lot
of folks who contribute to these things
it's not their full-time job right it's
my full-time job to care about open
source stuff but as per prior slides i'm
not a full-time developer
i don't know i can write enough code to
be dangerous and asking project
maintainers and contributors to help out
that's all well and good but it's not
their full-time job either right they
already give a lot of time to these
things so who can help us with it and
really just to brief aside thank you to
the maintainers and project contributors
for everything you do the project would
be nothing without you literally so
you're all the best
thank you
and project maintainers and contributors
are really good at small changes like
adding a test fixing one thing but this
kind of broad we want to evaluate
coverage across the entire project it's
non-trivial to do
quick shameless plug if any of you
contribute to atomic red team you get a
free t-shirt it's pretty cool you should
do that atomicrteam.io to learn more
anyway
um so the the solution to who should
help us coverage thing and solve it
the answer was interns ultimately it
turns out you can you can say hey this
is a really specific project that
requires a lot of learning um this is
probably perfect for an intern to assist
with
really quick internships 101. again we
did a whole thing about this the first
version of this talk but
if you are considering
hiring interns
rule number one
pay your interns treat them like a
part-time full-time contractor whatever
pay
your interns okay rule number one well
number two
offer to work with the educational
institutions if they are in an
educational institution please do that
it's very important
number three
treat them like you would any other
teammate they are not there to wash cars
because nobody else on the team's there
to wash cars like they're like anybody
else treat them that way rule number
four pay your interns just do it just do
it
shouldn't be hard okay and then
do not under any circumstances hire
interns to do menial repetitive tasks
occasionally you'll bump into situations
like hey we need three months of data
entry right just people putting stuff
into spreadsheets or databases
cool
hire a data entry person
not an intern
interns are there to learn from you and
to get experience so having them fill
out spreadsheets all day every day is
probably not optimal and finally don't
just use like great company culture as a
selling point like they're there to
learn not just hang out with the water
cooler that should not be the only
selling point which you've also solved
if you listen to rules number one and
four and you're paying them
okay
so who helped us with this coverage
thing that i've been talking about this
is cameron the intern former intern at
red canary cameron roberts camera's
great
cameron created all the prototypes for
everything you're about to see so thank
you to cameron for the for your hard
work there um cameron
has worked at a bunch of cyber security
firms an awesome open source contributor
likes hacking video games and playing
video games it was actually pretty cool
anyway if you find bump in the camera
and ask about video game hacking it's
very very neat so thank you cameron
so this
this is the atomic red team coverage
project kind of soup to nuts number one
we did an analysis or needed to analyze
all of the tests and count them
basically quantify them but do that in a
scripting way and then a way to
visualize that coverage so it's quick
and easy to understand part two was to
categorize the tests we have again that
depth coverage we need to do analysis
there and generate that data
but first we had to find a means to do
that
number three after we did the gap in l
we wanted to do gap analysis once we had
that coverage visualized we're kind of
still there which we'll talk about that
here in a moment and then talk about the
future which we're also going to do
today but this was the plan of execution
part one
count these things
sounds pretty easy right the breadth
analysis part do you have tests for that
thing if yes that's a win neat so
cameron the first to go with this we
we're gonna do it in python and then we
did in javascript to visualize it pretty
uh pretty straightforward seemingly as
it turns out it wasn't straightforward
um you know the initial goal was hey
let's just make a giant spreadsheet of
atomic tests and miter attack ids and
see what the delta is
but there's this weird misunderstanding
we bumped into
target platform was a field that
created some unexpected problems so
again in the mitre attack context a
platform is where you're gonna the
adversary is doing the thing like the
target os if you will
however
in atomics tests we've kind of been
wrapped around the axle a little bit and
that target platform was where you might
be executing the test because
historically atomic red team was based
on endpoints and so you think well i
need to run windows commands on a
windows box platform's windows easy
enough but that gets really complicated
when you start talking about cloud tests
because say you're doing a test against
aws
well if you're doing a test against aws
you're using an executor on a mac or
something to run that command
what is the target platform is it where
you're running the command or the thing
you're targeting and as it turns out
this was misunderstood and
miscategorized to a pretty substantial
extent so we had to figure this one out
and define that platform really strictly
in order to count these things
effectively
so it was non-trivial and again atomic
red team has this concept of
sub-platforms because
gcp and azure and aws are all
infrastructure as a service but they're
not all the same the commands are
different right so we had to figure all
that out however
with the good work we were able to count
those things very effectively and
generate some cool stuff like how neat
those charts and graphs are um
we're really proud of these because
these allow us a visual indicator of how
good our test coverage is how many tests
for a given technique we have it's all
heat maps people love heat maps right
right right maybe okay i'm seeing nods
that's close enough
real quick many of you want to make
charts and graphs do not write your own
graphing libraries please just use
google charts.js
makes your life way easier but here in
these heat maps you could see over on
the right oh green means there's lots of
tests for that technique id
red not so many white there's none or uh
over there we see this bar chart it
looks like the miter attack matrix if
you look at it and it shows like how
many tests we have covered at the tactic
level how neat right it's such a simple
thing but having these as visual
indicators enabled us to have a
quick easy way oh that we're missing
stuff there we're missing stuff for that
technique we should probably that's an
easy tactic let's just do that
it gave us that visual indication which
is really really important
now to the tricky part
how do we categorize this stuff that
depth analysis how well covered is a
given technique id and we need to find a
practical sorting method
and again that's just it's just
non-trivial at the face of it because
you know here on this left image here
well if you have it covered turn the
color and then you're done
okay easy enough but when we start to
say oh well what if this technique id
has 14 tests that's good that's covered
but only two of them are for linux is
that good is that good coverage right or
what if it has 14 tests but some of them
or all of them are really really hard
for someone to execute is that well
covered
these are the kinds of questions that we
had and then to further complicate
things some of these technique ids are
inherently tricky to do system time
discovery is
the easiest technique to test for in my
mind you type date into a command prompt
and you're done but then you think about
things like network network sniffing
well is that easy to execute you need a
network and you need some other
applications right it's just non-trivial
inherently and then you talk about
things like cloud storage object
discovery well now you have to sign up
for a cloud provider and you need all
this stuff and api keys to do that
again it's non-trivial inherently so how
do you count how well covered that thing
is
the answer was this scoring rubric this
is what we came up with
and
the goals of this were one
only use what's in the yaml
two define just some simple if logic
around it to define a score and then
apply that to what we call the
difficulty score
and then with that difficulty score we
can start to auto apply stuff and check
stuff and grade on a curve and all sorts
of fun stuff there
so here's the example of the rubric
again just a simple one but hey can you
copy and paste this thing would that
work if yes nice
low points um does it have prerequisites
if so
high points and so on and so forth and
this is how we defined our scale of
difficulty that was entirely machine
readable
the actual rubric is defined about
prerequisites do you have to download a
tool from the internet do you need
elevation privileges does it support the
recent version of the platform or only
run on windows me that kind of thing
does it require input arguments does the
user need to interact with this thing
all these uh does it use an application
does the test executor and the
prerequisite executor do they match if
not more points that sort of thing and
uh does some
does this thing require like manual
interaction again more points that way
so we defined this rubric
and what shook out of that
was a pretty neat stuff
so now we had scripts and charts and
graphs to define coverage
and we could see at a glance oh cool
you know mac os doesn't have enough
tests over there we should maybe go
build tests over there and then we had
difficulty graphs of oh
check that out it turns out that
technique idea is really really hard to
execute how could we make that easier
and so this combination of breadth and
depth coverage gave us a lot of ability
to really analyze
the project and its entirety in a way
that those raw numbers kind of didn't
really convey and again it was cool it
was all built up by an intern right it
was someone who could learn
everything about this these frameworks
these open source projects and get
really deeply involved in understanding
it and so it wasn't just a menial task
it was how do you create automation
around this complex thing so it's pretty
neat
so we came up with ways to visualize
that
and then once we had ways to visualize
it well now we have to figure out how to
fill those gaps we've identified places
that we're missing stuff how do we make
the project better for everybody
um how do we make tests easier easier to
use how do we add more tests more
quickly
and answer what i one of the biggest
questions is if any of you wanted to
start helping with atomic red team today
you're like well where should i start
which atomic test should i add first i
want to be able to answer that question
quickly and easily and not just like
lick my finger and put it in the air and
be like oh that one sounds good i
actually have you know have a means to
tell you where to start that was the
goal
so
to meet that goal we have kind of this
idea of the heat map to end all heat
maps and right here this is our
difficulty heat map with in a miter tech
navigator layer here and we could see
quickly and easily oh
the
red or orangey ones those ones are
trickier tests to execute the green ones
are easier tests to execute and again
the ones in white have no tests right
here
it's super easy to figure out where you
should start do one of the ones that
have nothing or maybe try to help out if
you
know how help out with one of the ones
that is a little trickier to do cool
easy question answered visually not with
numbers and spreadsheets right that's
the compelling bit to why we wanted to
visualize all this stuff
but again
difficulty gaps
this is a non-trivial problem to figure
out because
it seems like some techniques and some
tactics are just
harder
right they're just harder inherently to
add tests to and to write tests for
example
rootkit 1014
like
how easy can you make designing a
rootkit test like can you turn that into
a one-liner without any sort of prereqs
or downloading anything or what have you
like that doesn't seem seems like it
shouldn't be that easy so maybe that one
will always have to be difficult another
one is data from a shared network drive
well inherently you need a shared
network drive which adds complexity to
that test so again it's non-trivial
and so maybe there's no there's less
value and trying to make root kit tests
easier immediately and so defining that
value became also a little tricky and
you know some techniques are just more
critical for us as defenders to
focus on because adversaries use them
more right and so defining all this was
it's just hard to do and it required a
lot of homework when we were thinking
about it
so looking at this again bringing back
one of our difficulty heat maps here
defense evasion as an example defensive
asian as a tactic
is just more difficult to write tests
for we can see that visually here
quickly and easily and i didn't have to
comb through a bunch of stuff and make
guesses we just know that now based off
the rubric we designed and all the
automation we built around it and so
if that one is just more difficult maybe
there is less value in asking strangers
to write tests for it immediately
whereas a bunch of other things clearly
need some tests
again the whole point of this is to take
something that is complex and growing
organically and has new tests every
being built every moment and to add some
visibility for people who want to get
started and to tell us where we need
some support
another way we could think about it is
using this old product manager trick an
effort to value ratio right if we took
all of the stuff we could do
we could quickly and easily give it some
scores of oh that tactic is trickier so
the effort's higher but if there's no
tests there maybe the value is also high
and so we can define scores this way
again it's just like a ye oldie product
manager trick that we could utilize as
we have all this coverage mapping to say
oh yeah we actually need help in these
places more than others
so filling these gaps it's a work in
progress but we have lots of mechanisms
now that we did not have before to help
us achieve these goals
which brings us to the future
which is
kind of the call to action for today
one thing i'm going to talk about is
atomic test boundaries and the other
thing is detection and alerting coverage
so now that we've got all these maps and
all this data what do we do with it
sorry in advance to walmart's hackfest
if using this picture gets the stream
dmca takedown oh hold on no actually i
can fix that really quick there we go
okay cool so
let's say we wanted to make an atomic
bounty program right i say dear everyone
there's a test i want you to make and i
have really specific criteria for how i
think the test should be created or
things that i want to have in that test
and
you know the reward for this thing is
variable because i actually have an idea
of how difficult it might be to achieve
this goal right neat wouldn't it be neat
if a corporate
organization would sponsor the filling
of this sort of bounty it's not just you
being a good community member and like
wanting to commit to open source it's
you saying like hey i could get a gift
card out of this how cool is that well
lo and behold
auntie siphon training a john strand
corporation um actually has a bounty for
atomics right now it's going right now
it i think it goes till what the the
18th
and so
you all can go find that thing and
create atomics that are defined and the
ones that are great
get stuff from anti-siphon that's
amazing right and this just happened
independently because it's an open
source project and the community loves
to help out and this is the sort of
thing we want to do more and more and
more of as more organizations have
vested interest in this if we flash back
to earlier remember there's all these
for-profit companies that use atomic red
team under the hood and they just reap
all the benefits from community work
well
guess what they want more free features
in their stuff and the community can
provide them that and so they can create
a development cycle where it's like hey
we'll give you stuff if you uh push
stuff upstream to atomic red team and
then everyone wins right the whole
community is made better by this sort of
project in these sorts of additions
so that's very cool
now this is gonna be this is a
problematic slide i apologize i'm about
to change the definition of coverage for
everyone as we've been talking about it
for 30 minutes detection coverage
this is the next place that atomic red
team probably needs to go so imagine a
world where you all have this library of
cool adversary ttp examples right
well wouldn't it be neat if you could
automatically fire all of those things
in your environment and see if you can
detect them how cool would that be
like you could just see
automatically like oh yeah we're
alerting on all these things and then we
made a we changed a rule and could we
fire them again oh look we're
automatically detecting all these things
but we're missing that one like how neat
would that cadence be if anybody could
do that
this is the holy grail if we as a
community can define a way that
everybody can do this
there's much winning to be had
and there's been a lot of conversations
about how you could achieve this at a
community perspective we've talked about
sigma we've talked about sysmon we've
talked about maybe new libraries maybe
adding to the atomic red team
specification there's all sorts of ways
we could achieve this goal
and the atomic team maintainers are open
to ideas here like definitely so if
anybody has thoughts on this let them be
heard this is a community project we can
only all be better because of minds like
yours
so
this is
there's no defined answer for this even
though we've started to see movement in
this space i mentioned snap attack
earlier at attack con they demoed a
thing that was this
right but again that's a pro
proprietary company that's how they make
their money and so if the community can
come up with a way to do this that'd be
pretty compelling
so
again the future detection coverage how
could we figure this out together
however
there's a known problem and i mentioned
this earlier
we made a choice in building atomic red
team and the way it's designed to make
it so that people can add tests quickly
and easily and you don't need to be a
super expert and need to know every
single little process that the thing
might make or all the exit codes you
might have or any of that stuff you just
write a test and push it upstream
but because a given atomic test is just
an example and there's no concept of
success and failure in the atomic red
team spec
well if you're going to automatically
run a bunch of these things and then
determine your detections
logic off of that
how do you know all those tests worked
without looking at all of them
individually
how do you know that the thing you were
trying to do actually happened and that
you're not getting some sort of weird
flag that you weren't expecting or an
event log that isn't appropriate because
the test didn't actually work in bulk
because the atomic red team spec doesn't
have that concept of success and failure
this problem is very very tricky and
again we are open to ideas about how to
achieve this
huge library of detection coverage that
you could apply automatically
and one example of like how tricky this
can be let's go again my favorite
example system date or system time
discovery t1124
again
the test for this is the word date in a
command prompt and you push enter right
that's the easiest you could get
but how do you determine that that was
successful that you ran that test
successfully is it an exit code is it a
value that it returns what if you're not
in the us and date formatting is
differently how do you define success
for that command
every single time
and how does a person just
create that and what is the expectation
around creating that test
again it's non-trivial to define these
things and we are open to suggestions
and we we know that specifications need
to grow over time we know that these
projects need to adapt but
this problem this is the holy grail that
i challenge you all to try to answer for
the community
because we're working on it and it's
it's tricky so where do we go from here
we've talked about a lot of stuff right
i've talked about charts and graphs and
information and atomic red team and
miter attack
if you want to just dive into this if
you want to explore atomic red team
atomics if you want to learn about this
kind of testing if you want to
contribute stuff or join the slack
channel for this community or any of
this stuff where do you go well you
could go here
atomic red team dot io we just launched
a cool new version of this site
and it has all the integrated charts and
graphs and stuff we're adding atomics
all the time there's a bunch of new
features and functionality and it's much
more rich of a resource for people who
don't want to just like carve through a
github
blob of
yaml that's the goal of what we've done
and to like to show
does it work is my animation working
look at that so let's see you want to
search for lsas tests so look you just
type in elses and everything just pops
up and it happens in real time you don't
have to search github for stuff because
search
isn't great
not great
so
solve that problem a little bit so
this is one of the things that you can
do now if you want to search for an
atomic test you just put in a search bar
bang you're right there all the
information available to you
huge shout out to jose hernandez one of
the atomic red team maintainers for
building all this functionality out
again i know enough code to be dangerous
but jose really drove this this
functionality home so that's all there
atomicredteam.io you can search all the
atomic tests right now which is very
very cool uh another one again all this
great work cameron roberts did we have
all these cool charts and graphs look at
this thing you change it and it
animation happens it's very cool so
we're pretty proud of this but again it
provides you all that at a glance
visibility of coverage that you just
have and you can download attack
navigator layers and just throw those
into the attack navigator ui and boom
it's done also if you have not played
with mitre attack navigator and you do
stuff with mitre attack go check out the
attack navigator seriously it's very
very very very cool and it's very useful
when you're defining a way to visually
map this stuff because it can be a
little arcane as you're talking about
technique ids especially to people who
have no idea what this stuff is so
that's all cool and exists now and you
should check out navigator if you
haven't done so before so takeaways if
you've just been like playing fortnite
on your phone throughout this whole talk
these are the things you need to know
number one pay your interns just do it
if you take nothing else away from the
talk please do that
next up in atomic red team land atomic
test gap analysis is underway we've done
some very very cool stuff there it's now
visible to all so if you want to get
started with this it's all available to
you we launched a new site we've got new
tests being created by the community
like you all
every day which is very very cool we
have more information on what an atomic
bounty program might look like again
thanks to anti-siphon for making one
already but more bounty stuff and
knowledge about their coming soon tm
also you should contribute to atomic red
team it is very very easy
i mean it it is really easy and don't
just take my word for it
george ortiz
just tweeted this the other day
literally like a one-line test and added
to atomic red team i think what did he
use drop the imposter syndrome was how
he started the tweet anyone can be a
contributor so if you even have an
inkling of thinking about it
please do so because only together as a
community can we make this library more
rich and add to the value of this thing
for everyone
again you get free stuff
you can just fix typos it's great
anything we want anything any help at
all would be fantastic also we give
shout outs to new and top contributors
in the atomic newsletter which goes out
every month get your github name right
there like hey you're great
and everybody should know it
we have slack community
team dot io it's all there
cool
so we're done a little early but if you
want to know more i said atomic range
theme.io it's the place thanks everyone
thanks waldo hackenfest for having me
thank you all for being great
participants thank you all on the live
stream we're all done
[Applause]
adam
i want to thank adam for coming to grace
us with his presence and convincing us
all to use the attack framework this is
another in the encouragement to become
part of the community that's what the
message you're hearing here lots of open
source lots of everybody pitching in so
don't forget to pitch in and go check
out the workshops be sure and come back
for the next talk that starts at 10
o'clock
and
any questions from the audience
no
how about your handouts where can people
get your hand out so you're gonna post
them to the discord
yeah so if you want to talk to me or
learn more about red canary or atomic
red team stuff we're in the vendor area
just look for the red bird
bird um so you can come over there we're
giving away some free stuff too um as
far as handouts and slides and all that
stuff i'll post those when i post those
i'm sorry in advance it won't be in the
next 20 minutes and not i'm very ill
prepared wi-fi is problematic it's a
whole thing so but i will post these
slides asap somewhere soon so for those
on the on the live stream stay tuned
this is just early the morning of the
first day of the conference and it will
be a good day by the end of the day
evening and morning yeah it's gonna be
great
so stick around for the next talk too
come back at 10 o'clock if you need to
take a break buy a break take care of
yourselves don't be in the chair
it's code of conduct