[Music]
it's a pleasure to be here in Germany I
was thinking about trying to sing my
oder Lindenberg songs but I remember
from being at school near Hanover in the
1970s but then for ty I should spare you
that infliction of a beginning of this
talk so it's very good to be here in
Germany for the fifth annual Munich
cybersecurity conference and clearly the
very nature of this conference
demonstrates the extent to which a
digital revolution has transformed the
world we live in digital connectivity
has already transformed everything about
our lives it's broken down geographical
and physical boundaries that were once a
barrier to our global communication and
collaboration it's made us increasingly
reliant upon new technologies and could
any of us imagine a life now without our
smartphones unless we are reading
survivalist manuals and retreating into
the mountains somewhere it's become such
an integral part I think of all our
lives from interacting with public
services to finding our way around
cities that we don't know I'm struck
I've just spent three years living in
India my daughter was born there her
digital birth certificate was delivered
in ten minutes for a new digital
government service one example of a way
in which this service delivery is
transforming away citizens interact with
with governments as our digitally
collected world has expanded an
extraordinary raids so too has a scale
of vulnerabilities and the frequency of
attacks that we face thousands of public
and private sector organizations
worldwide are falling victim to
ransomware attacks our supply chains are
being compromised our critical national
infrastructure continues to be a target
for attack from nation-states and cyber
criminals and we're seeing threats to
our democracies from attempted outside
interference that democratic practice
which is something that I think we as
Europeans hold so very dear it's right
in the face of these shared threats that
we stand together as international
partners and allies to confront expose
and disrupt hostile or malicious
activity and you will have seen our
attribution of a range of malicious
cyber attacks to the work of Russian
military intelligence this builds upon a
host of cyber
we have attributed with partners
including more wanna cry incidents one
of the most substantial to hit the UK in
terms of scale and disruption to North
Korean actors we must continue to affirm
our shared vision for an open peaceful
and secure digital world based on the
rule of law and the norms of behavior
and and one of the key ingredients in
map this year will be a renewed United
Nations negotiations that will begin in
the General Assembly this September both
through a a UN group of government
experts and through an open-ended
working group of a General Assembly and
that process I think will be the next
step in the international process of
trying to define and consolidate a set
of norms that all countries can
subscribe to and protecting our people
and the systems that we rely on and
democracy itself is an essential goal of
governments and that's why cybersecurity
must remain a top priority because it
impacts both our national security but
also our economic prosperity in the UK
we have really focused in recent years
on developing a national cyber security
strategy and recognizing market forces
alone we're not driving the step change
required the UK set out plans for a more
active and comprehensive response
through the national cybersecurity
strategy in 2016 in it we set out
ambitious proposals to take a more
interventionist role to defend our
people to deter our adversaries and
develop our capabilities both in
government and beyond and we did this to
ensure that the UK remains the safest
place to live and do business online and
one of the most visible elements for
strategy was the formation of a national
cyber security centre and this brought
together our best intelligence and
technical expertise into a single world
leading Authority supported by partners
the NCSC has undertaken some pioneering
work in its first two years and a key
strand of his work has been the
deployment of his active cyber defence
programme
these measures aim to enhance the UK's
national resilience by automatically
protecting UK Internet users from the
vast majority of crude high-volume
cyberattacks that affect people's
everyday lives reducing a burden on
individuals and small businesses it's
essentially automated cyber defense at
scale but we know that malicious cyber
actors will continue to adapt their
behavior in response and it's vital that
we continue revolutionising our approach
to keep pace with a fret and that's why
upskilling is such a key part of this in
government and beyond we shifted our
focus towards creating sustainable
structural change we've developed a
comprehensive cybersecurity skills
strategy that sets out proposals to
nurture and inspire the next generation
of cybersecurity professionals and
entrepreneurs not only will this help us
develop specialist talent but it will
also develop a cybersecurity profession
to create clear Park career pathways
building more diverse and inclusive
workforce and it provides a sustainable
pipeline to take us to 2021 and beyond
and even within the Foreign Office
itself we are we are an institution of
diplomats that are perhaps better known
for our adeptness with words for numbers
or big data the fact that within my part
of a foreign office we now have
behavioral scientists data analysts
sentiment analysts and people who can do
large end data work speaks to thee and
the early moves to develop capability
even within the foreign ministry space
to adopt and respond to the environment
we're in but to achieve this paradigm
shift in our approach we must bring
about a shift in mindset across society
as a whole and that relies on the
strength of the partnerships we create
and our ability to demystify and if you
like decode what cyber security actually
is while it's difficult to avoid
headlines about attacks and breaches
doing something about it is still often
seen as too technical or too difficult
or someone else's problem and cyber
Security's everyone's responsible
we consider it vital that all
organizations must embrace an embed
cybersecurity from the boardroom down
this is no longer a technical issue
it is a grand strategic and policy issue
for governments for private for the
private sector and for civil society and
that's why we've targeted our efforts in
the UK at driving long term change by
helping boards to better understand the
risks they face and to invest
appropriately we must ensure that
boardrooms provide active leadership to
ensure cybersecurity is ingrained into
organizational cultures and mindsets but
we can do more and that's why the UK is
also partnering with over 500 private
sector organisations for our national
cyber aware campaign to encourage
citizens and business to take the really
simple protective steps that can prevent
the majority of high volume low
sophistication attacks and at this
halfway point in the delivery of our
national cyber security strategy we put
in place many of the building blocks to
transform the UK cyber security and
resilience and these are demonstrating
clear results but we can never become
complacent just as a threat from cyber
criminals and nation states continues to
evolve so too must we continue to
innovate and refocus our efforts to
bring about a step change in our
response we want our citizens to reap
the benefits of connected technologies
we also want to realize our ultimate of
ambition to make all products and
services secure by design and if there's
one kind of banner heading that you'll
hear repeatedly I think from Britain as
a stakeholder in this debate it is this
phrase secured by design trying to
hardwire secure design into everything
that we do as the Internet of Things
continues to expand it can't be right
that consumers are left to secure their
own products the challenge is to
encourage manufacturers to help
consumers by building protections into
their design so it's easy for consumers
to ensure that their devices are secure
as for homes that they live in while
this will take global cooperation to fix
we developed a new code of practice for
consumer internet connected devices such
as smart home assistance and toys
alongside other measures such as Keynes
my guidance on smart devices in my home
we're trying to shift the burden of
security away from consumers
international collaboration is obviously
a key part of is the successes so far in
delivering our national cybersecurity
strategy have been driven by close
partnership working with the
cybersecurity community in the UK and
beyond a continuation of that
collaborative partnership approach is
crucial to any future success we may
have and Wiest we put our money where
our mouth is on this not only do we work
closely with like-minded States whether
in the european space or with other
partners internationally we are also
investing some 30 million pounds in
building cyber capacity in other
countries internationally we've also
invested in one of the lead centers for
thinking about cyber security at oxford
university and we support the journal of
cyber policy at Chatham House one of
Britain's leading think tanks as part of
again our commitment to encourage a
debate as well as to encourage ket
capacity-building we remain committed to
working with international partners to
develop and maintain our principles of a
free open peaceful and secure cyberspace
and we will continue to stand
shoulder-to-shoulder with international
partners to call out harmful behavior
that seeks to undermine the rules-based
international system and we welcome
recent initiatives including a paris
call for trust and security in
cyberspace and the OECD Global Forum on
digital security for Prosperity which
will help us meet our collective
challenge to ensure that our digital
economies are safe and secure I hope
I've been able to demonstrate today not
just that we understand the scale of a
challenge that we face but but we're
seeking to cultivate the right
environment so that we can be are at our
most collaborative and agile in response
and I understand you know the private
sector agility is one of the new
buzzwords for animates meetings around
the world
I think agility is something that we
should be bringing to the policy and
regulatory response in this space as
well as we face new challenges in the
year ahead we need to ensure that we
remain focused on reaching across
organizational political and
geographical boundaries government is
never going to be the sole source of
good ideas in this space is going to be
the private sector it is going to be
civil society
it is going to be clever load-bearing
conversations but cut across boundaries
and that you know developing that whole
of government and whole of society
approach is key to become more than the
sum of our individual parts so that we
can continue to protect the economic and
individual freedoms that make us
stronger together thank you
[Applause]
[Music]