[Music]
what I want to talk about is artificial
intelligence and the question is we in
the last panel in the last discussion
and presentations we already talked
about that cybersecurity becomes more
and more challenging and for sure
artificial intelligence will change the
game again it will change the game from
two sides first of all when we think
about where the cybersecurity topic come
from it's not only from email it's
coming from IOT it is coming from
whatever is connected on this world
artificial intelligence will drive and
enable a complete new set of connected
devices artificial intelligence will
also enable a different type of things
the Machine and when thinking about
artificial intelligence artificial
intelligence is not good not bad so you
can use it in two ways
it can be the attacker of tomorrow as
well as the defender so the question is
how do we deal with artificial
intelligence in this way so first of all
I'm pretty sure artificial intelligence
will help to support schemes for with
say attacking learning how to find out
passwords how to change very quickly the
approach on fishing and many other sites
I think that's pretty obvious so the
question is what we have to discuss how
to deal with this on the other side
artificial intelligence can also be of
great benefit artificial intelligence
can supervise what is going on the in
the internet what is going on in the
data exchange environment and then from
these peten make proposals on potential
problem it can help the people who are
responsible for the defense
of the companies but we also talked
about the normal people on road the
normal people who like me and others who
are happy to get some more IOT devices
which help them in life which are making
life easy art IOT is about a matter of
ease-of-use IOT years and artificial
intelligence is instrumental on this if
you would go so for that we think about
the collaborative robot at home
artificial intelligence there'll be the
key engine in it
and to be very honest I'm not so sure if
and we debated today we should program
however they do our software diligently
I'm not too sure how trained to how to
train an AI in a diligent manner so a
lot of topics are coming up there but
they will come now there was another
question how to deal with as an average
person to this problem I fully agree
that we need to be significantly more of
the heir of what it means on cyber
security but I give you a picture where
I believe it is it will not work so
easily when you do your driver's license
normally you learn besides many other
things you should take care for the
pressure in your tires there had been a
phase where we had a lot of rollover
accidents in as in us with the SUVs why
because of deflated tires and what
happened there was a ruling that you
have to build in by the company's a tire
pressure monitor so for me the big
question is when I look at cyber
security at the cyber space how to deal
with this and in many other areas then
how can we first of all think about the
right ruling the right ease of use for
the end customer because if you have a
tire pressure monitor you will not
forget you will not think about dirty
fingers you will get the
Carville tell you you have to go to the
station and take care of work so AI can
be a crucial role on this hey I can help
in order to highlight if it detects
problems that to the end-users that they
should take care for on the other side
in order to make that happen we have to
think ourselves how do we enable our IOT
devices our infrastructure in a way that
this can be done reasonably well if you
have an unsecured item from the very
beginning you don't need even to observe
it just take it out of the network I'll
take it out of some relevant I would say
communication I personally would be
extremely happy if I would see such a
surveillance program which would if I
receive an email and the name and the
email whatever it comes true or not has
a color green yellow red green or
something where obviously this person
has identified all the device identified
itself from the very beginning and when
I think about IOT I even do not think
about the people writing emails the IOT
device well it's not so difficult when
you think about we have a lot of devices
today where we say yeah we can have a
secured Hardware we have that in the
phone we have that in the banking card
it is an anchor there you start with you
identify your device and go on from
there so if this device becomes yellow
what you can take it out of many
activities if it becomes red you may
think about to block it in the whole
communication area so again here
ease-of-use metals in two ways first
ease-of-use fools those who design
products I think you can ask for a very
high quality software but this is not so
easy to do we can develop a hundred
percent reliable software but maybe we
can't at least we
on the way think about automotive
functional safety requires that you can
develop software which is from the first
moment totally functional that even in a
case of a non-functional element there
is a fallback so basically we can if we
want but the question is can we afford
and I don't think we can afford so we
have to think about in two ways how to
use AI to create a surveillance and how
to make things easier for the people who
design IOT devices who design software
and at least for the user in order to
that and here I believe artificial
intelligence can help a lot how to use
it and how to get informed about what is
going on and what is off many of us are
using in their PC a virus scanner you
now can believe it or not but it's on
you some people put it off but I think
here
nevertheless it is running my not having
these topics in your software in order
to help his room because my expectation
is not that people are hesitant to go
and use new gadgets to be I would say
keen to have IOT but they will not
understand what is going on when you buy
a car I also tune would ask you to think
about the software which is in your
engine management in order to make sure
you know what what is going on in the
exhaust or whatever I think here it is
true V and there I that we have to
expect more but we have to make it more
easy now I come to one point talking
about these identities nobody debated if
it was meaningful to have the icon which
is kind of encoding the name of an
address which you know somehow into a
number why not having similar ways done
on a public-private partnership or even
on a part pop and
cooperation level in order to provide
services where the people might be
willing to pay for of course the idea to
have us incentive in order to highlight
vulnerabilities by the way it already
exists to a certain degree makes also
sense but again I believe artificial
intelligence will change the game
significantly on the attack and the
defense side so the question is what do
we do early enough to enable artificial
intelligence on the defense side in
order to provide a reasonably of as a
system which you can handle where you
can think about additional value being
created and by the way again a lot is
there the only point is how to put it
together in an overall working system
and to make a move on that so I think
with this I want to conclude and I'm
looking forward to see the going on on
the further discussion
and my question is again for this and I
administer stable she is a one who is
advertising a lot I think we should in
general think about how to help instead
of how to raise the finger with this
thank you very much
[Music]