[Music]
so and welcome to the first panel ladies
and gentlemen and welcome to Munich I
only came here once before this I came
to the third one and based on my
experience so far it's always a hot
sunny day on the day of the Munich
cybersecurity conference so the sun's
beating down I have every sympathy for
the the guys in the sunshine over there
two years ago when I was here I was here
in my capacity as the director-general
of digital Europe choose the tech
industry association and I'd also had
the privilege of leading a European
Commission policy forum on the digital
transformation of Europe's industry and
enterprises a fantastic forum brought
together many brilliant people and of
course cybersecurity was very much on
the agenda then as it remains on the
agenda today so now I spend time and
that delightful phase of my career where
I can do a series of things and one of
the things I'm doing is as a global tech
advisor to a communications company
Burson conan wolf which is a merger of
two of the many WPP communications
company a burson-marsteller and conan
wolf and one of our clients is telstra
the australian telecommunications
company and this is relevant to our
panel this afternoon and they're just
about to produce a report it'll come out
at the end of this month looking at
digital transformation on a global basis
and they've surveyed I think over 3,800
individuals in a dozen or so markets and
14 I think geographies and two things
emerged from that one that is very
relevant for today is that the
protection of digital assets is very
high on the agenda of everyone
undergoing a digital transformation
you'd sort of think that would be the
case wouldn't you but it's reassuring
that that comes out in the server but
the other thing that's relevant to our
panel and our discussion this afternoon
is that this survey looked at digital
transformation through four different
lenses if you will it looks deep through
the lens of process it
to date through the lens of technology
how well do people understand the
technology it looks at it very
importantly through the lens of process
and finally through the lens of people
and in a way I think that's the way the
panel's have been organized you're in
this conference this afternoon and we
have the privilege of organizing and
talking about that first topic that well
the last in my list of people so I can
sit down not turn my back now to my
panelists now I I am joined by five
great panelists who were all going to
make a really good contribution to this
and we're going to we're going to begin
it will try anyway to focus on people in
three groups and staff users or
customers as the second group and bad
actors as the third group now there's
clearly some overlap between those three
different groups but and and in fact
it's it was brought home to me recently
with some some other work we'd been
doing with Santander actually we've been
looking at the perpetration of data
breaches in the banking sector globally
in 2017
and this was a piece of work that I
think IBM had done and and I was quite
surprised to find that of those data
breaches only 42 percent were due to
outsiders only five percent were due to
malicious or bad actors and over half
were inadvertent insiders so it's very
relevant that we're talking over half I
mean that's that's staggering so it's
very relevant that we're talking about
staff as the first of those people now
let me introduce the panelists to you
and in Oprah so starting on my rights
Larry Clinton now Larry if you read if
you read his intro it says he literally
wrote the book on cyber risk management
I think you've got some copies of the
book with you haven't Hillary the cyber
risk management handbook published by
the National Association of corporate
directors and endorsed by the US
government and last year in conjunction
with BSI here in Germany you produce the
German edition of the handbook as well
so it's great to have you on the panel
to motor hero to Chia Oprah
that correctly is a professor at the Keo
University graduate school of media and
governance in Japan but he's also been
the deputy director of the university's
Global Research Institute since 2016
you've done more than written the book I
think you've written about 30 books
this guy's written our intelligence and
national security cyber terror cyber
security and international relations so
we won't carry on through the sort of
competing on number of books
Kirstin at this point Kirsten's already
had a brief introduction she's the
managing director of the cyber readiness
Institute and it brings together senior
leaders of global companies so big
companies coming together to help small
companies small and medium-sized
companies improve their cybersecurity
and your creds Kirsten very impressive
was formerly the executive director of
the u.s. Presidential Commission on
enhancing national cybersecurity so a
lot of a lot of experience to bring to
our panel on my immediate left Stefan
Mik 'lets is the engineering director at
Google here in Munich responsible for
privacy and identity and you manage
engineering teams who provide I mean a
lot of Engineers in your teams I think
provide users and staff with the tools
to control and manage their privacy and
I know you're also helped with the
development of the Google products as
well but last but by no means least
who's going actually going to kick us
off in this discussion is Stefan ludus
now Stefan I think you've got a
brilliant job Stefan it's very
impressive he's the computer security
officer at CERN which as you know is the
European Organization for particle
physics based in Switzerland two and a
half thousand staff so that's a pretty
good start you know for our discussion
but interestingly also when I counted 17
and a half thousand scientists around
the world maybe more now involved in
CERN's research were clearly all going
to have a their fingers in your system
somehow and we want to start with Stefan
on this issue of staff because Stefan
when we were having a pre discussion you
were actually quite vocal about the
quality of the people that we're joining
you and there a bill
to cope with the the demands on them to
help us protect our digital assets a get
the ball rolling Stefan if you would
yeah I didn't want to offend anybody but
just from coming back to cybersecurity
risk it's proportionate to the threat
the probability of having
vulnerabilities and to probability of
consequences I don't control the threat
part so I don't train attackers but I'm
doing the the defense so I have to be at
the contrary consequences we're running
lots and lots of different digital
systems like ours is doing and the
problem I'm facing we engaging with
students we're having lots lots of
people coming from all over the world
working at CERN for master thesis or for
bachelor thesis for short moment doing
development on control systems or on
soft developments and what I see is that
those students basically not coming with
a cybersecurity mindset to get web
designers they know brilliantly up to
set a web page web server but they don't
know how to do securely database
administrators don't know how to do it
securely so I was looking why is that
and in many many curriculums of
universities maybe not of some of the
professor's which are here but many
universities don't teach this for your
bachelor you doing operating systems
programming databases web secure web
service if you ask about security know
this comes later for the master and I
think this is this is utterly wrong
having a security conference is utterly
wrong actually because I've never seen
their functionality conference or
maintainability conference on
availability conference functionality
conference there's not existing why is
security different for me and this is
why all the two starters those students
should get an education when they learn
to program to program securely if they
learn setting a web server to set a web
server securely setting up databases
securely virtualization in a secure
fashion and what I see is the students I
am hiring the students earners hiring
usually they don't come with such a
background and we're not talking about
cyber security since yesterday talking
about this since at least I do since
2003 and
wonder why is that is that because you
are at Google employing all the best
people who've got the cybersecurity
skills and there's nothing left for
anyone else no well how do you file do
you find it value vish right
so it's certainly true baby have we have
a number of security experts on the
staff and we have a huge team that cares
about security not only for our users
which is mostly what my team is doing
but also internally and but then again
right we have a lot of staff and we have
a lot of people from different
backgrounds what I think is universally
true is that people understand the
importance of security especially on the
staff but that doesn't actually save you
at all right because everybody can get
fished and there's and that includes all
of the experts here in this room and
phishing attacks are increasingly
getting sophisticated to a level where I
think nobody here would be able to
distinguish so we have to be aware that
but everybody on the staff and everybody
handling our systems and there's many it
could be or every account could be under
attack of control and so we have to
defend against that as well which is a
very big part of our do you find the
same thing as Stephan that the people
joining you are basically immature in
their skills I know I wouldn't say that
you wouldn't think it would disagree on
that in a sense that and they might not
know all the things that they need to do
but they're certainly aware of it and
and they if given the resources they are
availablein to find out and let me tend
to Larry Nest if I may what so you've
been running this program for a number
of years you'd be you've written a
handbook why have you not fixed this
Larry we're doing our best
so I one of the reasons I like to speak
to European audiences sometimes more
than American audiences you folks are
classically trained so I think we should
go back to marcus aurelius who says of
all things you must find the essence of
it and the essence of the problem
in cyber security is not vulnerabilities
technology is just how cyber attacks
occur for us to get to the essence of
this we need to understand why the
attacks occurred and the core problem is
economic the the economic balance in
cybersecurity attacks are cheap to
acquire easy to operate very profitable
you have a great business model and on
the other hand the defenders were
defending a inherently vulnerable system
we're always one step down to the
attacker they have first mover advantage
and we have virtually no law enforcement
yeah but Larry I'm gonna see that's the
lab those are the bad guys here's what
about what about the poor this is the
point is that that we're asking the
wrong questions we need to change the
paradigm the reason we don't have enough
and you probably all go to Google but
the reason we don't have enough
sophisticated people in this space is
because nobody teaches security in in
the universities but why it's because
nobody wants to pay for security so I'm
guessing virtually everybody in this
room has a smartphone be honest now how
many of you asked about the security
when you bought this your smart phone
always for liars
they're always through the floor liners
in every breath we don't want it by the
way the government does won't pay for
security either one of my companies had
laptops and for a defense system put in
and they came to him and said hey these
are insecure and the company said no
problem we can secure them cost you know
the two dollars a laptop government said
no thank you
so laptops going in the core the reason
we need to change the paradigm is that
we are not talking about the economics
they don't teach secure coding because
nobody wants to buy secure coders they
want what we want we want apps we want
we want cheap we want fast what do we
want what we want you know fix my
internet get my internet to be faster
until we reformulate the economics of
this issue we are going to be nibbling
around the edges if you want I've got a
whole book on the cyber social
contract we need to fundamentally
rethink the relationship between
industry and government with respect to
our economics just the way Hegel and
Locke and Hume rethought the
relationship between the citizen and
government a couple hundred years ago
and by the way just the way you guys
managed your situation after World War
two for hundreds of years Western Europe
has been ravaged by almost constant
warfare two horrible world wars in the
last century for the last 75 years
virtually total peace and prosperity did
you solve that problem by resolving all
of the vulnerabilities at the borders or
did you get to the essence of it and
realize you needed to work together
you're right essence all Europeans you
needed to erect new bottles with new
ways of interacting and entities that
thought of themselves as competitors for
years needed to start to work together
when you did that you got 75 years of
world peace government and industry need
to do that now all these wonderful
partnership programs I'm involved with a
lot of we're nibbling around the edges
and they're not real partnerships not
the way Google does a partnership with a
company you're going to partnership
where you sit down and you talk about
the economics and make sure it's
profitable for both that doesn't happen
with industry government talks that's
the reason kiss and you've worked on
both sides of this partnership potential
partnership government and industry dues
do you agree with Larry say no makes it
more interesting but I want to step back
from what Larry saying a little bit and
that's what happens a lot we go back and
forth on this so one of the things that
you're talking about when you talk about
the human you reference the Commission
that I worked on and one of the key
issues that we discussed in that
commission was moving security away from
the end user or educating the end user
and what you'll hopefully all think to
yourself is well those are not
necessarily in conflict they can be
reconciled but there is this feeling
when you talk to technology people it's
you know just get the humans out of the
loop
well that is ideal but we don't live in
the avatar
humans are gonna be in this world and
humans do interact so we've got to think
about what do we need to do to educate
the end user and I would look at that in
in two environments and one of which
will align with what Larry's saying and
I'll just disagree with them at some
point just to make it feel better for
you John go through this but the first
is is we look at organizations we have
to educate our workforce we have to
educate the workforce on the basic
elements phishing authentication those
elements where humans have direct
interaction and I really push back on
the term cyber workforce certainly we
have specialties that require
engineering math and science but really
each of us are part of the cyber
workforce and if we don't push that
responsibility and that accountability
to every individual we're truly missing
out on the opportunity to educate the
second piece of this is as you look at
the organization's we're also talking
about society so oftentimes in the
United States but it happens around the
world when you hear a breach what you
then hear the news stories coming out
around are the individuals saying well
what if I was breached what if they got
my information what if what are they
gonna do with it what do I do now and I
would argue that that's actually not the
question or the right time for the
question we as individuals and this is
about educating the culture in the
society we need to be asking those
questions beforehand we need to be
asking about the security before we
reserve a room at a hotel before we
purchase a car before we fly an airline
because as long as we don't make
security a differentiator to Larry's
point companies won't make it a
differentiator we as consumers have to
start making it a differentiator we tend
to think of humans as a liability when
we think about security but humans can
also be an asset an educated workforce
and educated society is an asset and to
Larry's point about who asked the
question about their iPhones I traded in
my iPhone last summer and the engineer
the the technician as he was switching
it out was going through all the
security preferences he was just
clicking and clicking and clicking I
said wait a second what are you clicking
he was actually making the preferences
for me and I stepped back and I said you
know here is a great opportunity to
educate an entire society how many of us
have Samsung's have apples purchase them
when you are looking and you go to a
store and they start
looking through for you what an
opportunity because to Larry's point we
all hold a smartphone for an individual
to be able to be educated on this so the
point is we have to be looking at
security as a differentiator not just in
our society but in organizations and as
leaders and we talked about the board's
earlier top-down bottom-up we need to be
requiring that accountability and that
responsibility from all employees and
from all citizens and most a hero
weekend we're often I think criticized
correctly in European conferences for
having a bit of a European us loving and
we don't often get the Asian perspective
so it's great that you'll hear this
afternoon that should a week should we
learn anything else from Asian
perspectives we often feel that you're
sort of more add back on imagine that
story of going into the Apple Store and
they the operator clicking through the
options for you would that happen would
that happen in Japan okay so much so
thank you for inviting me so I'm
teaching cybersecurity policy or
strategy in my university so I'm helping
the Japanese government to formulate a
cybersecurity policy and the government
people are very very frustrated with me
and university professors because you
are not teaching good students to
Japanese universities so I always say
it's too late too late to educate 20
years old students so I want to talk
about the North Korean experience
because maybe so Russia or Iran might be
your enemy possible enemies but so China
North Korea our possible enemies in
cyberspace actually so in North Korea so
the government is picking up elementary
school student pupils maybe less than 10
years old and if they find a good
student in mathematics so they will pick
it up pick him up pick him up and so
those students are transferring to
Pyongyang and so their families are
living in a very gorgeous apartment and
so they are educated in a very talented
two universities universities later
so North Korea has three universities
for computer science
and we counted a possible graduates
number so it could be 7000 now but 7000
IT employees cannot be hired in North
Korea so what happens so if you prove
that you are very loyal to the North
Korean leadership they will be sent to
foreign countries China Malaysia and
friendly countries so they run now IT
business and sometimes they get to order
from puron so they start hacking so
those kind of system is working in North
Korea and say educating very talented
people from the now listen ten years old
we cannot emulate such kind of system in
Japan so as you said so people are not
happy with the security business because
they cannot be rich so you have to
maintain hundred percent security in
your business so if you cannot do that
you will be blamed so why so why we were
breached so why get cyber attacks those
kind of things happens so they are very
frustrated they don't want to go to
business they want to go to IT dot-com
business for money so security is not a
good business in Japan in North Korea
you can be a have a good life for cyber
security so that's why they are very
positive to seek talents technologies in
North Korea that's very different we
cannot imitate but but but as we know
that North the North Korean well the
whole structures so completely different
I mean what but what could we what can
we learn about how what we should do
differently from the experiences that
you've seen in China Japan or South
Korea North Korea what could we do
differently what could we do differently
in our universities so or before as you
put it to to fix Stefan's problem I'm
spending a lot of years to educate young
people but most talented young Japanese
people are hired by Google see I was
right I was right that's right yeah
and I agree with you completely we you
know if you're waiting to you know till
they get to Google or to CERN it's it's
far too late we need to make
cybersecurity cool we need to make it so
people want to go into cybersecurity one
of the things we're advocating is we
should be accessing the gaming community
we've got hundreds of thousands of kids
who are engaging in these games
why don't we leverage that why don't we
go after that and try to work with the
gaming community to build cybersecurity
into the games and then go to them when
they're 8 9 10 11 and say you know you
can make your whole living doing this
kind of thing it's cool and advertise
you know and put up attractive models we
have a certain one of my members is the
center for equality it was a similar
problem to cybersecurity everybody
thinks this Center for what's right what
it quality okay so the auditors they
have a real problem getting people to
want to be auditors because it looks
really boring and so what they've done
is they've done an advertising program
where they get really attractive
cool-looking good-looking people to be
their spokespeople and little kids look
at oh yeah I want to be like that I mean
we're supposed to be good at marketing
you know but we do not market
cybersecurity we should be marketing at
a young age yeah very good kisser
even it happens even before we have to
market it I think it's this is about a
culture right and when yeah when we look
at our students and when we look at what
we're doing right now in the schools we
are giving children iPads in first grade
to teach them how to read we're giving
them Chromebooks to teach them how to
write to do math there is no reason why
when they get that they shouldn't be
educated on what it means I think that
goes to Stefan's point when we talk
about creating a culture it is very
difficult the same way it is difficult
to both on security to a to a product at
the end it's extremely difficult to bolt
on security to a mindset we all know
from languages if you learn a language
when you're born and you can learn two
or three very easily at a young age it's
a lot more difficult to learn that
second language when you're 30 35 40 it
actually exponentially increases by 10
years when we think about in the United
States recycling and Comp
those are the kids right now that are
teaching the adults because they're
learning it in school it has been a part
of how they're learning and how they've
been been raised when we think about
cybersecurity where our responsibility
lies is teaching our children at a very
young age we've already made the
decision to bring the technology into
the classrooms there's absolutely no
reason why we shouldn't be bringing the
security into the classrooms the point
that was raised earlier though was how
do you get the teachers to be trained to
teach them that I think that's a very
important issue and we need to be
focusing on that but there is basic
cyber hygiene that continues to be the
source of so much vulnerability across
industry that actually could be taught
to a first-grader about authentication
and what it means to be secure and what
you do when you log on and log off that
we're still trying to teach adults and I
think that that elementary education
piece is what's been very missing in
most societies I don't want to I don't
want to do is out of a possible repeat
appearance and they say it's conference
but maybe you should have some school
children as a panel talking about their
attitudes you know I'm a I am serious
I'm not we should drop the dress code I
needed to get a suit for here I ever
think geek t-shirt with me and I wanted
to come with jeans and then see business
code business whatever not business
casual so thank you very much next time
would be fine do you have any thoughts
on what on generally I want to come back
to it to thinking about like our users
and and as we're talking about humans
right like it's certainly very very true
what we need to invest in educating
people and then early on I agree with
that right about cyber hygiene about the
important elements what they need to
know I think it's also important that we
give them the tools and the products as
well they can actually do that in a
reasonable way right one of the things
that we have been developing in my group
is what we call the security checkup and
we are seeing that like 700 million
users per year are actually doing that
whether we are going prove is like three
to five minute thing and to actually
check on where security preferences and
and and the idea there is not bad but
you have to be an expert to actually
adjust all of these settings but we are
giving you kind of a head
this way of saying like you think this
is better for you and and this is the
choice but you should be making and this
is the choice that you should not be
making everything this is insecure right
and I think we can do a lot more to
actually help out our users so that it's
part of a system - right it's not on the
user and on cyma hygiene only but it
also needs to be in the design of the
system
well we forget who it was Matt even
Julian mentioned the Internet of Things
and the growing you know oh no I think
it was Alexander mentioned the need to
have security by design built in even
more important now that we've got you
know all sorts of devices attached I
mean that how how would you feel that we
should do that I mean the stories of
people having their security setting the
passwords of zero zero zero zero one two
three four on devices attached to the
Internet of Things boom what should we
do in order to get that culture out into
the wider community of Internet of
Things suppliers and devices so and I
think as I said I think we can do a
number of technological steps as well to
make people aware of weak passwords
things that are kind of bad hygiene
right getting bit out into a wider
community of suppliers and I think that
requires an effort all across the
industry right it's basically sync on
what is kind of the standard that we
want to have for passwords all across
right here we are living in a world
where most of the breaches which we are
seeing are coming from things like
collection one writes databases of pests
but username/password
dumps right that is still the most of
the breaches source of most of the
pitches that we are seeing for our users
accounts as passed by Thomas where the
same password was used all across and
and I think we can actually get rid of
that by making people aware of it and
also by having a standard of like what
it should be for an account in any kind
of scenario I mean we we said we talked
about staff and then users and so it's
it's good we've got we've got onto users
I mean I'm interested in
this point about not putting too big a
burden on the users and it ties back to
your point I mean the the sort of
economic cost of you could also think in
terms of the hassle cost being an
economic factor if we if we say if you
want to be secure it's going to take you
ten minutes before you load up you know
we'll get going how do we deal with this
issue of making it easy to be secure as
well as secure by design first some
other statements I think we should start
with pupils with really with the kids
where don't agree what you've done in
the upload shop with the iPhone and I
think they could just got the defaults
wrong so we have to convince Apple to
get the come to work on defaults right
from the very beginning but what I still
wonder you mentioned awareness-raising
I'm doing awareness-raising training and
in-depth training and posters and videos
and online courses and games and serious
gaming and so on why do I have to be at
the cost why do I have to be the cost to
teach this to adults why are the kids
are not learning this and if you
remember this risk equation there's also
the vulnerability part there are two
products worldwide and this is not for
me
somebody said some women where I'm as
the end user I'm using Internet of
Things device and all the things for
buying everything digital why do I need
to be at the cost for security there's a
second product so why on software and
hardware security I have to pay and not
the producer and where's the second
product drugs so this doesn't work
together so I'm wondering where are the
government's I don't need to have
certification because this is just one
one time thing where the government's
starting with enforcing back bounty
programs so I don't know whether you are
running back bounty programs but I think
government should enforce this and I
tell you why for the financial incentive
and there might be a long discussion
says here's my proposal you oblige
companies who producing hardware
software to pay $100 if I find a
cross-site scripting vulnerability in
that one 1005 square injection 10,000
for he just fixed by catalog and the
owner of the software has to pay to the
first finder so now the company has a
choice invest the money in paying me
fine invest the money in the third-party
company doing security for them or
investing in their own processes
of course is not $100 it's proportional
to the distribution of the software and
for open-source and that's the bad news
is government needs to jump in so hope
and sauce government has to pay but I
think this would give all the script
kiddies all the youngsters who would
like to do security and incentive
because cash counts it will even give
some of the script kiddies a chance to
not sell on the undie on the black
market but coming to the legal world
thoughts about this then low because it
does seem to me you said people don't
want to pay for security and if you
followed that model the software would
just cost more wouldn't it because i
haven't analyzed that model it's an
interesting idea i'd like to think about
it but what i can take so we have
thought a lot about incentives and and
indifferent incentives will work for
different groups you know and i think
more at an industrial level rather than
a consumer level but for example and
what we advocate is what we need to do
is rebalance the economic model so that
it is in the organization's best
interest profit motive to build security
in so let's take IOT for an example it's
a big problem and an ADD model is by the
way we have incentives throughout the
economy in all sorts of different areas
that we haven't applied to cybersecurity
for example in pharmaceuticals least in
the u.s. in pharmaceuticals if if you
have a good track record with regard to
the safety of your drugs you get access
to a fast track method for patent
approval this is incredibly valuable you
know you're getting quickly to market is
really important and you're just on the
fast track it's not like you get through
automatically but you get to go first in
line why don't we give first in line to
people why don't we have a similar sort
of model for IOT devices where if you
have a good security record you get a
fast track with your next product coming
by now we've got the companies wanting
to to maintain this we could do the same
in regulated industries with audits if
if you know any of these industries I
can't stand on it so hey they're
expensive they're boring they're blah
blah blah blah they hate them you know
and they're really expensive and a lot
of times you have to do couple most
constant auditing how about if you get a
really
good audit you don't have to do one the
next year or the next quarter whatever
then you've got an incentive to keep up
that really good security record because
you don't want to go back into the old
system where you're doing wallets
quarterly as opposed to annually and
these I'm just offering us models
without going into details yeah back and
forth but I think that there are all
sorts in agriculture aviation ground
transport pharmaceuticals defense even
in security the Safety Act should be
applied better to cyber that we can just
take and apply to cyber security put our
fields are so young we haven't done that
yet Thank You April Walter the model
mice Harry you wanted to come in because
I'm a political scientist I don't
believe in economic model actually well
so one thing I want to take is a
reputation cause that's important so if
you lose a face in cybersecurity
so-and-so
companies the people are very very
frustrated so losing a face is a very
important factor but so hiding I drunk I
don't believe it in because it's very
difficult so these are people who care
security here in this room but I believe
more than 20% of the people do not
washing your hands in restaurant I'm
always watching people in security
conferences so people do not wash hands
so it's but people don't care so that's
important things so you can name it oh
you didn't wash your hands that's a
reputation of course that's the most
important thing okay Kirsten don't eat
the peanuts I think one of the things we
also have to appreciate is we talk as if
there's nothing happening and there's
clearly a lot happening and I know we're
gonna hear from Terry Halverson later
from Samsung I mean look at the products
that are out there that are doing this
well there are products that are out
there that are taking a look at this
what we haven't done well is cut across
the IOT space I think one of the
interesting pieces and we heard this
earlier that we're talking about digital
security for critical infrastructure and
we talked about data data is our most
critical asset right now and data is
held on everybody's device every
buddy holds critical data in their own
way we have to be thinking about how to
secure that data and also as we're
looking at these interdependencies
recognizing that we don't draw the line
at critical infrastructure
interdependencies IOT mean that our
critical infrastructure is linked to
that which is not critical and so when
we look across our culture when we look
across security we have to do a better
job at looking at as Alexander was
talking earlier whole-of-government
whole of culture whole of Commerce
because we're trying to secure the
digital economy which is an intersection
of industry government nonprofit
academia all these other elements and
we've got to be looking at that without
distinguishing and differentiating our
own models for security because it all
requires a baseline level in order to
raise the bar for security across the
board I'm I'm gonna if it's ok with you
because we started a little bit late I
will aim to finish at 22 which gives us
just over a little a little over 15
minutes hope that's okay
and I promised the panel that this
audience was a really engaged audience
with great questions and I'd like to
give you the opportunity to maybe make a
few of those points so art if you've got
some if you've got some questions or
points you want to make let me know but
just before we do that most Hiro when we
were talking earlier in preparation for
this panel you refer to the cyber
warriors of China and North Korea now
you've hinted a little bit about their
you know how no North Korea goes about
the cyber warriors and so thinking about
that third group of people the the bad
actors what insights can you give us
into the cyber warriors and among the
bad guys that we might not know about
yeah I'm running a gjk I trucked to a
conference so China Japan Korea truck to
sort of scholars dialogue but we learned
that people say so cyber attacks coming
from China but there are five types of
people in China
so first frustrated young young people
so they graduate from the Beijing
University or chinfa University but they
cannot get a job so they are very
frustrated so they are having found to
attack foreign countries the second is
economic spies but actually so they are
so the Chinese are fighting with the
Chinese
Chinese companies are fighting with
Chinese they are stealing information a
lot and so we our foreign governments
foreign companies also victims the third
is political spies
so spies under the Ministry of State
Security they never stopped cyber
espionage so they are just using cyber
technologies in addition to existing
technologies and force is PLA so people
Liberation Army see but they are not
using the final card yet so they are
preparing for future war and finally so
the mass analyst all yours so you can be
hired by anyone so they do not care any
victims as they can do not care any
employee employers so it's very
difficult to distinguish these five
types of people so we do not say it's
coming from China or Chinese person or
Chinese company it's quite a difficult
to divulge you differentiate these types
of people in as much as you can or are
able to reveal I mean are you you taking
any particular steps to defend against
the bad actors I mean is this the sort
of intelligence that you might be
deploying as much as you prepared to say
I mean it is a bad actors on the rises
it's something that's becoming more
important to you yeah absolutely I mean
we're not talking about details but it's
obviously and there has always been an
arms race and one of the things that we
are definitely seeing is the
sophistication of the attacks is growing
and it's growing drastically and I
hinted at bad it's not only for for like
very special targets but it's also
growing all across right I said like
everybody here in this room can get fish
right phishing attacks are growing
massively we block about in Gmail we
block about 10 million emails per minute
but are not reaching the inbox but as
the sophistication level is growing
right there is messages that are very
very hard even with machine learning
technology and everything that we have
to defend against and so the the
sophistication level is something that
we are seeing is clearly on the rise and
that is a hard work that we have to do
and when you're not tearing your hair
out about the students so you've done
quite a good job on that by the way and
when you're not tearing your hair else
about the students do you spend a lot of
your time worrying about really bad
actors if I worry then of course I worry
swell we are permanently I'm not
attacked like everybody else in this
room and we're just following this
malformed the problem with Malcolm is
you don't know how long it do it didn't
take you and what's the path is so we're
trying to adapt again and again again
we've seen the whole spectrum we see
script kitties and the white hats which
are just poking our systems you have
retraining even students poking all
systems and then you got cyber criminals
fishing one acquires been mentioned
before but we have seen up to our nation
states of hacking us for one of the
other reasons and then you have to see
no it's the arms race how much money do
we have to defend and where you have to
stop in also you have to accept that
CERN is we're coming every year 15,000
scientists from every country this one's
world students professors physicists
engineers secretaries technicians from
all over the from all over the world any
country and I'm saying literally any
country maybe not North Korea but all
the others so I can't do any background
checks on those people this is
technically impossible for me and even
in the academic world is not appreciated
during this so I have already certain
people on site just by statistics who
might have an evil intend against my
organization so and this is something I
have to face with this for physical and
cyber land that meets and this is the
idea hoddan that I'm facing remotely it
has to go in somewhere if you on the Sun
side you got much more possibilities so
um I hope you think that that has been a
valuable discussion ladies gentlemen and
got the first panel off to a good start
you will all take different things away
from it I with a few random things I
took away from it five types of bad guys
in China I mean could be anywhere else
but I mean I think that's quite a good
categorization I've always liked the
idea of incentives of one form or
another not necessarily financial ever
since I read the book about nudge you
know about how to change people's
behavior by using the appropriate
incentives it's not just about
regulation despite what we might think
here very commonly in Europe it's not
just about financial incentives there
are other incentives too but the
really most of all I took away from it
get rid of your ties stop wearing dark
suits and let's try and make it cool so
that's out of a job so thank you very
much ladies and gentlemen
[Applause]
[Music]