[Music]
I hope that we can avoid a complete
meltdown despite the title that you've
chosen this year but I do have to
recognize that in the 12 months since we
were last together quite a lot has
happened and some of it is quite
challenging the cyber threat landscape
has changed significantly the security
challenges we face from cyber attacks
and other cyber enabled threats have
continued to evolve and have continued
to grow we find ourselves battling to
prevent our elections from being
interfered with combating attempts at
manipulation through the malicious use
of disinformation but the topic which
has grabbed the most headlines so far
this year in 2019 is in some ways an
even bigger challenge how best protect
our digital critical infrastructure an
issue that goes beyond the simple
question of whether or not we should
allow who our way to build our 5g
networks what we need to think about is
how do we strengthen our digital
resilience as a whole digital resilience
after all is crucial for protecting
government information industrial
research intellectual property business
plans elections and democratic
institutions as well as protection of
our personal data and to do this we need
to protect that digital infrastructure
the essential plumbing of our modern
connected lives fight G but also the
cloud and AI at present as as you know
European companies collectively have
about 30% of the 5g market that's good
but some but they're challenged they're
more expensive than the competition
meanwhile more than 90% of our IT
devices are made in Asia notably in
China and China control 70%
global supply of the critical raw
materials you need to make those devices
US and Chinese investment in AI de
wharfs European investment for example
France has just declared a program which
is very welcome
investing 1.5 billion euros in AI over
the same time scale a single city in
China
changjun is investing 13.5 billion euros
this kind of dependency inevitably
creates risks and vulnerabilities
the US has moved protect its own cutting
edge technologies often using the
Committee on foreign investments and us
screening process its reacted to the new
Chinese National Intelligence law which
is you know obliges Chinese companies to
work with Chinese intelligence by
banning US government agencies from
using who are wäôre said teehee and is
encouraging other countries to do
likewise China for its part has long
guarded and controlled access to its
domestic market while vigorously
pursuing international expansion in
infrastructure real as well as digital
so in my view it's high time for Europe
to make some choices it's time to
discuss whether we want to continue as
now to see our own cutting-edge
technologies sold off one after another
we also need to consider whether it
makes sense for individual countries to
let out there 5g spectrum with little or
no coordination on what others are doing
which inevitably risks allowing one
dominant supplier to emerge across the
continent better coordination would also
help our collective investment in AI and
other vital technologies quantum
computing cryptography and others to be
more than the sum of its parts and these
issues raise raise challenges around
national decision-making which won't be
easy to resolve trying to protect
everything won't work we need to decide
what really matters in terms of the
digital ecosystem and whether greater
transparency
see around suppliers supply chains for
an investment is enough to offset the
security risks it may be that some
pieces of backbone digital
infrastructure are simply too critical
to risk again these issues are
inherently geopolitical so the solutions
in my view need to reflect Europe's
particular perspective based around
keeping markets open and trade fair
security concerns are not an excuse for
arbitrary protectionism but equally we
can't ignore them
these aren't issues that can be settled
overnight we're going to need time to
debate and develop a comprehensive
approach but we should also be asking
ourselves what can be done now already
using the terms and conditions and the
instruments that we already have in
place first the EU has approved a
cybersecurity act which is going to
reinforce the mandate of the EU
cybersecurity agency to better support
Member States in tackling cyber security
threats and attacks the Act also
establishes an EU framework for
cybersecurity certification boosting the
cybersecurity of online services and
consumer devices I think we can expect
5g infrastructure Internet of Things
devices to be an important part of the
agency's work salute the head of the
agency who's sitting here with us second
under the directive on security of
network and information systems the so
called NIST directive all member states
have to adopt a national strategy
defining the objectives and appropriate
appropriate policy and regulatory
measures this includes designating at
least one competent authority to monitor
the application of the directive at
national level and to nominate a point
of contact to liaison ensure
cross-border cooperation across the
European Union third the foreign direct
investment screening regulation yes
Europe's got one too
once it's in force will allow the
Commission of member states to cooperate
in their assessment of security risks
raise specific concerns posed by foreign
investments including in digital
infrastructure fourth the II use rules
on procurement while they don't
differentiate between EU and non-eu
companies do include a number of
safeguards including measures to protect
essential security interests reciprocity
is another key issue the EU actively
pursues new opportunities for European
companies by ensuring reciprocity and
international procurement markets and
while the rules don't cover the
provision of communication networks they
do cover the equipment used to build
those networks fifth the European
electronic communications code agreed
last summer will boost investment in
very high capacity networks across the
EU including facilitating the rollout of
5g by making Co investment rules more
predictable promoting sustainable
competition and again our security
these instruments give Member States the
opportunity the scope to take action to
better protect our critical digital
infrastructure but it also requires the
political will to act it's important
that we're gonna have to continue this
discussion we need to consider all of
these elements if we're going to face up
to this challenge as far as the
Commission is concerned we will continue
to push this agenda and work as closely
as we can with the Member States
meanwhile we're faced with with some
other challenges as well the pernicious
threat from the use of disinformation
and the manipulation of data and
behavior particularly important in
relation to the security of our
elections and democratic processes
malicious actors both state and
non-state are increasingly using digital
tools to seek to interfere in our
democratic processes and to manipulate
public opinion the European Parliament
elections are now just a few short
months away and I'm afraid they present
a particularly tempting target that's
why we've called on the Internet
companies back in April last year to
take urgent actions through a voluntary
code of practice the code was eventually
agreed in September
and we followed that up with an action
plan on disinformation at the end of
last year in the longer term we're going
to need to do more to ensure media
diversity and to build critical
awareness we're going to need to
continue to improve media literacy for
example through using tools like the
news guard browser which utilizes a team
of journalists to check the credibility
of news media against a transparent list
of criteria in order to give credible
sites a green tick and potential sources
of disinformation a red cross it helps
to give users a sense of the provenance
of what it is that they are seeing but
we also need to look at other sorts of
more immediate action we need to see an
improvement in how we detect and call
out examples of disinformation the
Commission has something called the
Stratcom task force that does that work
we're building something called the EU
hybrid fusion cell which will reinforce
it we need to continue to reinforce our
work with the Member States and we are
building a new disinformation rapid
alert system in advance of those
European Parliament elections and we
need to see the Internet platforms step
up and make real progress on the
commitments that they signed up to in
the code of practice those commitments
include urgent improvement in how
adverts are placed online greater
transparency around sponsored content
rapid and effective identification and
deletion of fake accounts clearer rules
around bots though personally I don't
know why we allow bots to circulate
political information at all more
effective promotion of alternative
narratives greater clarity around how
the algorithms are operating in the
political space all of this subject to
independent oversight and audit last
month we published a report on the
progress that was being made against
these objectives which recognized that a
lot of good work had been done but also
underline the concerns that we still
have about the slow pace of progress
we're going to need to go further and
faster
if these efforts are to have the
required impact needed ahead of the
European parliamentary elections in May
we're going to report every month
between now and then frankly to maximise
the pressure and get progress in the
time remaining we're also continuing to
implement our proposals from 2017 to
address the more classic cybersecurity
threats targeting systems and data we're
continuing to roll out the new
cybersecurity strategy in order to build
our resilience strengthen deterrence and
sport member states in cyber defense
that includes the creation of a genuine
European cyber security agency as I
mentioned as well as a network of
competent centers to improve our
resilience and target our research we've
taken important steps on deterrence to
create real and credible disincentives
for those who might contemplate
attacking us including improving law
enforcement access to electronic
evidence we've put in place a set of
measures for a joint EU diplomatic
response to malicious cyber activities
which includes working together with
third countries and the possibility of
restrictive measures indeed we're now in
the process of refining a cyber six
actions regime and working to tackle
some of the challenges around for
example attribution our efforts to
strengthen cyber security across the
European Union whether in the short
medium or long term need to continue
whatever happens in the European
elections whatever happens with a new
commission whatever happens around
brexit the malicious actors who seek to
harm us are not going anywhere
and it's only by working together all
across Europe that we can successfully
tackle these threats and avoid the risk
of a security melter thank you thank you
very much
[Applause]
[Music]