[Music]
very much and welcome to the spot-on
panel
I've been moderating the spot-on panel
for a few years and I just realized it's
my first spot-on panel without Eugene
Kaspersky so he will be he will be
deeply missed but we have stellar
replacements here we have Bruce of
course from the Belfer Center at Harvard
University I attended the Kenny school
myself and during my time as a student
there was always instructed never to
challenge the guy from Bell fair because
they literally think about nuclear
counter strikes every single day so
looking forward they are scary people
and of course we have Bruno from the
Vulcan anomic forum who has been working
on IT infrastructure and challenges in
the 2d IT infrastructure for more than
20 years and is also the graduate of an
equally scary institutions that I called
a gear economic so on Bruce we want to
start with you I mean the people here
the organizer of the conference told me
not to be too gloomy and then I came
across one of your latest publications
and the title is click here to kill
everybody security and survival in a
hyper-connected world are we going to
wipe our civilization with a few clicks
hopes not I mean but the title does
speak to something that we are all
talking about here that in fact as we
become more computerized as we become
more interconnected that these
catastrophic failures will happen and
we're talking here about how to deal
with that and I like hearing the
discussions about supply chain because
that is truly an insurmountable hard
problem we even get into the how hard it
was I like talking about incentives and
regulations and ways we can improve
hygiene about users because we are
moving into a world where everything is
interconnected everything is vulnerable
in ways that we are not expecting the
failures we we think are not what are
not what's gonna happen but does that
mean that the line between online and
offline is becoming increasingly blurry
I
don't think there is a line anymore so
we kind of cross one line when we move
to these things remember when you used
to like enter a chatroom and upload and
download and go online it was something
you did now it's something you are doing
all the time and then this is gonna
change because this is still something I
go to it's got a screen it's got a
keyboard but the computers of tomorrow
to relieve today and tomorrow the IOT
computers are something that's in our
environment there are thermostats our
appliances the the lights here and so
and it's fully immersive so it's not a
place we go to anymore it's a place
where in so that that line is already
blurred would you agree bro I mean you
have been working on infrastructure for
a long time
yes if a connectivity bill dependents
for societies on this device and data
are dependents but today is if you
remember the theme of Davos this year
globalization for the 0 building new
architecture I do believe that
cybersecurity is a good topic where we
need to refocus on a new path and we
need to change a culture on security and
and to embodies a culture from H but to
change that culture do you have the
impression that people even use the same
language that table for example policy
makers and techies like you can even
talk to each other this is actually
something I've been thinking about a lot
this is this this idea that we actually
need tech and policy to talk to each
other and you'll see this that if you
watch the u.s. face book hearings it's a
great example of policy makers having no
idea one didn't have them person up
there understood yet they are expected
to effectively regulate this platform we
see this in the debate about backdoors
the going dark debates where
regularities where government people say
we want this and techie say well that's
just not possible and they say well try
harder say well that's not how it works
so we are seeing a lot of these debates
in cybersecurity so actually in
technology at large bridge tech and
policy and we need
them together I'll talk about that more
later near the end but then is really
important and I want is I like to come
to forums like this like to see techies
at forums like this because we have to
be here well that's why we are here yeah
but I wanted to bring in Bruno because
you started a year ago with the World
Economic Forum you built this new
platform there I think we to around 20
people now and isn't that what you have
focused on to change the dialogue yes
not only not only for policy making is
we need meaningful information that can
be understood from decision maker which
is what leaders see suit of bots they do
not understand fully what cyber risk are
and what could be the impact on the
organization's on this stage so we need
to be able to change the narrative how
those people talk especially as you said
take ease and the organization and if
you look at the Missis straight
landscape reports of this year this is
one of the points so it cyber threat
intelligence cannot be understood by
decision-makers so how can you make a
decision if you don't understand mmm you
mentioned the face book here and I think
we all realize that we are not
particularly competent on that issue but
isn't there a bigger dial armor that the
government doesn't want the internet
really to be secure because it makes it
much easier to supervisor or to snoop
isn't that one of the problems or the
national problems in the dialogue
between techies and government I think
this is a huge problem you saw some of
it in that opening talk by the UK
diplomat who talked all about how we
need to design security in and how
important it is to make sure things are
designed securely at the same time the
government that same government is
trying to make sure that things are not
designed securely that they can be
eavesdropped on now these are both
important equities but the debate is not
happening at that policy level and so I
mean I'll describe it is you've got one
world one infrastructure may you can
choose when you build the 5g network to
make it secure so that nobody can
eavesdrop or you can make it insecure so
that everybody can use drop I get that
you want to eavesdrop and then you
don't want anyone else to but that's not
an option so when we talk about
designing security in we need to
understand what that means that means
yes we will lose intelligence
capabilities now you have to decide
that's worth it because right you know
every one of my legislators carries one
of these and it's kind of scary that
lots of people are you dropping on it
now I'm are we willing to give up
eavesdropping on the bad guys so this is
a policy debate informed by tech that is
the correct debate to have I can't
answer it and we need to have this
conversation but do you have the
impression because you have these
discussions do people talk past each
other do we increasingly talk with each
other on that issue
totally past each other maybe this very
little tech informed policy dialogue in
my space come change my vulnerabilities
do you think it's better in Europe no
it's just two completely what people
started for me estates what they want
they want prosperity economic prosperity
and stability in for their country so
building back doors is going against
arts so I don't believe that country
which is democratic and advanced would
push Australia UK so you want to keep
going the u.s. yes so more and more the
cities and we put pressure on being sure
that those infrastructure are secure
no bad rules and we should advocate for
this and in Europe we do that but when
you discuss that with people in Europe
you have the impression that they are
more receptive than for example US
policymakers yes and this affects
everything so here's two stories in the
news last four days so you can hack
construction cranes right those giant
things that move tons of heavy stuff
around you can hack those and like fling
those about two days ago I learned you
can hack refrigerators in supermarkets
turn off you know make them go hot
so here's two random IOT things which
are like stupidly insecure easily
hackable they're gonna be around for
decades and then this is the kind of
vulnerability we're living in and those
aren't exceptions those happen to be the
two that researchers looked at last week
it's not gonna not gonna be any
different for anything else but you we
mentioned the role of government but
then we have these huge institutions
private institutions like Facebook and
we were supposed to have Alex Thomas
here on the panel who fell sick
unfortunately but who left Facebook
because he was not convinced that they
really wanted to clean up their act I
mean Facebook you didn't leave because
they were incompetent ok interstate most
a little bit here ok well but you want
to maybe elaborate on the role of these
institutions together I think you call
that the surveillance capital
surveillance capitalism is a term by
Shoshanna Zubov she teaches at Harvard
Business School her book is fantastic I
recommend that everybody go by and read
it and use the term constantly and she's
talking about really a new market driven
force based on collecting and using our
data and it's permeating every industry
you know not just Facebook when Facebook
and Google are the poster children for
surveillance capitalism but you know
when you buy your connected refrigerator
it's collecting data on what you're
doing with it and it's gonna use that to
try to upsell you to try to and I'm
gonna sell that day to third parties is
that a term you would use at the World
Economic Forum so variants capitalism I
hope so yes no to build on security by
design is never ending story that we
want to push for better design
especially better cybersecurity from the
early design but this is still not there
and we need to transform cybersecurity
into a competitive advantage for
organizations so if you look at the the
new cybersecurity Act
cybersecurity framework from last year
yes yeah that is going to it's going to
be developed so this is a very strong
incentive for organizations to to add a
and to to go through a certification
that would demonstrate that their
product is better to another one and
this is hard I mean for facebook
security kind of isn't a competitive
advantage I mean being able to spy on
their users as a competitive advantage
that's how they make money
Equifax right the big data broker hack
the United States couldn't care less
about the security of its users because
I can't fire Equifax I mean they'd
collect my data that my knowledge or
consent
all right Siemens sitting in this chair
I mean it would make sense to say right
Romania our new industrial controllers
the Americans can't destroy your
centrifuges now right that is a
competitive advantage and if they say
that that's gonna be worth something but
but but by and large we've been trying
to make security competitive ants for a
bunch of decades and we've been failing
I liked all the talk up here about
regulation it's all about incentives and
if there isn't gonna be a rate you the
market this is what you got you can hack
the construction cranes that's the
market solution you don't like it we
need to raise the cost of insecurity
you're a bunch of ideas up there about
liabilities and regulations standards
those are all but if you work if you're
a skeptical of regulation what can be
done I mean do we have our only
ourselves to blame eventually them
because we as consumers except that they
are so I mean I tend to think people
scapel relations just like to pretend
but they still go out to eat at
restaurants right they still fly in
airplanes they still drive in cars
they're not actually worried this
building will collapse on their heads
regulations are gonna come house
societal the crane times right yeah
regulations are how society functions
when we can't ourselves be experts right
I boarded a Lufthansa plane yesterday
and I did not check the engines I
wouldn't even know how to write I relied
on both German and US regulations
ensure that I would have a nice safe
comfortable flight and the pilot be
trained and rested and all of those
things so there really isn't any
solution other than regulations and that
doesn't mean you must do this you can't
do that it's flexible standards it's
much more complex it's liabilities and
for airline security it's a competitive
advantage actually it is not you you
never seek Airlines competing on
security rightfully right fly our
airline we do full body searches on
everybody right fly our airline
everybody carries a gun so you don't
worry right you never see those slogans
security and air and Airlines want this
they want it not to be their problem
when something happens they do not want
to be blamed
they want the sided blame the country
blamed but not the airline not the
aircraft we had the Airbus person here
mate they're not competing on security
of a flight they are totally pushing
that to the government sorry yes to go
in that direction is we have to simplify
cyber security for consumer on customers
that's a fact is the same as as you said
for taking a plane I will not check the
engine so it's always a user ability
versus server security why do we use
still password today 2019 why do we
still design system whose password we
keep saying password is not safe and
we're still building systems and this is
hard we talked about on stage about
educating the user users are hard to
educate and and it's a couple of things
if you look at real education first for
people it's simple things that are
actionable wash your hands all right I
can do it it works
it can't be complex it can't be subtle
and a lot of times certainly in the tech
industry we blame the user so think of
the kind of advice we give users don't
plug in a strange USB stick kind of dumb
advice of that it's a USB stick what am
I gonna do with it don't click on a link
there links
don't open an attachment but it's an
attachment I mean these are all failures
of the tech system why in the world
should plugging a USB stick be a
vulnerability because USB was designed
and securely why should it be that
clicking on a link are opening an
attachment isn't in security because the
operating system is designed badly don't
blame the user for bad tech decisions in
your writings you are pretty down on
technologies such as cryptocurrency
blockchain as well pretty much because
you think that you can have trust in
tech and institutions only in people or
supply chains complicated but I just
wrote an essay appearing wired last week
where I kind of said that is like
absolutely nothing here there's no value
here so all the people who have been
sold a bill of goods you can relax for
the neurons Bateman yes it is a bill of
goods and it'll go away soon don't worry
about it and it's a complicated
discussion of how you really can't
replace trust with verification and you
can't replace institutions with code and
any system where if you make a mistake
you lose your life savings is
fundamentally not trustworthy it doesn't
matter how good the encryption is I have
to be there's no choice I'm dead surely
that in the industry we try to develop
solutions which are secure for the
people etc but at some point that's true
that it can be broken it can be obsolete
etc but what is important is to design
it from the from the beginning right
from the design phase
obviously innovation has to go fast and
many steps taking into account
cybersecurity is not taken into account
still today so this is the main issue I
want to come back to that dialogue that
you mentioned when you look at
institutions like Harvard Law School so
twenty thirty percent of the graduates
go into public
service law because even though it's I
mean they make much less money but they
think it's worth it and they are doing
something meaningful is also encouraged
by the professor's so the number of tech
people going into pro bono work is lower
so this is hard right and if you think
about public interest law it is a thing
if you're a public interest lawyer your
mother is proud of you and you go work
for an institution working for the
government you're working for the people
and you're making less money and he's
right right now 20% of the graduating
Harvard Law School class doesn't go work
for a corporation or a law firm goes to
work for public interest law and last
year Harvard had a seminar because that
number is so low the number of computer
science graduates who do this is
basically zero and yes there's certainly
because let me go off first though
because they don't want he's a couple of
things I mean I I think there's there's
not a lot of demand you know right now
the number of technologists on
congressional staffs is extraordinarily
small the United States I mean I don't
think it's better in any European
country that the number of technologists
working at some of these NGOs is very
small there are the opportunities and
also there isn't this the supply there's
this there's isolated instances but not
enough people and this feels important
so here's the way I so I now teach to
the Kennedy School which is kind of kind
of neat or I'm a techie teaching public
policy the Kennedy School in the 20th
century the fundamental question of
society was how much of our lives should
be governed by the market and how much
by the state that define second of 20th
century and that's why the Harvard
Kennedy School was populated with
economists because they could answer
those sorts of questions
I think the defining question of this
century is how much of our lives should
be governed by technology and under what
rules so you need more technologists
doing public policy to answer that
question and if cybersecurity an AI and
future of work and climate change and
bioengineering and food safety we can go
on and on
these are all deeply technical issues
but do the techies understand to the
same extent that politics is difficult
no I mean it's gotta go both ways right
I mean why we have this disconnect in
both directions right techies I mean you
heard the media heard the techie answer
to solving cybersecurity more bug bounty
programs and that's a great techy answer
it fails in policy but as a techie
that's a perfect answer sorry if you
stole in the room you work for an
institution that is basically trying to
change that I mean when you started your
institution or not but your Center
how did you attract people to work for
the forum on this issue man there's a
wider issue in cybersecurity skill
shortage as a whole in general so I
believe that around 3 million by 2021
in a skill shortage and this is not only
in Europe or North America but it's also
across the planet in Africa in Latin
America in Asia and and the problem is
how we build programs which are in
university program which are flexible
enough and close enough to the private
the mountain profit sector demand and
how we attract those people to to follow
those course and engage into carriers
into what could help me say is worth is
cool I thought that's a given yeah but
that's how are you gonna get people
right yeah but I mean what else could be
done I mean can we bring in foundations
can we bring in technology related
journalism or what what what are all the
options to thank change thank you in the
u.s. at least think foundations will
play a big part I think for a nation
Ford Foundation I mean right now I'm
people gonna go to the RSA conference
next month in California
I am the RSA is letting you a one-day
mini track and Public Interest tech that
Ford Foundation is funding we have six
panels and bring in people from academia
from industry from NGOs from government
to talk about different ways that
technologists are changing the world not
by building a new tech tool but by
affecting public policy have you met in
u.s. Paul
Jamaica was really tech savvy yes know
him or yeah not a lot of them okay what
about you you European politicians that
you met that are really I've networked X
out of European politicians it's not the
firm has developed the first Industrial
Revolution Center in San Francisco and
the idea is to to bring the tech side to
the policy-making so the from steering
projects around that mobility future of
healthcare blockchain drones etc so
there are the influx of people from the
tech side going to the policy making but
it takes time are there jobs are there
jobs for them in government in the in
the agencies in the legislators this
morning in term of discussion bringing
people together on the table and making
sure that they understand each other and
the understand where they have to go so
if you say we need more techies in
government it would be a good idea if
Zuckerberg ran for president I'm not
sure that's related where he's at
something to do okay thanks so much for
the dialogue and good luck with the next
panel thank you all
[Music]