welcome one and all thank you for
attending this very special class here
at Elphie University I know all of you
are excited for the holiday season we
all have a whole lot of the process
there and present wrapping and reindeer
feeding but we wanted to take a second
to caution everyone reminder that there
are certain risks in the world there are
certain security vulnerabilities and
when you're out and about either doing
the last-minute shopping or delivering
presents from homes or out can
commercial lock in America your keys
covered up and not visible that is
something that we don't talk about
enough but we should I know that
everyone keeps little kids hands on the
candy or on the ribbons and not in your
pockets but it doesn't take someone
physically grabbing your keys for them
to be compromised it is in fact possible
to merely snap a photograph of keys even
at a distance and compromise them copy
them and make your own to open doors and
that's what we're going to talk about
today I am here speaking to you an elf
you because I am part of a covert entry
team I know it doesn't sound like it
would land me on a nice list but I
promise even though we look like we're
being naughty clearly we don't belong in
here
my team and I do this for a living we
evaluate physical security of structures
and part of that involves getting inside
where we're not supposed to be
subverting the defenses and I'm not
going to a kid yeah it's fun it's
absolutely fun when you have permission
to be able to go around security
functions to go around lock doors to get
inside of special rooms it's not a bad
gig if you can get it now there's a lot
of different ways that we can you know
covert or denturri it can be perform
there's a lot of different ways we can
subvert locks and security but the most
basic I want to talk about today has to
do with locks and keys many of us use
our keys we unlock doors we unlock
padlocks we start our cars the key
itself in
most instances as seen in this diagram
what's happening is that the key is
interacting with a series of pins inside
the lock this is an example of a pin
tumbler lock the most common lock you
would ever have on a door a padlock and
so forth and inside that lock there are
a series of different pins in this
diagram we have red pins those are
called key pins we have some blue pins
called driver pins and they all are
exactly the right size to correspond
with the cuts on the blade of the key
that this person is using here and this
person is not on the naughty list
they're the nice person they are the
correct user of this lock and the
bidding on the key that's the cuts on
the key the bitung is correct for this
lock they are an authorized user so
great they can get in with their key
however let's talk about the bidding
values of a key it's not as some people
might think a world of infinite
possibilities any given cut on a key can
only exist in a series of discrete zones
simple discrete possibilities of
different bidding values and every
manufacturer every brand of lock has a
limited set of bidding values and
locksmiths and other parties can look in
their big book of knowledge and you can
look these up here we have a look at a
quick set brand lock you can see the
bidding cuts are always going to be in
very specific positions on the key and
the possible depths those green lines on
the edge are only in very discrete areas
well knowing that knowing that a key can
only have certain cuts and they will be
predictable and repeatable and reliable
that makes them measurable that allows
us to grab a key and get some
information from it now as we said
earlier you don't want to give someone
hands-on access to your key if they're
not authorized imagine what you could do
knowing what I just told you a simple
set of calipers for example that might
be all you need to go ahead and check
the different values of the key
you're it right there you can measure
those cuts because again every brand has
some manufacturers chart that you can
look up in a resource book like a
locksmithing book this key right here
this sergeant brand key well we can see
there a series of possible depths
they're all known values and if we were
to take our calipers on this key that we
found somewhere let's take a look this
first position that we're measuring
right here we've got kind of an O three
eight five well does that does that look
like any of the possible values that we
see in this chart here I don't know
about you but to my eyes 308 point 308
that looks like a value of two so we can
say this first bidding position is a
depth or a bidding cut value of two how
about the next one
we've got 0.28 such as well might be off
by just a hair but I'd say that's really
close to the value of three keep moving
down the key to eight eight again oh
that looks like another three we're
halfway there now we've measured another
1.30 so well well we saw that before
that looks like another value of two and
on and on down the key point two four
eight five where does that look like on
our list yep that's a five depth two
forty eight thousandths
you can quickly walk down the key
getting the bidding out and then once
you're done this note this number that
we have down here that we have
discovered this would be referred to as
the bitung code of the key this is all
you need along with you know the brand
of lock that you're in it that you're
interested in this is all you need to
initiate the creation of a new key you
don't need this piece of brass this
original key to copy a key in every
instance you can originate a brand new
key if you have that bidding value data
and by the way using calipers like this
it's not even the fastest way to get
that data there are what are known as
key gauge cards if you're dealing with a
very common brand so common
that resources like this metal card
exists on the marketplace instead of
adjusting the jaws of a caliper blade
you can slide your key right into this
slot and slip it over in this
stair-stepped metal pattern until it
stops can't go any further okay well
that's it to the next cut you can see on
this key would be much deeper it would
slide a lot further over and it might
stop on seven or eight and you can slip
slip slip slip and crank those numbers
out very quickly so that should
reinforce for us why you never give an
unauthorized person hands-on access to
your keys the fear is not that they
might run to your house and get in the
fear should be well they could easily do
this right behind your back and before
you know it they've got your key values
so you say all right I'm gonna get
myself a nice carabiner keychain or a
candy cane hook that I can slip through
my belt loop dangle my keys right on my
hip and no one can ever slip them out of
my pocket or take them off my person
because they're literally attached to me
that's great that's a good first step
but let's think about another scenario
what about a situation where someone is
only briefly near you and can very
briefly see your keys now they can't
touch them let's say that carabiner is
clipped right onto your you know your
big black belt under your red suit
however if someone can take a photo of
your keys we can do a very similar
measurement based attack to extract
those bitting values
remember every bitung depth and every
position is a discrete range of
possibilities it is a specific set of
values and using for example a resource
like this something like visual
gridlines you can easily look at the key
and say well clearly that first cut is a
7 the next cut looks like a 5 and on and
on that will get you the bidding code
that will allow you to originate a new
key never even having laid hands on the
source key now of course in a perfect
world if you want that photo to be nice
and crisp
you don't want good lighting
having some graph paper in the
background definitely makes this process
nicer when you're working in your
photography lab trying to line the key
up all crisp we don't all carry graph
paper well some of us do maybe you can
look a stocking stuffer gift idea this
year keeping some little graph paper
cards like this that can live in your
wallet you can slip one of those out
anytime you need it just for a second
but again this is a this is an ideal
scenario where you can touch the key
with your own hands what if you can't
touch the key at all what if the photo
is at an oblique angle what if the key
is on a keyring with many other keys
well a couple things can make your life
easier the best I can offer here a terms
of advice is try to hope and wish put it
on your wish list so that even for a
moment the keys will be separated out so
it's not clustered up with other keys
give yourself a high contrast background
here the brim of this nice black hat
that's a bit of a better photo that will
make this sort of optical duplication
process a little easier but as we're
about to experiment with even a quick
and dirty no effort real slack quick
covert photo with a phone or something
like that you'll be able to make this
work and part of my gift to you this
holiday season is the fact that I have
made template lines for a number of
popular brands of lock and key and
they're all up online they're all for
the taking they're all for you with
holiday cheer
imagine this example here imagine a key
that you can just barely get a glance of
and it's behind something and it's
slightly off kilter and not even in very
good focus if you have any skill in
image manipulation software like
Photoshop or GIMP or something similar
it should be possible to import that
photo to twist it around to get it lined
up nice and true with the grid lines
these grid lines have black bounding
lines on the top and bottom of all of my
diagram lines those represent the
outermost bounds of the Keyblade
now I'm not talking about the outermost
dimension of the key head or the key
itself we're talking about just
the blade just the part that would go
into a lock or just the part that would
go into a key cutting machine if you get
the black lines bounding the blade all
of the other intermediate lines blue and
gray blue and gray blue and gray those
represent even and odd depth values and
all of my lines on my charts do have and
you'll see this when we work later very
small numbers written in there so you
can easily read off the depth values as
you try to line your key up and let's
look at that in this example here this
first bitting cut the first blue line
here is a zero some brands of lock do
have a zero value that's it that is a
real cut but that's clearly not the cut
we're using it definitely doesn't look
like a1 or a2 we've got to keep going
down until we hit five well that looks
pretty good doesn't it the key the cut
of the key that we can see in the
photograph behind these lines seems to
be ended right there
now the next value over the next
position much more shallow of a cut it's
a blue line so we know that it's even
and in fact we know that zero is here
one that looks like a two moving on to
the next position now all of these lines
I can tell you and if we could see the
entire chart you'd see it goes all the
way down to nine is the deepest value
well it's definitely not a nine but it
is a gray number it is an odd number so
what is that nine eight seven the next
position is that a gray or blue well it
looks blue to me looks just a little bit
shallower than that seven because that's
a six and then we have another seven and
then we have another blue out of the
edge here that looks like a two in
almost no time from a very bad source
image in fact we were able to get that
bitung code that is all we need to
originate another copy of this key never
having physically laid hands on the
actual source key the analogy we like to
give be smart out there you wouldn't
hold up your ID just to the world and
say hi take a picture of my personal
information please it's probably also
not a good idea to hold your keys up to
someone who is taking pictures with a
camera you want to avoid leaking that
kind of information now this is all fine
in terms of theoretical world maybe we
can actually try it in the real world
let's see if we go ahead with this
photograph I have a couple of keys right
here
these were just laying on a table I took
a quick picture we have an American
brand padlock and we have a Schlage
brand door key let's start with the
American lock if I want to try to get
this a little bit straightened out
before we get going we'll do a little
more tweaking as we go but that's not
bad as a start okay it looks a little
bit lined up now in our list of lines do
I have an American lock I do all right
let's grab our decoding template for
American locks and let's import the
photograph that we have of a key well
how's it look so far it looks almost
lined up it looks like it's kind of just
slightly tipped down ever so ever so
lightly it's trying to straighten it out
slightly more alright the straightness
looks pretty good but it definitely is
not bounded properly these two black
lines are not correct
we need them to bound the blade of the
key an American lock here's a tip for
you very popular in the government very
popular in some corporate environments
this this beige hump right here this is
not the blade of the key you can barely
see in fact let's go ahead and zoom in
and I'll show you this right here this
lip that is where the key blade starts
if this were a blank key and you can
tell that if we look out at the tip this
is the maximum tip edge of that key this
will become clearer as we start to line
things up let's zoom out a bit here
let's try to increase our size almost
there
all right let's zoom in and take a look
at how that looks pretty pretty close to
me let's see yeah that looks like we're
bounded here we're bounded pretty well
here on the edge well knowing that let's
take a look at what our number values
could be we have our grid lines we have
our first bidding position right here
what line is it lining up with it looks
like it's lining up with this gray line
one up from the bottom the deepest
possible cut is 1/8 this first position
however looks to me like it's a 7
excellent we can even use helpful drag
lines if we're looking here that looks
like we're lined up with a 7 this next
position well a little bit iffy hard to
tell but I say it's closest to this blue
line right here and what's that blue
line lined up with that's lined up with
a 4 value wonderful moving along 3rd
position it's another blue line another
even number what is it that's the 6 and
the next position it looks like that
gray line lines up with a 7 we're almost
there we literally have one position
left it's a little blue line it's out of
the tip and it happens to be a 2 I think
we've done it I think we have been able
to decode this entire key and as it just
so happens we can check our work if
you'd like to how can we check our work
well the American lock company is very
helpful to consumers and locksmiths
alike how helpful are they well they
have a system where you not only get a
very nice brand and stamp on one side of
the key but you get a direct bidding
value on the other now what do we have
here 7 4 6 7 - that looks exactly like
what we just decoded using these
gridlines
outstanding work the process is
functional but that's a little padlock
key might go to something important but
we want to act
we get inside of a door we want to open
up a door with this silver Schlage key
let's try the process they're going to
try to just crop down our space a little
bit so we're not working with such a
giant image all right we're off to a
good start
do we have Schlage in our key decoding
list yes of course we do what would I
what kind of a gift would I be giving
you this holiday season if the most
common commercial lock in America wasn't
part of my suite of tools for you here's
our slate key drag it on over and import
it into our grid line view now of course
we do have to stretch it out so that the
key blade is bounded on either edge by
those black lines and if you say to
yourself look I mean this is all fine
and good but I'm not a powerpoint master
I can't afford the adobe suite of tools
I've never done graphical art before
well no time like the present to learn
something new and again you don't have
to be as good as a photographer running
a photo studio you just have to be good
to be close enough and let's see how
we're looking here this looks this
doesn't look too bad it looks like we've
dipped down just a little bit below that
this shadowy area let me stretch it out
just a hair more so we want to be just
up there a tick more now Oh went way too
far on that one didn't I here's our edge
of our key this is the hardest part just
getting things lined up and the fact
that I'm not perfect I take great
comfort in that and I enjoy that when I
when I show lessons if I don't want to
people to edit things out and say oh
look do you deem did it great the first
time he's perfect out of the gate no I'm
not perfect I don't think no one's
perfect out of the gate we do it as best
we can and we go from there now this
looks pretty good to me I might I might
bump this down oh you know what we have
this black line I'll have to fix this
and you get you get to see you can
submit a pull request or I'll do it this
black line needs a slight tweak because
it's not quite the right distance
heart from its neighbors but maybe we
can correct that just a hair
if we try here I think we are dangling
down a bit
yeah let's bring the tip of this key
there we go that looks that looks a
little bit better to me all right
I like the look of that so we have our
numbers and even if you couldn't read
these numbers we know that blues our
evens and grays our odds
so in this key position first bidding
cut it's definitely not a 0 1 2 I like
to for that first one how about you
let's look at the next bidding position
well it's definitely not a 2 here we've
got 3 I'd say that looks like a 4
definitely could be a 4 ah now quite the
Mindbender here huh
this looks like it's almost in between
two positions not a 4 could be a 5 could
be a 6 well what are we gonna say to
that if you were trying to originate a
copy of the key what I would suggest
start with the 5 and if the lock doesn't
work go ahead and hand file it down to a
6 value fortunately the tip of the key
that doesn't look nearly like such a
conundrum that looks to me like a 3 and
that looks to me like a 3 I'm betting
the last two values or threes so what
did we have there it looked like two
four maybe five or six three three well
why don't we go ahead and test that why
don't we check out and try to see if we
can originate a key that will get the
that'll get a lock open I happen to have
a lock with me right here inside this
lock well I don't happen to have a key
that'll work this is a blank key but we
thought to ourselves to 4 and then
either 5 or 6
three-three might be the key bidding
value to the locks of the key we
photographed we know that key works can
we originate a copy I happen to have a
tool right here that is almost like a
compact pocket version of a key cutting
machine this is called a pack a punch
and it has way down inside if you can
see in here
a tiny nipping jaw that I can actuate
with the large grip handle down here how
do I get that to my advantage how do I
use that in a practical way well if we
look on the top of this large carriage
we can clamp a blank key right into the
front face here line that up nice and
true then this silver carriage can
articulate side to side we can see there
are a series of detents so this will
lock in to any given position we can
work on the first position of the key we
can work on the second position of the
key and so on and so forth there's our
values we can work on the third position
you say oh no but deviant you've
forgotten something's - the key there's
no there's no more values well yeah they
come out the other side we thought of
that four five and so forth so the first
position of the key what did we say it
was a two right well let's dial our cut
depth to two I'm going to hold this key
right here and we'll probably even see a
little bit of brass fall right out the
blade there we are there's our two
second position on the key we said that
value was a four there we go another bit
of cutting the third position that was
the real question wasn't it we're going
to start with a five and if five doesn't
work well we'll try something else there
we are moving on the fourth position on
the key
said that was probably a three we've
dialed it into three and the fifth and
final position on this style of lock
it's only five pins was also a three
here's hoping okay
we have definitely made something looks
looks very key like right moment of
truth are we are we on the naughty list
or have we been nice how about that
right there that is a fully functional
key derived and originated from nothing
but a photograph so yeah don't hold up
your keys to strangers
keep those guarded keep those put away
because you never know if someone
naughty is in the neighborhood and
they've got a sharp eye or a small cell
phone that they might have gotten onto
the Christmas tree this year and if it's
got a good lens on it that's sometimes
all it takes for you to leak information
that you weren't expecting and to reveal
your keys to someone else who can come
along later and get in alright thank you
very much Kringle Khan and thank you
everyone here at elf University I hope
this was a valuable lesson I hope you
start thinking about the keys that you
might be exposing to the world and I
want you to all stay safe out there and
have a very happy and healthy holiday
season Cheers