alright hello everyone and welcome
welcome to elf University thank you for
coming up to spend some quality holiday
Christmas time here with everyone all of
us fellow hackers and Santa and the
elves I'm in fact indebted to Santa
because he was willing to host and let
me speak to all of you here as part of
Kringle con so what I would like to
present to you is five steps to build
and lead a team of holly-jolly hackers
this is all about team building
collaboration and ultimately growing and
sharpening not only your own skill set
but your peers your friends and family
and that's what we all are and our
hacker community we're all family and
while doing this to improve our overall
understanding of security and our
security posture so these steps will be
kind of high-level in nature but I do
hope to go more into how to actually and
actively accomplish these things so step
number zero the title of this talk is a
bit of a falsehood I actually start at
zero and go to five inclusive so it's
actually six but five steps sounds much
cooler and the title than six so this is
step zero because it's a little
self-evident to train a cyber security
team you'll need a space for them to
work in and grow so put together
infrastructure that both digitally and
physically encourages their development
this typically means unfiltered internet
access to a wide range of Technology
most notably Windows and Linux
especially Linux and you'll want to make
this space very cool and very hacker
friendly right so I have toys in there
like a Raspberry Pi Epona gotcha a
rubber ducky security books and
references etc create the environment
that fosters people's excitement and
interest and certainly you want this
space to be collaborative segregated
desks where people aren't working
together that doesn't seem to work as
well you want your peers to tag-team
problems you want to be in a room that's
kind of close together and friendly and
open and inviting with the ability for
yourself and your teammates to work
together
the real step number one is get your
people on a keyboard as fast as you can
that's the first thing you should do
and it should be everything that you do
everything should be hands-on
interactive when you're first starting
out and building your team of people
trying to recruit new people and get
some newcomers engaged
you'll definitely interact with some
individuals that have no idea how to use
a computer right what any of these weird
acronyms are what even is a mouse and a
keyboard that's okay you want to be open
to everyone and not selectively right
you're warm and welcoming so get them on
a command line sit beside them and show
that you want to teach them walk through
each step with them and get them up to
speed
you'll end up teaching a lot of concepts
at the start but you can make all of
these things really fun and engaging
personally I think that active
engagement for learning in real time and
then reinforcement is an awesome way to
teach people things and get these ideas
to stick you should work your hardest to
gamify everything you guys play capture
the flag right so make everything a
capture the flag give your people an
opportunity to one learn something to
practice what they learn and three
always be in complete control of what
they're learning
number two grow a central repository of
training material put things under your
Christmas tree this can take any kind of
form you want right it could be a github
repo it could be a list on a whiteboard
anything but remember the more dynamic
active and engaging that that thing is
the better so for example like a web
portal your team members can have an
account they can interact with
everything related to what your team
does make sure that that central hub is
open and accessible to everyone so each
team member can add and create their own
content and with that constantly look
out for new events that way you can pull
together all those resources that you
might gather from other activities and
exercises that you go to your priority
should be training value do everything
in your power to share experiences with
other people so usually that means
sending the maximum amount of people
pause
to some upcoming events you want to be
thirsting for new events so look on the
internet check the pulse for upcoming
competitions or events stay on top of
b-sides conferences knowing the tickets
go on sale which have CTF competitions
available and try and plan the
availability to go to as many of those
events as you can you as a leader should
create and develop challenges and
training material and make them
available to your people and encourage
others to do the same once someone
breaks the glass ceiling and kind of
creates their own custom homemade
challenge suddenly that excitement will
spread like wildfire because they'll
want to share their challenge with
everyone and others will want to make
their own challenge that is the secret
to fostering group growth and
development now you've got this awesome
feedback loop of training your people
you train your people and then you're
training your people to train the other
people that's super cool step number
three let your team members share their
knowledge now that everyone's educated
and learned up give them the spotlight
let them teach offer opportunities for
each individual to present and showcase
tools techniques vulnerabilities
exploits anything so every Sunday
maybe ping the team slack channel or
tangent that step three-and-a-half
create some kind of slack or discord or
matter most server or any kind of
communication method so that you can
keep in contact with your team and then
maybe let those veteran members or those
individuals that have been around longer
ask them if they're willing to present
or demonstrate something that way those
that have kind of already sharpened
their skillset they're knowledgeable
they can teach and train the other
members that might be new to the scene
and that can be anything some
presentations can be theoretical some
can be very general and just discuss a
topic some could get really deep in the
weeds talking about like cryptography or
blind sequel injection attacks Python
programming or anything so this gives a
bit more life to your practice and helps
spread the wealth
right as one person grows and develops
they can share what they learn and let
others grow with them and just like
creating challenges this sort of thing
is contagious once people start to see
their friends have an opportunity to
present they'll want to present too
mixed in with that is the intent to keep
constant communication and I mean with
worthwhile content right you don't want
to just kind of be spitting off random
articles and email things that you find
but you want to digest and curate what
you show an offer to your team I'd start
out practices with kind of what we would
fondly refer to as the spiel to pass
information and that would often include
time stamps and information from CTF
time org so we can monitor online
competitions that were coming up I'd
include information from the zero daily
newsletter that hacker one does or
things that I would catch in a subreddit
like our slash security CTF or our slash
net SEC and then at the end of this if
you're doing some kind of announcement
section you want to make sure you open
the floor to everyone so that your
teammates have a chance to share things
too and do that often
number four provide incentive for people
to engage and encourage them to give
praise and publicly recognize those
people that work hard your central
repository for challenges could have a
leaderboard where people who solve more
of those kind of custom homemade
challenges they could rise up on the
scoreboard team members who give
presentations or write write-ups perhaps
they could be given more points when you
provide an update like that spiel or
your announcement segment on a daily or
weekly basis don't hesitate to call out
people by name that are doing good work
if someone on your team is consistently
willing to give a presentation or
showcase something you want to recognize
them if someone solved a crazy hard
challenge in a recent competition that
took some like unique cyber ninja work
give props to them if only a few people
like a small number work on a capture
the flag with you but not all of your
teammates do that's okay
publicly celebrate the people that do
participate so maybe others will be more
likely to join in in the future
step number five play this is the most
important step actively do it actively
practice play captured the flags and
place so many capture the flags that you
as the leader start to grow some
association with repeat games say you've
played one CTF before last year and it
comes up again this year now you know
the discretion to tell your team oh this
is gonna be really hard one I don't know
how many we're gonna be able to solve we
don't need to put as much time into this
or hey this is a really good creative
game there are a ton of awesome
challenges I want you guys to try and
solve as many as you can what a capture
the flag competition isn't on play
online war games over the wire smashed
the stack crypto pals micro corruption
exploit exercises the holiday hack
challenge rings your opponent rank pony
bouquet are the list of practice
material just goes on and on there is so
much out there if the war games are just
a little out of reach for some of the
newcomers that's when you build your own
homemade content your own local custom
challenges you can share them in your
centralized hub tell your team about
them and help them work through it the
best benefit of creating your own
challenges is that the author is in the
same room you can offer as much help as
you see fit and other people can ask and
help learn all right so this is the
Infinity step repeat this process
do this over and over again this is an
iterative thing I'm sure that you
noticed none of these steps are like a
one-time only thing this is the pulse or
the heartbeat of a cyber team or capture
the flag team your holly-jolly hackers
and when you play read write-ups write
write-ups track down the solutions and
answers that maybe someone else
published on their blog
an article online if you solve a
challenge or someone else on your team
does and not a ton of other people get
it then do a presentation share the
knowledge recreate that challenge or
like a distilled version of it in your
own custom and homemade challenge that
again is accessible from that team
central hub that's how you improve tell
your team and your weekly or daily
update when write-ups are out and
available and encourage them to go read
through and ultimately throw everything
that you do with your team stretch your
people this is the icing on the cake a
lot of these steps when you implement
them will inherently mark you as the
leader because you'll be the example for
the team but if you want to hit the next
level to keep a team growing you have to
stretch your people and drag them out of
their comfort zone walk around practice
to make sure that people are actively
learning trying new things they all have
something to work on when a competition
comes up that you know has a lot of
training value and challenges you're
confident your game members can solve
then hold them to it
push them dissolve say five challenges
or ten or fifteen keep pushing them to
break that glass ceiling and show them
the people that are succeeding so those
individuals know hey these are the
stronger of veteran players those are
the kind of more leet hackers and they
know who to latch on to and ask for help
if they need it one thing that we would
do is we'd actually just create like a
cheesy Google Doc a spreadsheet where
other team members could mark the
challenges that they solved that way
there's a visual display of who has done
the most work who can help on a specific
challenge who needs a little bit more
assistance and it provides a kind of
like personal feedback or maybe a little
bit of accountability so that one person
can see how they measure up with their
peers and the people they sit beside
every day and maybe that fosters a sense
of competition right oh I can get just
one more I can keep playing I can keep
pushing this okay so this
wasn't entirely on target right
there's no five-step formula for this it
can't be
condensed or compressed down there's no
book on how to improve people and if
there were it wouldn't sell anyway
because you guys are all too smart for
that
you can't encapsulate what needs to be
done to keep people engaged learning and
growing within cybersecurity it's it's a
hard problem to solve but I think we can
at least figure out that for each person
it requires constant practice a platform
and a framework to progress in and some
means to feel good when they succeed
that's the most important thing keep
your people happy keep them learning and
keep them excited about this stuff
because this is really cool stuff
alrighty so thank you thank you guys for
listening I hope you found a few good
nuggets and especially thank you to
Santa Claus for having me and hosting
this incredible Kringle con - lets go
find those two turtledoves