hi everybody who here has a job in
information security anyone who doesn't
have a job in information security and
is looking to get one
who's got a job in information security
and what's a better one all right we're
all in the right place so I switch
presentation software but it looks like
okay all right it might be a little tiny
bit off we'll fix it in post
so as my find volunteer introduction
said and as everybody is aware there is
a lot of information security cyber
security work and also there are lots of
jobs not necessarily the same thing a
lot of folks are trying to break into
the industry a lot of us are in the
industry looking to figure out how to
advance and frankly there's a lot of
misunderstandings so I'm going to try
and clear up a few things but my overall
theme is that if you want to help with
our problems if you want to work on
information security we really want you
to come help us you need a plan you got
a lot of work ahead of you I want to
make sure that you understand what that
work looks like how you can go through
it and what some of the obstacles or
concerns that you need to worry about as
well as the ones that aren't real and
that people are giving you bad
information or perhaps just a
misunderstanding are like and I trouble
a lot of InfoSec jargon and a technical
process stuff in here but the talk is
intended to be very very open very
high-level and not specific to any
particular InfoSec specialty as I hope
you all know we have lots of them and if
you're particularly good at this career
stuff you might end up inventing a new
one that actually happens all the time
our field is very dynamic smart
motivated people
are always making new jobs for
themselves making new areas of research
for all of us so one of the the threat
intelligence themes if you will is the
idea of a whitelist a blacklist and
maybe a great list so the purposes of
the talk the white list is a list of
things I think you should do and it is
not the list of everything that you have
to do it is not a complete list but it's
the recommendations that I have for you
four things that you should definitely
look into and almost certainly belong in
your plan to some degree or another
great list of stuff I'm a little shaky
about sometimes it's good sometimes it's
bad applied carefully it can help you
apply it on wisely it can harm your
chances of getting the next job and
advancing your career and then there's
some blacklist stuff which I'm going to
beg you not to do and unfortunately we
have to hit a few points like that as we
go through the talk because there are
some there's some bad behavior there's
some poor choices that some folks have
made that I want to help you not make so
that you do get to advance your career
and so the I and the folks that I work
with get the help that we need so it's a
collaborative effort there are
absolutely jobs in InfoSec there are no
unskilled or entry-level jobs in InfoSec
if somebody told you that they're
selling something probably an education
program and you need to to check into
that get another source get a second
opinion all of our jobs require some
skills skills that you can pick up
skills that you may already have I'm
going to talk more about those as we go
along you will it always benefits you to
have knowledge and experience from other
work so the classic path into InfoSec
was to go through IT first right you
work on the help desk you work as a
system
you work as a developer and then if
you're good at that and you're
interested security and you pass your
exams you get to go and work security
full-time I mostly followed that road
but it takes a long time it's not for
everybody and it's not the only way to
get there and although there are
benefits from taking that road there are
skills and knowledge and abilities that
you develop that way that are hard to
reproduce it is by no means the best
path there are other ways to get into
security there are other ways to help us
with our problems and we need the
diversity right people who have a
systems background people who have a
network background are not necessarily
the right people to solve all of our
problems for one we are constantly
finding and looking for new ways to
solve problems sometimes knowing how
it's been done for 20 years is
beneficial to that effort
sometimes it isn't right we need new
energy we need new ideas but even beyond
that having done something else in your
life having a previous career having
undergraduate collegiate experience in
another field is incredibly valuable to
us because we secure real things we work
with real people and their businesses
and organizations and you need to be
able to communicate with them and talk
about a lot and understand what it is
they actually do to be able to help them
it is not a we just need to pay enough
money and get the smart people and apply
the security to the thing and now the
problem is solved and we can go do
something else there are a few of the
problems that our field actually work
that way and that is never a good
strategy another odd thing about our
field that is mostly good and benefits
you especially as a career changer or
somebody trying to break in
is that our fields are young and
surprisingly well-documented there are
not for the most part centuries of
history and academic research and papers
in most of the computer security
information security and cybersecurity
fields mostly there's only a few decades
sometimes a lot less than that there are
not for instance a few decades of
research until
worldwide web application security
because none of those things have that
long and although there's some theory
going back a little bit farther than
that that might be useful to you the
practical research only started when the
technology became available the good
news is that that information is
available the bad news is that we don't
take good advantage of it so as someone
in the field looking to move up I beg
you to read our history as someone
looking to break into the field and
wants to impress us with how your
background your skills and your studies
are what we're looking for please read
our history understand which problems
have been solved understand which
problems cannot be solved and so maybe
you should have spent too much time
working on them especially for like a
computer science or a physics
perspective if a computer scientist
tells you a problem is hard that's not a
judgment that's not them being lazy
they're actually giving you the answer
to an equation that says that at least
that method of solving that problem is
impossible so we need new methods of
solving the problem or a new
understanding of the problem so that we
can develop a new method so on the one
hand there are no entry-level jobs there
are definitely jobs another thing that
is commonly misunderstood or perhaps
miss applied is that for folks who are
switching into security but also who are
folks who are already in security you're
going to be learning outside of work in
fact most of us study all the time even
when we're not taking a class or trying
to pass an exam
we are constantly studying the systems
that we defend the businesses and
organizations that we protect or new
attack techniques that other clever
humans have come up with that are
themselves innovative and new and we
want to try and stay up-to-date with and
this is the key point this is the thing
that makes our business different almost
any other we are up against human
adversaries with giant powerful brains
just like ours and sometimes they have
bigger teams and more money to spend
than we do so not only do we need to be
good with what we're good at but we need
to constantly be
understanding the changes in the
environment that we work in we need to
be aware and respectful of our
intelligent adversary and we need to
stay flexible and we are always learning
so again as someone trying to break into
the field this is part of what you need
to demonstrate both at a loved level for
sorry at a specific level in terms of
actually doing your homework maybe
getting some certifications or taking
the right classes but at a higher level
being able to talk in an interview get
to at the end about how you study where
you get your security news from we like
to ask what's in your home lab right
these are the kinds of things that show
that you get it that you understand what
our business is like what our challenges
are like and that you really want to
help us so the qualifications that I put
up the barrier if there is one that I
would say is not college or
certifications or technical skills or
your background or anything like that it
is genuinely do you want to help us
solve our problems and are you going to
put the work in there's a few others
communication skills are incredibly
important you need to be able to talk to
other humans and we do have some ethical
requirements we are most of the time the
enforcers of the rules which means you
have to be someone who follows rules and
even though it's uncomfortable sometimes
you have to be someone who can enforce
those rules against other people while
still being a compassionate human being
and a professional and if that sounds
easy
then I hope it is for you it is not for
everybody
and my other top-level qualification for
you is an understanding of what your
contribution is going to be we're not
looking for cogs I'm not looking for
somebody who has a set of technical
skills because frankly I can teach those
to anybody who is receptive I need
someone who is genuinely interested to
solve our problems whose unique
background whether it's their
undergraduate major the job they had
before where they grew up what culture
they were raised in anything like that
brings new ideas to our heart problems
brings new diversity of every kind
diversity of thought as well as
background and demographics of course to
our teams and to our problems and
frankly especially because everybody
who's in the running should have most of
this stuff and most of them are going to
have college most we're going to have
technical certifications this is where
you can differentiate yourself this is
where you can start to shine out from
the pack of other applicants and believe
me there are always going to be other
applicants
so skills the core skills for all
security jobs are I would argue the same
and there are communication use of
computer systems and data analysis now I
put communication up here twice because
it's that important and there's lots of
different ways to think about it data
analysis statistics research methods
heading towards cool stuff like data
science and machine learning but please
get the basics down first incredibly
important to everybody working in
security and this is not to talk about a
specific part of security right this is
not about sock or forensics or app setec
or compliance or governance or any of
the wonderful different things that
people do in security everybody works
with data everybody needs to be smart
about data and you really need to have
basic skills about how to do some
analysis of that data yourself
you need to be able to use effectively
the computers and applications that are
available to you and the general idea
here is that you should be a power user
and whatever systems are common in your
environment so if you're in an
organization and you're following this
path because you want to move up into a
security role you have access to the
applications and systems that that
company uses if it is a Solaris 10 shop
running up an office probably unlikely
you should be really good with those
things
before you start talking to people about
making opportunities available to you to
help with their security problems for a
couple of reasons one getting better
with using computers will actually
improve your quality of life if you
learn keyboard shortcuts if you learn
how to do stuff without picking up the
mouse if you learn a little bit about
the automation capabilities that your
office software your operating systems
your and your data platforms provide it
will just make your life better you will
waste less time waiting for the computer
and doing repetitive tasks that nobody
wants to do but it also helps to
demonstrate your commitment and it makes
you look good in front of the client or
the Constituent right they're coming to
you with their hard possibly scary
computer related problems demonstrating
that you are beyond competent with a
computer that you're actually pretty
good with one giving them tips being
able to show them how to do stuff they
didn't know how to do with their own
computer then they might have been using
longer than you have really helps to
build a good relationship right you want
them to believe that you're the expert
you're the trusted advisor you know what
you're talking about and all kinds of
communication communication in different
media email I am Chad and whatever else
we have these days this is telepathy a
thing yet but also in person and there
is many kinds of in-person conversation
as there are kinds of electronic
communication and understanding the
communication is bi-directional if
you're just shouting at people in one
sense or another if you're just pushing
out information but you're not getting
feedback and not pay
attention to it you're not communicating
and that's probably not what you need to
be doing sometimes we broadcast
information but only in very limited
circumstances so those are all technical
skills really and you can go to school
to learn any of them but the technical
skills that most people are concerned
about for a security role are pretty
specific to the role so if you know
which specialty you're going into if you
know which job title is your dream and
you're trying to build up - if you know
you want to be a web application pen
tester if you know you want to be a
cybersecurity legal expert that helps
you figure out what technical skills
you're going to need and you won't
necessarily be able to develop those on
your own before you have that job but
you can figure out where the path is
what the prerequisites to those skills
are and how you could get those
sometimes the answer is college a lot of
times the answer is self-study and your
own experimentation depending on your
target role and your target
specialization these are going to look
very different there is actually awesome
data available to help guide you in
particular there is a data set available
from the National Institute for Sanja
Technology NIST cybersecurity workforce
education project that is available
through Web Services you can also just
pull it as a spreadsheet and you can go
to a job role main they have an
identifying code for every single one of
them and you can literally see an
annotated list of all of the knowledge
'iz skills and abilities that's the
KSA's that they believe that their team
of experts who did the data analysis
believe are required for that job role
so from a hiring manager perspective we
might look at this to figure out who
we're trying to hire or what skills we
need to train two people we're going to
put into that role as someone trying to
break into that role this is your road
map this is the list of skills that a
whole bunch of experts believe our nest
to that specialty and experts will of
course disagree on things the more
experts you ask a question the more
answers you're going to get but it's
really good guidance and it's free it's
online you can use it I'll have the
links in the notes when I post them
later your online presence and the way
that you interact with people in the
public you can have a significant impact
on your success in seeking career
advancement whether you're just trying
to break into InfoSec or you're moving
up trying to stay in the field looking
to move into a different specialization
thinking about leadership as someone
trying to bring into the field having an
active online profile and being in the
community helping out is a huge thing
this is something that we give us advice
all the time but very few people follow
it if you can volunteer in person say to
help set up and wrangle speakers at
events thank you sir that's awesome not
everybody to do that right understanding
your own resources the time that you
have available your own family community
commitments figuring out what you can do
that's part of your responsibility can
you fall into your online can you help
with the tech support forum for one of
the awesome Allah open source pieces of
software that we all depend on so a
number of the the security packages that
we use have vibrant busy online
communities that are always looking for
moderators and people to help answer
questions on chat channels in IRC or
slack on bailing lists and Google Groups
and so on this is a way to not only
actually get into the community and
start to help us which is pretty cool
but to show that you're doing it and to
start to create this data trail this
evidence if you'll forgive my use of
forensics terminology that you are on
our side that you want to help us solve
these tough problems that you want to be
involved
you can help out with those projects in
terms of code that's fantastic if you
can compete especially in certain
disciplines like attack oriented stuff
there are a lot of online or in-person
competitions where you can earn a name
for yourself even while you're still
studying before you actually try to
switch jobs this is a pretty good option
for some folks you should definitely
have some kind of online professional
network of people either that you've
worked with before who would recommend
you again mentors who are helping you
develop your skills and helping you find
your way through this path you don't
have to display that publicly but a lot
of people choose to I tried very hard
not to recommend particular applications
or platforms because I want to be
inclusive and I don't really like any of
those vendors but it is a useful thing
for a lot of people to have an online
professional profile that is linked to a
bunch of other professionals right it
makes it look like you belong it makes
it look like you are doing the work to
be a part of the community that you are
participating that you're talking to
people and that you're open to all of
those things working towards a great
list of the black list please do not put
a lot of information about your current
employers technology stack on your
public or even semi public online
information does anybody know why this
is a bad thing
is anybody participating in the ascent
CTF event attackers whether they're
attackers who work for us like pen
testers Red Team folks or attackers who
actually work for criminals and
adversary groups can't take that
information and use it to figure out
what technology those organizations are
using especially if you tell the version
numbers it is a gift to the attacker
that you do not need to grant you should
be able to talk about your work in a way
that recognizes your contribution
without talking in detail about the
applications that your employer
currently has deployed especially if
you're in a security role please do not
tell me what av you're running this is a
gift to the attacker that you should not
give and for my admittedly biased
perspective causes me to wonder if you
understand things like upset and OS ends
and what risk our organizations are
really at what a motivated
one might say persistent adversary is
likely to do and a lot with that
I still see home addresses on people's
resumes please don't do that
I don't want your home address I
definitely don't want our HR department
to have it unless they need to actually
send you something through the mail so
implementation details vary sometimes
you might need to do that for some
reason I don't understand but especially
when it comes to an online profile like
that you might keep on an unnamed
service please do not tell me exactly
where to find you any more than you
should say when you're going on vacation
anybody familiar with please Ravi calm
[Music]
and on the blacklist
please do not post to the internet any
evidence of unlit unethical or illegal
behavior seriously this doesn't help
anyone it's not a good idea anyway and
it will be a problem especially trying
to get into a security or information
assurance role at a number of large
organizations and certainly any
government role any kind of government
anywhere this is going to be a big
problem for you so if I offer advice
generally but no specifics about what
your career path looks like what your
process to hunt for your next job or
position should look like I just urge
you to have one and maybe more than one
right one play will never survive
contact with the enemy but planning is
essential to Mangala quo here are a
number of processes from different parts
of InfoSec that I think have some
application to looking for a new
position or were exploring a different
career field up top we have our instant
handling cycle and I'll pick her all you
know some folks are smiling and laughing
their preparation and having a plan and
being prepared for when that plan fails
and still having a fallback making sure
that you have stuff in your go bag like
your laptop and your power supply having
a second presentation program in case
the first one randomly manifests the bug
you've never seen before
identification understanding what
problems you're facing putting a plan
together to remediate those problems
whether it's I'm applying to all these
jobs but I don't hear anything back or
the numbers that people these ta people
are quoting me salary numbers that don't
make any sense for where
what's gone wrong identified these
problems researching them putting a plan
together grabbing your other resources
like your mentors like your support
network and working through them without
squinting too hard you can see how you
could apply it instant handling or an
instant response process to this and if
you spend enough time in that business
you apply pickerel to everything even
shopping for groceries because you never
know you might need more milk you don't
want to run out of milk definitely don't
want to be in traffic or on a train on
the way home to have your significant
other or housemate tell you that you're
out of milk because you know now you're
looking at a critical service failure
next up we have an attack lifecycle
this one is miters but it's pretty
similar to the Lockheed Martin one which
is more famous here we emphasize
reconnaissance understanding your target
and while I don't really want to
characterize your job hunt as a security
attack against the people that you want
to work for because that goes back
towards that unethical behavior thing
that I'm asking you to shy away from if
they pay you to penetration test them
then yes do all of this if they have not
done that and you do not have a contract
saying that it is legal for you to
conduct these activities then I'm
concerned and you should talk to your
lawyer before moving forward
but in terms of information gathering
this should absolutely be an essential
part of your job hunt at a strategic
level in terms of hey I'm thinking about
a career in compliance maybe I should
read ten or a hundred job postings for
compliance jobs and talk to some people
who work in that field to see if that's
worth looking into more or on the more
tactical end I know I want the position
in application security at this
particular financial company well before
applying and/or showing up for an
interview you should be looking into
that organization and finding out what
you can for public resources about
what's going on there making sure that
it is what you are looking for and other
silly things like
are they gonna be around in here right
these are things that you can probably
start to get a handle on from from us at
data right from public data sources and
this would be part of a good process you
should probably not weaponize exploit
and deliver malware again unless you
have actually been paid to do it or
otherwise how to get out of jail free
card another perspective may be
vulnerability analysis scanning job
listings targeting the roles that you're
interested in the orgs that you might be
interested in crafting and effective big
load but here thinking about cover
letters and resumes something the same
technological problems face you there
social engineering as a way to bypass HR
careful there but it's a good
perspective a really good resource here
is a book by Josh Moore called job recon
where he actually models the entire job
search process around advanced
reconnaissance he also spent some time
talking about having done all this
making the organization that you want to
work for create the job you want to have
and that takes a lot of work and a
little bit of luck but if you do your
research you do your homework and you
get lucky you might just pull that off
and it's pretty great when it happens
before we talk about your resume and
I've tried very hard to focus everything
in the talk about your plan and your
data and your success going back to
helping with some large-scale
misunderstandings I'm not going to try
and explain the whole thing here and
it's different at different
organizations but let's just say that
there is a process and that it is
primarily computer driven for how your
application your cover letter your
online profile and you
resume are processed is masticated a bad
word chewed up that easier
processed in parsed torn apart put back
together in queried as part of the first
of many stages of filtering that happens
before in most of these processes you
have any possibility of talking to a
hiring manager or a technical contact of
the organization you're trying to get
into now there are sometimes shortcuts
around this I mentioned having a
powerful professional network because
that's one of the best ones but just up
front ear I wanted to make sure
everybody understands that some of the
advice that you get from people with
different expertise about how to design
the presentation of your cover letter or
your resume as something that is
beautiful that it's visually stunning
that is cool looking and eye catching is
not going to help you at all in this
phase and so the simple answer here is
to make sure that you have a plain text
resume and anytime it's going anywhere
near a computer system certainly anytime
that you're uploading it to any
application system or mailing it's
anybody you provide that version if you
think that you are conversing with a
human rather than a chat bot you might
provide both and you might tell them hey
here's the computer format version of
the resume for you to upload I also have
a pre printed version if you'd like to
look at it and you can provide both if
that's appropriate but if you're only
providing one and you're not
communicating right know no feedback you
might want to send the plain text one or
the lightly formatted one because
keyword matching is a huge part of how
these filters work they also do other
stuff regular expressions white list
black lists scoring algorithms and yes
even machine learning and more terrible
buzz words besides are all involved in
what is apparently its own
industry of processing resumes for
companies who are trying to hire people
so another area where some
reconnaissance some mentoring some
talking to your your your guidance
counselor you got one might help you for
your resume on the good side I really
want to emphasize that you keep it
tightly focused of the things that make
you different and that make us
interested in you in a pool of people
with similar qualifications because
especially if you get through all those
filters that is probably what you're
facing right they also match the
keywords they have they're cissp or
their GSCE
or some other harebrained thing I can
make fun of those exams because I passed
them as I talked about at the beginning
understanding what makes you special
what makes you awesome what makes you
different and especially if you've had a
job before what you accomplished right
not what you did everyday not what
technology you worked on what did you
actually accomplish what impact did you
have did you make things more efficient
did you help them serve their customers
better to just save them money
businesses always love to hear about
that this is the kind of stuff that I
would like you to put in your resume so
that I can tell apart folks who are
likely to help us from somebody who
might have the technical qualifications
but who is not my preferred candidate
please do not include every technology
you have ever used as specially if you
are not an expert in that technology
there's a there's a pretty common habit
and it's not a terrible thing on itself
which is why we're in great lists
category now of listing a bunch of
technologies like having like a skills
grid or a technology Liz
your resume bet I've got one yeah mine
is pretty tightly focused to try and
explain what my utility is around those
technologies so I say I can support your
environment if you're running on Mac
Windows Linux OS 2 Solaris BSD whatever
I do not say that I wrote those things
or then I can write couple patches for
them I say that I can code adequately in
a couple of languages because I passed
some of those classes in school and I
practice a little bit but for years and
years I would get calls from recruiters
asking me if I wanted to apply for a
senior job or developer position now I'm
not a senior developer and I'm not
really that good with Java but it was on
my resume as a while as a language I was
familiar with not as something I was
coding myself but actually I was you
know basically doing tech support and
but really stretching application
security work with people who were
coding in Java the funniest version of
that was in about 1997 when I got a call
from somebody who was asking me if I had
five years of experience with Java
programming language and we're trying to
hire for a senior developer it's a
little bit of an age joke but Java had
only been in beta two years before that
the guy who invented it James Gosling
might have used it five years before
that but it wasn't called Java then it
was called oak and yet no understanding
how the data on your resume is going to
be viewed by computers versus by humans
very very important and when it does get
to a human to a hiring manager to
somebody who to use a phrase I'm using a
lot lately knows what the words mean you
want to make sure that you are making
the best case for yourself please do not
include your entire work history or life
history unless that somehow is part of
your case for why you're awesome and
special and why you should be in this
role most of the time that's not what
you need and it's not what we're looking
for this next bit is probably gonna
start a fight on Twitter again
so let me put it this way I've been at
this a while some folks think I'm pretty
good people that work tell me I'm smart
I teach classes in this stuff so some of
that has to be true my resume is two
pages if you are not as far along as we
in your career and I am reviewing a
four-page resume from you it had better
be full of awesome stuff or I'm going to
start to slide your resume so that which
is which wing is that I'm not going to
talk to you this way so this is cultural
so this country our region specific and
some of its different in industries so
for instance if you were applying for a
security position at an academic
institution they might actually be
looking for a CV even though they're not
hiring you as an instructor knowing your
audience doing your reconnaissance doing
your own scent talking to your network
all I'll help you out here
another thing that I've encountered and
yeah it was on these four and five
eighths resumes is a whole bunch of
jargon and acronyms from the places that
you used to work if even I don't know
what this stuff is I'm kind of a big
nerd Minecon I don't know what this
stuff is and I can't easily google it
it is now either extraneous data which
you made me scan which lowers my you
know internal scoring or it's more stuff
for me to ask you about that if you
can't explain what it is either now we
have a different problem
we'll get you an assignment on the
blacklist
as we started our fee Muir is stuff I
wish I didn't have to tell you do not
rely on your resume your not include
stuff on your resume that you did not do
do not include qualifications on your
resume that you do not have especially
when a simple ascent search or
DuckDuckGo query or Google it's fine as
long as we all agree nobody uses baby
if I take something on your resume or
your cover letter and I google it or say
I queried the board in question that you
say that you've got this credential from
and they've never heard of you well now
we have a pretty serious problem and if
we do that before you come on site it's
actually pretty simple
you're not coming on site you're not
going to get the interview if you are
actually on site and we ask you about
someone your resume and it becomes clear
that it is not your resume or that you
don't know any of that stuff we're done
because this is the easiest way out and
it is not the way up if you have like to
be trying to get a job in the ethics
business right because for the rule
enforcers you might be interviewing for
a social engineering position I might be
hiring you for a potential position as a
professional liar that might be your
technical skill but if you lie to us
we're done please don't do this and
please understand that people do this
all the time but I don't want to bring
this up it keeps happening all the time
things you didn't do technology that
you're not actually that good with
please don't put that on your resume if
you have to cite a technology in one of
your job words for like what you did and
you don't have something awesome to say
you can talk about the fact that you
have basic familiarity with it or that
you used it daily for next years right
that that's a true statement it doesn't
suggest that you're an expert and it
helps me judge how you might fit into
the needs that we have and we have lots
of different kinds of needs right
declaring that your basic where the
technology doesn't necessarily
disqualify you I'm actually much more
worried about you lying I can get you
better with the technology myself and a
number of other experts including a
couple in the room here can teach you
that stuff if you make it through the
minimum bar of ethics and you know
showing up for the meeting on time and
some other you know lifestyle
requirements
who are you long time
when you are successful at your career
plan towards the end of your path to
getting a new position whether it is in
a new organization in your trying to get
promoted or changeable where you are now
or even if you're independent and you're
just trying to land a new client because
that's pretty much the same process just
harder you're probably going to get to
go on interview and it might be on the
phone leave to start but it'll probably
go video or live if we're very
interested in you at least in my
experience the organizations that I've
worked with after a certain amount of
screening to make sure that it's worth
talking to you we actually want to talk
to you hopefully in some detail and
depth about your experiences and we
probably believe you have technical
skills if you got to that part you might
not you might turn out to a be lying to
us and which point shortcut you're gone
but we think you have at least the
minimum qualifications before we bring
you in for an interview before we get on
camera with you for a video interview
please be prepared for that interview
and understand some of the questions we
are likely to ask and be prepared to
answer them and maybe have a few
questions prepared for the interview
team as well that you may or may not get
time or have the opportunity to ask for
preparation right planning this is
practically a whole course itself and I
strongly urge you to practice and work
with your network mentors that are
available to you if you've got
counselors or guidance people available
to you and we'll talk about the overall
community network at the tail-end here
shortly but just as a couple of freebies
if you put it in your cover letter or
it's on your resume we're probably gonna
ask you about it if it was in your cover
letter or on your resume and we ask you
about it and you can't speak to it you
don't actually understand it it's
obvious you didn't do that then we're
back on the last slide you're lying to
me and we're done this doesn't need to
happen
I'm not looking for you to
the most advanced person in the world
with Python or Kali Linux or Digital
Millennium Copyright Act or everything
unless that's what the qualifications
for that job are in which case that's a
high bar but that's not mostly what
we're looking for and if you're trying
to get into one of these first security
job but not actually entry-level
positions that I think are of interest
to a lot of folks here having an
accurate assessment of your skills and
still making yourself sound as good as
you can is where you need to be at and
if you're doing that then I'll be pretty
happy I'll ask you some technical
questions to figure out your depth and I
will ask you some questions you don't
know the answers to on purpose
seriously why are people surprised by
this okay for two reasons one because
it's a fantastic way to check for
character and professionalism issues
seriously how do you handle a question
you don't know the answer to do you
freak it out do you like have a health
of it obviously I don't want that to
happen to anybody but if that's likely
to happen when you encounter tough
problems that you can't answer this may
not be the right field for you or at
least not the right specialty because
that's what we do all the time some of
our questions don't even have answers we
just come up with the best approximation
we can install whatever is available
from the repo and go with it well fix it
in the next release right yeah so be
aware are the kinds of questions that
we're going to ask and be prepared to
talk to your skills your special
background your qualifications if we ask
you about saying I don't know recent
significant security news like some new
breach or attack or cool-sounding
malware that somebody announced and you
go into dummy mode on us you're not
helping your case and it's fine if you
don't know stuff in fact please tell me
you don't know stuff if you're trying to
get an analyst position like
security operations group which is where
I work I don't know is actually the best
answer you can give me the only thing
better than that would be I don't know
but if I had access to this data I could
tell you within this amount of time like
that is a lead analyst right there
almost but start with I don't know you
asked me a question I don't know any of
those words tell me that honestly but
without like getting emotional about it
and we're in a preview place because I'm
not kidding I will ask you questions you
can't answer me I probably won't make up
stuff I mean legally good I don't
usually have to another giveaway for the
folks here in the classroom as well of
all the people that I've interviewed the
last five years anybody who ever watches
the video oh god I have been known to
put evidence on the table literally I
will print stuff I'm not the only one
who does this believe me and I will put
it on the table and I will ask you to
tell me about it and if you are trying
to get into any kind of analyst position
whether it's Sark analyst Rancic analyst
application vulnerability analysts
anything where analysis is in your job
role then even if you have never seen
that data format before I would hope
that you can tell me some stuff about it
and this is where without resorting to a
lot of homework without like trying to
get you to work for free as part of the
interview process because that's gross
right I'm asking you to do the job skill
that you say you have that we're trying
to fill the role for in the interview on
a small scale I'm not the only one who
does this it's not the only way it
happens but please don't be surprised
and now that you know this you can
practice so if you're hiring or if
you're trying to get a job in a security
operation center or it isn't response
group you might imagine that there are
some standard data types that we deal
with all the time
if you don't already know what those are
well please ask somebody including me
after the talk easy and practice with
them if you are studying this stuff and
you are sweating some of the exams that
I am making light of because some of
them are in my past and you know one I
need to take a practice test on and take
pretty soon so a lot of the same
material is there and you know speaking
personally as I said I teach this stuff
so I have a pretty good understanding of
the material and know exactly what to
ask to figure out what your level is at
and your level doesn't have to be super
advanced has anybody heard the story
about when we don't allow some
interviewed to work for Google so Google
as part of their beard and vaunted
interview process there's a lot of
different things but one of the
questions that they asked when it comes
to your technical skills is they asked
you to rate yourself against the rest of
the world on a ten-point scale I mean is
qualitative not quantitative so you know
we'll take a swag at it right so they're
talking to this one candidate for
software engineering position it's a pre
pretty well done guy and at the time
Google's way into the Python programming
language it's still pretty big they're
they like going now a lot too so they
asked this guy they asked we don't in
all the world all of the developers how
do you rate yourself on a scale of one
to ten with your skills at Python it was
a pretty cool guy it's very humble smart
person he said well I will give myself a
nine because it is possible that there
is someone in the world who knows the
stuff better than I do
Zubrin know who IDO is he invented
Python you made it up but in a technical
interview when asked about his skills
there was room for doubt and humility in
his heart that he might not be the best
person in the world at that thing
so take that to heart as well don't
shoot you low if you know something be
able to demonstrate it but don't worry
that you don't
that you don't have the skills yet
especially if you're just trying to
break in nobody expects you to you have
a tremendous number of resources
available to you to help you in your
career path at large and small scales so
in the greater InfoSec community there
are all kinds of cool orgs there are
mailing lists and forums and meetings
that you can go to there's some really
great mentoring and and like job help
communities some of those a lot of them
honestly are invite-only so this is
where your professional network can
really help you there are in those
communities in our professional
organizations and in our hacker clubs
specific programs and competitions and
volunteers to help you with this stuff
you can get trial interviews you can get
your resume review there's actually some
fine folks out in 48 doing that for
conference attendees take advantage of
these resources both because it will
help you but also because that
demonstrates the kind of overall
problem-solving that we're looking for
in the Atlanta area specifically we have
awesome professional organization
chapters for soö us but CSA probably
couple others that I forgot to mention
we also have some really cool hacker
clubs like our 2600 still meet net Linux
DC 404 and manís tavern force Ave yep
third Saturday third Saturday and you
see 770 out in carnage very far away
near is already pretty far away so
especially if you are the the canonical
new person if you are trying to break in
you don't know anybody and you don't
know anything yet these orgs especially
honestly the hacker clubs are other than
the professional Lords are a really good
place to start to find like-minded
people to find people who are either in
the same struggle or people who have
been through it so I actually got one of
the best jobs in my life and later the
opportunity to go full-time in security
from a posting to I think we figured out
was DC 404 Keith's around here somewhere
was his fall that's how I got a net
secure works in IT which I was later
able to transition over to a full-time
security job so hacker clubs pretty
great they also have presentations a
different educational value or sometimes
some guy just gets up and starts ranting
about career stuff in your personal
community your family your other social
organizations right because we're very
open here
people have different families different
religions culture whatever you guys
there are probably people available to
you who can help with some of this stuff
even if they don't know anything about
InfoSec they can probably help you
through dialog understand what's special
about you and what you can do to
emphasize that how you can communicate
about that how you can talk yourself up
without lying or making stuff up
different yeah so short answer there
start going to meetings which you know
is a little funny for me because I
hardly arranged one
so we just have a few minutes left is
anybody in the room have any questions
okay so I tried to be a little careful
because it's a controversial topic what
I said is - two pages have as many pages
as you need to tell the story you need
to tell if you're trying to get a higher
level position you may need to
demonstrate that you've done this job
successfully in a number of
organizations of different sizes right
that may be the the story that you need
to tell but especially if you're just
getting started
I would I would shy towards the the
shorter resume and remember that the
computer cannot digest it before I get a
chance - and you mentioned on the even
text text format and that's the format
to upload it can I do it my resume
review also so not to use RTF format is
that it's probably okay it just causes
security bells to ring in my head for a
totally unrelated reason ASCII text is
safe I was like it's safe because that's
not the world we live in but it's a cup
a lot safer than RTF because RTF has had
some surprises okay
these have a boring version please so
was there was there another question
[Music]
questions like that but when you ask
about my consistency 6/10 questions and
what you say so if you're actually in an
interview you might already be under NDA
which helps if you're just talking to
somebody about a job opportunity you
kind of have to make the judgment call
and sometimes it just depends on where
you worked if you worked at a civilian
organization with a reasonable level of
security but you know you didn't have
any kind of clearance or any kind of
crazy government stuff then you just
have to decide if you trust the people
that you're talking to enough to share
that information with them I just beg
you not to make you public on the
Internet
does that make sense if you did work for
some of those places you absolutely are
not allowed to talk about the technology
that you used which is another reason to
have all this other stuff to talk about
right to have these other skills to have
these experiences this stuff that's
special about you if you actually worked
in the intelligence community or if
you've been enlisted for 15 years and
you you honestly aren't allowed to tell
me what you've been doing then we need
something to talk about otherwise the
interview gets really awkward those are
not much fun either yes yep okay so
thanks for the questions thanks
everybody for your time hope you enjoyed
it I'll get the slides and links posted
and if you're looking for me and haven't
found me already
[Applause]