okay welcome to this sound over the
whole West right here he's an
engineering manager at CrowdStrike you
know you'll be going over the sound of
evoking various aspects of audience
degree this one take time to thank our
sponsors here at V Sox from the Kennesaw
State Department of Information Systems
like to thank the NSA and for spirit of
help systems so without further due so
the sound to be talking about audio
security but before again I just want to
take like a whole what attracted you to
come to this talk several others that
are going on some really good so what do
you think of when you think of all your
security I have two surveillance
surveillance
yeah privacy privacy all right so
basically I made it up there's no such
thing as audio security but there should
be now the reason why there should be is
because audio systems are coming in in
all kinds of places right they show up
everybody and I would argue that this is
something that's really just in it's
like very beginning phases they're not
going away if you go back in like in
computing history the ability to just
talk to your computer is something
that's like baked in like all the way
through our our size how did people
interact with like kidfox you know the
the car the nightlife talk to it how did
we interact with data awesome Star Trek
talk talk like this is baked in and then
all the way through to like there's a
really old ad for Apple where they
started off pretty the name of the
system but the whole ad is talking to
the Macintosh and having it do things
now the ad was was not completely
far-fetched they had a little bit of
things even the old new device from
Apple II many years ago you could at
least tell it to set a date so the
ability to interact with a computer it's
like really old promise and why did it
all of a sudden like so only recently
have all these other pieces come
together for it to become like something
that
dude today so in with that as a good
security researcher you should think
about like what are the ways that this
this device can be misused and used and
also the privacy issues everything else
so most people will they think of all
your security or audio devices voice
assistants think about the physical
special-purpose
voice assistive device the Amazon echoes
the Google dies and then not really
special purpose but a Siri speaker or
actually the avatar the Apple speaker
which had Siri pregnant but then there's
a whole bunch of others to the they're
really just they really just constitute
like microphones some thin processing
and then a speaker of some sort that's
it
and then IOT side of it they're actually
the best case of IOT they have
end-to-end encryption the firmwares
locked down there was one version of the
Amazon echo that had the very first
version you could tag onto the board and
then get root access that's how we
they're they're based off of an Android
operating system and they have apks that
are installed you don't install any of
the case Amazon but other than that the
device is really locked down there's not
a whole lot else going on there so what
else is there that we can talk about I
want to introduce the idea of voice
assistance is being disembodied think
about Star Trek where you're walking
along the bridge you talk to the
computer do this thing right
that is a voices system and there
they're not just limited to the physical
device that the device is really just a
pic report for you to say you know
here's the device or here's the
capabilities but the capabilities are
built into a whole bunch of other things
like carbs phones remotes all over the
place they're showing on public areas
are starting to have like a voice
assistant approach to so um they're even
showing up in like channel systems for
those of you who aren't aware chat ups
are like taking a chat type system like
slack and being able to interact with
your corporate town or Jenkins or some
other servers and then adding a voice
overlay to it just tell me why it's go
build this in other words they're used
more and more as shortcuts for helping
us do things that we want to do there's
all kinds of apps that are built on the
phone where you can like
your voice like triggers to do things
Siri used to be known as happy
interesting side until the marketing
team thankfully came along and said
don't really want to sell a product and
how to people but the idea that like I
think it's kind of a series anybody
familiar with how you might not from
when you're sorry I should've done it
neighbor not familiar with that 2001
Space Odyssey either recommend that
because that is one of a original like
sounds people
it's where the I'm sorry comes from yeah
he ends up boxing the guy out his face
and tries to kill him right yeah which
is why he's saying into the house it's
not a good idea to name your right voice
so one thing that we can save like
generalized over voice assistance is
that the Platonic ideal and we're
talking about like ideal forms for a
voice assistant is really a combination
of three different machine learning
models and I know machine learning might
give you some heartburn it's used in all
kinds of
context whatever but this is really the
reason why my voice assistants are
popular now and they work popular when
they were first conceived that can like
even the 50s the bells Bell systems had
something called the Audrey system that
was trying to detect numbers that was
all it was really designed to do but it
was a sort of a primitive voice to speak
voice to text other bit of trivia there
the the person who created Tetris was he
used to work for the KGB before he came
to the US and he said one of his
projects there was to be able to speak
to the big fighter plane and like the
pilot would be able to tell it to do
things because at high G maneuvers it's
harder to move your arms but the sound
you know sound waves travel at like 700
miles an hour so you can tell the plane
to do something you never do it I don't
know that they ever got that implemented
but just the notion that this was
something that was way back in the
sixties so today we have all all the
processing power to make this come
together and what we really had is in
the nascent phases of having a useable
voice assistant it's not there's still
some huge gaps but it's still at least
useful to where my kids can have it so
anyway three different machine learning
systems voice-to-text the natural
language processing part of it and then
the text-to-speech each one has its own
threat model and I only want to talk
about the first two because the meet
different times uh presented this is
that trying to to light cover three
different machine learning models and
one top is way too much so just the
first two to begin with we have to pick
apart the acoustic landscape if you
think about it we've actually
experienced here in this classroom like
in the sense this talk has started the
the fact that there are multiple
different sound events and sound like
occurrences in this landscape going on
at the same time we actually two
different hallways with their own
acoustic space that's bleeding in
because the doors are slightly cracked
but then each one of you guys is your
own source of sound and we're sitting
next to my kids in church you know and
then like so there's there's all this
stuff going on in the Honorable space so
the first thing we have to do is pick a
part that's space that audio space and
zero in on the sound events that we're
interested in and throw the rest of the
way
that sounds very simplistic for me to
just say it but to actually do it in
processing is really hard for instance
they've been doesn't even have like bows
or the headphones that have the - built
into them that try to like zero in on
your voice so the way that that works if
it picks apart the space and then tries
to zero in on your voice one of the most
hostile places that you can
the headphones out isn't an airport so
was talking to a colleague of mine once
and when he was talking zeroed in on his
voice when he stopped talking
it ranges and finds the announcers voice
the person standing next to mostly they
announce so point is lots of stuff going
on it's really hard to process so the
voice in the whole sound landscape
occupies a fairly narrow band a male
voice hundred to nine hundred Hertz
female voice like an octave higher so
350 to 3 kilohertz the human ear has a
really wide range Oh bit of trivia
wallows researchers miss for the male
voice is typically around 100 Hertz
James Earl white he had 50 years as his
natural voice range the lower your range
of voice that's the radio voice the
human ear
125 to 12 kilohertz so quiz time who
cares the most about the range of voice
frequencies and all that what industry
what device manufacturers yes
all centers all senators beakers or
somebody else's hearing aids period
definitely and phones in fact phone
manufacturers cell phone manufacturers
in particular have some of the best
white papers on this they try to to
really narrow in on voice does anybody
know why any guesses safe man exactly
yes now you're tempted as someone who's
operating like in this space to cut out
everything above 3 kilohertz because the
average female voice can't you know it
goes up to 3 kilohertz maybe you'll snap
it out at 4 kilohertz or something like
that but the nature of sound waves is
that it presses up against the higher
frequencies so it's if you don't include
the higher frequencies then you lose
things like consonants and it's harder
to understand so we need to capture like
generally the entire range of semen here
it may be a little bit higher - which
comes into play a little bit later our
brains are wired though because the
audio landscape is something that we
naturally like process and we've been
doing it for forever
we feel that we at least a little tricks
but fill in spaces of frequent
a range that we don't actually hear oh
and the last part of that is pull it
apart sound events is inherently lost
that means that when we're when we have
the acoustic space how many of y'all
have seen a waterfall diagram of sound
or anything like that okay that's it
takes the entire spectrum plots and on
the graph actually even plotting it on
the graph is losing information by
itself but the point is the more you
hunt for a signal the more that signal
trades so going back to the the trick of
the brain this is the Alexa dauber
commercial which was over the first
commercials where Alexa was not actually
triggered because there was like this
whole rash of you know Alexa commercials
and news reports triggering Alexa's it
was this funny case of a news story
about a kid that was able to buy things
on their parents Alexa and the story
actually contained Alexa by this and
then the news report actually triggered
like all the people listening to it
Alexis so there's this like infinitely
of Alexis buying things
people reporting about so Apple came up
with a solution they would let
commercials and news reports know if you
cut out this range in the frequencies
people will still hear the word Alexa
but the device will not pick up on it
because the model is not trained for it
okay it's an easy way to just bypass the
triggering there's an implicit in
teresting security implication here -
you could be tricked into hearing
something the device is not processing
because our ears are tuned to filling in
this information in other words it would
be a way to have a covert channel so the
way that you pick apart signals in an
audio space is basically a what's called
a fast Fourier transformation so you
take the time domain so the lucky signal
over here and you want to pick apart all
the different signals up here that make
up the signal over here so if you
combine all these signals that come to
this if you pick them apart it gives you
this okay that is the heart of audio
process and it's actually the heart of
video process in their image processing
or just about any other signal
processing okay but especially for audio
processing so we've got the frequency
graph here that most people are used to
looking at but what we're looking for is
specific audio events yes is that so
microphone is just going to give you
changes in voltage when it's best
vibrating and so that's going to give
you that picture on the time that you
have shown it at a time domain and then
say that the fast Fourier transform is
to pick out the individual frequencies
that have to be costly in that yes so to
go back it's good I probably need to go
back so a microphone is capturing
samples of the audio space and it's
capturing like across the frequency
domain that the microphone is - - not
all microphones pick up the same range
but whatever ranges of frequencies it's
tuned to it will pick up a snapshot in
time of what it hears for us those
frequencies and it picks up like that
won't be like it's basically just a
frame of data that has this is the
intensity of the signal at each one of
these frequencies at that time and so a
microphone digital signal processing is
something like I guess the average would
be like 16,000 samples per second okay
and so what we're doing is we're taking
that we're all audio 16,000 samples a
second and we're trying to take out of
those like several seconds or probably
even milliseconds we want to pick out
what signal we hear in that so that's
another piece of all your processing is
we're taking the audio space we're
taking a sample of the sound like every
second every usually every 200
milliseconds or so we're taking a
snapshot and then we're running a fast
Fourier transformation on it and then
seeing what what signals are in this
space at this time that makes sense
okay if I lost you I have cars message
me later but that is basically the
processing part of just figuring out
what signals are in the space at that
time so what we're doing is we're
looking for sound events specifically
we're looking for human voice sound
event support if we're making a audio
assistant however not also Alexa has
this interesting guard mode that you can
enable and the reason why you don't have
it enabled all the time is because it is
a like some sound events sound very
similar like glass breaking or dropping
a glass on the floor or something like
that so I liked so detecting sound
events this is like the very basic car
alarm is won by continual sound glass
breaking it's very similar sound or a
very definite sound in fact here's a
collection of different sounds and what
their plots look like on what's called
the male spectrum a spectrogram is what
I was talking about earlier you take the
sample of sound and you run the Fourier
transformation over it and you're
picking out here's what here's the
signals that I'm detecting in the space
in this given time so if you zoom in on
this it looks like there's a lot of
ribbons down and that's because there
it's a like a chunked collection of that
sound
face at that time if you look at it you
can either fool yourself into seeing it
or just take my word for it or like
reason into it that these the graph of
the sound there fits what it's
describing especially the hydraulic
hammer you can see the rhythmic and the
fact that it occupies all frequencies
and then it comes off then it occupies
all frequencies that comes off wind
milling machine and the sound of
generator you can see that the generator
is more intense than the milling machine
and that the wind noise just generally
flooding all jacks the one that's the
most interesting here are the two that
are most interesting of music and
talking talking is very unspecified in
other words unless you're singing a note
in a song at a constant rate it's not
going to fill the audio spectrum so what
that means is there's only a very short
amount of time that your voice is making
a an impact on the sound waves in an
acoustical space right so the sampling
of that in time and all that matters
music even any of you guys use Shazam or
anything to like
determine what song is playing at a
certain moment didn't I have a pixel
lightning chance a pixel phone okay the
pixel phone actually has this built into
it you can download like a chunk of it's
actually 500 Meg's of audio fingerprints
and it's not for every song of the world
it's for the top ten thousand songs and
so what these fingerprints are doing is
they're taking the audio space here for
this
and there they're determining if you
have this frequency and then 200
milliseconds later you have this
frequency it's a constellation that's
that is effectively fingerprinting a
song and it takes somehow 350
milliseconds of audio data to figure out
what song is playing not a whole lot
and that comes into play later so
another thing before I keep on going is
that the Alexa card doesn't work on
every device it doesn't work on every
device because the MOR triggers you add
to the device the more it has to
actually do classification which is
machine learning operation and the more
processing power has to have so the
Amazon echoes can't do this I also have
in there gunshots because one
interesting feature or interesting
aspect of like audio detection or
whatever is - you can triangulate where
where something comes from or where it
where sound is coming from
so voice the text is all about what's
called phonemes phonemes are pieces of
speech ok does anybody remember learning
how to read phonetically like these two
letters make this phonetic sound like or
whatever else these are the things that
we hear and so phonetics was a style of
teaching that was about taking what we
hear and transcribing it back to the
written language okay same thing needs
to be done here for voice of text so
what we hear in the audio space are
these these costs are these vowels and
consonants these
these combinations and one interesting
thing about this is that phonemes change
over time they change by region did
anybody have Grand Central Station
before it was Google Voice yeah did you
actually it was like the first person
I've never run into they had Grand
Central Station basically Google started
this project or no Grand Central Station
started the project and it was like you
could replace your voice mail with this
really cool new technology that will
just capture it and story and what they
were doing was they were trying to build
up their voice to text across a broad
number of people in different regions
and it turns out that you're like how
you say words impacts how machine
learning models were made to a really
great degree so Google started there
basically started their Google dot
project or their voice assistant project
like over a decade ago because that's
why they bought Grand Central Station is
to help build on this time I had a
particularly southern friend of mine
I've always called Lee West voice mails
and they would always have some
hilarious stuff wrong did anybody have
Dragon NaturallySpeaking
like yeah you remember how long you had
just had to read to it before it before
the model was correct you had to read to
the for like an hour or more before the
model would get built and but the thing
was it was built to your voice no one
else's it was a model train to you the
trick with modern voice assistance is
that they're trained across a lot of
voices not all but a lot yeah
differences to do with how we start out
more or less the site places which
diverge it was really just about the
bowel sighs he meant how the length of
the consonants really determine how
strong accent was and they may be
different but the problem I see when
you're if you were trying to recognize
work if your machine is consistently you
know long or short entire but within
within that region but in another region
there may be a word this is the same
word yes it has the opposite right say
well they pronounce it totally different
in different regions so does anybody
have a guess how that's handled by the
model I can see how being handled if you
you are bid we write from but it doesn't
know that right then you would have to
say a lot of words before it would guess
ok there everywhere on earth where I
expect this right sound we're
substituting this now therefore that
must be one of these regional accents so
one of the features of the Grand Central
Station later Google Voice was that when
you saw your what it when it spit out
for the transcription of your voicemail
you could go back in and edit it and
what that gave them was basically
reinforcement mark so they can and it
was free free labor reinforcement
learning across thousands and thousands
of people and what they also got was
regional information right so those two
pieces together we're able to say
somebody calling me from New York for
instance there's a certain set of models
that probably apply to that person and
so what you do is you layer the
different models when somebody speaking
you layer the different models and say
first you need to do like regional
protection right and then you need to do
like and there's certain markers like my
Canadian friends in the abudance and
stuff like that like that's dead
giveaway
but not all of them have that there's
actually you're right it's a little bit
deceptive to say that
voice-to-text as the it's like an entire
machine learning system it's actually a
collection of them one of them is where
you're from and based off of how you say
certain words and then applying the
right model to the voice construct what
I wanted to bring up here with phonemes
is models that are trained off of us
speakers and I guess getting down into
it even regional speakers they aren't
transferable there's not a generalized
model to say and now we know Korean or
Chinese or what across has to be a whole
different model a whole different set of
trainees what that means is well this is
the collection part it goes back to the
privacy Amazon and Google so this this
case came out late last years and I
remember this Amazon like all of a
sudden this guy so what happened was he
asked them I want to know what you're
collecting about me can you send me my
date now out of this put on our
investigators have here there are
certain things that we can conclude out
of this one it is broadly possible to
tie someone back to their Alexa device
otherwise they wouldn't have been able
to give them any of us out of the course
second Amazon has no interest in like
separating your audio from everybody
else's audio it's basically put into one
giant s3 bucket okay and warframes
I'm just guessing in the architecture
based off of this event so effectively
an engineer and Amazon just like here's
basically your audios in this range in
this bucket here you go okay this was
not a security breach necessary because
it was one guy who was asked a question
and he filled out the ticket incorrectly
it should not alert alarm us that that
the engineer made a mistake what it
should inform us of though is that the
data is stored and continually like
models are continually run over that
data to figure out different properties
so yes it is recording it is storing it
I don't know how long the retention of
the storages no idea I wouldn't be
surprised if it wasn't very very long
because you need a lot of data to build
these models of correctly and also there
was a related case I don't have a
picture of this one - in the news
article but Amazon employees recently
like in their internal chat talking
about like different things than they've
heard from customers well if they have
access to them like the buckets of all
the information then of course they have
access to the individual information -
and apparently it's enough to where you
can actually cure yourself ok related to
those two articles throw out another
article of there are two active court
cases that are pending in the discovery
phase they're there some subpoenaed
Amazon give us the recordings of this
Alexa the reason the belief elite has
been triggered and has data about some
crime that happened as far as I know
Amazon still fighting but yes it is that
it's recording Amazon employees have
access to it to the degree that you
trust him
is the grade that you are comfortable
with having one of your house car now
another thing on this before I go into
the water falling the device is always
listening but it's not always streaming
what's happening in the room at that
time notice I said the court case they
had a reasonable belief that the device
had been triggered the device doesn't
start recording and like chunking that
information until it's been triggered
until the wake board has been set going
back to the sound events so the the
guard duty that's pushing down a lot
more triggers basically to the device if
you hear this instance then it's a
trigger so those those events become
triggers the trigger for almost every
device now is the wait word okay Google
a Siri Alexa
Oliver those are the triggers the reason
is because the device can't be doing
that much process it's a small device I
mean the heart of it is not that smart
device but when it is triggered then
that's when it starts and it doesn't
capture the entire audio space there's
actually some really cool research
articles from of the Alexa T the Alexa
side of Alexis Sciences they had a
division of assignment and one of them
is anchoring the weight word to the
person that's speaking you may have
analytics in their house I usually ask
anybody I'd watch and I give this this
also because I love the promise of
audience period but it basically in our
house when we when we go to play music
when my kids will say they'll trigger
the device Alexa and they're still
thinking about what they want it to do
or like play and another cannabis would
bring it play this play another song
okay the point is we'll get to it a
little bit more in a second but the
device doesn't know who's speaking it
has no concept and flesh that out a
little bit more in a second but now all
it's listening for is the wait for it
and then it sends the rest of it or it
tries to pick out pick out who speaker
is they can't take that
send the fast Fourier transformation
detect which is actually a very small
amount data but it's still enough data
that you can reconstruct voice up dammuz
on systems so how can we protect the
device from listening to us all the time
so I propose that we should think about
so there's the network concept of a
firewall that protects the ports from
coming in I propose for audio security
we have a concept of a waterfall
waterfalls flood out sound behind us an
extra make your device work better to
noise helps us isolate sounds if you
have a headset noise-canceling headset I
did this recently installed an AC unit
right behind me and so it's like
flooding the space behind me and after
listening to all of this and all the
research I was like I bet it's gonna
make your
better two little conference calls she
was right because it floods out all the
noises past that like the street kids
and everything else another note here
silence and noise as far as a digital
processing is roughly the same what we
experienced the silence is really
lowered intensity of the audio space so
all those combined we can do something
like put a parasite onto a digital
assistant device and what that looks
like
is this funny we'll have here 3d printed
when it's got inside of it is a
Raspberry Pi a this is part of the
project alias if you guys are interested
in that it's all the plans for the
software everything's over the source
what it does is we teach it your own
weight word so you can rename your
device and it's listening for your
weight work while flooding the device
under of the sound and then once you
trigger it with your weight word it
stops flooding the device under the
sound plays the lake word for device and
then you can interact with it as normal
most people are going to spend the time
or whatever to build this so I'm not
advocating this is like a generalized
solution mostly it was a fun hobby and
an excuse that I gave my wife to spend a
lot of time so but I bring it up because
flooding out devices with audio and
sound like you remember the old spy
movies I'm sitting in the bathtub
running the watery stuff there's still
some usefulness to that mentality so if
you're around the device think about am
I the only one speaking or am i a part
of a crowd is how easy or hard would it
be for that device over there to pick up
my voice and stuff like that so this
brings me back to the speaker
identification the most that a device
can do is detect that there are multiple
people speak
in an in a space what it can also do is
perform like very simple calculations on
the frequency range of your of the
voices that are speaking to say is this
voice high and squeaky like my kids
friends probably a child okay or is it
is it higher or is it lower than 350
Hertz probably a man's voice otherwise
if it's higher than like 900 Hertz maybe
a woman's voice somewhere around there
these are probabilistic calculations
right the amount of human data the
reason I spent so much time on the
frequency ranges the amount of data
that's in a voice is not enough to give
you like confidence cryptographic
certainly not anywhere close between
this person's voice and another person's
voice even if you trained a model using
dragon even that sort of a model there's
training your voice it's not enough for
somebody that further for the model to
say this is absolutely this person
basically the collision the the degree
of collisions there is very problem so
while researching this I as if I
remembered that there so this is from
the movie sneakers very big movie person
in case but movie sneakers has a scene
in it where they're trying to get access
to somebody's accountant so they're
trying to find like recordings of this
person's voice saying hi my name is blah
my voice is my passport verified okay
and then the whole like scenes the movie
or them capturing clips and phrases of
the person is saying pieces of them the
funny thing here is that the technology
to clone a person's voice already
existed when that movie was made so it
was completely superfluous nobody would
have done it but after researching this
I decided who in their right minds would
implement unlocking something with your
voice well it turns out a bank would do
that and specifically my back
and so this is their like thing about
you can access your account on your
phone you just speak to it and hey my
voice is my passport because we remember
we remember the movie but we don't
remember the lesson from the movie in
that same page is my voice ID secure
sure we have a proprietary algorithm but
you can't bend the laws of physics to
make the voice have more bits of
information in it to make a
cryptographically security
this is a dumb idea but lest you think
that my bangs the only one that did this
there's multiple banks that business
multiple banks including HSBC the fun
thing about HSBC is somebody decided
this is a bad idea they went and they
proved like here's how we can do it not
only did they do this but they did it on
live BBC Leighton they brought in the
twin I love this picture because it kind
of captures the whole light this was a
dumb idea to protect my bank my bank
account with my voice I'm not going to
go into all the other things but I will
layout view anytime you see voice being
used as a access control run it can't be
it's like I'm not gonna I don't want to
be too strong in this denunciation but
no pin drop is a great local company
they're researching the space of how to
do it but it's also in conjunction with
other factors it's the second thing I
love pin drop but even they won't claim
like we can totally secure a count by
one factor force yeah catch me
afterwards how do we do it like when I'm
listening to you like I've heard you
speak before like I know your voice even
without seeing you pick up cues yes I
mean I wouldn't assert that that's
graphic certainty but like you know when
I hear
voice of recognized label yes I know it
yeah we know the characteristics of the
voice what I'm saying is like it's you
broadly you know that it's me and not my
wife and not some other completely other
people that you met you have a kind of
fuzzy matchstick but my point is
something else can come along and
duplicate that voice like it's not
there's a whole nother section of this
talk about duplicating voices that's
what the cryptographic certain stuff
comes in okay
like you know that you think you know
that it's me but the other part of the
talk cloning voices we don't really know
right and so moving on there's a lot to
go into here and really what I found
that also recently as a pixel allows for
you to voice unlock your phone another
bad security design but at least Google
decides never mind
so they have this feature like you could
I'm not gonna follow that place when you
go to turn it on
they at least tell you this makes your
device a lot less secure and yes last
month
they completely remove the feature
because it's completely insecure it's
funny because like these large companies
are putting out poise security and then
walking it back alright
NLP I don't know if I'm able to do this
in three months but we'll try this is
how you're Alexa uses in a feed
other stuff your weight word your launch
which is an application invocation wait
word action application and variables
that's how it works so what you're doing
is you're telling this and then the NLP
in your device Alexa cheese it fills in
this other information so if you say
Alexa play law it cheats and says so
what you want is this music application
whatever else so to quickly go over that
companies tightly control the taxonomy
and to craft a better user experience
they have these cheats in it basically
you don't know what happier talking to
this is a real security model you don't
know what app you've triggered when you
tip when you ask Alexa to tell you a
joke you don't know which app is
actually providing the joke which
matters when you want to Joe this from
the broad pool of jokes you don't want a
continual stream of Jimmy Fallon jokes
which is what Alexis started doing a
while back no way to tell there's no
there's also no sense of context no sono
session does anybody can anybody guess
what the security application is of that
no session information your device has
authorized once for your account and
anybody was able to speak to that device
has that authorization level there's no
elevating lowering authorization reading
this stuff so some of alexinnz features
have allowed you to like tie it to
broadly if if the adult is speaking
whatever what they're trying to do is
filter out children okay but it's not
it's not super secure
so there was part of the NLP part is the
family had their conversation recorded
and sent to a contact that was not a
security issue baked into the elects
what happened was the NLP picked up on
the weight word then they then it
matched something that sounded my call
and then it matched something that
sounded like a contact and then the rest
of it was just an open channel okay but
it was that the model was very very like
a truck it was trying to be super
helpful and pick up all these key words
from a very far distance called a far
field problem and so novel so we were
talking about like regional dialects
whatever that's one issue
another issue is how that sounds across
the span of a room up to like 30 feet
away so Google's Amazon's response to
this was to limit the field that it
would listen to so the effect of that is
now I have to yell at the Alexa in my
talk with me rather than being able to
just talk to it and it deals with all
the deep data so to sum up and there's
there's ties to say about all of these
pieces our is really not enough to do it
justice so if you want to catch me later
feel free I've got business cards
everything else going it's we whatever
later three areas I want you to consider
voice identity and authorization is not
something that audio systems do or I
would argue can do by the physics of how
much voice or how much data can
invoice the apps that are on the Alexa
camp part they don't have a way to
identify themselves to you so you don't
know what happended to you it's highly
it's very easy there's research papers
on injecting malicious apps into the
skill store although Amazon is very they
they say they're very diligent about
police and have conveying sensitive
information we never even got in that
part but it's across a medium that we
are designed to like here and process
and then the last one privilege
separation when it comes to basically up
one session token' for the device and it
is a forever session time so with that
thank you guys for coming been asking
questions all along but is there any
other questions that we didn't get to
real quick I don't want to be too unkind
to the next speaker
yes okay so for authentication I've seen
another company and do this where they
would they would give you the string of
numbers and say repeat these numbers
instead of saying like a phrase that you
can kind of piece out record its data
better security solution or say gonna
read this phrase with that help you know
basically any any audio that you use if
this is a single source of audio then it
could be spooked it can be played but
they have a program that would say okay
I'm gonna it would have to have all at
mine you mean like a capture of a voice
yeah you could replay it because it's
random right they're gonna say repeat
these random numbers yeah and if you
don't you you'd have to piece it in
together and then play it right not
really because
second half of this talk was all about
voice money and so nutshell there as I
conclude your voice in like ten minutes
or so of sample data and then I could
play whatever I wanted
oh so you can just you can make it up
right okay
yes of all the things you listed that
need to happen feel like think they are
that's one area of intense research
yes absolutely sir or absolutely yes
thank you guys and