hopefully everybody got some good talks
and today learned a lot of new things
right awesome so this talk is going to
be a little bit of a departure from what
I talked about are the types of things
typically it's a little more technical
this is going to be what's more focused
on the privacy aspect and aspect of
owning smart devices or using services
so the title of this talk
Alexa knows my kids better than I do I
think it kind of sums up the state of
devices today I really you know just
just they're invasive as when they're
pervasiveness into our daily lives and
I'm gonna go back through that course
here in just a minute
other than what has been introduced
already I am a husband and father of
four
I am also known as the Eco manager of
household operations at my own I work
for security and in solutions as
mentioned and I mainly deal with
enterprise security monitoring solutions
so helping people to stand up
oh space intrusion detection systems
network-based intrusion detection log
management types of stuff like that so I
love doing that stuff however this of
course again is a nice departure from
that I love coffee and I have to have
coffee in the morning please I'm talking
if I have to have it and I've had it and
I
security software enthusiasts which
means I love going through you know just
like security and it's completely
open-source I love going through and
other tools that can be abused to
enterprises and really trying to tie
those together to make them effective so
again our world today there's really a
complex assortment of devices everywhere
you look everywhere you go you're either
being recorded somebody or someone's
listening to you and these devices a lot
of them you know their roles really are
as an assistant presence so a digital
assistant may be that help with
collaboration with coworkers or maybe
just for entertainment purposes right we
wanted to tell us a joke or when in your
song things of that nature so being a
parent and really just a human being in
general this damage is kind of scary
because of all these things again so
many things to interact with and so much
data capture and really stored outside
of our control or we don't know if it's
been duplicated and elsewhere just lots
of things to consider devices services
so Alexa in general most of you probably
know what Alexa is already there's
anybody here in having it at Alyssa
enable device in their own they're
currently using
oh so in a nutshell just a virtual
assistant developed by Amazon super
popular these days uses a natural
language processing to go do things for
you and remember results and it
ultimately it just provides that
capability for automation and
convenience right so just allowing you
to go do stuff like setting a timer
playing a song or something else
I'm just hopefully saving you time and
giving you some benefit out of that
process now there are a ton of a lesson
enabled devices you can see a few here
of course the echo echo dot show and of
course they're integrated into other
third parties like neck get your saw
hardware I'm sorry GE so smart switches
smart outlets all sorts of stuff even
devices running Windows 10 can use Alexa
along with Cortana so once again it
gives you a lot of capability at really
Amazon a lot of capability to peer into
your life and the lives of your family
to see what's going on see what you're
doing a few stats so right here some of
these are from different time periods
but it was really the most it's credible
that I can find so twenty thousand
number was the number of unique devices
on which Alexa is available right so
you're talking about across hardware
manufacturers you're talking about
different models and stuff like that and
the number of skills available so those
skills typically refer to you know
something Alexa can do of his service
reaching out to us
and then finally 100 million there are a
hundred million devices running Alexa in
general her sold at least to the public
today and that was at the end of q4 of
18 so they're obviously way out so how
it works in a nutshell and this is an
extremely technical at all so please
forgive any technical inaccuracies but
in general lessons waiting on a wait
word right so it's waiting on you to
give it that hot where it's a traitor
and do its thing so it's always
listening you know like locator and I'll
show you that the device is listening
and we store the echo devices and it
will go off once you say that hot word
and that word and then it will go off to
the cloud servers it'll say hey what you
got for me yeah but either way you know
once it's received it once is triggered
that hot word the surface are gonna
store that possible yeah always
recording and then they're gonna try to
if you have the development features
enabled their automatic they're going to
try to train Alexa with that and they're
just gonna store it indefinitely on
their servers unless you go mess with it
or review it so once again once it gets
back to those results its visit out to
you and either understood what you said
or it didn't and you know you get
something back yourself also how it
works in a nutshell this sounds like
wait word right and I think it happens
all too often with with many folks and
and I'll talking about a little bit more
second but something else you know this
is a man record in this ticker
conversation nice is like don't worry it
is and then the clown says once again
let's store it so they still store the
data even though it wasn't a valid
request and then alexinnz comes back
won't respond the board of the study
that doesn't know what it is so it's
it's something to keep in mind that not
only it is valid requests you know it's
listening in for that WIC word and not
only this reality of was that provide
the WIC word but ones that sound
acoustically similar and they'll be able
to effectively discern it and you know
that's it's gonna be a flaw with the
software in general so once again a wait
word is not always awake word mistakes
happen everybody knows computers are
hard
humans are not perfect no where are the
machines that they intend to perfect
right so an imperfect human can I create
a perfect machine therefore we have to
expect some mistakes are gonna occur and
some day is gonna be collected when it
was not inside too
and here's Chuck Norris just kicking a
negative doctors all right so they've
collected Emma's on collects a lot of
data now just general I'm going to that
but through the alexa service it's
really trying to provide it's extending
to that service to provide 360-degree
view of yourself to amazon and this is
all really for Amazon to of course
potentially make more money they're
trying to do a profile of you right so a
lot of times when when folks think about
you know they're taking my data and
simply solo to third parties and stuff
like this it's not necessarily the case
with Amazon or they like the service
it's much more valuable for them to have
your data and be able to use that data
and have exclusively since I believe it
was seventy-five percent of most folks
doing online shopping done it
so they definitely want that information
they don't want to give that away so
easily so some of the data that it
collects is with regards to language
right so our vocabulary the words that
we use right so people with different
upbringing as may use different
vocabulary you know people just people
in general right just depending on their
education level or their personal
preferences and it seeks to understand
that to better training service all
right
so it's taking that voice recording and
everything that it's learning from you
and analyzing all those words that you
say in addition your speech patterns so
maybe your cadence right so the way that
I am talking now it may see things like
that and better learn to process speech
with pauses or things like that so there
are a lot of different ways that it
processes work it interprets your
language to better people to you in the
future
so personal preferences honestly a lot
of you know websites or services do this
but again this is you know using the
service it's again another entry point
to providing that data and compiling a
profile the deadline floor so it might
be John there's a music for which you're
searching specific artists things like
that it might be types of venues for you
know if you're looking they go out drink
have a buy a pizza things like that and
of course maybe styles of clothing that
you purchase you know what which would
make some where it's all looking at
these different things trying to go to
and once again that's kind of guys in
hand sorry in a hand in hand with the
personal preferences of course a lot of
those personal preferences are going to
be tied to certain buying habits right
so well people may not always act on
approaches you know from searching for
these different items and they're still
gonna track the types of things that
we're buying the brands of things that
you're buying how often you're buying it
are there certain intervals they buy so
maybe they can recommend or they can
fold in some type of discount later
based on your buying habits right it's
all for that whole money dollar some
other data so if you have any Smart
Switches right and they smartly outlets
house fixtures lamps still like that so
like thermostats that use Alexa and echo
B or something it's going to store all
of that as well so if we get status
indicators from that various details
from those devices right and it's gonna
store all that and once again with your
other activity once again I just want to
reiterate on the voice recordings that
Alexa I'm sorry the Amazon storing
through this device of service you have
this clips of audio that are stored from
successful and unsuccessful attempts so
again that's something to keep in mind
and these are really stored indefinitely
unless they go out proving them because
I'm you know there's no need to give her
that data and rolling
some of that that marketing power or
appeal then they won't do it
and by the way I'm not trying to make it
in the house and that guy so today to
review are you - sing this in the news
recently it came out most popular has no
last few days but Amazon actually
employs a lot of people that look at
these voice recordings they're
essentially trained to go through and
look at these and help train the Alexa
service to better utilize his voice
recordings and interpret them so it
helps them to transcribe that the
workers health and scientists yeah
transcribe that information and when I
mentioned that loaded details are paired
with these recordings I still feel like
an account number a person a mana device
serial number are still not something
that I would want associate it was a
recording and I would think that it's
still not that difficult to correlate
that with user identity right either
through another customer service
representative or some other access that
that boy had I said that I think it's me
a little pause and once again recordings
even consist of private conversations
singing in the shower I children the
crying for help
you know maybe they got a boo-boo and
they're asking for dad my mom are you in
criminal activity right I mean it's
anything
so a few kicks is in the news I
mentioned that they announced the the
workers that I was analyzing the
recordings but there's also another case
so State vs Timothy barrel this was a
double murder case in which an echo
device was present and the judge
actually ordered the recordings to be
turned over to the state of New
Hampshire you know this is something
that we're gonna see then and again time
and time again as his devices
proliferate in people's homes I'm gonna
see potentially turned over to
government for some sort of purpose or
effort to either prove or disprove a
crime right
another case James based in Arkansas was
another suspected murder of colleague it
was eventually dropped the charges were
he actually voluntarily handed over
their horns though in that case you know
it might have actually helped him that
he had that and it disproved their
hypothesis or at least I did not give
any credence to you know there are other
arguments and also a family in Portland
Oregon you might have heard about this
one they were talking about some of our
wood floors just chilling at home and
for some reason right now they're Alexa
thought they wanted to initiate
interaction with Alexa and then that
private conversation actually got sent
to one of the husband's contacts with
one of the workers as employees so
there's definitely some stuff there that
once again kind of gives me pause and I
struggle with this
because of things like this ultimately
it's about trust right we are trusting
Amazon to protect our data as well as
our children's data whenever they're
recording this right and the best
assurance that we have is the thing or
are the things that they tell us through
public announcements through the terms
of use on the website through the
privacy settings that we enable are
disabled and that's really all we know
unless there's some some big breach
right where it comes out that you know
some things were handled as we thought
they were so that's really all we have
is trust we can trust them but honestly
we have nobody to verify the verify
and I want to talk about kids so
obviously I you guys know kids know a
lot of Technology at school right and I
rides with a lot of Technology so you
know there's computer-based learning all
this stem right all these activities
that are allowing kids to interact with
you know different services and
different concepts and it's important
that we really teach some of these
things well and I'll get to that in just
a minute and of course at home right
other technology and entertainment
purposes like YouTube Facebook my plate
for tonight minecraft roblox that my
kids have tech knowledge is not
necessarily a bad thing just with adults
profiles so Amazon all sorts of people
and that services are leveraging those
profiles and data points to market and
appeal to various folks right and that's
one thing that we have to keep in mind
as parents how our kids interact with
that how what kind of profile they're
gonna have published by the time they're
18 already nothing interacted with these
services
and profiles right so profiles really
consist of hundreds sometimes thousands
of data points just depends really on
what aspects of these services that you
interact with another gathered through
various interactions there's personal
details that spoke up before are all
garnered into this profile and simply
those profiles are paired with things
like predictive analytics right so some
make decisions basically about how it's
going to market to users what's going to
appeal to them and things of that nature
right and these profiles may even yield
the tales that maybe parents don't know
about their kids right how they've
interacted with service details that
derailleur conversation or regular
interaction us as human beings would not
know so it's very important that we are
aware of that activity and you know just
just thinking about that kind in the
back your head what kind of profile are
you said how worried your children or
profile I think I have when they're
older
again use of technology with limited
knowledge or awareness can be dangerous
it can cause unintended consequences
right and I promise I don't have the
tempo hat on I'm just trying to kind of
keep you yeah
just thinking about these things and
potential long-term irrevocable effects
right everything that we put on the
internet it's there forever right and
this activity or you know this limited
use is really propagated through social
norms right it's normal to use Facebook
right it's normal to use Alexa it's
normal to do all of these things so I'll
talk a little bit about that so social
norms really what are they they're
unwritten rules a behavior acceptable
anywhere in society and you have various
types of course both ways more instead
boobs won't getting that into that too
much but they essentially exist to
provide order and society and really
it's important for us to as human beings
to be effective in society to conform to
the contract need to be an effective
member of our society and in the past
expectation of privacy was always social
norm right so it's just a given
so going with a bit more on social norms
they're driven by advancements and
technology so things like watching even
throwing the stranger things playing for
that again or utilizing smart devices in
general these are become social norms
for us right norm to trade that
convenience so what happens if we don't
conform to these social
yeah yeah privacy either that right so
we can lighten men you mean we don't
have to use these do you mean it's not
that much of a benefit to use these but
I'm still giving away all this privacy I
don't think I want to do that so I mean
there could be enlightenment right it's
not always the case
there could be alien Asian I can cause a
decrease in confidence anxiety or
increase things I think and it can
affect relationships right like we
secure the Grandma's house anymore
yeah we've talked to her over the echo
show ok so how does that affect your
relationship and then also affecting
change so it offers a new perspective
you know folks that don't want you see
these devices but it requires the cool
clear second support and really early
you know being a stakeholder and really
supporting me through that and affecting
other people so what happens if we can
form when we need to cookies right we
have a natural desire to conform to peer
pressure and group judgment so we have
to set that loss of privacy which really
isn't immediately quantifiable and only
at the seats of the use of the Alexus
service can we really begin to I guess
calculate and not really to a finite
degree the effects of what's been
reported or what we've provided so once
again I'm running low on side we're
mishandling exposure I'm sorry there's
the potential for
and when your exposure there so we can't
trust that it's always going to be
handled correctly even though this is
and we're always training convenience
over prices is demanding here is that
we're giving them bits of data so that
we can go set a timer for an egg right
and they can make mad cash and that's
just I mean yes there are certain
certain benefit but it's just really you
know it depends on that so we can take
that control don't take steps right so
we can have a proactive approach and a
lot of that's really built into in Lund
settings themselves they've done a good
job of that I just think they could do a
better job of publicizing it right
making it more well known so there's an
interface there the Alexa privacy
okay sure all right and so then we can
actually see the voice history all the
voice recordings that Alexa has ever
recorded right
Alexa I'd like to watch the office
here's what I've found so it transcribed
that one right there because it's not
what I was talking about but this one up
here I didn't know what I was talking
about I was talking to my kids so it's
definitely important to review this type
of information I think on a regular
basis let's make sure that you know
there aren't in unintended consequences
there and once again the smart alert
history if you've got smart devices you
can see all that type of stuff here I'm
sorry like you know the switches and
outlets and things of that nature
even smoke and CO two Testaments right
and then this is really gonna be the
more general third-party home devices in
which you interact with where you can
delete the history there so it's also
another cool point and also to school
permissions you can limit the
permissions or at least you can review
them on here so each skill that you're
using you can see what permissions they
have in this various types of data and
finally I mentioned this earlier but the
feature development you can actually
disable participation on this and they
will not be reviewing your recordings
although they may still hand select some
of them from time to time they will not
go through that same procurement process
or that same review process and another
protection just muted right so it's
simple but effective you know you have
to go over there and what press apply
right but a trade convene surprises and
what's a DV trusted yeah yeah do you
trust it too and once you meet it do you
trust it right you trusted is actually
music all right all right or just play
it all together right no power there
were problems but but really what's the
point if you're on blame right if if you
you know it's just it really it takes
you know a certain expectation you just
have to have that hand in hand
expectation of privacy right like wait a
minute wouldn't even up could be nice
wise what's that yeah shooting you can't
she can't go to the fire
certainly yeah
but you know real quick just some
alternatives I just wanted to mention
not to try to sell people on not getting
a lesson in with devices but they're all
are open-source all turns out there
they'll actually store the data locally
and not send it off and you can do this
on your own Raspberry Pi as well and I
think West Widener and his talk
sound of evil actually talks about this
a little bit and he mentions this next
thing I'm going to talk about but yeah
Mycroft is that company pretty cool I
haven't done yet but definitely
interested in you have the mark one okay
some thinking the consideration so the
other thing I was gonna talk about is
project alias have you seen project
Davis at all no okay so this is
essentially again kind of a Raspberry Pi
type thing and a 3d printer thing where
you can sign it all together and you're
creating essentially a hat or a mask for
this and then it's going to sit on top
of there and it basically you know
intercepts any requests to that
microphone right so you're essentially a
listing in that divot yeah sure
all right so so yeah you know and and
again like I said what's wider to the
tail is this a little more technically
in his talk so I definitely check that
out
he's on YouTube he's done said what
besides and he was just that this piece
out today in the same talk so it's a
very good pretty good song I encourage
you to check it out but other than that
I will leave you some additional
resources really just the Alexa Terms of
Use and privacy settings I think are
just a big helping themselves just what
they're already publishing for you
howa manages data and of course West
winding down here checking out his talk
there's this Twitter handle right there
[Applause]
alright alright and that is it contact
you can reach me on Twitter hit me up at
the real W Lambert
[Applause]