[Applause]
salut Bienvenue
well Jill to the Mancha Street offensive
this jet but you see Oh she'll clean Jim
had passed Jim that they won't say Jim
OC love it when we take the fella say
avec food and now I will speak in
English okay I'm really excited to talk
to you about one of my very favorite
subject areas thanking on insecurities
so first of all who am i Cheryl this
boss I work in cybersecurity now I am
with a small firms I Kira include it's
offensive stuff I was with KPMG before
that I have a lot of interests as you
can see I have a poli-sci degree so it's
important to remember anything you learn
you can bring into the security
community and use I love to give talks
and I'm also a founding member of the
Diana initiative where we promote women
in security and diversity finally online
I'm known as encrypted and last but not
least the views expressed here are my
own not those of my employer but let's
get started a couple of years ago when I
was a total newb
I saw patterns repeating themselves and
while that might be good at knitting it
is not such a good thing for security
and bad behaviors lead to lot security
the basics well they weren't being done
well if they were being done at all and
I found attitudes ranged from blissful
ignorance to adamant denials again
history repeats itself and that's not
necessarily a good thing you can make
book on that so we're seeing big data
become bigger data and IOT taking over
the world right but we are still not
getting the basics right the problem is
we rely on what we know or what we think
we know we're living in a world of some
pretty dangerous assumptions and
that's leading to some cracks in the
framework of what run our daily lives so
what I want to point out is that
information security cyber security
these do not live in silos
these are integral to everything that we
do now we get that everybody else not so
much
let's talk about some blasts from the
past who's familiar with Conficker how
about everybody knows Stuxnet good good
bedtime reading who's familiar with the
stories around Saudi Aramco two words
wiper mal they're their dad stuff and it
made a resurgence this year
how about Hartley oh geez yeah and who's
still cleaning up after this one okay
there are candies candies for all of you
because you've suffered so much I know
and it's just like it keeps coming back
it never went away
yeah so we're not we keep repeating
mistakes and the problem is this is not
like the movie Groundhog Day we're not
getting better at doing the same thing
over and over what we're doing is
leaving windows of opportunity open and
when you do that who needs back doors
right so the attackers are literally
banking on our insecurities which brings
for me anyway a few things to mind and
I'm going to share them with you that
what we need to say isn't being said
that's why I did this talk I did it
behind closed doors in Vegas and I just
had so many people coming up saying they
have a lot to say but they can't talk
about it but it's what we share with
each other that's crucial that
information helps us spot patterns do
trends identify things in the malware
that link one group to another so that
we can see their next move their next
pivot so let's talk about Swiss baby and
we are going to or how about geopolitics
and who's playing whom because there is
a real art to the long game and China
and Putin are masters at it that's
playing out in the theater real right
now because it isn't all about the money
let's talk about what attackers do
better than us I've got two words for it
collaboration and communication the fact
is these guys have learned how to work
with each other because cybercrime is an
extremely efficient business model these
guys share their information work
effectively as defenders we have to get
it right all of the time as attackers
they only have to get it right once what
we benefit from as a community what we
thrive out as a community is the
information that we share and teach each
other and that we need to communicate so
there were not all of us working in a
silo heads down trying to find something
that already exists this will give us a
leg up it will save us time and time is
a luxury we don't have
so let's move into stories about Swift
ok so we assume that banks especially
Swift right if you know anything about
Swift and you're going to after this
take better care of our money than
anybody ok so what is Swift other than a
very important international
organization with a couple hundred plus
members and a lot of money involved it
originated to facilitate transfer
payments between nation-states and and
it was done to make it easier more
efficient and faster these are really
important words in business in
bottom-line and in profit we know that
business is what drives us we know that
we serve the businesses we are part of
however it does not mean security so
Swiss cents payment orders between
institutions and it uses unique Swift
codes this was based on a relationship
management application that runs over a
bilateral key exchange
so essentially is about syntax processes
and a turnkey solution for ease of use
when Swit talks about itself it talks in
terms of efficiency this is what
business understands is reliable now we
know that we're supposed to trust but
verify right
however when we're being told we are
supposed to trust an organization like
Swift because it is the best at what it
does we do and then there's this okay so
we've got availability levels which are
a proof of their security equipment okay
please tell me anybody does security
equate with up time is up time
equivalent to secure anybody there's
chocolate on this no there is chocolate
chocolate for the room yes over there
security is not uptime I'm sorry okay
so since I got to give that talk on
Swift and that was like a summer ago and
I built it as a fairy tale on banking
security I have been following a steady
stream of attacks building a knowledge
base on it looking at the trends that
have been developing and it it really
has not led up so what I'm seeing here
is so much more than a cash graph and
that's really important what happened
with Swift the trusted messengering
service is a really important lesson for
everybody who's in the financial
industry and then security as a whole
this story for me was always so much
more about not the attackers trying to
get a billion dollars and only getting
81 million what what it was was three
questions it was who was behind those
hackers why did they specifically target
the Bank of Bangladesh and who was
desperate enough to digitally rob a bank
ah okay so this was from BAE Systems
when they initially identified the
attack and it's really quite fascinating
in terms of I would call it the
sophistication of the attack the
components that they knew how to
leverage you're working with what is
essentially a closed system and it was
accessible to the members however we
know that net attackers lurk in the
networks for as long as they need to and
they gather recon they get in and then
they live there because we don't find
them we don't find them because we're
not looking for them this goes back to
let's get the basics right we know this
and that is what they were making book
on so somebody figured out what the weak
point in that money chain was for Swift
the daily transfer printouts paper
printouts of the transfers this is a
highly sophisticated system but they
rely on paper transfers paper printouts
of the transfers every day this is key
because it's quite the story now it came
out in the news that it was all at the
fault of a $10 switch okay we all know
server room terrorists right everybody
has seen that server room of cables and
stuff that should not be in there and
it's easy to point the finger of blame
but the fact is I think that's held up
as a reflection to all of us to learn
from it wasn't because of that $10
switch it was because of everything
around why there was a $10 switch in
service it was because of a printer this
printer to be exact and that's kind of
the brilliance of the scheme so a whole
lot of checking and monitoring the files
was going on not by Swift by the bank by
the attackers the attackers were
watching every single move every single
line of code making sure they knew when
that printer kicked in what it needed
what it did why because the malware they
they wrote for this intercepted the
confirmation Swift messages so it read
it parsed and then it converted those
into PRT files and then into the
specific PCL language used by this this
model of printer that's very exact
somebody really did their homework and
then these temporary PRT files were
submitted and once they came through
they got overwritten with zeros and were
prospectively deleted enabling the
attackers to step in at that point
control the process and walk away with
the money so there's a lot of
speculation there was a lot of
speculation at that time about whodunit
and I'll admit my my trio was the
obvious ones China Russia North Korea
now in this case Russia and China really
weren't good targets because they're too
big to make this kind of noise this kind
of a power play globally they knew they
would suffer eternal condemnation it
wasn't in it it wasn't in it for them
and it was only really a billion dollars
these these two nations did not need a
billion dollars badly enough to put
themselves in the hot seat however North
Korea is the different story this is a
nation if you know anything about it
that is impoverished it really is it's
it's sad and the people there are
starving because of the way the country
is being run because their wild card of
a leader will stop at nothing to get his
nukes this is a fact and we now have
watched it play out arms Fox and CNN
real life so how long did it take for it
to come apparent it was the Lazarus
group at work in North Korea with a
wrench and with a wrench because in many
parts of our world coercion is how you
get things done and they needed
something to get the initial access and
then to cover their tracks so my theory
was that Lil Kim wanted all of the same
nuclear toys all the other cool kid
ha but we know that good nukes cost
money right and Kim had broken his piggy
bank some while ago the things we do for
money his nation was starving so he had
some very capable houseguests known as
the Lazarus group living under his room
now does anybody know the story of
Lazarus what that term means in the bib
in the Bible it's about a guy who rose
from the dead so it's used to imply
somebody who literally can rise up from
the dead and this is a hallmark of this
group they will they will do their acts
they will disappear only to reappear
again their ephemeral and they have been
impossible really to pinpoint to a
specific entity or party very
interesting there ven DDoS attacks
dating from 2009 you can see they're
involved in a list of very interesting
activities and even this year there was
some wiping of master boot records going
on because of them they're able to make
their work look like hacktivism so that
throws you know a red herring in the
works and harder to attribute and as we
know attribution unfortunately is the
hardest thing to do and one of those
roadblocks that keeps us from moving
forward we can't move forward and you
can't pin that big pin the finger of
blame until you are absolutely certain
well they've been active in sabotaging
operations in a range of industries not
just financial and a pretty wide swath
of nations have been impacted now North
America is only just beginning to feel
their talents and is it me or is it that
we don't pay attention as much until it
actually lands on North American soil
anybody want to weigh in on that one
does it have to actually land on our
doorstep before we will take action like
I said time is a luxury we don't have
The Washington Post issued a really
interesting article very recently
analyzing what was happening in terms of
the nuclear developments in North Korea
assessing Kim Jong as the type of leader
and not in a rational leader somebody
with a game plan that we had
underestimated or sidestepped because it
looked too crazy basically they said
that if you deem Kim Jon you need to be
irrational you are implicitly under
estimating him and we might be doing
that for a few other things as well
he's crazy but he's crazy like a fox and
that's why attacks were being made on
thanks that the rest of the world really
wasn't paying attention to it was
Switzerland uh-huh it was England mm-hmm
it was the US for sure but go put it in
some place in Southeast Asia that people
don't really know about there's not very
much attention and it's actually
division it gets pointed there so case
in point let me well let me say this
it's not our world over there
like I said coercion is how things get
done this is the nation that doesn't
have the resources to work with that we
take for granted on a daily basis they
don't have the money and they don't have
the training and they don't have the
mindset to put in place the security
practices needed to really secure a
financial facility so if corruption
could end coercion or how things get
done in the rest of the world how did
these get factored on a nist spreadsheet
and security audits
this is the heist by numbers what had
been recorded up to date and then very
recently taiwan has weighed in with an
attack on them now the attackers went
after about sixty million dollars so far
most of that has been got me back
there's about five hundred thousands
still on return and they are absolutely
this time attributing it to the lazarus
group so lessons let's do a swift recap
now this isn't the first time that a
nation states handed over the dirty work
to an independent contractor you can bet
that russia has done that as well as the
united states and other major countries
but in what is essentially a win-win
scenario except of course for the bank
of bangladesh the attackers went after
that cool billion and save for what was
a pesky spelling mistake on the transfer
which got rejected they had to walk away
with the 81 million here are the banks
involved and this third point i'm going
to ask you to remember this we'll come
back to it
I thought this was very telling it's a
wake-up call for those just tuning in
yeah it is true because when it comes to
the games that nation-states play well
Kabul economic chaos it's right up there
so let's talk about shadow brokers and
you know that other shoe it's gonna drop
because you can count all of the cards
but that wild card is going to turn up
and when it does nation state exploits
are now out there the turtle blue we
know what happens and thus kiddies have
them and they are playing with them so
I'm going to share a little post
Halloween Horror Story with you okay
chocolates chocolates for those who did
not get chocolate yes yes
Oh guys oh I'm a horrible pitchy garden
[Laughter]
okay I promise
laters okay let's talk about what was in
that treasure trove that the shadow
brokers revealed as their Easter egg on
Good Friday
Ars Technica said this not me so Swift
Swift was adamant at the time that they
had not been hacked or their code their
code had not been hacked
well sorry not sorry because that Good
Friday dump was full of stuff
including code for hacking banks that
were part of the Swift Network in
particular thanks in the Middle East and
these belong to a cheaper offshoot of
the Swift Network known as service
bureaus and these act is like their
they're like cloud services for banks
but they're less expensive because it
costs money to pay money and Swift is
very pricey well one of those was called
east nets and remember this is the
United States the NSA their exploits
east nets is one of 74 certified service
bureaus within the Swift Network so
they're all part of this trusted network
until Swift says oh you're not as good
as we are and actually they do that
I'm all for value but I'm gonna raise
the question here what isn't it's more
easily targeted because it wasn't a
premiums with offering I don't know if
any of you know of Matt's wish but he is
a security researcher a Microsoft MVP
and quite active on Twitter he has some
excellent accounts in a blog post and I
follow him for stuff especially breaking
news and he did a really good take down
in terms of what was in the shadow
brokers treasure trove and and how it
impacted the Swift Network especially
those Middle Eastern banks he said this
given the small number of these service
bureaus of which there is just 74 and
that they have like maybe one IP address
how easy would it be to compromise any
if not all of these service bureaus I
believe that one with you
Matt's wishes ago - for me for many
reasons and I really I'll have some
information on my very last slide if you
want to look it up further he provided
some screenshots at the time of the dump
and explanations about how the NSA had
actually compromised with before North
Korea was even in this game so here you
can see some of the findings that were
in that trove that stuff that should
never be available these are compromised
in men accounts sophisticated these were
multi-stage attacks that bypassed the
Cisco AAS a firewall appliances so they
exploited and they infected the Windows
servers and then they copied the Oracle
databases of the numerous hosts that
belong to Swift now we know that Oracle
has many bad dates right we know that
Windows is Windows nonetheless this was
not something that should have ever
happened and it is as bad as it sounds
because these service bureaus were part
of what was considered to be a trusted
network moreover Matt and I would agree
with him on this one likens it to
Stuxnet in that this was that very
rarest of occasions when a nation-state
targeted another nation-state with a
bunch of O'Day's yeah that is very very
significant it went after that
nation-states critical infrastructure
with those Oh dates and banks are
critical infrastructure
here's the list of targets that the NSA
exploits were targeted at from as early
as 2013 and that are now out there and
being played with so this is the
equivalent of hacking all of the banks
in the region without having to attack
them individually right this is very
easy to easy and why we should be
worried because this way you can access
all of their transactions compromised
this is what it actually looked like
when you run the exploits against for
example the Palestinian Bank and over
here there's hard corded hard coded
passwords in those credentials that were
lifted from the machine language from
that treasure trove and that's exploits
for sale so yeah stuff happens right but
this is what stuff happens looks like
when it's global financial well let's
talk about attitudes
so this is one reason why I don't sleep
all at night I don't know but maybe one
in five bank executives being able to
detective Reach is that like pigs
sniffing out truffles this is actually a
higher percentage than most children who
believe in Santa Claus and this one well
I'm sorry to say but you know that if
you cover your eyes it does not make the
bad stuff go away yeah the struggle is
real and I have done audits and I've met
those who swear by their methods over
best practices and they manage our money
and these are the things I have heard
over and over again by people who
honestly honestly should know better
I can't say more except that you find
Adobe in places you never ever should
I'm going to take you through a little
tour of carven AK dry decks and lurk uh
show of hands who's familiar with these
or has heard of them okay these are some
Big Daddies of financial malware and
really good stories to tell and it's
continued to evolve and it's become more
sophisticated than when it first emerged
back in 2011 that was when it was known
as Primus I'm gonna give you a bit of a
history lesson because in history is
context we always need context that's
how we can build our patterns connect
the dots and try to best anticipate the
attackers next moment okay so some
hallmarks about draw about dry decks
it receives dynamic
configuration files it uses web
injections to steal money it infects USB
media and it hides the CNC servers
behind proxy layers all smart moves but
they're very good at it now it's not
unusual to see exploits fade away and
then they come back however I don't
think we're very good at expecting it it
seems like we get surprised every time
this happens for example Zeus thinks
does anybody familiar with Zeus as an
attack vector right so it came back
August of 2016 and went after Brazilian
banks interestingly enough coinciding
with the Olympics there's always a
reason
well that activity appeared to die down
and then interestingly enough IBM
x-force researchers discovered it at
work
newer refurbished going after specific
targets in terms of Canadian and
Australian credit unions credit unions /
banks why credit unions are smaller
smaller means they don't have as much
money they don't have the resources or
the mindset to really have the defenses
in place
it makes them excellent low-hanging
fruit right for the picking there were
about 33 URLs that they identified and
interestingly enough the attackers and I
guess this is part of it and this is why
we're looking for the patterns they were
using the same CNC service that had been
initially deployed back to 2016 for Zeus
Citadel attacks and remnant lurk well
this one's from Russia With Love it was
part of a cybercrime operation used in
the click-fraud back around 2011 again
the Russians are really good at this
stuff so the gang went after about 29
million in customer accounts and then
they got a little greedy and they went
after 39 million using false payment
transfers Oh does that sound familiar
it's a less Swift and those were blocked
so it got retooled and revamped to
exploit weaknesses in bank security of
which there are many
and it was coupled with the angler
export now there was an international
effort amongst law organizations that
actually succeeded in taking these guys
down and then the angler exploit
actually disappeared from view one
interesting point to note and this is a
score for the bank's they identified
this attack and actually changed their
defenses to recognize and meet it so yes
it can be done this is one case but it's
hope now Cisco Talos has identified that
the lurking was also involved with the
necker's botnet has anybody heard of the
necros botnet right okay good and it's
important because who's heard of walky
walky ransomware
it distributed locky ransomware along
with droid x banking malware okay and
that brings us to Dooku and file the
smeller who here has heard of file of
malware or had to even deal with it it
is scary freakin fascinating stuff and
it is derived from thing that brought me
here
Stuxnet which we've heard about one of
those offshoots so do goo 2.0 was
discovered by Kaspersky six months after
it had been residing on their networks
their corporate networks and this is
because it lives in the memory of the
computers so it's very hard to trace
anything that's memory resident we
understand how that works it's terrible
if you're trying to do forensics and we
need to do forensics in order to
understand what went wrong so when an
infected computer gets rebooted it
actually changes the name and you are
looking for the wrong thing it's already
over here given something else another
interesting point about Dooku is our
Dooku 2.0 is that the calling card has
to do with embedding PowerShell
into the registry to download as
meterpreter and this has become a trend
over this past year something very
interesting to note this is new has
anybody been following their parts have
you heard of silence so we all know the
importance of doing recon correct any
mission especially if you're on
offensive security you need to
understand your target the attackers are
excellent at recon and this gives them a
leg up on us now
what's key is while it looks like our
veena and it borrows from it it is not
carbon AK it's already had about 10
different banks that's attacked and it's
still ongoing it utilizes spear phishing
emails to download and execute the
droppers there's a backdoor which sends
the system information then malicious
code is delivered affected pres are
stolen everybody cries and it starts the
screens recording so yes everything
that's attached to the network that is a
screen is potentially activated to
record what the bank employees are doing
and this is how you gain initial access
very important point
does anybody have a guess as to what
this map is about there's chocolate I
will throw you a chocolate just because
okay what have I been talking about big
word starts with C anybody okay Oh
carbon a carbon arc yes so there's a
song that goes everything old is new
again and this is a case for carbon AK
in order to really understand attackers
what we need to understand is history
for the point of context to really
appreciate their pivots and finding
context within their past pursuits we
can get a sense of where they're headed
to next we need to be able to do that
now we've been watching carbon act pivot
from banking into hospitality and retail
it's gone after chimichangas it's gone
after our favorite fast-food places damn
them but yes because in this industry
which has far less money to spend on
securing itself low-hanging fruit is
always in season yes and we know that
cybercrime is based on efficiency it is
the perfect business model but carbon
arc is too established within the
financial realm to forever leave it so
they have been doing you know retooling
themselves and what they have done is
upgrade to exploit some of our favorite
tools who here does offensive security
pen testing so you know things like
Metasploit meterpreter veil and
PowerShell things that we used for the
powers of good they now use for the
powers of evil and the other thing is
that this is not signature based malware
so I'm sorry No
Junia you cannot use virustotal cuz
first key Symantec McAfee and God knows
what else
silence they're not going to pick these
things up anymore we can't rely on it
like we used to so we have to evolve
with these new attacks if we go looking
using these we are not going to find
them and honest to god they are in there
so I'm going to walk you through what is
essentially the pivot of carbon AK and
the operation gran Mars motive money
control and total ownership right
collaboration they do it better than we
do spider labs reports analyze this and
talked about how several groups came
together so that's different signatures
and you would only have known this if
you were tracking the different
signatures of these groups and
recognized those footprints in the
butter now there is still validity in
signature based identification if we're
actively monitoring it know what to look
for and what it's relevant to oh that's
a lot of work though and are we going to
get the backing from the people who will
pay for it I don't know they have to be
able to prove the validity of it
another point is being able to share
threat intelligence which again who here
is a proponent of sharing threat
intelligence who here thinks it's not
such a great idea
no share knowledge who here has a gag
order by their company that they're not
allowed to say what they think I'm so
sorry here have a chocolate okay
so yes you could be warned if you've got
the monitoring setup on your systems to
track for specific signatures number
three we know that this is the most
common attack vector this is how they
get out well how far would you be
willing to go to stop them at this step
does anybody here listen to the podcast
breaking down security with Brian break
all right he had a guest on recently I
love a lot of podcasts this is one of
them Michael Gough is an expert on
ransomware
he's given some really good talks and
one of them was about how he analyzed
the human factor now we all know that
the human condition is our biggest
challenge how the hell do we keep people
from clicking on things right that's it
that's the essence of phishing Michael
Gough said well maybe we we don't maybe
we just go one step above the humans the
way you could have baby gate up across
stairs and we make it so that it doesn't
matter how many times they click nothing
happens so he did an experiment over the
course of a year and he went into their
systems and enabled their systems to not
recognize that double-click now they
didn't lose business it was probably
very different for people people don't
like change and it was probably slower
or harder but the fact is it went from
like a ridiculous percentage of 60
percent down to 2 percent within a year
because the attackers realized and they
were measuring their statistics that
nothing was getting through they stopped
they stopped they found somebody else to
bother they moved on I would recommend
you listen to this podcast if you would
like to see how you might implement
out-of-the-box thinking because that's
what's gonna do it
and I thought it was fascinating
moving on they passed the hash for
privilege escalation we're familiar with
that step persistence
we're familiar with that part by a
scheduled tasks so if you're not really
looking at things if you're just
expecting to see things you're gonna
miss this
and then the attackers gain their domain
and admin in C&C points both in Europe
as well as the US then they leveraged
cloud services enterprise access who
here who here has to deal with the joy
of cloud services on a daily basis how
happy does that make you in your job who
here understands the concept of shadow
IT exactly so that if you are thinking
you have 60 cloud services how many do
you really have it's an exponential
number you've got 600 oh yes that is
what's going on and once it's like
Pandora's freaking box once it's out
there you cannot take it back
you cannot restrict it it exists and you
have to live with it
so the attackers built this malicious
code and it utilized the memory resident
PowerShell and JavaScript VBS right so
it's taking some tools that we all know
and are familiar with and turning them
to evil we've seen like TV movies about
people who've got red eyes blowing it's
kind of like that Metasploit powershell
veil
these are frigging powerful programs
when you are a pen tester they are
really good at what they do so in the
hands of somebody that you do not trust
it's a bad bad thing there was a remote
backdoor for data exfiltration and then
I hate this part valid Komodos
certificates for the whim
we've seen over the past several years
what happens with trusted certificates
what happens to companies that don't do
a good job managing their trusted
certificates you cannot really trust
trusted certificates is what I'm trying
to say and this is now part of a
systematic series of attacks against
hospitality but not just hospitality
this is going into retail point of sales
machines how many terminals are in one
Walmart how many Walmart's are out there
how many grocery stores are out there
and e-commerce so the target base is
massive and if you just do the numbers a
little bit of money over a lot of people
adds up fast
hackers are smart with math and then
finally they changed up the command and
control servers so they put one down and
take one up again to throw people off
the scent tricky but it worked
well we live by this saying don't we
it doesn't always play out so coming
back to my litany on trusted
certificates being not so trustworthy
does anybody have another example of
untrustworthy trusted certificates they
want to throw my way well is that thank
you
very good come up you get a chocolate
when you win and when we're done okay
and there's been more we we have systems
in place with breaks that we cannot fix
this is a key example and then the long
game
patience perseverance persistence they
get in there and they have a long-range
plan key would be China and Russia
they're really really good at this and
the problem is once we realize what's
going on
we're already pawns in the game it's
already playing out and that has become
our reality I'm gonna take you now on a
world tour of cybersecurity as I see it
the intersection of global security and
information security this is the man of
the hour isn't it holy crow so just he
who has all of the money make all of the
rules well two hundred billion dollars
says that he thinks so and resources and
staging grounds matter so back in August
of this year the banks in the Ukraine
braced for yet another attack if you're
not familiar with what's going on with
the Ukraine essentially Putin is
old-school KGB he would like Russia to
become the Soviet Union once again and
pull back all of the pieces that left it
and one of those pieces for him is to
Ukraine and he has been going after that
like
dog with a bone since 2015
so I likened it to Putin's petri dish
his fiber experiments in the Ukraine are
netting results but what's he going to
actually leverage those results against
in terms of a bigger fish a bigger
quarry and this was on the heels of the
Pecha not Pecha outbreaks
let's do a little walkthrough
geopolitics and global finance China is
an interesting case in point it's been
steadily acquiring pieces of Africa and
it using that for its staging ground we
hear about it we read about it in the
news but really don't make the dots
Africa is volatile and for them China is
just one in a succession of colonial
takeovers that have left that continent
nothing more than warring factions
regardless it offers China geography and
resources which that nation needs and
will put to very good use North Korea
well we have been watching the news
reports it's small but it's volatile and
it's unpredictable and it is driven by
the desire of its leader to have nuclear
capability and be the top the kingpin of
that he has to be in with all of the
other players and he's not going to stop
until he gets what he wants it costs
money
Kim has stable falls of hackers at his
disposal at his service and as well
he's only too willing to take on the
dirty work drugs trafficking and things
that we don't even really want to think
about the rest of the world won't touch
but he and will do this to fund his
habits and now I've got an interesting
story to share I'm going to use the
Polish Bank attacks from earlier this
year and I'm going to ask was anybody or
has anybody followed that story from
about the beginning of February this
year attacks on the Polish banks anybody
else it's a good story okay so a few
banks in a small country will teach all
of us an important security lesson there
were a series of targeted malware
attacks against Polish banks now again
why Poland this is like a little country
it does it's it combines its own
business it's actually very good in
terms of security and bank security and
research and they discovered they were
being hit and believe me I was watching
because I have a bad Twitter habit then
crying out for attention and persistence
when these attacks were going on and
they were saying we're really good in
and what's happening and has anybody
else seeing this and the silence was
deafening
so the attackers went after the data the
data and not the money that's
interesting and they left a very
interesting trail of traffic in terms of
exotic locations and encrypted
executables that nobody had ever seen
before that's a rarity in our community
really to see unusual like malware that
nobody can say where this came from
there are a lot of very smart lines out
there they were coming up empty on this
one I was following the Twitter it was
2:00 in the morning okay and there were
unauthorized files on key machines
within the networks so nothing really
happened until a group of commercial
banks said hey wait hey wait we've been
attacked and then people started paying
a whole lot of attention they realize
there was a problem they follow the
trail and it led to a poisoned well it
was a web server huh within the
regulatory body of Poland's financial
sector the regulatory body was issuing
the crap now do you want to know what
the interesting part is
tada hahaha it's the Lazarus group again
holy crap these guys get around and we
still don't know exactly who they are so
according to semantics this is a threat
actor behind about targeted financial
attacks within 31 other countries from
October 2016 the Polish website that was
used to target the Polish banks was
delivering a particular strain of
malware that wasn't since Heston's been
identified to be part of the toolkit
known to belong to the Lazarus group so
there's there's three strains I'll tell
you the names of them if you want to
make notes back or finless doctor
philosophy and back door canto P but you
can read more about it the fact is at
the time it was happening nobody had the
same information to connect the dots did
you hear that other shoe drop mmm okay
so this is what it looks like it's not
just Poland that was being targeted
there were a hundred and fifty different
IP addresses and you can see they're
worth banks and institutions Mexico
Brazil Great Britain nobody's exempt
from this but it was Poland it was kind
of like a red herring so they would go
after some other targets possibly more
lucrative targets that cyber was one of
the earliest blogs from a local guy in
Poland trying to make sense of what was
going on and asking why is nobody
listening because we got a problem here
and he said we need collaboration we
need to share this threat information
because we need to be able to identify
it and put the pieces together so I'm
going to share something that I noted
that is trending and I'm going to ask if
anybody else is familiar with it web
application compromise how many people
would say they've noticed a definite
trend in this in terms of becoming a
problem specifically targeting the
financial sector
well what's interesting is dark reading
just recently issued a piece on it and I
I know that I heard something on the
podcast and read the Verizon data breach
report earlier this year again that
identified this as a growing trend much
more of a threat to the financial sector
and actually eclipsing if it's possible
the human factor as a threat in breaches
I'm going to move on now to Southeast
Asia again another territory over and
above Bank of Bangladesh bank heist ATM
jackpot II who has heard of an ATM
jackpot II this is a it's a pretty cool
technique and the machines literally
spewing the money out at you it's a cash
grab that is a smart one and this was in
a it was called the cobalt siege it
covers a very wide swamp it is not
limited to just a few countries we've
got United Kingdom Spain Romania
Netherlands Malaysia and much of Eastern
Europe and it probably landed on the
Americas it's been dubbed as the new
model of organized crime because it
really works and the FBI has issued
warnings to US banks this past summer
because of it then there were some DDoS
attacks extortion accept attempts on
several banks in South Vietnam by a
group known as the Armada collective you
may have heard of them they're known for
issuing empty threats
big breads nothing happens I'm just
gonna say this where there's smoke there
will be fire I wouldn't call them empty
for a while and then there is Brazil I
call it the Dark Horse because it's
rather interesting it is the epicenter
of where banking malware is formed it's
mostly self-contained but it has a
thriving industry in financial
cybercrime
this is the country where corruption is
so entrenched they openly sell their
crime wears on social media like
Facebook is where you brag about the
exploit you've built and how much it is
for sale
not only that they offer training
courses for a few hundred bucks you can
get a really good education and how to
set up yourself in your own little crime
wailmer malware shop and it's a booming
business last but not least and I'll
call this a game-changer for good reason
we all know that CIA right
confidentiality integrity availability
this book turned on its head this past
year by petra naw Pecha when
availability because of ransomware has
become the most serious issue we are
contending with an availability isn't
just something that affects business
it affects hospitals it affects banks if
we can't get our cash
if we can't hook up to a life-support
system if we can't heat our homes and
it's 30 below yeah it really matters so
what about the fact that the latest
pivot and ransomware was not about the
money
it was never about the money it wasn't
designed to get money it was all about
attacking availability so money can't
buy happiness but what if they cannot
buy the essential or services that we
all rely on Ukraine wasn't banking on
that neither a week and this was a power
play
so integrity matters when you need to
restore your data and your systems we
know this is a problem DRC business
continuity people really don't have
plans in place and if they do they
haven't necessarily tested them we have
cloud services but have we actually
checked to see how the data syncs up I'm
asking this because I have a couple of
friends who guard and test the
mainframes who have worked in finance
for 25 years who are tough guys and
actually very scared about what they
find on an ongoing basis
we are not prepared for when we go to
restore after but is a catastrophic
event and the data doesn't think up
because somebody has been nimbly moving
through and exfiltrating one bit at a
time and that's all it takes so that's
pretty much it for me are there any
questions comments you would like to
share I know I'm kind of overwhelmed you
or maybe it's the chocolate all right
well this thumb it up yes
it is interesting it's the case of the
terrible parent the parent that will buy
themselves a pair of Louboutins or a
lovely Louis Vuitton handbag but their
kids are starving it's exactly that
mm-hmm yeah absolutely and I don't even
think the hackers are making that much
money they're scared and at least they
have a roof over their head and food on
their tables like other people don't
remember Kim Jon had his brother killed
so behaviors and attitudes are key
understanding or did you have a question
there is certainly I can speak to Canada
a lot of companies the finance as well
have been living under the they keep the
secret to themselves it's a dirty little
secret we now have a new data breach law
coming in effect that they have to
disclose when something happens this is
going to be a really big awakening call
for everybody because no you don't want
to stay I got breached
you don't want to say this was a problem
you don't want to show your weaknesses
also from a competitive advantage and
profit building you don't want to share
how you do business because you want to
stay ahead of the path and that's that
mentality that's enforcing behaviors
yeah yeah
no it's not my personal opinion it's
gleaned from a lot of research and
looking at what people are saying and
connecting the dots and being able to
say okay this keeps coming up when
something keeps coming up we've really
got an issue and it's being reinforced
by numerous voices however we haven't
recognized it because it's not as it's
not as big
it doesn't Trump it hasn't until now
Trump Trump for example and like
squirrel right squirrel squirrel
squirrel were attracted to the moment
yeah exactly
okay yeah
[Music]
yeah
so the sad truth about nation-states is
we all know what they all know what each
other is doing they are they are in
league it's eye on each other lies if I
on each other they're going to throw
somebody else under the bus when they
have to save themselves when there's a
bully amongst the ranks nobody nobody
questioned or stood up to Putin because
they weren't willing to take the hit and
they wouldn't unite as a collective
because the risk was too high it's much
harder to do this at nation state level
okay I will share with you this last
slide and I want to say thank you thank
you very very much
there's Kenny
[Applause]