hello oh okay that's right I guess
that's my volume okay thank you all for
coming for this session I'm going to
present bits inject which is a tool that
I formed it lets a local administrator
on the local system to run code as the
local system user in session zero it's a
whole new way to abuse the bits service
the Windows bit service that we will
talk about to abuse it to round your
arbitrary program as the local system
user and and actually do many other
manipulations on the jobs queue that
bits maintains and first couple of words
about myself I'm Dora Zoe currently
doing a security research at safe which
in Israel and my experience my
experience in security involve many
different angles I started with data
analysis and to network research and now
doing mostly software research of good
Christian creatures and bed creatures
the bad ones such as malware and
ransomware and the good ones such as
this Windows component and we'll start
for those of you who are not familiar
with the service bits stands for
background intelligent transfer service
it is actually not only a service it's a
mechanism that is composed of the
service which is the client and a
protocol the protocol is defined by
Microsoft
it's called bits and it sits on top of
the HTTP protocol it adds some verb and
headers to allow transfers over HTTP
communication so we start from the
bottom it's it it is a service a Windows
service running in session zero as the
local system user and it is here to
allow other users to transfer files to
download or to upload it is said to be
intelligent I didn't check for the real
reason why but I have some guesses one
is that it has many advantages
features and that you wouldn't expect
from a simple downloader you can it can
handle a rich rise for for your transfer
and it can handle a proxy authentication
it can have your jobs can have expired
expiry date of weeks and months and many
other recoveries that it does with
itself and maybe most notably it is
intelligent because it is meant to
optimize the bandwidth usage it gets
many download and upload jobs to to
handle and it calculates the right time
to transfer each of the files and it is
run in the background you just tell it
what to do which file to transfer and it
does it all alone a couple of more bits
about bits it is here with us since
Windows XP since 2001 and it evolved
since then with the five major versions
we're currently at version 5.0 which is
not that recent version five came out at
2012 and it is used normally and very
very commonly and for software to
download their own updates and the most
notable use is Windows Update and
windows download its own updates using
the the bit server the bit service it
has many advanced features some of them
I already mentioned and other users that
are not Windows Update and that's a very
common are Google Chrome updates are
using bit and Microsoft Office and
onedrive also of Microsoft is using bits
for a synchronization of files for both
upload and download you can see many of
the main events that bits produces in
the event log when you filter the bits
client source I'll start with a quick
demonstration not a demonstration of the
tool I just show you to get a glimpse of
how bits is operating maybe you never
notice it in your system
so for that I'll open one of the
software sorry about that one one of the
software's that use beats
this is a hex editor Neal and when I
open it it looks for it's it's checks
for new versions and it finds a new
version and you can choose to download
the download is done by bits and we will
show you the download has started as you
can see in the status line we will go
and see using the utility called
beats admin it lets you see what's in
the queue in a bit skill and as you can
see a new job has been created and but
to see way okay I didn't catch it in on
time and but what we would see here is a
job I created by hex editor that
downloads file from Exedy to servers to
a temp location and then and the editor
handles there and execute the update and
now for the name of the demo of the of
the tool itself I will use the easy and
the easiest flag that's in the in the
tool the tool is a Python script it
accepts many kind many different
parameters and there's an easy mode to
just give it a path of command to to to
execute and it will be executed in
session 0 as the system user so I just
put it here for a second
we stop we start with a command and run
as an administrator an administrator
kamancheh and we will go to the tool
itself sorry
now as I said before it has many
different parameters to give you can
create your own job and control the
properties and this flag gives us a very
easy way to just execute let's say
command we will go through the details
of what are the different steps that it
that it operates you to get to the
execution and and just for in about a
couple of seconds we will get a pop-up
maybe it will be only it's only on my
screen
the pop-up just tells us that we are
moving to a new service on session zero
is trying to communicate with the active
desktop
unfortunately because it moves to
another session and you won't see it
there and but we have a video of that on
the second demo afterwards and so we'll
move on
now
yeah
so the place that is talking about is
the is the session that we got into with
a command spoon as system and we will
later see another video demonstration
that will show you that on Windows 10 so
let's talk about some background terms
that are important to understand the
method bits can be used by many clients
it comes shipped with a bits admin
client Windows has it built in since
Windows XP it is now deprecated in is is
it is replaced by powershell commandlets
that are especially for beats other
third-party software such as the one we
saw before are using it to go directly
communicate with the common interface
that meets exports all of them are
operating and creating jobs bits jobs
its job each job has a job owner the
owner is the user that originally
created the job and if you use bit admin
as as user called user that user will be
the owner of the job throughout its all
operation it can be of three types
download upload or a very special kind
upload reply all of the operations are
done through the comm interface and bits
operates as a comm server and in proxy
server a local server and that accepts
requests from different clients the the
methods are exported exported by a qmj
our proxy that and and the actual
implementation is done in q MJ q MJ r dl
all of that is supposed to operate
seamlessly with different users and
trying to create and operate different
different jobs and bits has the job of
maintaining this hole in a queue and
even survive after crashes after
a different event and that are not in
the control of the user and for that
reason Microsoft thought that it is a
good solution to use a state file on the
disk the state file is actually a
presentation a binary serialization of
the job objects that are currently in
the queue and it is updated all the time
on every job change when bits needs to
be rerun for example when you open the
computer it loads all the content of the
file it's DC realizes all the jobs and
load it into memory and continue the
operation and serialization and
deserialization has always been and is
still a very fertile ground for
injecting arbitrary data and expecting
well unexpected unexpected behavior and
this is where this method seats and just
trying to inject my own data to the
state file and expect bits to load it
and operate just as I specially crafted
the data already known malicious uses as
another and that's a straight use that
you could imagine and I've seen a
downloaded that just invokes a command
that uses bits admin or powershell
commandlets to download payloads for
example and it is used as a persistence
mechanism a malware called Zillow is
using a very key feature that we will
talk about it and it's very important to
understand that feature because we use
it as well it's called the notification
command line which lets you define a
command line that will be run when the
job finishes if the finishes or turns
into an arrow state and this Marvel just
added the job that defines a download of
the same malware again and the execution
of it so even after you see and deletes
the Mara image
this may be weeks and months after you
may see the same mother again running on
your computer because the job persisted
on on the beats queue and it is a very
good candidate for c2 communication it
is just HTTP communication and it is
done by an OS service so it's not always
a monitored and it is very common to to
let the network controllers allow this
kind of bits transfer because as I said
it is used for the unloaded downloading
updates for Windows so what was my
inspiration to go and and take that
component into the research table
Windows updates Windows updates uses
bits to download updates and windows
update itself is a service running with
the system privileges and when you look
at the queue while Windows Update
downloads a an update you will see that
the owner of the of the jobs of the
windows of the jobs is system so I was
jealous of our Windows system how
Windows Update does it because I wanted
to do it as well and provide my own
command line that will then be executed
as system so why in the first place do I
want to get to that objective local
system has some privileges that are
above administrative privileges and to
name a few it can open a register a very
important registry key and hive and
security and Sam where the ntlm hashes
of the passwords are stored if it is run
on a domain controller it has
unrestricted unrestricted access to all
the objects and object types on the
active directory and it has the network
privileges of the machine meaning it can
identify itself on the network as the
machine as there always itself and it
has covered identity because of the
actions are done a system not all of
them are audited and it is very hard to
differ
she ate when when you do forensics wise
and it's hard to differentiate the good
operations of the system and the
malicious ones and most specifically if
we look and do who am i / all and see
all the privileges that each of the
users have and this is the difference
system has more privileged than the
administrator also to name a few
assigned primary top primary token gives
the ability to change the primary token
of a process only the kernel and system
can do that and lock memory privilege
lets you define pages in memory that
will remain in memory and won't want to
be paged into the hard disk
TCB privilege and lets you that's the
the the process to act as their OS
itself there are others we want to get
into them so what's the view and abuse
that we are doing I remind you we want
to use the feature that lets you define
a command line run and that's called set
notify command line that's the name of
the of the function in the common
interface that one should use to define
a command line and you just define a
string that will be executed using
create process as user in the win API
call and the user that it will it will
be run as is the owner of the job so I
will walk through the research process
that I have made and the first step that
I tried was to and just open a command
shell as a system in my own session and
the first thing that comes to mind is
using peers exact this is internals too
so I do just that I create I created the
job and to give it a real meaning I need
to define the transfer that I want to
make so in this case I want to download
software software exit to seat them I
creating a job had no problem and the
commands accident but this
command failed with this exception
unable to add file to job because the
operation being requested was not
performed because the user has not
logged on to the network at that point I
didn't know what that means but I
encountered a very absurd situation
because when trying to cancel the same
job using the same user I got the same
exception so God in this case system
created a rock in this case a job that
he cannot cancel and that was my first
hint to go into the state file itself
because that was my only way to delete
that job I deleted the file and it
recovered just like when doing reset
will look more into the the state file
later of course and okay so what Wang
Wang is the name of the Windows Update
service service at this point I wanted
to try and figure out how poor Wang
succeeds in creating and operating
system job and I can't using P exactly
so I my methodology here was comparing
the two flows step by step and trying to
find what it's different shields so the
normal flow would go like that what Wang
and switches to the context of the calm
in the face of qmg are DLL this is how
you use in proc server come in prog
server in Windows and then you can use
the the pointer that you get for the
interface to invoke on that server
different functions so naturally the
first function that I want the wind is
doing is creating a job and you can see
in this screenshot and the dynamical to
that function create job with the
parameter the static string W client
download and this is exactly the
description that you will see on jobs in
the queue while Windows is downloading
updates the next call will be to add
file same as we did with with bits admin
and you want to give the real job to be
done and after you did that
the job is still not running you need to
call resume this is where the job really
starts to get into the queue and to be
handled by bit the last two calls are
actually not called explicitly by the
user they are called various in various
occasions when bits calculate and and
decides that it is a good time to
transfer another chunk I remind you it
handles many downloads and the transfer
job and wants to optimize the usage so
these are called
repeatedly by the bit service itself so
as I said I compared the two flows and
the first call to create job and was
identical in parameters and identical in
the result in the outcome both succeeded
and a job was virtually created in the
queue the call to add file as you
probably remember failed when used by P
execs the same parameters were given but
one failed so this is where I wanted to
dig in and find the difference between
the two cases
so in short and these two lines are the
lines that I'm going to explain in the
next slide
in short the reason for that exception
is a bad pairing of the client security
identifier and the session ID and don't
get confused between a
s ID and the session security identifier
and the session ID and these are two
different things and the solution that I
that I have made to overcome this this
situation that caused the exception is
to fake the session ID when the session
IDs fixed
we got to a good pairing of these two
artifacts and got on with the execution
so what are the checks and enforcement's
that beats requires for a job to operate
and it is this kind of checks are done
on every crucial
request every crucial operation on the
job on creation on adding a file on
resume and many other calls
so access check for those of you who are
not familiar is a very root and main
function in the Windows security model
it is a boolean fact function that
returns either grant or deny true or
false and it is used here as a comm
server security and enforcement and
using the interface called I server
security this interface is given to any
con server that that is used in the
system and it has a generic
implementation of a coin personate
client and Corey were to self that an
impersonation takes and clones the token
of the of the client thread checks the
client thread trustee and might be a
user a group or relevant a session ID
checks it against the DAC a list of the
object that's in in place and returns
either grant or deny this is how access
check works an object has a security
descriptor inside it's there's a duck
the list with access list entries so two
threads are trying to get read write and
execute permissions on the object and
the first one is denied because as you
can see the first entry says that Andrew
is denied of read write and execute you
can be more explicit than that but the
third be grant get the permissions
because Jane is in Group A and as you
can see the second entry says that group
a is allowed to write and everyone is
allowed to read and execute if you
combine them both the the request of the
access is given so the first checkpoint
was actually really a security
enforcement and a second
one is an enforcement that beats defines
for itself it's not a generic it's
something that meets decided to have and
it requires the requesting user to be
logged on in an active session for the
job to continue its operation and for
that reason there's a check for the
active Logan Logan sessions that own day
that are currently in the contender on
the machine and so in this case user
called one as you can see in the arrow
in the left is in session one this is
the regular session when the first user
logs into Windows and there's always
another session session zero where all
the system services and other
application services are run so how are
we going to do that in more detail after
the two checks are after the first check
has passed we we did the second check as
follows we want to switch to the logon
token token of the requesting client of
the client thread and clone it and
perform the action that he requested
with its with the remote token and the
40 in order to clone it bits wants to
find the pairing of the security and NT
file that's in the job object that is
the job owner and the session ID from
which the request was made and to get
the bits uses and API call get token
information and when I used P as exit I
didn't know that before but apparently
this exact is run with the user with the
system user but in the active session
that I did I invoked it from in that
case this is session 1 and because
system is not logged in session 1 we got
the exception system is always locked
down in session 0 and is never logged on
in edit any other session so my goal
here was to try and mimic the and and
replace
the return that we get from agra token
information to session 0 and actually
pass the test so how do we do that and I
backed the process the service the
process service SVC host
you find the one that runs bit if you
debug it and I put a breakpoint and just
before the call to clone user talk just
before the exception is from I do the
same steps to create and define a job
and then we get to the break point and
now just as simple as that I change the
return but the return value of get
talking information that is one is
stored in a place in memory I just
change it to zero and the the check I
pass the check and at that point the job
is written into the state file so I pass
the check once and the the result the
actual valid job is in the state file I
don't have to pass it again and and the
fault here is that bits when when loaded
again we load that job and once do the
check again it just takes the the
content in the file this you realize it
and performs what's in it so that's how
it's done
session ID now is zero and we pass the
test
just for future reference
a lot of the token manipulations and no
impersonations is done under a class
called seen as an impersonation and that
eventually called an win API call called
impersonate logged on user with the
token that was copied from the client
thread so after all checks are done the
action is performed using impersonation
and the server then gets back to self
but the job is now valid it is in the
queue it is also projected to the state
file but the initial state of its job is
suspended and to move it from suspended
to actually
and transferring off of the job you have
to explicitly call resume and many other
states and there are some nuances
between the different states and there's
a error and transient error error is a
complete and final error and transient
error is a kind of error where bits can
recover from and so my our next obstacle
that we need to overcome is to change
the state of the job if we and I tell
you after checking that the state that
we want to move into is either killed or
connecting when the job is on one of
these states the the bits of service
will continue with the transfer so do
you remember the first hint that I had
to go into the state file so I went into
it I reversed engineered the the the
structure of the file it's a unclear
part file and that had to - that I had
to try and make many attempts to
understand where the changes are applied
and the file is located in this folder
in a program data downloader there are
actually two files that are updated
alternately and it's interesting but I
don't know the exact model of of the of
the decision when to update which and
there's a kind of backup model here well
when one is used the other is used as
called backup and it's updated sometimes
sometimes this one is sometimes in the
other for all effective use that that I
needed the the one that's in effect on a
current time and current point in time
is the one that stated in this registry
value and what's the content of the
state file it is just a straightforward
unencrypted and partially protected a
binary representation of the jobs in the
queue why and say it's straightforward
because this is how you're going to see
a string representation for example the
string of the job description
starts with an integer and that setting
the the string length in characters the
characters that follows and the null
termination character at the end and
this kind of properties are written to
the file with various calls to serialize
and write it is unencrypted so when you
open that file with an X editor this is
really what you're gonna see nothing
else to do here and it is partially
protected what I mean here is that the
file is used by a service that's running
in the system scope so as long as the
service is running a handle is a is a is
present a handle to the file is present
from the service so an administrator can
really modify the file but same
administrator has the rights to stop the
service and when the service is stopped
the file can be modified and then you
get the the service back on again and
your modifications are applied to memory
when bits and this you realize is the
the file and what could be done better
here is maybe put a colonel lock on the
file or at least have it with a trusted
installer and permissions so now that we
know how the file is is a structured we
found the exact bytes that gives that
represents the job state we change it
from 3 to 0 and now the job is killed in
general these are the steps that we made
we stopped bits service we replaced the
file with the new modified file the
under the state file and started bits
again this is what we see when we look
at the output of bits admin list where
we see the whole queue of bit and just
the important stuff this is our job it's
called TTT and the connection at the
is connecting it is owned by the system
and it is elevated in with system
integrity level the command line that
will be executed when the job finishes
is what we saw before
just CMD eggsy the integrity level just
as you see you saw here and system it is
the highest integrity level just to to
produce view of you who are not familiar
the integrity level is another way for
Windows to differentiate different user
actually differentiate the same user
that acts with different integrity
levels and that what for example gives
the ability to have to have the UAC and
[Music]
interface an administrator can change
the UAC operation and that's something
that's done with integrity that with the
highest integrity level okay now notice
that the method that I described and
meant that we are replacing the whole
state fun meaning that any jobs that
were previously in the queue are
overridden or deleted and so I wanted to
find a way for injecting my own job not
interfering with with other jobs and in
addition I didn't want to have to debug
the service on the machine that I want
to do that on if there's a remote
computer it's very hard to debug a
service on the remote computer and but
apparently if I do it on one machine and
take the state file to another machine
just copy and paste the same file to the
same location the same queue is applied
in the target computer and there's some
variations on different versions but
there's a finite number of versions you
can do a factory on on your home system
from machine and produce state-by-state
files that represents queues that you
want to be executed on another computer
copied to that computer and this is what
you get
and that's a pic of how the file is how
the file looks the structure of the file
the different parts of it and properties
of jobs that are currently in the file
and this is the template that you can
use it in the github repository the
turned off of this project and you can
use it to pass your own and state files
both for Windows seven eight and ten and
it is covered almost for all the
properties that are there so as I said
before I now want to push my own job
without interfering with the other jobs
so also we know the the file structure
and we found that in the in the queue
header there's a counter that says how
many jobs are in the queue we just
increase it by one and find the place
where a job ends and just before another
one starts and push our own job and I
was realized the job that we prepared
and we just added a new job so bits
inject is the tool that will let you do
just that if we inject a new job to the
queue it will remove remove remove it
when the job is finished
and one of the options that you can do
is prepare a job that has the local
system and owner and the command line
being whichever program that you want
and editing some other parameters and
properties of the jobs and some will be
added in the future and the next thing I
want to talk about is the interactive
session detection and that we saw before
actually you didn't see but you will see
in the video
that's a mitigation that's in Windows
since Vista and it's actually a service
Windows service run in the background
and it monitors other services and pops
up a message when another service try to
communicate with the active Logan
session and because services don't have
to communicate shouldn't children
communicate with the desktop
and the user session so how do we
overcome this there are two possible
ways one is just to use a command a
program and that we want to execute
that's that is not interactive
it doesn't require opening a window and
that way the the mitigation won't be
triggered another way is just changing
the registry value that says whether to
have this mitigation or not and you can
see the picture of the of the pop-up
that we couldn't see before because of
the move to the answer to the and
session zero and now we'll see it with a
prepared video
this this time we'll see it on Windows
10 it works just the same so we have a
program called write file which just
writes a file called stub file to see
temp this is the the one we want to
execute we firstly look at the queue and
we see that there are no jobs in the
queue you can see here now we use the
script bits inject to prepare a job
called demo that will download this file
to this location and execute this
program as you can see I'm using a local
server and and this should be a bit
server there were no I didn't find any
implementation of bit server in Python
so I wrote one it's called simple bit
server it is also in the repository and
it can serve as a bit server now the
first step is to prepare the job we give
we give some of the parameters on the
command line and some are default and a
new job is created and serialize this is
the data that we want to inject into the
queue then we run the win we inject it
and run the bits service again now we
stop we pause on the on this part and
look at at the queue what we see here is
our job demo
owned by system connecting because we
already made it change to change the
status this is the command and it will
be executed as system and this is the
file to be downloaded we continue with
the operation we intentionally made the
server not have this file so we get
error 404 and the fact that you
requested the requested URL and does not
exist it moves the job into error state
and this state means that bits will
execute the command line as you can see
bits actually
tries try the four times it it is
defined by default to do before we tries
you can change that and the next step
would be to remove the job from queue
actually in this video as well because
of how the operating system is working
you we can see that session I'll try
just to flip the laptop to the other
side so you can see and but in this case
the program that we use wrote a new file
bit stub file and as you can see the
owner is system so I will have not to
try to use our tool and show you how it
looks because it's a very rare place to
be that session I didn't see it before
I tried that just a second
so again I'm using the script the tool
to have command shell to be spawned with
system in session zero let's wait a
couple of seconds for the job to go into
arrow state just like we've seen in the
video
and it won't work because I lost
connection sorry we'll try it again I'll
reset the queue just for me to make it
clearer and I'm connected again
just couple of seconds it will go into
arrow state
here it is now I try to flip the laptop
nothing but not Explorer is running
nothing but the command the the program
that we specified in this case this is
and if we press Who am I
sorry about that
request Who am I and we see that we are
empty authoritative system
so as you can see thank you we are
system so anything we do under this
process will be as system as well let us
exit and return to the active session
and again I mean what does anybody have
a question we have some more slides
coming after ok that's it that print ok
yeah you mean when Windows updates use
this bit yeah so the URL is given with a
skewed you can operate in both secured
and unsecured way and the downloaded
file is of course signed by Microsoft
and the signature is is checked it it
was a good it could be nice if you could
just replace the job with a difference
URL and have your own file served but
Windows Update won't really run this
file yes no so that's the the thing here
I don't use any of the documented did I
get you yeah I don't use the interfaces
because I just go into the state file
and change what I want this is a new
kind of interface to control with and so
you see in the repository the simple bit
server and that as I said sits on top
inherits from a simple HTTP request
and it is used here and as I told you to
accelerate the the time that it takes
yes I get that at the end sorry okay
have it yeah it is you'll see the link
on the on the last slide and it was
already this talk in a shorter version
was already given at Def Con a couple of
months ago this is an extended version I
didn't get to go into details on the
last one and I got the opportunity to do
it here and so the simple bit server is
used to to intentionally move the job
into arrow State and actually on Windows
10 and you can do the same without
creating any network traffic at all and
there's a check on the volume C on
serial number of the destination path
that you created and if that check fails
it goes into arrow state and you can
just put a random a random string on
that virtual sorry serial number and you
get the arrow that the destination
volume has changed and actually bits
inject checks if you run on Windows 10
and always prefers this this method to
not produce network traffic so to sum it
up what were the conditions that made
this method work oh maybe the the kind
of things that could be done better one
is that the service relies on the state
file data without purification after the
data is in the file this is the
controlling that and this is what will
be executed and a lack of unique machine
identification this is what allowed us
to move the file from machine to machine
without changing anything without
needing to provide any other parameter
another problem is the integrity of the
file the in the state file that as I
said is done in operated by the system
but can be modified by an administrator
that can stop the service and this
the last one just made the whole thing
easier the the file is just a clear
straightforward serialization of the
objects along the way and I found
another cool thing you can cool way you
can abuse bits this time you can make it
fail when when it tries to download and
the good news for it is to choke at the
folder where Windows updates needs to
download the updates to and make it fail
the the way for doing that
is that because bits before you download
the content of the file it creates a
hidden file a temporary file and with a
name convention as follows a bit and
then one to four characters and hex
characters and if you calculate there
are only about 70,000 different names
you can and that are valid in this
format so if you it's kind of a race if
you know where file it should be done
with the to you go and create 70,000
hidden files with all the options and it
just fails and with an not that
indicated reason and if you see it on
Windows Update it says that some updates
were not installed and the ever found
windows update encounter encountered an
unknown error so you get deprived of
specific Windows Update and when when we
look at it from an apt group help
perspective this is a good way to weaken
the security of the of the machine
because if you didn't get the update on
I think it was on last May and you are
vulnerable to wanna cry and you can use
similar to how bits inject works you can
use it to change job properties change
job states of jobs that are already in
the queue and completely remove a job
from the queue the response I got from
Microsoft when reporting that to them
is that a malicious administrator can do
much worse things and if you really look
at the definition that they have on
vulnerabilities they say that an
administrator if you're already in a
newsletter you can do whatever you want
I get that but as I showed you before
there are some privileges that system
has that administrator doesn't they
could do maybe a bit better to mitigate
that and this is where you can find the
tool the code white paper and and the
simple bit server and you can find me in
email and in Twitter and thank you very
much