first off this is supposed to be my nut
my schedule it was switch if you're
looking at your paper schedule it's a
different one right but it was changed
on the website so if you're not supposed
to be here I'll give you a chance too
otherwise you'll be stuck for me poor
and art okay about me talk about me
first right
I work at fortunate a senior security
researcher I published articles in virus
ability and if you know that it's
actually I made it a user friendly
malware research so you can look into
those things and then if you have time
you can read them and I also wrote some
articles in our company blog blog that
forty Netcom that's the sales pitch
gonna kill me here
I just made some matrix were some of the
fun press that I've been to and mostly
my profile looks like that but deep
inside that's me supposed to be Batman
but it feels appropriate with the guy
anyway okay there are different kinds of
malware that we can look into but this
one if you're if you want to analyze
millions of malware at the same time he
used the same the line if you've been to
the other talk earlier use that and then
throw it all and then you get all your
analysis it can probably make my life
easier to write I may try to use that
assembly line but for for me this we are
going to look into just one sample today
not one million okay we're just going to
look into the code how it works and and
everything but first malware categories
there are different kinds of malware
nowadays okay and most likely we heard
in the news about ransomware like bad
rabbit patch and so on and so forth now
we're going to talk about this
ransomware we're in it is not just a
ransomware it is also a pile in factor
which is a virus it needs and a host
file to attach itself
impact okay we're going to look into
some of the visible signs of this
ransomware okay the reversing stage how
you want to reverse the malware itself
okay we try to of course if it is a
Palin factor we try to clean it so we
have to extract the host part and of
course we're going to look into how it
creates actually upon demand polymorphic
algorithm we know going in to look into
that and if you want to create a
metamorphic malware now I'm not saying
you create a metamorphic my way we're
just going to look into how it creates
that engine and then how it it is
actually generated we're going to look
some of the video demo I don't usually
do live demo it doesn't really work for
me
okay so we're going to look some of the
video demo how the malware works in
quality but we I use only poor for
debugging okay buck is let's before we
look into burlap we what is a file in
fact our file inspector it needs a host
file for example your calculator that
exe it needs to attach itself to an
executable and and put the code there
that is a pile impactor okay usually it
is hard to restore normally if you're
infected with a parent backdoor just
reformat your system just kidding we try
to still clean the system a ransomware
of course everybody knows ransomware
when apply right but Robbie the last one
the picture it tries to hold your
computer for ransom that means you have
to pay in Bitcoin to get your your
system back but that is at not actually
a bulletproof sometimes you pay in
Bitcoin you still don't have your system
back right it increased fast and of
course you use the Bitcoin for payment
and the lock is a combination of both
it is a ransomware and a file in back
door and locks your screen and deep
within KB use assembly line you will not
might not be able to see the polymorphic
algorithm and metamorphic algorithm so
we try to divert on that system because
assembly line
stay somebody from assembly line here
they might kill me okay don't tell
anyone okay it doesn't touch your screen
ransomware if you're infected with Iran
somewhere like this
maybe I'm infected we're done okay long
lunch
if you're infected with the ransomware
the good thing is unlike other malware
you will know you're infected okay
because if you're infected before
malware or trojan doesn't want you to
know that they are stealing your your
system but if you're infected with this
kind of ransomware you will see a blank
screen purse you will see if you if you
live in Canada it knows that you are in
Canada it will ask you for course
Canadian dollar but if you're in u.s.
you run this ransomware it will ask for
your USB it is an old one because it
still had the BTC point five eight eight
now it is probably if you want to pay to
the peakin agents probably point zero
how much is Bitcoin now it's like crazy
right and it will look something like
that okay it will be looked like coming
from from your RCMP okay
now getting with the ransomware normally
it tries to educate the user for example
you don't know Bitcoin it will explain
what is Bitcoin because they want you to
pay so it gives you information and for
example where do you get a Bitcoin you
only have your your ATM machine you can
actually go to different places where
you can actually change your money here
Canadian money to Bitcoin okay I
there is one in in Vancouver okay
downtown I haven't seen it actually but
I've seen one in Seattle us okay but the
problem is I'm about to do a video shot
of the at Pace but I need they need your
driver's license so it's not actually
anonymous anymore right so
didn't do I didn't do it if you don't
live in Vancouver and where's Quebec oh
let's get back okay if you're infected
with this ransomware and you live in
Quebec do you live here you can go you
can click this one and then it will tell
you where to change your money okay very
educational
of course you can access your screen
because it is locked so you can only
have notepad and of course some network
connection and thence that's it okay
okay don't worry if you're infected with
ransomware you will know okay that's a
common malware normally we try to we try
to analyze the malware using a debugger
or some other tools assembly line you
can just send everything and then you
will get the information that you want
but if you want to go deeper okay you
can use quality bug immunity the big
debugger which is almost the same
actually same features but this one is
you can use Python scripting in order to
automate your your debugging and if
there is a 64 version of the malware you
can actually just use x64 dvg okay it is
actually being develop most of the time
it's like that they have the daily or
weekly weekly updates normally when we
try to okay assuming this is your
executable file when we try to the crib
or unpacked the malware okay and then
you will be able to get the decrypted
version and then now you can do the ID a
static analysis or you can also still do
the dynamic analysis okay
okay for this one the reversing stages
the at first when you get your burlap
you only have the text section and the
research section okay there's like two
spaces there and then when you try at
the very end of the executable file
there's this code the metamorphic
algorithm that is our purpose later on
okay when it it trusts the metamorphic
algorithm it generates this particular
they go
bytes after generating the decoded bus
it generates the main function and then
when we have the main function it now
produces that what I call fun demand
polymorphic why do we call it only one
polymorphic because every time it runs
it will decrypt itself with the original
key and then after executing that
particular code it encrypts back with a
different key that means every time it
executes a single function it will look
something like this it is no different
from the original code because it is
encrypted now with a new key okay and
then execute another on demand and then
if you put some colors in your virtual
memory K it will look like Christmas
lights different colors different codes
compared to the original one that means
every time it impacts your files it will
create a different set of op codes that
is what I call on-demand polymorphic as
a file impact or let's look at some of
the different kinds of file inspectors
okay we have appending prepending there
is only how how they try to to impact
your files appending is it's coming from
gate attaches itself at the bottom of
your hosts file prepending is at just at
the bottom cavity is harder to clean
because it looks it looks for spaces in
your executable and put those codes
inside overwriting
just operate everything if you have
overwriting file in fact or you have to
reformat your system sound like this
this is your malware appending this is
your host file okay this is the pre
pending cavity it used looks for spaces
and so on somewhat but beer love is
actually it grabs your host pile and
clip the host spine and put it inside
the big build up file okay and then and
then this is now your impacted by
they were going to I'm going to show you
a bit later on on which part do you try
to you can try to encrypt you're ready
clip your horse while extracting the
host belt from gridlock is kinda a bit
as long as you can find the key you'd be
able to turn the clip you're your host
file
yes it is using a simple XOR not very
complicated it doesn't use AES or some
some different cryptographic system ok
the hot spot is actually somewhere here
if you're able to run met the
metamorphic algorithm get them in
function you got all the on-demand and
then after a while you will be able to
get those but you don't need to run
everything here you can actually find
the host part and then extract it then
you can have your your host part back
but if you're infected with this ok ok
try to the opera broadly you can
probably download some or your AV system
will be able to clean those Hospit the
antivirus that you have installed it
will look something like this
ok this is your host pine encrypted ok
it will not look the same like this
because it is always it always changed
if you're in if your host file if your
calculator is infected today you clean
the system you are infected the other
day if you compare those infection will
be different right because of the formal
peak algorithm all you have to do is to
look for this particular code you can
actually search them in your debugger ok
if you find them then you will be able
to actually decrypt your hosts file that
is the initial key if you want to follow
the code all you have to do is to look
for this one just simple XOR that is how
it encrypts your file ok and then just
just follow the decryption it will just
make some loop ok look going back here
it will execute until finally everything
is decrypted your host file will look
something
this now the host file will contain or
the impacted part will contain the
actual pile there is that the pile name
that was encrypted and then this is now
they start of your first MZ and said
header there is no they start of your
your file or your hospital all you have
to do is to cut from the end said up to
the end of the the host part and then
you'll be able to extra for your host
part and that's it that is how you try
to clean your system with your impacted
works there is no your decryption key
let's look at the on demand polymorphic
okay the only one polymorphic looks see
like this there is a code okay with
which use the Decrypter to decrypt the
block of code using the old key okay you
will you will try to look for the
garbage code the garbage code this were
in we don't actually need them it is
just to to make your analysis even
longer it's the main purpose of the
garbage code is to to waste your time
right all you have to do is to skip
those things and then find the x or okay
and then you'll be able to to the creep
your your malware or Billa okay the red
ones they are actually their garbage
code you don't need them okay they
change too so if you're making a
signature detection for that you'll but
we won't be able to you have to skip
those things hey there's the generate
the kitchen function which generates the
ducky x EI x wishes the value or which
the ducky and then there is now your
starting location of the decryption
if you want to decrypt you can follow
this you can dump it to your old debug
and then you can party those those bytes
it that it will be decrypted that is the
actual C is only a simple XOR that is
the actual decree
within the xo1 and this is actually your
key it checks it is just a redundant
check to make sure that you are actually
in the right malware in the right code
okay there is now your X or decrypt or
if you go to this to this function and
then it will try to decrypt that
particular function and execute it uses
the de creeper to do that okay to
generate a new key it uses a function R
DT as if it timestamp counter it changes
every time you run that's why I told you
when you actually when you infect your
calculator today it will be different
actually in the afternoon in the evening
or the other day because it generally it
generates the key based on the time
stamp counter okay and then it uses the
same set of codes in order to this one
generates the new the new key he uses
the are DTSC save it in different memory
location and then using the different X
or e or the Decrypter then you'll be
able to get the new kid all you to this
so dope for this code and then you will
be able to see how it generates the new
key just a location device needed to
generate the key and then there is now
your new key place on this in this
number and this location okay if you're
going to look at the same code this is
your your your code with the old key and
then after generating the new key you'll
be able to find it the same set of codes
looking at the offset you will be able
to find a different set of keys so this
is 9 B 7 B this is 9 7 a and something
so it changes every time it gets that's
why it's called the on demand
polymorphic
what happen what I'm infected good thing
I have Supergirl oh we are very now and
uh let's go to sorry about that
what happened did I step on something
where are we
yes realize I had so many slides see I
don't have yet my my demo and then it's
destroying my system again let's do this
oh they're done
cases so that's the new key this is
where we die ohai still working ok the
Decrypter actually uses the same
algorithm as the encrypter but it just
uses a different key if you use an X or
X or function if you use X or and then
use the same key XOR it with the same
value
it actually encrypts and eclipse ok just
using the the same value if you're going
to look into the original said this is
the encrypted code ok I just grabbed us
and just grabbed it ok with the old key
getting the first 16 bytes and then this
is the decrypted code ok section bus is
here and then after executing this
decrypted code it will actually generate
generate the new key encrypt this one
with the new the new key look they are
in the same memory location okay this is
encrypted with the old key this is
encrypted with the new key and this is
your decrypted code if you want to make
a signature detection in your company or
or Europe you're doing it at home ok all
you have to do is to look for for this
one first because even though you have a
different key every time ok you will
have the same set of decrypted told
different keys you won't be able to
detect this one every time okay but you
have to to follow this one to be able to
detect your your samples and just know
everything this matter if you're going
to look up you're going to make
signature with the code ok do not fall
do not detect this one because this this
contains the the garbage code collected
is to detect this except this part ok
because this one changes to let's go now
to the metamorphic algorithm metamorphic
is kinda different with the polymorphic
polymorphic is it changes the code but
at the same time it encrypts encrypts
plus changing
code that is polymorphic in my turn okay
metamorphic is it doesn't change the it
changes the code but the code is nothing
cryptid that means you can still execute
the code
what is metamorphic paper example the
basic for metamorphic is for example you
want to put a value to a register for
sample value zero to a certain register
ei XK you can do that in so many ways
mobi X 0 X or the same register it gives
you 0 K subtract the same register again
you it gives you 0 or you can do a
different combination of codes at the
end you still get the serum that is
metamorphic okay if you want to create a
metamorphic algorithm all you have to do
is to generate the same or different set
of working codes but the same result
that is metamorphic polymorphic
encrypted plus changing changing of code
metamorphic it does it doesn't increase
K but it still changes the code that the
problem is it's hard to find similar
bytes and there are different lengths
when you create the metamorphic
algorithm of course unpredictable code
the problem with this one is if your
antivirus engine K tries to detect your
your sample and then it it punked it it
points that they are actually encrypted
it will try to encrypt it will try to
decrypt that means it is malicious in
itself if it is encrypted but if it is
metamorphic K
the mod the code still executes your
antivirus engine will think that it is
just a regular application that is one
of the difference with the metamorphic
and polymorphic there are different ways
to generate the metamorphic engine okay
but Birla were going to focus on burlap
k verloc uses different instructions to
generate the registers okay it uses
different number of bytes it has a
pseudo random value generator
generates different sets of instructions
we'll see that later and of course it is
it has a different length of code this
particular part this function generates
a pseudo-random number and then based on
that number it actually detects I do it
will tell you which register to use EDI
ESI for whatever EAX okay and then up
from that code it generates a new
address register and code register okay
for example the buffers temporary it
changes it depends on the on your
execution okay it changes the location
and then it generates randomly what kind
of address register that you use and the
code register we see that later in the
video demo okay after generating the
pseudo-random number it depends on the
value of the the register eax
EDI combination of e^x EDI and EBX for
example this one it generates a mob
address register value and then if it is
EPA X is 1 he is 0 similar but this one
it generates the code register and then
it depends on the value again IX EDI P
DX it will tell you if it is subtraction
addition or whatever ok so that is how
it generates the different combinations
of bytes or different combinations of
registers - ok so it is not very it is
not fixed that's why even the
metamorphic algorithm will generate
different set of codes and this one also
generates the second this is these are
the combinations of registers for
example if it is it generates the b8 it
will get the move AEA X if it generates
the c3 it will get a dbx it depends on
the generated value it will look at this
is the lookup table on which kind of
register is it needs to do ok
I stay with me people already sleeping
it's okay I will just wake you up later
the last one the last actually the last
code is actually the one that generates
the the trance the moving of the bytes
key to a different registers like this
okay let's have some video demo to wake
you up this is a HUD video okay this is
a this isn't only how I can falsify so
this one generates the pseudo-random
value and then based on the
pseudo-random value it will generate
again the combination of bytes you will
see here I just followed the virtual
memory 9000 okay after generating that
one you will see that it will generate a
combination of seed now there is for
this one call instruction okay based on
the number of the different combination
it generates the mob edx and a random
value right and then another
pseudorandom value generates that
particular byte it will keep on
generating the the bytes what is the
main purpose of that one
the main purpose is it is tried to
create a metamorphic encrypted value in
metamorphic value for the poor bytes
here it will create a series of mode
subtraction and addition values addition
instructions okay
just to produce the ball four bytes here
this is the the decrypted code okay
later
after creating those theories of
subtractions and additions instructions
okay you will be able to to change this
to a different value change it to tour
detoured and it
looks like an encrypted value what
happen what's going on with this again
stiff again our DPS Steve guess the
random value
so it generates that big bunch of codes
or the like 718 7 bytes I seven lines of
instructions to generate just to to port
was on the poor bytes
you will see that it will change the but
the poor bytes value in the original
code so that one changes by now see it
changes that particular four bytes
just superb bytes and now it is going to
generate the mob instruction where in
that value will be placed to a certain
register that one the mode B word in the
X psi and then that seven or eight lines
of instruction is only poor for the
first D word okay for first four bytes
now if you will see here I just press f9
rf8 okay and then it generates this more
than ten instructions tool to try to
encrypt the the next four bytes okay and
then again followed by the mob
instruction it will continue doing that
until all the the actual the original
code is already in its encrypted form
okay but it now generates its new set of
metamorphic algorithms so you will see
that the metamorphic algorithm is only a
combination of addition subtraction and
mob instructions it is very simple
actually in turns but if you want to
make a very complicated one you can
insert garbage code you can insert nope
operations were in it will delay further
analysis but I'm not the bad guy here I
am just saying that it will delay the
researchers time okay for example you're
trying to analyze this at work and then
you only have like an hour to do the to
do the execution or to do the virus
report okay you cannot do this you have
to use the same language right to
generate the base report but if you want
to dig deeper on the
you want to see how it works or how to
try to do the - to try to extract the
the file okay you have to go deeper like
looking into this and then the malware
is the main purpose is for you to waste
your time debugging okay but if you
really want to dig this one and then you
only have an hour or two and then you
didn't produce the result you'll be
fired
okay I'm actually I'm not yet paid yet
I'm still working okay so that is how
metamorphic algorithm or this the engine
metamorphic engine that the malware uses
in order for it to to generate the
metamorphic code later we will see how
the metamorphic this is creating the
metamorphic code
okay later we will run the metamorphic
code to bring back the original my way
okay so that is how it executes the
whole thing it's almost done don't worry
if you're hungry it's almost done
they said we will be here up to 12:30
right no so that is so so it different
number of bytes different number that is
how it makes it harder the good thing
with this one is later I will tell you
how to simplify the the reverse
engineering
if you encounter not only for build up
if you encounter a malware with
metamorphic algorithm it will there is a
simple way to skip those things I will
tell you later if you if you stay if you
don't you will not see it so it
generates that one if you look into the
malware with metamorphic algorithm it
will be like it will look something like
it's hard to do right so that's the end
I didn't finish the whole thing okay so
the generated metamorphic algorithm is
actually this one the very first one we
go back to this one this is actually the
generated metamorphic algorithm is the
very first set of codes being exactly
that once you execute the malware he it
changes in sizes it is approximately to
828 kilobytes lon
okay I compared to samples which is the
same same host file okay but different
sets so this is the the decrypted at the
encrypted metamorphic encrypted code
this is the actual malware code okay the
first D word divorce the poor bytes it
actually decrypt that one into this one
okay the second D word is actually
generated by this group of codes to
produce this one the third D word is
actually produced using this one so
different number of bytes different
number of instructions different lengths
okay another example the some second
sample that I use okay the same the same
host file different encryption okay I
didn't change the square boxes here okay
to show you that they they have
different sets of codes look at looking
into this
they have different bytes here but it
generates the same malware code okay
third D word and so on okay
comparing the per sample
this is your second sample which is the
same host file different encryption
okay comparing against the first avoid
for the second and per sample came of
EDI
it uses even the movie selection is
different second award different third
award and so and support but if you want
to create signature detection okay you
can actually just detect the decrypt
advice again they are the same even
though they are different it uses
different number of bytes they are still
the same except for this one okay that
is the initial value initial key which
is different every time but if you want
to detect this it is always the same
demo be X and the nope
and the jump okay that is if you want to
make variate action
and for the another demo showing you how
the metamorphic engine works or the
metamorphic algorithm works so this one
we are now running the the generated
algorithm it is now going to change back
the code okay every time it has the mob
instruction
this one this one changes okay it is now
returning back the malware code that is
actually the very first set of execution
of the malware it will continue again
until the whole metamorphic code
generates the actual malware algorithm
and then the secret is if you
encountered the malware that uses
metamorphic algorithm there's always a
jump out there's always a way out
all you have to do is to put a
breakpoint on that particular location
and then you will be able to to skip all
the time wasting debugging okay all you
have to do is to look for that
particular part
if you encounter a code and then your
debugging is step by step and then you
figure that this is actually a
metamorphic algorithm all you have to do
is to look for the jump out put a
breakpoint up to four four ollie and
then execute press f9 do not press f9
first before you put the f2k it will
execute your malware right so all you
have to do is to it will continue doing
that imagine if we I am actually
automating this with with just pressing
C and pressing some 100 times I think I
think I press 1 million times there
chalo this this is actually there is
actually every time you encounter a
metamorphic algorithm there is a jump
there is a hole going out look for that
breakpoint and then execute it you will
now be able to see the actual the actual
malware called after generating there is
now the call EDX the EDX contains the
is the that part this is the the one
that is already decrypted that is your
mother called okay that is the technique
of the decrypting the malware made
metamorphic algorithm okay there is look
for the fall or the jump out cold Rico
Pro conclusion I look to this for
reversing elected is to look for the
metamorphic algorithm end of the
metamorphic algorithm as I said earlier
the jump and the hole copy the decrypted
code if you want to analyze it in I da
or what this ascender that you have
detection get the patterns from the
decrypted code not from the the
encrypted or the the metamorphic
algorithm okay and for cleaning most
most of the time the malware has
registry keys a loop to do is to delete
those things first you can extract the
host files and of course they need all
the drop wise or a simpler thing is get
get you installer and operate the whole
thing and you're dead right that is for
the for the cleaning I think that's the
only thing that that's everything that I
have any question mercy we have 10
minutes for question No
for for me or if you're going to do if
you're going to analyze the the malware
and then you want to to generate the
virus report for example because that's
what I usually do I can I can run all
the tools that I have run the malware
and then I will be able to get all the
the codes but because I prepared this
for the presentation for the top ok took
took me awhile for it for the analysis
part you can have like a week doing the
because you're trying to look for the
algorithm and so on and so forth but it
will take longer if you want to make
some slice and everything but even
though the malware is very complicated
if you use the tools and everything to
automate it you will be able to get you
will be able to know that is it is a
malware you'll be able to Turner that
that is malicious but if you want to go
to dig deeper it will take you time
probably one week is enough to see the
code ok to see the metamorphic and
everything one week without slipping
okay not not regular work time okay and
then he'll be able to see the code and
then another probably a month to do some
some graphics for the presentation for
you to be able to sleep while you're
listening to me that's mostly how it
works but if you use assembly line send
all your samples there and then you'll
be able to see your your body support
question no the thing is if you have the
infected malware or impacted very low
okay if you use ID a right away you
won't be able to see anything because it
is polymorphic and metamorphic encrypted
so you have to run first it in a
debugger and then you break point you
stop somewhere
you got the decrypted code and after
that you can now dump it back to IDF
but the kitchen and the name you have to
get over it yourself
did I answer your question yeah yeah
yeah yeah you have to to know analyze
the function then or this function
actually generates the metamorphic then
you put the name so that when the next
time you encounter the function you will
know that it uses so you don't need to
do it again
right you will know what it does
pressure so the question
was it what is the impact of the
discontent gated malware from day to day
basis there are actually different kinds
of transformer that uses different kinds
of techniques like for example beer love
is using metamorphic polymorphic engine
k2n uses file infection most of the
ransomware that we have is they just
encrypt your files put a message and
then that's it okay but this one okay I
personally choose this one because it
also impacts files because even though
you unlock your skin you will be still
be infected if you get the infected
files okay but there's another one like
petia if you heard up a TIA
the one with the blinking skull okay
that one uses some form of polymorphic
algorithm metamorphic but it is it uses
some crypto logic but at the same time
it is actually impacting your operating
your MBR the Master Boot Record so it
uses it overrides your Master Boot
Record and at the same time it tries to
locks your your screen so that that
particular part is actually petia is not
actually encrypting your files it is
encrypting the table the MSFT table of
the file and then that's it you will not
be able to to use the nature so
different malware different ransomware
they uses different techniques but for
your second question we can actually
categorize them for example you will be
able to get the same group of weight the
way they use it and then you can tell
that this actually this particular group
created the same set of mugger because
they just reusing their code but some
malware authors they just actually uses
other other peoples code and then they
create their own so usually that that's
what happened question the windbg the
windbg is actually a very strong
debugger okay but i prepare only an
immunity debugger and x64 dbg because
I'm actually familiar already familiar
with the GUI and everything but windbg
is very strong if you're if you're doing
using windbg I said yes you can stick to
the windbg it's probably the the way we
use all the bugger C's is by preference
you want to use this we wants like going
to McDonald's you it you want
cheeseburger the other one but but this
their their burgers right just different
flavors question you want to it nice now
right thank you for for your time