all right so first things first okay my
mic is working excellent all right so
actually he just did this part so we can
skip it cool all right so two new things
in this presentation we're gonna have
two new attacks one is a hostel portal
attack and you can use that to steal
Active Directory credentials from WPA to
AP now works out to recognize our cats s
and the second thing we're gonna go over
is the indirect wireless pivot which you
can use to bypass nak mechanisms so
before we do any of this stuff we need
to talk about WPA to EAP now the cool
thing about 30 p2 EAP is that it's very
vulnerable to rogue ap attacks so in
order to really talk about EAP we need
to talk about rogue AP's and Rho VP is
that pretty much the bread and butter of
modern wireless pen tests you can use
them for stealthy man the middle attacks
stealing radius credentials all kinds of
really cool stuff at their core the way
that they work the most simple type of
rogue ap attack is the evil twin attack
and that is if you look at this diagram
that we have here you can pardon me if
you look at this diagram that we have
here we have like four laptops that are
connected to this access point and this
access point you know just to pick on
Def Con a bit but what we'll call this
network Def Con open and there's an open
network so I guess the question is if an
attacker word it creates another access
point with this very very same name how
these devices know to want to connect to
and the truth instead really come down
to who has a better signal-to-noise
ratio and better signal strength among
other things so essentially what this
allows you to do as an attacker you
could just create your own hotspot you
know mimicking the the network that
you're targeting and this will force
devices to connect to you now you have a
man in the middle and you can do all
kinds of cool stuff with that so this is
not a new attack I mean this these have
been around for pretty much like the
inception of Wi-Fi so you know we're
talking 2002 is when the evil twin
attack first started to kind of emerge
you know fast forward a couple years we
have karma attacks and that's a
different attack by the unity has oviya
and chain McCauley
you know that that's if you use like a
pineapple that's pretty much what it's
doing that's word 2008 and we have free
reign as wpe
by Josh right and Brad and Tony wits and
this is actually where you start to use
see rogue ap attacks use as a method of
stealing credentials from radius radius
networks and then back you know fast
forward a bit to 2014 you know that by
this point karma attacks have been
significantly less effective so you know
at this point two really awesome
researchers
daaamn white and in de villiers they
actually figured out how to improve this
and kind of you know get back to square
one and make this really effective
attack again and filing 2017 very
recently we have to lure ten attack
which targets Wi-Fi sense which is used
by it by windows so i mean one thing
that all these different in this
evolution of rogue AP attacks has have
in common is the fact that they you know
the Robie p it's a kind of primarily
falls into one of two roles man the
middle tax for stealing credentials and
also breaching wpa2 networks to gain
access to the wireless network we're
going to look a little bit different in
this talk today and that's using Roby
opiates after the means of lateral
movement alright so now that we've gone
over a gap he attacks so when we talk
about wpa2 EAP or WPA enterprise we're
usually talking about two
implementations of this EAP so we're
talking about you if a peep and he appt
LS anyone here familiar with EAP at all
all right some okay cool so just a brief
overview of how this works
you know what we see here's a diagram
and this thing but this quiet over the
left side this is your client device
also knows the supplicate if you wanna
be technical that's like your laptop
your cell phone whatever and this over
here is the authentication server now
the authentication server now when the
client wants to connect the network the
clients gonna send off that occasion
request to the authentication server and
the authentication server is going to
respond with an x.509 certificate and
you know once this happens we at this
point completes provided by the way that
a client accepts a certificate at this
point we complete the outer
authentication we move on to the inner
authentication the outer authentication
can only proceed once the client has
established that it can trust the server
so we finished the outer authentication
and then the secure titles establish
between the client and the
authentication server we move to the
inner authentication at this point which
is where you actually enter in your
username and password and all this
happens to the secure tunnel now the
reason by the way why we need a secure
tunnel is the fact that well actually so
EAP right we're talking to EP as an
authentication mechanism basically what
that's authentication mechanisms
providing you access to is access to
this Wi-Fi network to Wi-Fi networks WPA
capabilities until you finish the soft
indication mechanism this is entirely
happening over open Wi-Fi because you
can't get that encryption until you've
finished authenticating so with the
other secure tunnel you could actually
sniff this entire process offline and
you'd have problems
in fact legacy implementations of EAP
we're very susceptible to this if you
find a PMD 5 there's one that comes to
mind so you know when I mentioned
they're actually two components here but
that's that's actually a bit of a you
know oversimplification we actually have
three components in total the supplicant
or wireless client which we were talking
about earlier that it's screening here
with authentication server well your
wireless wireless client is actually
communicating over layer two so in order
to make this work we actually need
something that's able to speak layer
seven which is what your radius server
speaks so that's why you need the access
point in the middle which is you know
technically knows the Authenticator but
we can just call it the IP and that just
kind of sits in the middle this whole
transaction and acts as a mediator
between these two parties so you know
our complete diagram actually would look
like this you know it's very similar to
what we had before you see the
authentication requests the x.509
certificates were returned as a response
client then trust it or does not trust
it but the key difference here is that
we have the Authenticator operating as
an intermediary between the client and
the server so we mentioned that you know
evil that open networks are susceptible
to evil twin attacks where these these
attacks where you can't really like
force devices to you connect to a rogue
access point and attack them in that way
well and we also mentioned that ap in
until like the CFP process completes
this entire network is gonna be
operating over open Wi-Fi so it follows
then that this entire process should be
attackable using Rho VP attacks and
actually that is originally how you
would gain access to wpa2 enterprise
network is essentially you create your
own and you know your own wireless
access point with its own authentication
server running in the background spoof
the target network and force the client
device to connect to you this point you
present the client device in an x.509
certificate if the client accepts a
certificate a secure Tom's established
with you and at this point the client
authenticates with you and you're able
to you essentially get a mschap e to
challenge a response was can be cracked
and that gives you radius credentials as
the talk was first talked about by
Brandon Tony was to 2008 and essentially
you know yeah it's been around for one
time it hasn't really fully been
addressed yet so we mentioned mschap e
to as the inter indication mechanism
that's used you know to
once we once we finish the
authentication the thing that happens to
the secure tunnel the inner
authentication mechanism used by EVP pin
even TTLs is called MSG avi - and Emmas
Chevy - there are a couple ways that we
can crack those I mean mschap you to
challenge the responses that we that we
captured the first one is a straight
dictionary attack say just sequentially
iterate over passwords anyone like kind
of see like why that might take a long
time yeah well actually we're actually
in luck because emili´s Chevy 2 is
actually vulnerable to something called
a divide-and-conquer attack so basically
to researchers named David marked Moxie
Marlinspike and David Holton back in
2012 they figured out that you could
actually well the MFE - essentially was
very very similar to 3des
and you could actually reduce it to 56
bits of DES encryption you know similar
to what you can do with mes until mv1
and because of this you can actually you
know crack these things very very very
very fast and in fact you know with
their FPGA pace cracking rig they can
actually do it in you know under 24
hours a 100% success rate that's
regardless of the length of the password
so in other words to summarize if you
have a situation in which with EAP
peepin even TTLs you can force the visor
to connect to you to authenticate with
you and then once you get that those
hashes that they send you in this in
this authentication process you can
crack them very quickly do the
cryptograph you grab cryptographic
weaknesses so here's this like a quick
demo of essentially what this attack
would look like you know the attacker
would create a certificate and then
would create the rogue access point and
you can as you can see here right you
know the access points enabled and
you'll see a Emma Chaffee to challenge
and response kind of pop up on the
screen after the client associates it
finishes authenticating and this will
happen very shortly speed this along a
little bit there we go
so yeah the attacker then takes the Emma
Chaffee to challenge a response in this
demo there it's just like a dictionary
attack because the divide-and-conquer
this takes a little more time a little
more work so but you know in this case
you could just whoops
it's a very sensitive keyboard all right
there you go gonna leave that alone and
so at this point you take the challenge
response feed it to a asleep which is
this tool that does a dictionary attack
upon them and from there it will crack
your password in this case it's like a
really simple password so it's gonna get
it very quickly but this could take a
lot of time if you do the dictionary
attack with a complex password so yeah I
mean that's that's traditional weakness
of EA pppt pppt less is that you can do
that you can you can capture crunches
that way the solution that was kind of
introduced to mitigate this issue was
something called EAP TLS and EAP TLS was
introduced in 2008 and essentially uses
a mutual certificate based
authentication for the outer layer of
authentication so in order to pass that
outer layer of authentication you know
basically both the client and the server
have to present valid search to one
another so you know this actually stops
that stops the rogue ap attacks that we
talked about earlier dead in their
tracks the problem of EAP TLS is that
you now have a situation any network
administrators out there like anyone
ever just like sis admin's I mean anyone
Wow ok none ok well essentially um
essentially that the problem is if you
can imagine you're running a network and
you now in order to deploy this thing
you now have to install a client server
on every single device on your network
that can be kind of painful and
time-consuming and if you have like a
really large you know enterprise network
it can also cost a lot of money if it's
not something that you know you're
already equipped to do so essentially
you know it as a network administrator
you kind of you know end up with this
classic security versus convenience
scenario where you kind of have
authentication mechanism that you that
you can choose but they have like known
weaknesses but they're still pretty easy
to use or you have a very very secure
but also very impractical and method of
authenticating with the network so you
know essentially this creates a market
gap and this market gap can be you know
is for products that can can can
essentially compensate for the security
issues found in eep-eep eep-eep TTLs but
are also easy to use so I mean the
current trend in this regard is to focus
on breach containment rather than breach
prevention so in other words you
acknowledge the risks associated with
using these implementations of EAP and
say you know what it's too expensive to
employ EAP TLS instead
focus on making sure that once an
attacker gets on the network but they
can't do any damage so you focus on
breach containment and what we're gonna
try to answer today is whether this
actually works I'm just gonna like flip
to this cartoon here before continue I
can't draw as you can see all right so
yeah so I mean that the most common way
of approaching the problem of breach
containment is to use an app and you
know that's reasonable right because a
network act an act mechanism or in a
compliance you know case you don't know
what it is it's it's a device that
essentially is able to distinguish
between authorized and unauthorised
Network endpoints so in other words you
connect a new device to the network and
the night.the the nack is gonna do some
kind of magic I'll go more into that
later and and and by doing this it's
able to identify whether the new network
is authorized or unauthorized to be
there if it's unauthorized it's gonna
you know put it in a quarantine VLAN or
it can't really do anything or it's
gonna block the port entirely you can't
really take the device off the network
because the device obviously can get
back on the network in the first place
this was why we're using an ACK
but anyways personally we have two
varieties of nack we have agent based an
accent agent let snacks and agent based
max I mean sensor the way the work is
you have a software component that's
installed on every single authorized
network on the endpoint on the network
and the software component communicates
with like this the centralized brain of
the neck or the controller and and by
doing this it's able to report back
information about the internals of these
devices and this is there so really
effective unfortunately you're also now
the situation where you have to deployed
something on every single device in our
network and this you know is kind of
back to square one because needle is
impractical as eap-tls on the other side
inspecting we have agent list acts and
these purely external methods you can
pass the fingerprinting act of scanning
and they're actually you know a lot
easier to employ for this for this
method because for these reasons because
they actually don't require you to
install something on every network
endpoint unfortunately you're also
unable to examine the internals of these
devices so you can bypass them simply by
masquerading as an authorized device so
I mean once again this kind of leads us
back to yet another you know kind of
iteration of this dilemma of in security
versus in practicality I which in turn
you know creates another market gap
there's like huge demand for solutions
that offer deep interrogation
capabilities of agent base knacks but
don't have the additional overhead and
this has led to the rise of something
you know that what we usually call the
next generation or we'll usually call
next generation axe
so you know what's kind of like position
themselves to be the best of both worlds
you know these usually use like a
variety of techniques to do this I mean
a lot of them like you know advertise
themselves like machine learning based
or whatever one really interesting one
actually I tried to bring this device
here because we have one in our building
somewhere so I actually opened at the
ticket to our IT department and yeah you
can kind of guess how that what you're
like actually not only that legal got
involved was like like so yeah so like I
actually can't legally name this device
so we're gonna call this vendor a but I
just want to pick on vendor a a bit
because like it's a really good example
of a well thought out attempt to bridge
this gap but it doesn't actually work so
vendor a actually uses WMI to
interrogate new devices as they're added
to the network so this is cool because
it lets you you know perform these two
deep internal checks without using an
agent and the way that this works is
that you know it essentially
authenticates with new net network end
points over SMB using a single
administrative service account and this
service account you naturally has to
have remote login privileges in order to
do this it has to have pretty deep
administrative privileges d8 in order to
be able to perform these internal checks
and this is cool because it lets it
perform these deep interrogation so you
don't need an agent it's wonderful
except it also creates a single point of
failure you now have this device that
you know has like god mode mode
privileges that as soon as you put a new
end point on the network it tries to
authenticate with it you know over ntlm
which you can relay to other things so
naturally you know like if you don't set
up your network with us and be signing
you can just start and this thing's
there you can just kind of add new
endpoints the network and then relay
these authentication attack attempts to
basically anything you want unless you
enable SMB signing which you know I
guess I kind of stopped in your tracks
from doing that but you still these if
these these really really powerful
hashes being sent to any of your device
that is added to the network so that
kind of sucks I mention that some be
signing basically that's the process of
signing packet for an authentic but ya
know interesting thing about this vendor
is that they actually you know they do
offer if you if you if you kind of probe
them about this they do actually offer a
piece of software that you can install
in on your network at endpoints to kind
of prevent this this this kind of
problem from occurring but when you
think about doing that it sounds like
they're talking a lot the subject
they're talking about a
like an agent pulled over again and
considering the chief selling point here
is that no agent is required yeah kind
of back to square one again so the
reason why I bring this up is it just
kind of illustrates the point that there
really is no magic bullet here security
with convenient it really is a paradox
and it ultimately comes down you have to
have an honest business decision about
how much of either one you wanted any
given situation all right now we've
talked about knacks
another another cool thing we need to
talk about in order to go back to what
we originally you know going forwards is
whether this containment thing works
let's talk about client isolation on a
wireless network so client isolation
it's typically used to prevent wireless
devices from communicating one another
you can do it on a wired network too but
a wireless network case actually uses a
security control typical use case is a
open network you know the way a tor 2.11
is supposed to work and say we have
these two laptops our character this
network this this ap here supposed to
act as a mediator between all traffic so
if you know laptop a in the bottom left
that's offbeat laptop being the bottom
or top right are trying to communicate
with one another
if the AP doesn't want us to happen they
can just start dropping packets and and
this one occurred the problem is that
you know at least on a wireless network
client installation is a purely logical
control you can't really prevent radio
transceivers from communicating with one
another and this was a point that was
really seized upon by a research
researcher named Cedric Blanchard in
2005 and he introduced this really cool
tool called Wi-Fi tap which was later
revived by Oliver Lavery of GDS way
before my time there but since we the
way it works is a tree's packets from
the victim to the AP using a Wi-Fi
interface on monitor mode and injects
response to those packages if they came
from the AP this allows Wi-Fi tap to
actually bypass client isolation and
furthermore communicate with devices on
an open network without actually being
associated with that network in the
first place so that's kind of like blows
the whole like client insulation thing
out of water so I mean there are some
other tools that do similar stuff but
with more capabilities so the aircraft
suite has some really they have air town
in G which is really cool because you
can do this on a web network it has tkip
ton in G which lets you do this on a WPA
one Network although it's a lot slower
and they're also like some theoretical
attacks which honestly I don't really
believe they work but it's I just kind
of put them in here to be thorough
there's whole 9196 which apparently
theoretically it should be you should be
able do
wpa2 Network yeah I don't really know
I've never actually seen it work so I
mean here's demo how like Wi-Fi tap
would work and essentially you know what
we're gonna do here we have three VMs
each represented by these terminals the
top-right is gonna be a VM that's gonna
host our access point actually this two
VMs I'm sorry the host operating system
two VMs and this this so we have the
first VM which is our gonna be our
access point the second VM which is our
which is going to be our attacker and
this is on the left here where I'm kind
of moving my mouse and then the bottom
right we're gonna have a terminal that's
kind of synced to our host operating
system so we've created a network using
our first VM write a wireless network
and we're gonna associate to with it
using our host operating system as you
can see so we've done that the first
thing we're gonna do is we're going to
send five IC IC MP packets from our host
operating system so we've done that
since five of them and as expected we
receive five ICMP responses so there's
this really cool proof-of-concept tool
that comes with Wi-Fi tap you know and
it's called Wi-Fi ping essentially all
dozens and jack responses to ICMP
packets it's a really cool
proof-of-concept because it just really
easily shows that you can do this so
we're gonna send those five ICMP packets
again but this time we're also gonna be
running Wi-Fi ping from the attackers
machine over here and as you can see
despite the fact that we're sending five
ICMP requests we're receiving ten ICMP
responses and this attacker here is not
even associated with that network so
that really just demonstrates that
client isolation is you know ultimately
doesn't really work if you really want
to try hard at getting around it but
yeah you know that's enacting you know
we were talking about whether knacks you
know you know if they're effective or
not identifying endpoints when they're
authorized or unauthorized but I really
think that that's actually missing the
point because you know nak isn't really
the only problem problem that you're
dealing with on a wireless network you
know if you think about the role in
containing a wireless breach you're
using it to prevent attackers from
accessing sensitive information after
the breach occurs you know the way that
does this is if an unauthorized employ
is detected you know you're gonna take
one of two actions you're gonna place
the endpoint in quarantine or you're
gonna block the port so in other words
you know violating an access control
policy set forth by this nak it's going
to call it an act to impose some privacy
correction on this device and a wired
network this is actually a physical
restriction in a wireless network as we
just you know slot with legislation
there's gonna only be a logical
restriction so I want you to imagine
this scenario we've just actually you
know we're on like a pen test or
something or what you know and we've
just you know gained access to a
wireless network and unfortunately
there's this been there's a snack here
that was kind of waiting for us and it's
placed us in a quarantine VLAN and so
we're kind of dead in the water because
we want to get over here to this
restricted VLAN where we can access
these sensitive resources
unfortunately we know that we have one
victim device already on this network
and it's authorized and with the reason
why we know that is because we would
have had to attack this victim device to
get access to this network in the first
place using the technique that we saw in
the very very beginning of this talk so
the question is how do we get out of
this how do we pivot from this
quarantine VLAN to the restorative VLAN
so before we you know talk about that we
have to review a couple things one is
element argument and betina's poisoning
basically the way NetBIOS name
resolution works is that you check your
local cache and also you check your
lmhosts so essentially when one Windows
machine wants to talk to another Windows
machine on a network right it's first
going to check its local cache and also
check it's like you know hard-coded host
file which has a bunch of the names and
IP addresses that result one another if
all that fails it's going to attempt to
use DNS you know it's gonna make the NS
request to local name servers if that
fails it's going to fall back to two
protocols called Elliman RMB TNS which
are you know implemented differently but
basically behave the same way and the
best way to understand how I'm an
element rmb T Network is through example
so we have two windows computers named
Allison Leroy and Alice wants to request
a file from Leroy because Leroy's a file
server Alice does not know Leroy's IP so
Alice is going to attempt to resolve
Leroy's hostname
both locally and also using DNS but say
this fails at this point Alice will fall
back to element R and n between s and
and and by doing this else will actually
send a broadcast request to every single
host on alice's subnet and this
broadcast is request is basically going
to say hey are you Leroy if you are
please send me a response with your IP
address and of course you know every
computer analysis summons can receive
this and the idea is that only Leroy
will respond yeah right
this basically like creates a problem
because you know you can just sit on you
can just sit on the subnet and
listen for these requests and if you see
one you can just send a response to it
and you know essentially providing the
victim receive the response before your
response before the before the
legitimate you know computers that this
is gonna you know essentially the first
one's going to be considered valid the
first one that the the targets and
receive is going to consider ballot and
this one actually let you force devices
to send traffic to you as an attacker so
it's a really effective and the middle
attack and this is just kind of how it
works essentially the most common tool
for doing this is called responder by
the way written by Lauren job Laurence
Joffe and kind of kind of fast words the
point we running so essentially the way
this attack works is you're gonna have
you know some poisoners here which gonna
respond to these you know any of these
MBT a necessary element are requests and
you're going to also have authentication
service on a variety of ports listening
for this attempt to succeed so we're
over here we're actually going to open
up Explorer on our victim machine named
Jenkins yes there is a machine named
Leroy later on and we're gonna put in
the name of a non-existent server well
that's gonna do because the server
doesn't actually exist it's going to
force this device to fall back to Elmen
REM BTS and the result is that hashes
are going to happen very quickly as you
can see already that causes the attacker
be able to harvest hashes so yeah you
know as far as our little escape attempt
here that gives us a little bit of the
way there let's talk about one more
thing and that's redirect a sunbeam
so the redirect S&B is an attack that
was developed by some people at silence
a few years ago and essentially the way
that works is that you forced the victim
to you to visit an HTTP endpoint so you
provide them with a URL and it it this
URL takes them to a server which
instantly redirects them to a rogue SMB
server on your machine so you basically
make redirect into a file that you are
hosting you're not really hosting it but
you know you're listening on the port
where it's gonna try to connect to this
will actually cause them to to
authenticate with you and by doing this
you can capture ntlm hashes or relay
this until my authentication attempts
there's a variation of this where you
actually redirect them to a non-existent
SMB share instead which
trigger element are MBT Ness but either
way it's a pretty fast way to get
hatchets it does require social
engineering so this is the part of
presentation where we actually got to do
new stuff everyone's here
yeah we made it this far let me do the
time check really fast actually
all right it's like 4 p.m.
good we're doing great all right so
hostile portal attacks they're actually
a way that you could steal ad credits
from wireless networks without network
access this kind of ties into the next
stuff we were talking about earlier but
it's more like a stepping stone that we
need to in order to pull off its attack
so I I'm guessing you guys have seen
something like this recently staying at
this hotel or anywhere yeah so that's
that's a captive portal and essentially
the way that it works it's usually used
to restrict access to open Wi-Fi
networks and the way that they work is
that you know when you pin to the
network all your DNS queries are gonna
be resolved to the location of that
captive portal login page all your DNS
traffic is gonna be redirected to the
network owners DNS server so that you're
forced to use this specially configured
DNS server and additionally they'll
usually you know redirect all your HTTP
traffic to that login page as well so no
matter what you do until you you know
either entering credentials pay for or
just spoof someone's MAC address you're
forced to go back to here no matter what
you do every time you send HTTP traffic
pretty much so a hostile portal attack
it kind of actually like ties in this
this this captive portal concept with
with the redirects SMB attack what
happens is that when you when you launch
a hostile portal the first thing you do
is you use a rogue ap attack to force
the victim device to associate with you
once you do that now you're their
gateway so that enables you to do kind
of something similar to what we saw with
the captive portal except that instead
of redirecting their HTTP traffic to a
login page we're going to redirect their
HTTP traffic to an SMB share on your
machine as we saw with the previous two
attacks this will actually force their
browser to attempt ntlm authentication
with you so kind of show how this works
and this in this scenario we have
jenkins again and we have the legitimate
access point in the top right in this
terminal and we have the attackers over
here in the left terminal and so jenkins
the victims currently
associated with this Network example
Wi-Fi and here we're going to actually
you know send somethi off packets and
that's going to force Jenkins to roam
over from the legitimate access point to
the attackers access point and you see
it's connected here the attacker is now
going to open internet explorer and it
goes to the home page and already we
have hatched this because we you know
sometimes defeat traffic actually if you
see you know we're typing in the address
bar there there's like this autocomplete
feature where it's just every time you
type a character it's making you HTTP
requests to try to autocomplete for your
little Bing search thing and that's just
send the hashes to the attacker over and
over again so that's a basic cost portal
attack I guess an open network here
we're talking about WPA EAP network so
you actually have to you know bridge a
couple more gasp before we can use an
attack against an enterprise network so
once again when we're talking about WPA
EAP most cases we're talking about EEP
EEP EEP and EPT TLS both of these used
ms Chafee to is the inter authentication
that method so an interesting thing
about em is Chafee - it's a mutual
authentication protocol you know this
means that the radiance server actually
has to prove knowledge of the supplicant
faster the clients password for the
interrupt n ocation to succeed so what
this means is that although the attacker
can force the victim to authenticate
with the evil twin and use it to steal
hashes or you know that can be cracked
it actually the radius network the
attacker actually cannot complete the
entire authentication process because
the very end of this authentication
process the attacker has to prove
knowledge of the victims password and if
we knew the victims password who
wouldn't be doing this attack in the
first place so we have to we have to you
know find a way around this problem and
there are a couple ways you can do this
for weak radius passwords the leg works
actually already been done once again by
Tom white and Ian de Villiers back in
2014 they came up with a technique
called Auto crack and AD which can be
used for weak radius passwords to kind
of get around this whole issue and we'll
talk about that in a second and for
stronger radius passwords once again
remember that you can crack them as
cheffy to challenge responses very very
very quickly so you know the solution
there simply to crack those offline you
know come back the next day and then
finish the attack so auto crack can add
the way with it it works
you know hostapd by the way is the name
of the radius server that you
traditionally use when you perform this
kind of the style of the tap so at the
very end of the MS happy to process
authentication process this is what
we're looking at actually is the the
last two steps of MS jv2 authentication
process this victim device is going to
set a challenge response to the radius
server or hostapd in this case now
hostapd at this point is going to
attempt to load the user's password from
this this very special text file that
stores the stuff in plain text the I
know it's silly but yeah it's gonna
attempt to load the users password from
the EAP user file and you know using
that password that's loaded from the EAP
user file it's then going to construct
the this authentication response which
is used to prove knowledge of the
victims password to the victim you know
at this point it sends that to the
victim with the authentication success
message and the entire thing is succeeds
the problem is that you know as we
mentioned this this spot here where I'm
kinda waving my mouse that's actually
where this process is going to break
down if you don't already know the
victim's password right because we're
you know they've sent us the child
response but we don't have their their
password or empty password hashes which
is past your equivalent in the EP user
file so this is gonna fail right there
so I don't crack an ADD it's actually a
really really cool technique and the way
that it works is that instead of
immediately loading or attempting to
load the password from the if user file
you take that challenge response and
then shoot it off you may be just gonna
make an API call to a remote cracking
rig that's equipped to crack these
things very very quickly so you send
this challenge and response off to a
cracking rig it kind of looks like a
tool here in the top right if you can
notice and then you know essentially
once you crack that you receive the API
response from the cracking rig then you
just append the cracked a password or a
password hash to the end of the EP user
file at this point host hippety which is
which is patched to do this by the way
loads this pasture to pasture has from
the EP user file as if nothing happened
uses that's constructed the
authentication response and from there
you know this whole process concedes
so that's Auto cracking add the second
option as we talked about is to simply
crack you know that the credentials
offline and finish the attack later and
you know once again with a the proper
effigy it's fpga-based hardware I can't
talk today or even just like
sufficiently powerful for cracking great
you're going to get really really good
results usually within 24 hours so
here's the same attack that we saw
earlier
this time we're leveraging this attack
against a wpa2 EAP PEEP that work right
we're using you know it's no longer an
open network and we're using the auto
crack and AD technique and as you see
here this time it's not an open network
the user is going to receive a
certificate warning it's you notice it's
not very descriptive by the way just
says are you expecting this network to
be here well considering you just
connected to this network a few minutes
ago probably but yeah as you can see it
still succeeds and we have the ntlm v2
hash that we were able to capture using
the hostel portal tag so what is what
does this attack get you it gets you
lots and lots of ntlm hashes you know
the results you get are actually very
very similar to element rmb teen s
poisoning but there are a few key
advantages here and the the most glaring
one is that you don't need direct
network access which makes it stealthier
you also are not limited to a local
subnet now you get everything that's
connected to a wireless the wireless
network it's also not a passive attack
you're not waiting for element REM UTS
requests are similar to show up on the
network you're forcing this to happen so
back to a little scenario we were
talking about we can actually build off
this to do the second you know new thing
that we're going to introduce today and
that's the indirect wireless pivot so
you can use this to bypass rogue if you
can use the bypass port based actual
control mechanisms on these networks
that we pretty much spent the first part
of the talk talking about so here's our
scenario again once again we are on this
quarantine VLAN and we want to get over
to this restricted VLAN so let's assume
by the way you know we already have the
victims of password hash and we know
this ten minutes we're good
awesome okay so yeah so let's assume by
the way that you know we already have
this victim's password hatch and the
reason why we know this is because we
would have had to capture this to get
all this network in the first place so
you know assume we assuming we have two
wireless interfaces and the first
wireless interface or the one with that
IP address on let's quarantine VLAN we
can use the second wireless interface to
use a rogue ap attack to force this
victim to connect
our second wireless interface at this
point we perform the hostile
portal-to-portal attack once again using
the second wireless interface and use
the capture and TLM hashes from the
victim at this point we crack that
hashes offline I mean we may not have to
come back and pick up the pick off the
attack where we left off but at this
point you know we essentially kill a
rogue access point and this allows the
victim to reassociate with the target
network so you know at this point this
this still is an authorized device so
you know at this point the the device
will get moved back to over to the
restricted VLAN which is where you want
to go and this point we wait for the
reverse shell and we've successfully
bypassed an app a better way of doing
this see use nasan be relay attack say
that we have two victims you know with
with an account that can access both do
the same thing forced them to connect to
your second wireless device perform the
SMB relay attack from one to the other
and then once again kill your rogue ap
and allowed them to reassociate the
target Network now just wait for the
reverse shell and you bypass the nak
once again so quick demo of this
happening so essentially we you know now
we have Leroy and Jenkins by the way
we're gonna be attacking and we have the
legitimate AP is gonna be over here on
the left the first thing we're going to
do is we're going to force these devices
to connect to us using a real ap attack
and you can see we just did that here
now we're gonna force the second device
to connect to us and then essentially
we're gonna start this SMB relay server
or use ion packet for that and we're
going to handle our duel of our agent
handling using Empire so the first thing
we do is we're actually gonna grab you
IP address of the victim device that
we're gonna try to you know pivot into
I'm gonna feed that to our SMB relay
server we are then going to generate
some HTTP traffic on one of our victim
devices and you can see this activity
here that's the SMB relay attack
actually happening this will give us an
agent on this device and we're gonna you
know this point fast-forward a little
bit the way we're going to do this is
were actually is a persistent module
persistence module that places a
scheduled task
on this system and his federal taxes
going to launch a reverse shell and this
reverse shell is going to execute you
know once once the devices are connected
back to the target network and it's
gonna give us that access so something
really interesting happened when I
actually recorded this which was that
you know I actually forgot to attach the
virtual USB interface and VMware so I
was like oh well this the sucks because
I'm gonna have to rerecord it but then
something really really interesting
happen and actually that's kind of why I
kept this little this little thing in
here essentially I had placed 120
retries that happened over an over 45
second period on this reverse shell so
in other words when I reconnected the
wireless interface and then went to you
know kind of like clear clear the
screens and and and restart this attack
it's just kind of you know start with
pick up where I left off I magically
received should see it bobby-pin a
second the reverse shell that I was
originally looking for and I thought
that was kind of cool so I left it in
there because it proves a really good
point about like really persistent
implants is the fact that you know you
can you can't actually design something
that will just you know doggedly try to
like connect back to you despite the
fact that if you can't do so immediately
so that's indirect Wireless pivot you
know the equivalent technique on a wired
network would be literally like
unplugging the authorized device from
the wall checking to a hostile network
on which you can attack it and the
reason why this works is it for support
based yeah I love that movie so the
reason why it's attack works is that
port based action controls they rely on
the assumption of the physical layer can
be trusted in a wireless network
wpa2 EAP is the means to us the
integrity of physical layer protected
when a weak form of wpa2 EAP is used
this means the attacker can actually
freely control the physical layer and by
doing this this actually renders
port-based nak mechanisms useless what
this demonstrates is that port based nak
mechanisms they don't effectively
mitigate the risk presented by weak wpa2
EAP implications and you know
furthermore it also demonstrates that
adding port based nak mechanisms to
wireless networks that does not make the
use of EAP TLS or if you keep any less
inappropriate if the network in question
is used to grant access to sensitive
information so you know before we wrap
this up gonna make one last is you know
kind of case for using EAP TLS it's
really not as bad as it used to be you
can use you can actually leverage group
policy quite extensively to configure
8'o 2.1 ex-clients your best options
really to use a private CA to leverage
ad as much as possible to deploy eap-tls
and you can even you know distribute the
server sort to clients and if you're
like in a BYOD situation you can use a
really streamlined view ID on board a
solution or an MDM to disturb you the
search that way and actually you can
even use lots and Cripps although like
even on let scripts website they're like
this is probably not the best way to do
this but I mean that is an option as
well so just some closing thoughts
just because wireless and wired networks
operate in the same way at the logical
level it's important to remember that
they don't necessarily operate the same
way at the physical level so that's
something to keep in mind when designing
security controls for wireless networks
and also has the community we really
should question whether it's a truly a
sound business decision to neglect
eap-tls in favor of a more reactive
approach that forced us on actions
control and threat containment and
finally if there's one thing to take
away from this talk it's that this needs
for security and convenience are really
often at odds with one another so it's
really important to maintain a healthy
skepticism towards solutions that really
promise to be both of those thank you
cyber questions okay any questions no
questions all right cool use or we got
the slides shoot actually like I don't
know where the slides are yet I guess
like check the hacks test Twitter
because I'll light just tweeted at them
and then the slides will be there does
that work all right cool awesome sauce
some other hands over there okay anyone
else no really all right that was easy