hi-oh so it's kind of a tradition that I
get that post lunch slot it's the second
time this year I'm getting a slot so I
hope you all paid well but I hope that
you are motivated a bit and I thought
that I will do some game where I say how
can you say fast but then are you in for
it no okay so let's start with the talk
I'm here today to speak about
vaccination and anti honeypot approach
it's not that I'm against honey pots
I've clarified it but later on I'm Pro a
different approach of repelling
attackers by acting the other way around
from honey pots wonderful animation
you'll see a lot of those animations I'm
doing my talk be ready for it
what I'm trying to do is well today we
are in the world of like we're we are
like trying to chase malware it's just
like cat and mouse game but well we end
up most of the time the other way around
you know the mouse chase of the canton
yeah it's quite problematic and I feel
that we're too much in this state and
rather the other way around so what I'm
trying to do is turn round well it's
also my first time in Canada yeah yeah I
once speak a bit about it before I start
told to technical like boring stuff when
I flew here I thought it does worry
about see ya this was my like my idea of
Canada like till now oh I remember that
there's also this guy I'm not really can
he looks like his Canadian Mountie knee
Mountie Mountie yeah Mountie I'm not
sure he's Canadian but it's was also my
idea of Canada but then I remember
there's also like this guy which is one
of my favorite singer songwriters and
also Canadians oh qoodles for you Canada
and I thought no Neil Young is not the
only one so yeah there are plenty of
more amazing people from Canada which I
really like and appreciate and what oh
yeah but there's this guy also so yeah
so Canada this is on you yeah this is
the last that allows the animation of my
intro to Canada so what's next
what we are about it after they hear a
bit about 20 pots was what is the honey
part bit of like basic concepts about
honey pots
what is an anti honey pot but not in the
world of computer security but in the
nature it's not my idea there are a lot
of cases in the nature of anti honey pot
and from there we'll take this concept
and apply it to computer security with
hands-on examples and really deep
technical stuff which I hope you're up
to we'll do a bit of good idea that idea
when applying vaccination to you know
realize enterprises or even home users
and also have a knife demo okay so a bit
about myself
hi I'm gal which is wave in Hebrew my 21
year old geek from Tel Aviv my company
it's not mine I'm working for it it's
called Minerva labs this kind of my day
job what you seeing here today but
there's not like a commercial
promotional talk so if I'm talking about
layer it's ok it's not it's ok also I'm
calling myself Margot psychologist
because what I'm focusing on as the the
fears of malware what it tries to evade
I invented the term it's not like I'm an
evangelist like all of those guys that
I'm not a I'm just a malware
psychologist senior one
I know my way around all kind of weird
exotic languages like Python and Java
and I know like a bit more useful ones
like Arabic also other Arabic speakers
in the crowd
hello Salafi khumba Manasa but hax first
and finished about - so yeah and also
I've learned another nicer linguistic
joke which I thought I'll do here Dave
as JFK did and it's like visiting Berlin
he said bin ein Berliner
right so ich bin eine québécois right
epic war is the term yeah so another
nice linguistic thing and I did tons of
stuff from PowerShell little strips to
attacking SCADA systems that's it's all
important but what I like about this
target all the like the different stuff
I did they all have some kind of common
ground they are all tried to to evade
some some points and this allows us to
vaccinate against you'll see it later on
in stock it will be much more clear so I
just want to follow me or ask me
questions this is my Twitter by the way
if we need to take any photos doing to
talk feel free I don't mind it's a bit
too fast sometimes there are a lot of
links doing talk feel free to do so okay
so let's start with what is the honeypot
we'll do it the James Bond style you can
see on the right side it's Sean Connery
and on the left side as xenia onatopp
from the classic Goldeneye so she's the
honeypot it's a bit statistic and James
Bond is known to be some kind of made
surgeon istic scumbag but well she is
the honeypot she abuses James like
his lifetime no hunger for beautiful
dangerous woman and she's always the
first girl to appear and Bond movie
she's doing like this little dance and
she looks like a cat for James and then
he comes over but then most of the time
he realizes though you're not what I
thought you are so been you know more
zhenya want to talk and that's like what
happens to most of our movies and and in
life most of the times there are good
products which do honeypot related kind
of stuff but this happens quite a lot so
this is the honeypot what is an anti
honeypot well I like to think about anti
honeypot as a very natural approach of
repelling attackers you can see those
two snakes here and this photo it's
quite easy to differentiate one from
another and one of the the milk snake
and one is the coral snake once venomous
and the other is not the one which is
not which thinks that the milk snake he
tries to mimic the one which is venomous
and by that he repels the kind of I know
birds or whatever that tries to attack
it by just looking like one which is
dangerous this becomes tough we are
gonna do today you know to repel
checkers from our computer we will look
like we are venomous poisonous we'll do
our best and by that we will repel
real-life threats and a lot of them
actually there's another example of two
butterflies it's called by the way
Bayesian mimicry I think so
this kind of butterflies it was recently
announced that it is not this guy it's
like a really biological thing but it's
not the exact kind of mimicry but also
those butterflies are at least
like a year ago they were considered to
be hackers there you have the the
monarch butterfly and the Viceroy
butterfly you can see that they look a
bit different and it was considered that
one of them tries to mimic the other
which don't have to be false but who
cares and by that some that just like
avoided of eating it because it who I
don't know call them like diarrhea or
something and so yeah there are also
hackers the they don't type color zero a
tree but there are also kind of hackers
okay let's take this talk to a bit more
practical place because you know yeah
vaccination isn't an amazing concept
yeah it's fit it's working but it's
working in the nature and we are not
going to take our PC from back home and
paint it like it was a venomous snake or
I know paint like I'm the butterfly
wings on it it it's most definitely
won't work and first in order to repel
the attackers we need to know what they
are afraid of and I did this work of
categorizing their fears I started about
a couple of years ago and recently I
found a new fear of malware so didn't
like it for plus plus ways to repel bad
guys let's start with the first fear you
guys in the crowd how many of you are
blue teamers at least yeah yeah so more
than one they're afraid of you and
different panelists they're afraid of
anyone who tries to dissect them they're
afraid of running in sandbox you're not
actually afraid they just think it's
more cost-effective not to be executed
in a sandbox because then they'll be
captured and analyzed and all of their
extensive array of VPNs and VPS and God
knows what which they really try
hard to set up it will be wasted and
it's expensive and if you are a cyber
crime gang well you want to be cost
efficient because you have competition
it's like a real really competitive
market I think so they're afraid of
first like virtualized and analysis
environments sometimes they try to
measly that reverse it directly if you
manually analyze them sometimes they
want to fool like automated analysis
tools like sandbox they seek hints for
either static and dynamic analysis tools
like Ida Ida Pro or Wireshark which is
dynamic it's a sniffer now but debugger
ism they seek for the actual
infrastructure for VirtualBox for vmware
for AQ mvu and all this kind of stuff
it's been out there for years now this
little snippet it's a very simple vision
technique it's like finding a window of
all et bugger or windbg and it's been
out there since blackhat 2007 it's over
10 years old so it's not a kind of a
cutting-edge technique you don't need
you you can evade this way from like
automated analysis and manual analysis
although this kind of stuff I found a
bit like salting because I know that
when I debug male work I look exactly
for this kind of stuff and well dude you
must be kidding me if you're doing this
kind of stuff I'm debugging you using a
debugger so I can see where I'm doing
this kind of stuff but just my personal
idea about it so another example from
this is the lucky sample from bit more
than a year ago
are there any asking injures in the
crowd
well if you look up close you will see
that there's like a really complex
jumping array over here and
it's just like if it's match of like car
by car string which it gets through get
username a it will germinate but only if
all the roads out found and if you
translated that's fing down here from
from ASCII to you know human readable
stuff it will be sandbox so this lucky
sample will never run on your machine if
you use named sandbox I actually
considered changing my his name back
home and at my grandma's PC to sandbox
to avoid this kind of stuff it would
work if you know about like the recent
emote at which wreak havoc look up close
if its source but enough exhausted like
I think it Jo sandbox have a really good
D compilation of its source code and is
afraid of the exactly the same thing
just FYI so yeah a bit more recent
example you all know want to cry but
have you heard about you iwi X no and
there was a bit of talked about it wanna
cry you could have got the sample of it
you just needed to set up an SMB honey
pot but you iwi acts on the other hand
it was a bit more smart so researchers
had really tough time finding a sample
of it and why it's just like copy pasted
code from repositories it's dislike its
did the is debugger present it searched
for pipes at search for load modules and
for average loaded model sorry for files
the most elementary stuff you can think
about I actually was able to find the
the source where it you know copy/paste
it from this like almost the exactly
same order else and this also as almost
the same order it's amazing to see how
easy it is to be stealth fear like
almost totally completely stealth
because it was never observed almost in
the wild
and they did have an operation so I
guess that they were able to infect guys
they used internal eternal blue and
double pulsar so like everyone else they
must have some kind of success this
one's a bit even more extreme you can
see that the exact same pattern you see
here by the way with way too much back
slashes somehow windows kinda scenes
handles it but you can see the exact
same order over here and over here and
funny enough where this arrow points you
can see that both of those also copies
from each other because they all also
have this closing bracket thingy over
there and well I know who copied from
who but also and have a cop based job
all the artifacts relates to
virtualization infrastructure like
cuckoo
I think cuckoo wasn't free via slide and
here it's just like either a VMware or
VirtualBox
again nothing new it's all known it's a
colleague based job I have actually
another talk about writing metal from
scratch using copy paste but this one
for maybe next year well next year
they're also afraid of have like blue
teamers but the other way around
today you have great security products
some of them are more expensive than
others some are less expensive some of
them for free but bad guys can test
their stuff offline they can learn you
let's say a bank buys your I know let's
say say if ISA whatever product and
severe large bank so II said will have
the logo of this Bank in a web site or
web I know Bank of America is using our
products and well bad guys can I have
not move east by the way they're
actually a product but then that guys
can just offline how we're doing against
them are we good are we not and they can
decide
based on the results of their execution
in their lab against this products well
should we or shouldn't we yeah in most
cases they won't meet all the products
but we had a case of Tesla crypt and
lucky a different variant of lucky from
roughly a couple of years ago where they
executed in all cases other than if
there was a registry key associated with
ESET Kaspersky Lab or not G data it was
a vast I have the sample here for life
demo later on I'll show it to you live
well they know that they bypass like
nine percent of the AVS and they have
their operation ready to go and it's
expensive to you know don't press the
button but then you have a very costly
infrastructure setup so and as we said
you need to be cost effective so well we
can be afraid of only two vendors and
still be very effective so why not let's
just see if those registry values are
present and by that will decide if we
execute or not and some examples for
similar one similar mail well which did
it it's not petia by the way am I not
going to speak about the affiliation of
not paid yeah or bad rabbit but not paid
you actually checked if there are
specific processes related to Norton
Simon packages same and Kaspersky it was
a bit complex they did a real nice trick
using a white mask you know the bottom
line is that they you know they had like
five D
capabilities and if you had Kaspersky
specific ones won't be executing if you
had known and semantics other ones won't
be executed I did all of the bits
calculation over there in a table and if
you had ever Kaspersky or not--and slash
simatech you had a really good chance
that it won't fit if you NPR or will
propagate through your network which is
amazing just like by having specific AV
which doesn't prevent anything the
malware will decide not to attack you
and well this prevents like 20% of stuff
but later on we'll see how we can create
this kind of indicators that will make
the malware be afraid to prevent even
40% of the capability of the Medway it's
not like amazing but think about most
damage won't be done that rabbit just
the same again nothing about affiliation
or I'm not trying to yeah it's the
Russians not sorry and that God knows
who but it's exactly the same trick they
calculated some kind of a custom hash
and compared it and they did of the same
bytes calculations
Kaspersky released the I think it was
guess first yes from secure list they
released the all the process of its
either dr. Webb or McAfee in this case
and actually the I did the test in my
lab and it will keep executing no matter
what but it's won't rip the disc locally
the MBR will still be destroyed so it's
not that helpful in this case that you
can trade all those processes and maybe
you the next not bad rabbit petia
something will be prevented by it just
like vaccinating your machine with
random processes
and by the way I released I rewrote the
the hashing that was used by bad rabbit
in Python I did a little experiment
brute forcing it but Kaspersky released
the results before me so if you want to
see it is available and my kid have
account under a good rabbit
yeah and have a joke ok next we're at
the first image of a cat in the
slideshow by the way we have we have
like cartoons back in the first line but
no matter that guys are also afraid from
themselves dislike the classic
vaccination it's a subclass of
vaccination actually they create
infection markers to avoid infecting the
same machine twice because garden hose
what happens if you encrypt like with
two multi-threaded ransomware the same
machine twice like what is the first
private kid
what was the first like private and
public and then the AES and you don't
know what was encrypted when it's like
awful awful thing so you use infection
marker and if you start to infect a
machine you won't do it again because
you don't want to make like then the
encryption irreversible or you don't
want to execute two instances of Trojan
horses because maybe if you are abiding
binding the TCP port you'll get an error
because you can't find the speed say
this report twice do the same address
because you know physics they've
sometimes do it properly they sometimes
do it less than properly taken for
example hold the TCP port at the mutex
but most of the times used and actually
problem unix
there are so so many examples for it
this one is from configure which is just
the same it's more examples you see
later in like the next couple of slides
and the pattern I always seek is a
reverse engineer is get last error and
then compare it with B seven which is a
already exist
whatever this means that the music's
already exist and then you can see the
exit process called like couple lines
later it just moves pretty small so just
trust me but always seek for this
pattern another one which is a bit more
contemporary this is an average yes yet
another lucky example from very very
early example lucky by this one is from
a guy named sylveon I can't pronounce
his last name sorry guys that's like
amazing what he did here what like the
bad guys did here
they created a registry key called
completed with a value which was either
true or false it was under hklm software
naki they actually did amazing software
engineering here I would done exactly
the same if I had like a commercial
product called lucky I guess and if he
created the same value and the same key
in advance and the completed was set to
true it won a trip to a machine but it
is a radiant ripped one the registry
value saver sure so yeah it's a writing
cryptid so and if I create in advance I
know that there is like a large Loki
outbreak and i vaccinate endpoints
against this outbreak by creating this
registry key I'm winning the game no
matter which Packer you used which
obfuscation infection back to the
payload it's same payload it's going to
check this registry value I'm the same
rent registry key and I can prevent it
from it running display so yeah there
are a bit more like recent examples like
spora spore was this Hoffler text font
wasn't found
thank it also the same thing it's such a
search actually a mutex which was M
concatenated with the volume serial
number in decimal format we released uh
like our guys back home released a
vaccination against it you want you can
use it I think spore is no longer a
thing now but it's nice to have publicly
it's of course open source etc wanna cry
again one of the largest infection yeah
we we had this nice little guy met with
check vlog which is currently under I
think like Criminal Investigation or
something
he found the kill switch which wasn't
vaccinations what kill switch but there
was also vaccination he had mutex which
was the same pattern you can you know
things with larger so you can see it it
checks for this set Emma Stone win
whatever with an a concatenated in the
end which is not a real mutex which you
might see and it then you can see like
the guess let's get this error and
compare EAX with v7 which is what I said
you should always look for and if you
created this mutex wanna cry won't run
your machine also in this case we
released a nice vaccination this is a
very interesting case because you know
when you double-click on a sample use it
Windows has this lovely lovely concept
of sessions and it will run in your
session but one cry was spread over and
exploit and it was running and system
privileges so if you create a script and
you vaccinate your machine by
double-clicking it or I know spreading
it over
WMI or something it won't be executed in
the same session as wanna cry so yeah
you can even like take the sample
download it to your machine double-click
the sample after you double-click on
script of course and you can see how it
is prevented I am vaccinated but no
you're not because it's not running in
the
correct session and we have a little axe
session about it in the last part of
this slide of the SOI presentation but
should be careful when you do
vaccination it's it's not like that
simple always yeah and yeah also not
petia and that rabbit we have this great
dude amid server which is a friend
we found the donations for delve it's a
simple fire we need to create and then
you can get rid of girls I think it's
not even an infection marker in bed
rabbits case it's just like he prevents
the capability to make it persistent and
by that he just like it's just like
making note freshens away and well we
have so many cases like this I believe
it's to be continued at least like this
genre of infection markers we have it
like since forever since the early 90s
so I think we'll see much more of those
next category of fears Russian yeah it's
not actually like just specifically
Russian but we need to be careful what
we wish for when you do vaccination when
you create all kinds of markers and you
know many ransomware won't infect you if
you have Russian or Ukrainian or any
kind of Kerala keyboard well it's it's
nice so let's all add keyboards you know
maybe they're afraid of you know maybe
they think this nice little fellow will
be after them and if they infect Russian
citizens possibly he's like really cute
and furry I don't know why but
other software what I like to call
comrade targeted malware that's my
granddad voice and they will infect you
only if you have Russian keyboard so
well repelling some of the attackers but
I'm luring some other attackers so what
is mine it's a bit of a tricky game as I
said vaccination is nice it can be
really good but we should be careful
what we wish for and yeah that's like my
last all new category of malware fears
crypto - crystal - everywhere it's like
my first attempt to use this meme and a
finger there is right and crystal miner
is the next ransomware this from like
where I'm standing and from my point of
view it's a quick easy money which it's
hard to detect ransomware are where it's
difficult today to write a proper
ransomware
there are a lot of like I don't know if
it's like necessarily consumer grade
software that handles brandsmart day but
to do like a proper ransomware which
will attack a properly defended
organization it's pretty difficult to be
and crypto miners are much more
efficient live you know being liberated
with little knowledge and I think it is
we're gonna see much more of those but
with this new malware we see new type of
fears and crypto miners are
interestingly afraid of test manager
yeah your friendly neighborhood task
manager because when you enter a website
which uses a queen-high for somebody
infected you with variants you know like
a modified version of the XM r IG xml
ring oh god knows how you call it it
were grind your CPU many times the first
time I browse to a website which hosts
the coin hive script I heard a male
worth for the first time in
my life my CPU went crazy and I have an
i7 so that's not like a weak CPU or
something and the first thing I did what
opening task manager understand what the
hell's happening I beats again diner
with my a-v but no it was the browser or
so yeah chrome is is lousy and crying's
your CPU from time time but it's not
that crazy
and I then eliminated tab by chap and I
understood that a large website it's
using coin hive I had this what the [ __ ]
moment but this malware
if it's this kind of detection by
analysts like me by just searching for
the window of evil task manager or you
have some Russian things there which is
test manager in Russian and whenever a
window like this is opened it will just
terminate which is nice there's also
like another thing called an Vela and
variants also a Russian task manager
some sort this was taken from a campaign
we unveiled a couple of weeks ago called
the water miner I don't know if you've
heard about it or not it was the spread
at the GTA mod in Russia so this is why
they target specifically task manager in
Russia this one variant which which
search window this one actually search
for task manager and NV reg Z as like
the process name they called the create
who helps for into snapshot the API and
then they just iterate it over it and if
they found the strata running it just
terminated immediately because I don't
want it to detect me I want to stay on
this machine I want to make some more
money
it just makes perfect sense I guess well
you
so we know what are the fields well we
know already what is a honey pot what is
a hand-tied honey pot we know how to
apply the fears in the nature to fears
and InfoSec like kind of genre but how
bad guys know what to bug out they don't
look in our machine and say oh you are
virtual your sandbox you are they over
there or you are trying to monitor me no
they have specific artifacts and I did
categorization in this matter as well
between static windows artifacts like
registry keys and values files folders
oh can we create persistently and this
what makes them unique I can execute a
simple script and just create all those
for good and I'm okay
I can create you know hklm software a
vmware inc and it's there for good on
the other hand we have dynamic windows
artifacts which are a bit more tricky
processors Music's of Windows like
Windows iOS windows the window you have
in the OS that's like a totally
different wall because you know we can
if we create files yeah you can create a
file and forget about it but should we
try to run ten thousand like Windows
processes music serve whatever at will I
don't think it will end good I have a
script for it - we will try those
scripts later in the live demo they're
also available online and same like
under gal beads I'll post the link is
like in the next slide so you'll be able
to try it as well if you want to but
it's a bit more tricky to do this
dynamic vaccination you might say there
are more
Solutions but but they're like a bit
more commercial and I don't know about
any product which perform with this kind
of the dynamic vaccinations in large
scales effectively which is not
commercial a third category which it's
very interesting but I'm not doing it
it's not like a simple Python script to
write you and also vaccinates like using
this kind of stuff well you have low
level tricks memory using pop codes the
first one which I am aware of is the red
pill by joanna rutkowska
it's amazing it's really efficient
I think it's efficient till the days she
seeks for a specific that's not a spring
it's like specific vines in the memory
which are in constant look it's like
amazing it's I think it's harder to find
this kind of stuff than writing an apt
in like some kind of way many other
things like timing attack scoring the AL
DTSC and trying to measure time stamp
like different serves which are
different between real machines and
machines with hypervisor or you can do
abuse for all sorts of hardware features
you can also call the CPUID instruction
and find like the idea that if the maker
of the cpu which it's different and
there are tons of stuff chung Ventana
constant but why bother this like story
time now those guys are the copy kittens
they are an Iranian apt we unveiled
about if it was over a couple of years
ago they attacked the Israeli Ministry
of Foreign Affairs successfully if I
might say they took an open source
project called the fish the paranoid
fish if anyone aware of efficient you
know fish yeah they've got a vac nose
for fish
so proficient that has a really good
open source project quite basic but
quite good which assist you to find out
if your sandbox is hidden or not you
execute it inside your sandbox and then
you can see if it's detectable by
malware by simple techniques so yeah it
uses the the red field not the red field
but other if like the timing attacks in
hardware featured and it used all this
kind of stuff but well it also seeks for
files and registry keys and artifacts
and for dynamic artifacts we talked
about and and then the the logical
operation of or is performed between all
those different tests and like in real
case like the copy kittens need because
they copycatted fish and then if you
successfully triggered one of the tests
by the original fish to be true which
means it of the sandbox
they won't execute their apt so if I'm
trying to if they even like sorry to
vaccinate against even like a PT class
Iranian malware writers I can just
create the file c program files vmware
it's a simple of step well now it's time
for a good idea bad idea
yeah I hope that you all see in any
maniacs is kid so good idea as a blue
Timur right not a red teamer but it's
quite the same a good idea as a defender
is to sorry as the other way round as a
as a red teamer but it's all for the
same it's blue Timur a good idea is to
search after persistent artifacts not do
all this kind of a problematic timing
attacks which yeah I know I actually
executed some of those attacks on on my
virtual machine then it's failed I want
to have a chance which always succeed in
making me avoid being detected because
if I'm detect only once my entire
operation is gone in some cases if I'm
an apt group
wanna be the chocolate when you are
running an apt you will but you try to
postpone it as much as possible you'll
look for the common artifacts in most
times because they won't be changed like
every version or two and well it's also
good for us when we vaccinate the
endpoint then ideas are also the same
for both attackers and defenders because
bad ideas is going for you know it's
trying to detect a specific process but
if you are starting before the other
process then you won't detect it because
I know it starts like one minute after
the Machine starts and you're already
persistent so you won't see it started
your like test for the presence of
specific AV will return false although
it is installed and I can thinking about
tons of scenarios like this our case you
don't want to do this kind of test
that's human behavior monitoring for
example moving a mouse well yeah that's
like kind of a thing that I demonstrated
I wrote a tool called the smooth
criminal which detects sandboxes by
moving Mouse's it's this really bad idea
all I did was you know what we do today
in sandbox is just like jumping the
mouse from one place to another and by
that we fool malware to think there's
real analysts moving the mouse and what
I did as an attacker I just like did
calculus basic calculus and I calculated
the derivative of the location of the
mouse which is like so it's the speed of
the mouse and I checked if it's like if
head has low values it's good if it has
high value of the mouse is jumping from
one place to another and I was able to
define a threshold but pretend you know
I just come it's a really short script
it's a bad idea because I was able to
push I open the pull request for cuoco
which wasn't first yet but i pushed
Kukui fix exactly for it it is very easy
to mitigate it it's not robust at all
and as an attacker you don't want to do
this kind of stuff so yeah we kind of
already talked about fenders and I want
you to have like a good time so let's do
a bit of demo time so I will open this
one I have a machine just for it we'll
see some examples of executing my script
which is available online you can also
let's if you wanted it's available and
this like address and I'll read it a
snapshot because I forgot it it before a
talk shame on me give it a snapshot
let's drag this direction this direction
that direction yeah so it is my VMware
machine I don't
VMware tools installed so it's quite
stuff but it's not perfect I will
execute the fish show you how much it's
it's a bit like a stove you can do the
same back home if you have a sandbox
I really recommend using the fish it's
also open source so no worries about it
if there's a test which is ok which
means I'm stuff it's in green and what's
not stuff isn't red so you'll be able to
see that most of it is in there
in green what kind of good let's execute
some malware to show how catastrophic
situation is no yeah let's go for
example for the low key I talked about
this one I have a proc one which is
filtered on it and I use the magnifying
glass because we don't have a telescope
fire yeah that's good let's go down okay
so yeah you can see that it searches if
I need to use the mouse you see it on
the top there I'm like the magnified one
you see that it's search of if either
ESET or a vast its installed and one's
name is not found yeah I can't see it up
there yeah ok just make sure it just
like continues its execution sorry and
it loads all too suspiciously lll then
well the things which are more
suspicious for a visa I guess when it is
loaded the CNC server is already off
lines with wonder trips but well you get
the idea by simply creating those couple
of registry keys you can avoid really
nasty ransomware
let's try another one
I have another case here of a malware
called iron gate it was unveiled by fire
how do any fire I guys are proud today
know so it's also really really simple
it's the thing that you will do has like
a guy who don't know what you're doing
the first day when your boss and you're
right I'm malware that evades VMware
this in this case it was written in
Python I used the decompile for why
because it was compiled but you can see
the actual source with the comments
which is nuts
but you can see that the first function
is detect VMware and well what is this
detect VMware well why go to yeah well
it's the most like as I said you don't
want to be over complexing things when
you're right
and yeah it's awesome yeah gnostic great
you don't want to make things like over
complex when you're writing a malware
you want to evade vehicle machines they
just likely they have a commented test
here for the disguise ee port which is a
really good way to find a virtual
machine they combed it out for some
reason and why and they haven't have a
test year for the registry key of VMware
which is like the most obvious thing to
detect VMware by I have all the hashes
of those samples in the repository I see
that I don't have time to execute all of
them but you can see that it's just like
searches for the most obvious things
like VM Mouse or something
let's do a quick reverse snob shot I
will vaccinate the Machine and
afterwards we'll execute the same sample
and we'll take all me a minute
then you'll be able to see how you can
avoid infections live my demo because
it's a live demo and we're good to go
okay so first thing I will execute my
script over here it can get a flag if
you want you can create only the like
static art effect if you want you can
create only the dynamic artifacts I
create both of them in this demo you can
see that like 10 processes will be
created here in a second
yep it's all the same executable
duplicated over and over again and
renamed but it works so who cares and
let's execute it start frogman execute
the same sample and we'll be able to see
the difference it's not a magnifying
glass yeah you can see in down there the
red thing that's lucky being terminated
it alright terminated because we saw
those registry keys we'll see if now in
frogmen yeah so you can see that once
he's up there in the magnifying glass
once it found that Easter Keys was
created it's just like the next thing is
a thread exit it unloads a bunch of
stuff and process exit which is the win
for us because our theories say yeah
there are tons of more examples in my
repository and tons of more examples out
there and I assumed I don't have time
for questions right now
anything okay so anyway I'll be more
than glad to take questions afterwards
but if you have any questions right now
I preferred the even slide for it so
that's 9 yeah that's the second cat of
today and the last one questions
actually there is a good example of an
infection marker that is created between
malware but it's not the manual which
shares it it's the they use a framework
to obfuscate the code which uses an
infection marker so they all use the
same framework and by that they used a
same infection marker yeah yeah and
spora for example you have a really long
living family of ransomware which was
really effective and they all use the
same Unix because why not I'm lazy also
I understand them I wrote I did an
entire talk about copy pasting other
guys curves and writing malware from it
so I'm the same so thank you I'm
available for more questions afterwards
if you want to