yeah nice to be here my name is Karl or
Kelly and I'm going to talk a little bit
about a project me and my teammates from
our CTF team did over the summer
basically where we think we're a bit
with some Game Boy and Game Boy games
yeah short introduction about myself
said my name is Cole 28 years old I have
a master's in computer science from kth
in Stockholm and I work as the head of
security at the healthcare startup key
however that's not really relevant for
today's topic I also play a lot of CTF
competitions with our team hacking for
sodium and if you would like to get in
contact with me at some later time you
can reach me on one of these methods so
that's the first part of the mail
address at cedar to calm there's a
limitation in like resolution and screen
space here in this game where ROM so can
this please work
yes so as I said I'm in this CTF team
and since last year we are helping
organize seeing our own CTF competition
it's called the Midnight Sun CTF so the
idea is to do this every year and we
started with last year so we do an
online qualifier in the spring and then
an on-site finals at the kth University
here in Stockholm so we did it for the
first time last year and then again this
year and we're already planning for next
year and we have a student class for
student teams an open class for everyone
and I'm kind of like the responsible for
the technical aspects of the competition
and one of my design goals when doing
this was that when we have this on-site
finals we should utilize this fact that
we have
teams on site at the same place so I
want to have some challenge that uses
some kind of physical aspect so in this
year's finals we had a challenge that
was called the HFS calc which was
created by one of my teammates Bob and
it's a pony ball challenge and what does
that mean so a portable is a category a
standard category in CTF competitions
where you get some kind of program
you're supposed to find one or more bugs
in this program to corrupt the memory of
the program and thus gain control of the
execution flow and typically get
yourself a shell and the flag this is
typically done on like mainstream
architectures such as x86 or arm because
that's what people are familiar with and
that's what's easy to do but we did a
Game Boy game which was a pony ball so I
mean okay the game is maybe stretching
it a little bit it was a calculator app
on the Gameboy so we had flashed it on
actual Game Boy cartridges I actually
have with me today some game boys and
the cartridges so if you want to like
look at it and try it out you can come
see me either tonight or throughout the
rest of the conference I will be
carrying them around I guess we'll do be
some some kind of deposit system I guess
it looked like this so the setup was
that the teams were given a copy of the
Gameboy ROM that they could download to
do computers and they were also there
were also these game boys with the game
flash to them there was one difference
though that the the copy they got on
their computers just had a placeholder
flag so they could analyze the code look
at how it worked but even if they
managed to arm find the bug and create
an exploit for this they wouldn't get
the fact they would have to go to the
actual fish
Game Boy and by inputting their exploit
through the gamepad or they could
exploit this and leak out the flag so
for anyone who has been doing these
kinds of challenges in a more regular
setting this was kind quite a like
standard textbook challenge where you
had a buffer on the stack which
contained the results of the different
calculations unfortunately there was no
bounds checking on this buffer so you
could continue making calculations until
you would overflow this buffer and then
corrupt the return address of this
function which is like the standard way
of exact in one of the most basic ways
you can exploit a program I mean I won't
go into too much detail on that it's
like if you ever try out anything like
this not not on a gameboy but like on a
regular computer this would be like your
first like Pony Bowl 101 challenge and
then there was a bit a little bit of
protection to prevent some attacks but
the protections were pretty weak so you
could by analyzing the the code you
could overcome this protection and then
by playing the game in the correct way
you could eventually cause it to go into
a different function this is what would
happen if you didn't overcome the
protection so this is a little bit of a
spoof of what it would look like on a
regular system with the same protection
if you failed to overcome that
protection I don't think any other Game
Boy game has this kind of screen anyway
if you did it the right way you would
get the flag like this and with a little
image related to one of the sponsors of
the competition so uh we did that for
this finals that was in in June and we
started thinking about
[Music]
the Gameboy and what what can you do
with the Gameboy and how can we take
this further so first of all like what
is the Gameboy I mean okay it's it's a
it's a extremely popular gaming console
but from kind of like a computer science
or hacker perspective it has its own
basically custom chip which is like a
hybrid between the C ad and the Intel
8080 and it's a four megahertz processor
with a little bit of DRAM and then you
have these roms which are on cartridges
that you can insert and um they are the
the simplest ones are just 32 kilobytes
of memory but then there are more
advanced cartridges where you can swap
out the top 16 kilobytes of memory for
other sections of 16 kilobytes of memory
so this is called a bank a block of 16
kilobytes of memory and you can cycle
through these banks so some of the game
boy games even had as much as an 8
megabyte wrong a lot of content in the
game as an LCD display 160 by hundred
forty-four pixels which runs at 60fps
so quite impressive for like 89 I think
he was released and this is also why my
slides are a little bit pixelated
because they follow this these
restrictions
[Music]
okay great so we I mean I'm a big fan of
anger I've talked about it
previous times and we started thinking
about maybe we could build like
implement the gamer architecture for the
anger binary analysis framework and do
automated analysis of game boy games
that's a crazy idea that could work so
anger is uh it's a Python framework for
analyzing binaries it's mainly developed
by the security lab at UC Santa Barbara
but have a lot of other contributors it
supports a bunch of different
architectures unfortunately not the game
boy y know this we thought that this
would be an excellent exercise because
it is extendable you can build your own
you can implement your own architectures
and plugins and modules for this
framework and basically what you have to
do is you have to build a lifter that
takes the like machine code or whatever
you're analyzing and converts it into
vex which is the internal kind of
representation the intermediate language
I think really used by valgrind but also
been adapted by anger to use for their
binary analysis so you build this lifter
that converts your Gameboy code into
this vex
representation and that way you can
interface with the anger framework so we
started doing this encountered a few
challenges with this mainly three
challenges first of all we had this Bank
switching issue in most programs you
load the program into memory and each
piece of the program has a unique
address in this case that's not how it
works because since we can switch out
the bank's they will still have the same
address so the same address depending on
which bank is loaded can mean completely
different parts
the memory this was fairly easy to solve
though what we basically did was that we
kind of extended the architecture to
instead of used like 16-bit addresses we
created this fake register that kept
track of which Bank was loaded and then
we pretended that everything was like
24-bit addresses instead and did some
tweaking there and that was no problem
another issue is that in most systems if
you have a piece of memory and you write
to one address and then you read from
that address again you will get back
what you just wrote that's not how the
game way works because they have reused
all of these addresses for the ROM I
mean from the name it's like read-only
memory so that's where you have all the
code and data for the game so you will
read this but you will there's you can
you can't write to this memory because
it's read-only so what they've done is
that they have kind of like reused these
addresses so that if you write to one of
these addresses that is instead
interpreted as sending data to the
control registers within the Game Boy
cartridge for example for switching
these banks out or in the case of a game
like pokemon gold which has a real-time
clock in it you can communicate
communicate with the real-time clock by
writing to these addresses so here we
had to kind of implement like a hooking
mechanism so basically we're hooking
every write checking what address we're
trying to write to and if it's one of
these control registers we make some
adjustments to what the operation is
doing also no big prog mean it's a
completely solvable problem basically
then we realized our third challenge
which is that this is like in a method
system it has interrupts specifically
the game boy has five different
interrupts it has V
blank interrupts which is fired every
time one frame has finished rendering so
you have a small window of time within
which you can modify some parts related
to the graphics there's also the LCD
stat interrupts which gives can provide
some information about what's going on
with the rendering you can use this to
create like wave effects over the screen
and things like that this is a
general-purpose timer interrupt that you
can keep track of different timed events
there's a serial interrupt for if using
the game link cable I don't know if you
ever play it for example again if you're
playing Pokemon if you want to trade
with someone you connect the cable to
your gameboy into the other Gameboy and
you can communicate with each other so
that's the input related interrupt
related to that and then you have an
interrupt for just input so why is this
a problem because basically an interrupt
means that at pretty much any time we
can have code that starts running like
the other code then what we think is
gonna run will run instead and that
causes a lot of issues if you trying to
model and analyze this code so yeah as I
said we solved first challenge with in
creating this extra fake register and
using that for reading stuff the control
registers were handled by doing like a
global breakpoint checking what we're
we're trying to write and divert this
write somewhere else and prevent the
original right with the interrupts
however there is really no good solution
because there isn't really like a good
idea of how to model like multi-threaded
processes which is in in this context
which is basically what this is but we
are we can make it we can like minimize
the problem at least a little bit so for
example the serial stuff as long as
we're not looking at games which use the
game the game
in cable we can just disregard that for
some of the interrupts the V blank and
LCD stats interrupts our we can hope
that most game designers have only put
code there which relates to the
rendering of the game and not like the
actual game logic so if maybe we could
just disregard those and it will I mean
it would mess up the image if we tried
to render it but we're not so hopefully
it won't matter
and it won't when it comes to in input
interrupts it turns out that our most
games don't really use it they are
instead pulling the input state and
checking what the current input is so in
most cases we can also disregard the
input interrupt because it's it's
typically not used the general timer
thing will of course be completely
different depending on the game there
might be you know we might be able to do
some manual tweaks and you know patch it
and somehow but basically there we we
didn't have any any solution for this in
the general case so this works resulted
in some like we build some various tools
for parsing these things and still
working on this anger module there's
still the idea was to be able to kind of
release all of this today but we had
some last-minute discoveries and some
bugs and stuff and we didn't want to
just release the garbage so
unfortunately we had to postpone that a
little bit
one big resource that we used throughout
this thing was there's something called
the Gameboy pan docks which is some
people who have basically reversed
engineered like how the game works and
documented this very thoroughly it's a
very good resource if you want to
look into this game we're hacking a
little bit more so the whole idea we're
doing this thing was that we won't do to
kind of like do some like automated
analysis of of game boy games preferably
like at a scale and the idea was that
maybe we could find some some new bugs
in games that haven't been discovered
yet
and for the anger module the idea was to
be able to maybe not like analyze the
whole games but at least like sections
of games to build up like to find out
the relationships between different
parts of the code to simplify the
analysis we also looked a little bit
into like fussing of games by like
building our own emulator which is still
a little bit work-in-progress the
problem with the games is that like
typically the whole point of games is
that they're kind of like preventing you
from progressing and there are very many
different states and if you just like
open a game and press buttons randomly
you typically won't advance the state of
the game that much so you would have to
build something more clever here which
we haven't managed to however it is one
positive result throughout this whole
project we did find a way to basically
use an existing bug in a popular game in
a more powerful way that it has that has
been done than what has been done before
and again this is something that we were
hoping to be able to finish up before
today but yeah
the idea is that we think that we might
be able to get a new world record for a
popular Game Boy game using this bug so
we'll see if we manage manage that
so throughout the as a kind of like last
thing at the competition the original
idea was to have two gameboy games and I
mean we we chose to not release the
second one because we had enough
challenges and we thought that we would
release it for the secretary conference
instead so tomorrow or possibly Friday
we will release another Gameboy pony
ball challenge and which is in this
similar vein but this one would will be
an actual game it's a snake
game that you can exploit to find the
hidden flag inside the game so we will
release this both online so you can run
it an emulator but also I will have
physical cartridges of this game so you
can play it here throughout the
conference and we are thinking to have
some kind of competition and first want
to solve it some kind of price more
information will be on that so the final
little thing we did for this was that oh
so we have this challenge we have this
challenge with with the game that you
want to be able to exploit typically
when you are do building these exploits
on a regular computer you want to be
able to automate the process to keep any
manual work at a minimum and you
typically you're iterating you're trying
something and you realize there's a
mistake and you redo it and this
calculator challenge we did I mean that
one was extremely simple but it still
requires like up towards like a hundred
button presses to perform the exploits
which is a bit tedious especially if you
make a mistake so we thought that for
this a little bit more complicated one
we would create a way to automate this
so we added into the game that it would
react on the serial input from the game
link cable and you can treat that as
input as well
and then we took one of these gambling
cables which is very simple like a two
pin or three pin it's a clock and then
data in both directions basically just
cut it in half put some connectors two
at the end and connected it to an
Arduino and that way we could control
the game boy game from the computer by
just sending stuff up through the arena
and that way you could automate the
exploit for this Gameboy game from your
computer and like iterate on your
process so there was just a small extra
little fun thing we did and that's
basically what I have any questions
comments great then I would just like to
thank some my teammates who helped out
with this project and our helmet from
the anger team who has been helping up
with a little bit of anger internals and
also just a plug our monthly vulnerable
live show on YouTube which called Pony
Racing where each month four competitors
get the same pony ball challenge and
compete against each other trying to be
the first one to solve it while we
provide the commentary and analysis very
good learning and educational resource
so with that thank you very much
[Applause]