okay so today I'm gonna be talking about
razzle acceptation the the cool stuff
about the verbs of acceptation actually
that happened in the in the pass right
now and reinventing ideas sharing some
sort of the research that I was doing
and along with other cybersecurity guys
from Google research team and yeah
debugging the exploit kids they're
trying to inspect the develop delivery
methods for the these kind of exploit
kit so it has actually two part the one
part like it's technically the second
one is a scary and yeah we gonna see how
it goes so Who am I my name is Jimin
apoyo for Ingram Micro as a security
consultant I have a cool website called
buffer overflows that meant check it out
so web browser it's very interesting
it's a it's a sport for the security
researchers actually as well as the
cyber criminals why and and some stuff
that I will be talking about today that
is not developed by individuals
developed by highly skilled guys like
racial research institutions and stuff
for doing crime and why it's interesting
anyone is using browser oh yeah anyone
using the internet using browser so yeah
this talk is not about Dom tree
explanation these are story so
we're gonna jump over if we gonna
exploit the web browser how do we start
yeah we actually got a lot of
methodology stuff like this the first
one we are we can go ahead with Watson
Watson wasn't existed decade of like ago
so right now we have webassembly this is
what I assume is JavaScript school
browser range in old fashion and then
known and doing no and I'm referring to
some sort of any wiring simulation that
is yeah not no knee maybe in hips you
pray so the old fashion was starting by
Java droid boy this is the most popular
one we got yeah ah Java actually there's
Java drive-by and silent Java drive-by
which is what
really common in the browser acceptation
technique because it's across the
platform it works very simple it's easy
to develop that exploit it's easy to
debug the java code is open source
oracle guys after sun microsystems we
got why oracle so there was a lot of
stuff happening in that move especially
in the exploit development so yeah at
the atom flash supplier this is
Microsoft Silverlight the ActiveX for
the Internet Explorer exploit gates so
we got black hole we got angular neckla
magnitude the these kind of cool guys
they have a fancy logo they just put
their names if you really dig into the
exploit case and the crime history
you're going to find really as malleable
why says the king of exploit kit is a
black hole why because it's used really
cool delivery techniques if we say about
executing a malware you know like there
is hack form dotnet and the these spot
for dark web and the desirable prime you
pay ten bucks and you get a man were
actually encrypted full undetectable
bypassing the UAC use actual user access
control for Microsoft I think kcl are
ACL are these kind of stuff actually
when you when you have the binary or the
man where it's it's really not that
complicated to run on the system but the
idea is or the complexity is is to
deliver it throughout the browser and we
got a lot of delivery technique within
the browser like if we talk about the
past like the cross the platform one and
so on so when black hole is data
actually we got angular an angler it's
used very advanced
enumeration technique I'm not gonna like
analyze all of the stuff only like the
the stuff that is related to the topic
so it's used like Internet Explorer
Flash Player at a reader zero day
exploit packed
now the Kulemin or enumeration technique
that is used in angular because they are
when an angler is a start this is what
I'm reading in the news it was actually
targeting high in
visual profile and we got to stage of
enumeration the first stage is to
enumerate of course the user engine
diverge in the running operating system
and the use of kind of stuff and then if
it's like Internet Explorer 8 9 10 so it
goes ahead and yeah at 1 this CV which
is recently discovered basically it's
it's an exploit within the XML parser
within the internet support exploiting
it is very basic you just supply a file
that is exists on that system and when
this trying to parse the XML trying to
pass that XML element so it actually
gives it an error messages that's how
they they you know that that foil is
exist on the system or not so based on
the on the error messages but on the
other hand it gods improved like
development when when yeah are they
they used the rest protocol which is
there was actually supplying the the
localhost which point out into the road
directory in the Windows system talking
about Windows 86 so this will a brain
tout the the content or the files within
the directory so what do you get
actually you get these kind of stuff
dummy's hard to read but it was actually
used to enumerate if there is Kaspersky
installed image tool the the Microsoft
exploit multi Gatien to and these kind
of stuff because because they have no
control after running the exploit so
that's why they use the enumeration part
which is I think it's it's a bit
advanced so yeah they basically supply
some sort of vendors if these windows
are exist so they do a different type of
exploitation but this is what the the
cool enumeration technique and who I
they use this kind this kind of
technique I mean what is the purpose
it's very simple when we get an analyst
like someone supplied this into virus or
these kind of stuff so and then I was
get a nightmare and G try to figure out
what is the malware is and how things
work
and basically they supply they know some
file that is existing on the NSPCC and
then they try to make a play around use
after free if you talk about the web
browser you're gonna go ahead with use
after free heaps of prey and a lot of
stuff and myself I love pointing guys so
at pong Pony use after free it's always
been exist till now it says it's exist
so you're gonna find even in the future
ten years later if we stay alive so it's
it's just a yeah it's a it's really
popular the heaps of prying attacks and
this kind of user after free and simple
200 not gonna like dig into it we are
the the like if we say there is a
developer that made an application so
basically he allocates oh it's a
designer right so he used our pointer
called dangling pointer computer science
where we have dangling pointer white
pointer these points will envelope
memory address or object and when that
array of more is afraid so the attacker
goes and reuse that memory they call it
code reuse as well so we got a blog a
blog B block is a freed block B is
controlled by the attacker
they used the previous allocated block
and he try to execute you if you
research about you have UF attacks
you're gonna find like memory leaks this
kind of stuff what it is mainly yeah
used for code execution because nothing
to do with the with the memory address
this is a quick example points are
pointing to an Emma Lake freed reused
get the memory so four years of happy UF
in Firefox in C monkey and it was from
2007 till 2011 and if you really go
until now would say in some sort of UFX
application still exist if you go that
they use like they say disable
JavaScript if you really follow the
Twitter tweets of the guy they say yeah
okay don't use Firefox also so simple
terms how it works I'm gonna show you
the the the POC but in simple terms like
it's a we initializing a very fake V
table
and this vitae will point to a P P STR
which is in the Windows kernel P STR
means binary string it's a Deewar d
double ward to two whites so double is
four byte
each byte is 80 bit and 32 bit we got so
then the allocation for the hip start
and we're filling it with a new shell
code so it's have really vanilla if you
can read my screen you're gonna find
there is an object this is how it works
there is an object and this object we
call it using a foo after calling it we
creating some Unicode that's why we use
an escape over here and then a shell
code to pop-up calculator and then do
the the hips if I have the hip Supriya
walks basically just sort of string just
create swing variable in JavaScript if
you want to play with the hip or the
virtual memory and then you assign some
sort of junky value to that string and
then you add that swing to himself and
then you subtract that string so that's
how it works so we're creating one
thousand fake allocation and this is how
it work now the scary part snowman was
in operation I don't know if you heard
about it but it was targeting really
high individual profile yeah a targeting
United States military guys and guys in
French research institutions and except
right when Lee was walking for Windows
Internet Explorer 10 these yeah without
diving and do the politics but a really
cool technique about this exploit which
is yeah published by fire I it's the
delivery this is the cool technique so
basically a victim visit an HTML webpage
a server reply with an iframe the iframe
connect this to the server again and
then it is called an IMG dot HTML which
is on the other hand place an SWF file
that has an actions to correct this is
where the exploit is and that the the
SWF file actually go ahead and try to to
Fitch
although GPG and me
that image is not a placed on the file
system memory on the file system it's a
place in the memory as an array buffer
so it's like a every Asian technique and
then it's drop in DLL with at 64 and a
DLL read from that txt file and it's a
second stage or and then it's one the
the shell code which is connect back in
a reverse reverse connection so in in in
very simple way we got the URL loader
which makes an internal request this is
a snapshot that I took it and then we
got the array buffer initialized and
then the underscore URL which is yeah
which is make the which is holy the name
for the Jaypee file this is returned
into a loader and that loader returned
into the memory and it gets executed so
what's here it's a buffer array executed
within the memory cell nothing placed on
the file system Adobe Flash I'm not
gonna talk a lot about it so Renault
Java drive-by so yeah if you if you yeah
I mean Java drive-by exploit is very
popular so after you've I mean I I have
no other space over here just only for
one year the Renault is basically a Java
secret engine written in Java which
basically you can yeah implement
JavaScript calls and this kind of dumb
stuff and to the Java itself and then
you build a communication channel but it
has a it's had a bug in its design where
you can initialize a script engine and
you call the JavaScript engine and then
after that you bind it into the applet
at the top it's extending applet so you
want into an applet then you pass an
object and when this object is passed
you actually return an error an error an
error object so basically it's an eighth
of a roll class that native error class
uses to string method that two string
method is not controlled which is you
get like yeah there is no no context
association with the current thread
because in CLE it's it's a runnable
object so it runs it straight
and that's simply you just place the
initiative Metasploit you place the the
stuff that you want to be executed in
Java now I'm gonna go ahead with the no
one will do it I think what I don't have
is this edge so I just built an
application and assembly that's a fully
functional web application that I can
give instruction into the browser and
this code runs without a decoding or
star or something this girl runs in
native way native so if we gonna check
it out
sorry sorry and I was joking
no cheat so yeah basically it's an
assembly application we got yeah you
know some sort of binding section the
chicks in have have some sort of ticks
and then we we doing some assembly calls
to instruct the web browser in order to
put these and and yeah manage these
these stuff the listener for the HTTP
the protocol some some assembly
instruction manual wrote it in right now
we got them all out with it as in half
one inch warning
go ahead so yeah we got some sort of
functionality going on if you inspect
the source code there is no cheat there
is nothing like what the JavaScript it's
it's mainly based in assembly what on
the other hand now if I talk about I
want to fuss the browser for example
write a native assembly code this is
really a pain right so that's why we got
a fancy stuff called web assembly which
is basically it's not an assembly it
it's a it's basically has its own sticks
wall structure which is not not an
assembly but the difference between the
assembly the the web assembly actually
and the JavaScript because we already
have the JavaScript is the web assembly
is a compiler target okay so the web
assembly is a compiler target it's
faster than JavaScript
yeah it's one a code it's runs actually
close to native not native close to
native and then it's a QC c c c++ code
and what is bring to the table
speed portability flexibility this kind
of stuff yeah here you can see that the
JavaScript code new need to be passed
and then compile up to my then execute
only the way assam code need to be
decoded and compiled and if you follow
the rule the the current model zero day
right now I mean the the one that are
published you're gonna find that it's
written in the assembly modules and
there are some modules specifically in
the import and export so all the
browsers right now supported and the
cool part you can write a JavaScript by
calling assembly functions so this is
the difference between the normal
assembly that we know and the textual
format of the wasum
and how the winery format so the Watson
binary structure we got type import
function table memory the global
Explorer start element code and each one
of them is a separate topic but we we
got the custom section which is this is
where the phone already started with the
Watson parser a custom section means
that the section is not exist over here
and that that is passed the checks so
basically why some had a problem with
with with the verification of the order
of this section so and the C code and
see yeah this is place there is a
validate order and this is if the
previous section is a custom section
return true and it's passed so it was
actually a design error I'm gonna talk
about these just flocking web assembly
yeah if you build an application using
web assembly you can have two method for
the delivery one is downloading a file
the second one on the fly on the fly has
exploits also and this is why they only
flies is faster and also it's faster for
the stagers was some personal
exploitation we got some sort of
functions within the within the parser
itself and if you really read up the
code you're gonna end up with a lot of
heap stuff and and you have this is one
example of them we got a function called
get why some buffer from value and this
function actually takes today a dataview
wave buffer and it has a victor and then
this this is passed to another function
which means we will right now have a
buffer twice is copy it we got out of
read out of bounds read and now we we
get memory copy out of that this is how
the POS you look like i passing it out
of you loading it into web assembly
module after creating some fake loops
and we we get type confusion when
with with buffer overflow now I'm gonna
preform a live demo with life more about
using where I am in an exhibition this
exploit is made up by the workers why
the workers used over here it's because
these workers runs in sorry
yeah these workers run in their own
thread so basically we were defining
some constants the allocation for the
spray holders reclaiming getting and
finding the patterns and going out oh
very quick so yeah the reading addresses
the writing addresses the corruption
table reading objects cleaning up
getting the freed memory the shellcode
and yeah the how the RSC is walking
basically this is this boat that I want
to talk about we have awasum wasn't
converted into into Hicks and this
loaded into inside until ray and after
loading it we creating an animus and we
passing an animus definition for our
Assam aerial loading the code that we
define over here and a nun for table
Jake then we serve this as an export
export function which we it gonna run in
osm file right after that we do some
loop on the shell code we verify some
stuff the post meshes over here is not
an HTTP POST machine it's more about the
to work and self so we basically pass
the worker is the thread and we pass
process to that thread so it got one in
its own thread and initialization we
trigger the free into a five-block cards
we try to find the information in the
log it's it's it's like
yeah except Lloyd but let's see it in
action this exploit I hosted it on my
using Google for a chrome right now my
system is patch everything is who I
hosted it on my website I hope you talk
again a brute force for the making some
attempt for the allocation on the buffer
gonna take some time for brute forcing
its brute forcing and we got the end
catism West is really dangerous moving
on we got the lava story between a CA
SMGs and just-in-time compiler and
basically it's the same idea for the
heap spray of the flash player the guy
who came with this kind of exploitation
action is really cool because it doesn't
use any code reuse so there's basically
no no brute force nothing is going on so
yeah just to see it in action very quick
a piece of junk
virtual allocation read/write/execute
three bytes Taser and the virtual memory
right after that we got an MSF venom
encoded to SMGs payload we are getting
some yeah the the fake objects moving
about the blocks creating this
allocation getting the addresses
triggering the worker same technique
using the back end it's right and then
passing the the process getting the
offset looping over the blocks
triggering it by creating fake SVG doing
some sort of animation in order to
allocate some sort of memory stuff now
trying to I hope it works
okay and we got the CMD and instead of
the calculator
moving on yeah it's the same one that I
see here right so yeah the the
techniques for delivering the web
browser exploit it's basically when I
actually was entering into this everyone
telling me don't click a link don't
click a link so I was really afraid but
right now it's a I think it's it true we
got a lot of social engineering
techniques that has been it's been
delivered one cool things about them is
you enumerate the system and before any
managing the system actually what they
do they create a pixel one pixel em is
right so they host this image on any
kind of server and when you go to your
gmail account in order to insert an
image from a URL what what you give on
the server side you retain a base64 jiff
so if the Googlebot is requesting that
that image that how how you insert an
image into your Gmail browser it gonna
go fetch that and on the other hand when
a request happens on the server side you
grab that quiz so who requested that
image so you get the request data out
looks sometimes it blocks the the image
loading image from external size but to
be honest when you load an image from
external side it's really a problem it's
not only about enumerate in the system
now if you and my research and you can't
find this information documented these
guys load an iframe by default so they
don't block it what means is that you
send an email to the victim right and
then you inject an iframe to your
payload and when this get executed it
gonna be executed within the email and
what the email use just Google what
engine each email one of them is using
so I think this is the next generation
for the exploit kit the hidden part my
research
no one is mentioning this is the black
hole for web browser predation no one is
writing about it mainly the Dom tree
explanation like XSS these stuff
aisel type of acceleration but on the
other hand you can set an item get an
item remove item clear this what what
this happens in the browser local store
in 2018 I did the research that is I was
able to create an exploit that plays a
swing shellcode and to the browser
browser storage but the only missing
part that I had how I can trigger that
payload without going to execute
something else the problem that I had
actually what I did I created an exploit
GS which is yeah duh yeah it's very
basic it's a store some some sort of
shell code that is yeah it get it from a
target or THC which is like a calculator
and then it's it an item within that the
local storage and then we get that item
but how the problem is on the browser we
got a lot of limitations actually this
is beyond like buffer overflow attacks
is how I can let the browser's read that
shellcode and getting it executed I
can't make the browser read there but
how I can get it executed so I created
an extractor and we're gonna run that
extractor and gonna go grab the this
string within the browser and get it
executed so this is was the only missing
part but it's still ongoing research
whatever similarly is still ongoing
you're gonna find a lot of bug if you do
static analysis this is only the the
thing that I can show to you in 30
minutes ah the conclusion browser or
exploitation basically is a science in
its own so it's it it's a it's the most
complex topic is in a Brian binary
exploitation but the resources are
really found handy whenever we had to
enter this this is base is the exploit
DVD POC the Google research team the
binary acceptation debugging for
: if you don't always see II it's really
cool
these are the credits for the guys the
references and me and Pony if you've got
a questions so that's pretty much it
Thank You Jimmy awesome yeah I'm sure
people have questions for you
in the break we're gonna have a quick
break but yeah yeah Jeff a website that
you can point people to for examples in
your blog whatever yeah these materials
will be published so you're gonna find
it on sexy and and on buffer overflows
dotnet where I post stuff about research
scientific research here recently was
doing research in the compiler design
programming language design how we can
find explanation there so you can find a
lot of cool stuff over that cool so
thanks again Jamil