so the way the cookie crumbles I didn't
prepare really a lightning talk I never
do
I prepared a challenge the center
challenge if you haven't solved it
please do there are some nice prices
still there fetch but yeah of course I
work at center and that's why I prefer
the challenge instead of doing lightning
talks I'm gonna try to do this anyway so
first of all unfortunately I'm gonna
have to explain a really stupid old bug
that is what an almost 20 years old it's
called CSRF and it's really boring so
let's say that we have a authenticated
system of some sort and you log into it
with your username and doesn't really
matter okay so now I'm authentic ated
there is a button there I should
probably not push it but let's try oh
snap so that was bad for me I should not
have done that so let's just forget it
ever ever happened and hope that yes
okay so that didn't happen let's log in
again so I don't want to push that
button obviously now to explain the
concept of a you CSRF vulnerability I
load a say another page in the same
browser let's say I visit this page okay
so as some sort of mail system I got a
web page here of some sort and as you
can see there is a image down there so
let's go back to see what the status of
the reactor is let's update that oh snap
so somehow that button got pushed that
way and for all of you who've been doing
any kind of web security you realize
that this image actually points to the
URL that caused the reactor meltdown
it's just a simple stupid request that
is sent from my browser but even though
it's sent from this site this site
causing my browser to send the request
but still it's yet it gets authenticated
and that's why this still works so this
has been like an issue for the past well
18 years at least
so they figured out a way of solving
this
it's called same side cookies and I'm
sorry so instead of using that crap the
old login I have an improved login that
will give me a better kind of cookie
which is basically just if you used
normal set-cookie header you add to it
the attribute same side which means that
the cookie will only get sent
if the request originates from the same
site that you want to send the cookie
from that means that it will still work
if I if I push the button on the site it
will still work but if I load if I
reload this then the request my browser
sends because of this page will not
cause the other page to to do what it
just did so let's try and update that
sure okay so same site cookie appears to
work it provides it's solving this
problem which is great of course if I
would be stupid enough I get new mail
and in this mail there is a link so
there are some limitations the same side
cookies of course because you might want
to be able to click link and end up
authenticated in another system so in
this situation I have link and if I
click that link
well again I end up in this bad
situation where it basically meant that
I clicked the button that I didn't want
to click okay so that is bad now there
is there are several different ways of
solving this one of the ways of solving
it would be to force the request to
check the request and ensure that it's
not a guest or head request that's
actually a post request but let's
experiment again because you could do
you could set even stricter saying site
attributes so now here's another
improved version and now I'm using again
the same site attributes
but now this time I'm using the strict
value instead of the lakhs value that I
did in the previous round let's try and
load that mail again okay so if I click
this then I end up at a page where I'm
not authenticated so even though I
clicked the link now this thing's that
strict attribute means that it's still
not sending the cookie so when end up
unauthenticated is this page which is
good because that means that I'm
actually protected from this type of
attack even though I'm not even checking
the method of the request and so it
seems this problem is solved if you just
add the same site strict attribute to
your cookies of course it means that
people won't be able to land on a logged
in on your application from clicking
other applications but there is of
course an issue and now here's the
running point because this is really
experimental so I don't know if this is
great because it's browsers or caching
stuff so I'm just gonna well let's see
let's do this again I am opening this
I'm logging in with the same site strict
attribute so now I have this really
solid strict cookie I should be
protected from pretty much everything
let's try and load a third mail okay I'm
just gonna take a little short break
let's go and reload this page again Oh
No
so apparently that didn't work why is
that how could this possibly have
happened well it's as easy as checking
the source code for the web page and
what it says is oh it's a pre-render
link and it specifically says in the
specification do not send same site
cookies on pre-render linked and yet
chrome does exactly this and I sort of
expected them to fix this because I
prepared this talk for the spring pub
and I also posted it to a bunch of
people saying hey you guys are bug
bounty hunters you just submit this to
Google and probably earn some money
because I'm not gonna do that because I
believe in pen testing not bug dantas oh
sorry no I believe bug Mantis of course
and no plans of thing where it anyways
so this still works if there are new
added bug bounty hunters that want to
cash in on this feel free to do so but
be aware if you use same site cookies to
protect your site against cross-site
request forgery then please check the
request methods because this is not
water salt water tight yet it might be
some point in the future but this still
works I probably will work for at least
have you in boar days I guess for
someone submits it and that's it bill
ahead of time
[Applause]
you