thank you thank you very much pleased to
meet you all it's my first time in
Sweden and it's the first time in the
hacking conference where I key as a
sponsor so that's you know Swedish
things
so today I'm going to talk about AWS
Amazon Web cloud services and how we're
going to attack and what kind of attack
vectors in both the exploitation and the
post exploitation process then I'm going
to show some demos hopefully they work
so that's me that's how I look like in
my traditional dress
it's called Fatah it's really nice and
stylish some racist people call it a
table cover idiots right so I've done
some talks and trainings all wrong with
the world in Europe in Asia in the
Middle East of course my focus currently
is on API is security and the cloud
basically the reason I chose this
profession is working on cloud security
allows me as individual in Kuwait to
actually reach out to the entire world
instead of being constrained to the
local regular enterprise environment in
Kuwait and Kuwait is really small so why
should I
constrain myself and that small
geographic area when there are seven
billion people in the world who need you
know to be secured so that's why I chose
cloud security as as my current
profession of course so that's my
personal reason for it
that's my github and my Twitter if
you're interested so where is kuwait
kuwait is of course in the Middle East
can anybody find Kuwait yep the small
one that's quite and you can't you see
that it's in red can anyone guess why
that's why Kuwait correctly holds the
official highest record for temperature
52 is actually in the shade yeah and out
in the Sun it once reached you know
arguably around 67 degrees so that's why
you know
I came to Sweden to just you know have a
change of the temperature currently in
Kuwait and some temperate starts to cool
down so now it's about 46,000 degrees in
American that's three barbecues or I
think 125 height right so yeah it's
really hot in kuwait kuwait is also
known other than hate code is known for
the kuwait hours which was actually
designed by a swedish architect so thank
you very much coat is also known for its
really good food and if you look at me
you can tell right so if you visit
kuwait don't do it in the summer that's
number one
visit the kuwait towers and by the way
the pointy end is actually very sharp
don't ask how I know
and do you know take her time to
actually seed taste all the food in
Kuwait when people talk come to quit
from the neighboring countries they
actually go on a diet before they come
to Kuwait so yeah before I start my talk
I would like to actually start with the
references because I stood on the
shoulders of giants those are the main
references I used for my talk I don't
like to mention John Francis in the end
when I am when I am rushing for a time
so I actually start we would like to
start with the with the references these
are two really good books that you might
want to take a picture if you are
interested in cloud security secur
DevOps and the whole and that whole
profession so why would I attack edible
yes because Eddie Willis is the king of
the cloud currently it has the lion's
share of public cloud services they are
well documented and widespread when I
say well-documented I mean that it's all
written but they changed the
documentation so much you actually need
to have someone who only specializes in
all the FBI documentation changes and
there are people who actually do that
because there are lots of services in
Amazon inedibly as you have the basic
service from s3 the file Cloud Storage
all the way to ground satellite stations
so Amazon edulis provides really big
let's say assortment of services so
that's for example that I am talking
about a table as a ground station I
who uses that so while security inside
mes itself is actually excellent market
awareness of security in other words the
customers and how they can use Eddyville
executes securely is actually lacking so
let's talk about how a blast changes the
security let's say model for you in a
better way many attacks don't work
inside the cloud for example you don't
have to care about armed spoofing inside
Amazon you don't have to care about
destruction of your old hard disks for
example the data center security now we
don't have to care about that anymore
worse is that your model some let's say
parts of your traditional model don't
work as well so for example IP
reputation is less effective because
attackers can just attack you from
inside Amazon so the same applies to
country blocks because Amazon has lots
of regions over the world so a country
block is actually less effective so we
need to actually upgrade your security
model the scripting mode of Amazon is
called a shared responsibility model
which which means that the
responsibility is split between you and
Amazon some things you care you have to
handle and this will not help you on
that and some things Amazon will carry
on for you so for example Amazon takes
care of the hardware the storage
electricity physical security and all of
that and you have to care for your own
applications your own servers there are
some managed services inside Amazon like
s3 and RDS Amazon will handle that for
you the backups for example you take
care of your customer data you take care
of your credentials and all of that so
if I want to attack a customer inside
Amazon now note that I'm not talking
about attacking Amazon device itself
attacking customers inside the Amazon
Cloud so if I want to attack these are
the most popular attack services in
Amazon s3 the distributed file storage
inside Amazon ec2 which are the virtual
cloud servers inside Amazon RDS the
managed database
Amazon manages the DB for you including
all the updates and backups so you only
connect to the database and you know
send your data and lambda which is the
offering of Amazon for their function as
a service a feature which means that you
only apply upload your code your
function and Amazon runs then
varmints to execute that function for
you so we don't have to care about
updating the OS for example now attacks
against these let's say services usually
are being done for data theft mining
cryptocurrencies on your expense so
someone could for example attack your
Amazon account and then they take your
keys and then they run cryptocurrency
miners and you're going to pay for all
that processing and they've gained the
mining operation on your on your build
and of course on somewhere but that can
be made less effective because Amazon
allows easy back and restores at the
cloud now let's talk more about ec2 a
Seto is Amazon's fancy name for virtual
VBS servers so basically you run you
choose your size for your own VBS you
can choose the the type is it Windows or
Linux and then you can just log into it
using SSH and then you can just manage
it just like any other VBS of course you
have no say in which Hardware runs on
your ec2 and you don't have an info
about the neighbors inside Amazon that
are running next to you on the actual
hardware host you're responsible for the
LS and the updates and the hot security
inside so in this in this image do you
see the mouse cursor yeah so that's your
your instance it's inside Amazon and you
connect to it through the internet using
your SSH key and then you manage this
server just like any other server that
you that you have so in reality it's let
it's nothing special you can just attack
it the usual you attack any other server
and exploit against any running service
web applications for example OS command
injection local file includes and of
most importance for us is SS RF server
side request forgery SSR f is a
variability in which you ask the trusted
server to access internal services on
your behalf so you for example you'll
ask the server connect to this private
IP for me and then the server will
connect and then give you back the
result so the reason SSR F is a special
in the cloud is because Amazon and also
Google and I think even as you're they
have this special feature called instan
metadata and internal metadata service
that runs inside every virtual server in
the cloud this metadata URL is usually
this IP and you can call this is only
internal to the instance itself so only
the instance from inside its own OS can
call this URL and of course if you call
this URL using an SSRI vulnerability
where you're outside and you ask this
vulnerable instance to talk to this URL
and then give you the result you reading
it from inside the instance this
internal metadata service can expose
interesting stuff like credentials other
interesting details about the metadata
the server itself which you don't see
next also if you want to attack ec2
instances you can attack what they call
the user data startup script when you
create a virtual server in Amazon you
can specify script that runs every time
the server the server boots up for
example it could be a configuration for
a updating for example your source code
from your github repository updating
packages so usually it contains some
sense to date like passwords Amazon also
if you see if you see this image you can
attach to the server and EBS which is
elastic block storage what it means is
that it's just like a regular small
flash memory virtual disk that you can
attach to the cloud if you can they
attach that and then access it you can
find interesting data for example if you
are running active directory inside
Amazon Cloud you can maybe copy this
NTDs file which contains all the hashes
so these are the main types of attacks
that are special to a DB les instances
now as a seraph usually you know the old
web operable days it actually lived in
the dog house nobody care about cared
about xsrf it was always low priority
who wont fix or even totally ignored so
people are always cared about RCE
SQL injection cross-site scripting
nobody cared much about xsrf because
they thought it was you know it didn't
have that powerful
demo ability where you can easily
demonstrate how dangerous it can be now
amazon came and saved s SRF
and the world of cloud became king in
the cloud as a survivor abilities can
result in full infrastructure takeover
so we're not talking about takeover or
the server or the database itself we're
talking about full takeover of the
entire edible s account of that customer
for example as we said we can use SS ref
to contact the local metadata service
running inside this idealized instance
for example you can ask for the security
credentials that are running with the
server so for example I did this from
inside one of my instances I called the
internal method metadata service ask it
for the credentials of the current
server and then it gave me an access key
and the secret which are the username
and password for the Amazon API using
this I can just plug it inside Amazon's
API and there can make requests that
will allow me to get what access to
whatever resource this instance has I'm
going to show a demo for that very soon
so I'm going to show a project made by
Rhino security lab it's called cloud
goat project it's an intentionally
vulnerable application now they have
virgin to bomb dunk to display version
one we're going to use SS RF to actually
try to get more interesting stuff from
inside the metadata so I'm going to show
it actually in a demo now so that's the
beige if you see the design is really
nice it's actually responsive you don't
say it come on
Yanis could you would you mind kindly
help with this do you see the slides now
no nothing shows so I'm gonna plug this
one out and blog it's back again see if
it works okay now let's see if this okay
so as I said it looks nice and the
design is responsive so now this is a
simple URL fetch your application don't
laugh that's my design skills so what
did this application does is that I give
it a password that
give Terrell it will go and fetch that
URL for me okay
some go to what is the password for this
one that's the password don't want you
getting my keys right so I'm going to
for example connect to google.com now it
will call Google comm not from my own IP
but from inside Amazon so as far as
Google is concerned it's being contacted
from inside Amazon so that's really nice
so far it's really basic people use SSL
vulnerabilities for things like
accessing internal IBS and all of that
so as we're gonna see it fetches a route
for you when I did the this screenshot
it was actually falafel day so the
Google dork
you know showed of these this falafel
sandwich so that was nice yeah now I'm
hungry
good thing and one she's coming next
right so basically we now know
understand what's a chef does can we try
protocols that are not HTTP protocols so
instead of calling pages maybe I can
call an FTP protocol maybe I can call
other services running other protocols
instead of HTTP so we can try the file
protocol let's see let's see the demo
okay you can't see the demo again I
don't know what this why this happens
okay so let's go back again let's strike
the which file do you want of course
everyone's favorite right so now we can
call the file protocol so it's not just
HTTP protocols you can call basically
whatever depending of course on the
library being used in the backend so
that's nice now we have access to much
more than just HTTP you can read the
local configuration file you can read
source code you can read all of that
so what else we can do
back again sorry why don't you try
something else why don't you try the
brach file system anybody knows what the
proc fast
I don't see many hands being up okay
good
so the Brockville system is a special
file system virtual fast inside linux
which allows you to have access to
certain properties of each process and
certain properties of the current
process and it is attached like a
regular file inside inside Linux so I
can access it using /proc and then the
process ID for example five or ten and
then some are phone inside it so some
interesting info inside the broad file
system for each process could be the
starting command line options
environmental variables memory mappings
arm cache table mounted devices and even
the accessible itself so if you have for
example an application that's actually a
Python script you can use the proc file
system to read its own source code for
example so let's see an example here
I could call /proc and that's life self
which means that current process so I
don't even have to guess my brother's ID
so I can just use /proc slash self and
then I can use command line to see the
command line that was starting this
current process this is interesting
because people could start processes
like this right application and then
using the flags for this name and
password so this would for example show
up for me using slash bot can also use
/proc default the virtual brach file
system to read the ARP cache table
inside the server so this is interesting
because now I can see other IP addresses
and other MAC addresses inside the
current network I can see what kind of
devices they run I can see more targets
for further exploitation and the local
network so this is actually a sample
that I ran on my instance so it's really
a nice to have these if you think about
a seraph in ways beyond just HTTP
protocol you can see really interesting
stuff and of course we can just call the
Eddyville as metadata service like this
actual it's a URL returns for you
directories so I'm going to show right
now
so I'm going to say so I need to copy
that again okay so now let's see the
metadata service actually be to think I
already have it here so I'm going to
show how it starts then step by step
we're going to redouble the metadata
service soap retrieve the contents these
are the metadata service directories
with a bit of trial and error and
reading documentation you can see which
methods are actually interesting for you
copy the password again okay so now
metadata let's go back in there and then
say make a data survive password again
okay mate data time I did yeah Wow and
now I didn't put the password okay okay
so now we have it lots of interesting
stuff now Amazon's identity and
management services called I am so
that's we're going to check next of
course I'm cheating because I know
beforehand but eventually you want to
try and see everything inside here
because these are some really
interesting use information then I am
now the password again does it getting
really annoying right at least it works
by the way if you want to hire me from
my web design services I don't recommend
that so security credentials now we are
getting more interesting stuff
credentials copy the password again okay
so now ec2 as we read that the role name
that the role I gave to this server to
run so obviously it can for example
access as three buckets using read-only
privileges only so now I could use this
and then also layer the password again
and it would show for me the credentials
actually the access key and the secret
access key so I can take these and then
just plug them inside my own inside the
Amazon AWS ABI and then you'll have
access to this role whatever permissions
that role has you will have also so we
can call any ABI that you want so let's
go again back to the slide we've seen
how we can call the metadata service
release them both as we said the
credentials so what can I do with this
if you want to know how dangerous this
can be you can just ask the Capital One
Bank which I think a few months ago they
were compromised using what is thought
to be an SSR vulnerability inside an
instance running a wife and that's
really ironic so what the attacker did
it was a she by the way she actually
used this SSR variability and then she
got the Amazon access keys from inside
the instance metadata service and then
used that she blogged it in the Amazon
API and then used that to call and read
the s3 buckets of Capital One Bank
including I think millions of date
customer data and all of that so this
results in a really big let's say breach
for for a seraph so if you want to try
something like this of course if you're
authorized you can use this tool that I
made you know how the need is the mother
of invention so I was doing consultation
of my clients in the cloud and then I
realized there are some steps that I
needed to totem 8 and I needed to make
easier so I made this tool what it does
is it's a post exploitation attack so it
assumes that you already have gotten
your keys for example through the
Assessor availability and then you can
just use this tool to launch some
attacks against the analyst environment
for example you can dump the credentials
saved inside this Amazon account Amazon
provides for your credential store like
a vault
it's called EDS secrets manager and an
evil s-parameter store
scientists you can for example add your
encryption keys database password and
all of that and of course there's an API
for it so you can just query it and then
have access to be secret themselves if
you have permission if your key has
permission for that you can remotely
control ec2 instances the way the only
way to control an ec2 instance is to use
the SSH key that was set up in the
initialization process of this server if
you don't have this as a set key then
you can't log into that ec2 server there
is a way of course from inside amazon's
ABI
it's called system manager that can
allow you to have root or administrator
access shell on that server without
having access to this such key so I made
the toolbar to actually utilize that now
bark means like link in Arabic by the
way so you can see from the logo you can
get Metasploit reverse shell on the ec2
instance coming from inside Amazon so
the connection the connection is going
to be from inside Amazon from inside
Amazon services so it's going to be
really more difficult for traditional
defense mechanisms to actually detect
that and of course dump ec2 instance
metadata do some attacks against lambda
functions we want to see when I created
bark I actually wanted to try out the
idealized API features so I made a
training mode inside so if you want to
use it you don't have to actually mess
up and running production value can just
use the training mode which will create
for you some services temporary roles
and servers and then you can attack them
and once you're done with the training
mode you can just it will clean them
after itself and it will actually try to
utilize all the three features from
inside Amazon so it will try to use the
size of ec2 instances that is actually
inside the free tier of Amazon so we
want to get billed for it this is an
example of how you can that's right how
the training mode works it asks you do
you want to create a Linux or Windows
instance what kind of payloads do you
want to do to utilize for example
Metasploit and then you can have here
your own listening server that listens
to the mid spot reverse shell so that's
we are using DMS whatever shown here and
then you hope you have to get a virtual
coming back to you so we don't see that
in a demo very soon now and I hope it
all works I'm not gonna do the same
dance here okay so also it can dump
credentials inside a SS it can give you
more information about your attack
service or how many servers how many
functions are there how many security
groups and now I'm going to show a demo
next of Paul of course for this tool is
to create more lambda function attacks
make it modular add some persistence in
backdooring
features cell now I'm going to do the
demo and I hope everything works fine so
okay ask you logo you know hackers love
that so I'm gonna you don't say anything
you know just tell me beforehand guys
okay so I can so I don't get embarrassed
like this all the time now it shows up
right and as I told you ascii logo you
won't see it again okay nice thank you
very much i love this crowd so where was
i am going to copy my credentials so i'm
going to say set profile give it the
credentials it will ask for passwords
and to not show them because it's a demo
mode so and now it will ask what is your
preferred region I'll use the default
one because it has the largest set of
supported avi features help let's see
what we can do let's try the training
mode hell the game start okay so it will
help create the temporary environment
for you to say do you want to create a
Linux or Windows environment let's say
Linux it will now choose a certain type
of Amazon image for the server now it
will to take few minutes to create it
hopefully much sooner so we have to wait
for it meanwhile
have a server that's waiting for the
connection so hopefully it will work now
if you noticed if you want to use this
feature inside mark you need to have
this permission inside this inside your
Amazon API role so Amazon ec2 role for
our system which allows the SSM servers
the system and your servers to run
commands inside your ec2 servers so
that's the main role that you actually
need for this feature to work inside so
okay now we have created it the instance
is created what kind of attack do we
want let's see Metasploit what Ivy do
you want to use I'm going to choose this
Ivy now don't - okay so what port that
support it will say what kind of shell
do you want now it will sell it will
give you the command that you should you
can just copy best inside your listening
server just to make it easier to prepare
the listening environment so now it will
launch the listener for us then it will
try to create a payload it expects that
Callie a that Metz what is installed on
your own system so this is a Kali Linux
server so it has the ability to do that
because that's what is already installed
now it's sending my temperature by thumb
based payload that's the command it's
sending to the instance now we will see
if we got okay so now we have got a
session see that now I get to do the
same dance write sessions I and then one
and now I have the sessions info so now
this is the Amazon server connect me
back to me if I get for example a shell
now I have a shell inside inside Amazon
so inside the Amazon ec2 server even
though I don't have access to the SSH
key so that's one way you can do both
exploitation attacks inside the server
once you're done the training mode will
understand that you have returned and
now it will say okay now I'm terminating
the instance cleaning up deleting the
role and everything and then after that
it will say that to tell you that you
are now done and that's it is finished
so let's wait for the training mode to
to to be complete
now okay so now it now it is done with a
training mode everything is a cleaned up
I don't hear any clapping so that's
really yeah thank you very much so if I
want to use this tool in production I
can just use the attack service function
this one will go through your entire
Amazon in all of the regions available
and try to find any server that's
running inside this region because
Amazon uses lots of regions in the
United States in Europe and Asia and
South America for example now recently
in the Middle East as well in Bahrain so
it will go through all the regions try
to find all the servers and the lambda
functions running inside the region try
to give you all your options for any
activity and it was the exportation
attack that you want so for example here
we can see we have some lambda functions
it also displays the environmental
variables for them because they could
contain passwords and secrets API keys
for example so let's go up-up that's an
instance that was stopped we have lambda
functions you can see their
environmental variables for example
Twitter API keys so the environmental
variables for lambda functions could
contain some sensitive information let's
go back up again these are our instances
for example their public IP so it gives
you let's say a whole view of your own
environment let's see some ec2 attacks
we can list all the images that we have
now let's run some attacks you can chose
choose against all instances or just one
so I'm going to say just one and then
I'm going to have to paste or just use
stamp completion for my instance so now
it will say what do you want to do
download the metadata for me for example
this one is really simple it will go and
send this Python command which will
actually display all of your the
metadata service from inside this ec2
instance you can also do a reverse shell
so now we can see we also again have the
access to the access key and the secret
axis
okay and then you can use this one
inside work for example for more attacks
so that's basically basically it now we
can go back to the slides okay next for
me I'm going to attack to describe the
lambda function in AC to serve as your
responsible for running the server and
nobody likes that because we don't like
to update OS we don't like to update the
environment don't like to update all the
windows updates if you're running
Windows servers so Amazon allows you to
just put your code your code files
Python Java for example and then Amazon
will create the environment that runs
for you they call serverless of course
there's this really small server that
lives for less than a second to execute
your function then go back again so no
server operations needed for server
lists the variables against several
functions are the regular application
rambled is like OS and RCE there's a
special type of ability that effects
several functions we call it server less
event injection attacks the way Cerberus
functions work is that they don't accept
input from users directly they accept
input coming from events which are
events triggered from inside Amazon
itself so I'm going to show an example
of what an event could be for example
suppose I have a Severus function that
does virus scanning so I listen on an s3
bucket and if anyone uploads any file I
will try to scan this file for viruses
on malware okay so the way this service
would be written is that it would listen
for an event from s3 bucket and anytime
someone uploads a file on the bucket
Amazon itself will trigger the event for
my lambda function telling my Lander
function and a file was uploaded in s3
so who's actually invoking my service
function it's Amazon itself using the
event so this is not the regular model
in regular applications where I know for
sure the flow of functions and how each
function calls the other that's why can
these gaps and the assumption of how the
functions could be called we can have
these type of attacks inside lambda
functions inside lambda functions
because you don't have a server that you
anymore some attacks some regular
attacks don't work as well so for
example if you upload a file we have a
file upload variability it would not
work inside lambda why because the file
system inside lambda is mounted as
read-only except for temp and because
the instance itself is short-lived it is
started by Amazon for a few milliseconds
to return the code and then it will be
destroyed so whatever file you uploaded
will be gone in a few milliseconds the
same applies to any reversal that you
have it's not going to be persistent
there is no metadata service inside
lambda and fortunately for attackers of
course no local files are usually
sensitive inside lambda so how can i
attack lambda functions I can try to
dump the environmental variables inside
lambda to access to gain access keys so
lambdas access key and secrets are
stored inside its own environmental
variable instead of the metadata
metadata service like in ec2 instances I
can use lambda to actually for example
backdoor it I can download the source
code study it see if it and think let's
say sensitive inside and then I can even
upload my own source code to the lambda
function I can just backdoor it add
whatever line that for example sends the
credentials to my server and then I can
upload that and backdoor the function so
these are the sorts of events that could
come to lambda functions a VI gateway
calls a three files database events for
example that's remember the example I
told about the lambda function for virus
scanning suppose that it does this it
calls our system in Python and then it
takes the bucket that it received and
then it
for example copies it to another facet
or another bucket for the virus scanning
so of course what we have here is a
regular OS command injection attack so
I'm going to show a demo now it's called
a wasp dam variable serverless
application
it's a project contributor to a wasp by
company called party girl apps I'm going
to show because I already installed it
basically it's a it's a webshop
for games you can just buy any game that
you want and if you buy the game
go to the process of buying it I'm not
going to show that you're going to
receive a message from the application
itself telling you that we have
processed your order and then we can
just delete download your receipt from
here okay
of course this I made this a long time
ago so the link has expired
I can do it again but I think we're
running out of time however let's check
what kind of link that we have here it's
a a bucket inside Amazon that uploads my
receipt to a certain directory so what
it does is that this application takes
my order and then creates a receipt on a
bucket and then allows me to do to
upload my receipt so what if I try to of
course this is a process if you want to
test yourself I'm going to upload the
slides you can just try it yourself like
this so if I access this file directly
it's actually downloadable and now I can
audit the parameters of that as three
buckets this one for example allows
anyone to upload allows any a develops
account to upload so for example I can
just copy this command I'm going to
create a file empty file okay
so echo okay now let's see if we are
connected to my ideal s account okay so
now I'm just going to copy this command
what it does is that it will upload this
file to this bucket now it says it
applauded the file so I'm going to
access this file
what was the file name so now I can
access the file it is public because I
was able to this the the first available
T in this application is that it it has
an s3 bucket that allows anyone to
upload to it so now we know that this if
you check the source code of this
application you'll see that one of the
functions actually handles uploads from
inside s3 so if you check the code here
that says bucket do you see the mouse
cursor you don't see the mouse cursor
okay so let's do it the old way okay
like this now you can see the cursor
right okay so it listens for events from
Nestor e bucket and then it to try to
take the the file name itself the key
which is called where the key inside s3
means the file name it will do some
operations on it it expects the file to
have an underscore and it expects the
file to end in dot Rho extension so then
it will take this file or the final name
event will do echo date and then it will
echo for me the actual file name so what
it says that it will send out to the
output of the system that this file name
was downloaded and that time of course
if you check this this is a regular
command injection attack but the file
name is being taken from inside s3 so
someone could say you know what it's
okay it's an event coming from sign
inside Amazon so what could go wrong
right the thing is s3 can accept any
type of name so any type of file name
even if it contains commands inside the
family material it will be acceptable of
course I will try an attack now I set up
the my listening environment using an
egg rock what I'm going to do is that
I'm going to run this command so what
this command does is that I'm going to
upload the empty file to my bucket and
then I'm going to inside the file name
I'm going to give it a command curl to
post the result of the whole my command
to which address to my listening address
I sat in a garage
listener and then I'm going to boot dr.
o in the end so that the function
triggers and then I'm going to upload
this file if this happens and they go
back to this command here it will take
the file name right which is whatever
and then semicolon curl and then to run
the command and send whatever is the
results here so now I have my neck Rock
listener waiting and then I'm going to
open the leg lock web interface waiting
for requests now I'm going to copy the
command I already have it prepared now
let's try to do it again it says
uploaded let's see okay so now we have
something in Negril we have a request if
you see their post data it's what its
leaves the name of the of the function
only one club thank you very much
unbelievable so let's try something else
let's try for example this command see
if we can get something else going on
let's try a command that requires multi
lines okay that's why you would put
actually in inside the post request for
curl so we have a request now you name
that the command results and then the
listing directory so what really
happened here is that the attack came
not from outside but actually from
inside Amazon's own infrastructure so it
was an event sent by Amazon that's what
we call event injection we injected our
attack inside the event that would be
sent from Amazon to the lambda function
listening for us and then we utilize
their variability inside lambda itself
for the code to actually run our own
command so that's basically how it works
thank you very much
thank you very much now why don't we try
something that's more useful for us as
attackers let's try the command called
and which Brantly environmental
variables right now let's see if we have
okay so that these are the environmental
variables you can see the tokens and the
keys where is the key secret okay so
that the idealized secret key so that's
the same as the metadata attack in DC
two servers inside lambda it's in the
environmental variable if you want to
try this tool after we're done make sure
you delete the bucket and then you
delete the stack from a side cloud
formation feature inside Amazon so that
you don't leave your environment
vulnerable for long so as we said the
parameter variables contain all the
interesting stuff you can use lambda
function as a sort of an automated
backdoor so we can create a lambda
function that listens for example for
any addition any user being added to
this account and then if they get added
you steal their code their access key
and access token and then you send it
outside or for example listen for any
new instance that kid gets created so
lambda can also be used as a backdoor
mechanism or eheh what are you listening
for interesting event that happened and
the victim idealised account and then
you act upon it now let's talk about the
permissions servers inside Amazon the I
M Identity and Access Management Service
inside Amazon access right I think so so
this manages for you they were all the
users there all the groups the API
access keys permissions and trust
relationships so we're going to see how
that works especially of course we've
seen the API access keys we've talked
about this one a lot let's talk more
about trust relationships a trust
relationship inside Amazon allows you to
give temporary access for other entities
to your own role for example suppose I
have an instance and in situ instance
and I want it to be able to upload files
to my s3 buckets so I create a a role
called upload files to s3
and then I attach the scroll to this
instance now this instance when it runs
it can use this rolls permission to
upload files to my ass three bucket
because this allows this this allows me
to actually create an environment where
I don't have to use hard-coded keys
because Amazon will store these kids
forming inside the instance metadata now
when you attach this role to this ec2
instance you're creating a trust
relationship you're saying that this
instance the ec2 instance can assume
this role and gain temporary credentials
for it to use it to call the Edible sf3
fbi's to upload files to it so this
feature the trust relationship features
is through an ABI called called STS
assume role of course it has lots of of
interesting let's say use cases it can
allow you to actually use it across
accounts so suppose I have an ad an
Amazon account for my environment and
someone else's account can't call this
function if I allow them to an example
if I have an environment that is for
production and environment for
developers and they want developers to
temporarily be able to for example
deploying functions or deploying
resources on the production environment
so I can use this STS assume role policy
document this is an example okay suppose
we have a dev account with this ID and
then we have a production account with
this ID okay and then we have Andrews
mature administrator role on the
production account so this is the Amazon
resource name for the role role of
administrator under the account of for
all force for the production account I
want to allow my developers in the dev
account to temporarily be able to use
this role to for example deploy servers
so I will say allow which principal this
principal the account all tools for the
dev account now it means that any any
user on that they've account can use
this call to temporarily get credentials
for the admin structure on the other
production account and then deploy
servers and then once we're done their
temporary credentials will be gone so if
I was an attacker I could do the
following I could add
own attacker Amazon a saccharide e and
then add it to the list of whoever's
allowed to call this role so now I will
be able to use the Amazons
I am update assume all policy to attach
and backdoor the role itself here so
this is really interesting because
that's not one of the things
administrators or defenders inside
Amazon really look for they tend to look
for the traditional stuff but this is
any less specific stuff so you should
always add these roles and their policy
documents to your integrity checks to
check if someone has played with it and
you know added their own account ID so
that's one way of how we can backdoor an
edible eyes account and I've seen it
happen with you know administrators
being fired without having the access
remote for them so they do this quick
backdoor stuff to be able to hurt the
organization that fired them one of the
best ad blast attack tools to actually
do this exploitation and post
exploitation attacks is called Paco it's
made by Rhino security labs it can do
some of the attacks we discussed for
example backdoor assume role to add your
own
for example account ID to the terminal
policy it can also use create a model
called lambda back your new users what
this model does is that it will create a
lambda function anytime any user gets
added to this account it will backdoor
that user create an access key and
secret key and then steal that to a
server off site for you so it's
currently the most feature complete open
source as well as attack tool in the
market before I finish these are the
resources again if you are more
interested in edible s then we started
with maybe now we want to take you know
picture of the of these really cool
books and if you if you done and then
I'm also done so thank you very much for
your attention
any questions
I'd be happy to answer thank you very
much Thank You Mohammad these are all
very nicest features right mm-hmm
thank you what do you think is that like
the biggest misunderstanding when people
start talking about security in AWS they
don't treat amazon's documentation they
think it's just another server in the
cloud it is but you have lots of
documentation and features inside Amazon
that's integrate with these servers and
databases inside Amazon so if you don't
really follow up and understand the
environment you're running on you're
about to have problems all right but
it's like a pet peeve like the even the
people that have read the manual always
misunderstand this part it's something
like that yeah you can say yeah yeah all
right do you have questions from the
audience as well have ten minutes before
it there's one question there and back
to the mic runner that can get there is
there a mic run around this side oh I
think we need four mic runners in here
it's so big thank you for a great talk
so do you have any quick comments how to
find and mitigate these vulnerabilities
first of all where are you I don't see
you okay well okay yeah so that question
again please they have any quick
comments on how to mitigate these Myr
abilities I mean you said there were
features in the Amazon Cloud but the
only great way to find these real quick
okay so if you notice everything we
discussed so far resulted one way or
another of one of two things either we
have an application about
vulnerabilities and abilities in your
own servers and your own application
that resulted in exposure for your own
exposure of your own Amazon API keys
right and then the second half of the
variability was that those keys usually
had much more privileges than they
needed right so if you really give good
attention to your application security
plus understand really how Amazon's
permission system works you can really
reduce and sometimes even prevent any
post exploitation attacks from being
meaningful on
your own Amazon environment and that's
easier said than done because Amazon has
I think almost 6,000 permission types
half of them don't allow customization
so it has to be star like everything so
there is still lots of things to do on
terms of security and permissions even
from Amazon's site so it's not it's a
it's a really difficult problem to
actually tackle I'm not going to say
it's easy I'm not going to say just do
that no it's actually a really difficult
problem I hope that answered you thank
you right the question where I am
curious as to what is Amazon's take on
this set of issues because they usually
say that they take security seriously
not you are aware of that yeah you know
when someone says they take security
seriously we don't tend to believe that
but the thing is I don't blame Amazon
it's a really huge infrastructure and
it's really difficult to make changes
within with f/a structure as it is
running I mean it's a live Astra
structure millions of customers they
just can't change everything on a whim
so it's really difficult even on there
but and I'm sure they are more
interested in securing their own
environments I'll give an example
remember the instance metadata we talked
about remember how easy it was to call
it we just give the SSL verbal to the
URL to call Google cloud for example in
comparison requests a special header to
be sent so you can't really add the
header when you use an SSL availability
so it kind of defeats the instance
metadata exposure inside Google cloud
because they request an internal header
to be set with the request so of course
you can still attack it in Google cloud
if you use if you have an orbital proxy
for example but it limits its greatly
limits the exposure of the instance
metadata inside Google cloud and I
really think Amazon is supposed to put
something like this such that you need
to add something extra
not just the URL itself to attack the
incest metadata so yes there's still
lots more to be done even on Amazon site
yes tighten up security once it's
deployed right yeah
microphone coming so how often do you
end up walking into something where
people have had training on this and
they still are absolutely freaking
clueless really all the time okay it's
miss its compass see when I told you
that amazon has six thousand permissions
and half of them don't require
customization they can only be what like
a wild card it's not an easy problem to
solve but if you know your
infrastructure well if you know your
environment well you can make it really
secure I've seen some organizations do
something else different entirely such
that the users don't have accounts on
the production environment at all so
they only leti often to get from another
account so this kind of you know
segregate into duties and makes the
problem a bit more difficult for the
attacker to actually reach out to
everything inside it more questions no
it's like this Thank You Mohammed thank
you you're my very much thank you for
your attention