up next we have our lightning talks we
have two presentations the first one
Charles Lee on ipv4 redistributions
secondary markets
you
good afternoon I'm going to talk to you
about something which is vitally
important to all of you you already know
it you may not know it in quite the same
way the single most important asset of
your corporations is your IP numbers
none of you function without them you
can buy all the routers and fiber and
cross connects and whatever else but
absent numbers you don't have a business
so without further ado we're going to
talk about some numbers about the
numbers first let's start off with a
long-standing myth that the internet is
running out of numbers this myths was
started around 1995 and the reality is
that the rirs the regional internet
registries are impact running out of
numbers they've gotten 3.7 billion
numbers through the ion of functions and
have parsed out the preponderance of
them some of them still have some
numbers for example AP nick has a
reasonable supply but it's trapped in
policy so unless you're willing to live
with a slash 22 they cannot fulfill your
needs each region has its own rules
about allocation but in the Aaron region
for example they're down to less than an
eighth less than half of an eighth and
declining difficult to predict when they
will actually exhaust but with the 4.2
billion by the way these will all be
rough numbers rather than specifics of
the 4.2 billion numbers that are in the
address table 595 million were set aside
special purpose by RFC at least 3.7
billion iono has allocated 3.7 billion
that means I Anna is effectively empty
they're doing cleanup but essentially
that pool is gone as a consequence the
situation exists that the rars cannot
fulfill your needs for additional number
this means that the business environment
within which you operate as changed or
ever and always this is a new business
reality
this is neither good nor bad it is a
fact so thanks to Jeff Houston we've had
a lot of conversations I was able to put
together some numbers about the numbers
for example allocated but unadvertised
there's about a billion numbers which
have been allocated and don't appear in
the general purpose routing tables
anyway that doesn't mean they're not
needed it means they're not being used
or not used in the general public
Internet a second category which I found
under the research paper title which
only an academic could love the title
being capturing ghosts predicting the
unused ipv4 space by empowering
unobserved addresses after digging
through the title and the 27 pages of
the analysis approximately 1 point 1
billion numbers are advertised but
unused this means there is approximately
2.1 billion numbers out of 3.7 that are
not in use in the public Internet today
now the two things together have
implications for you and I'll draw that
as a conclusion in just a moment but
let's deal with the second myth burst
there we go v6 is the answer to internet
number needs this was the mantra which
raided again around 1995 and
unfortunately it doesn't help a great
deal because b6 is a replacement or not
an extension of ipv4 it is a brand new
internet the two are incompatible on the
wire so we're going to have to
transition we're going to go from the
public internet it is exists today in v4
to a public internet that exists in v6
and that transition is going to take a
lot of time and billions of dollars not
fortunately it's not billions of any one
person's dollars but there's a lot of
money to be spent here
dual stack which is our generally
accepted most predominantly accepted
means to do this transition means that
you need both before and v6 numbers
neither is sufficient so that means we
have to talk about how long will dual
stack persistent now I took a shot and
said it will persist at least until
native be six packets or eighty to
ninety percent of the traffic in the
internet I would also suggest it we may
take quite a bit longer than that for
other reasons but this is a lightning
talk so we're going to move on so given
these two facts sets let's draw some
obvious conclusions v6 does nothing to
mitigate before number needs until v6
rules the internet before is not going
away anytime soon if ever again there's
some reasons why before might persist or
a very very very long time and the
obvious conclusion out of those two
statements is that redistribution of
unused v4 number blocks is necessary for
the foreseeable you again this is not a
this is not a good thing or a bad thing
this is a reality statement we're going
to have to redistribute numbers so how
is that redistribution going and what
are the rules that are being employed
well it's being done by free market the
laws and forces of supply and demand
rule demand ie need is self determined
by the buyer if you go and you go to an
AR AR and say I need a 16 and he can't
fulfill it your need did not go away
it's the means by which you get it
fulfilled has been changed they're not
going to be getting more so you're going
to be getting it through redistribution
in that environment demand being set by
the by the buyers and the other side
supply supply the broader your market
the larger the available supply the
lower the prices this is basic marketing
amex right supply and demand will come
into equilibrium around price that is a
fact so in theory all three point seven
billion numbers in the general purpose
internet are available the question is
at what price now that's theory because
businesses cannot give up those numbers
they have them they need them their
business is dependent on them you can
effectively say the price is infinite
the price of acquiring the numbers from
those companies would be the price of
acquiring the company and in regard to
prices they're going to be set they are
being set freely by consent between
sellers and buyer though the seller asks
the buyers offer a negotiation ensues
sometimes and that is how deals are
struck valuation is affected by several
factors but because although all numbers
were created equal they are certainly
not treated that way and after several
decades of being used and misused and
misappropriated moved around there are
mitigating circumstances around all of
them so terms and conditions of the deal
would obviously affect value technical
characteristics are they trash sitting
on a black list somewhere things like
that so there's all these
characteristics which influence the
value if geolocation is important to you
what region of the world is it going to
appear it all of these things dictate
value and that means that the value is
not static and assistant around the
globe they do change its high
variability between regions what is
always true is that determination of the
right beholder is critical you
absolutely do not want to get engaged in
a transaction where the seller doesn't
have the right transfer that is a
nightmare waiting to happen do not want
to go there right embracing this new
redistribution model has put in place a
couple of policies one is policy 623
allocation and assignment
they eliminated needs assessment there
was no point for them to determine need
if they weren't going to be giving them
out seems to be there think the second
one also put in place roughly the same
time and perhaps more important was
policy 605 which was services to legacy
internet resource holders and the common
language version of that policy is that
you as a buyer may elect to put a
contract in place with right or not in
either event right we'll update the
record to the name of the present
Boulder that is very important what that
did is unlock all the legacy blocks all
the legacy blocks which have been
trapped because people put sell them
because they couldn't get their
registries updated now can it unlocked a
large supply of numbers for the market
it accommodates capital market
requirements for control of financed
assets this is this is more of a nuance
but is a significant one because what
this means is as a company you may not
have use your own cash there are banks
which we work with which would you
about financing that deal where you make
finance payments and they control they
are the holder of the block until you
have satisfied your debt it's the same
as taking a mortgage on your house they
have to have control the house until you
satisfied you're dead most importantly
this was a clear commitment by right the
accuracy of the register they had made
the decision that accuracy was single
most important aspect of running a
registered I'll come back to that point
just a minute
so what can we learn from the ripe
experience there's a bunch of beers
which have been dispelled they just
simply were fear they were not founded
in reality speculators have not appeared
there is not a host of people running
around buying up blocks and speculating
on value it just doesn't happen and if
you consider the cost of doing it and
the ambiguity about technology you'll
understand why a quick technology
innovation from one of the geniuses in
this room and all the this changes
routing tables have not exploded there
has not been this huge disaggregation of
routes and the routers continue to
function quite well there has not been
registry churn there is not a constant
flipping of number blocks where there
are continually updating a rare accuracy
of the right registry which already was
pretty good is getting better it is more
and more accurate every day and prices
within the region and within other
regions have remained reasonable and
fairly stable there has not been an
explosion of either supply or demand it
has not oster a nightmare scenario these
are the facts I would encourage you to
talk right if you wanted to get them
validated they make quite public but you
need not fear these things these are not
reality so what does redistribution look
like it is a secondary market it is a
new business reality it is one you
cannot ignore and as a consequence you
now have to think about acquisition not
allocation so previously where it may
have been the case the technical
justification was adequate now it is
just the beginning and as an example
your business cases Matt must now
include a new line item cost of number
block acquisition if you don't do that
and you have a business case which is
absent getting numbers and you discover
that you have to go get numbers you're
going to have to go back to your
business people and say oops I forgot
this line
item that is a painful experience I'd
encourage you to avoid it a second
reality out of this is that very
specialized expertise is required
there's a whole new set of knowledge
that asked to be put in place one is for
mining of unused numbers now that's a
discussion and a presentation in and of
itself but identifying unused numbers
that are available appropriate terms or
right that is very hard lifting that is
good hard work and it requires very
specialized expertise secondly you're
going to have to make sure that the
expertise is in place for protection
protection of you protection of the
seller it is in your interest on either
side of that equation to protect both
party and this is protection against
failed and flawed transactions illusion
market manipulation again whether actual
or alleged nobody wants their name in
the paper that they stole number block
from a retired school teacher so there
are reasons why you need some
specialized expertise and protection in
these transaction call fraction every
presentation I've seen at the nanog has
asked you to do more I apologize I'm
going to join the grab so first you need
to advocate for global registry policies
that are supportive of redistribution
redistribution is incessant any policy
that that works against that necessity
works against your interest but you need
to advocate for things which help
redistribution not limited registry
accuracy is essential to registry arm
relevance an inaccurate registry is less
than helpful so if accuracy is not
improving go get policies in place I
help make it better and third start
educating your suits yes we know that's
what do poke
suits are necessary and you're going to
need them you need your finance people
you need your lawyers you need your
people and they do not have a clue what
you're talking about when you walk in
and say I need a number bot so start the
education process early that's it if
there's any questions to be glad to pay
not really a question just to comments
first of all these four does v6 does
nothing to mitigate v4 give me ldp six
give me the ability to do more teeny
over v6 and I'll prove you wrong today
because I can free up about 20,000 IPS
on my network secondly speculators have
not appeared you obviously haven't heard
of a glycol blue hang the reason that
you're not seeing speculators in this
market is because right now they're
coming and taking the space out of
AfriNIC through fraudulent applications
and speculating on that we are seeing
the speculators they've taken at least a
/ 10 of space out of a Phoenix in the
last few months so sorry I really
dispute that well I am NOT operating a
registry and I'm talking about
redistribution if you're having
speculators or bad actors coming into
the registries I don't question that now
that number blocks have market value bad
actors will appear that is a fact that's
one of the protection things I was
talking about and you need expert East
oops stop any other questions no let's
go get some beer
sorry not quite yet on the beer but soon
we have one more lightning talk on the
topic of amplification by Alexander
lemon
hello everyone my name is Alexandra
lemon and I am pleased breath left and
this will be one more pass on very
popular topic today did also big gates
and first the question whose people
being present sir being hit by those
implication attracts past here just so
few I wouldn't believe Jack and who
observe did awesome amplification
attacks originating from the network
just one em that's the definition of the
problem block of observation let's take
a look at this list of by quite usual
suspects they all access lack of ability
to establish out ECT stay off plan and
the all access web design they are all
amplifier ball and I'm sick and tired of
this product balls so we decided to take
closer look what they look like how's
the mirror and the current apv for a
visit so we waited there and that's what
ens looks like nowadays as you can see
maximum amplification are multiple
multiplier of 60 is almost unattainable
so we are as community did a really good
job eliminate the threat congratulation
ntp well doesn't look that good still
problems there chair can not coming SNMP
I have no idea what these three peaks
are honestly if you have any ideas why
this or present is our measurement just
come up to me afterwards and let's get
started
SSD the largest peak is 78 this is a
maximum amplification multiplier of DNS
and this looks big budget so we also
measure it this product also houses a
cave are on the time scale in between
junipers and october thieves of the past
year and what we found is 100 1.6
billion packets for first stage for
every first stage of attack back even if
it's purely theoretical still Wow right
second thing this is the piece clearly
is the king of amplifications the ntp is
down there on the bottom and there it
comes to note well not notes a
hypothesis ah why we're not dead yet
possibly because we were lucky enough to
have bad protocol such as SS b 2 b CJ aj
add parameters of our network and it's
probably not about how many packets you
can generate even theoretically it's how
many packets will arrive to the target
of your attack so it's all about knowing
balaji in effort that's why we are lucky
enough stay alive and functional even
such severe problems with amplification
in current if poor at its fate so what
we only make a bit will we just lie
dormant for next 3 years and see this
amplification stack returned with
vengeance or will will be vigil
empower network clean and well managed
and if you have a question how your s
number looks from our vantage point
you're free to email to me and have your
personalized shipboard orcish me up in
the hallway or here in here and I will
show you how your networks loops we are
from our tool that's about it I wouldn't
I can't hold you from your much longer
sorry questions
I hope question alinco so can i just
email about any is number i'm interested
in well if I understand the question
right we have established out
instigation procedure so we will make
extra effort the check if you're the
person proper person to manage this
particular a s number so we will not
disclose your amplifier circuit board
Hank more questions then it's the beer
thank you thank you just a reminder
again if you have a submission or a
lightning talk those are due at 8pm
tonight go to be seen an org to make
your submission thanks for the beer and
gear next
you