thank you my name is Rajee ball of
Emperor product in charge like part of
the product team in brooklyn for the
routing products so there has been some
good sessions on the d dose and other
security or you know the topics over
here so but i wanted to share with you
is the data privacy across the internet
data privacy in simple terms means
protect what's yours so especially when
you have you know these large flows
content growing going across the
internet then what are the challenges
right so that we are seeing and we are
hearing i wanted to share those findings
with you into the next light
so in the data privacy we are seeing
like strong growing interest there are a
couple reasons one is the data breaches
so you might be hearing you know last
year they have been data beaches for the
traffic in transit and like on the on
the endpoints like you know the pass
terminals and why are these data breach
is happening right so data beaches are
motivated by multiple things one is the
intellectual assets it's almost like
when you leave your home and you have
your laptop bag with you then what do
you have for you hope for like you know
nobody takes it but you know what is
worse than somebody taking or stealing
your laptop bag is somebody be able to
take the data off and so that is one of
the primary motivations is similarly
when you have data going across the
transit especially the internet then
intellectual assets and then there could
be like your your customer information
on it there could be a the premium
content content is king as we know right
so somebody are taking your content away
from you I mean without paying you
without any charge I mean that that's
not something that they own or another
key driver is the regulations so which
is for example are in the infrastructure
you might care about your data center
data center you know sort of like data
privacy but similar to you so your
customers have different drivers like
for example health care would hear about
HIPAA financials would care about the
sarbanes and similar to that PCI and not
only that like you know the media
companies would care about Holly
protecting their content so it doesn't
stay that you know they have to have the
security but then given the nature of
the business that's how it's you know so
it's getting there in terms of the
opportunity encryption yes but then
they're more few examples i would like
to share or the findings is for example
a remote data center or another one is
like you have let's say your layer two
networks so layered two networks you are
the fibers with your customers connected
in but what if like you can have them
come across the internet site still you
have the fiber available remote caching
side
can be another example so going into the
details of what to protect that could
vary that word that depends on the
nature of like your the content and the
business and your customers it could be
the disaster recovery traffic across the
internet video video has been growing
right so if you're sending it from let's
say one studio to another or from a
distribution side to the different
studios it's going from 1 k-2 2k and
soon it will be going to 4k and 8a so
imagine the flow the flow size going
from you know like from sub 1 gig
several gay to even probably like you
know or 10 gig medical imaging financial
information are some of the other
examples here so the use case what is
the use case here use cases imagine like
you have two data centers and you have
the bulk transfers right so we have the
customers who are experimenting you know
so we see thy the customers who are
experimenting or the communities who are
experimenting like you know so going
from one guy to ten gayi 100 gig close
now across the internet you may not put
100 gig that might be quite a bit but
what about like you know going from sub
1 gig to like several one gig to like
you know so so 10 gig how do you get
there and it's not data center to data
center you could have the campus you
could have the remote stadium site you
could have the branch offices so it's
all part of the same network the
important part here is that how do you
connect them all together end right so
because if you have these sites then
what can you do or what level of
encryption right so so and the what is
the what is the cost of doing and not
doing that and that's where the
challenges comes in which varies by the
network and the use case but first one
is there is a stigma right so the first
portion that we hear from the customers
when they think about the data privacy
is the impact of the performance
performance is very important to all all
the all the operators right so every bid
that they can ship out on the network
without having to drop the performance
is a plus so there has been
this stigma associated with the
encryption is that if you turn on the
encryption in your network then the
performance goes by at least fifty
percent or even higher so that is the
number one challenge that we hear so I
want to share that with you second one
is what is the larger size of ipsec
tunnel so so some of the operators are
concerned about that you know if they
put the ipsec tunnel like ipsec in their
network what is the largest they can get
to can it scale through the requirement
can it handle like 10 gig flows for
example like inter data center bulk
transfers so the data rates have been
going up and up and there is no stopping
so how much can you push like what is
the biggest flaw that she can get to the
third one over here is aggregation hub
if you look at the use case the scenario
is distributed or take an example of the
brand sides let's say you're 20 brand
side with one gig each so do you want do
you want a full mast do you want like
you know every branch to have tunnels
with other brands or do you want to be
able to have all of them talk to each
other so how do you do it so that
requires the heck aggregation hub so
what should be the capacities of the
heck dication hub so that is has been
one of the limiting factors also is that
if you do 20 branches as an example of
one gig that would translate into a 20
game but what if you want to go and
continue to scale up to 200 branches
then what would be a requirement because
then you would have 200 branches coming
in and they want to they want to be able
to talk to each other right so that
would translate into like somebody be
able to handle 200 gig enter play
traffic encryption level encryption
level has been very popular like 20 of
128 bits has been out there you can see
the ipsec and other implementations it's
not new it's a very popular mechanism
ipsec is a very progressive technology
so it has been out there for decades
very well used like in too many and
networks with with the you know small
medium large
appointments but what is new what is
changing what is challenging is that is
128-bit encryption enough so so does it
protect what you care about and that's
the reason so how about aes-256 so that
would be something like another
challenge like challenge number for that
would like to point out here so
something to think about when you're
thinking about the data privacy across
the Internet last but not least there
could be many when we talk about
Internet it's not an easy thing because
you would need like you know several
factors which play a role but the last
one that I would like to point out and
share with you is the frame side so what
happens with these encryptions is once
you turn on the encryption it adds an
extra header so when you have 120 bits
as 120 bites of a packet size your tax
is going to be up to like 64 bytes that
means like your your performance is
going to be impacted so so what so what
is a butt so that could make it very
challenging like with the small traffic
or the small sizes what if like what can
you do to basically mitigate that how
about 1,500 byte packets right or even
higher by doing that what happens is
that your tax is still same its tail
says add that extra header off up to 64
bytes but as you increase the size then
that would be a way to reduce that tax
and have the performance out of your
network so that you have high
performance network with encryption just
like you do with your 10 gig 40 gain 100
gig nut boy so I don't want to be
between you and your lunch but if you
have any questions to be a painful push
okay so is there if there is one potion
or please let me know otherwise you have
the email we can talk offline or during
the break or feel free to send an email
hey Thank You Rajiv thank you Tony so I
should say or normally would say thank
you very much for coming but maybe I
would be better to say thank you very
much for staying but thank you also to
the program committee for having I trust
that I don't ously have to rush because
we don't have anything following this
except for the break but I don't have a
lot this is some work in the true
lightning talk mold where it's its
ongoing it's not finalized some things
we were doing over the past three or
four weeks myself and a couple of
colleagues at DePaul University James
and match a I if you were paying
attention earlier this morning you
probably would have heard something
about net comp and if not I'm afraid I
won't have time to go over what netconf
is but if i can get you to look up from
your laptops for just a moment how many
of you actually have some netcom running
that you may or may not be using in your
network just by show of hands a fair
number of you okay maybe a few dozen
anyways that's interesting I assume most
of you that raised your hand probably
you're doing it with with juniper gear
but would be my guess and if not it I
would like to hear otherwise perhaps
after and if you are you to have
something like this and in your config
tree where you turn this on under your
services you'll you may note or you may
be learning for the first time that net
comp by default runs over TCP port 830
now if you're a user of the old Jew no
script which is what this has arisen
from you could run that over port 22 as
well but people are turning on this for
the first time by default will have it
over tcp port 30 and i didn't realize
this until not long ago in our network
we had we were looking at some other
research stuff with multicast and i
happen to notice port 830 was open on
route and I said what's that and I hit
use Juno script before but not net comp
being somewhat newer and then when I
figure or when we figured it out
we realized that it was on a lot of
boxes and none of us really realized
that it was someone had turned it on for
something and so then we wondered well
who else has this on and do they know
about it and what sorts of potential
issues might there be for those who may
be unaware that this stuff may be turned
on part of the problem for this perhaps
being accessible on some networks may be
our fault we have this very old secure
junos template on our site that hasn't
been updated so it's effectively
outdated and stale now for it's a decade
in fact a lot of the stuff that's in
there was things that I had put in there
before I even joined team coumarine I
that may mean it's parsha it for about
it but I haven't heard many people ask
us about this template recently so it
may not even be used but if this needs
to be updated I would certainly like to
hear about it so maybe we should do a
new version of this because it's so well
if we got out of date so I went look or
we went looking we scanned one of the
probes that we did it just took a 10
million random ipv4 addresses and we
said well who who will respond to us and
TCP 4830 and let's follow up that and
see if we get an ssh connection and just
doing a random skin in the address space
for that we've actually found very few
not not many at all some but not very
many if you're in the security track
yesterday you may have noticed or saw
Jarrod talk about being able to identify
junos versions using a particular
protocol if you don't recall what that
is that'll be a homework to figure it
out but we have a way to identify Geno's
boxes the internet so I took a sample of
those specifically and then probe those
and we found at least comparatively
higher percentage of boxes that do have
net comp listening and some the versions
of jew nose running vary quite widely
and some facts some will be running
that's just H less than version to a
version 1 now net by default for an
implementation is to run over ssh but
there's also an RFC that says you can do
net comp over TLS there's also one that
says you can do it over beep but I don't
know that any
actually does that but over TLS so we
said well then that's a different port
so let's take a look at that what's
probe randomly and we found some there
even a few more than we would have found
over port 830 from a random scan and
those are actually kind of interesting
so i thought i would show you a couple
of things that we found and i hope you
can see this in the back and so if
you're looking at your laptop's this is
where you you look up and you chuckle a
little bit and make fun of ATT this is a
this is a box from ATT that does have
net conf over port 830 open but port 22
is filtered so they're probably in the
situation where they've they thought
they were locking down the routers
probably enabled nap comp and forgot to
put a filter on their loopback interface
for that as well I'm the certificate
side so if you look at netcom for were
TLS felt a lot of interesting things
here these just pulling out some of the
attributes of the certificate quite a
few banks I don't know what sorts of
devices they are we haven't done a
terrible amount of investigation of this
yet but some interesting things and you
may note that last one a dot mil
people's eyebrows always tend to rise
slightly when you hear about a dot mil
being exposed with something that is I
don't know if that name matches the IP
address that we had but I can assure you
that the IP address that that was
associated with was it no address so
this stuff is certainly out there now
the question must be asked well is it a
big deal is that we know what's the
threat here how much of a problem really
is this and it may not be that much i'm
not here to cry wolf and i would suggest
you if we could some of this up don't
panic but there may be threats and so
this is why we wanted to try to take a
better look at this and bring this to
your attention perhaps with the ssh
netcom to the things that i might be
most worried about if it were me would
be the ability to perhaps do a denial of
service attack on that netcom service
user by default your junos boxes have a
connection limit and so if you could tie
those up whatever you may have doing net
cough may not be able to get through
the other thing is probably more
worrisome is if you have weak passwords
associated with a ID some account on
this box we've certainly seen as a sage
brute force attacks in the past we
certainly don't want to see any more of
them so this doesn't Italy make the
problem really that much worse unless
those people who thought they were
protected with their loot bag filters
don't actually have them protected now
this TLS services certificate one I
think there's a fair amount of detail on
the certificate that's quite interesting
I don't know if you would consider it
high risk of that being exposed but the
one thing I'm not sure about yet we
haven't studied we haven't finished
studying this is that my fear is those
systems that do netcom over TLS may not
have strong authentication you may just
be able to attach to them and perhaps
using generic ID and passwords do
effectively anything you would be able
to do via command line but just using
that comp if anyone knows how this stuff
works over some of these devices and I'm
not even sure all the devices that do
net comp over TLS but I'd be interested
to know more about that before we
actually start poking around a little
further so I'll leave you with some of
the questions that we are going to try
to answer as we do a little bit more of
this and some of these questions may be
for you and I won't read every one of
these to you but I would be interested
to hear if you think this is worthwhile
should we continually provide some sort
of day to feed like team comer does for
other things do you want to know about
this stuff in your network I I'm pretty
certain many of you here probably have
some of this stuff maybe I just told you
something about your network you didn't
know once you go looking so I'd be
curious to hear any response to this
this effort and how much more time we
should spend on it and with that I thank
you very much for your attention in your
time
I think that's Michael in fact it is
like Sinatra yes that um keep in mind
this stuff also runs on ipv6 by default
if you have ipv6 turn on your router
well the net conf isn't turned on by
default is what if so you isn't turned
on by default if you turn it on it will
turn it will go so if you run like a
Juno space appliance in your network and
you think you're blocking all traffic to
everything but that but you forget to
put the filter in ipv6 it's the same
they're going to open ipv6 to the whole
world so I say this from experience
obviously this is a obscure enough
problem but yeah this stuff runs on ipv6
to let me make sure that your ipv6
filters match your ipv4 ok thank you sir
laminex hundred curator loves what do
you think would happen exactly if CPU
resources on control playing of your
juniper box will be completely exhausted
like one hundred percent accusation what
could happen yeah what would happen well
this is somewhat nightly specific to net
comp but i suppose number of things
could happen your routing protocols may
start dropping packets the routing
sessions may drop all that sort of stuff
right and please and things will happen
so don't expose your control plane to
public network right is that I think
that's part of that I think that's part
of what I'm saying yes that's it ok I
think we're finished for you thanks very
much
you