alright so next up was Lee Howard from
time warner cable he's done analysis of
both policies and adoption of ipv6 and
web when access networks and has some
suggestions about the impact for Public
Policy I'm going to make you king or
queen as the case may be congratulations
now that your supreme monarch of your
nation somebody some citizen comes to
you and says what are you doing about
ipv4 run out how do you respond well
maybe you go to your you Ministry of
Communications Minister of
Communications or maybe you go to your
humble Vizier myself and now it's dr.
Jesse soul as at the past couple of days
congratulations to him we we are happy
to present some counsel to you on some
things that you might do based on what
other countries have done your first
question Your Majesty might be is this
actually a public policy issue this is
something that we need to worry about we
in the royal we sense my answer would be
maybe this is up to you ipv4 is the
status quo with the status quo is
changing and I've demonstrated in
previous talks about how costs will rise
that you know TCO of cg end costs money
there's a there's an address market and
what you might mostly be worried about
and this is what some other countries
have demonstrated concern about is that
the deployment of ipv6 might be costly
or hurried or island e to make up a word
those costs are obviously you know how
much it costs in hardware but also
mostly in knowledge and the opportunity
cost Barrett izing v6 deployment over
anything else that you industries might
do that hurried pneus may tends to make
things error-prone if people start too
late and realize they need to rush that
island eater my get from actually the
case of Singapore where they have a no
island in policy where they want to make
sure that anybody that they're there cut
their companies inside their country can
reach any part of the internet whether
it's v4 or v6 and not have
islands of dis connectivity so it's
pretty important um and what one of
things that you might want to pay
attention to is coordinating the the
deployment of ipv6 to some extent in
order to maximize the network effect
that is to say that if somebody has
deployed v6 they want to maximize the
benefit that they get from ipv6 which is
that network effect and so some
coordination might help there maybe
there's some things you can do so what
has happened how has deployment happened
over the course of the internet well
there's this really interesting
visualization we took ilovecharts that
turn out pretty so actually this is
jesse took some data over time of web
deployment among various countries now
the x-axis is the proportion of
countries sorry the x-axis is the
percent of websites supporting epi v6
and the y-axis is the density the number
of countries for that percentage that
supports v6 so for instance at five
percent a very high number of countries
have five percent of their top 50
websites for TV six and as you go out
along the x-axis a very small number of
countries has forty percent but you can
see especially the top countries you
well you can't see because it's too
small but you can see that the top
countries have moved from over there at
the five percent I've moved across the
x-axis because now they have a much
higher percent of their website
supporting v6 what we wanted to do each
line here represents one day and how
many countries that day at top websites
sporting v6 and what we're looking for
is where there are sudden jumps where
there is white space so anytime that you
see a wide volume under the curve that
means more countries have more support
that's good that bright red line is
world ipv6 launch that's when a whole
lot of idea of sites suddenly supported
v6 that's great and then we noticed a
couple of other sort of Buster's of days
where suddenly traffic moved and moved
out to the right meaning more countries
at a higher percentage those turned out
to be odd flare turning on doing major
activations of these six so you know
there's there's one company so may
be one thing that Your Majesty should
consider is it is talking to CloudFlare
and seeing what they did there seems to
be some direct input just from that one
company now let me talk about what a
government might be able to do so there
are basically three as we observed
various countries deployments we
observed three different kinds of sets
of things that happen the first is
direct policy efforts things that
governments can do themselves just
because they are the government so
that's the sort of thing that a monarch
decree is going to happen then there are
partnerships with public and public
private partnerships hybrid policy areas
and then in this final case we talked
about the charismatic policy
entrepreneur within both individual
companies and firms and within the
operational epistemic community there's
some jargon there that I'm going to have
to come back to and explain what I mean
by that I want to talk about that so let
me first say what can a country do to
promote ipv6 well they're basically
three sets of things you can do one you
can do the direct government's effort of
requiring government websites and
services to run over v6 cosplayer you
can provide some kind of incentives or
requirements or private industry to
support six or you can provide funding
even maybe a company to deploy v6 we've
actually seen some cases with each of
those so let's look at what's actually
worked so here here's a list of
countries with high adoption of ipv6
among their top 50 websites this is from
Eric Pincus site and I've specifically
listed on the top mmm well so there's
there are several countries tied there
and I left out a couple of countries
that I didn't think I'd especially
interesting case it so some of these
countries have by so I let me go ahead
and explain um there's a policy type
which coordinates York or relates to
what's on the right side in some of
these countries there's a small group of
companies that is deployed v6 and that's
what matters in others there's a single
company that's made a big difference and
I've got the percentage of the top 50
websites that's board v6 and then their
ranking overall so the Czech Republic is
the number one country in the world or
web deployment of ipv6 when you're
looking at the top 50 websites
thirty-four percent of their website
support Busey
okay thirty four percent that's that's
pretty good what kind of policy do they
have well they specifically require
government services to be available over
ipv6 and CZ nick has done a really great
sorry Nick that's easy has done a great
job of providing reports on going about
which government sites support v6 pretty
impressive so there's a specific case
the u.s. is number three they also
specifically require government services
to be available over ipv6 and then I
should go ahead and show you what I've
circled Singapore also requires these
six to be available for all government
services now you can argue that well but
we haven't achieved a hundred percent
but there's been some success here and
what the correlation looks like it's
when a government requires there's serve
their web services their websites to be
available over v6 they go to their
hosting provider who says well we've
never done v6 before we have to go to
our transit providers and get b6 they
have to deploy v6 and there's an awful
lot of work that somebody for the
government is getting paid to do to push
this rock uphill when the next private
company comes in and says dual-stack our
website Boris they go short we've done
that before no problem and so the it's
the first site is really hard and after
that becomes much easier so there may be
some correlation there some reason why
government services should be available
over ipv6 and there may be that and that
may make a difference in the case of
singapore's there are two other
incentives that I've listed here that
one of the things that government
specifically can do they can require
companies to provide ipv6 for the
websites and they can even provide money
for them I only know of two countries
that have done either of these Singapore
which you can see listed here has both
required v6 as part of its no I lending
principle and China which isn't even
listed here because very very few
websites in China support ipv6 at least
that we can see externally and that's
partly because they haven't made a focus
of webs of web content given credit
there now Singapore has also actually
paid some of the transition costs for
certain countries charge for certain
companies so for instance they said we
they paid for the their ID a paid for
one bank to support ipv6 so
with that when ecommerce sites tried to
go support ipv6 there would already be a
bank that was available that could
support that service so there that was
their strategic effort to make sure that
they're removing obstacles for the next
company however there still tied at
number six twenty-two percent of
websites I'm not sure this is up to you
you're the king or queen you can decide
whether this is an important strategy
that you need to undertake and will note
that we do not that china isn't listed
here but what about ISPs is there a
correlation for isps well here's a list
of many of the top eyes countries in
terms of number of consumers that
support ipv6 I've included a couple that
aren't really in the top because they're
also I think interesting use cases and
I'll tell some stories as we go along so
Belgium is obviously far and away the
top country for ipv6 deployment among
consumers I'm going to say that again
unless you are from Belgium your comp
your country is far behind belgium in
terms of v6 deployment so what have they
done they had an incredible effort where
they they got together the
communications ministry the National
Police and even the equivalent of the
Commerce Department the economic
authority and the ISP Association and
they talked about well is this important
what needs to happen here the law
enforcement was very concerned about
area grade net and they said it's
illegal under EU law that's a personal
an IP address is personally identifiable
therefore it must be personally
identifiable and if it's shared among
other users then it's not personally
done to file any more well nobody else
has had that reading but it's a very
interesting reading the economic
authority and the telecom authority all
said well this is actually this be for a
run out problem is a competitive problem
so a new market entrant would not have
ipv4 addresses they would have to either
go by addresses thus increasing the cost
of providing competition and providing
an economic advantage an anti
competitive advantage for the incumbents
or they'd have to provide CGN which is
also expensive and provides potentially
a lower quality of service for those
customers
so they required v6 of all is beat and
they provided they allowed for 16 to one
address sharing ratio temporarily to
help companies get along that way so
Belgium is unique in that regard and you
can see it's been very very effective in
terms of their deployment of ipv6 I note
that the two incentives that I've talked
about there where the cyber security
concern about address sharing making law
enforcement more difficult and the net
neutrality competition effort making
sure that new entrants to the market
could compete with the already existing
providers pretty interesting so here
I've got circled again the rest of the
top part that the rest of the government
direct policies board top is BS we've
already talked about US government does
require v6 for web services not sure
that's had a direct impact on is Pete
adoption the Czech Republic I might
mention them and Singapore has has all
three of these so it's up to you as the
monarch of your country to decide which
of these factors is most influential but
maybe there's some other things that we
should be looking at so if these are not
necessarily clear winners among is BS
what's riven deployment um what kinds of
things are well there are these hybrid
public-private partnerships there are
two essential kinds there there's both
the government as a legitimating
convener bringing in private industry
talking about ipv6 and then in some
cases we have the RIR as a
quasi-governmental or as a policy
entrepreneur in some cases working with
government and in some cases acting as a
national authority to bring together to
bring some legitimacy to those meeting
convention in both cases part of the
goal and I think this is part of the
important goal is bridging the gap
between the engineer and the CEO CTO CFO
COO the sea level we because it's I can
be pretty confident but people in this
room the network engineers in this room
know that ipv4 is running out at Erin
that's probably a safe assumption that
the CEOs for every company represented
in this room know that ipv4 is running
out
and what that means to their company so
some of these things are how do we
bridge that gap in communication between
those two levels of the company so here
again list of ISPs and talk about first
government as legitimating convener in
Belgium I talked about the example there
where the government several several
different ministries in the government
brought together the ISPs and and work
together Singapore I talked there they
also brought in and they did a lot of
training to among the private industry
and Slovenia Slovenia is we can
specifically look to that example as a
country where one particular person
young George went to the government and
said this is important to us as a
country and they said wow it sure is how
much money do you need and he said I
don't need money I need you to send some
invitations on letterhead CEOs of all
the Internet companies and bring them
into a meeting and ask them what their
plan is for ipv6 and therefore the CEOs
said what's ipv6 and had to go talk to
their engineers and say what's I I need
to have something to say what do I say
when I get there and so that helped them
bring have something to say and then
they all SAT together in a room and SAT
and looked at each other and those who
didn't have anything constructive to say
about ipv6 were a little bit embarrassed
and so then they kept having meetings
every six months where these companies
would get together and talk about their
plans for v6 and the ones who had
nothing to say we're kind of him you
know clearly by it that was a little bit
embarrassing for them so we also have
the rirs as policy entrepreneurs going
out to both be the national governments
and in some cases in many cases going to
the the local ISPs and the local
operators to talk about b6 deployment
lack nick has obviously the three cases
I have circled here are lack Nick cases
has done a bang-up job of reaching out
to companies throughout their region in
the case of i think it was bolivia in
particular they were going to have a
meeting of the ixp about forming an IXP
and they said well gee while we have the
right people in the room let's also talk
about ipv6 and so they were able to get
a lot of ipv6 allocations
made in that country and get a lot of
people concerned and thinking about what
their transition plan be having said
that you're the king you can decide how
much of an impact those particular cases
have had on overall ipv6 adoption among
is B so if it's the case and I'm not
certain that it is but if it's the case
that direct government and ends
partnership government practices aren't
the primary drivers of ipv6 what is what
has happened that has been the primary
thing where we can say that happens
therefore we have ipv6 adopt but we need
to look at what are the incentives that
drive people to enable ipv6 for their
companies and there are basically two
there's money and there's mystique so in
the first case the money tends to be
more money individual firms where
companies network operators whether it's
ISP or a web content or cloud or hosting
where those companies determine on their
own that they have financial incentives
for deploying ipv6 in other cases we
have but we're calling operational
epistemic communities and this is a term
that comes from older scientific bodies
and academic communities where the there
are bodies of knowledge sort of held by
a particular bodies in our case its
operational the epistemic communities
because of correspondents these are
communities that primarily take place
over mail well so a community that
primarily exists as a mailing list might
sound familiar and there might in fact
be some correlation between mailing list
operator communities and deployment of
v6 and we can point to specific
individuals who have affected change and
affected ipv6 policy changes as our ipv6
policy entrepreneurs so within an
epistemic with me within an operational
epistemic community we can what we can
say if you bring glue if you bring
knowledge to the community your prestige
increases the more information you
provide the more people ask you
questions and you can provide support
you gain prestige by doing that and in
some ways you could say that deploying
ipv6 gain
prestige and some of these community
what's the correlation here same list of
ISPs we look slike I forgot to circle
the 3a under next to United States so
six of the top seven countries for isp
deployment we can point to a single
company that is boyd ipv6 the incumbent
so in this case I'm going to go first to
Luxembourg Peru Norway Switzerland the
incumbent has deployed ipv6 for its own
reasons nobody told them they had to
there was no requirement that they do so
except for whatever reason somebody at
that company said we need to do v6 and
they did and the reason that these
countries are so high in the list is
that incumbent has a significant market
share so once one company the poi v6
that matter to the entire country in the
other cases United States and Germany
there is no single company that has
enormous market share and who alone
would move the needle but the country in
you know in the top ten but there's a
group of companies who have all deployed
v6 in the United States you know who
they are usual suspects they're all over
on all the list in Germany it's a couple
it's you know the major tellico
incumbents and several the cable
companies have all deployed v6 and
because they've all deployed b6 is
actually in aggregate a significant
chair of the sixth boy there so there's
no single company but each individual
company deployed for their own reasons
and this is the case even if we if we go
look at world ipv6 launch that was
coordinated but each of the companies
who participated had already begun their
v6 deployment so it looks like that's
non-us that there is they were doing if
their own reason in the other end ok so
these epistemic communities where do we
find strong epistemic communities in
Belgium I conventions with the ISP
community in the United States which is
you know I would say this is a very
strong operational epistemic community
the gain prestige by bringing clewd and
an odd people love to share with you
about your knowledge the Czech Republic
has a very strong operational
opportunity in the same way Singapore
kind of talked about there's a little
bit and Slovenia's so it's up to you i
let me go ahead and so it's up to you to
figure
out whether that has a strong
correlation or a less strong correlation
with success and finally there are
certain countries where we can point to
an individual and name him almost every
case it's him to say that person or
those couple of people have changed the
policies of their firms and other
communities to support ipv6 so we know
in Belgium it's Eric binka and splinter
van de Velde made significant change the
policy of the government to support ipv6
in the United States as many the same
people when you think ipv6 what do you
think of those the people I'm talking
about in Norway it was Ragnar at the at
the incumbent at the Czech Republic it
was Nick's easy and it's lavenia again
John George we know who these people are
it you can be that guy who makes a
difference in the policy of your firm
your network and even your community so
in summary since you asked Your Majesty
since you asked here's what you can do
there are direct things that you can do
you can require government services to
be available over v6 you can provide
incentives to industry requiring them or
provided in financial incentives to
deploy v6 you can work with industry at
to convene members of private enterprise
and talk about their v6 plans you can
look to your rirs as leaders in some
cases those are also by the way nirs and
part of what you need to be looking
towards if that's the way you're going
is closing that gap between the
technical people that those private
enterprises and their executive
leadership and finally you may want to
look for those charismatic these six
policy entrepreneurs those people who
can who have ped ability in their
operational epistemic communities and in
their firms and can make change from
within and those are determining the
firm's individual incentives looking at
the communities to provide support to
each other and and finding those
individuals who can bridge that gap so
what should you do well that's up to you
you are the supreme monarch it's it's
your country you can run it however you
want to I'm simply providing some
insights and what I've seen in other
countries but government's who are
desiring to foster ipv6 might want to
consider requiring these six or their
websites that seems like something
where there may well be a correlation
between web adoption and government
support you may want to coordinate with
industry representatives to lever to
leverage the kind of operational
community that supports each other in
deploying things and to provide a little
bit of incentive in terms of competition
and and prestige Borda point of view 6
you should also review your data
retention laws and your privacy laws so
our isp is required to or prohibited
from recording where people go where
their customers go to on the web is
there were privacy requirements about
addresses and about CGN logs our
websites required to log source port and
timestamp those those kinds of concerns
and of course the Belgium example of
competition is there available copies is
it possible for people to come to
compete in the appropriate address space
and then there's also some other
observations that we've that I've
mentioned countries with lot with very
high deployment rates tend to have one
or more large operators deploying
depending on where the market share sort
of falls out for a given country they
tend to have strong operational
communities like this one and I mean
generally national communities nano is
an exception and it's not a specifically
national community it is more it is
regional but it's a it's a strong region
and they tend to have that guy that that
policy entrepreneur who is promoting v6
and that's the person who gets things
done and that would be my call to you as
the monarch of door firm or your country
or your fantasy land is you can be the
person who makes that change within
whatever your sphere of influence can be
so I would be happy to take more
questions from you in your royal robes
or your tiara or whatever it became
thank you
ok
hello Tony Talbert comcast are there any
other examples of technology initiatives
that in the past or in the future that
you think this model might apply to but
that's that's a very interesting
question this all of this research has
been Jesse and I had put it into a paper
that we originally presented at T PRC a
research conference I forgot to include
the link the paper it's still it's a
working paper so there's more work to be
done on it and the data that it captures
is from a point in time roughly six
months ago I did update these numbers
for to reflect current data whether it
applies to other technology initiatives
would be sort of depends on the overall
policy model and probably recommend
reading Jesse's HP dissertation back
Doug Montgomery NIST at least in the US
government's case the policy is actually
much broader than that it includes all
publicly accessible internet-facing
services and having handheld that for
over a decade I can certainly tell you
that I think there is some deployment
that that policy inspired but one of the
biggest things that's a problem right
now is actually getting email services
up over ipv6 and the real problem there
is the infrastructure of reputation
services for lack of a better name that
modern you know anti-spam aunty fishing
systems rely on and I wonder if you have
any comment about ways forward with
those kind of technologies that you know
don't show up in any standards body but
seemed to be critical barriers to
deploying other services I would
definitely give you credit for being one
of those ipv6 policy entrepreneurs that
we were talking about i would also i
wish that i had a solution for spam I
don't it does seem to me that there are
certain assumptions that we can make may
be there may be assumptions that we can
make about buying reputation from one IP
address
two neighboring addresses so that now we
don't know how many addresses whether
it's a 64 or a 60 or a 56 or a 48 any
given case and there are things that we
can do there where maybe we can start
doing some correlation it requires more
CPU more horsepower to do those
computations I that's the direction that
I'm sort of thinking and I haven't
written a formal submission to mog to
say here's you know some things we ought
to do I've been sort of trying to work
with vendors to say well we make this
happen and in particular been trying to
work with my mail and system security
guys to say how can we fight spam and b6
one of the interesting things on eric
pincus data is which countries have high
levels of b6 deployment for email and
they tend to be countries where a lot of
companies are using google as their mail
provider hi my name is kristina chew i'm
with auntie T um you have a according to
your study Japan is ranked at number 12
but in the category it in the policy
category it is blank you know it has you
know ninety one two or three so I'm just
curious why do you have an explanation
to that it's a very bad explanation
which is I had a very hard time finding
an expert who could tell me about
Japanese policy around v6 deployment so
because I was unable to find somebody
who was fairly authoritative I just
didn't include a comparison of their
policies with regards to be six so i
would love to include more detail in
japan's policies because they have
provided some significant policy
leadership in the area okay and you know
since i work for entity i knew in the
mid 90s or early 90s you know the
Japanese government gave a great push
into ipv6 they want to be you know seen
as a leader in the ipv6 arena so you
know the reason entity become one of the
ISP launched a commercial ipv6 service
mainly because of the great push from
the Japanese government and another
thing you know I know you know based on
your ISP ranking all this Japan is
number 12 but you know if you look at
the Japanese infrastructure you know
there are earthquake alert system it is
purely ipv6 so an entity also have a
subsidiary is khoa hoc kirikiri TV which
also primary run on ipv6 and it is a
closed network so probably because you
didn't see it because it's a closed
Network so um in Japan des a tree you
know ipv6 is quite well developed
because of the strong government push
yeah that's that that's true from what i
understand and i absolutely agree with
you it's an it's a unique case because
of the private deployments of ipv6 where
and i should point out that the rankings
that i was showing were from eric pincus
data and he's using Google's data which
measures the number of hits that they
get over ipv6 compared to ipv4 so it's
entirely likely that the representation
of v6 deployment from Japan to Google is
is not representative it may well be
that Japanese users don't go to Google
as much because as they do to Japanese
oriented sites but thank you yes hi
Casey DCO verisign very interesting work
and data and and I look forward to the
link with the rest of the results and
and the ongoing work I was actually
going to address Doug's question that he
he raised just a minute ago so this is
in partial direction that back at the
last night ugh i presented some of the
work that we've been doing and kind of
passive measurement of smtp spam over
ipv6 and some of the correlation we were
doing with ipv4 known blacklisted hosts
and that's actually a work that's kind
of ongoing what we're trying to continue
to get participants where possible and
the ideas in a nutshell to actually look
at some of the ipv6 activity among known
blacklisted hosts by using correlation
activity but
tween the different attempts to send
spam so slightly off topic but in
related to the general discussion of
this deployment and hurdles that are
there blocking ipv6 deployment are
making it more difficult you remind me
that if I were monarch one of the things
that I would decree by rule is that all
crl and OCS be servers must support ipv6
that would be good so that we could
check whether their certificates are
valid based when you have a v6 only
existed yes Angelico google just off top
of my head when you get when you get
government involved which comes to
operator or company and say okay I want
you to support ipv6 it's quite possible
that we'll just deploy something let's
let's get quad a record for a web
service and let at answer to over to
pink for example yeah so I wonder if you
looked at any correlation between
government involvement and let's say
ipv6 brokenness level the data that I
remember on brokenness level is is way
down in the noise now compared to where
it used to be and I also had a caveat to
say that the when we looked at specific
policies they've been implemented I have
not adjusted for time so some of them
may be fairly recent policies that
haven't had time to take effect and I
don't know other than the China gates
where the Chinese government provided
incentives for isps to deploy a certain
number to deploy ipv6 to a certain
number of users it's almost impossible
for us to measure that outside of China
so it's very difficult to tell how much
success they have had and what the
quality of that success is I know that
from the the google data we see
fluctuations week-over-week from half a
percent to four percent and knowing what
the what the real level is is is almost
impossible to measure so I haven't been
able to do any kind of good correlation
of the quality of the point it's a very
interesting question though I'd be
thrilled to have suggestions on how to
adjust for that okay thank you all very
much
you