hey if Khan hey that's how I was
thinking engine song lights of my eyes
yeah
Oh what was inserted someone position as
a mother how a local John Hawkins
LaJolla I said Celia now and I see Tony
means this is open someone saw another
Patel also I think that's how you
accessorize ago which depends only been
young even get a definition consider the
Internet of Things IOT honeypot
assessing how good afternoon ladies and
gentlemen my name is Ken Xiang yeah I'm
from Malaysia yeah I'm a honeypot
hobbies which is I deploy honeypot at
home just for my personal pleasure
personal interest basis so today I'm
going to share a few what I have seen
for the past 18 months to 2 years right
now yeah so what I've seen for what's
happening on my honey pot yeah so far
for the next 30 minutes for the next 50
minutes we are going to explore three
different simple story so the first one
definitely I'd love to share a few about
let's try to explore together about some
of the Internet of Things new protocol
which is MQTT UPnP and definitely telnet
protocol okay
so the second thing so let's try to
explore together about how my honey pot
looks like and then are the third stuff
I love to show you a lot of interesting
story that happened on my honey pot I
promise to you I'm gonna share some of
the love story that I have in my honey
pot with me right botnets not only one
minute bonus but lots of me I mean right
botnets yeah so I promise last but not
least i only share some of the photos of
my honey pot so if I don't show you
about the photos don't let me go okay
yeah for me IRL teases about device to
device communication sensor to censor
communications
machine-to-machine communications i love
these pictures that are the most because
it actually conclude and symbolize all
the Internet of Things and what is that
so just a quick introduction about
myself my name is Ken Sean I'm from
Malaysia Omar Minaya are sick of fish on
Hornet I found a Luke Wilson Takayama a
Comic Con 21 so it's all parents - -
have one for peace and open
and on how their in-house and warm Oh
myself okay I'm part of the honey net
project which is how this project is
open source project that focusing lots
of honeypot technologies and cyber
deceptions capability self during my
free time I developed honeypot at home
involving some of the open source
development post such as dioneo Harry
Potter also two years back founder one
of the problems how can we deploy a
honeypot in the easiest way so
Christopher lake from Singapore and I
both of us we started one or two project
called honey pie what you and I can do
go to the website download one of the
image burned into the SD card boot in
the so called raspberry pie I guess
homemade pie and then you have your own
honeypot setup so we try to make this
process to be much simpler much easier
so every one of us can deploy a honeypot
now is this way then from time to time
give me my free time I'm part of this
hang in the box h-hi TV conference crew
yeah and then I have a lot of stickers
and postcard
so later just talk to me talk to me that
a you one is postcard you want this
sticker I'll pass it to you yeah because
uh next year we were having a hangar box
in a Singapore and in Amsterdam and in
Beijing as well yeah just a slightly
promotion yeah
story time treats back to year 2015 okay
I'm starting to explore about the IT
security and my approach is pretty
simple
why not we just create a honeypot put it
into the internet and then let's try to
observe what will happen to the honeypot
itself so this is the main idea that I
have in my back in a 2015 that's also
the early Union and then at a time I try
to study about the narrow protocol basis
we should look at an Internet of Things
protocol just a couple of Google and I
thought of this is a very interesting
fact in daily basis we browse website so
it is using SSL HTTPS but for internet
protocol they are much simpler compared
to the HTTP list about common protocol
we saw that
fundamental design of the IOT protocol
the first requirement it has to be
lightweight which is for example I have
one sensor are the sensor we put in the
train tunnel the trains pass by zoom and
then we've tried to calculate what are
the speed of this train yourself so this
result will be sent back to the
controller and then this result will be
sent through so-called 3G 4G so in in
this case the bandwidth consumption had
to be as low as possible so this is the
first criteria of the IOT protocol
design I mean that's why I learned the
second thing is about it has to be
reliable so in terms of the protocol
communication result it must have the so
called QoS which is the quality of
service yeah so I try to dive in further
and further then I found that oh I have
two candidates which is this through
protocol I'm going to implement this two
protocol into my honey pot yeah so these
two brocco be MQTT protocol and then
second one will be
UPnP protocol so let's try to learn
about this through protocol very quickly
so you may ask that you can Jung I've
never heard about this MQTT protocol but
in fact anyone's have Facebook
messengers on your phone anyone yeah I
think everyone have facebook messenger
on a phone the underlying protocol of
Facebook messengers is mqtt yeah if you
use Facebook messengers this is the one
that underlying enter part of the
application itself so it's time for MQ
telemetric protocol it's running from
port 183 this protocol is just simply
very lightweight and simple is running
with these so-called architecture
publish and subscribe
oh let's try to explore a bit about this
protocol so this program is very simple
compared to HTTPS SSL we have a lot of
certificates or a change but this one it
is you have a central broker which is
the mqtt at the center and then you have
a couple of different clients or
so-called sensor connect to the same
central Booker this subscribe to the
same topics okay for example topic 1 2 3
then someone as long as there's one
client try to publish the message
hey I'm here this message was a it was
just broadcast in to all the clients
connected the same broke yourself pretty
easy right yeah so I think right now
everyone is the MQTT expert so let's see
we thought about like protocol if this
is just a normal HTTP request you can
see that we have the get request hose
with a couple of our user agent and a
cookies of in terms of file size in
terms of alpaca size it will go out to
around 600 bytes of data or even 700
bytes of data but for MQTT yeah this is
the interesting one which is around 60
bytes of data and this is included all
the requests and response what are you
seeing on a screen is off it's just a
client try to publish a message call
hello to the topics sample topics so
pretty lightweight really slick switch
is only 60 70 bytes of data and the
broker will responds back with a few
bytes of our acknowledgments yeah so
this is how mq TV works
again now everyone is mqtt expert okay
so I'll move on to the second protocol
which let's try to make a quick one I
learned about this UPnP protocol yeah I
think a lot of us understand about this
protocol personally this is my favorite
because I loved about the concept that
zero network zero configuration
networking for example we have the
printer you got I can see okay fine I
got you on some channels oh and then the
printer the first thing you will do you
will try to assign this up with the IP
address by CP or statics IP the second
things the printer they will start
announce their shells such among the
same network who is my name neighbors
who is my friends who who else having
the UPnP protocol enable and what do you
do is uh you started and now himself hey
I'm pre I'm the printer who are you hey
I'm the printer who are you Scott and
someone can try to ask the printer the
printer is out to provide more
information such as watch the printer
versions was a firmware version
so these are all done through by so
Cody's Yuki and people go and after that
you proceed with the different phases
such as controlling and inventing I look
into this program because a two years
back rapid7 making one of the very
interesting research about UPnP proto
itself and then they found that for the
whole world
eighty-three millions of our eighty-one
millions of yuning IP address responding
to this i UPnP request which is they
have the UPnP pot enable over the
internet and then 23% of that consists
of one of the they are using those one
of vulnerable versions of the leap UPnP
and what we need to do if you are plan
to be a botnet we just need to will have
one single packet single UPnP request
and we are going to pawn that UPnP
devices so within a day or two you have
a botnet with 23 millions of nodes that
you have in your hand but again don't
tell anyone I show you how to be your
botnet because I just try to show you
about how to be a honeypot but I I'm
trying to study about it this is a
particle behavior so right now all of us
we have to protocol you know hand the
first thing is MQTT hope the second
thing that we have is the you PMI
protocol in our hand I'm going to
implement these two protocol into the
honey pot so the honey pot that I used
to is daya honeypot nori if not able to
remember this name the only honeypot
hisses I don't wanna die only hypothesis
so it's like a points how to say Samsung
hop in I'll do good no jelly it's
visible they all die onion that she
seduces Kapoor in so younger and then
for Daniel honeypot the best thing about
our honey honey pot it has a very
powerful
never a protocol emulation capability so
from Ford I only speak a lot of
languages for example he can speak SMB
protocol it can speak about HTTP FTP
MySQL even a voice over IP protocol yeah
and then what I did back in 2015 I
improved improve or I plucked two
different
protocol wishes and qtt and UPnP insight
in the diana honeypot so what I do let's
try to look at it together
so remember about the publish and
subscribes architecture in MQTT so what
I did is I change transform the ionian
honeypot to be the MQTT broker so these
are the guy who is standing in the
between I expect that all people will
try to connect to my honey pot yeah and
then they are going to publish some of
the message to my honey pot so my honey
pot would say yes I got it I got it for
you I got it then we will log everything
that has been published or any message
that connect to this a honey pot itself
so this is the main idea yeah I think
this protocol is pretty simple to
emulate it I try to add around 12 or 15
mq deep commands into it and then later
UPnP protocol this is much interesting I
decided to turn the ionian honeypot into
different devices we can choose the MP I
want to profile one profile to profile
tree and this profile will be for
example we can turn the only hydropower
to be a super micro IP MP devices yeah
just need to I need to change the
setting itself and what if we let's try
to turn the honeypot into a Samsung TV
yeah so let's try to tell the honey
points out to be a xbox360 so this is my
plan which is try to turn into a
different devices I'm gonna put in the
internet and try to see what you have
yeah I've been doing for the past 15
months and they are 18 months yeah
definitely right now we are gonna push
this to the Internet so this is back in
2015 but for 2016 this guy come into the
scene which is a mineral Barnett yeah I
was a lot of us know about mineral bonus
because definitely these guys had to
pawned
try to go into a loss of 150 thousand of
devices internal optical devices such as
home router
DVR machines and IP cameras and then
they will try to guess just a default
password 60d our default password once
they go into environment they will try
to plan the mirror I bought into that
personnel I love the best part of me I
born head is I I love the source code to
be to be open source any one of us can
be born again but don't tell anyone that
I keep sharing about how to be a
botanist you can download from the
github try to compare it and try to see
what we can have but the problem is for
me even the source code is a is a open
source but for me it took me more than a
week just try to calm poet so lesson
learn so forum in Urbana they have three
different components the first component
would be the scanner which is the one I
try to responsible for scanning the
whole internet finding the fall password
and they will pass it those passwords to
the second component which called loader
this loader guy they will try to load
all the things out of my payload into
the system itself into devices once the
pedal got executed they were connected a
so called a command and control server
so these are the three main component
but for me to me almost a week this is a
pretty embarrassing because I used to
build VM with just one gigabytes of RAM
inside I realized that my opponent don't
love this thing they want at least two
gigabytes of RAM in the VM so this is my
mistakes which is a solid embarrassing
next time if you would like to love to
be your own botnet or your own source
code so buy more RAM
yeah yeah
so Mary Burnett they're using lots of
town air protocol a lot of us know about
telnet protocol protocol but maybe two
things that you may not know about
Turner protocol which is so this program
is developed back in 1969 when Neil
Armstrong go up to the moon these guys
thought I mean
telnet start to be using and also we can
watch a Star Wars movie with tonette has
anyone doing it before watching Star
Wars we've done it protocol no all right
yeah so you can just Google or you
because a Google they have a very nice
tutorial so how you can wash down it how
you can watch our Star Wars by telling
it so the tutorial will tell you
okay right-click on a command prompt run
as administrator then type telnet inside
that copy and paste this URL and then
you press the enter and then you will
see the message coming in a long long
time ago from of a galaxy far far away
and then this is you can imagine the
sound I mean listen I mean I meet these
sounds all right I mean this is not in
the tonette but I mean what you can do
is how you can watch tonette Star Wars
Internet itself yeah so just now we have
MQTT and then we have a UPnP protocol
what I'm going to do right now I'm going
to run a telnet honeypot yeah I'm using
this honey pot called glutton the Latin
honey pot this is newly developed by the
honey honey night project this project
gotten it means that all eating so I
tied some window to Isengard and she's a
chance was a tons of queer Cancer Agency
for wins house I guess the trance degree
so it is that okay bees are on me that
she allows its and honey portal Canyon
what I do is just like this this guy
eating order hamburgers into into myself
yeah and you considered this concept is
pretty nice this honey pot will listen
on our report and then all the traffic's
will be handled by different handler for
example even enough for for three the
tonin is running on powerful tree this
honeypot will be able to handle it
because it will pass it on to the
different handler yeah I'm try to
improve this
telnet protocol in a gotten and
eventually this turn out to be a one of
very beautiful conversations or before
you know I bought net yeah I remembered
I'm trying to run got on honey pot and
within three minutes I got my first hit
which is a you know a botnets try
restart solid talk talk to me
so right now we have a honeypot setup
MQTT UPnP and then the toner protocol so
what we going to do
yeah we are just going to push it on the
Internet stay relaxed I was told by
someone that I need to put up pictures
of the cat photos in the hacker
conference because these cat photos
definitely will get everyone hi I don't
know get everyone excited yeah so let me
put another one all right so just a
disclaimer right here I know a lot of
security research company try to try to
deploy a lots of honeypot around the
world so some of them they have
thousands of honeypot around the walls
but for me I would have one in my room
just one this is one in my in my room my
wife are always complaining why you have
something always blinking at a corner no
this is my honey pot yeah so right now
I'm going to show you some of the story
that I have for the past 18 months about
my honey pot itself so let's try to go
through by different protocol which is
from MQTT then like next I'll explore
UPnP and about tonin yeah so for the
past 18 months for the past two years
it's pretty silent I only have around
600 or 700 requests that came in to my
to my room and try to talk to me in
mqtt language yeah sometimes pretty
quiet some days we'll have like 30
requests or less I'm pretty disappointed
when I sing this particular graph it's
all for me honey pot is meant to be
hacked if the honeypot is not God
there's no traffic inside honeypot or
there's no activities in a honeypot the
honeypot the source of is purpose
definitely so let's try to go into
further sorry what we what we see I saw
from a mqt deeper perspective the
honeypot will be able to do a
fingerprinting to see who are the one
who connecting to earth and then from
time to time you are seeing this guy
they are using some of the specifics our
client ID and then they were log in with
a username call now password call now
yeah it is pretty simple
I'm pretty disappointed I'm so sad when
I having this particular resource all
I'm thinking of oh
my honey pot filled so but when I try to
look at
the next protocol which is a UPnP
protocol I found that I found this very
beautiful attacks pictures let me shadow
you yeah so this is what I have I call
it this picture as a Malaysia KLCC twin
tower or you can see her two big spikes
yeah together or it could be to Taiwan
Ealing II like the guitar yo young good
Taiwan healing years ago
let's angle back for for at 18 months I
have 6.5 millions of connections try to
connect in my room well I'm not that
popular why you to keep connecting start
in my room it was six thousand or six
point five millions of requests yeah
these two spice happen during June last
year and also this one is happen in end
of December yeah so let's try to dive in
into what's happening in the December
timeframe yep mom I have three thousand
requests into my rooms in the daily
basis for at the end of 2017
so Happy New Year guys this is my this
is my new a gift three thousand requests
of UPnP always talk to my room in in
this year and of 2007 at year end of
2016 new eve of 2017
just a simple calculations I understand
it are there around to 200 or 300
requests in minutes per minute basis
into my room I love to explore about
what is the exact traffic's to fly when
you look at the green side eye catching
solar sun's angle you gotyou p.m. here
and I got naked young
Oh at a home so dirty soon as you said
this is what I have in my honey pot
itself so you can see side-by-side
comparison the first main differences is
about a h OST this particular hater the
normal one will be just have the hitch
as a capital letter but HF but what I
have received is a host:2 mudo star
Sierra Rose you guys actually Google is
our can it out is some more system or so
so I see someone say Oh what you Padre
she's got you PMP she's a second traffic
hazard lights she could put on
open-source lacing the like a deed also
I thought okay it's like get honey mint
Baracus alright only time to it has its
own DDoS attacks oh and then I see
another interesting thing is the host
usually supposed to be a broadcast
address such as two three nine two five
five two five five zero two five zero
but sometimes you'll see those kind of
specific IP address has been configured
into the UPM UPnP requests yeah so I
mean these ones some of the interesting
attacks are that I sing from UPI MQTT
and then from the UPnP perspective yeah
so ladies and gentlemen for the next
couple of minutes I'm going to share
with you about some of the love story
between my honey pot and Mirai botnets I
will invincible it's a musical society
and I think couselor
a caper cake on a suit honey pot can
knock a bonnet I see Leo come inside she
tell you are sorry to see all you all
right taro three horses Oh me I born to
hunt zillion apart how many payload case
unless Li Oh
so ladies and gentleman this is for
telnet protocol this is exactly the raw
locked for glutton honeypot so let me
show you if you just a simple quick
tricks or to read about this data quick
tips so you can see from the rowlocks
we understand who are the one who
connecting to us second things you will
see the log in with a username and
password and then they will perform some
of the further commands pay attention on
those lines that contain the word our
ecv receive these are the one these are
all the incoming commands that have been
i've been receiving from my honey pot so
in this case you can see after they log
in either use them call root password
five four three two one
then they will try to send me the
command called enable system shell and
then also slash bin slash these are be
visible busybox or me right so this is
just normal
mirai scanning face
because I just as I mentioned you know I
have three component the first orbiter
scanning the second would be a pillow
delivery and then that the table will be
the so called a command and control
channel so this is what happening in the
at the beginning so now number when I
think kusas you since a crisis oh this
is the first variant that I've seen what
are you seeing on the screen I try to
make everything highlighted in the green
color so everyone can see much clearly
so this is the exact sequence that from
coming from my opponent so once they log
into our to your two devices they were
hired to check if these devices is the
one that they are targeted with so they
will try to perform some checking for
example PS and Nuggets Ling PS causes a
cat slash peels prop slash MOU and yes
Wow
huh and then they will try to check here
for this folder is writable what they
will do is they will try to echo some of
the bytes data into /div /div on yeah
Mirai in a Japanese word I understand
this minion stand for future yeah and
then in this case they will try to
perform some of the random strings with
the word score II see CH I see CH I in
the invoice basis is itchy itchy itchy
itchy in the Japanese language is means
sexy or naughty yeah so I would believe
that these are this guy who creating
these up you know mineral bond it
definitely they are the big friend of
the enemy and maybe a big fan of
Japanese culture so in this case after
they have all these things they will try
to W get the secondary payloads we
should the main mineral botnet me right
payload from the loader result you can
see from the screen which is at the
table you get HTTP double clone slasher
is fifty nine one eight five two two
four one dot two slash bin me right um
so this is the first variant that I've
seen this is exactly the default
variants if you try to build the
holdings from the source code yeah and
then the second things this particular
version is a slightly smarter because
they understand that they will go
through the same thing which is very
login to the same system devices and
then they will perform
the PS command try to check out the
environmental but what do you do they
don't like the W get commands because
they understand that with the W get
command you are try to go to another
website to download something now maybe
this process can be easily block someone
can just get an IP address I will just
block the loader so in this case this me
right pillow delivery what we feel so
for this particular variants of poor net
they they use the echo these functions
they try to write a lots of our echo
bytes into particular file those
highlighted in the green color x7f 45 4
C 4 6 this is the magic header of the ER
fo yeah so we have a couple of commands
that continue on going on going and
eventually me right bunny will own the
box so yeah the top variants is pretty
interesting
I'm running a honeypot but someone's
always try to beginning on the June and
until July someone keeps calling me from
the in from the external network I just
try to be friendly if you me ripe on it
but why you are keeps calling me why
kill you are keeps speaking a root words
to me WTF yeah
so this is what I observed from my honey
pot I saw this guy always sending me a
message
WTF WTF WTF WTF what a friend yeah and
then what you will do is uh well while
they try to check if this folder is
writable they will try to copy /bin
stress echo file into the name the found
him called big pop I'm his opening song
all kinds and good luck guys Dickinson
saga yahiko-ya wrong so sing song face
and the face and read very much -
someone contends I'm mad so that's like
a honey pot you what you see are Tony
your son is the only medium this is like
a WTF WTF oh does a kind of odd also it
dances you father into Jetta pusing what
he runs out who's gonna Sukhoi its GUI
way so it's gotta move holy songs also
say Peron
from license eight shillings on a chizel
well your questions okay it's like
Google or something so it's all the
juices WTF cuz the time I look oh
startup UTF site Google as his
illegitimate son good saga so so so so
she analogy ago time is a sauna in
silencing bar so he was you eat well so
SUNY I was what you can current show a
big print she's with her single seokwon
since Emma what you part huh okay France
at Google tell it's all she saw watch a
hey it's about big mop and she said
hustle TC you got Skype ID she's a big
ball prime Jesus message Lee and see
that we took us away the lizard squats
DDoS services the way your internal call
my DDoS service of artistic retirement
or didn't even want Alba turn Lisa
Scott's back then they are famous before
a lot of DDoS
the us lots of gaming services and then
back then informally our formulation
viewers back there is a very sad story
about mh370 the missing plane until
today we still no able to find out but
this guy these are squats they claim to
be the one that they deface Malaysia
airline website and they put a page
called fall fall plane not foul I mean
it's sad because we are still trying to
find out the plane but you try to deface
the website and then you put in these
kind of sentences yeah so I got a
Facebook then I try to cook for go for a
Twitter oh these guys on Twitter as well
but uh just be careful don't follow this
guy just tired don't follow this guy you
can observe about what their activities
or what is the next DDoS services that
they are trying to perform with against
a loss of gaming system but don't try to
follow them so in this case is the Sun
house she saw a consolation system
inside DDoS bellezza nega nega gaming
and nuggets on could see tomorrow so
what is the man who won it so honey pots
came and okay in yes right all right so
what's all it's a good it's a good three
quick Horsell to get more holder to
authorities so it's a moment enzyme
morrow the honey pot in the cool so yeah
these are the third variants that I have
and then you have seen a very sexy
naughty beam right button and then you
have seen a very smart beautiful mirror
I born in we have seen a very rude you
know I botnets so I've seen this the
fault Bonin is this guy is pretty happy
because I what did what they would do is
they will try to write some fouls when
they try to test this foul is writable
they would test the right of our to
found him called /div ha Jiki Jiki
in the Japanese language it means go
crazy or happy yeah so I think this is
some of the characteristics that they
have and also they were used they will
love the would call PPP helper for the
default for the default
those are my opponent you will always
use a DVR helper but this guy did love
her PPP helper so the last one these are
the fifth one the love story that I have
my opponent is a pretty these guys are
pretty nasty and pretty stinky because
I'm from by looking at the W get way of
doing that the W get usually they will
try to download a UFO ERF or dot a are m
dot armv7 but in this case they download
a picture one dot jpg but this is not a
picture just a name yeah but I mean in
fact the file itself is still your FL
which is me right binary so we should
stay customer and that and that pupae
themselves these pictures will become a
random names which we call z XC v BN m
on on the device once they downloaded so
this is Z X C B and V is in fact is the
sequence of your keyboard so the kibo
have 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 9 10 Kirra brt
asdf and then this is the third row that
you have yeah so I think these
particular variants they are just pretty
sneaky and pretty nasty yeah definitely
as a honeypot levels we will just love
to collect all these our payload and
binary so that is delivered to us yeah
this is the resolve the love love the
love story definitely you can see a loss
of binary that's been collected and then
difference outside you can become a
small
- KB or vowels and even up and even
though they are you can have a much
bigger size around that to her a KB or
phallus definitely yeah Mira is so it's
not enough I don't know why we might try
to fall in love to my honey pots another
hot if another botnet falling in love to
my honey pot I saw so this is a last
story that that I going to show you
today
so while looking at all the mineral
bonus I feel I find on a botnet which is
a Hajji me Barnett I'll try to talk to
my honey pot and they are fighting to
each others I've seen this bonus since
the day one and running the talent honey
pots this particular protocol honey pot
since early this year
so I love to personally I'd like to
mention that this honey pot is the honey
pot the pawn all the single things in
just nine with my commands yeah
so what they will do is that they login
to your to the device with a username
password and then they will perform
checking for example they will use the
DD command try to write a 52 bytes of
data into into the DS how to check if
this folder is writable and then there
was this performant little you get and
get a additional payload within nine
commands boom the box is porn yep
but looking at this command but
interesting see happen is during May 27
from the top from a green those are the
initial versions of the hajiman bonnet
but then for me one started from a May
27 something is missing which is this
particular W gets command is gone so I'm
trying to compare these two together
what the hell what's happening but the
main things that happening this is very
slightly different which is the DD
command the initial one come on just
like wahoo Lehman like a dd- girdling
because it's without singing like a
variance command japonica quoi okay kid
not the other once they remove these
apparent Isis in fact bypass the loss of
detections of lots of open-source
honeypot available on the internet so I
think those guys they are reading
detection the Atari check if any one
started are detect them and then they
are try to modify
what you can do in terms of I'll try to
pipe try to get back on SS yeah after I
fix the code yeah we got have you get
back and I we have even more better
things which is a we noticed that a Haj
Amin borax start to use TFTP command
with a special sequence of the
configurate of the argument TFTP - l
that's our and that's G yeah so I showed
us love story about for my appointment
in my honey pot coming somewhat asking
much about having someone someone she
tell you are I hope and also comes in
each he said put the soup on and also
time in high school easy peasy Osceola
and also has its home women signaling
your summons associate he cotton
transient war house you guys and Jung's
echo no dance rep I'm here yeah or
sometimes they were they were just
support of what's called payloads yeah
and then I'm also sometime I sing what
the hell are you going to download the
file from 0.020 from VW get for my
perspective I think this is the mixed
miss configuration c2 which is maybe
when it has the bone itself but they
don't really configure about properly
with but they were leave it as default
0.000 but problem for me what I want is
she swept out oh it's operate Naga
consider this ones and garage young it
took upon and she's jaimé jaimé
configure how the English a thousand
easier so as promised I share about a
story that what I have what I seen for a
UPnP protocol MQTT and then the Tony
protocol I'm going to show you sometimes
all my pictures about for my honey pot I
solve yeah so this is the pictures that
I have from a honeypot our home yeah and
then I've won and yet I I grow my honey
pot from one to three so this is the
daytime this is the nighttime so this is
the daytime this is the nighttime
this is daytime this is at nighttime
yeah so if you like to play if a honey
pot are definite this is a couple of
links that you can try to play with yeah
just download
set it up yourself you can try about
this ordinary people gotten to go to the
political poutines how oh it's physical
honey pie
it's good some good seconds how many
pilots a good image oh yeah so this is
what I have for the day against I would
say that playing with honey pot is a
very good learning experience for me I'm
just a very simple setup I sing a lot of
different activities and those
activities is all my expectations I
don't owe me no you said okay come mean
I'm born at lies that somebody could
sing military to our whole Toronto
general it took us a week on staff is on
harnessing so she's won tonight easily
said phytolacca wait he's a tall carry
pot honey pots the castle son right
honey one thing things on the internet
took a Hulya once I mean she thought if
a thunderstorm or someone sitting on I
say someone pausing she needs almost
asleep and calm susana associate Mequon
how so
I believe that I just doing all these
things for my hobby basis it's not about
my work I deploy the holding into sat at
home so I believe that every one of us
can do even much much much better
compared to me yeah and let's try I just
do a simple promotion this is about a
hanger box conference next year we have
a hanger box conference in Amsterdam in
Singapore and for October next year we
have one in a Beijing so feel free to
join us so many topics if you'd like to
yeah and definitely talk to me so I'm
going to give you some of the stickers
postcard I have a lot in my back yeah so
just say hi and talk to me yeah I think
this is what I have for today I think
thank you very much thank you decon for
the photo opportunity
appreciate sees anyone
[Applause]
freedom inside again so now Takayama's
Monty Oum acai Fong from Shanghai
audiences yet territory uh Ling Wang
called jostle honey pot holders Mira yo
somos ssanghwa tea you know
Oh turn yourself well the ways I have
been looking shoe elements a machine
known as somebody once again wow that's
a big one okay
how nah woman Joe Titus mm Kui yeah
Dario don't know Wendy Dom okay tell
Jamie my dad oh hi joe dimaggio GA
mienai ha ha