hi guys thank you
or coming feel good about after lunch
my name is Vladimir I'm walking for
outcomes of the company based in in
Moscow Russia with about 25 people
working in not exactly they computer
security we're doing the computer
forensics for for over 20 years
first 5 or 6 years we are doing mostly
on mobile forensics and first two or
three years cloud forensics here is just
just one some of our customers I won't
make that presentation commercial don't
worry
today we're going to to talk about the
iCloud keychain first about the iCloud
in general in case if you if you don't
know what is that about the two
two-factor authentication a little bit
and then about the iCloud keychain how
it is implemented
internally and what are the risks of
storing your information in the iCloud
keychain how many of you are using
iCloud keychain no one really how many
of you use an iPhone but it's probably
less than than Android consent and
nobody is using iCloud kitchen really
it's extremely convenient feature but I
will tell a little bit about it later
let's start with with a smartphone
intense first I'm actually using the
smartphone much more than the computer
nowadays on even at home even though
yeah I have a notebook I have a desktop
computer but but I do maybe 2/3 of my
work from there from the smartphone
everything is in there I my corporate me
and my personal mail all my passwords
accounts to social networks pictures via
diction videos and and so on I also use
the iPad they of course connected to the
same Apple iCloud account everything is
synced between them
if
I can log on from from the iPad to my
office computer which is running
cleaners that I don't like at home I use
only wacky and and so that the
smartphone is actually an essential
storage of there's no private and
corporate information this quite a lot
of data is there including for example
the Gila location history even if you
disable almost all almost everything on
on Apple it's a little bit more safe
then on Android on Android if you
disable them location-tracking still
steal some data will be there on Apple
it is better but not much of the people
disable that because you want for
example geolocation tagging on only
pictures just just to save the history
assume what are the speaking of
forensics and and how to get access of
the data stored on the smartphone there
is quite a lot of whom methods exist
that's not only well table they work for
for other platforms as well as well for
Android phones the most comprehensive
method is JTAG or chip off anybody of
you is aware what is that that's
actually reading the memory chip from
the smartphone that's a destructive
method hg chip off when I remove the
chip from the smartphone put it into the
chip reader and extract all the data
from that because the data might be
encrypted jtech is a bit more safe
that's connecting to the special port on
there on the phone not all the phones
have have that port it's actually used
for debugging mostly but that way you
can also get all the data from there
there is also a physical acquisition
which is hot and which is not available
for latest iPhones for example there is
a logical acquisition method which which
is much much more simple basically it's
just creating a backup of the iPhone
and now that is a cloud tech position
method and it becomes more and more
popular just because a physical
acquisition doesn't work and for logical
acquisition doesn't provide all the
information the problems of cloud tech
position is that there are quite a lot
of different platforms the most popular
app from Apple Google and Microsoft
Microsoft that's not only about the
Microsoft phones or an account now
Windows 10 mobile but also about the
Windows desktop systems there also since
syncing quite a lot of data between your
computer and Microsoft cloud to get data
from there then then the major problem
is that you have to you have to have the
credentials or login and password end
and if the account is protected with
this with two-factor authentication you
have to to have the second factor as
well which can be a smartphone the token
SMS or something else
speaking of cloud there are several
acquisition methods available as well
the cloud may be just a storage like a
Dropbox or Google Drive
there are also backups in the cloud
especially for the app for iPhones for
Android that
backups and not so comprehensive and
don't contain all the data from the
phone and there is also a syncing method
when the date is is being synced across
the cloud and all the device is
connected to that cloud and the data
available from all those methods in is
sexually different in the set of data
mean a full device backups as I said
available only only for Apple and only
if you enable the the cloud cloud backup
which some of the people don't do
especially paranoic ones most of the
data is there but many of the
application
opt out making up their data into the
cloud and cloud backups over the iPhone
they also contain the the keychain the
kitchen is the most secure storage in
the hour separating systems because it
contains the most critical data such as
tokens encryption keys passwords and so
on even their grade cards and in cloud
backups this data is encrypted using
them our Hardware specific key so if you
restore from the cloud backup of
Apple iPhone to the other device all
those data store it in the keychain will
not be restored only part of retexture
have made the names of the records and
so on but it won't get your passwords
back there is no standard way to get the
backup out from the cloud above simply
doesn't offer such option so we have to
use the third-party software to download
backups we have introduced such software
I think three or four years ago and do
remember the celebrate the League of
celebrity for us involved two three
years ago know that at that time about
hundreds of iCloud accounts of
celebrities has been hacked through the
iCloud backups and the photo store at
there has been published then on some
forums and and and so on only after that
Apple enabled two-factor authentication
protection to iCloud the cups before
that I quote the cups were accessible
using just my cloud or Apple ID and
password
speaking coughs synced data on Apple and
there is a bit less information than
photo for Google Android devices Google
Android basically sync almost everything
there is there is also a backup but once
you restore the Android device and
connected to the same Google account
information is like
single back speaking of a pole that is
much less but still there is quite a lot
of interesting information especially
for forensics when investigating the
crime er whatever there is a call log
for example Apple actually never
published that information and never
tell told us that the locks are being
synced we have found that when when
exporting the data storage and iCloud
and there is no option on a only a phone
to disable singing of collogues there
are also media files if you enable the
iCloud photo library there is a health
data surprisingly which I think
shouldn't be stored in the cloud because
it's a critical there is also mail but
one which is cloud-based there are also
all your internet activities they also
synched apart from I think only the
search history from Safari is not being
synced what the history itself is there
is also some some other date like Apple
pay don't worry your credit card date is
not stored if you use Apple pay only
worth four digits and that's it home
devices that use the home kit the valid
data
well it is a storage for your boarding
passes tickets hotel reservations and
and so on so there is quite a lot there
is also information that it's not so
easily accessible if you go to Apple
website and check the document about the
law enforcement what information Apple
can provide way legal records you'll
find a full list what do they provide
and that includes for example all the
history of you put charges of music
applications and so on there are also
male lakhs and lakhs of iMessage and
first time there are no communications
themselves no chats Madras steel some
logs for example when you connect it and
send something and there is some of
deleted data about a half year ago we
have discovered that the files in iCloud
photo library and not being deleted even
after 30 days and store it actually
forever never will didn't officially
responded but in just a few days after
we have discovered that and released the
software to download the little files
they closed the whole and and now media
files store it only about two weeks that
is also available the list of all your
devices connected to the account you can
you can do that right from your
smartphone or your iPad and it details
about every device including the serial
number and so on
now let's so let's talk about the
kitchen the kitchen is is something
unique that there is no such thing in in
Windows operating system maybe that the
closest analogy is Windows registry but
the keychain is is more interesting it
contains he has the most critical
information the the passwords encryption
keys and and so on there are three types
of the keychain which are very close by
the structure and by encryption the one
is on the iOS device the second is in in
the Mac Mac OS operating system and also
the iCloud keychain and all those three
are connected and might be synced across
their devices on the iOS device there is
no way to to look what is inside the
keychain what the only thing you can do
it can create the local backups backup
in iTunes
that backup should be created with the
password otherwise the date in the
keychain is encrypted using the hardware
key but if it is encrypted with a user
supplied password you can decrypt
keychain and des create decrypt actually
some of the records from the kitchen not
all of them many applications use
another security class that doesn't
allow the items from the keychains
kitchen to be decrypted speaking of
Makos it is simpler to browse you can
you can click on any item in the
keychain and check the box total to you
supply the lagoon password and see the
contents of that keychain eating for
iCloud keychain there is absolutely no
way to view it until you sink the
yarmulkes computer with the keychain and
that that way you can browse the iCloud
keychain items that data being synced
and downloaded to do MA computer but
exactly the same way one by one records
if we compare the contents of the
kitchen store written in local backup in
in a cloud you'll find that they're
actually very close in the documentation
on the iCloud keychain on Apple website
it says that only some of the passwords
are being stored there like Wi-Fi
passwords passwords to mail accounts
passwords to websites and something else
but doesn't say anything about the
encryption keys about tokens and and so
on and the other thing that is not saved
in the iCloud keychain is they are of
the complete text here is how the
keychain looks like if you export it
into the XML file
the first example is so that the path up
to the Wi-Fi access point here is the
the peso to IMAP mail account and and
here is their the passer to to Gmail
account and there is not only the record
name the account name and the password
but also the date and time when this
record has been created
and when it has been updated this is
also critical for for forensic session
actually the resource credit card data
Stewart in the keychain also about the
same way there is card card whole domain
the the card number the expiration date
and just know the CVV code sorry there
are different protection classes of the
keychain and they just define basically
how secure that record is some of the
key chain items available for example
after the not just right after the
device is booted and turned on but after
it is unlocked with the passcode and
also there is a flag in the keychain
property that indicates how it should be
encrypted with a hardware key or with
the password and should it be synced to
the iCloud or not to break into records
in the local keychain you have to break
the password that cell phone on on the
backup itself it was reason relatively
easy in all the versions of iOS up to
our stem in I all stem 10.0 2.1 did
exactly
it was actually an epic fail from from
Apple they that was that the same hash
storage and the iCloud backup which is
relatively secure with ten thousand
iterations of sha
one but they also stored that the other
hash that was just single sha-256 and it
was extremely extremely fast to break
millions of passwords per second even on
the CPU not speaking of the GPU they
learnt the lesson from our report and
from release of our software and next
version in in 10.1 they removed that
that we cache and in version 10.2 of iOS
they extremely hardened and their
hashing and now the speed of peso
cracking on the CPU is only about five
or six passwords per minute not per
second and on the GPU on the first at
one available we can only get about
hundred passwords per second which is
also not much that means that the
passwords to iTunes backups are
[Applause]
extremely hard to pray I would say not
possible to break at all even if you
have a supercomputer you can break only
about maybe four or five characters
until four of course you use a very
simple password here is the MCOs kitchen
and I told you about you can see that
there are all the pairs all the
passwords all the items together
together under the login and just a
little bit lower there is an iCloud
actually that they can be viewed all
together or you can do only the cloud
teaching items of course after they have
been synced with the local computer
speaking code for iCloud protection in
general it is pretty good there is a
document on the Apple website describing
what algorithms are being used and the
algorithms are strong that the key
length is 128 or 256 also once someone
access your icloud account you receive
their own notification or on email and
after if you unsuccessful
them's trying for example to break the
password to your iCloud account then the
account will be locked by the way that
that's probably not a very good idea
because if you know someone else Apple
18 you can just try to log onto that
Apple ID with a few incorrect passports
and and his account will be locked and
he'll be out of singing after celebrate
three years ago Apple also protected the
iCloud because with two-factor
authentication actually at that time it
was to two-step verification which is
older and which is not so secure because
it mostly uses SMS and SMS can be
intercepted or no rockton there are some
ways to break into them with a to phone
you a two-factor authentication it's now
much stronger the only way to break into
account with two-factor authentication
naval of course if you don't have the
second factor such as device or SMS code
is to steal the authentication token
from the computer Mac or Windows that is
locked on into the same iCloud account
and using that token you can access all
the data in the iCloud well except the
iCloud keychain and there will be no
notification and no need for second
factor now when you log on to the
account protected with 2fa you'll get
immediately the an education on on all
of your connected devices and you even
get the map with a point from from where
the account is is trying to be to be
accessed speaking of the night cloud
keychain again it syncs it keeps and
synced quite a lot of passwords to two
websites to mail accounts to Wi-Fi it's
also stores their credit cards and the
technical implementation in
that it will actually blow your mind
it's really hot and multi-layer but
basically how it works
there is a special storage in the iCloud
that keeps all that iCloud passwords
there of course encrypted and that being
exchanged across their devices one
device is locked into iCloud it send a
notification message to the to the cloud
asking to provide with the new items or
if you add a new item to the local key
chain for example accessing the password
protected website that item in just 5 to
10 minutes is being uploaded to the
cloud keychain as well
and all other devices connected to the
to the account will will get that
password as well to set up iCloud
keychain without on the account without
two-factor authentication there will be
an option shown speaking the proof with
security code it's not from the from the
first look it's not really obvious what
is that and how it's actually protected
an account by default apple offers to
set the security code the same as the
pest code on the device itself but there
are also options available you can use
the random security code generated by
Apple you can create a strong security
code or you can not create the security
code at all at all and there is an
important thing about the creating the
security code and we'll show you why
with two-factor authentication this much
more simple once the two-factor
authentication is enabled there is
basically almost nothing else to do
there is no security code you'll just
get the device approved with a SMS sent
to the trusted phone number and that's
it
but there is one more thing
the new device is enrolled into the
iCloud keychain you will be asked for
the passcode of one of other devices
that are already connected to the same
iCloud account and iCloud keychain that
looks weird for example I have their
iPhone I made a setup for the iCloud
keychain there and then I trying to do
the same on the on the macbook for
example and macbook asks for the best
code of my phone that looks strange but
i will share what what it is for and now
i think starting from iOS 11 because
they I never seen that in I was 10 once
you connect the device to the account
without two-factor authentication you
you will always get the red mark there
it looks like it almost exactly as they
like when you eat of the health system
is available and it is reminding you to
set up the two-factor authentication
that's actually a good idea for the
iCloud keychain there are two modes - -
to work with there is a sync mode and
there is a recovery mode synced mode I
already told a little bit about it it is
about the exchanging the passwords and
credit card numbers and everything else
across their devices and between the
devices and the cloud and there is also
the recovery mode what it is for it is
phone in case if you you have lost for
example access to all your trusted
devices but still you want to get your
passwords back this methods works
seriously differently deep inside there
are different protocols different
encryption different keys and and
so everything else you can get basic
information on how it works from the our
security guide which is for some reason
is updated not immediately but after
they are released but about a half a
year later and but it still describes
that the the basics of that about the
keychain syncing it describes that such
thing like a circle of trust you
probably remember that the term from
from the well-known movie there is a
public key for the syncing identity and
there is a private key which is
impossible to break it uses elliptical
cryptography and all synced items I
encrypt it specifically for the device
so so the other device cannot get direct
access to to the item sync from the from
the other device fro for the kitchen
recovery
there is a special established escrow
service in the iCloud it is really
really secure but it works slightly
differently if you have that two-factor
authentication enabled and if you don't
have the two factor authentication
without two-factor authentication you
you probably remember at all about the
iCloud security code it is really really
important and if you do set iCloud
security code anyone then your iCloud
keychain items will be stored and
accessible by the escrow service if you
don't set the iCloud security code at
all
then the yo keychain will not be saved
and their iCloud it will be synced
directly across devices to be honest I
am not sure how it is implemented
exactly technically because it that that
is out of our reach you cannot go so
deep inside until the Apple services but
still there is no way to pull the items
out of the iCloud if
you don't have their iCloud security
cool set so if you if your paranoia can
think about accessing here now in cloud
keychain items by the three-letter
agencies the most safe configuration
seems to be without the factor
authentication surprisingly and without
that cloud security code the bad side of
that is if you lose access to your
trusted device for example just just
broken your phone or forgot its stone
you won't be able to to get your iCloud
keychain items back never in the
recovery mode that's a basic diagram how
it works explain it a little bit later
there is an escrow service there are no
much tails on that oh by the way Apple
also mentions that there is a special
hardware security model model somewhere
in the iCloud there is absolutely no
explanation what is that and it says
that after 10 and unsuccessful attempts
to breaking into it that all the data is
being securely or wiped believe it or
not I don't know here's how how it works
are you aware of kbecque term I'm not
sure it's widely used by by different
speaking of the kitchen in general not
only the iCloud keychain and it is also
available in the local items backups the
ok bag is actually the storage where
different encryption keys of any any
client is stored there is a key back
password which protects the access to
the key bag itself and the key bag
itself contains the keys used to to
encrypt the items in the iCloud keychain
here is the the the record of the iCloud
keychain items the the the first abayas
is the deviation indicating the
written the next hope bytes is a
protection class now also tell about
that and then the the the size of the
wrapped key and then the date itself
encrypted so again about the iCloud
security code I said that it is probably
the most safe method to to protect your
keychain from anyone else don't set the
security code and there are three
options available you can set the simple
code with just four or six digits they
can be complex security code that can
contain any characters and there is a
next item is device generated or random
security code you will have to remember
it and it is visually not possible to
remember 24 random characters you have
to write it down and another funny thing
is that if you use the simple complex
security code then in the iCloud it the
hash of that huge code is saved and
being used and if you use a device
generated security code then that code
itself is saved there so that was
probably thinking that it's secure
enough for every device that is enrolled
into the iCloud keychain the escrow
proxy has the record that looks like
kondo table I see DP and dot the device
here that that's a hash of the unique a
device ID ID and the contents of of that
record is randomly generated a backup
back password and it's used with the RFC
algorithms doing to encrypt the keys
from there from the kbecque the escrow
proxy as I said that it's not documented
how it works but what we have discovered
that it uses that secure remote
sort SRP protocol which is much safer
than the in general protocols we used
even for SSL connections it is
absolutely safe from when the middle
attacks in contrary with HTTPS and they
it doesn't need the passwords to be
transferred across an network even they
even the hash of the password and it
doesn't keep any critical information
such as password that cell phone on the
service so it it is based on the access
by by tokens the the most interesting
key keychain cloud keychain records
stored and the escrow service ah that's
a chrome Apple secure backup
it contains the backup back password and
it is being used for the full restore of
the of the O's who iCloud keychain and
there is also another types of Records
come Apple I CDP with a device hashed
out that about that it contains also the
backup back pass or bar but for
individual records for given devices and
and so that way we can recover note the
complete iCloud keychain but the
individual records of it if you don't
said that the factor of authentic now
authentication then the algorithms works
basically as that client I mean the
device general is the random 25
characters okay big key then it is with
the hashes generated with the 10,000 of
sha-256 from the a the iCloud security
code or the base coat of the device
there is no difference between them and
from that point of view then it is
encrypted with the using the hash as the
key and that encrypted cable key store
it in the escrow
there is a kind of API to walk with the
escrow proxy and it is used of course
only internally but Apple itself to
require the certificates to to add new
secure records you go get the list of
available records there to get the phone
number associated with the account or to
send a verification code there and some
other things to initialize to recover to
get the data back to update records when
the password has been changed to some
resource and so on
there are also some public records which
are more easily accessible without all
that all that stuff with a with
encryption keys some some device device
data the number of failed attempts
actually so we can get that one once you
log on and try to add the device to the
iCloud you know circle of trusted
devices and in some other data
another thing the iCloud keychain is
based on is a srp protocol version 6
to be Hohenstein I don't have a have an
idea what how it is different from the
previous session that that report is
actually the result of the work out of
large team of our researches and and so
even me after reading that don't
understand all the technical details the
entire deep inside but as I said by
analyzing the so-called public records
in the iCloud keychain we can understand
for example whether the iCloud security
code is set or not and if not we are out
of luck and we cannot get anything from
the iCloud and if that code is set we
can we can log on access to escrow proxy
which is used to for for syncing and for
recovery is based not on the
presser button access token and the
token is actually different from one
we've widely used to access the iCloud
the Cubs for example when we're going to
dry cloth from the muck of India's
computer so to get some of your data
synced between the computer and the
iCloud the token is generated and saved
locally and we can extract it the creep
and used to access the iCloud backup so
iCloud synched information but that is
not the talking to access the iCloud
backup now the token x4 for for iCloud
iCloud keychain as is called passport
equivalent token and it has a very short
time to live for security reasons only
five minutes and to get that token we
can't reverse that algorithms from till
till the end the new type of
authentication is being used code is
Reyes a in synced model everything looks
a little bit simpler but to to work
completely with sync mode you have to
add the trusted device to that Soho
that's not so easy
rather using the private API but that
will be immediately recognized by all
other devices you'll get an education
that some device is being added to the
trusted circle so it leaves that traces
but but still if you able to do that
you'll get full access to the key value
storage and all the items only in the
kitchen there are also such thing as
called Tom's that are actually encrypted
records of individual items that that
allows to work in a same mix it mode
between between synced sink and and
restore the over it more often ripping
the Tom's is
is really also hard and multi-layer you
first get the list of the
available from the Apple service you
find the record tidies you you get the
backup password for every record AG you
have to unwrap the key back key decrypt
the keys from the key back and and only
using that key get a get access to the
encrypted key chain items what are the
important parts of a out key chain first
- yes as I said the new authentication
that it was started - in MicroStation
10.10 but only the it's basic
implementation in mark MCOs 10.11 this
seriously improved there is also the the
thing called initiate data stored on the
computer once you add the computer to
the trusted trusted circle so it can
access the iCloud keychain and there is
a continuation token that is the most
most important key to all the data and
with that continuation token we just
actually hurt you - to access and to
decrypt but it is a reticle possible
from the computer you'll be able to
access the iCloud keychain and get all
the items from it without pain
notifications without need to know the
Apple ID and password and without the
second factor I think I have a little
bit time I will show a very quick demo
how the iCloud keychain as accessed I
have to supply the Apple ID and Passport
I will I will use my own our main
account it is protected with two-factor
authentication
but I already accessed that account from
that computer so I won't have to pass it
again but let me see whether in the
internet connection works yet is it will
take just a few seconds to access
and the net connection seems to be slow
okay so here I can select the list of
all trusted devices that's all the
devices connected to the same iCloud
account that have or had the iCloud
keychain enabled there but even after
removal of that device from the trusted
circle I still can use its passcode to
access the iCloud keychain so I'll
select say my iPad and its passcode I
select where to download and it also
takes just a just a few seconds oh
incorrect base code sorry
let's write in it's another interesting
thing about the incorrect attempts after
five incorrect attempts you icloud each
Oh No
what didn't get wrong
I think it's actually a program on the
internet connection but not anything
okay let's try with with the other
account which doesn't have that
two-factor authentication enabled but
here the iCloud security code set
now maybe someone accessed my iCloud
keychain already and change the passcode
okay when accessing the my cloud
keychain for the account that doesn't
have have the net factor authentication
set I will have to enter their called
security code first okay then the second
step is after entered the security code
I should receive an SMS from apple with
the SMS code yeah I got it download
let's see okay now it works we go to
explore backup and we have a different
categories of data extracted from the
iCloud keychain just as the Apple IDs
and passwords actually access that quite
a lot of different sample ID accounts
from from from my devices from different
purposes for example our corporate
developers account on Apple and and so
on and the passwords to them are stored
there I have over 40 network Wi-Fi
network passwords I have several mail
accounts that include our corporate
exchange account and my personal mail
there are passwords for websites almost
400 there are nine credit cards some of
them I exported and probably the most
interesting part is the the tokens you
can see you can recognize the tokens to
social network accounts for Facebook
Twitter Linkedin Adobe and some other
things in the Apple keychain
documentation there is nothing about
that actually it only tell us about the
passwords but not about
not about the tokens I'm really close to
the end some some some conclusions and
some risks at exercycle keychain you
cannot use just the sink or recovery
mode
they're both also will won't work well
for for accessing the data so what we
have used as a kind of mix of the sink
tant recovery mode so that's like
recovery but not for the whole kitchen
but for individual records you can of
course use a pure sink and there is also
no API but at least you you basically
know how to do that and how to add a new
device and get the password sink there
but that leaves quite a lot of traces
and notifications on there or all
connected accounts to access the
keychain
you need to have credentials Apple ID
and password you need to have access to
the trusted device or to receive an SMS
code if the account is has known to
factor out a cloud security code said
you cannot access it if it does have the
cuticle set you you have to know it and
also after that you will also have to
receive their the calls and send by SMS
if you still have the old account with a
legacy 2-step verification only account
it's not recommended to use it at all
it's not convenient not safe and
probably not secure it's now almost not
supported by Apple so I would recommend
you to change it to two-factor
authentication and if you are really
paranoid and don't want your data to be
even theoretically accessed by by
someone else it's the most secure way is
to have the account without two-factor
authentication but and without the cloud
security code set
but that way if if you pass or to be
leaked someone will be able to access
for example
become the only risk and which is not
explored yet if if someone get a
physical access to the mock computer
that is connected to the same iCloud
account and has their iCloud keychain
option turned on and still the
continuation token from it
but that's extremely hard to get to get
we're working on that for several months
and we weren't able to do that yet I'm
sure we will but we need some more time
and and and and finally the other
conclusions now they're cloud keychain
remember that it contains not only the
passwords but also the authentication
tokens and T for example your other
accounts for securing messengers for
social networks and so on are protected
with two-factor authentication and you
think you are safe but if you you you
you will get your device stolen almost
and someone will be able to break into
your iCloud keychain he will be able to
access all of your accounts you have to
change all the passwords and and enable
two-factor authentication again the
other interesting thing is that the
cloud keychain as we've found for
instantly in just about a week ago
seemed to be created in the cloud right
when you enable two-factor
authentication even you have you have no
single device with the iCloud keychain
enabled still the iCloud keychain is
there but it contains only the special
system case but no user passwords and it
also contains some some new special case
that I used in iOS 11 I cannot disclose
that information yet and we're still
exploring exploring that and probably
the the best way and the best advantage
of that approach accessing the iCloud
keychain is for the case when you cannot
for any reasons get access to the local
keychain for example when the devices
has the strong iTunes backup set
and you cannot perform the physical
acquisition and even if you manage to
break that iTunes password you will not
get all the records from there some for
example some of Sakura messengers like
Stella Graham they do store the excess
tokens and in the local keychain and but
you won't be able to decrypt them from
there only from their iCloud keychain
you can so that's it thank you
[Applause]
talent women in Tijuana kitchen at young
children our cantata you Nikken able to
instill to a kitchen table are not only
a total come to our target even continue
cousins what about you on a second
Toshio center now do only without out on
Kate Chancellor is shattered he wanted
to see me summon a second and publish
when she manages you do another I won't
even animal unit Arthur Thompson can't
yet