[Music]
all right
hello
welcome to circle city con
my name is
richard
and uh my name is adriel windley but you
can call me dre
yes so welcome to our talk about stories
from the trenches
uh a glimpse into msp stock life
as it says at the bottom of the very
beginning of this
of the slides uh a lot of the pains that
we're expressing are personally
ourselves
and not our employer
all right
so let me tell you a little bit of who i
am
i have a bachelor's degree in computer
science with a minor in mathematics
a master's in computer
information technology
a year experience as a tier 1 msp stock
analyst
2.5 years
as a tier 2 uh msp stock at the same
place
my current role is being a msp threat
intel analysts
at this current moment and there's my
certs
sweet
all right and
i have a bachelor's degree in computer
engineering technology
a minor in business administration a
master's degree in information
technology security management
and i have been in the sock for
a year and a half as a tier one
analyst and two and a half years
as a tier two analyst
and within the four years that i've been
in the sock i have served one year
as a subject matter expert for our indus
industrial control systems division
for some of our ics clients
and currently my current role is a mdr
threat investigator
so let me explain why we're kind of
giving this talk so
the key thing is
we kind of want to just
tell you guys things we wish we kind of
knew before we even
came into an msp sock or kind of like
our experiences within east sagin itself
so because of that we're going to be
talking about the technical skills we
learned
we're going to discuss like we're going
to mention the practical skills that we
utilize in our day-to-day work
as well as also providing advice that
we've learned both from our experience
as well as any mentors that we may have
had within the sock or from just various
different cons
so
let me tell you a little bit about my
first week
into
msp stock life
so in my case i actually came in with no
knowledge of networking or network
security
if you think that's strange because i
said i have a master's degree in
computer information technology well my
focus was actually more on host
forensics or like
mobile forensics also so i really didn't
know networking when i got in so i was
actually kind of
extremely worried
since
that's primarily what the sock was
focusing on at that time
and so
i went in completely nervous like no
search to my name even
and just went in
knocked on the door
for my first day
got in uh sat down asked around saying
why i kind of need to learn what i need
to know
and so
after a bit like a tier two actually
like said hey let's go
on a walk and just chat a bit and so we
actually chat a bit he told me about his
experiences how he went from retail
into uh analyst work and just how he
managed to grow
eventually
like a manager also came
afterwards
after the walk and actually tapping on
the shoulder too and said hey let's go
for a walk and kind of did the same
thing and i'm it was primary to view
like how i am as a person as well as
like engage my personality and how i'd
fit into the sock
and so for the entire first week
i was shadowing people and learning just
basic networking information
and
i was worried like because networking
has quite a bit of moving parts to it so
i was worried that if i didn't know
everything
i would not necessarily be able to be
competent enough to actually continue
working there much longer
so i actually worked very hard to kind
of like pick up every what everyone was
doing
and so by the end of the first week
after i managed to get access to a lot
of our tools i began doing the very
basic work that they had
all right so for me i came into the sock
with around about 15 years uh pr prior
rt experience as being a system
administrator
and i had one year at the previous
position before
uh working at my current employer as
uh working with an internal auditor that
we had
for we were checking vulnerabilities on
a windows 10 build
and they were going to use that windows
10 build
for a unit of computers
for
several people to use when they were
accessing a state
state grant state
state financials federal financials so
they want the machines to be uh
as vulnerable as as less
vulnerabilities as possible
and as secure as secure as i can make
them and the internal auditor could make
them as well and got a chance to use
tenable and nessus and that was really
my first
i guess you can say foot step or step
into
the security
realm
and then i use that of course plus my
previous experience and my education to
apply for a job at my current employer
and
i got on and
i came into the soc my first week
actually when i came into my interview
for the position i had suit and tie on
i was a little nervous and
i noticed then the culture shift from
my previous position to working in a
sock where you're working sometimes
you're working eight hours a day
sometimes you work 10 hours a day it
just all depends so
being comfortable
and
you know not having the the worry of
having to wear a suit and tie or be
quote unquote business casual that was
one of the first things i noticed after
i was hired and i came my first day
so i sat in a conference room with two
other new hires one came from houston
texas
and one was an internal hire who came
from a previous division
over to the sock
and the person who was from houston
texas we were both going to be working
in the ics realm as well as
being a sock analyst so ari came in with
a dual role mentality which was
pretty cool
and got a chance to read over
a lot of material and a lot of security
information
uh because they wanted to make sure that
out of the different documentations and
platforms i was going to be reading and
using and seeing customer data and such
that the highly confidential
confidential data and such that i
understood everything that i was going
to be viewing i had to sign a lot of
different papers which was
uh not a problem and i took the same
walk as richard with my uh supervisor
and we went on a walk he wanted to talk
to me about
my uh current uh my current mindset
where i want to be where i want to go
uh any questions i had about the role
and he told me a little bit about
himself as well and how he got from
where he was before he came into
being a site manager to
to to that point and
it was a very
enlightening and a good conversation to
kind of take the stress off when you're
about to start you know in a sock where
it's uh close close quarters when you're
right next to someone
in in an operations control uh
operations control environment so
came in uh watched a lot of videos about
uh the different platforms i was using
the division itself
and the work that i would be doing in
general
and
when i left my first week i went down to
the stock and started working and
lo and behold the first
case case work that i started to do was
with wannacry and that was when
the big wannacry outbreak happened
over a lot of virtual customers and
that was pretty much a
i hate to say shocked but i was a bit
surprised that the outbreak was
happening over so many customers and
you're talking dozens of cases are
coming in like per hour if not if not
more
so
i got a chance after the first week to
really get my feet wet and to really
dive in to
uh want to cry and and and what do who
what where when uh why why things were
happening and
that was
pretty much my first weekend in some so
all right let's get to the stories
so
i would like to talk first about
a
case that i had and
as you can see the picture is not as uh
alluring as you may think but this was
about a pecan duck and a hidden malware
so you see this peking duck here nice
pretty picture
the pecan duck is nicely glazed and
coated it looks very nice on a on a
plate on the table well
i actually had a case that was uh
similar to what you're seeing and i'll
explain more
so i received the case from one of our
customers
and i did my analysis and the the
picture came in as a phishing email so
i was able to grab the document grab the
file and
pull the file down and
put it into one of our evaluation tools
and take a look at it and
the file was a picture of a peking duck
it was nicely glazed
uh
cooked well like it was
uh you know somebody was just taking a
really good picture
of a duck that they cooked and it was on
a dinner table so nothing at first
glance was like telling me
that this is a malicious file a
malicious picture this jpeg is something
i should be worried about as a tier one
analyst
so
i did some investigating because the
picture was very small
but the
size of the picture
itself was several gigabytes so i was
noticing that it's unusually large
for
just a picture of it's a small picture
of a peking duck
cooked so
i went ahead and did some more analysis
and
they're different the different
platforms and software's that we use in
the sock that's one of the the cool
aspects of working where i work and i
got a chance to put it in one of our
evaluation tools and
i gotta i had a
glimpse into
okay this picture
has an embedded filing following it let
me take a closer look at this embedded
file and see what it is
come to find out that that file was
uh once it was decoded that file was
actually a trojan virus so
i alerted my shift lead and my shift
play was like okay wow this is
pretty cool stuff
so
i didn't know
at that point what i had discovered
it was until later i did more research
that me just taking that time to put
forth that effort to really just
find out and evaluate what this file is
that this actually was
a steganography and
if you don't know the goal of
stereography is pretty much to
keep people or or people like myself or
others of thinking that
a picture or a file
is something that it's not so
it's more or less a practice of hiding a
secret message
inside of something that really isn't
secret
so
if you if you really think about it for
example
if you know you go fishing with your
buddies or you take a picture with a
picture of your uh two-year-old a
two-year-old birthday party and you take
a picture and you send that out to
people
somebody's gonna pretty much open it up
and
they're not going to think anything of
it but
if you're a threat actor or a hacker
and you're trying to do this to entice
someone or use social engineering
this could really be a big deal so
uh the picture fortunately
was uh one was not opened uh but in
stereography once the picture is open or
the file is opened
and that picture or file is executed it
could be macros and excel anything
that gives that file the execution
command to run that system could have
been very very bad but
luckily for me
that file is not run it's not it's not
executed
the customer is able to go into the
email and of the of the of the employee
and go ahead and delete that email and
nothing came up we
also have to survive the scare
so this is a picture here of
a software that can be used called quick
stego and as you see on the left
you have this lady who's dressed in
business casual suit her laptop she's
working hard if you got that picture you
wouldn't think anything of it but if you
weren't expecting it it's a good idea
just to label it a spam or just delete
it and don't even worry about trying to
open it and see wow what what is this
picture who's sending it who sent this
to me because
the good thing about this picture as you
see from this example
this picture was embedded with the
sonnets by william shakespeare so
someone in this example was trying to
send someone some
shakespeare
information
about the sonnets so
you can put
if you know how to embed
files and you know how to embed uh uh
even malicious files malicious code
you can really either send somebody
something in secret
so nobody will see it or
you can really send somebody something
that can really damage their computer or
the network they're working on
so
for me
the lessons that i learned from all this
being
pretty much i was about uh i would say
within a year into
about my role in the stock was
anytime you have any data or files that
you're not sure about
always use your security appliances your
platforms your whatever software that
your employee has or maybe you have
yourself
and just submit them into some type of
evaluation tool
uh whatever you may have mcafee norton
on your computers um just see if you can
run just a quick check just to see
if what you're seeing if what you have
on your computer is malicious or not so
very good thing to do and
it's always very easy when you're
looking at something like a picture of a
peking duck nicely glazed and looks like
it's just ready just to eat
as something that you know this actually
could be harmless i wasn't expecting
this picture i have no idea who this
person is sending it to me so it's a
good idea to do your due diligence as
i've always said before and i apologize
uh
presentation
it's always the good job to do your due
diligence when you're handling a file
picture
uh excel document anything of any sort
that you're not expecting and even
sometimes a few arcs maybe if you are
expecting it but it doesn't come through
the same way that or the exact way that
you thought it may come through to you
it's still a good job just to do some
due diligence just to reach out and say
hey
is this what you sent because you just
never know
all right
so
let's go into a
situation i've been in before which i
like to call fishing for answers
so just to go over quickly what phishing
is in case nobody like in case some new
people within cyber security are
attending this talk
by definition from merriam-webster
phishing is a scam by which an internet
user is duped into revealing personal or
confidential information
which the scammer can use illicitly
what this kind of means is
any information that can be used to kind
of break into a network such as
your username and password maybe your
security questions
maybe your two-factor authentication
code or even your banking credentials
like all these can be kind of gathered
from
phishing and so this is why attackers
may use phishing or harvested
credentials from previous phishing
campaigns
into brinking into a network because
why would you not want to just open up
the
door when you have the key for it
so
in this situation i've been in like it
was just a normal work day
i was working on the queue
uh my co-worker was working on an
incident from the customer
where they detected a successful
phishing attack where the user actually
put in their credentials
luckily that user actually reported to
their security team hey i think this is
a phishing attack
and so they sent to us to kind of
further investigate for it for them
and so
while my coworker was doing that i was
just working the normal queue and i
actually picked up a
instant not necessarily related to
phishing at the time but rather a person
clicking on an email link
when i looked further into it it was
a microsoft
it was a microsoft
phishing attack and so i actually went
further in i began looking at wsa or web
security appliances or http logs and
just gathering up as much information as
i can to see how far in the phishing
attack they went
and i saw that
they pretty much put in all the key
information they the attacker would need
to actually log on to the customer's
network and then i realized wait a
minute this is for the same customer
a successful phishing attack
let me verify with the my co-worker that
this is the same incident
and so i reached out to him and actually
chat with him about it
and it turns out that yeah it was the
same exact thing however he was actually
having issues
just trying to trail down
how the phishing attack occurred
because they just gave him the username
and so he
looked through dns logs over the past 24
hours that involved the user
and he was just scratching his head
going like
where is the phishing domain
and he actually broke it down into two
lists
one where
it's the raw like every single dns query
that they did
every single domain they went to
and then he had a filtered one where he
removed things that he considered false
positives
and so
going through the filtered
domain lists i i didn't see the domain
and so i asked him hey is is this really
all you had
and it's like no i had i had some benign
ones too if if she really carries a look
like go ahead look he showed me that
list and i actually saw it fairly
quickly
and the reason why he marked it has been
nine was actually because the fact that
it was a sharepoint domain which
because sharepoint is a cloud
environment created by microsoft
a lot of customers use sharepoint
and in fact
that's where phishing is actually
heading more towards where they're using
cloud environments or cloud servers in
order to host
phishing attacks so that way
it's unlikely to be blocked by
enterprises since
nearly everyone uses the cloud at this
point
and so
i worked with him about that
gathered all the information we needed
we actually found an additional user too
that the customer did not know about
that actually put in all their
credentials so
we then said hey this user also did this
the same exact thing and
the next day we come back in and we
actually got kudos from the customers
because they didn't know so they
actually did the
normal phishing procedure of like
resetting their password and like
ensuring that they have two-factor
authentication turned on
and so
in this case like
the lessons that can be learned from
this is like sometimes a second set of
eyes is necessary like
a person may get like tunnel vision and
view it has to be this information
or they may not have like necessary
knowledge
to like further continue further on like
in my case i
have about three years of like looking
through fishing domains or
phishing attacks and just
understanding how phishing attacks work
and
seeing what domains they go on
uh
usually how they're successful and so
for me i'm a lot more familiar with it
whereas
he did not necessarily have the
information so
in my case like this extra information
came in for use and additionally like i
had
a advantage over him in the fact that
mines actually came with the email link
whereas he did not necessarily have that
and
working off all that like as i mentioned
communication between teammates is
important and even key at times since
that means that
we can all pull together our information
and knowledge as well as help each other
change
our perspectives on what we're working
on at that moment
all right well
i want to talk a bit about a
case that i had and
as you title you see the importance of
firmware updates
uh just give you all a
little bit of insight into
what i experienced and a bit of what i
was able to find out and
learn from this particular event
so a case came into our sock and
the case was just one that we received a
lot
in general from
our ics customers in icsq about
a
system that was accessed but
within our internal notes for our
customers we have particular systems
that are
uh i guess you can say
are a key part or
integral systems important systems that
are within the infrastructure
of the particular company so
it was one that if we
saw access to this system
and we saw particular systems that were
internal
that we would know that
more than likely it's just someone that
the engineer is on site or an
administrator that's accessing those
systems nothing to worry about but in
this particular case this was a system
that actually had an unknown
uh unknown id associated with this
access and
with the platform that we're using we're
able to also
do some investigation into the ip
address
and the mac address from this system so
uh the case was assigned to
analysis first and i uh it was escalated
to me so
i received the case did my due diligence
my investigations into the case and
ended up finding out that there was
indeed someone
who was trying to access
a particular important part of the
company's input the company's uh system
infrastructure this this system was very
important
but the access was coming from outside
of the company's network uh outside
coming in external internal so okay uh
good good good good job uh
of finding that now let's go ahead and
do some more some more digging so
the the system the customer security
administrator or engineer on site
learned that the the the external
person actor was trying to access
a integral part of the or rig's
uh systems and that was the driller's
chair
now i wasn't familiar with what
a driller's trail was let alone its
importance at this time so
i was kind of at the point of okay well
drill this chair sounds important
let's let me do some just some some
information gathering on my own and
luckily there the the the the access was
trying to be made from the outside but
it was blocked there wasn't a full
uh full access wasn't granted but
the problem that we had here with the
system was
this is the system that i was told from
the customer that they cannot take
offline or take down or find any
downtime to update the firmware so
a lot of a lot of systems when you think
about ics systems
a lot of these systems they do use
legacy systems
some some not not all the systems that
are within a
ics company are all old or older uh
legacy system systems with legacy
software but this particular one was
so
the fear was that someone could access
the system that didn't have the proper
update supply from the supply patch
management done anything
and they could really do some damage so
this here is a picture
that i just uh showing you of
a typical driller's chair now this is
not the one that i'm referring to that
was with the customer that
i i i work with but as you see
driller's chair looks very sleek looks
almost like a gamer's chair with the two
joysticks and
the two consoles that uh control a lot
of different things so
when you think of a driller's chair this
is a typical driller's chair
that uh
the the ics uh or rig companies have
so
i
fi i just came up with a definition just
to let you know what a driller's shirt
is and the drillers sit in a specially
designed chair
as you saw with the joysticks to control
drilling and pipe manipulation so
drilling
and pipe manipulation so think about
that if a attacker or
some type of threat or a hacker was able
to
get into one of these systems
they could possibly
i'm not going to say go as far as
control
the drilling and
the
the the whales that may be uh drilled
into but
there could there could be some damage
and the touch screens as you saw the
screens
they they allow for different automation
of the logging and
they keep records data interpretation
it's a lot of things that
the drillers chair controls so
when i when i say firmware updates and
updating systems
a lot of times as i told you it's hard
for customers to be able to take their
uh critical systems down
so
what we had to do pretty much was come
up with a downtime
a pacific time
quarterly or whenever the customer could
could do it to take the system down
and to apply
the necessary updates so
if there was another
another type of
trial or breach that was possibly about
to happen that we could at least make
sure this system was secure
that was the goal from that point on so
one thing that uh
i've been lucky to to have my get my
hands into is
the platform that we use was very good
with showing the alert and
the unknown id and
giving us the information that we could
use to perform
a investigation on this issue
and
because hackers themselves and anyone
trying to access these systems and you
see on the news with
these uh ransomware attacks that are
happening
all throughout the globe
it's just so much money that can be lost
it's some you talk about downtime yeah
uh if this that system were to have been
accessed somehow
that the downtime is going to be
very very uh it's going to be some some
maximum downtime there's going to be
some issues so
it's it it's one thing when
you think about the ics systems or
systems in general but for me being in a
sock i had a chance to actually
be you know
in the in the meetings and be with the
uh some of my uh peers and managers to
see
how how actors threat actors target one
of those systems how they target systems
how they scan how they
uh do have different techniques that
they use and
how for us
we use our different malware techniques
and and malware detection techniques and
the customer you know uses their uh
techniques as well to make sure these
systems are updated and secure so
for for for me with this case which was
a doozy
and i learned a lot from it it was it
was a
a very insightful case was
always make sure that your systems or
any systems are up to date with the most
recent firmware updates very very
important
and also because of this it was good to
see the customer take seriously
uh the preventive maintenance that
needed to be done and to also start to
schedule
downtime for critical systems
and
if possible
if this system were to have been
affected
the one thing that would have taken the
customer
uh down even with more downtime would
have been having to take that system off
the line
because anytime you have a malicious
connection of any type
it's it's really a good idea just to
pull that system offline
get it get it scanned get it cleaned up
uh replace the necessary parts if you
have to a hard drive or whatever and get
it back online as fast as you can
some customers can afford a downtime
still a good idea do the preventative
maintenance and you won't have that
issue happen in the future
all right
and now let us talk about the last
situation
in this uh
talk which is java the false positive
so just to make note
i was not the one who worked on this
instance however i heard about it and
actually investigated further in order
to actually determine
what how we can mitigate this issue in
the future
just because one of my biggest things is
you can always learn from mistakes
and improve upon them
and so in this case
we actually had a incident come in
for a zip file
and there were
a large amount of alerts generated for
it because the fact that it was seen on
hundreds of hosts
and so and anas
kind of
kind of investigated it and
looked into it and determined that it
was malicious
so because that he reached out to
the threat intel team about any new
campaigns involving the malware family
which was a
remote access trojan or
remote administrator tool depending on
how you want to
define it
but pretty much it's a tool it was a
malware that lets an attacker
access a host remotely
and so he believed it was that
and posted an associated file
of the zip file
within
the
within our team chat
and so the third intel team actually
researched into it and analyzed the file
and said like
the file he mentioned is malicious
like it is 100 it was 100 related with
the rats however
they looked further into it and saw that
the case he was working on
was benign the zip file was not related
to malware at all
however
the analyst insisted that it was
malicious and that
the intel team was wrong and that
actually caused an argument within
the team chat in fact it got bad enough
to where other analysts were actually
starting with the third intel team and
he was arguing against them too so it
was
getting pretty heated
and so what ended up happening was the
analyst
grabbed all the instance related to it
and sent it to the customer as a p2
now what that means is it was a priority
two case so it was a high priority case
for the customer to look into and work
on
when it's a p2 for us we actually call
and email the customer in order to
inform inform them that
hey this is very important you guys need
to look into this as fast as
possible and since the customer knows
how severe a priority 2 is
they actually began
getting worried and began asking us for
a lot more hunts
looking for potential compromises
uh command line arguments related to the
malware
and
we weren't finding anything
like
and in the end
what ended up happening was the customer
came back i'd say about a day or two
later
after we finished the hunt and they said
hey
it's benign
it was a part of a java update
don't worry about it and they resolved
the ticket
so
out of curiosity i talked to the last
analyst that worked on the incident and
he told me that
while he was trying with the customer
the customer said that they blocked it
and quarantined the file on their test
environment
and what ended up happening was it
crashed multiple servers within their
test environment
because of how important the
java is to their network
and so some of the lessons you can learn
from this
i even i've i've even learned from this
is that sometimes you don't
you can't always trust your security
vendors like they're not going to be
always correct you may need to do
further research yourself
analyze
if your tools are correctly detecting
malicious activity
and
pretty much
just use your experience
so you also want to try and trust the
judgment of your threat until team when
they give you like enough supporting
evidence to
say hey this is benign or hey this is
malicious
because remember
that that's their job like they've
they usually research into
similar threats
so they have
a good amount of knowledge on that
aspect
and
as a kudos to the customer
i am very happy that they had a separate
test environment which is why
i view that's always great to have a
test environment when it's possible
as you don't necessarily want your
production environment to be your test
environment since
in this case
if they did push it to their production
it would have perhaps their network
and
that would have been terrible for
business
and
another thing to learn is actually how
to backtrack statements well
because as i said before some of the
analysts disagree that it wasn't that it
was benign it wasn't malicious
and so when they were working that case
they kind of tried to change it from the
perspective of being malicious to being
suspicious
so
that's where it's very important to
learn this skill and
the final lesson is to understand that
everyone one makes mistakes
and so
one of the important things is to
understand that
mistakes happen like the biggest thing
is to kind of learn from them and move
on because we're human
we're expect to be
accurate almost 100 of the time but
we're not going to be
and so
that's where it's important to kind of
say hey
this is what i did wrong
so next time i'll try and not do that or
hey i see this person did this and it
got them the wrong information i'll try
this
and just
try and improve from mistakes and
then use them as a stepping stone to
move on
all right all right so to summarize our
experiences uh first thing i want to say
is
i'm not sure if you all notice but i'm
going to tell you
working in a sock is a
very very
unique
experience and i say this because
when you're in school or you're taking
uh you know classes for a certification
and such reading about uh stereography
or about these different uh my malware
families or threat types it's something
to read about it but it's actually
another thing to be
in an environment that you can actually
have hands-on experience working with
these type of uh cases with these type
of uh events that may come in uh seeing
it firsthand and
the soccer is a 24 7 365 day
uh journey i'd like to say because
this is going to be
a dull moment it's always going to be
some type of
find or
something's going to happen uh
and it's one of those things where you
as an analyst or an investigator even a
manager you get a chance to really have
that experience to intuit to see
how these different type of
uh things work as far as things that you
research you read about you went to
school about uh in for security for
information technology
it's like i guess you can say any other
job but
i've i've really had a dull moment in
the sock and
for me starting out
as a tier one when i had minimal
security knowledge and and now i'm i'm
in uh our uh mdr uh division
uh i've i've been very uh uh blessed and
lucky to
be able to experience and see a lot of
things that
uh i've only read about and the the
recent i said the recent ransomware
attacks that uh happen uh
different companies you know i work in
the ics division a subject matter expert
with uh one of our customers and just
having that outside knowledge being able
to apply it to oh yeah well actually
i've actually
worked in this space and i've actually
actually worked with
a possible driller chair infection
or having a
having a
outsider send a customer
a customer employee
a
picture when the picture had a trojan
virus embedded in the file actually uh
worked with that to have that experience
is invaluable
so
i want to say that richard uh you have
anything you want to add
i mean
i do agree that
mspsoc is a great way to learn a great
environment to learn in all honesty
because all these stories that we talk
about they they're from different
customers
so it gives you a good idea on
different networks
like different procedures
and just
different logs to work with
and so it tested your ability as an
analyst and allows you to
improve just off of
environments being different and what
information they provide you
and so i do understand like why some
people would like to stay in the stock
for a long period of time
so
personally like
i i could not continue to do it but it's
honestly
it was critical to my experience in
security
that's right i understand 100
so
uh if you i have any questions uh feel
free to reach out uh to us on twitter or
message us in discord
uh if you have if you think of anything
uh after the fact and uh i'd like to say
thank you all uh for tuning in and thank
you for your time