[Music]
hi everyone hopefully the sound is
working i hope everyone's doing well and
thank you for your patience let's dive
into this talk now
so today we're going to talk about
burnout the greatest start to your
organization security we've always
talked about burnout before the pandemic
but even during the pandemic we saw
so much burnout i think all of us went
through it at some point but let's be
real
with each other i think infosec
basically it runs on burnout and this is
a huge problem because burnout can lead
to a security situation so let's dive
into it
for those that don't know who i am my
name is chloe misragi i'm the co-founder
we open tech which is a group basically
of marginalized genders um and allies
that are trying to change uh how things
are in security and tech to bring gender
equality but we also provide a safe fun
supportive environment
um hacking is not a crime i'm also the
co-founder for that also known as hinak
and we're basically a grassroots
movement to try to get hacker rights
through changing the public perception
of what it is and who is a hacker
because we can't get rights unless we
change the public's mind um i'm also the
growth strategy consultant on the side
and advice columnist at security
boulevard so every friday i have an ask
chloe
column where i basically answer your
questions
and provide advice if you want to learn
anything else about me
please go visit standoutintech.com and
yes that is my handle at the top you can
find me on instagram on twitter linkedin
feel free to connect my dms are always
open
now let's get into the real reason why
you are here
does this seem like familiar to anyone
so this was rsa conference just last
year
and as you could tell the audience was
full of hope
and it was a it was like the starting of
a new year we hugged we shook hands we
attended events full of people we had
drinks and food together we leaned in to
hear each other at busy events we had to
speak extremely loud to be heard across
the table and we even attended karaoke
it was a glorious time
but then
all this happened
and then this happened
and since then
we've been like
this and now we are in 2021 and hoping
things will get better and it does look
like things on the horizon are but it's
still overwhelming because we never had
a moment to catch our breath nor we
never had a guide on how to deal with a
pandemic
and those that try to get therapy
sessions sometimes that was really hard
because there's a wait list and they're
still waiting to get help
so
let's be real with each other right now
we're walking a very fine line of just
being barely okay and terrible
and all of us have been dealing with
burnout well
not all of us
i'm looking at you new zealand lucky
people
but even in new zealand and everywhere
before 2020
in security we've known about burnett
and we have been
through it before all the chaos fell in
2020.
and with burnout we're placing ourselves
and organizations at a huge security
risk we'll most likely click a link
because we're not 100 who we are we may
not patch right or overwhelmed by what
is needed to be patched asap
but let's also be real sometimes we're
kind of seen as bots
and not humans and humans cannot handle
24 7 work because when we are
working all hours and always expected to
be on calls online how do we even
balance personal life and work life
because burnout occurs when we are not
practicing self-care
and when our work demands more from us
we spend less time on personal life and
the balancing is completely gone and
stress increases we feel guilty we we
struggle to sleep because we feel like
we're trying so hard not to drown
and you may even notice changes on your
own team such as like employees would
draw or
fast to become sad or angry or delays in
email response or projects this can be
seen even remote too you don't have to
be in person to notice when employees
are burned out let's be realistic
and right now working from home and
remotely has increased the number of
work hours increased expectations and
has really increased the blurriness of
work time and limits
because you want to let your manager
know that you're working
and we don't really have boundaries
anymore
and some of people have actually quit
because they can't juggle the work and
personal life and because their company
failed them please understand this you
didn't fail yourself your company failed
you
because they couldn't be more flexible
and they don't practice inclusion and
equity and you might be like wait chloe
why are you bringing inclusion equity in
this
but let's be real majority of the
workers that have left are marginalized
persons
and especially women because they've
been always been the person that has to
take care of the kids that has to
prioritize their personal life over
their work and this is a huge setback
for women later on when it comes to them
coming back to their work because of
that gap
so let's be really blunt right now
between you and i we haven't had a nine
to five job for ages it doesn't exist in
infosec and this is a really
contributing factor because employers
push employees to work from nine to five
and yet send emails and slack messages
and text message and call you before and
after hours this places you and your
team
at a very losing situation because they
feel obligated to respond and this is
why the burnout cycle continues
and for those who are not aware of what
burnout starts to form and look like it
could be that it used to take a few
minutes to respond to an email now it
takes an hour or so
you feel exhausted trapped maybe empty
you feel
like
you've pushed yourself to a breaking
point
where you no longer are coming up with
new ideas and not inventive but rather
taking meds to help with the aches
you're overly anxious over events and
deadlines you can easily cry or get
angry faster than usual you may not
respond to friends and family when they
call or text for some time and then this
guilt starts entering
your personal life is completely
slipping now you can feel it slipping
your life is now your work
and you start to feel unappreciated for
your work
at your work and then you become
resentful at your work
and then you end up hating and dreading
your job this is the moment you lose
your team members because what we've
been doing is putting employees at a
huge health risk don't believe me
think about it this way no matter how
much sleep you get you feel exhausted
when you're burned out and emotionally
depleted as well which then mimics
depression
you may even struggle with sleep such as
trouble falling asleep or staying asleep
and when we're stressed out our cortisol
increases and it gets so hard to shut
down our minds which causes us to toss
and turn and reduce deep sleep or even
gain enough rem and when we don't get
proper sleep stress levels increase
mental state can start shifting to
anxiety and depression symptoms
and when we're overly anxious or
experienced
depression
we start to get sick a little bit more
often have you ever caught yourself
suddenly you're getting colds more often
but the usual trends is gastrointestinal
issues headaches infections colds flus
cold sores rashes or irritated skin like
somehow your skin's getting more
irritated
and
the one thing to note is that stress
does lower your immune system
so when our immune system is low and
stress is high your joints and muscles
get stiff because your body is on
survival mode thinking that's a
perceived threat it can even turn into
muscle weakness and fatigue if left
untreated prolonged stress
it increases high blood pressure and
then we have to worry about heart
attacks and strokes because there's so
much adrenaline and cortisol over an
extended period
burnout is not a joke it's extremely
serious and we have a real problem in
our industry that's lean our colleagues
and ourselves into this situation
and for those that don't know the
difference between stress and burnout
i always use this as an example when
you're stressed you take a bubble bath
you'll feel better right
but when you're burned out you can take
all the bubble baths you can drink all
the glasses of wine you're not gonna
feel better
that's the difference
burnout happens when we have way too
much stress that has not been dealt with
so let's get real into
why we're still in this burnout trap
within infosec
and we're going to have to look at the
results of our industry because we have
a very interesting industry it's 24 7.
there's not too many industries like
that there's not too many jobs that are
like that but we have those
so here are some facts please note that
these facts were done and uh the
research was done before the pandemic
these numbers are probably much higher
than they are
but twenty one percent he says said that
they've taken a leave of absence because
of job-related stress 41 of csos took
this as a significant step even though
many responded being afraid to take sick
days and 35 percent neglected to take
all their allotted time off
because 48 ciso said that their work
stress has impacted their mental health
well 35
impacted their physical health
40 percent of cso said that their work
stress has impacted their relationships
with their families or children and 32
said it impacted their relationships
with their spouses or romantic partners
and 32 percent said it impacted their
relationship with their friends
23 percent said that they're using
medication or alcohol to manage stress
once again i want to point out these
numbers were done before the pandemic
please note it's probably way higher
than that now
and
when it comes to american cisos and uk
csos about 94 to 95 report that
they basically are working more than
their contracted hours on average 10
hours
more per week
in addition to 83 percent of the
american c-suite execs and 73 of uk
execs confirm that they do indeed expect
security teams to work longer
hours in other words we're expected to
work beyond normal work hours and we
don't get paid for that extra work hours
by the way as you are all aware of
but look the cso is a manager and also a
leader and having someone who's burned
out that leads can become dangerous to
employers security risk and increasing
possibilities and managerial
issues coping with such issues can lead
to them self-medicating on the job and
walk in a very thin line of what is
appropriate
but once again this is not a css fault
please understand that
it's a system that is very much broken
an industry that isn't sufficient in the
long run it is this industry that
continues to fail us and runs on people
being burned out
so let's take a moment here
we have a foundation that doesn't
empower anyone
we have a foundation that disempowers us
in every single way there's no wonder we
have a rotating door and a mental health
crisis in our industry and i'm about to
show you why it's like this
so why are we burned out let's talk
about this
well
by being the security we're monitoring
and operating 24 7 and sometimes we work
throughout the middle of the night
because we cannot sleep well because
we're always at the edge of our seat
when it comes to security because we
know attackers work all hours
and we are always worried when this
breach will occur because it will occur
because we all know if there was a
breach it would be ad hoc style to fix
it don't believe me
well according to the opponent institute
while secure response planning is slowly
improving the vast majority of
organizations surveyed 74 are still
reporting that their plans are either ad
hoc applied inconsistently or they have
absolutely no plans at all
additionally more than half 52 percent
of those with security response plans
said that they never reviewed it or had
no set time period of when to review it
or even testing those plans at any time
and with covet 19 and working from home
how many of these plants have been
updated
yeah this is one of the reasons why we
had a 300
increase of successful breeches
so what did we do we totally forget
about the human element
we throw tools at the problem because
it's so much easier think about it so
much easier to understand the human
element role that plays here
because it's easier for us to comprehend
if we throw more tools at it we'll fix
the problem it doesn't work like that
we're humans
and that does not sort anything out if
anything it makes the situation much
worse because when we add tools to it
guess what it's not in the plan and
coordination is completely off and these
third-party tools we have absolutely no
idea how secure they really are either
so this is really stressful i mean are
you stressed out now i mean perhaps your
crystal level is rising
no well then i want you to imagine a
situation
imagine you're part of a crew and you
just found out your cruise ship is
sinking
but you found that after for some time
because you were alerted by your system
your customers are bored trusting you
for their safety your team is scared
some are paralyzed by the fear of
failing
but you're trying
your best and they're trying their best
but there's a catch here okay your
entire team hasn't slept well and has
seasickness
so they're not exactly 100 state of mind
if anything you could say that they're
kind of
functioning at the same rate as someone
who is burned out
okay so you have the backstory here now
imagine the captain pulls out the safety
binder to know what is the protocol at
that moment unfortunately the binder
that was updated is not on your ship
you're using an old procedure but have
new features on this ship
are you stressed out now
because this is what it's like dealing
with bad plants and when the human
element is taken out it leaves you with
a wreckage
because the truth is
bad actors are everywhere
as you know they attack at all hours
and zero days drop often and we
constantly need to be up to date what
bad actors use that takes time and
energy and this is why we struggle we're
part of a crew and when we don't
function well or communicate well it
becomes a really scary situation
and the reason we're in security is
because we know how incredibly important
it is but we also need to come to terms
that if we work around the clock and
don't practice self-care or
we don't even promote employee wellness
what's the point of it all
because we can be in danger to the
organization as well if we're running on
low battery and feeling not well
and this is why burnout matters
this is why we keep turning
to tools to not find the time to plan
practice and self-care we become that
security team that syncs we won't be
able to fix a breach fast and it's
really really scary
and please don't turn around and blame
your employees if they're not performing
well because the majority of you that is
what happens you let the team member go
without checking to see what have you
done that has reduced their performance
because chances are they're burned out
and feeling very much alone
with kevin 19 we're taking care of
family members on camera daily unable to
leave our homes can't see our friends
and family some of us live alone some of
us put off our important time events
and we've lost people close to us
and our colleagues are struggling we're
worried about keeping a job we're
worried about affording the life we have
we're worried we may get covered we're
worried we may not make it through covid
and we're not a machine
we're human and the human element
created security and runs on security
so we're struggling with saying okay
before covet and during covet
except new zealand
so how can we lead like the prime
minister of new zealand let's think
about it
she worked with the people and planned
and she worked with specialists and
listened and took actions
because the reality is that when we plan
and take actions there's less disruption
when we listen to each other there's
less disruption
and that's what we're going to talk
about is how do you invest in that so
then we can do better
investment number one listen and take
action together
be strong be kind ask your team what
they need
don't just listen i want you to take
actions when we listen to each other and
strategize together on how to improve
the team or department it reduces the
stress because stress happens when we're
not being listened to or feel
uncomfortable to speak up
your colleagues by sharing that certain
tools aren't needed or that a there's
like this tool out there that just flag
things that all in one that is better
and they may share what is missing on
their team
perhaps less meetings are actually
needed let's be real we don't need an
hour meeting most of the time we only
need 15 minutes or sometimes we just
need an email
but by working together on what are the
issues we can collaborate together on
how to reduce issues or completely
resolve them
investment number two plan together
strategize together with collaboration
and listening working together with the
team to make strategies and revisit your
security response plan
make it up to date
revisit your plan every time a new tool
is removed or added team member change
environment change and so on by creating
making solid plants it helps speeds up
the recovery and reduces the stress when
a breach occurs because there's actually
a plan that's up to date
also you kind of owe it to yourselves
your colleagues your organization your
customers as well i mean look at what
new zealand did okay
they planned
they had 25 deaths we had over 560 000
deaths in the us because someone didn't
plan
or listen
or take actions
investment number three
encourage self-care
studies have shown that when dealing
with burnout taking one week off away
from work or anything related to work re
provides recovery for a burnout
if your employee is burned out make sure
that you feel support to take time off
also encourage it often to the team
because majority of employees and
security they're afraid to take time off
because they feel guilty for not being
there to help their colleagues
and or kind of also giving more work to
their colleagues as well or coming back
to a dumpster fire i feel like that's
like the number one thing is always the
worry of i'm gonna come back to a
dumpster fire
so if you can
if you're a manager give everyone one
day off a month for a mental health
break and lastly make sure you have one
day per week dedicated to having
absolutely zero meetings
i mean i mean it one day a week
this could be a monday this could be a
friday this allows your colleagues to
catch up on any items or projects you
don't need to have meetings every single
day have one day where there's no
meetings
investment number four be kind respect
boundaries
please be kind to one another because
from what we have learned when we work
together and understand how we impact
others we start practicing empathy
and empathy is certainly missing at
times in our industry i mean just
listening and being there for one
another is
it reminds us that there's people who
care for each other and because we
cannot assume how someone is doing by
the way that they look or their
performance we do not know what each
other is going through
so instead of going at someone
reframe
think up
before you speak or act i mean that on
twitter too you guys
because you really don't know how that
will impact the other person
and plus that's kind of like bullying
too so reframe yourself before you do
anything think it through before you
take action or speak
because
it's just important for us to be kind to
one another because if anything what we
have seen in the pandemic is that we are
so divided especially in the us it just
feels like we're such a divided country
right now
and it's hard
to
try to have a conversation with someone
who from another political party
and this is the thing we need to we need
to figure this out
because i don't think the politicians
are doing too much about that but it's
something to think about is that the one
thing i can talk about forever about the
pandemic is just the awareness that
we failed as humans to have empathy for
one another
we couldn't get and work things out to
try to make things better
and i think that's one of the things
that
uh reason why new zealand shared that be
kind
because that's the element we need to
stick together to protect the world you
know from darkness or security threats
but also from from ourselves
but we also know that being kind is
respecting boundaries especially at work
and you know of course
six feet distance and a mask
so what can you do
right now this could only take you about
10 to 15 minutes okay
so it's only going to take 10 to 15
minutes right now you can even take a
screenshot of this slide
and share it with everyone
because the reality is this is how you
can fix this really fast
one just set a weekly 101s for 15
minutes with each employee
what do you mean by that chloe well what
that means is that your manager does not
follow or micromanage you what happens
is that they have a 15-minute
meeting with you it doesn't even have to
be 15 minutes
where you basically are sharing
everything that you're working on and
with your manager so you all are on the
same page and what to prioritize this
helps reduce the stress level but also
allows you and your manager to have good
communication with one another
make monday or friday no meetings day
every week there should be a no meetings
day set for your team
and your department to be honest if you
can make it company-wide do it
monday or friday is always great because
it's always like a holiday so it doesn't
really affect you too much
now you also want to do is set up a
meeting with your team to explore ways
to improve together remember that
strategy session
that's what you need to do basically you
look over your plans
you also need to look over the tools
that you're using
and really think what is missing on the
team what can be improved on and this
should be about an hour meeting
but you should make sure that everyone
in your team participates and make sure
you ensure that everyone feels valid and
feels comfortable speaking up
i'm not going to tell you how to do that
that's something for you to research
something to google
but also you should create an anonymous
survey like one that is actually
anonymous because the thing that you
should know is that
insecure we're kind of paranoid and so
one of the things is that even if you do
create an anonymous survey we may think
that you may be trying to track us in
our opinions and thoughts and we're
worried about losing our job so it's
really important is to actually create
an anonymous survey and just have it
open where people can drop
um and and write comments or suggestions
the thing is is that we need to do
better when it comes to feedback a lot
of times when we give feedback to hr
they don't take initiatives or they'll
do like this kind of like half approach
of initiative or an action and that's
not
helpful
so the one of the things is that if you
are asking for people suggestions and
you're asking for advice you need to
listen and take actions
ignoring it is not going to do anything
by being a good manager if you are a
manager it's about
wanting to see your team members go
beyond you you are a mentor you are
their coach
you are supposed to provide directions
and you know help them through their
career
and so that's why it's really important
that we start owning that part
and lastly i want you all to remember
when we work together and listen to each
other magic does happen when we work
together making sure people get personal
time off without them fearing of taking
time
you know away
we're then becoming collaborative
and when we collaborate we reduce the
stressful items that hold back the team
from like really thriving
and when we focus on balancing work and
personal life for everyone that's when
we no longer have the dumpster fire
because burnout is a security concern
if we don't treat it
and it is uh something that we need to
treat
because we're all human and a human
element rules in the world that we live
in and whatever you do and whenever in
doubt just remember
if new zealand can plan well so can you
because in all of us there's a frodo
who's on a journey to get rid of a
malicious threat
so overview of this entire conversation
is burnout places you and your team at a
huge risk
collaborate to form strategies to
improve the team that's what you should
be doing right now start making plans
and revisit your security response plans
if you have them making sure that
they're on point
and up to date is really important and
promote self-care by being kind and
respectful to boundaries that means
if you need to get a hold of an employee
and it's not urgent send an email and
remind your employees that when you send
emails it's not urgent
that when it is urgent it should be a
text message this is something that is
really important that we practice that
means also slack don't be using slack
after work hours and we also have to
enforce those boundaries as well
because if we are not balancing our work
life and our personal life we become our
job and then we lose who we are i think
that's a lot of reasons why we get
burned out
because we forget that we're more than
just our job
so i just want to say thank you guys so
much for having me um
and you know i'm here to answer any
questions that you have and once again
thank you to the conference for having
me i try to wrap this up a little bit
faster because i didn't know how much
more time that i would have but i do
know that usually this talk does
bring a bunch of questions so i'm happy
to answer any questions and if you are
uncomfortable asking any questions feel
free to dm me on discord or on twitter
instagram and linkedin my dms are always
open and thank you all for existing
i'm going to stop sharing my screen
all right
um
let's do this i see some questions
coming in
so let's do this all right ray asked a
question which is can i put an out of
office alert on my email all the time
not just one out of the office or is
that a bit much this is a great question
you want to know how i deal with this is
that i use like account i block my
mondays and fridays so no one can book
meetings
period and the reason i do that is that
i
want people to know that those are my
days to pick and choose whether or not i
have a meeting or whatnot
now if you are going to take time off
it's really important that you know talk
to your manager about it make sure your
team is all okay on it
but when you take that time off so if
you are burned out the only way to help
reset that is by taking time off and i
usually recommend about a week
if you have a more severe case taking
two weeks off is
pretty good
so having one week is kind of like a
quick refresher um but when you do take
off that week make sure that you
like turn off all devices don't check
your work email don't do anything on
social media literally take a week off
from social media because social media
is also contributing factor of your
mental health sometimes so it's
important for us to reset that by
disconnecting to reconnect with
ourselves so that means like not doing
anything infosec that means when you're
taking that week off that means not
studying for anything or learning the
latest technique or tools like just
don't take that week to like learn how
to play the guitar or something or learn
how to paint
um that's really important for you to do
now when you do take that time off make
sure that in your your calendar that you
when the day you come back is blocked
off so no one can set meetings so right
when you start
um i mean right when you are setting
your calendar invite for going out of
office make sure you give yourself an
extra day so say for example if you're
coming back on the 23rd say that you're
coming back on the 24th in your email
and this is a way for people not to
expect a fast response giving you a
couple days of catching up
um but also that when you come back to
work you're gonna be fly with an inbox
it's also important to let your
colleagues know that you're not gonna be
able to look and go backtrack and slack
that they should see you in every email
that's something about your
responsibility or your duties for your
role
and you'll be able to then know what to
prioritize when you get back because
you're going to come back to a flooded
inbox let's be real
and in this you'll be able to go through
on the day when you get back now the
other thing you should do is send an
email to your entire team members asking
them you know right after like an hour
two you've gone back and you're in your
inbox
asking
what is needed within the next 24 hours
is there anything that needs to be a
high priority
this is good for you to know right when
you come back so you know what you need
to work on and and then the emails can
wait but you want to try to generally
catch up on your emails within the first
two days of coming back so that gives
you some clean way of not having any
needs on the first day but also making
sure that no one has expectations that
you're not going to respond to any
emails until the day after you get back
so those are some good tricks to learn
um let's see what other questions do we
have
um
okay
when you
do go on vacation
how do you get others to respect it and
not load you up with tons more tasks
when you reach it
i love this one um okay so
one thing to note is that there's a huge
chance you're going to return to a
dumpster fire
because that's just how security is so
the one thing is that when you're caught
up and you've had like that week of like
detoxing from everything
um
you feel better like you can actually
handle things and so when you get more
tasks when you get back you'll actually
be able to handle it mentally a lot
better
because when you're burned out you can
just push things all the time like
deadlines
give yourself extensions
and sometimes it takes you like an hour
to complete a project when in reality it
used to take you like 10 minutes to
probably complete that project so you're
going to work a lot faster so it's not
going to impact you as much
but also to note like
once again to do what i kind of shared
about when you're taking time off how to
do it in a way where it actually helps
you a lot or gives you about you know
two days of being able to catch up
that's going to help you a lot to do
some stuff like that it does reduce the
anxiety and the anxiousness
um what other questions do we get here
um okay um any thoughts on handling
working hours with the international
team
so
one of the things that i would say is
that when you're dealing with different
time zones it's important to actually
recognize who's on what time zone this
is one of the reasons why i'm not the
biggest fan of slack sometimes because
people tend to message off hours
so what would be a cool idea that you
can do is to talk with your team members
to find out what times that they
actually work i know that sounds really
strange but the reality is not all of us
are
early morning birds i don't remember the
word for that but
um we're not all very early um some of
us actually are more like night owls we
prefer to work more at night because we
feel more creative at night so one thing
that i always talk about is that i feel
like companies can do a better job by
having more flexibility with ours like
having that set time for everyone just
puts everyone into a huge bucket and
that doesn't work
um so one of the things is to
acknowledge this problem the other thing
is to just look at on what hours work
best for everyone
so finding there might be a sweet spot
that there's two hours every day that
everyone on your teams no matter where
they're located is the best that's the
best time to set up those group calls
and remind people that if they need to
have a whole team meeting that these are
the two hours every single day during
the week that works the best
i think that's really helpful
but yeah also you know you can add time
zones to calendars that also helps
a lot
what other questions do we get
how does self-study come into play when
trying to maintain a work and life
balance
this is a great question um i myself i
am a constant learner so i am taking
courses always i'm always wanting to
learn something new
but i have to admit sometimes i dread it
and because i don't have the energy or
i'm not passionate enough about it but i
also know i want to do these things
so i think it has a lot to do with
balancing your work and personal life
but the other thing is that when we're
burned out it's very hard that even when
it's after work hours to be able to
focus on something and we may actually
have like kind of convinced ourselves
that to be able to disconnect from the
world is to watch tv or watch movies or
play video games and that's not
necessarily true um in a sense that you
know
we have to kind of change that mentality
a little bit so say for example what you
can do is you know watch an episode of
tv
and then reward yourself
i will not reward yourself but to read a
chapter in your book or whatnot and then
uh reward yourself with another tv show
this is one way how to do it um and this
is actually a really helpful approach if
you are someone who has problems
focusing for long periods of time
is to do kind of one hour block so one
hour you focus on one area the next hour
you focus on a different area and then
so on um especially if you're one of
those people that hyper focuses um
when you're passionate about things and
only when you're passionate about things
usually when we're studying we're not
always a hundred percent passionate
about it so it's really good is to kind
of like focus on studying for one hour
take a break for one hour and go back to
staying for an hour or study something
new in your book that kind of like off
and on kind of thing it does help if you
can't hyper focus on one thing for a
period of time
um
all right
how do i get through my thick skull that
burnout is real and i'm not immune and i
tend to be worse about it than my
employer
this is a great question because for the
longest time i always thought that my
personality is that like
that i could just keep going and going
and going and what ended up happening
was that for two and a half years i
didn't take a single day off
i made it not a single day off for two
and a half years and i was going to
conferences i was going on weekends to
conferences i would go to three
conferences in a week and fly across the
world to do these things and i just
thought that i was immune to it as well
but not really immune i just knew that i
just need to catch up on sleep at some
point
um but it does catch up on you and when
it does catch up on you it kind of feels
like it's overnight sometimes or it just
sneaks up on you or you suddenly realize
oh my god
maybe i've been distracting myself this
entire time and i've been burned out
and i've been
like trying to you know
pretend i'm not one of those people
that's burnt out but i totally am so i
mean the thing is is that
it's really important is to understand
that when you are not having
self-awareness of how you're feeling and
dealing with situations you're going to
have these type of problems
and no one is immune to this i'm going
to be honest every single person has
been burned at at some point in the past
year
um and many of us are still burned out
right now so just think about it that
way is that no one is immune to it if
anything you will have burnout at some
point and this pandemic really shows
that just note that like you have to be
understanding of your symptoms so like
journaling once in a while really helps
understand what's going on so if you
ever feel trapped that's one thing
if you feel empty that's another thing
if you're feeling overly anxious or
you're feeling sad frequently or angry
frequently that's something to
understand
if you're having
problems falling asleep or staying
asleep the whole night
these are some signs
the other sign is i've noticed that
when you drink extra caffeine so for
example if i'm drinking more than one
cup of tea a day
that's letting me know i'm starting to
go into burnout
and this is actually very common we tend
to reach for caffeine to like keep us
going because we feel so exhausted
and it may be a temporary trick but it's
not actually working as well as you
think it is
um the other thing is to acknowledge if
you're drinking more this is another
thing to notice um is that for example
if you're drinking every single day even
just a glass of wine or a beer a day
you need to acknowledge that
that's going to be a bad thing you don't
want to create a routine of drinking
every single day even if it's just one
drink
that's something to be aware of a lot of
times where when we're stressed or
burned out
you know we'll use marijuana more often
will drink more often and these are
things of escaping in a sense so we have
to also recognize that also by eating
you'll be you know whenever we stress
we'll either reach for like the junk
food we always reach for the junk food
and so like you'll crave something
that's salty or sweet we don't care
about our health as much and that's
another thing so when we're not
appreciating who we are and not
balancing that that's going to be a huge
problem
but yes everyone gets burned out you're
most likely you could be burned out
right now it's just been recognizing
that and understanding that these little
things do add up
uh
why did you decide to give this talk
what was your inspiration what made you
want to give this talk
um so before the pandemic happened
um
yeah like literally that year i
basically was realizing that a lot of
people in the hacker community
kept saying that they're burned out or
they're tired or they feel trapped or
they feel unappreciated and it really
acknowledged that we have a mental
health problem in our industry and our
employers are not caring
about it so i actually was on a panel uh
with mental health hackers um at besides
sf
uh
in 2020 actually and we talked about
this and i realized that okay we need to
have an actual talk just on burnout
because i'm afraid that if we have a
pandemic we're going to get really
really bad here
and when the pandemic hit that's when i
recognized okay i need to start creating
some talks around burnout
because that's really important for us
to do
and so basically that's what i did i
kind of created this
this talk about how you can
work with having burnout how you reduce
burnout how do you fight burnout how to
recognize burnout so i started giving
that talk last year and then i also
realized that
i'm not going to fix
things in a big way unless i start
talking about how this industry it just
makes it
happen over and over and over again and
we're not solving it we're just talking
about it but we never take action and so
i want this talk to be like that i want
us to have these conversations i want to
open that door for us to have
conversations on how do we improve this
industry that was created in a way to
cause burnout
so that's why i created this talk
i think that's all the time that we have
for for q and a like
um within here i'm not quite sure i'm
just gonna double check
um
but yeah so i just wanted to let you all
know that i'll be in here but i think i
need to wrap up because i know there's
gonna be another talk coming soon
but if you guys have any questions at
all feel free to reach out my dms are
open and thank you all for attending
this talk and you know
i really hope to see everyone in person
some point soon
and yeah thank you everyone
i'm going to close out of zoom now