[Music]
hello everyone thanks for coming
i'm alex freelos and i'm joined by my
colleague here jack butler
and we're presenting on covet 19 tracing
apps the proliferation of rush
development
now a little bit about ourselves
i'm uh currently a director at fortune
500 company
directing a penetration testing team
i'd like to consider myself technical as
well as managerial
some of my interests lie in web
application testing aviation testing and
just enjoying the outdoors
and my name is john butler i'm a mobile
application security specialist and i
have a strong background in the
prevention of reverse engineering of
mobile applications i currently work as
a security specialist for a leading firm
in the mobile application security space
named guard square and much of the
research
and the takeaways that we're presenting
on here today were conducted alongside
my peers uh and as part of my daily
duties at guard square
now to get things kicked off we're going
to provide a brief overview of what we
hope to accomplish during today's
conversation and to give you a bit more
context regarding the analysis we
performed and the findings we've made as
a result
to do this
i would like to give you a little bit
more of a backdrop
starting with the purpose of today's
conversation which is kobit 19 contact
tracing applications now for anybody
unfamiliar with what a contact tracing
application does or what the purpose of
a contact tracing app is it's very
simple a contact tracing application is
simply designed in order to trace
individuals using the application
and alert individuals of potential
exposures to cobit 19 virus so if i come
in the proximity of another user who has
tested positive for covet 19 i will then
receive a notification so that i can go
get tested myself as well
now
as part of today's conversation we're
going to provide a clear timeline of
events so that you can understand not
only the analysis that we performed but
also
the time in which we performed that
analysis we're also going to be
discussing the importance of a trust
especially as it relates to contact
tracing applications and effectively
fighting the pandemic
and we're going to be going over our
analysis so our testing approach and our
methodology the body of applications and
scope as well as our findings that were
derived from analyzing all of the data
that we found
and lastly we are going to be providing
recommendations as well as key takeaways
when it comes to
any contact tracing application not just
that of covid19 but potentially future
contact tracing applications as well
and
other rushed development scenarios which
might equally apply
so now that we've provided a general
overview of what we'll be discussing
today we can move on to providing an
overview of both our testing approach
and our methodology and in order to do
that i would like to cover these three
main points regarding our testing
approach
so that's going to be the body of
applications that actually were in the
scope of our analysis
it's also going to cover the individual
controls that we were looking for inside
of each of the applications that we
analyzed and finally it's going to cover
a summary of findings based on the
analysis that was actually performed
now in order to give you better line of
sight into not only the analysis that we
performed but when we performed that
analysis i created a slide here in order
to provide a general timeline so you can
see in june of 2020 i had the
opportunity of analyzing 14 of the
original android covid 19 contact
tracing applications at the time the
data was limited to android these were
only apks and so i cannot uh evaluate
and investigate the ios side of the
house but um at that time the privacy
and security concerns were certainly
enough in order to spark an interest in
performing a second round of
investigation in order to expand that
data set perhaps and also uh take a look
at how
new applications have progressed over
time and so that's exactly what we did
in december of 2020 as you can see
not only did we
reanalyze the original 14 uh
android kovid19 contact tracing
applications that we looked at initially
but we expanded that data set by adding
another 38 unique android kovid 19
contact tracing applications
totaling 52
android applications on the android side
of the house and we also extended that
data set by adding 43 unique ios covid
19 contact tracing applications in order
to get a better
uh
look at what we actually see on the ios
front as well
so in order to provide a 30 000 foot
view and a breakdown you can see that we
analyzed 95 applications in total the
majority of these were created by public
health authorities around the world
something that's interesting is that not
all of these applications were created
by individual countries but you can
actually see that some of these were
produced by
states and u.s territories of which we
had the opportunity to analyze some of
these as well
now i would also like to introduce
what's called the exposure notifications
api
the exposure notifications api was
created by apple and by google back in
may of 20 of 20
2020 excuse me and
the main goal here was to unify the way
in which developers create both safe and
secure contact tracing applications
and it is quite simple it works on a
very simple but secure bluetooth
implementation
so if i am using the application and i
come in contact with another user who
has tested positive i will be alerted of
that potential exposure so that i myself
can go ahead and get tested myself
now once again this does not rely on any
form of gps tracking information and it
also does not request any other forms of
potentially sensitive user data such as
a passport number or a phone number or
other pieces of information which simply
aren't required to anonymously safely
and securely notify users of potential
exposures to the virus
now i've also provided some developer
documentation here for anybody that's
interested in taking a closer look
regarding the implementation and the api
itself you can also see that it provided
some some links below
in order to give you
more information surrounding the api but
that won't be the main portion of
today's conversation
you know there were two primary goals uh
when creating the exposure notification
api
that being safety privacy and of course
security as a whole
so safely and securely
notify users of potential exposures
goes about this by using bluetooth
and not gps data but also to limit the
amount of information that's actually
collected uh so that it is not
left unsecured and unencrypted for
attackers to find later
um and so the way it does this by is by
actually not collecting any additional
pieces of information at all and
therefore it doesn't need to be secured
now the real key thing to understand
about the exposure notification api that
differentiates it from other solutions
or other options is that the first it
doesn't rely on gps data which is a
privacy concern
in of itself
the second thing is that it also does
not request any additional pieces of
user information which would otherwise
need to be secured but in
some of our analysis we noticed um you
know there were applications that are
using gps data um collecting other
pieces of information and not securing
that um
so
with this in mind you know there were
certainly many expectations and many um
many outcomes of
of receiving this key innovation and so
that brings us to the next slide
one of the things that we want to do is
really discuss some of the key
expectations
that
that prompted the creation of the
exposure notification api as mentioned
the api's primary goal was to provide
core functionality for developers who
wanted in public health authorities who
wanted to
create secure contact tracing
applications
and as part of this the goal was that if
you know google and apple
thought that if
developers create safe and secure
applications and then people are bound
to trust those applications and as a
result they'll use them whereas in
contrary if users do not trust the
application then they're not going to
use it and if the masses of people
choose not to use kobit 19 contact
tracing apps because they don't trust it
then it's not going to be a very
effective utility in fighting the
pandemic so it's very important that
people trust them and in order for
people to trust them they need to be
built both safely and securely with
privacy in mind so apple and google came
together they produced this api to do
just that and naturally as part of this
the expectation was that health
authorities around the world would adopt
this very convenient tool in order to do
just that
now the results themselves were
something different and this is
something that we'll take a look at here
as you can see in our analysis what we
found is that sixty percent of the
applications overall uh adopted the
exposure notification api so 62 on the
android side of the house and 58 on the
ios side of the house
however 40 of applications
did not
elect to use the exposure notification
api and
as a result they took a do-it-yourself
approach to security
uh by instead
doing it themselves so
for example we we noticed applications
that were using gps data collecting
other pieces of information these tie
into some of the security and privacy
concerns that we'll discuss later and um
some of the unnecessary
pieces of data that they collect and
fail to secure properly
now
something that's very important to
understand about all of the information
and all of the data that we're going to
discuss today
is that we're not focusing on the 60 of
applications which did in fact use the
exposure notification api and therefore
do have a good security posture we're
focusing on the 40 and that's really
where we're going to zoom in in order to
take a closer look at the 40 percent of
applications which deliberately elected
to not use the exposure notification api
and in many cases actually collect
additional pieces of information
which
in many cases were also not secured
so this is going to be our main focus
today the 40 of apps that did not use
the exposure notification api
now finally we would like to introduce
the individual controls studied so for
each of the applications inside of the
body
or each of the applications inside of
the scope that we were looking at uh so
the 40 of applications that did not use
the exposure notification api but
instead took it do it yourself approach
to security
these were the individual security
mechanisms that we were looking for now
as opposed to reading them all off i'll
let all of the viewers here take a look
at these individual controls
but each of these are aimed at removing
context from a binary and make it hard
and making it harder for reverse
engineers to understand how the
application works and therefore how to
exploit it
so now that we've
explained our testing approach and our
methodology we're going to go into a
full overview of the
data and the analysis that we actually
performed as well as the takeaways that
we were able to derive from analyzing
that data
so hopping directly into the data you
can actually see um here on our first
slide we are taking a look at the
android applications now of all of the
uh 40 of applications that fell into the
category which did not use the exposure
notification api uh we did take a look
at 20 do-it-yourself android
applications and of them we have
actually mapped the different percentage
of those applications that adhered to
the controls that we were looking for
and possessed these different protection
mechanisms and it's very clear that
on the android side of the house most
applications don't possess these
protections and therefore additionally
possess weak security posture
piggy backing off the last slide you can
see on this slide that we've provided a
number of applications and a percentage
of applications which adhere to the
control mechanisms that we took a look
at on the previous slide
so for example you can actually see that
95 of these applications possess
two or fewer
of the
protections that we were looking at now
please do bear in mind that the slide
that we're reviewing right now is just
the android portion of the applications
that we looked at but
just from a 30 000 foot view of the 40
of applications that we analyzed which
did not use the exposure notification
api 95
of those applications used
um
two or fewer protections meaning they're
not building these applications with
security or privacy in mind and actually
zero of them had five or more of these
protections
so now taking a look at the ios side of
the house you can see that we have
equivalently provided the same control
mechanisms that we looked at for the
android side and in the top right hand
corner you're gonna see that uh for the
ios side of the house we actually
analyzed 18 do-it-yourself ios
applications by do-it-yourself we mean
these applications deliberately elected
not to use the exposure notification api
and instead elected to implement uh
controls themselves
now what you can see is that most of
these features
are actually implemented very
conservatively across the applications
that we analyzed and actually app
attestation and name obfuscation just
simply don't appear at all
so
once again on the ios side of the house
we are very quickly realizing that
robust security does not seem to exist
inside of the majority of these
contact racing applications
and now once again you can see
that we have provided the same chart
that we did for android
in order to display the number of
applications and the percentage of
applications which actually adhered to a
certain number of the controls that we
were looking for so in this case we can
actually see that 61
of the ios applications that we looked
at so 11 of the 18
actually possessed two or fewer controls
and
in general 94 of these applications
possessed two or less so on the android
side
we can see that 95 of those applications
and on the ios side we can see that 94
of those applications possess two or
fewer of the controls that we were
looking for once again representing that
these covid app contact tracing
applications are not being built with
security in mind
now beyond the lack of security controls
which we were able to highlight in
previous slides we also believe that uh
privacy concerns should be a large
portion of today's conversation and
should be eliminated so we're going to
take a look at gps privacy concerns
which we observed in a number of these
different contact tracing applications
and we're going to start by calling out
the fact that
many gps apps or a number of the gps
apps that we observed actually collect
additional user information which is not
necessary such as a passport number
phone number a device id
or other pieces of valuable information
which aren't required
to anonymously notify users of potential
exposure additionally those sensitive
pieces of information were
in some cases stored insecurely such as
in unencrypted sqlite databases
or
potentially leaked in other ways
making them uneffectively or effectively
unencrypted rather
so
it's very safe to say that
this is definitely a privacy concern
these applications actually don't need
to collect additional information which
is the point of the exposure
notification
api which only relies on bluetooth and
does not collect any other sensitive
pieces of user information
um
and with that being said this can
actually call into question
uh the safety of these applications and
potentially hinder the value of contact
tracing applications when it comes to
combating uh the pandemic itself
so now we would like to summarize the
results and on the bright side starting
with the good news sixty percent of
applications did indeed adopt the
exposure notification api and that's
really good news
but what we really focused on during
this conversation was the forty percent
of applications that uh in some
negligent way elected not to implement
the exposure notification api and and
many other examples actually uh
performed other pieces of unnecessary
and unsafe um forms of data collection
like gps tracking information passport
numbers phone numbers and more
on top of this we notice that many
applications again we're leaking that
information through unencrypted
sqlite databases http cache so on and so
forth and this is a big concern
so that brings us to our second point um
reliance on gps tracking data um i think
has been proven to be um an inferior
method than bluetooth when it comes to
contact tracing applications that need
to be built with privacy in mind and
bluetooth does a great job it gives you
all the tools that you need uh to both
detect with your when you're in the
proximity of somebody who has been
exposed to covid and therefore alert you
to the fact that you yourself should go
get tested as well so don't use gps
tracking data use bluetooth use a common
api like the exposure notification api
and
again don't collect other unnecessary
pieces of data which just very simply
aren't needed in order to notify
individuals of exposures
and finally
in summarizing results uh i think it was
very clear based on the previous slides
that there was a gross lack of static
and dynamic protection
when it comes to the applications that
we really dug into and took a look at
all these individual security controls
what we found is that due to these um
the lack of obfuscation the lack of
encryption and the lack of runtime
protections that were embedded inside of
these applications
it would be very easy for
reverse engineers to tamper with and
change and exploit these applications
in in different nefarious ways
some other observations that we made
throughout our testing and research
was first of all that application
security
is not determined by nation's wealth
so for example if we look at israel
who's number 32 out of 196 in terms of
gdp
in the year 2020 they had significantly
worse application security than some of
the countries in africa who had their
own contact tracing app
now that's contrary to what we thought
we thought that a country who had high
gdp had a lot of money for developing a
contact tracing app
securely
but that's not the case
second of all gdpr and hipaa violations
were noticed especially in the diy apps
england's was one their test and trace
program broke gdpr data laws because
they weren't adhering to
to gdpr regulations when it as it
pertained to the storage and processing
of data
now thirdly there's the encouragement of
waiving data privacy rights there are
users who are downloading these
applications thinking that they're
robust with security and privacy in mind
but that's not the case
so there needed there needs to be
transparency and there wasn't in terms
of
how privacy was being handled
let's move on to flawed development and
integration
we clearly noticed that development
teams were having difficulties in a
variety of areas
first of them being timeline sensitivity
with the pandemic picking up in pace
development had to be rushed to get a
working application out as soon as
possible
the sprints as a result were focused on
fixing functionality or creating that
functionality
leaving little consideration for
security in that time
the second thing we noticed was that the
development team had to choose between
you know their approach to constraints
whether they wanted quality
which would require a long development
time or if they wanted
short release time but as a result
control the spread and potentially save
human lives
the third difficulty that we saw these
development teams have was
the fact that this was such a unique
solution there hadn't been a contact
tracing app before that
was that had to be released on such a
large scale
there was no previous poster child
i don't think that a developer could go
on to
stack overflow and get the necessary
code and call it a day
so that wasn't really possible there
and the fact that these applications
were handling
sensitive data this had to be looked at
in terms of privacy
some some applications of course uh
considered privacy and security very
well others didn't but either way there
had to be some sort of uh consideration
for that sensitive data data even at
that minimum
the rush to development of these contact
tracing applications didn't come without
any effects
there's actually quite a few effects
that came about as a result
as i mentioned in the last slide there
is a main focus on functionality of the
applications and a limited regard for
security and privacy as a result
just mainly because the goal was to
develop an application as soon as
possible and release it to the public
furthermore there is a lacking of
features that would allow for
integration with other apps or covet
apps let's say the european union wanted
all of europe's countries to integrate
into one application
this wouldn't be possible
because this integration feature wasn't
built in however as a result less time
was spent on development which means
that
getting to the controlling of the spread
happened sooner so you can claim that as
a benefit
lastly there's you know an ethical
dilemma these developers know that
there is there's a known risk of
security in these applications yet
they're still releasing it well
the question is do you release an app
that is unhardened due to lack of time
and money
on one hand the spread might be thwarted
but at the same time it's opening doors
for for a long-term headache if these if
these people's data gets stolen and you
have to weigh the long-term effects
against the short-term in that case
let's move on to recommendations for
timebox development
so the first recommendation is to unify
apps and that can be done in one of two
ways or both
the first being using a common api and
the second being consolidating apps so
the first way is you know using one of
google's or apple's
apis
also known as the notification exposure
api
or similar now i put an asterisk there
because i believe that it doesn't
necessarily have to be a private company
solution it could be a you know public
government
created solution but either way you know
global issues should be fought on a
global scale
there should be that common api that
should be utilized when it's there
the second as i've mentioned is
consolidating apps there's way too many
apps on the app stores
users have trouble knowing which one's
legitimate which one's not
and the fact that there's so many state
level apps that's just contributing to
the issue and to that
we're just saying no let's let's skip
not having
these state level apps
you know country countries fine but
making sure that it's uh you know
utilizing the the common api and not
a do-it-yourself one
uh anybody who's not complying with this
you know our thoughts are that they
should be fined there's going to be
proposed
contact tracing app requirements and
anybody who's not adhering to them
should be fined
the second thing we'd like to recommend
is a security focused sdlc
now for those of you who aren't familiar
with what an sdlc is it's a software
development life cycle
and it's typically found in
companies and pertains to how
development
goes from start to finish
we're particularly recommending a
shift-left approach
which means uh including security
earlier and at every phase meaning that
it's everywhere and that is a
forethought not an afterthought
we're recommending that teams aren't
siloed so if there's a security team
that we want them to work with a
development team and for communicate
communication to be facilitated
there doesn't have to be a pick one
approach
to choosing either functionality or
security you can have both uh and that's
you know the fact that these development
and security teams can work in parallel
together
especially when new features are being
released
you know there could be an iterative
approach where security is constantly
being checked
in these features
one thing that would allow for you know
security tests in these types of
feature releases is something called a
technical security review which
documents
that you know that there's been scanning
in the code that's been performed
documents the inter inter-service
communication let's say the service has
to communicate with another service that
will be documented there
along with any any scanning results
testing that had been done
if there is no software development uh
life cycle uh in the case that a company
doesn't have to adhere to
let's say pci regulations or hip uh what
have you
then typically you can hook it into an
existing change management process
you can hook security processes into
that because whenever there's an
application that gets added to an
inventory let's say typically there's a
change management process for that and
very similarly you can just include
security aspects to to be included in
that
now we would like to go over some
development recommendations for current
and for future contact tracing
applications alike starting with use a
common api if tech giants like google
and apple are going to give you all the
tools that you need to succeed in
creating a
a contact tracing application built with
both security and privacy in mind use it
implement it and benefit from it not
only are you going to benefit from it
but your users are going to benefit from
it
they're going to know that
as a result that their
their information is safe that they
don't have to worry about that
information being leaked due to
negligence when it comes to security and
as a result of being able to trust the
fact that those applications are indeed
built with both security and privacy in
mind they're more likely to use those
applications which is going to make them
a much more effective utility in
fighting a pandemic like the one we've
gone through or any other potential
future pandemic in the future
as part of this don't collect or store
any other pieces of user information
which are not required
to
alert
users of potential exposures so again
going back to the exposure notification
api collect and use as little as
possible don't collect gps tracking
information
don't collect other
pieces of user information
again try to try to use something like
bluetooth don't collect other pieces of
information one of the key benefits to
not collecting other pieces of
information is of course then there is
no risk of that information being leaked
and therefore you don't need to secure
it at all
the second recommendation that we have
is to adhere to um
uh security standard or framework like
oauths uh
mobile application security verification
standard um which as it sounds acts as a
blueprint for security architects or
mobile developers alike who are looking
to build applications with both security
and privacy in mind
and we would also recommend that if for
any reason
you do or public health
authorities do decide to build contact
tracing applications they do not decide
to adopt the common tools that are given
to them like the exposure notification
api in future use cases um to actually
utilize code hardening solutions if
needed so if you do decide to collect
additional pieces of user data
of any kind then it becomes your
obligation uh to
in in your liability to secure that
information otherwise if it does get
leaked um
it's your fault so ultimately what we've
found is that while many teams do have
what it takes to build perfectly
functional applications um baking in
security is something completely
different and especially on such a
rushed timeline this can be a very large
task
so for that there are code hardening
solutions that will allow you to
implement multi-layered
protections both static and dynamic to
provide robust security inside of
applications that will ward attackers
and make it infeasible to reverse
engineer those applications in a very
short amount of time
so those would certainly be recommendat
recommended by us if for any reason
public health authorities decide not to
adopt a common api and to actually go
ahead and collect additional pieces of
unnecessary data
and the final product we hope is that uh
more safe secure and privacy focused
contact tracing applications by creating
applications with security and privacy
in mind the ultimate goal as it always
was is that
users will trust those applications
they'll use those applications and by
using those applications we'll all be
safer
we can make a difference we can make an
impact and hopefully
find a way to more effectively fight the
pandemic
now with this we'd like to move on to
some general agnostic recommendations
for code hardening solutions
just so that we can be most helpful
again going back to the main point a
code hardening solution shouldn't be
needed when it comes to contact tracing
applications these applications should
essentially be shells which really only
alert
users of potential exposures based on
bluetooth activity
but if for any reason you
stray from that
recommendation and you do decide to
again collect additional pieces of
information it does become your
liability your obligations to secure it
and if you don't have time to do that um
you don't have the the in-house skill or
specialization to do that then i would
have to say that this is very common and
we'll discuss this uh
in in following slides as well
in order to make
life easier faster and more secure for
everybody you can adopt a code hardening
solution
and so we're going to run over a couple
different code hardening solutions which
can help
vastly improve the security posture of
applications both statically and
dynamically by applying multi-layered
protection in a very short amount of
time so a number of weeks
so starting with dexguard dexguard is a
android hardening solution once again it
is
a fully encompassing suite of tools
which is designed to specifically harden
android applications against both
hackers and reverse engineers it does
this by again
applying multi-layered protection um
both static and dynamic the same is true
of ix card which is its ios counterpart
it's designed to provide an equivalent
level of protection but for ios
applications
and so if you are building an ios
contact tracing application it does
collect
additional pieces of sensitive user
information it would be a good idea in
order to secure that using a solution
like ix guard
and finally there's threatcast
threatcast will provide real-time threat
event information so that you can
actually monitor what's happening and
how that application is being attacked
in real time and then respond to that
proactively
now finally we would like to move on to
the triple constraint and the importance
of actually adopting the triple
constraint
now the triple constraint is the idea
that in any project management scenario
you really have to choose between time
cost and quality and oftentimes you can
only pick two now in this case what we
found is that you know many teams did
you know have a very short amount of
time to develop applications
and they weren't willing to put money
into securing these applications either
as a result the quality really suffered
what they could have done is they could
have put in
some more money in order to employ a
code hardening solution that actually
encrypted and secured all of the
additional information um
that they collected and and this would
have been a much more
responsible
the second thing that we would like to
cover is you know resource allocation
what we find is that professionally
speaking most teams certainly do have
the in-house specialization needed to
create very functional and performant
applications but what they don't have is
the in-house specialization needed in
order to bake in robust multi-layered
security that is truly capable um of
warding and making it infeasible for um
very skilled reverse engineers uh to do
just that reverse engineer and tamper
with those applications um so if you
happen to fall into the majority of
teams like that then our recommendation
is
don't try to reinvent the wheel um
utilize a code hardening solution in
order to very quickly
and conveniently build in security to
your application so that you can protect
the user base
and ultimately
as part of this it bleeds it bleeds
right into the rest avoid do it yourself
security implementations
like we observed
here in this data set so again adopt the
tools that are given to you benefit from
the tools that are given to you if tech
giants like google and apple are going
to give you a common api which is
designed to
help you build core functionalities into
applications in a safe and secure way
certainly use them
but don't expect you know high quality
low cost and you know low time
commitment when it comes to really
anything in life
if you enjoyed the topic of this
presentation we'd like to recommend some
ideas for future projects that you can
take on yourself
quite simply vaccine passport
applications they're very similar to
contact tracing applications but they've
had more development time as they're not
time pressed in terms of development as
they're racing against the surging
pandemic
they're also more unified meaning that a
whole region such as the european union
is only relying on one
one application versus a multitude but
there's still a reason to be skeptical
because
we've seen the way that the development
approach has been for the contact
tracing applications
despite there being more time it doesn't
necessarily mean that development has
included
security practices and processes
some test cases we'd like to recommend
there is seeing if you can change the
approval status of uploaded covid tests
and also seeing if you can bypass
the proof of vaccination validation
where i believe you upload a picture of
your vaccination card
and with that we'd like to open it up to
any questions
thank you
you