[Music]
wow
hello and thank you for joining me my
name is kathy ullman i'm also known as
investigator chick and we're going to
talk about communicating
during an incident so many of us i think
are familiar with incidents
whether they're small or something
really big
pretty sure if you haven't been paying
attention uh
you know you might not have seen stuff
about maybe
solar winds because that's not a thing
right
so we're going to talk a little bit
about communicating when you do have an
incident because we do talk a lot about
incidents uh in terms of recovering from
them and preventing them but not so much
about communicating during them
so here's our agenda we're going to meet
the sloth
we'll talk about why this particular
subject matters
we'll talk a little about our strengths
and weaknesses in infosec there are some
things we are incredibly good at doing
and there are some things that we could
use some help with and how those
particular things help or detract us
from this goal
then we'll talk about communication at
multiple levels so
you will need to communicate in an
organization up the chain down the chain
sideways
so we're going to talk about how that
communication differs
we'll talk a little about non-verbal
communications because that's just as
important as our verbal communication
and then i'll give you some final
thoughts
so here we go
meeting the sloth
so this is a slot from the buffalo zoo
where i adopted him uh
it's been almost two years now his name
is flash
he's very sweet and i'm very fond of
sloths so i i almost always bring a
sloth to the party uh figuratively of
course
this is a little about me i won't dwell
on this i have some degrees i have some
certifications i help out with a whole
bunch of stuff
and uh you know so if you want to know
more about me
you are welcome to google and read more
about this
i want to bring
hacking is not a crime to your attention
very briefly
i think this is a very important
organization the idea being that you
know those of us who are hackers
what we do inherently is not a crime
however the intent can change that right
so if you're interested i recommend you
check us out at hacking is not a
crime.org
moving on
so let's get into the meat potatoes of
this conversation
so motivation why should we care about
this subject
well this cat is very interested clearly
but what are the odds
and this isn't this is not meant
to be the the scary slide it's really
just meant to point out the fact that
you know we can see patterns right
there have been a number of breaches and
in 2018 to 19 we see breaches going up
and then from 2019 to 2020
gee the total number of breaches go down
so is that good does that mean things
are getting better
maybe
but i would say
oh i don't know maybe it's just the kind
of breaches that we're having and
the way in which attackers are coming
after our information
is now focused more on something like
ransomware
so the point of this slide is just to
point out
that there is an increased frequency of
ransomware as i mentioned earlier the
whole business with solarwinds
and all the things that have made the
news lately have typically been some
form of ransomware
so maybe we're not losing a gazillion
records at a time
maybe instead
we're being forced to deal with
ransomware and that's certainly a
pattern that's going up
so the reality is that
everybody's going to be dealing with
incidents
so this is a quote
from the former fbi director
and
he argues that there's really only two
kinds of companies those who've been
hacked and those who will be and
ultimately
those who will be hacked
and those who will be hacked again right
and so the reality is
this is everywhere
we're going to have an incident at some
point
and
really if we take some time and we think
through how we're going to communicate
during that incident we will be better
prepared to deal with whatever comes
down the pike instead of being in a
fearful tizzy running around like
chickens with their heads cut off
all right so this leads into our
strengths and weaknesses in infosec
so as i mentioned earlier
folks who do this job
tend to be really good at certain things
right what are we good at
first of all i want to point out
that the reality is
while technology can play a role in
solving some of the problems we see
like you know ransomware any other sort
of
attack
really we're dealing with people
and
i.t folks infosec folks not always so
good at dealing with people
so if you really want to understand the
security problem you have to realize
it's a people problem
so how does that tie back into this
notion of what we're good at and what
we're not good at
well here's what we're really good at
doing
we
are exceptional at fixing problems right
just like this little kitten we can
solve all the problems you've got to
break we fix it
especially in the defense universe i
mean you know the offense folks they
like to break things defense folks have
to figure out how to fix them although i
have to give kudos we are starting to
see some folks in the offensive space
providing you know just as much
usable information and intel about how
they broke something to be able to help
fix it which is fantastic
so this is an area in which we really
excel in general in the i.t space and in
infosec
this is unfortunately what we're not so
good at
we do not excel at communicating with
each other or with other people
and some of you may recognize this this
image
i would play a clip for you but the the
clips some of them are a little grainy
but this clip is from an old saturday
night live skit
with
uh
this particular gentleman on the right
plays nick burns the computer guy and
what he does when he shows up at your
desk as the worker person who's trying
to get help
is he belittles them he talks down to
them and he says move
right
if you're the person whose job it is
to do the thing
you are there
to
write a word document that describes a
project that your organization is
involved in
you're not there to do technical support
you rely
on those of us in i.t
and in security to support you in some
way well nick is terrible at that and
unfortunately he represents a large
chunk of us right
i would like to think i'm not in that
chunk i've made a career out of going
out of my way to try to explain things
in terms that folks who are not
technical understand
i came out of a support role before i
moved into security i was in support for
a very long time i started on the phones
in a call center like many folks have i
did word perfect support
and you know these people they rely on
you for help in the same way that we
rely on other folks in other industries
plumbers electricians any sort of
industry you can think of
where we don't necessarily have that
expertise
so when we do a poor job of
communicating with folks
we set ourselves up for failure and
that's a problem and it's especially a
problem during an incident
so patience
they say
is not something that we often have a
whole lot of
it's something that is hard to come by
and you know i i have felt this very
angry way on occasion
and that's really hard because when you
have to explain something for the
20th 30th time
you don't really want to have to explain
it again and yet
that is part of our job right is that we
have to explain things we often have to
explain them more than once
so what are the repercussions of us not
communicating well
with these folks
well
there can be a loss of trust and in
reality
the security office in an organization
or even if you just have you know some
folks who are in a role if there's no
big organization
because this talk is meant to cover you
whether you're in a tiny organization
maybe you're it right you're the only
person in the job doing i.t and security
and you you wear all the hats right
or maybe
you're in a large organization where
there is a full security office and a
whole bunch of people doing all kinds of
other types of support
it doesn't matter
what matters is that when you don't
communicate well with people
you can lose their trust and if they
don't trust you they won't tell you when
something's wrong
and think about what happens if you
don't know something's wrong right
the folks who are out there are eyes and
ears we can look at logs all day long
but in many cases
the log tells us the bigger picture or
can tip us off to some other piece but
maybe just maybe it's that individual
who says i see something weird and that
individual could either be
somebody in the
i.t space the infosec space or none of
the above
so it's important to keep their trust
future communications will also be
problematic if i'm uncomfortable talking
to you
because you've belittled me or you've
talked down to me in some way
i'm not going to want to pick up that
phone and call you right i'm going to
call somebody else for help and maybe
that person wasn't the best choice to
call because maybe they don't have all
the insight
so this is really important um you can
be the cause of an additional conflict
because again you know now you maybe
they had a different phone call they
called somebody else and that person
gave them inaccurate information now you
have another conflict
there can be
in general
bad reputation
vibes
uh on a company if that communication
about an incident in particular is poor
we've seen a lot of that right the
intern did it that caused all kinds of
fantastic thumbs up i don't know about
you but i
really wasn't particularly happy to see
that
there's going to be an overall increase
decrease in morale because when people
don't feel good about who they're
working with and they don't feel like
they can communicate with you especially
during an incident
they're not going to feel good about
where they are what they're doing and of
course it's going to lead to additional
stress
so i'm going to use an example here
that is pretty basic
as you might guess it's going to be a
ransomware type example i'm not going to
go into the specifics of the particulars
of the ransomware
i'm just going to show you
some
common examples right everything from
wannacry to the solar winds
uh you know the point is that all of
these kinds of things now can lead to
some form of ransomware where either our
data becomes encrypted or it becomes a
situation where
the attacker first
steals a bunch of data and then offers
it back to you for a ransom so it really
becomes more of extortion
so the details aren't important what is
important here is i'm setting up a basic
incident
so we've had an incident happen one of
these things has popped up on on a
machine somebody notices something
really strange has happened
so you know the question at that point
becomes what do we do now
what do we do
well we could do this we could just walk
away right that's usually not an option
i don't know about you but i don't
really want to just walk away and lose
my job
we could panic and freak out
that's also not an ideal situation right
we want to
take a step back and think about this i
have a whole other talk
one of my hobbies is
i've been a firefighter since 1997 and i
have another talk that talks all about
the
similarities and differences of
firefighting and information
security incident response
i would say this is not the time to
panic and freak out and i talk a lot
more about that in that particular talk
so instead we're going to have to
communicate something
something bad has happened again even if
your role
is you're you're it and now you have to
communicate to multiple levels within
your org or
maybe your role is smaller and you're
part of a larger group and there's
multiple groups
you still may have to communicate to
multiple levels within your organization
so let's talk about what it's like to
have those communications
what kinds of things to focus on and
ultimately
um
how we're going to get that message
across
so these are the audiences
we're going to focus on the end user
mid-level management and our executives
and the goal is going to be what we call
framing the conversation
which is a really simple concept
framing the conversation is just about
what is important to them that's how
we're going to preface that conversation
so that they're not sitting there
wondering when are they going to get to
something i care about you're going to
jump right into that right away in a way
that they understand
so
in thinking about that you want to
anticipate you know what questions might
any one of these folks folks at any of
these levels ask you
you also need to consider how and where
you're going to communicate
that's called a communication channel
so does it make sense with certain in
individuals or groups to communicate on
an internal website
i mean depending on how bad the
situation is that might not be
appropriate
do you have to do some sort of a
one-on-one presentation with somebody in
upper management it really is going to
depend greatly on the situation
is email appropriate
maybe part of what is happening with
this particular ransomware is the email
system is impacted
so
maybe that's not the best meet
maybe you have to get everybody in a
room and have in-person conversations
again you have to consider that channel
and because i never want to leave this
out
you can always try lawyer approved
carrier pigeons if nothing else
so let's talk next about the end user
so what does the end user focus on
they normally want to figure out how
this is going to impact their work
completion
what is it they do
and how are they getting it done
well this incident impact their
day-to-day
activities
your goal with these folks is to
communicate to them
what happened and why when you can now
that doesn't mean you tell them all the
little technical details
trying to explain solar winds to an end
user for example
uh no
you're probably not gonna do that
but
from the context remember we're talking
about framing that conversation for them
so within that context what happened and
why
for them
you want to use this as an opportunity
for awareness training where you can if
what kicked off this incident is you
know a phishing message or
some form of
um
uh whether it's a phone call or somebody
coming in
and you know they're doing social
engineering in some
capacity that's okay use this as a as an
opportunity to teach right you're not
going to call out
the person or people that were
specifically involved here you're just
going to say
this is what happened this is why it
happened and give them those basics
you want to give them this information
in a way that will be helpful for them
both at work and at home
one of the things i do
within my job at the university of
buffalo is i teach awareness stuff
and when i do that i make a point of
what i am teaching
to not be just solely focused on work i
certainly talk about our different data
classifications and how
they need to
uh
you know avoid sending certain kinds of
data in email for example
however
that's really no different from what
they should be doing at home and the
reality is if you can encourage the
right kind of behavior it doesn't matter
where it is if they start doing the
right thing on their own personal data
because they care about that data
chances are with a little muscle memory
they're going to do the same thing in
the office
so show it as a benefit to them hey if
you
you know if you understand this and you
do it the right way this can protect you
and the people you care about and your
own information not just that of your
organization
you want to be effective and efficient
whenever possible
so
and in continuous as well you don't want
to send one message and then stop
because then people get antsy and they
don't know what's going on so continuous
messaging is very important
so what do we mean by
well be concise right less is more again
like i was saying a moment ago
we want to tell them what happened and
why but they don't need all the
technical details they need to know
what's relevant to them
again be judicious
we don't want to blame folks whether
it's management or other other
individuals
we don't want to provide irrelevant
information to them
sometimes this can be awkward because
you will get asked questions and you
know your organization has to kind of
dictate
what you're allowed to say but be
thinking about this before it happens
not in the middle of it happening
and we've talked about patients right be
patient
even if you have to explain it for the
300th time and you have to go in a
closet and scream and tear your hair out
and you know beat the walls or whatever
it's really important to be patient
at the end of the day
you want to provide communication
at a level that these folks can both
understand and relate to
on their level
and that can be a real challenge as i
mentioned before for those of us in the
tech field because that's not what we're
used to thinking about and it's very
easy to assume that other folks know
what we know and guess what
they don't
and in some cases it's amazing
what other folks know about other
subjects that we don't right so keep
that in mind
this is how we're not
going to communicate with those folks
right we're not going to scream at them
we're not going to talk down to them
we're not going to try to freak them out
or frighten them that doesn't
help our cause in any way
so be upfront and honest this whole idea
of lies to children that will come back
to bite you so don't lie about what's
happening you may have to omit certain
things that's not uncommon
you want to make sure right off the bat
you are addressing any kind of fear
uncertainty and doubt
because this population in particular is
going to be very susceptible to how does
this impact my job what does this mean
you know could i could i lose my job
will i well the projects i'm working on
will something happen to them
as much as you can you want to address
that and that may require a conversation
with
other people
to be able to do that right
remember
that perception is reality for your
average end user what they think they
see whether or not it's true
is their reality
and what that means is if somebody
reaches out to you and says something
weird is happening on my system
and you know from what they're telling
you it's probably nothing
you know they they probably just uh hit
the wrong keys right they hit a funny
key combination and it caused a window
to pop up or it changed a venue a a menu
view or something along those lines you
may recognize that as no big deal
but you never know
what you might miss
so take the time and investigate even if
you know it's not a problem
remember what i said earlier about trust
and how important trust is
and any kind of security awareness
is based on trust it's really really
important folks need to feel like they
can reach out to you and say
houston i think we have a problem and
the sooner somebody tells you that the
better off that your organization will
be
all right so moving on to middle
management right
calm down it's all good we're fine
so middle management is typically
focused on whatever their business
processes
so are they out of some operational
entity do they run hr is this i.t
it's going to impact their department
and that's going to be their focus right
they're not going to look at necessarily
their day-to-day
uh
specific tasks they're going to be
thinking about
what their overall business process
involves and how this is going to impact
that
again you want to speak to them at a
level they can understand and relate to
so what does that mean well again we've
already talked about that very
specifically
but it probably means you're going to
avoid things like geek speak which we'll
come back to
so no technical conversation with
management unless you happen to know
they are
tech savvy and that means they
understand the kind of thing you're
talking about
so there are folks who are in
development um who do programming and
they may be amazing coders and they may
not understand anything about
operational security directly
maybe they do maybe they came out of
some kind of role where you know they
spent time
researching security things the point is
don't take it for granted don't assume
this is how we're not going to
communicate with middle management right
we're not going to do the chicken with
the head cut off
because
that's not helpful we're not gonna run
around and scream oh my god the sky is
falling because that'll just cause them
to say this guy is falling and that
doesn't help anybody
so with ideal middle managers
the ideal middle manager is phenomenal
at delegating they have amazing
interpersonal skills
they're very effective with
communication they can negotiate like
the best of them they have outstanding
emotional intelligence intelligence and
they are
fantastic influencers now i don't know
about you
but i'd say this is a pr
space now i can tell you right now the
manager i have is spectacular
and he's probably as close to this as
i've seen in a very long time but the
reality is it's not very common
so we're going to talk about engaging
with your regular middle manager right
not not not the perfect one who's really
good at all of the things but maybe who
is good at some of those things because
ideally that's why they're in middle
management though we all know that
that's not always the case
you want to be supportive of these
mid-level managers
you want to work with them to come up
with some kind of action plan if you're
talking about i.t this could be an
action plan to deal with exactly what's
happening whatever this incident is
it could be giving them the information
they need to make an action plan for
their own unit
but it's got to include communication
that goes up and down the chain
don't leave those users in the dark
remember how important we talked about
that communication being continuous
that's where this kind of comes together
right
so
both telling the folks above these
mid-level managers what's going on and
the folks below them is critical
and
more critical is empathy middle
management is a really really hard job
the folks who are above middle
management they want to stay there and
they want to push mid management down
that's at least typically the the
thought process of course not every
manager is like that but
you know your your typical folks in
executive positions don't necessarily
want to be kicked out by somebody
beneath them
and the folks who are below mid
management are in many cases trying to
get into middle management
so they are often caught between a rock
and a hard place and it can be a really
big challenge
so empathy is important you want to make
whatever you discuss with them whatever
plan you come up with it should make
them look good because guess what
that will ultimately make you look good
so what is that plan going to include
well
at a minimum it's going to be a
description of the incident again in
that context of what they care about
ultimately you want to
think about all the stakeholders that
are involved are there internal and
external stakeholders you could very
well have a situation where
you're calling in law enforcement so how
is that going to play a role do you are
there um
you know other board members you have to
think about uh are there other entities
that are
tangential to your organization this
could impact
so you need to be thinking about all of
those stakeholders and if you're in a
main security role or you're all by
yourself this becomes even more critical
and it's tough to think about in the
moment right
so if you can be thinking
in an incident who you need to gather
together so that that communication plan
includes those folks and you think about
this in advance that will only help your
cause
now with regard to this specific
incident
consider the recovery options and time
frames and that doesn't mean
the best possible option
or the worst possible option it's all of
the options
and how can we keep this from recurring
was this
you know was this a single action
that showed some sort of
gap in a process
was this something where there was a gap
in technology you know what's the
likelihood of this happening again so
you want to reduce that and you want to
talk about how that's going to be done
and the end goal what is the end goal is
the end goal
to get to a certain point in the
incident with these folks or is the end
goal
getting all the way through the incident
this is going to differ depending on
what's happening in your organization in
general
if it's the case of ransomware and it's
say a department-specific ransomware
where
maybe you have you know
20 or 30 people impacted a department
share but it hasn't become entity wide
so the end goal may be to get those
systems off the network cleaned up
in the sense that you know they're
completely rebuilt from scratch you
recover data from backups and and you're
good to go
maybe it's a global
outage and the end goal is to get just
some basics up and running again it's
going to vary but you're going to need
to work with these mid-level managers to
discuss that
managers do need to be accountable for
user and that does not mean we point
fingers it means they need to be aware
of the strengths and weaknesses of those
folks right and if you have folks that
are challenging and i think we all know
at least one person who falls in that
role
you need to figure out how they're going
to manage them
and the mid manager may look to you for
assistance with us but management needs
to take that responsibility
so these are some questions that you
want to be thinking about and asking
right
how are potential ransom payments going
to be handled
don't ask this question when it's on the
table i mean ultimately of course you
will but but think about this in advance
what are the situations in which you
absolutely wouldn't have a choice and
maybe you'll see a situation you've
never even thought of but but think
about that is there a case where that
would be
a thing and if so
how are you going to handle that
are you are you working with an
insurance company where they bring in
another organization that handles that
is is the answer just straight up nope
we're never paying a ransom and now
of course there are legal liabilities if
you pay a ransom or at least there is
legislation that suggests as much right
so some other things you want to ask you
know is this something where we can
collaborate with another unit
so is mid management going to manage all
of whatever they're working on or are
they going to delegate some of this out
are they going to delegate or they may
be going to negotiate with another
entity whether it's internal or external
to help and these are all decisions that
mid-level managers are going to need to
think about and make decisions about
during an incident
all right top of the tree here let's
talk about those executives
executives require a little more finesse
because they're looking at that big
picture
the overall company's goals reputation
performance their vision
and they have very little time
now obviously in certain situations they
may make more time for you
than usual
however
you still want to think you've got 30
seconds in an elevator
so let's imagine
you're going to hang out with fido here
in the elevator and you know the exact
some executive in your organization
how are you going to tell them what they
need to know in approximately 30 seconds
now that's not to say that at the end of
that they might not ask you for more but
imagine that's all you have
so you need to do your homework you need
to understand as much as you can about
these individuals
you don't want to wait until you're in
the middle of this
understand how your executives like
communication
because you might have communication
options depending on
what is going on
for the channel right maybe this
individual really really really hates
one-on-ones or really really likes
one-on-ones so remember when we were
talking about the communication channel
well you're going to consider both the
situation itself and the people you're
talking to in terms of what might the
best option be
you want to enter and exit gracefully
regardless of what they say to you the
tone of voice they use
be professional it can be very
frustrating if you're not taken
seriously or if somebody's panicking you
don't want to respond in kind
so think about that
you're going to present and discuss
strategically if they ask you to talk
further
write about that particular
information
that you started with the 30 seconds
right so if they do want to talk further
and whatever you say it needs to to
involve some sort of strategy and at the
end of the day
remember these people they're just
people too many of them have families
and home lives and it can be really easy
to lose sight of that because they're
the big boss so and so
but
they are people
this is the kind of thing your executive
will probably want to know
they're going to want a non-technical
description of what happened and when
non-technical even at the say cio level
they may want non-technical because
their strength may be in business not so
much the actual technology itself
remember when we talked about the
possible options at mid-level management
well
this is where you're going to
potentially
provide this additional information
maybe you're in that at that level
you're going to give them the best case
in the worst case and what's most likely
and ideally the consequences of what
happened and underlying causes if you
know them and again you're going to
leave out technical jargon um we're not
going to dive too deeply into this
you're going to do it from that big
picture
so when speaking to executives we're
going to avoid the techno babble we're
going to avoid the geek speak the lingo
our buzzwords right all of this kind of
stuff gets in the way of us
communicating that message
so which executive should you get that
message to
well you want to make sure that
ultimately if it's a large
company-wide incident you want to get it
to all of these groups
because finance may be impacted
what we saw recently with the pipeline
right the issue there the initial issue
there was quite frankly their billing
system went down well that's that's
finance right but operations is impacted
because it's it's going to impact
whether it's some portion of the org or
a larger portion of the org probably is
going to impact
their
operation from some perspective
you may need to let hr know this is
going to depend on the size of the
incident and how many folks are involved
you certainly want your heads of
marketing or communications or pr
whatever you have and maybe you have all
three
and this will depend again on their
function in your organization
but those executives should understand
that there's something happening
legal certainly and in fact i would
probably bump legal up the food chain to
one of the highest parts because
especially if you're going to be dealing
with any kind of legal ramifications
from something like ransomware you're
going to need legal and you're going to
need them to understand what's going on
so they can advise you properly and of
course if you haven't already told it
they should know too right
so the question is we've gone to each of
these groups
we've discussed
or maybe you know you went to one group
and a co-worker of yours went to another
and you've told them all of these things
you've given them the right information
you've tried to relay the best you can
what you understand about this you've
tried to frame it in the best possible
way for them to understand it
the question is
just because you said it
doesn't mean that they understood it
so
whether or not
they got the message
you may not know
one of the ways
we can know whether a message is
received is non-verbal communications
now obviously we talked about these
different channels right these different
communication channels
you're not going to have a sense of
nonverbal communication if it's just an
email
you're not going to have this if it's in
some other messaging you know teams app
perhaps where it's just some sort of
text it can be very difficult to read
any kind of non-verbals and we can
misread that very easily
but if there's any kind of one-on-one
whether it's in person or over zoom for
example
or some other mechanism
there's usually some non-verbals and
that's what we're going to talk about
next
we want to pay very
close attention to body language right i
mean look at these faces
you know what's going on with these kids
right you know who's really angry who's
who's quizzical
who's surprised
we can see that in their body language
so it includes all of these kinds of
things whether it's facial expressions
or posture the kind of gestures we make
it can come across in something as
simple as a handshake or how someone is
breathing so that's the kind of thing
that we're talking about
so how do we interpret these nonverbal
cues that we see because people give
nonverbal cues all the time
so what happens if somebody has raised
eyebrows right how do we interpret that
well the problem is there's multiple
ways that many of these things can be
interpreted
raised eyebrows can be you know surprise
they can be doubt
they could be some form of discomfort
if i'm staring right into your eyes
and i don't blink and there's excessive
eye contact
is it because i'm like super interested
in what you're saying
or is it because
i'm really trying very hard not to let
you know that i'm lying to you
because if i stare right at you maybe
maybe you'll think you know i'm i'm
giving it my all and it doesn't matter
and
um
you know that that can be misleading
what about crossed arms and legs
i think we've all gone into meetings
where people cross their arms and legs
so
does that mean they necessarily are
close to an idea which is a cue we can
get from that
or
did someone turn the heat off in a room
and it's cold or you know just maybe
somebody's not feeling well maybe their
mind's a million miles away
same thing with exaggerated knotting if
i'm doing this
all the time am i just really nervous
about whether or not you're accepting my
idea
or am i super excited about what you're
saying
the point is that any one of these cues
can be misleading
so we need to think about what we call
the nonverbal cues
and that's this idea where we read the
person and the situation and we sort of
blend it together right so if we have a
situation where somebody has their
eyebrows raised their eyes are looking
all over the place and they're maybe
gripping something really hard
odds are
if all of those things come together
there's a sense of discomfort
so we need to take each one of those
cues and pull them together as opposed
to just looking at them individually
all right so i'm going to wrap up here
one of the things i want to make sure to
get across is that our job i believe
very strongly that our job in security
is to educate
that's my number one job all the
technology stuff i do throughout my day
and i do a whole bunch i wear tons of
hats in our office because we have very
few people i do incident response i do
forensics i do awareness i do all kinds
of things
but regardless of which of those
technical things i'm doing or
non-technical things i'm doing
i believe my job is to educate
if i'm writing a forensics report it's
to educate through my words if i'm
giving us a talk i'm trying to educate
through
the uh the verbal word as opposed to the
written word
we are not there to adjudicate
incidents are hard
nobody i think really enjoys walking
into an incident
and having to be you know kind of in the
middle of that and the stress of the
incident i mean certainly those of us
who are incident responders
um
you know there is a certain excitement
and and i can't deny that there are
people who really enjoy that rush and
that's awesome
but everybody else is probably really
uncomfortable and so remember that we
don't want to be the folks who are
making judgment
we want to learn what other people know
one of the jobs that i had early on when
i was doing support i worked for an
entity
that
was a government contractor
and you know the the jokes people like
to make about
it's not rocket science
guess what
these folks are rocket scientists and
they were super duper smart
guess what i don't know a whole lot
about rocket science guess what they
didn't know a whole lot about
computing day-to-day desktop computing
boy did they know their rocket science
in that level
but you know using microsoft word that
was a little more challenging
so
i taught them
about
how to do what they needed to and the
tools that they were given for that
purpose
and they taught me some cool things you
know about rocket science now i'll be
honest i don't remember a whole lot
about it right now
um but the reality is we need to share
our knowledge as i mentioned before
we really don't know what they don't
know and they don't know what we don't
know and so communicating and sharing
communication is absolutely a two-way
goal
you want to share
information you want that person to give
you some feedback so that you know in
some capacity that they understood you
and vice versa
i'm a big proponent of be that change
you see folks out there who you know
treat folks not well
don't be that person
and i'm gonna i'm gonna skip the
question slide because we're gonna we're
gonna go do that online uh but i wanna
end with this thought
um this douglas adams quote because as i
mentioned i started my journey in
security really with end user and server
support that's where i started and i had
no idea i was even going to go there
i have an in my initial degree is
actually in music industry i have
several other degrees that have nothing
directly to do with security
but i think ultimately regardless of
that i ended up where i needed to be
which is why i love this quote
and with that i will thank you very much
for coming to hear me today
[Music]
go