[Music]
hi everybody
my name
and is
or is my name it's not a nickname and
i'm here to talk to you about javascript
obfuscation it's all about the packers
um
and as we move forward uh toward the end
of the presentation hopefully uh the
meaning of
of the name of the presentation would
make much more sense
um and maybe we will decide to change
the name of the presentation we will see
as we move forward
um
so let's start from the beginning right
uh i will introduce myself shortly um as
i mentioned my name is orikatz i'm from
aust israel chapter lead i work for
akamai
um i'm a data driven security researcher
which means
well
at least at my eyes that i'm really
really focused on data but i'm really
focused with data to get security
insights and and
and more to that
when i try to classify what i do my well
always my goal my objective is to to to
take security challenges and turn them
into science and solutions to move them
into the science and the solution space
um
and last but not least i have very
boring social network persona therefore
i will not encourage you to follow me on
my twitter account or underscore cats
really boring i'm tweeting once every
few weeks and it's boring don't do that
i encourage you not to do that
um
so let's start the presentation so
in a sense well my presence started um
over a year ago in a sense i was doing
some research research about javascript
obfuscation
and i published three different blog
posts on in that context um
the first one was more into
different techniques being used to
obviously javascript code
the second one was taking one very um
relevant example for office kd
javascript and trying to de-obfuscate
that given code which is the picture
that you see on the right on the screen
and the third one was to try to do some
more statistical point of view on the of
javascript foscation on the landscape
and and and when i was doing that
research and publishing that um looking
at that given an example that you can
see on the right it took quite some time
to do that it took me you know
a matter of skill set and a matter of
resources and time to do the obfuscation
and i asked myself the question can i do
that
in a much better way can i do that on
very high scale kind of execution of
that same thing or very similar to that
um so that was my first objective uh and
the second objective in that content was
to be able to take a javascript code and
being able to identify that as being
javascript code being obfuscated um
with a
with a preferable kind of result that
can enable me to say if that giving
javascript code is actually malicious
right or physician well and we will talk
about it obfuscation is not always means
something bad
and we'll try to explain that a bit more
uh during the presentation now
the third
objective that i had
the third objective that i had was to do
that on
static analysis kind of you know and um
you know
looking into the data and what that mean
you can take javascript and do rendering
for the javascript and then try to
understand what the javascript is
actually doing but i
one of my objectives is not to do that
for many reasons and some of them are
related to performance and we will talk
about that and and try to better explain
that later on
and my final objective you know at the
beginning of that research was to try to
assume the pareto principle
and priority principles say the
following thing
80 of the outcome is a result of 20
percent of the causes
and and
in our context is
well i
don't
uh try to solve the entire uh javascript
fuscation um um
phenomena or the detection javascript
confiscation phenomena i'm trying to
detect 80 of the cases that i consider
them creating being created by twenty
percent of the javascript obfuscation
packers all right packers are the the
software that will uh take a uh a
javascript code and do a deal
sorry obfuscation of that given code so
that's my assumption i'm not trying to
detect all the the coverage that we have
out there for javascription only part of
that
with that in mind a few questions that
cross my mind
uh first question was uh why and how
javascript is being office game
um
and we'll address that in the in the
following um um slide
the second question that came to mind is
what are the numbers out there right so
i'm into the
um you know um goal of trying to detect
a javascript being obfuscated in the
wild in in scale kind of
uh capabilities but the question is how
that
javascript frustration phenomena
is widely used in the
in the wild right so that's a question
that i have in mind that i wanted to
address and we will answer that
uh the third question that crossed my
mind was so jeopardy confiscation does
it always mean malicious or not so so
the spoiler for that it's and i assume
that most of you or some of you are are
familiar with that is that affiliation
doesn't mean a bad thing right but we'll
go over that and see some example and
try to better understand once javascript
is being used in a while and it's not
malicious what are the use cases and
what we're seeing out there
and the final question was is it
possible to detect javascript for
sketching right uh and we will go over
that and try to figure out how to do
that uh from a technical point of view
and following to that we will also try
to address you know some of the
questions that we well as i said i
appear some spoiler for that we know
that not always javascript being
obfuscated means something bad therefore
can we differentiate be between
javascript that was obfuscated
and means something good versus
something that mean something bad mean
malicious in that context
so this is part of the thing we're going
to cover
today um so let's start from the first
question right why and how javascript is
being obscured and to try to better
understand the why
we need to discuss javascript right
javascript is a client-side uh code
right it's a code that is being exposed
to the end users being
executed most cases on our browser
and once being executed we actually know
what the code is supposed to do before
it's been executed because it's it's
visible to us as opposed to server-side
code right and in that context
that can explain why javascript is being
obfuscated and regardless if it's for a
good reason or a bad reason right
regardless if you are trying to
obfuscate a legit kind of code or you're
trying to obfuscate the malicious code
because if someone wants
to make sure that it will be hard for
you to understand
what that code being executed on your
browser is doing you will try to
auto-escape the code and try to make it
much harder for you to try to understand
the context of the code the
functionality of the code and once the
code is actually executing right it's
not impossible but it makes your your
life much harder to understand when
someone is doing that
now
in order to do that it will probably
create a code that is unreadable and
debuggable
and when you think about it in the
context of malicious code
or even a benign code in many cases it
will create a code that is obfuscated
because it will invade the variety of
detection techniques that are using
text-based or hash-based detection
capabilities
so it could be someone that
created a code that it doesn't want um
for example search engines to see what
uh
this code really represent from a
texture point of view so we will do an
obfuscation for that
uh you can imagine for example we see
one of those examples
an email address if someone created
um contain an email address in the
content of the page and you want to
obfuscate that you might use javascript
frustration to try to hide in that
context because you don't want search
engine to find that
kind of information or just you know uh
scanner internet scanners or variety of
you know bots that scan the internet now
from malicious point of view if someone
created a polymorphism kind of code that
constantly change if you try to unders
if you try to
track that code by creating signatures
that are text based or hash based
obviously detection will not work
because the code is the well
the representation of the malicious code
continuously changing as we create new
samples of an obfuscated code of that
same malicious uh
originally malicious code so this is the
why right and how well there are a
variety of techniques and i will go over
three of those that are well the most
popular and the most you know
um common being used so you can create
an app you know to create an obvious key
code you can create a code that is
repetitive or meaningless
in the context of the function names in
the context of the variables that are
being used
and once you are doing that that makes
the code unreadable and in a way
undebugable
you can use an anti-debugging code
techniques in order to make sure that if
someone will try to debug your code it
will be harder for him to do that right
um it's not impossible again uh at the
end of the day it's code that is being
executed on the client and therefore
it's always possible to do that but it
might make your life much harder to do
this once someone is putting more traps
in that code
and finally well using a code that is
doing um
um computer kind of resources and time
exhausting meaning running dead code
that just being you know executed
without any meaning which will create
much more time for the page to be
rendered
or pointing putting timers into the code
being executed we'll create a situation
where a given code will take much more
time to be executed to be rendered and
as a result of that will create some
issues from a performance point of view
and this will
and this given item is actually related
to
to one of my objectives from the
beginning when i said that i don't want
to create a
solution that has a performance issue
therefore i'm not rendering the page so
that was my incentive from the
beginning now how the story start right
uh so i told you at the beginning
that a year ago i was looking into some
javascript code and was doing some
publication around that and while i was
doing that i was
seeing four different examples for
javascript coding office cadence right
the for example that you see on the
screen so this is a part of the code
this is a one function being taken from
different samples of code
and when you look at that at first
glance you can say hey it's it's not the
same right it's different
but if you take a second glance on on on
that given code you do zoom out
you will see that actually there is some
pattern here that repeats itself in a
sense right
but i will tell you hey it's a different
it's a different
code in the context of well the meaning
and the context of the code being
executed because those four different
examples representing the the
the two upper examples are representing
phishing examples one for a bank and one
for some social networks
and on the bottom you can see on the
left side it's mage card kind of
javascript being obfuscated on on the
right side it's a mellow dropper being
off escape
so wait
it's different samples of code that we
say that they look a bit different but
we said that they look
look a bit the same right the same
pattern but they're actually different
because they are actually executing a
different kind of threat using different
kind of functionality of javascript to
execute you know
different kind of you know
threats to to the clients
but what we're actually what we're
seeing is it's an obfuscated function
being used by the same packer
on those four different examples and
this is the pattern that i was looking
for right it's an anomalous javascript
function that has a variable that that
variable contains a name of the function
well a function in a sense and that
function is doing a while with in a
decreasing kind of uh
um
way on an integer that was applied to
the original function
and inside that while we are doing some
reshuffling of
one
of the parameters that was originally
supplied to the upper function doing
some
um shifting and pushing meaning doing
changes of that given array being
supplied
the elements of the order of the
elements of that array
and that is actually the return value of
that function so that's a classic
obfuscated function being executed by a
given packer right
so now comes the question
so we understand that there are the same
threats or well different threats being
used using the same packer to do the
same functionality of obfuscation
now the question comes so
can we actually detect that pattern
right we don't want to detect the name
of the variable we don't want to take
things that are constantly changing as
we saw before but we want to detect that
given pattern of the functionality being
executed so in order to do that what i
was doing i created a proof of concept
for that uh in in that proof of concept
what i was using is an ast kind of um
representation of javascript code ast is
an abstract syntax tree it takes the the
given code it will create a structure
for that code and if you can see on the
left side
that's one of the example that we see
the page before this is the on the right
side now you can see that the
representation of that in ast right
uh so it's a structured kind of way to
represent some of the code being
executed
now if we will try to think on the
pattern that we were looking before
right without the verbal name without
things that might change from
one implementation to the other
just the functionality so when we look
on the ast tree and we will look on
specific places we might ask ourselves a
question do we see a structure that has
a function and that function has a y
statement
and it's a decreasing kind of while
on an integer and can we see some
pushing and shifting of a given element
in an array so that's the way for me to
that that was the way for me to take the
concept of trying to find patterns
of
obfuscated functions or obfuscated
packers and try to implement that and
that's the proof of concept that i
created i'm taking a javascript code i'm
doing an astr presentation for that i'm
running on that looking into the for the
pattern that i you know was able to
create and if i am seeing that i'm
actually matching the detection and i
was doing that in python
so that's the concept and that the
technique for me to detect those kind of
signatures right the those pattern-based
signatures of obfuscated code and i was
doing that for five different packers
obviously packers right um and here are
the five well you can see three the the
other page has another two so the first
two are actually a basic ones um
both of them are doing uh decryption or
unescaping of values which are really
really well basic from uh um
from a fuscation point of view they are
not really complex um
and most of the well at least it's the
second one i i knew that it's an old one
that mostly been used for fishing
websites
uh the third one and and well the third
and fourth and the fifth are actually
well they are different but they are the
same
they are different because it's a
different implementation but there's
they are the same because all of them
are actually doing some sort of a
manipulation of a given payload
someone is providing a payload and those
functions will try to do some splitting
of the data doing rent while doing
reshifting or um changing the order of
the data
doing some padding or adding you know
some um encoding mechanism on the given
data base64 or your url encoding kind of
uh decryption
so that's the first those are the five
different examples five different
examples that represent five different
packers then i decided that i want to
focus my research on those examples and
all those examples only
and i gave each of those different uh
packers a name uh actually i was doing
that a bit randomly
as you can see on example number four
which is called packer right with a dash
between the the letters so i decided to
do that because
once you call that function the name of
the variables or the parameters being uh
delivered to that function are p a c
k e r which represent becker
and that's how i named that given um
um pecker that i'm that i'm trying to
find a way to detect it in the world
so we have that functionality
we have you know the proof of concept of
taking a javascript page being able to
do some
uh parsing of the page being able to run
on that parsing and match some
signatures that i created for five
different uh packers uh javascript
frustration packers
here's some of the results right we need
to verify that we're doing the right
work here so
on the left you can see the five
different packers and you can see that i
the first data set that i used was a
fishing web
phishing data set
uh of over 100 000 urls and i was able
to see there's really decent result for
that meaning the the assumption that i
created a pattern based detection for
office skating
um functionality representing different
javascript packers
uh created some result nice result from
from my point of view and i was doing
that on a malware data set as well with
even better results in terms of
of the number of hits that i was able to
see but it's more than that because that
those two data set represents something
malicious i wanted to do on also the
other side which try to see if those
same function well that same
proof of concept can also be executed on
data that is supposed to be legitimate
right in order to do that
i used alexa ranking
um
18 000 top most ranked website in the
world
and the interesting part is that i start
to see hits
on those websites as well
and i was doing that also on a random
data set of of domains that in that
context they are not represent well they
are not highly ranked as opposed to
alexa and they are representing
something more spreaded from a
popularity point of view and i was able
to see um very similar hits to alexa
being
done on that data set as well
so these are the numbers right the
percentage of detection of each of those
data sets and you can see obviously that
those that are classified as malicious
had will hit rate much higher in terms
of percents
um
versus those that represent benign
benign data sets
and i was doing some you know trying to
figure out what are the insights that i
can take from this data what's the
interesting part
and i was doing some you know uh
analysis of that
and what i was able to see the first
conclusion which is a good one which
means that
the technique that i was using the
javascript function and detection is
accurate
or in other words i was going into the
alexa and the random data set and try to
see if there is for example
matching there for the
pattern that i was looking for
that that pattern is for
you know reason that i cannot explain
represents something that is not that
given obfuscation techniques that i was
looking for
okay uh and in that sense when once
looking into those i was able to see
that those hits were actually
representing
and obfuscation techniques the same
foscation technique that i was looking
for but they were hits on the benign
data set that i was using or in other
words what we can learn from that
is that obfuscation is obviously um not
being used only for malicious content
it's also been
used for a benign content which is an
interesting thing
now the second part that the the second
insight that those who was able to see
is that i had really good result right i
have over 4 000 different new phishing
and malware urls or domains in the
context of this exam
that are actually
being detected
as the running obfuscated code and in
that sense it gave me an advantage
because one of my goals to be able to do
that on scale to do that kind of
detection
and it's important to say that well once
you try to do that you know techniques
as i mentioned before
those that are using text based or hash
based detection that were obviously
failing
in the context of javascript being
obfuscated
in the new technique that i just
introduced
they are actually being detected
correctly and i can see those hits and i
can actually create some detection that
i didn't have before
now few more interesting thing we can
see that some of those packers are
actually associated with malicious
activity for example the aes decrypt
function or the cactus
which are mostly being used for phishing
attacks
um
and that's interesting because that
means that if i will detect that kind of
activity that kind of an obfuscation
activity
according to this this data set i can
assume that it's malicious right it
doesn't has implication on benign kind
of data set therefore
it can be indicated so a strong
indicator for uh javascript being
observed but more than that it's
malicious
and finally as as i said before um
what we learned from here is that
obfuscation is different than malicious
right there's also benign usage
for javascript being obfuscated so
that's interesting right um
so a few questions that come after that
right um
the first question is so we talked about
benign website well legitimate website
that are being obfuscated so the first
question come to my mind is so what does
it mean why those websites are actually
trying to obfuscate some of their code
and i look into that so that's the first
question and soon we'll see the answers
the second question was okay so
well we understand that obfuscation is
different than malicious well meaning
frustration can also
represent benign
so how can we differentiate between
something that is obfuscated
uh and it's benign versus something
obfuscated that is malicious and that's
the next step for us to do
so as i mentioned so we know that some
of those benign examples of domains that
were sampled uh are actually
representing inaudible using obfuscation
technique and i asked myself so
why it's being done so here are a few of
the answers for that first of all as i
mentioned at the beginning of the
presentation uh email addresses for some
reason
some website decide to do some
confiscation for that and make those
email addresses
not being visible if you look into that
um without doing rendering to the page
and that there this is their way to try
to evade
um you know
variety of scanners or
search engines or you know whatever bot
we see out there trying to harvest those
kind of email addresses
again i don't agree that that's the
right approach but that what they were
doing
i was able to see a variety of
cookie clients and functionality being
obfuscated again i'm not sure it's too
right and or the relevant thing to do
but that what those website are doing
trying to obviously they're called
trying to make it
um to create some security by obscurity
in that context
um many examples for third-party scripts
being obfuscated uh scripts for
advertisements scripts for doing
translation of services you can think
about it like that let's say that on a
third party i create some javascript
code that is supposed to be integrated
into a variety of website
i might decide to do some obfuscation
for that code to make it unreadable or
not well understood to those that will
look at first glance into that code
and again it's security by obscurity in
that context but that's something that
happens in the world and that's what we
are seeing here
and last well was uh adult content that
is well
in a sense uh
a grayish area kind of you know websites
that has a lot of you know issues with
them that related to security and
obviously
for some reason well not obviously but
for some reason there are more using
those kind of affiliation into their
code
so we talked about what are the example
that we see out there then comes the
question so how can we differentiate it
how can we take a given javascript code
that was identified as being obfuscated
and try to differentiate between the
benign use case and the malicious use
case in order to do this i will use a
technique that has two approaches
approach a and approach b approach a
will try to do a loudly approach b will
try to do the blocking
now what does it mean let's talk about
the allow list so what i was doing i was
saying okay so let's take all the benign
data that i have which means the random
and alexa data set
and i was doing some sort of a pivoting
around few well three different elements
the blue element the blue circles that
you can see here the domain names
the orange one is actually the hash
value of those
javascript code being obfuscated right
and the greyish one the bigger one are
representing alexa and random so in a
sense what i'm showing here is very
similar to the third party example that
that i mentioned
is that once the same code that was
supposed to be integrated to many
different third party code that is
different websites is being used in the
wild we are starting to see some
relationship between them and that
relationship can help us to take it to
the next level and say let's try let's
try to create allow list allow list that
will tell us that yes if we see that
given code that it's an obfuscated code
but we are familiar with that with that
code because we were able to profile
that code as being used by many
different websites out there that has
really great
popularity ranks or something like that
that by itself can reduce 20 of the
problem meaning out of the
nearly 240
domains that i was able to see that our
hosting with our benign domain that our
hosting uh obviously the javascript
twenty percent of them were actually
solved like was we're able to solve them
and try to classify them as allow list
because they can see a reuse of the same
functionality
same javascript functionality being used
by those different domains so that was
the first step of the approach which we
called it the allow list
the second part of the approach that i'm
trying to suggest is that the project is
based on machine learning
and the basic concept is the following
right let's say that i can see a
javascript that is being obfuscated in
that context
now come the question can we retrieve
can we pull up some um
features out of that javascript code
that will enable us to make more
decision based on those features maybe
those feature will enable us to
differentiate between b9
javascript being obfuscated versus
malicious javascript being off scheme so
first example for such um feature would
be um array kind of um
[Music]
object being used in javascript
and many of those functions are actually
taking a raise and put the payload
inside that array so feature would be
for example number of elements in the
array
the length of the
elements uh what kind of characters are
being used
as part of those
elements um can we see some prefix of
encoded kind of values being used so
these are for example some example for
features
different kind of feature could be for
example the
identifiers or well um identifiers
that are being used as part of that
javascript code right identify could be
variable name function name
any name convention that happened in
that page
so if we can for example count the
amount the amount of identifiers being
used or maybe we can say hey if we see
identifiers that start with underscore
zero x
which you can see on screen that's an a
very common kind of technique being used
to try to create the code that is not
readable uh maybe that's an indicator
maybe we can count those numbers and
those numbers will enable us to make a
better decision again between benign and
malicious
so here is example of plotting uh of two
of those um
features that i decided to use right
and in order to better understand i was
deciding to focus on a very specific
packer the
the push shift packer because i was able
to see that that given packer is being
used for both benign and both malicious
kind of um use cases
and i plotted two of those features
under on on the left on the y's you can
see the number of unique identifiers
number of verb well
as i imagine identifiers would be
a variable's name functions name array
names
those kind of you know those things
those objects are representing
identifiers in that context
and on the x's what you can see is the
number of elements in in array that i
was able to see
and first look on that graph give us
pretty good answers and why
because we can see that they're
different classification very easy
classification that can enable us to
make decision
the most right uh um rectangle and the
most upper left one actually
representing two groups that represent
just malware activity
and as a result of that if we can use
those features
we can easily be able to identify
javascript code that is being used and
has the relevant numbers
associated with those features as
something being classified as malicious
but we're still having some problem
because we can see that in the in the
center of the graph
we have um values for both b9
in other words alexa um
uh random and malware being mixed
together so we want to better look into
that so i
zoom into that and what we can see here
is we still have some ability to do
something here because we see still see
that there is some differentiation here
when it comes to the values for those
features in the context of benign versus
malicious
so
this is only this is the graph
this is a graph with two
um
features being used think about it from
a machine learning point of view you use
many features
that will enable you to take even that
small group and try to differentiate it
between benign malicious
and this is what i was doing i was doing
for the sake of of experiment the usage
of three different features uh the first
one is number of
identifiers uh starting with underscore
0x
the second feature was the number of
elements in an array and the third one
was the number of unique identifiers i
was able to see on a given script
and i created the decision tree based on
a random forest algorithm that was
running
and when i was looking into the only the
right
most um
the right path on that tree
and try to better understand what that
this tree can help me in the context of
being able to identify between something
that is benign versus malicious
what you can see is that if we will take
those three features we'll ask number of
underscore zero x identifier bigger than
and well on a given script and on that
given script we can also see that there
is an array with over 17 different
elements
and more to that there are unique
identifiers greater than
only that path on the tree will enable
me to solve
over
750 of the samples that i was able to
see and classified them as malicious and
by that eliminate some of the problem
that i was having was having and in in
that concept try to better explain and
understand
how a machine learning module can help
me make a decision based on you know
some of those features that we were able
to classify
so in that context we have an approach
we built something that we can do some
detection we know how to detect
javascript that is being used in the
while and represents something that is
office k javascript officially being
used
uh we were using some technique to try
to differentiate between benign and
malicious now how can we use it in a
more practical kind of way
so our first approach would be to
implement well the technique that i was
just showing you right um
the core functionality of detecting
javascript being obfuscated and then
building some module that is based on
the allow list and the block list and
try to better understand if we look into
a given javascript whether it's
malicious or not that's one thing to do
a different thing that we might want to
do is we'll try to use the core
functionality of
identify well identifying javascript
being obfuscated
and use it in the context of our website
for example if we look into our website
and scan the website and see that there
is no javascript office data javascript
being
used on the website and suddenly we're
doing another scan of that kind of
website and find an example of something
being obfuscated
that by itself should you know
alarm us and they should take us to the
next step of trying to better understand
what's the reason the code is there is a
legit third-party feed it was integrated
is it something uh that was injected to
the website uh major kind of scam so
that's another use case that we might
want to use a different approach would
be to enrich some of the data that we
have with other indicators for example
if you can see javascript code being
obfuscated we can also ask ourselves
what's the age of the domain is it the
newly registered domain or is it an old
domain newly registered domain that has
javascript being obfuscated in it
my assumption is that most likely right
it's not
it's not a boolean decision most likely
the chances that that website contains
something malicious is much higher than
expected
a different kind of indicator can be a
popularity of the website if a website
that is highly popular has some
javascript been obfuscated well it could
be nice on our if it's well website that
it's not highly popular
maybe we can make a decision based on
that maybe it's not the right decision
but maybe it's a decision that we can't
take meaning if some website is not
really popular and i can see javascript
being obfuscated if
even if it's not malicious blocking that
website will not
be something so dramatic from a
defensive point
right
so this is some of the approaches from a
uh realistic or practical point of view
um
a few of the questions that we have in
the beginning right we had four
questions why and how javascript has
been obfuscated and we covered that
uh what are the numbers behind uh the
usage of jobs within the wild you
absolutely obscure in the why we saw
numbers related to that as well
uh we answered the question that we
actually answered at the beginning but
we actually explained that a bit uh more
in depth around javascript obfuscation
and whether that represents something
malicious or not
and last we actually talked about the
different techniques that we can use in
order to identify javascript being
obfuscated and more to that we took into
the next level of trying to
differentiate between benign and
malicious javascript
so what are the next steps for me right
um because i'm not done yet um
i want to release the code i'm not there
yet uh i need to still work on that
hopefully i will do that in the
following month um
maybe add another signature for
additional packers i use only five in
this experiment uh while doing that i
i was able to see more
packers uh like looking into the data
and was able to see something that was
able to miss
and i acknowledge that those are
packers that i was that i didn't created
the signature for those package from the
beginning
uh so maybe i'm adding those uh refining
some of the data that i was doing uh
more rich data more
um you know if more volumetic data will
might
result with a bit different um insights
that i want to do
that i want to have in that context
add more feature to the machine learning
algorithm
in order to
better to have better decisions
based on
um
well to have better detection in the
context of
looking into javascript code
being obfuscated and we want to make
sure that we are making the right
decision know how to differentiate
between malicious and benign and as much
feature as you take well it's not always
that but
taking the right features to represent
uh the ability to better detect is
something that i need to um
do some more work around that
and last ability to create uh maybe the
capability of actually detecting those
patterns right um those five different
packers that i
uh used i
did
well i was discovering the pattern
manually
now comes the question can we do that
automatically can we go over some code
and try to figure out if there are some
patterns on that code
representing something very unique to
javascript obfuscation packers that can
be used in that context
um so at the beginning i told you that
the name of the presentation it's all
about the packers
uh with the dashes between the letters
and i during the presentation explain
what's the reason for that uh it's one
of the functions that i was able to see
right and you can see that example here
and and the interesting part is that
while i was doing that uh i was at well
i was telling myself hey i cannot use
those fireballs as an indicator for that
given functionality that obfuscation
functionality being used in the while
i i want to ignore them they are not
relevant and i was doing the right
decision because as i was doing that uh
suddenly i was able to detect another
variation of that same functionality of
the same obfuscation functionality but
this time using
instead of packer using the
the letters representing pect right
good for me
but as i continue i was able to see
another example using something entirely
different again using the same
functionality from an obfuscation point
of view by using different variables
to that functionality
representing something that starts with
underscore 0x right
and therefore i thought to myself maybe
i should change the name of the
presentation to something that you can
read at home and i don't want to read it
now um
that's just hopefully a funny anecdote
i think we're i'm done for today
um and i'm
available for
questions
so let me just
go to the relevant place
looking for some questions
i don't see any given uh
questions out though out there
if there are any please let me know
and we wait few minutes and we will
drink some water
because i need it
if no question comes in
so um feel free to reach out to me uh
the emmy uh i'm here to answer your
questions
um
[Music]
i think we are done for today
thank you very much everybody