[Music]
hey everyone and welcome to our happy
little con it's circle city con 8.0
it's been a heck of a year a year we
really couldn't predict except we did
predict it because last year was the
apocalypse and um we decided that back
in august of 2019 sorry
about that we couldn't resist uh trying
our newfound power of prediction
and uh yeah so we had to uh we had to
work with that and uh that was a pretty
strong that was a pretty strong
confirmation that we have
uh foresight into the future and
clairvoyance so we're going to put that
to good use and we are going to now
predict and declare that we're going to
have a happy little con
uh and happy years and happy times are
to come
and uh so yeah so we hope that you'll
enjoy this conference we hope you will
engage in the joy of hacking and
learning and training
uh learning how to use all these happy
little tools that we get to use
creating happy little buffer overflows
happy little sequel injections all these
little happy little accidents we like to
have
um
with uh when when trying to test
people's security
uh so join me in
this opening ceremony as we go through
and show you what all
circle citycon 8.0 has to offer you this
year
uh we do have to start off with our code
of conduct yes just because we're not in
person doesn't mean a code of conduct
doesn't apply uh everyone who got into
the discord uh over the past few days uh
you did have to click
on a
agreement that said you were going to
follow this and we will be
holding everyone to account for this
including people like myself
let me read it for everyone just real
quick so everyone's keen and down on the
sickness
uh we have no tolerance for physical
verbal sexual harassment of any human
our code of conduct is be excellent to
each other okay the golden rule
failing that
is don't be an or we will kick
your ass out
asking questions of a speaker during
their talk
to get clarity or debate or debate a
point is not being an ass but heckling
and haranguing the speaker is if you're
not sure
ask or err on the side of basic decency
and common courtesy
if what you're doing would not be
acceptable to have done to you your best
friend your worst enemy your sister
niece daughter brother nephew son mother
father or any other human don't do it
also do not let another person treat
anyone else that way whether you know
them or not if someone asks you to stop
stop
if you're having an issue with the
circle citicon participant of any badge
type
find a radioed member
don't have radios this year but you can
check out uh some uh check out a
moderator on discord uh they're on the
right side of your discord there's gonna
be a section called security and uh it
should be mods or security and you
should be able to reach out to any one
of those who are online and you should
be able to grab a moderator and report
uh or talk about something that has uh
that has violated the code of conduct
um and they will assist you in
determining next steps steps
that is make sure you feel safe and hurt
if a moderator is cause for concern for
any reason or a staff member is a cause
of concern please bring it to myself i'm
odd job you can also bring it up with
dns princess and you can also reach out
to jocelyn we're three people you can
reach out to and we will also take
take appropriate measures um as well so
that's an immediate escalation in case
you need it but please do if it's a
participant please do reach out to the
moderators staff does reserve the right
to determine what constitutes being an
ass
so just just bear that in mind
so getting into discord um so you should
have had a wonderful email come to you
but if not here's your chance you can
get into the discord by going to discord
gg circle citycon
uh there is also a video in the uh
welcome video that you see when you fill
up when you uh react to the code of
conduct there's a video on you on
youtube that's listed there
go ahead and watch that it's going to
show you how to check in the rest of the
way to the conference if you have any
issues
check out any of these helpful little
channels we have welcome and rules which
is where the code of conduct is we have
registration and support
we also have con support
so registration support can help you
just making sure your ticket is valid
getting in con support can help you with
pretty much anything else to go with the
conference
and we also have a job hunting channel
and it's open to the public so if you're
looking for work
and you're looking for jobs there's
going to be probably job postings from a
lot of different people on there
if you're looking to hire folks for your
team for special projects you're working
on feel free to put all the job
descriptions that you want in there we
want to get people hired we want to get
people into this industry we want to
show that the skills gap is uh is a hoax
it doesn't really exist we're all out
here we are all ready to uh to to get
hired into infosec um and we all we all
have wonderful skills so let's let's
help each other and let's help each
other get hired and let's help each
other enter into this wonderful
uh industry and this practice that we
love
uh there is a schedule uh you can go to
registration.circle citycon
it should be updated fairly regularly
but
any last second changes of course are
going to be announced via discord
announcements so that's the quickest way
to determine if there's a deviation from
the schedule
and of course our conference wouldn't
happen without the love and support from
multiple people and first we want to
thank our platinum sponsors uh blue
mirror
we also have checkpoint software
and we say that this conference really
couldn't happen without our sponsors but
we really mean it for lightspeed we
literally can't be delivering any of
this without our sponsors because
lightspeed is giving us the
infrastructure to actually stream all of
this to twitch
so you can thank lightspeed for us
having these available to you today
we also have reveal risk who is a silver
sponsor for us
you can also see our bronze sponsors
here black hills information security no
starch press optive security innovation
and wild west hack and fest
want to take we want to thank every one
of these for coming in uh several of the
sponsors also have booths down in the
sponsor section of discord they also
have voice channels so that you can have
voice and video conversations with them
and we encourage you to do so
um and see what they're about do some
networking they may be looking to hire
folks as well so it's never a bad idea
to jump in there and see if there's any
job openings people you want to work
with but also see what they're about see
what technologies see what solutions
they have available and
have great conversations having great
conversations with the sponsors uh as
part of what this is all about sharing
this information and connecting with
each other
uh we have uh an oh great opening and
closing keynotes
i have opening twice uh if it looks like
these uh slides were put together at the
last second uh you're very observant uh
opening keynote is by ray redacted who's
associate producer of dark net diaries
and uh a bit after this uh opening
ceremonies he's going to be presenting
on the complete and total history of
hacking at 3 000 seconds and i'm not
kidding it's actually 3 000 seconds a
closing not opening the closing keynote
is going to be by megan kaczynowski she
is the threat intelligence lead for snmp
global ratings
and she's going to be giving us the
secret to increasing your budget getting
promoted and expanding your team concise
and clear reporting so be sure to check
out these two wonderful speakers uh at
the opening and also at the closing of
this conference
we also want to take time to thank all
the other speakers who have uh who have
come to circle city con to share their
expertise share their knowledge their
research uh how we can be doing things
better how we're not doing things so
well maybe uh and how maybe we are doing
some great things out there how things
have changed uh we've been around in
infosec and hacking for quite a while as
ray's gonna ray's gonna point out and uh
there's some great things that have
happened over the past several decades
and there's some not so great things
there's some troubling things so these
folks are going to bring to to bear some
of those talents that they've been
cultivating uh for us and uh and and
talks that they've developed to share
with us
we do have the villages villages are
back this year uh we do have a hardware
hacking village um and thanks to cyber
city circuits you could you uh should
have been able to um
go out and purchase a solder kit that mr
blinster is going to show you how to
solder together over in the hardware
hacking village uh they do have a
schedule of some demos going on uh so
you can check in with them and be able
to see when they're going to be showing
you how to use oscilloscopes and
multimeters uh how they're going to
teach you about electrical components uh
there's several there's several
activities they have going on there so
be sure to check out get your soldering
iron out and uh
got mine right over here actually
get your soldering iron out and make
sure you go over to the hardware hacking
village also be sure to uh get out your
lock picks got my lock picks right here
and head over to the lock picking
village
uh lock picking village is going to show
you how locks work they have a few talks
and activities as well in there um and
demonstrations uh so you can go learn
how to how locks work how to how to get
better at lock sport and picking
uh and also other security
physical security considerations as well
we also have owls treehouse which is a
special kids area that we have this year
um and it has its own discord we do have
a channel in here that will be
essentially the gateway to that
discord server uh and
there's a couple main activities in
there there's going to be a pringles
enigma can so
uh
who doesn't like eating chips and doing
an infosec project
with just a pringle scan you can
actually create the very same machine
that was used
in world war ii to hide uh
communications um from from any
listeners so you can learn exactly how
the enigma uh log our algorithm and
everything works to figure out okay how
to do this i'm also going to show you
how to encode messages and decode
messages so there's going to be
wonderful activities in there for kids
uh kids are an add-on ticket this year
so if you go back into your ticket you
can just add on your kid you must
supervise them at all times but you are
welcome to join al's treehouse
we also have a happy little colors happy
little coloring sheet
it is available on the website as well
circlecitycon.com
as you can see our logo um you can just
go ahead and color inside the lines
color outside the lines that's fine it's
completely up to you this is your
coloring sheet you get to do whatever
you want with it
um if you want to put trees around it
you can put trees if you want bushes if
you want rivers if you want to color a
whole mountain behind it you can do that
it's a lot of things you can do with a
coloring sheet
and make sure you put your name on it
because if you
take a picture of it and you reply to
happy little colors we're going to
feature that on a live stream that we're
going to talk about in just a bit as
well
so we definitely want to engage not only
kids but also participants feel free to
uh take this opportunity to have a have
a coloring sheet and to sit down with
colored pencils markers watercolors
paints whatever you have
and uh be sure to
color in the beautiful coloring sheet we
have
we do have some happy little contests
two big contests we have this year is
capture the flag who which is being run
by the boilers this year uh from purdue
uh so we have uh capture the flag
ctf.circlecitycon.com
and you can register there if you want
to win prize uh you will have to be in
the discord so you'll have to actually
have a ticket and be in our discord
they're able to actually check to see
which your discord username is if you
have any troubles uh with some
mismatching they can also help support
you and make sure you get entered
incorrectly
if you are registered we will make sure
that you uh you are eligible for a prize
if you win
um and also radio radio frequency
capture the flag uh so we do also have a
rfctf brought to us by the rf hackers uh
you can go to rfctf-helpingdiscord
for anything that you have but you can
also go to circlecitycom.com
contests to learn about each of these
contests as well but i always recommend
going into the discord channels for ctf
and rfctf rfctf's very interesting this
year because all you need is a browser
or an ssh session
they're basically throwing up some
things in the cloud so that you can be
able to mess around with radio signals
sdr wi-fi
really fun stuff i hope you take
advantage of that if you've ever wanted
to learn wi-fi you don't have a hack rf
you don't have an sdr you don't have the
appropriate tools this is a perfect
opportunity to do so they also have
presentations on their website to show
you how to go about solving challenges
as well to give you some help
ah the joy of ms paint
so we have an ms paint contest this year
and we're going to judge that tomorrow
on circle city con live
um
basically what we want you to do is we
want you to take any of the artwork you
see around here
uh we also have some of this artwork on
the website um so we've got
we've got a hoot the owl we have mr j
the jaybird we have russia tosker the
squirrel loki the raccoon and we also
have
veni
the deer
my cousin vinnie we also have a rainbow
vomiting onto a paint palette uh so we
have that and you can also do the tree
pretty much anything that you see on our
logo and our artwork we want you to do
an ms pain of it uh we're gonna look for
most accurate depiction of what we see
on screen but we're also going to do an
award for most creative so if you want
to change the way any of these animals
look or their environment or do some
other things uh as well just given some
ideas
don't know what we're gonna see but
we're going to judge it all and the most
accurate to what we're seeing here on
screen uh without tracing by the way
tracing will disqualify you if we think
you're too accurate
we might decide to disqualify you that's
purely up to our subjective uh knowledge
um
yeah so
be sure to do that we'd love to see
everybody's art all you have to do then
is to submit you just have to go to
hashtag joyofmspaint on twitter and as
long as you upload that
and twitter we will uh make sure that we
take that into review and uh start start
looking to see who we want to uh want to
have when who's going to be the winner
we're looking forward to see all
of these wonderful uh wonderful ms
ms paint creations or monstrosities
it's ms payne after all
for entertainments we do have some
entertainments uh some throughout the
day and some through the night tonight
we're going to have uh a dnd session
that's uh that's a very different thing
that we've normally done so this is
going to be really fun to
join into d and d i'm going to be
joining the game
uh and several other uh people you may
or may not know are gonna be joining in
there but from 4 30 to
roughly eight somewhere around there
whenever the dm decides to quit or we
decided to run away and stop
we're going to be in a dnd session so we
welcome you to to watch and have fun uh
while you watch us play d and d uh if
you've ever seen harmonquest or some
other some other shows where they roll
20 or some other shows where they um
or whether it's critical hit whenever
you see
critical role actually
i can't remember all the different dnd
shows there and uh role play shows there
are if you've ever seen any of those
it's really fun to watch some of this
there's gonna be some drama there's
gonna be some some fun action happening
um but we hope you'll be entertained and
uh obviously we hope we win
so come see what will happen and befall
us as we venture in dnd
uh friday uh which is tonight we do have
cocktail con they're gonna be sharing uh
various things with us talking about uh
whiskeys talking about non-alcoholic
beverages and mixing they're going to be
talking about um making some of their
favorite mixed drinks but uh 7 p.m and
on
we're gonna have that there is a
cocktail con
channel that you can get into and get a
figure out exactly uh what stream uh
these are all gonna be on you can just
go to discord and we will tell you
exactly where these streams will be
uh we also have a saturday dj during the
day sam the record man is going to be uh
spinning from 12 p.m to 4 p.m
so be sure to check that out there is a
discord section uh called stage and i
think it's actually just called dj and
you can listen to uh sam the record man
spin from 12 to four so if you're
working on something
uh you will be able to um
you'll be able to listen to some great
jams
saturday night we're gonna have inverted
geek uh and she's going to be singing to
us and playing to us at 6 00 p.m don't
know how long that's gonna last but it
could start at 6 00 p.m so we hope
you'll join us for that
and then sunday wake up bright and surly
at a.m to 12 p.m
gimli and sam craven are going to be
cooking brunch for us uh
we'll be hosting that on circle city con
live for everybody's entertainment um
but we're going to see what happens
there they're coming from cocktail con
to bring us brunch so we hope you all
join us for brunch on sunday 10 a.m to
12 p.m and by the way all the times here
and all the times that you're going to
see throughout the con are eastern
because after all circle city is in the
circle city con is in indianapolis but
broadcasting to you live from
indianapolis
the circle city
merch we have merch merch merch merch
merch we do we have merch we have over
30 items up in our merch store which is
hosted by teespring you can go to
circlecitycon.com merch as you can see
we do have cell phone cases they do have
iphone we have both kinds of phones
iphone and samsung
they uh they take care of both of those
types with various sizes and varieties
uh and then we also have tote bags long
sleeve shirts we have joggers and the
joggers contain a surprise in the
pockets just a little just a little fun
uh that's in there so if you want to see
what the inside of those pockets look
like you're going to have to buy them
and see what's inside
we also have fanny packs
a few different types of t-shirts i
believe i'm wearing a comfort tee right
now from our teespring store this turned
out beautifully i love it it's very
comfortable it's a cotton poly blend
and it's again it's very soft and
comfortable we also have v-necks we have
very form fitting shirts we have very
boxy and straight line shirts for
everybody for all different sizes we
also have i think they go up to 5 or
even 6xl on some of the shirt sizes so
uh for those of us who are big or small
or thin
uh we can all enjoy a shirt from the
teespring store
uh they also have
pouches uh they have a uh neck gaiters
they have face masks and they also have
leggings and guess what all of these are
not in just black as they're shown on
screen that's just what i was able to
screen grab here they're in all kinds of
colors reds and blues and grays and
teals
and magentas and all kinds of colors so
be sure to go on there find your
favorite color in your favorite item and
get that delivered to you some of them
can be rush ordered by the way so if you
want them sooner otherwise it takes just
a few weeks
um also back onto merch real quick if
you go to circlecitycon.com
merch
we do have a special merch pack that you
can buy and uh that website will take
you to stripe no yes it's asking you for
your credit card no we're not taking it
stripe is that is our credit card
processor uh and uh there are roughly
about 30 merch packs that we have
available to sell so be sure to get
those soon um and then we also have the
circle city con patch
we also have oh that's upside down
we do have the circle city con patch we
do have a coin we have a wonderful
sticker sheet similar to last year it's
really psychedelic with all these
wonderful colors we have here um
and you can get that we also have
stickers and you will also get an
attendee badge a physical badge that you
can get
so there's only about 30 of those and
they're about 50 bucks i believe is what
they are
all righty so
little news about circle citycon if you
remember last year uh we were we
announced that we were going to be going
into a non-profit there are some bumps
along the road and trying to get there
but we're kind of halfway there right
now we are c3 conferences incorporated
is the non-profit entity and it's taken
over circle city con as we speak
um it's the same group of people where
the same managers with the same board
we're just going into a non-profit
status now
we provide training opportunities to
those interested in joining or already
in the it information security
industries
and this is accomplished through
organizing circle city con in
indianapolis indiana as well as
providing grants to those who are in
need of support to get the training they
need to enter the industry these are
very exciting times for us and we're
looking very much forward to um
to working with
people and getting people more training
that's what we've always done as a
conference since year one we have had
our free trainings and ability for you
to come in and get training at our
conference for extremely low cost
virtually nothing i think most times
we've ever done as a little fee to
reserve your seat day of con but
walk-ins have always been welcome during
the physical conferences it's been a
little hard to do this year uh for for
for planning purposes
um
but yeah so
and since uh since we're non-profit
since we're going to this non-profit
status and we do have this up
make sure this advances
oh
have i frozen
oh no
you go down here oh
it looks
ha
it looks as if it has gone through and
um
eaten my last slide
um so i will just go ahead and stop
sharing my screen and come back to me
hello
um
and so basically um
basically what we have is we do have a
donate button now on the circle city con
website if you go to circlecitycon.com
there is now a donate button that goes
through donor box uh we do have a
campaign going on right now we're trying
to raise five thousand dollars that goes
to c3 conferences incorporated uh 50
cents of every dollar we receive is
going to go to the general fund to put
on next year's conference
and 50 cents of every dollar is going to
go into a board fund which is going to
be used to give grants to those who are
in need of training um
who aren't otherwise able to necessarily
fund their training or come from
underrepresented communities so we're
trying very hard to uh
to to get people into the industry and
getting into this practice
in many ways our hobby
so yeah we hope you'll we'll hope you'll
join we hope you if you can give five
dollars five dollars if you cannot give
it this time we do not want your
donation if you need if you need money
to survive we're not wanting you to take
money out of your pocket to survive
there's wonderful people that have such
great hearts and want to help people so
much that you'll hurt uh even yourself
we don't want that we want you to be
happy we want you to make sure you're
supporting yourself and everything so
this is not a plea this is not a call
for for for everybody to donate this is
a call for people that can spare five
bucks people that can spare 10 if you
want to spare a thousand that's great
too
uh but we want to uh make sure we do
that i do need to say this disclaimer
and that was on the next slide that i
was going to show uh it's a disclaimer
saying that we although we are a
non-profit that is registered with the
state of indiana we do not have the
501c3 status yet we are in the middle of
that with the irs uh and we are getting
that we're hoping in the next 60 days
they'll give us a call and say we're all
good to go
um but we have been advised uh by uh
legal folks that uh
even your donations today will be
will be able to be deducted off of taxes
as long as we get that determination
letter later and then certainly after
the termination letter comes through uh
and we have that 501 c threat
status solidified you will have the
ability um to write that off on your
taxes for future donations but we'd love
if you could donate today um and help us
reach that goal of five thousand dollars
we think we can do it i think every i
think we can do it um even if it takes
us just a little extra time but i think
everyone can do it so if you would
please uh give give when it's convenient
and give when you're able
and i think that's about it actually so
i think the next order of business will
be for the keynote which is going to be
ray redacted and you can check back into
this channel uh track one and uh at 11
a.m eastern remember all times eastern
and uh we will see you sometime on some
other channel as well
see ya
you