of good morning everybody arm thank you
for coming to my talk
I know it's still early for some people
even early for me um
so many people may be malware it's more
interesting
and ipv6 wall which we're
nearly at my first I'm topic of this
talk
first my name is Marco Rosa
you might know me from sousa Linux
because I wrote all the insecurity
stuff in susan i text like this was a
firewall heartening securities
six trips and stuff like that on more
probably you might know me as a fun
house or 10 Mikes items work programme
hydride
a map in she's getting other stuff like
that um
has anybody have you so all the slides
were even
for my talk five years ago an ipv6
security
anybody now you're still too young to
downright
by five years ago and ipv6 okay
what we see here what we see everywhere
yes
when we talk about I sixty-something I
think people have
my topic Star Wars like
in some distant future maybe we will
have have ipv6 hopefully not maybe
conduct the bullets
maybe we'll possibly don't react to it
we can order maybe we'll just wander
away
weekend do stuff that really matters
that's my image I have when when people
talk about ipv6
so hopefully it will not affect us
because we already have
enough stuff to do well in reality
there's nothing to touch because already
dear
first we talk about the operating
systems and routers and firewalls
stuff they all come ipv6 in a bit since
five six seven years already
so the ipv6 stuff is already here now
the question is
when will I can be 63 come being in
should use to it scare
well next year this is because the big
tackle provider like t-mobile or
even I talk to one guy who works here at
the
in a mobile company they said they don't
have my kids anymore
and the more mobile users come with a
mobile phones who wants to be always on
and check your emails
they don't have the IP address for doubt
so what do they need
ipv6 because they don't get no ipv4
addresses additionally I know from
budget to conduct their
currently starting to deploy ipv6
created for business customers
so you don't gots ipv4
internet connections anymore when you go
to try to come but you
will start to get ipv6 connections and
same for DSL
ninety to 95 percent of all the
you spell internet connection singer
Mick are by Georgia Telcom
all the others I one-and-one free nets
and so on are just a reseller sold out
may also have to introduce ipv6 next
year
that's why they are happy scrambling to
get it running
and now we see some well human nature
alright still so far away still so far
away enough time to do stuff
and one maybe 40 fuck now we have to do
something and then you get results like
we see
into stock so
let's start with the basics because I'm
pretty sure not everybody's you strike
me six
and should start by saying this is a
technical talk
I'm and I think well it's the first
even the first technique of order
because certain pox of them after this
one will also be all technical
finally so ipv4
that's what we had everybody about has
currently it's four octets we have four
billion
possible IP addresses and its on the
bottom its
how it IP address might look like it's
an example I hope everybody
no stop night pp. 6 address 16 bytes
long
16 octets I'm I don't know how to
pronounce dis
possible numbers of IP addresses let's
say it could be enough for a while
and how it typical I P ipv6 address
looks like it's like top
still pretty short thats that has
reasons
even if its 16 bytes if this is our
example address
the six 16 bytes
are grouped by two bites which are
present in hexadecimal they're separated
by a colon
it set up point forgot
not before leading tours are omitted so
it would be serious here is your for
and along the chain of Heroes
are replaced with just two columns
because of that the ipv6 address
can look very short even shorter in ipv4
address and related reality it's very
long
submit typical stuff and this is a
standard and this will be
everywhere so this is not just people
technical or
let's say only if you will really do
that everybody will use sixty
slash 64 subnets a single stop
that but you're just my clock in one or
two pcs
in other words has the address space of
four billion times the whole internet
so every so often is large enough for
for everything we have already
down a broadcast address anymore nothing
like okay I dress a remote broadcast
into some Smurf attacks
there are more Picasa dress but you can
only access doesn't want to cuz address
from your local network
so if you want to accept what the costs
addresses from a different network
doesn't work
so this has some impact
especially when it comes to remote
scanning
if you don't know what IP addresses the
other end using
well how do you find that if the size of
this office is four billion times the
whole internet
the question Yukon just two
a broadcast being to make this to make
it easier to find something
well because it's not broadcasting so
you really have to test
every IP address not group no broad
cause
not the whole something just doesn't
work
that it's one of the issues when does
come for example to penetration testing
ipv6 networks
from remote dell also features one is
of the consecration that something which
my penis pretty cord is plug-and-play
you clock in any fights and you don't
need DHCP because as a DHCP replacement
everything works out of the box
you get your get your arm local network
address
you get a router or you get to the masts
everything if there's a new router
coming on the network
don't have to come here and everything
is automatic for the climb
everything's autoconfiguration
IPSec is mandatory in the protocols
every device which has ipv6
also has IP sec which is also a nice
feature
if it ever is introduce a largescale
there is no mobility option so this is
not necessarily implemented everywhere
which means you can travel with your
laptop keep all your sessions
but trouble in the trench let's say
Russell and Russell your flights
to New York and there you go to
conference while keeping euro
telnet sessions life
ASO at least this is what division yes
if it's really possible like that well
but thats the vision
ipv6 is a lot about vision hope things
could be when
but it's not really sure if it were
really work out like that
because there's not be the deployment on
hold scale for the experience is missing
and of course enough addresses for
everybody I think I saw something like
every script centimeters on planet Earth
can have 10,000 IP address ipv6
addresses
they should really be enough does out an
ipv6 header
looks like um if you know how an ipv4
header looks like you will see
go out this looks easy this look simple
wheres all the stuff of course yes
source in this nation this is larger
but beside that where's all the other
stuff and now the interesting question
what is the stuff which is missing
yes one thing which is missing is the IP
Iddi identification field um first
there's no heckling
anymore the reason hatteras is now fixed
I could before its dynamic so if you
have options take
the header can be larger is best for
alters a course that never know
if they receive a packet what is part of
the what is part of the header what is
part of the data they are not interested
in
to know it's fixes 40 bytes there's no
one to pick identification
up field anymore simply because they
thought
it's not needed now now after 25 years
of
ipv4 Internet we see was interest
interesting idea and in the beginning
but we saw it was not needed
so we can drop it from ipv6 there is no
check some anymore
and not before there's the checks on on
the ipv4 header
now it's at the Internet it's a reliable
enough
if we don't meet up and if there's a
check some it's done by the upper layer
so TCP ICMP ICP now ICP version 6
as mandatory check some so it's only
UTPA where check summers
optional and the check some include
source and destination
and the next header there is no
fragmentation
header and now it's interesting question
state and fragmentation ipv6 Austin
Texas know what's that also
said to be unnecessary we're confident
and there are no options because then
again they had a weird
would not be fixed shift so every option
is an extension header
extension header is what is new an ipv6
everything which is not absolutely
basically necessary for
routing a packet from A to B is optional
an optional means it's an extension
headers Hatter of it on
which lies between ipv6 header anti
she's a beauty better had a
Andheri of lots of stuff fragmentation
because not every packet must be
fragmented so it make sense to make this
option to put it into any take letter
saw started coming
is coming back now we have sauce writing
back in ipv6 IQ sec destination options
hope i helped as a lot of other stuff
so there's quite some hatteras
this is how it a packet can look like it
has multiple extension headers we have
the ipv6 header
there it's eight next header is the
routing header which is the
source routing header now next heresy
fragmentation Heather because it
the package spectrum entered and then
would be the Yuki header plus
the first part of the day tre this is
how an ipv6 packet can look like if they
are
arm more extension headers
so if we look at that it looks much
Center if you compare ipv4 ipv6
ipv4 this peak after so many options
what do you do
this is way sumpter so it should of
course be
more secure because we have all the
experience with ipv4
ipv6 just we learn from our mistakes it
made it better and
archer and the features we might need in
the future
so everything should be fine right well
just in theory as we can already start
by seeing about
while they are extension headers week
mites
assume that it's not so simple as it
seems in the first place
for example an extension Adam H
be there only ones on me is its legal to
have
true sold starting as a sort of
fragmentation headers
in what order made the trek make the
difference
extension headers maybe what options are
to: for
extension headers recorded numerous
options for every of this
extension headers and in this way
restarts
is just the start with things that
complex so ipv6
is reality so much more complex night
before
did even all the RT designers of the
ipv6 protocols and
sup protocols and stuff and they're
writing all they are clever are obscene
stuff
are overlooking water abilities even
from all the necessary and ipv4
so this is a reason why there are lots
of our abilities and desist just the
stuff which is in CV
now where there's a CD Co registration
over on our ability
well as the 2002 there were 21 abilities
yeah but you see its growing cause more
implementation but also more awareness
and more
security testers
on this what is currently in 2010 but
the problem is if you adjust for CB
now you get a number but not but the
number is just being published once you
as as researchers say now you can make
it public which means usually off to fix
the stair
look even in fee from March April of
there will be new CPE which has 2010 at
in there now so this is why
this is the expected cap washes what is
still in there and
it's not copy my own CD entries because
I still have to make them which would be
three or four
at so this will even spike larger than
out
so kids in 2005
I did already in presentation on my ipv6
security research
now I will shawty Redd up really
shocking about 20 percent dear
and present use to of course your
because
used up it all
the wall surrounds a toolkit I'm
programming because when I started
drinkin 56
I want to do some security testing and
noticed don't know tools
I want to see how disrupts I wanted
create that packet and about no
to love able to do that even the most
basic attacks notable
even today lucky and Matt can at least
to connect Canton ipv6
and we have to meet us but with which
has ipv6 support
beyond thats still after five years
stairs one more man in the middle to
which implements the stuff
I already implemented five years ago so
you know no new stuff and that's it
now so every everything in my research
really
walls about that whole kit which
contains no I think
35 tools so good luck examine my took it
because you just feel well
all the stuff which is invariant not the
best documentation
like that so first what we know and I
before as
arc scooping we also have not been
sticks
there's not the our protocol anymore
it's done by up ICMP 6
I'm types you it's called neighbor
discovery spoofing
ever expect same instead of this and are
request
you sense neighbor solicitation ICMP
request to the network
you the system which has to I'm
IP address you are asking for is
responding with a neighbor
advertisement back which has the mac
address
well of course anybody can also for such
a request so
we have a tool which is called parasite
six which that's exactly it out
this is on the network into every sold
solicitation request which comes
its moves your own Mac or retin a Mac
or fix Mac which is not on the net for
gas I like it
now we have to pick a two-track address
detection dos this is so something also
already have an ipv4
just that duplicate address detection is
not done by many systems
in ipv6 its mandatory
so was it what does that mean well it's
also done by name a solicitation just so
the system wants to use new ipv6 address
so it sends a message on the network was
ICMP same type never solicitation
request
who has decided he addressed because I
want to use it
sensor the network and if there's no
reply from the network the system knows
okay nobody's using IP address
I can use it so it is not to duplicate
on the network
again Houches recommend to securities
just check
is create a tool which sets always yes
I'm using that IP address I'm using that
IP address I'm using that IP address
apso denying all in your system's its IP
address connectivity
even works for existing systems but for
example some three hours
effetti texas' on a cute resin used
shuts down
to interface so even for existing
for life system already on it for you
can now the net for excess
even with Windows it works
it's totally okay if you ask questions
in between I'm fine with that
yes Rafi
you can also deny it repeat the question
she doesn't neighbor solicitation what i
do. just
it the one dated the mac Address
I 6 yep its every machine comes as ipv6
address
automatic but it's just link local
address right so
every she should have a unique addressed
yet but as his death has to be some
solicited because
guess address book already been used
this is why the source addresses
unspecified so there's no IP address and
the request
which it of course where what's the
system since the onset was
is to everybody so the on sir which
destroyed ascending
work to do and system which already had
using his address to send
everybody does address is in use but
theoretically matters
should be unique world should see me
ideas especially if there's somebody
evil
or if he was for example privacy option
the privacy of generates randomly
every day a new ipv6 address and then
has to check his address is already in
use
because more systems and more the higher
chance X
in 10 years as one coalition
on you can demand the middle with
redirects redirect already broken I
seems
in ipv4 you also have tonight I PV six
I'm in the good thing about the redirect
the tax I before and ipv6
um they work by default
because security redirect are always a
neighbor if its windows with Linus does
matter
if redirect are secure secure means it
comes from your default draw for
and it contains a real packet the victim
is what sending
then the redirect accepted by the system
and this is
really easy to follow on look up my
slights from
five years ago its all explained here
and there's a to redirect 6
I think for ipv6 does matter implants
are out wonderful
I'm 26 just more secure in that regard
to take only works
locally on the local om now on ipv6
ipv4 it works from the other end of the
world
if you know what the address of the
Deepwater otters
that we have DHCP or better bought a
conflagration because this is what
originally
they want to remove exercise with JCP we
are cool people
we do everything out of the box on the
networks autoconfiguration
nobody wanted to pee anymore which works
with the router advertisements
still do you have a router and the
router Edward Hines on the network I'm
here
I'm unknown see I'm the responsible
router for Dish Network
this is the IP range from which you
should choose yourself
your IP address you want to help if you
want to if you want to use internet
services
yep you to resolve the DNS so
this is done all by the router
but what happens if there's if you set
up your own Roger
yes a feature which which is about not a
priority and by default
all rotor steps a priority to medium
if I start my own fake routing
advertisements
demand on the network says my priority
is high
I will be the default
so this is 50 percent of my talk from
five years ago but let me continue on
the router advertisement because tests
how much you can do except
just with that stuff yeah kick the
default route has a debt default on you
don't want to that the phone right to
exist anymore for the target easy
you sent your own daughter retirement so
you will be the router of the roots
so it is already in the work that's what
if you're already routing table but is
still the default order for whatever
reason
you spoof router advertisement from the
default router
but with us your own lifetime because
project advertise it has a lifetime so
how
long this disorder active in if no new
road record highs incomes
then considered as roger is that now
so you spoof a route which question sets
your lifetime which means oh I'm that
so just to be sure you're really the
default all two of two routes you send
again your own router advertisement
this router is dat as long as it doesn't
send its own daughter
advertisement again and your default
route and the default or it doesn't
exist anymore for target
I'm we coming back to this point
because you could say okay but if you
spot the router advertisement
the default talkable C-dot and can react
on that
I show you later four different kind of
a trick techa
on a different protocol how I can do it
at that the router doesn't see that
can all routers which are on the network
and the the target systems will think
that
all internet is local is
in the proper collection I haven't tried
it is really works but it's in the RC
and it has to be implemented
otherwise in systems are see Compline on
that if there is no router on the
network to find
everything is local issue because I
might be right over just picks up the
traffic and forward through the right
direction
so it's another it's a if something
doesn't work because of product price
when this somehow
except by system everything can still
work
I'm another sing which happens if you
send out a router advertisement is
that all the system stop being UAL stock
the already are ipv4 they have to at
least six capability
there just waiting for our truck with
highs which showed up a I could be six
okay here and wants to offer advertisers
receive
they are dual spec ipv4 and ipv6 never
did use both
what could probably go wrong here
um you can port can I could be six now
so one you say and acknowledged his rock
advertise on a comp
the system config was its ipv6 address
you can scan it ipv6 address
by duplicate address detection you know
what the new IP addresses its choosing
and imports cannot and as I can before
it's a different IP spec and ipv6
you must have filter also ipv6 otherwise
turn off its rules
when you can port scan all ports without
if I win fire warning in between a port
filtering
it will prefer ipv6 so if it does Tues
requests under an ipv4 and ipv6
addresses received it must use
the ipv6 address so
how about on
trade the tunnel so you're really IQ's
you really implement ipv6 connectivity
and pollen all the ipv6 traffic through
you
and sniff everything or announced
a remote network address space like Pay
Pal locally on the network with the room
remote at router advertisement so if it
if a system wants to connect to pay pal
disputing think 0
that network's local cool habitats your
system
says lots of stuff you can't you just
without replacement
um what you can also do is project which
has been flooding
actually dad was something why was
thinking I mean of course
if system config curious its IP address
based on the prefix a router is
announcing that this is a network here
and you can have multiple IP addresses
can have 10-15 IP addresses
on my PC is no problem at all and it's
normal that you have 3 45 ipv6 addresses
that is how its design um
the next step what happens if I simulate
10,000 rogers & all announcing different
networks 30
ten different I peter is accomplished
what does happen
so for me let's say that hackers
security researchers mind
that's just the next step it's very easy
to come up with that
with that idea so what could probably go
wrong with vendors
ap use all the affected operating system
which when you started texting 110 100
percent CPU load 100 percent RAM usage
so they doing nothing anymore
ap Cisco and the Cisco PIX all Cisco US
Windows 2008 Windows 7's mendosa
westall Linux but really old maybe more
that's just what I tested now
how can that be you must be local on the
network
because that's where all to read what I
type receive so here for example at the
conference
you can just win everybody of you who is
using Windows
would not be able to do anything yeah
until turning off
rebooting and having same problem again
so what the vendors to what they fix
just could just fix it for the IRS
this is the box fix-it for the IRS I'm
in awe that is coming soon
I was told next week in two weeks this
is the book that you put up
and Microsoft it's not a problem
we implemented like its in the standard
so
if it's in the standard it must be okay
if our system's out
not accessible anymore 100% CPU percent
if you use
wall is that our problem
up Apple is not affected by the way
today got that thing right Linux doesn't
that's Cisco fix it but
Microsoft is not a problem unbelievable
yeah I'm some jerk sets five years ago
because of his vast IP space injustice
of net
and because we don't have brought costs
and stuff um it is not possible to
remote
life or ping scan on ipv6 networks
the drug was me okay I admit
up by doing some organization I came up
with some ideas some %uh very
easy to come up with um but actually I
needed some
research on that's a statistic research
how to get a
call can we identify remote systems in
ipv6
first weekend not scan the whole range
now if its four billion times the whole
internet it doesn't work
ap it would take even if you could send
what one hundred million packets per
second
it would take 10 years just for that one
topic well maybe just one or two systems
are there
stuff he's down a broadcast so we can do
that
what is up to you obvious what we can do
we can you search engines public
databases for example how we can
check the web page of a company to see
what ipv6 Day half
we can look in the DNS so we can do it
again as brute forcing
we can see what is the main exchange
with the name server and see if they
have ipv6 addresses their
and we can look for common addresses
and becoming up and if you combine them
all
maybe there's a chance we will identify
some systems
so I was interested in how many systems
are to
if I combine these soul
I look into a search engine done various
ipv6 directors what's needed some
I'm webshop not packing but let's say
weary many population
I'm so I could generate 40 14006 I do
51 possible demands plus sub-domains
and did you test brute forcing attack
so I took everything off every domain I
found its up to man
boolfalse 3,000 possible hoskins so I
use
what our usual ha spends the night
before I added some I took the
put the one for me just by tax put got
some
work text files and put him also in
there so three thousand real of
on and at home 40,000 DNS entries
well the point is if you're looking for
VPN
as a host name and you're just went for
BP n what are your results
results is the results are everything is
the penultimate
engine Internet of course because you're
just looking for bpm
so this might not be the right approach
to talk about
what are common hostage because if
you're just looking for up now we will
just see
www but what we can do we get the
from the DNS entries these are about the
process which is good at the moment
we find the IP address but on the ipv6
addresses now we can do statistics
ASO iPhone 14456 you to get sick the
dresses
in twelve thousand nine hundred
forty-two networks
and 5,000 434 unique host addresses
which means unique host addresses the
host part
so if you have a c-class network the
most common
host party dresses dot wall now
well assets less texty for softness mean
you have
four billion times your internet as
possible host addresses
getting down to just for 5400 values
being used
it's not a large space so to say
so is a seed distribution of host
addresses
USC terrace 1
common address which was used about
1,000 eight hundred times
in this is or suppress 1
answer and so on and so on so what you
can create is
addiction Neri list for a host addresses
ipv6
and if you look at this he will see okay
this is fair
things go slowly but up to here it's
very effective
with just a few checks you find a lot of
systems
missus here at about a range of 700-800
so but just checking $7,800
700-800 ipv6 host addresses
on a subnet will find many many systems
statistically
if it's the first one of its randomly i
coming to
on host address and I'll analysis so
when I got the
5,000 for 34 unique host addresses I was
doing okay
what hardy's host addresses where did it
come from
of course some come from
autoconfiguration which is based on the
mac address
so the vendor ID is
let's say come to some are contoured by
hand
and others a concert by DHCP because
some people still use DHCP for
management reasons
so autoconfiguration here it's based on
the mac address
or the privacy option or it's a fix
random because a different kinds and how
you can implement a
and its on many operations you can
choose
which of the three types one how um
if it's done by hand its I the random or
by a pattern
the pattern would be one to 34
bought 1000 1000 2003
and we have tips to keep disappearing
you define the pool
and all the implementation I review they
give out the IP address
sequential which makes life easier
so if you get got one system which is in
the DHCP
space address space just look below an
offer with net address space
got it so what I don't implement its
in mine scanning tool of
sorry forgot so here operation the mac
Address
24-bit key space usually prevent your ID
which is possible to do its like a class
a networks can privacy option fix random
no way its its its true random by hand
well if there's a pattern of course once
you identify with the pattern is
piece of cake if it's done random
well that and of course the ACP again
it's easy
so I'm fermented by hand
the patterns identified and the DHCP
usually H CP ranges
and if bought a conflagration is
detected equal
what country at the home ec address
range so because if you have one server
by let's say
HP or Dell you might have more service
by HP and Dell
so just the the loft bite three bites
might be different so that's that's
what's interesting tool
also searched space so if you configure
something by hand his example
what are people are usually doing now
the service port support 84 web for
example 5314 s over
or one the service port 23 two and three
and four
to have more of them or service bought
colon 123
some museum the ipv4 address yeah so
88 call on one call on 23
call on 24 so if you know the ipv4
address
you know exactly what to scan for and
some funny stuff like
Bay that be foo and so on and so on
this are the common yet appear anxious
so if you use DHCP
s 6 which comes with liners or I
example configuration and stuff this is
what you will see they also added the
first part
each into my scanning tool and this is
what the distribution is like now
autoconfiguration
is just part which is larger pipe on
ipv4 addresses it's not so often random
good luck
is relatively rare and the heart
to guess addresses all also pretty large
but
dis large piece of the pie
is what we can guess which is roughly
66 percent so
my life's going on the 12,000 where
roughly 13,000
all networks with good for them to
thought possible host addresses
wealth of 380,000 a life addresses
some firewall twice can't on paying
night the decision
San on port ATV you TP a real
UT at the end supp pick it apart 53 and
stuff
yank up more unique Austin networks um
from the population you can see
that I'm still missing some of the
possible hope I'm addresses
so as to the still pretty steep
and not arm not a platform
there's still more I can identify so I'm
pretty sure until my next
Park course this is just scrapped
because after it was someone some
speaker didn't get his visa can you talk
so I'm not really done already with the
research
on I'm pretty strike up to 70 75 percent
so you live scanning I did the same on
the
on the river stuff so every worst all
the DNS entries
I got the knesset entries all the live
system
and got 13220 s entries
now the unit cost him so interesting
because no I could see
okay these are you our host the host
names and units which are used
so i cant fetus again into my DNS good
forcing
for hostnames I didn't have been before
because I see what is really used
and then you get no ipv6 addresses you
can check does new host address is
coming up and so on and so on
so what you have here its roof approach
until we have all the ipv6 host names
which are usually used in all the host
addresses
of ipv6 measure Houston you get very
good be a very detailed picture of
statistically how you have to perform
your net remote networks can to find
most systems as possible so in
conclusion
just by the US Food forcing to fight
ninety percent of the system's
in which are in the DNS on ever rich
up
yet but I'm only checking for the
reverse DNS and that's where base
stuff but it's not 100 percent because
what people it put the in the DNS
ap out sorry another such I'm not
academic I don't care for academic stuff
I check for real work stuff and it's
good enough for me we can talk in
we have gone in
um with a lifeboat forcing I see real
systems I can see what is on the
networks
now so I can see if what I found here is
real life handedness
real life is good say 66 percent on
average
can be found and if you combine both
Washington DNS and what you can get from
the life system
and now it's getting really very hard to
say but it's rock in nineteen knife
90 to 95 percent on Everett's
which means on some systems you will not
find anything
and others he will be 100 percent is
just average
on the average network but we have a lot
more stuff now
attack on what the cost is a discovery
protocol howdy nine with the cost
traffic
um works like that the router sense
politically
general query messages a who wants to
listen to what the cost
and everyone wants to listen to a
monthly cost
addressed says I i'm I want to have
someone to cast the nests over traffic
and then the router foster other also
whenever there's skin as well because
traffic tends to the network
on what you can as a hacker to you sent
done message
done message means I don't want to
listen
to the more the custom s tough anymore
is proof that s 8 and the router now
things okay he doesn't want to listen
anymore
their security in the protocol that when
that happens
the router sense again a message was is
it's really nobody wants to listen on
this anymore
and a wouldn't say a still want to
listen so
this doesn't work um
what we want to be is just query router
we want to become that we want to
eliminate this one
and be the query Roger there something
the protocol because after multiple
routers on the network only one should
be the creamy rotor
so the decision process for Secure
Router is
who has the lower mathematically ipv6
link local address
so before school Jenna query message
or on clear images as this address which
is the lowest possible address
have never seen it configured anywhere
never ever
so you will always be the clear over
afterwards
den you spoof the done message for a
well what happens it does just 20 bucks
for a very short period of time
because if you as its Corey rotted do
not
sent just sent a clear message from time
to time
um the other offer will become active
again is that with the query is gone now
I have to send a message
so still enough security the protocol
on so ima send in general analytic you
clearly message regulary but Inouye
did only distraught just use it and the
target doesn't see it
so how can this work and then
few nights ago I had stayed here I just
school cream in touch with
especial mac Address don't want to cuz
mac Address
what the cosmic address is specified who
can receive that message
and if you send is with you what the
cost all right to make a dress
only the routers will pick it up even if
the IP address
is for all the systems
and this way is cool first gen a clear
message to become the query
monster school done message
for the system and then sent the cream
is from time to time but with that
special naked
only the router accepts it
but the target missile doesn't and that
way you come pick and pull completely
disable the
with the cops routing into that part of
the network
but there's more um in 1998
kids in 1998 I found vulnerability
online us waken
see on that on the local network if
Linux host for sniffing
and guess what on Wednesday night from
the same vulnerability in ipv6
and Linux and Windows again so re
implementing on one abilities
you sent a ping to the charger and I
just want the cosmic address
if you just use any mecca dress doesn't
work it must be more to cost a dress
the system should not be listening to
but it was too sleepy time for
any suffer like that is activated on the
Windows or Unix Linux machine
if you prefer lies with the pink and you
know specific
are any side channels ipv6 another BEC
wall is the question I V six is
side-channel especially if that's how I
was in between
the problem is that with all the
extension headers file vendors contre
filter on the continent extension
headers
I talk was just about the property is
set because she is constantly design
changes because to come to the pit what
comes texas tender
the conference on content and extension
headers you know a few things which are
evil known evil that that's what it
feels about everything problem through
so you can send hold both work files
just an extension header ouch
through the final and econ prevent it
so if you have a few talk was such a
texan ipv6
it's just someone who think got a boring
talk because at
too many ways you can with ipv6 but in
the end
don't be scared with a goods Design Inc
which security infrastructure you sign
on ipv6
you can eliminate lots all the stuff
that not everything for Tekken wiki to
deploy at you sec
IPSec totally and completely and stuff
but im with smaller stuff you can
to fuck some secure host configuration
and eliminate some of the stuff
um yes I V six is very complex its
intellectual challenge the more you look
into it the more you understand how
complex it is
and if your time if you're seeing
security search in your tired of finding
security will be some stuff nobody cares
about like guess book
PHP application for bars 0 dot one beat
up
now and you really want to find spun
ability stuff which is rather easy
because lots of stuff but also which
have meaning
so interesting one abilities I'm 26
stuff they should go to
so be an explorer so much so many
protocols
100 people can study on and still find
different vulnerabilities and issues
so join me join researching ipv6
it also makes people in protocol more
secure in the end that what
actors to criticized so things can be
made better
so here's an example you can see in this
his late in space if you want to play
with i believe how to get into your home
inquiries to see how easy process is and
other you have a static town or happy
child to your home
despotic on Flickr local Jeffrey like a
g6 on you local network
on list of everything which is new
in I my ipv6 attack toolkit which is
lot of a lot of stuff books um
it's not a publicly is still because I'm
still developing lots of the stuff
so it's not complete but anybody was
tense and patches a new tools gets gets
full access
also I don't want lots of people to scan
the internet now when are you too when
I'm still do my research and see what
are good addresses
but I will do soon smaller optic
complete stuff so this reckon on the
tool
after Christmas I will enable web sites
here
where you can find all information on
how secure leak on Flickr a PIX how to
secure a Windows host to make its
to protect against ipv6 the text of how
to do remote pen test and things
um yeah and if you need any if you have
any idea to six metres you say I want an
external consultant help me design it or
Penn tested or PS review this file for
the first two innings drop
well ask me thank you
we still have time for questions we have
time for questions
three minutes yes three minutes first
question of mines on this
talk on ipv6 disability of addresses
will mean we will see something like
I'm cricket papa's words which are
tested for ipv6 addresses
school so that probably what of my was
referring to that statistically looking
at that
will lead lots of matches but is
people choose clever ipv6 addresses are
listed on the ruse
scores and that's also why I'm doing
this presentation
to make you aware don't make it too easy
if you have to put this possibility to
make a trend
do it random I mean that's the point
any more questions
longer before you start talking I don't
ever discuss want to proceed and miss
mathematically
what so ever I'm nothing official guy
actually I'm or the practical
key something different regarding a
rogue
arsenals man's it lies from me
this doesn't have to be some you guys
make
features someone's two regions laptop
comes to you
vision for natural uses
times miles place Roger your own
so this happens real large
altman's tens that somebody please drop
so Iran 6 trudge
local times
look at different roles your chin
so numbers from before
what's your your
overall comment life
six holes all your numbers you can
phone this many real life
people extras makes
numbers times percentage s have to
restructure some
or totality life 26
missus the point is
nobody can also discuss how many ipv6
really alive addresses the arkansas just
say I took as most networks I can
which I I personally would XQ that I
found about 50 percent
of the all internet to but it could be
eighty percent could be 20 percent
Santa concentrated on the and networks
of course all the
and transport networks and between the
rocking networks I didn't
candies the routing issue because you
just have to trade strategies
appear exactly that's when my guess is
that what you found
most generous old man you have to think
it's
boxes and all those mess
deployed used whatever there in Asia
are using random addresses which
point haven't found me just so
when you say with your choose yo force
you get
eighty percent of hosts and thats eighty
percent
postponed all your other tactic
scheduled between
anti-religious liked totally true but
then again
cool what's if in a remote pen test what
what you look for
our mineral 10+2 I would be authorized
to she's check the security of that
company
and I wouldn't care about do you spell
users
how which is different goal but I could
have sat at more in the beginning
yes you can only find stuff you're
looking for
is always a problem only if you look for
money on the floor you its more
prosperity find money on the floor
if you buy in you mercy this which is
very venue you will notice so many
people more of that before he would not
have noticed
so you usually find only what you're
looking for dizzle
problem
little late SLA this position so I don't
know if you ask before
but who the room here has be six at home
in the office which is a truck
there more than I expected actually
service who has ever competed 6 world
could be way more and will be morning in
few years