alright guys I'm gonna hear me I'll try
to just this thing it troubles okay
let's get started as I just been said my
name is Peter networking here at
Facebook bit autograph I'd talk is
identified by the address in ila and
specifically the application to visual
networking alright so I begin by saying
that the whole concept of virtual work
is confusing but is so many technologies
people use on the host right now mostly
overlays Jerry Envy Jerry VXL an epic
geneve with so many encapsulations and
control planes it's sort of hard to
track what's going on and why people do
this so we started by looking at the
problems we're trying to solve at
Facebook with the our approach so first
of all containers containers are really
hot right now like it's as big as VMs
were like few years ago everyone likes
them I guess everyone knows what dr. is
what screw brothers is people like this
because it's lightweight it's easy and
seems like to be really efficient we do
have with a facebook as well not dr.
necessarily it's our own implementation
but this is our approach to
virtualization on the host and there are
two main problems you encounter in
networking space with containers the
first one is the fact that you may run a
lots of containers on one machine
sometimes two sometimes ten in some
cases up to a hundred for example and
these guys have to share the IP address
for machine in some way or another in
most cases people ever have to allocate
multiple I transfer machine or reuse
port numbers across processes both cases
a little bit problematic especially port
allocation second one which is specific
to facebook was mobility when you move a
task to a different machine which often
happens on rescheduling you will have to
change the IP address of the task or a
process in our case or container I keep
saying task because we call containers
as tasks at Facebook
okay so these two challenges require us
to address two different goals first one
being able to allocate IP address /
process on this slide it says 80 v6 and
it's silhouetted 06 because we don't use
a pu for internally almost in case of
our containers probably every single
process use IP addressing only our goal
was to be able to allocate unique
address poor linux process secondly
address mobility we wanted to that
address follow the task or process when
it changes a machine it's not the creole
necessary but it simplifies a lot of
functions in our internal banking
systems okay so the two goals address
for process and mobility so I Lay was we
are one way to address this and this is
the solution was deployed so far aisle a
is built on the old well-known concept
of identifiers and locator split I guess
everyone well played with my the same
one talked about this abbreviations
before LNP GSC eight plus eight this
used to be a very hot topic in
networking probably ten years ago when
they had these discussions about
internet table scaling was multi
proposals allen key was one of them so
you may think of ila as a technology
which builds on allen p so wait works is
pretty straightforward underneath you
have this 8 for 16 byte address ipv6 and
you split this into halves first half is
called the locator locator is 64 bit
long it's used for Roger hookups in the
network it may change over time of a
course of a life or address the second
part is identifier identifier is a kind
of a name of a process but he'll set the
address it's immutable is given to a
price on a start it doesn't change so
the way I only worked is that
it required that every node or host in
the network had a / 64 predicts not an
address by the peripheral secondly as a
process with my great building machines
it's a la address this 16 byte entity
would change locator field submersible
concept it says okay this for 64 bits
identify the encode the location and the
rest is the name however in case of
previous solutions like L&T the
requirement was that the changes in
valle cater were visible to the
transport or applications which meant
you had to change the CP code or linux
tack or any other networking stack to
accommodate for this changes and think
this was probably the biggest problem
LNP this need to change the transport
stack was we kind of impossible to
implement so Alli kind of works around
this limitation it hides like other
changes so basically it makes transport
layer believe but the locator field
never changes it looks like it's one
fixed value 16 64-bit entity but never
changes the way it does it is by doing a
stateless snap underneath the transport
layer so every time you use a packet it
will have to be written back to her
fixed locator so I only comes naturally
have to have this / 64-bit prefix I'll
get to it naturally like any of these
idea box lid solutions of course every
host has to maintain a mapping from the
identifier to locator to tell where
particular name or ID is being now
located and lastly I only adds one new
concept called le router it's a special
proxy a gateway but allows the non le
machines to talk to ali machines if you
remember island p was requiring that
every machine was modified to support
LNP ila works on this process by
mediating or adding this additional le
router but
allows the ideal world to talk to non le
machines okay so this is an example of
how this whole mad thing works imagine
you have this prefix it called sir
prefix I'll explain is a bit later in
next slide but this is the 64-bit
locator what remains unchanged in the
alley address so we have one LD host on
the left on the slide left right so it
has a process which has the aldi address
the entity in orange is all day address
the facebook one two three four facing
book is the special fixed locator and
one two three four is the name or idea
of a process at the same time this
process sorry this host has a green
address validator this locator
identifies the position of the customer
Network symmetrically you have the upper
counterpart the host with different
locator and different alley address so
pay attention they are the address
belongs to a process and the locator
belongs to a host now we have process
one setting packets to process to as you
can see both fields I think of area
budget allocated in the slides so but
the source and best addresses they both
have I la fields so the orange undecided
names as the heat'll wire we rewrite the
locator portion with the actual physical
locator what happens now is that network
knows to transport this packet to the
other side will have the other locator
on the other side we do reverse
translation and you write these physical
locators the green fields into the
orange ones into the sir predicts and so
in this way the net prevents the
applications from seeing these changing
locators we always see this one fixed
prefix facebook ok so now back to this
magical sir predicts as a management has
special meaning in la network it's a
stands for a standard at the fair
representation this is the fixed
pre-configured parameter for
le hosts this is the locators team of
transport and most importantly these sir
prefix is being injected into a TV 6
network by the LD routers this is
necessary to be able to attract via
traffic from non le hosts into the alley
costs so you may think about this as
this sir prefix is magical prefix being
a name of a subnet one virtual / 64
subnet which is being shared by all
processes Rhino machines so look in the
left you can see let's say all our
containers sharing this one address
space on different machines physically
and the alia router acts as the gateway
or the ipv6 router on the spiritual
subnet but provides communication
between the processes and non la world
most importantly this cloud on the left
is virtual it does physically exist it's
been formed by the processes running on
tons of different machines ok so next
import concept as I mentioned earlier
router this guy is responsible for
knowing of all ID to lock a traumatic
syndrome in the network it maintains
full cash it does inject this magical
surprise of a network to attract traffic
from non le hosts in this way it
provides the mediation or proxy function
between non la and ideal world and
lastly as we'll see in some other slides
other router also provides the Gateway
function between la processes in some
cases it's very important I bring this
analogy before to think about le router
as an ipv6 normal ipv6 router on this
one virtual segment its various
phonology to understand how it works ok
now so this diagram we have what we have
three hosts and one non la coste the
only guy is on the cloud which supposed
to have a dv6 network but it's truncated
the other router injects the story fix
facebook in this case it's not shown
diagram somehow got away an ally costs
sorry I mean normally host send packet
to allay machine so here's the key I be
not only host have no idea about those
mappings or identify secateurs it only
knows but it has to send pocket to the
circuits and since this prefix is in the
network it got sucked into the cellar
router and now our router has a
translation what it does it does better
right and sends a packet to the correct
machine the alley hosting tour now ok
packets for me it does a translation and
response back directly to the non la
host for most of you who deal without
balancing which looks very much the GSR
the actual return scenario and by no
mistake it's very simple concept we this
also of loads the other router from the
need to send traffic backwards to the
model a hosts now let's see how the
other router may be used to help provide
transit between ila hosts same scenario
we have our router and to LA hosts so I
outros usually injured Switzer predicts
always usual business now let's imagine
that the aldi hosts on the bottom does
not have a mapping for example cash is
empty what happens next it sends a
packet as usual no translation in the
network the packet gets sucked into
Valley router because of this circlips
injection what happens next well guess
translation and sends back a direct
packet very similar to the IPO 6 router
like ICP redirect you tell the
originator hey now use this mapping
because available and this allows the
ideal host to shortcut and bypass our
router for further interactions so
unlike the non le hosts le costs may
respond to your messages and install the
mappings on demand ok control plane
control plane is necessary in Iowa
to mainly inform the early routers of
all existing mattox so good news there
is no standard so you can mess around
actually invent some crazy things it's
really good time to play with this
technology in our case as a mansion with
only a few things you have to do first
of all the other routers have to learn
of all active mattox basically to know
where each identified belongs to which
the caterer secondly an early hosts by
by this virtue of this requirement have
to always inform the other routers of
the active mappings as they change on
the fly because remember tasks can move
things may change and you have to always
update the aisle a router one very
important thing about the ILA is with
data plan insistence we didn't exist in
island p or in our proposals which is
very specific to I early as we seen
before the other routers may send with
direct messages and these messages are
being sent on demand I mean not on
demand driven by data plane traffic when
you receive an entry a packet you will
send a quick message it doesn't involve
any contraband transactions it's purely
driven by the traffic and in turn the
hosts themself may also send results
back to our hosts tell them of still
entries for instance if a given host
loses a mapping for ID and still
receives packets for a psyd it may tell
back to originate the hey stop because I
don't have this mapping anymore and this
will force the sender to invalidate the
cache entries once once again the
analogy to ICD 6 is very very clear we
currently don't use ICMP use UDP packets
but the concepts are very much the same
ok now let's look at the most fun part
funniest part is the mobility how we
implement mobility using all this magic
all right now this scenario will have
three la costs so they have a list a qui
Hamels mapping caches we have two other
routers so it's very important you are
not limited to just one
router he may have 24 16 we can all
inject the syrup refix in any case
fashion now we have host see talking to
host be using the early addresses like
in this case there's two processes IDs I
give on the diagram we talk to each
other now imagine that the process on
caused be changes its attachment changes
location what happens next is the job
scheduler or a container schedule it's
speaking out using the open terminology
remove this entry because task is gone
immediately our flow is now invalid we
hit the black hole and caused the be
sends back the invalid entry mapping in
this case the invalid mapping is
truncated but this is essentially an a
message saying hey this mapping sound
valid at the same time the host which
now has the task tells Valley routers I
now have this mapping update your caches
what happens next is a host SI falls
back to the routers because it doesn't
have an option with no cash and to
anymore but luckily the other routers do
have this entry before the packet down
to la costs at the same time they send
back with that message to be host saying
hey this is the new mapping and
magically flow now recovers and flow is
directly so basically driven by the data
plain packets only we've been able to
switch over between the two flows first
one the other routers and second one now
goes directly that's pretty much all the
magic to implement task mobility will I
la once again it's really important to
remember that this whole real-time
mobility is only possible because with
the data plane messaging use the control
plane signaling handshakes might be
slower in this case relying on the data
plane messaging makes is much more
efficient and faster okay now beyond
most part deployment
diploma to Facebook specifics we've done
how we progress so far so first of all
as I mentioned the most critical piece
in a architecture Island p or any other
is to allocate a / 64 ipv6 prefix / host
that's the most developer a shin so the
diagram on the right shows you very
simplified design here are key three
levels Rex which pod and neck data
center so spine is those covers data
center part covers like say one cluster
and rach covers like from like
40-something machines now what we have
is that on every Rex which we have a /
50 for static route / 64 static route
for every server then we summarize this
to size 54 because we can reinstall this
lots of routes upstream we have to
summarize them to 54 this allows you to
have up to 1000 routes / x which if you
want to we don't need right now but it's
possible to use them all and so on this
Dean summarized upstream and you get
like one principal data center this was
very critical because we had to allocate
new address blocks just to number every
server additionally we've / 64 prefixes
I think basically we got a couple a
couple or a few more of / 29 but we
allocate them inside for the two blocks
and each / 42 is sufficient to give you
30 data centers together so it's pretty
much enough space thanks to a few cigs
with a lot of numbers and addressing to
camera so this setup problems most
problematic to deploy because we had to
reconfigure every single Rex which every
next pulse which and so on so forth
pretty much every device in the
dissenter had to be updated to
accommodate this the good part is that
this was very static you pretty much
have to allocate this once and then
never touch it okay now first
integration
star 64 / cost sounds very easy I think
this too almost as long as it took us to
configure every switch probably I'd say
we began deploying this in may we finish
this like in August something obvious
intersection numbering it sounds easy
have chef recipe which applies this
unfortunately configuring this new
addresses broke some applications
because people like to be fine thanks
ebel way we do things and you also have
to reapply this prefix on every new
server deployment this output shows the
actual IP addressing from my dev server
development server as you can see we
have a business address which is
deprecated well it doesn't mean with
deprecated the basis of course it only
means that we you set the lifetime for
this prefix to be a zero this is the not
very well known trick it's kind of
hidden in somewhere FCS what this means
if a lifetime of a previous is zero the
applications will not automatically
choose it for up for adverse binding so
for example if you do connect outbound
you will not pick us address
automatically so this was very important
because initially the connectivity to
the split was broken and if you make
applications use this you'll actually
get broken applications this still cause
some issues because we're people who
like to discover address on their own
and it shows this address by mistake but
overall this one pretty smoothly we did
try our approaches we did try to apply
the prefix to add virtual interface that
Danny or thunder face that caused some
other griefs so in the end we stopped on
assigning this new search 64 to physical
Nick ETA 0 as you can see the interface
has two more addresses linked local and
the older pivot 6r is nope you for if
you have a if you even look at this the
server IP relative is 6 we now have lots
of clusters and lots of data centers
which will be 6 only becoming the condor
Matt facebook
and this was just pretty much next step
in addressing these machines okay so how
do we get from this address / cost to
address / process it's very
straightforward now that you have ila
you can randomly generate a third 64
number and give it to the process say
hey use them sir prefix and this random
number as your address and it sounds
very simple and let's change the
collision but likely right now with the
search 64-bit address space the
uniqueness is pretty much guaranteed
sent by the fact that you three take
sort of time to get a collision in
aesthetics in a 64-bit address space so
the next more tricky part is how would
you make a process use this new address
because people normally don't really
bind two things right we just like okay
bind to any do connect and expecting to
work magically and that's pretty much
coming good approach of course in our
case we had to somehow force this so for
people or processes which can cooperate
we give them a variable environment
saying this is your address use it right
for people who don't want to cooperate
or cannot cooperate we have this pretty
ugly hug right now you promote a shared
library before process and you make
process use this guy it intercepts bind
connect and our calls and forces the
assignment or allocation of your address
to be done automatically so that the
case should even know about this we
start business as usual and they are
forced to use the new address this is
kind of nice because it helps us avoid
any need to change application on the
downside if you break something it's
hard to debug because people often not
very cognizant but you have the LD
preload stepped before application very
popular right now in community in the in
public in open source namespaces
namespaces and most evil and l2 galan
very great conceptually they break other
things right now for us so which rive is
in some small experiments we don't do
this actively so right now if you look
all process you run they share the same
namespace default namespace on the Linux
cost they just have different addresses
they can use okay next is DNS support
people surprising don't like using
addresses for like log output other
things so we want these new unique
addresses to have DNS names effectively
one genus name poor contain your upper
process right now we generate name on
the fly when you start a new job or a
new process it looks awful like this
it's pretty lengthy name it uses like we
local domain which is typically used for
like you know mdns multicast DNS we kind
of use this because it seems like a nice
analogy of this virtual subnet will you
have this addresses share in one star
six to four the variable name here says
you okay this task grinds in prattville
it belongs to team called net systems
and so and so forth and number 0 is a
number of a task in a in a global job we
only create quad-a and PTR records
straightforward nothing fancy and right
now this is a very custom hack so we
have I think who is unbound for DNS
names and then with a special process
which accesses this back-end database
called DB DB DB DB I don't think is open
source but I think we spoke about this
before it's kind of fun if you know this
similar to Amazon dynamo it's a global
key value store but allows you to create
a key value pair somewhere and then read
it elsewhere it's really simple not to
be performed on rights because he's
transactional semantics but it works
really well for us right now because the
rate of change what we have isn't very
high okay hot support um this is an
excellent magic what we did up for
ourselves I la is now supported in
mainstream Colonel I think since version
4 point
I forgot what exactly to be honest we
have a module called la so this module
implements aisle a using the current
table converting table if you're
familiar is uses the lightweight tunnels
extension which also allows you to
attach avatar encapsulations like VX
lens on mpls lightly tunnels is kind of
this new framework in the external to do
always in cap the cap magic all the
times netlink men think is ok if you
like it it's not as great if you kind of
wonder liability but allows you to right
now create and populate mapping tables
on the linux kernel machines ok so this
will show you how you can configure a
single host for a la forwarding so first
of all you load the module la this is
basically if you want to play with you
at your home of the aisle configuration
you have to download the IP command let
us build it has this option to right now
define a ling capsulation so first
comment of course you can figure the
survey fix your address are they on your
machine and you'll look back in this
case pay attention this orange stuff is
a surprise x second one you a static
route which tells okay for this upper ID
Alligator Alley address use this
capsulation so on the left here is the
alley address on the right is 664
translation we rewrite have to apply so
when the packet hits this entry gets you
written and flies away and lastly you
have a mapping for incoming packets so
if a packet comes to your machine and it
has this locator and visa densifier so
locator is red identified as green you
translate it back to the surface so
three commands bind route and local
translation this is actually how do is
initially enough implementation was
simply using the IP command to create
and remove entries ok alia routers as I
mentioned is a big deal for LA right now
we make every horse early router so
every cost which is part of a leader
main
injects the server if X she may have
like piles of machines which inject this
left 64 prefix and attract any gas
traffic to themselves on one hand it's
kind of confusing on the other hand
gives you really nice little bouncing
but traffic come into a network you can
watch shared across thousands of
machines we probably move to a model
will have dedicated machines for other
routers right now it is to be easy to
make everything very symmetric control
plane as I mentioned the hosts have to
inform the routers automatics once again
this has been translated so it on cated
only on the bottom you have early hosts
which are also other routers just happen
to be when you start a new process it
gets new address and it populates and
rise to back-end database saying hey
this is my ID to locate the mapping and
this is my dns name and then every
machine simply download the 35 second
it's really a fan fancy right it simply
runs a busy loop with 75 seconds
downloads mappings update local table
this simple approaches are often more
reliable than more offensive and driven
ones it's all very reactive obviously
because it may take like five to six
seconds before you respond to a new
mapping but right now it's sufficient
for our needs it's clear to standard by
works for ourselves and also notice this
gets replicated everywhere global it has
a network because ebdb is database which
run globally across all data centers
very very simple nothing standard would
different need something better in the
future ok this brittle tells you about
the scale deployment right now it's
experimental we try this on a bunch of
tasks it's used in production a very
limited fashion we definitely want to
move forward with this globally we'll
probably have to hit much more obstacles
in the future right now things look
promising but you know you also get in
trouble as you move forward I mean
already we have discovered a few issues
like I only does this view rights and of
course this breaks the wonderful ICT
messages on the transit
if you do trace route because on the
middle will send packets back which have
a payload that has the addresses which
have been translated the same for PMT
you so right now this break some tools
we definitely have some work in progress
to fix that because operationally people
cannot tolerate tres had been broken or
PM to not working even though in data
center beam choosing such a big deal
it's really nice to have it working
properly ok so the future future of ila
is how plan to develop and the next
steps to plan to do so first of all more
acronyms you're Zeno of ila LNP GLC next
one is EB PF I guess everyone here use
BPF in the life in one way or another
because this EP dump is initially in
healthy built on BBF so BPF is blurred
key packet filter spoke berkeley right
this time great it basically a language
for packet filtering used to be a BPF is
extension of the old BPF language called
classical etf now it's now a jit
compiled so it's byte code which
compiles to next instruction set in
kernel and it allows you to inject
arbitrary code which was an unsecured
node not just filtering purposes for
much more up for much more different
users and once you big deal for us is
because it allows us to extend clonal
functionality on the fly from user space
you can write something in this bytecode
you can inject it in the kernel and it's
been involved by kernel functions
outside visual space so for example
example use case is early router right
now application which implements other
router purely a CDF program so always
lookups always translations are done by
a DPF program which is simply upload
into kernel and attached to inbound
processing another abbreviation as
philosophy I promise xdp expressed data
path is originally new development in a
non-secure
no is the kind of response from coma
community to always dpd k and our color
bypass magic it allows you to implement
very simple and fast internet working in
a few words you can attach a BPF
programs very early in the driver code
you don't have to wait for full stack
processing you can inject code early in
the cardinal and this allows you to
implement functions with very low
overhead for example our router attaches
directly to a driver and you don't have
to walk the full particle passing chain
you don't have to go for us in table you
can process things very very quickly of
course some limitations but in a few
words xep is a method to implement very
fast working in kernel well just use
cases right here and obviously if you
have to you can always punt from SD
program or BBF program to a kernel for a
normal processing and once again this
vision menu I think it's been only
around for like eight months since this
announcement was only support in Colonel
4.6 and 4.8 I think for a few drivers
with much more work going on and lots of
interest in the current community in the
HDD functionality okay if you folks have
to keep in mind a few things from this
presentation here we are first of all
what's ila ila is a thing that gives us
unique address for process allows us to
provide location independence and it all
works on these two fundamental pillars a
DPF and xdp and that's it I'm done with
acronyms and I'm going to take your
questions thank