I'm hearing impaired and sometimes
wasn't listening to a football or a
baseball game so I thought I would just
share a few thoughts with you and that's
really all they are as a few thoughts
sometimes you hear this called Internet
of Things a lot of us have been thinking
about what this might imply at Google
and an alphabet we're also very
interested and my big concern is what
some of the implications are of having
large quantities of programmable devices
that can communicate with each other
what are the implications of that and so
I have only a few slides and I would be
interested engage in some kind of
dialogue which is why I'm brought my
headset up with me so let's let's see
where this takes us some people use this
term cyber-physical systems
many of them use that word to mean
things that physically move things
around or somehow affect what they will
call the material world and I get into
arguments with people about this because
I think a robot could also just be a
piece of software like an automatic
stock training program it takes input
from the real world it does something
and then it does some kind of
computation and then it actually affects
the real world like your bank account
and I think of that as a robot as much
as I think of something that picks up a
glass and moves it from point A to point
B however I got into a debate about this
with one of my colleagues at Google who
suggested to me a different terminology
so he stuck with robot is a physical
thing but he said a bot was another way
of referring to a thing that was
software and that's not too far off the
mark when you think about what we talked
about when people have botnets and
botnets are really programs that are
running in computers or things that have
programmability
and cause trouble like the recent big
500 gigabit per second DDoS attack which
was claimed to
come from IOT and I thought I didn't
think we had enough IOT devices out
we're out there this sounded like a
misrepresentation until somebody pointed
out to me no no it was cameras webcams
there are a lot of those out there and I
hadn't thought that there was enough
horsepower in those webcams to cause
that much trouble I confess that I
haven't gone down deep to find out
whether this report is accurate from the
standpoint of origin of the attack but
the volume was certainly there so it
already tells us that there are things
out there in sufficient quantity with
sufficient programmable capacity to
generate a substantial amount of traffic
and therefore a substantial amount of
trouble so I sort of think of
cyber-physical systems as anything
that's programmable and that you know
that can communicate now I have to be
honest with you even a massage chair
worries me even if it can't communicate
it's got software in it we have these
things all over the Google I don't sit
in them because I'm afraid they're gonna
go like that while I'm inside and
because of some bug in the software than
any of you who have ever made your
living writing software know that we've
not figured out over the past 70 plus
years how to write software that doesn't
have bugs and I think about the you know
the sorts of things that we do with our
websites now it used to be just a kind
of formatting and pretty pretty pictures
and now we actually ingest code that we
execute or at least interpret by
JavaScript and Java and Python and so on
and those two are a comment becoming
kind of BOTS like in effect
so we're ingesting what if you like a
robot into our web pages or into our
browsers effectively and the browser now
becomes I bought in effect and then I
wonder about sensor networks oh and
those have a similar potential for
interfering with or at least affecting
the real world means something even as
simple as the thermostat is having some
effect on on your surroundings so I
think rather than having a huge argument
about
what's about and what's a robot I think
we should be leery of all of these
programmable devices that have the
ability to communicate and so I start
from a mindset the hoping for the best
and planning for the worst so that's why
is the software stupid um
and I'm stealing that obviously from a
previous presidential campaign oh by the
way David I couldn't help but notice
you're one of your slides was titled the
art of the deal and I didn't know
whether that was a deliberate reference
or not but I'll leave it I'll leave it
at that
so okay so software what do we know
about software well you know it has bugs
and we know by the way that the devices
that we install whether it's at home or
in a an industrial setting and by the
way I think a lot of us outlaw I won't
confess to this weakness whenever I
think about Internet of Things I tend to
think of scenarios in residential
settings but that's actually probably a
mistake because the significant
population of these things is likely to
be in industrial settings where robots
are being used to assemble things if
those of you have ever seen the videos
on YouTube of Tesla in its assembly
plant in what Fremont California the
last time I looked there were 160 robots
putting these cars together it's pretty
amazing and this is going on more and
more so that the numbers the absolute
numbers may very well still be in the
residential setting or the things that
we wear no wearables or we carry around
with us but there is a significant
component of industrial setting devices
as well of course they're all
programmable so I worry about updates or
things that are going to be around for a
long time especially if they're embedded
you know in the in the house somewhere
that you don't even may not even know
they're there until they stop working or
they need a new load of software and
then you start to get worried about well
where did this update come from and you
know
is it valid updater is it in fact a
piece of malware how do we make sure
that it comes from a valid source how do
we know that it hasn't been altered in
some way or just corrupted do I know you
know how it got it from its origin to
where I'm uploading or updating the
software I also worry about the
longevity here because there are going
to be some devices that are in theory
supposed to last for you know tens of
years and yet the company that made the
product may not be in existence in which
case now you're really in the soup if
you really do need an update and you
can't get it I I am increasingly
persuaded that the strong authentication
of the parties involved in an exchange
that involves this Internet of Things is
really an important capacity for us to
develop and to assure so this gets into
the configuration world that you heard a
little bit about earlier today I'm
thinking about what it means to
configure all the devices that may end
up in the house and there could be
hundreds of them if you start thinking
about all the switches and the lights
and other devices that are part of the
house or the car or you have on your
person or in the office or in the
manufacturing plant so configuration and
who can configure becomes a big issue
how to identify the party how do I
identify the party that has the right to
configure this collection of devices and
then there's the scaling up problem
that's a very believable example from my
point of view is imagining I have a
hundred devices in the house including
the light switches and some of the other
little gadgets and I moved to another
house which also has a similar
complement of things already there so
now there's two hundred devices that I
have to configure the last thing in the
world that I want to do is sit at my
laptop typing ipv6 addresses all
afternoon trying to get it configured
properly and then I started so we have
to have ways of making this easy and
simple and safe but then I also worry
about being a
configuration mode in the
fifteen-year-old next door noticing this
and configuring himself to control my
entertainment system or for me the more
important thing is controlling the
cooling system in the wine cellar I'm
really worried about that so the other
side of the coin though is accidentally
configuring your neighbors stuff into
your system it's kind of like cartoons
where there's two people are in bed and
they've switched the controls of the
heating blanket and neither of them is
getting satisfaction right and so you
can imagine scenarios like this
happening in households that are filled
with these gadgets so scaling is a big
issue though making it simple and safe
and working properly is really a
challenge then there's artificial
intelligence which i think is a misnomer
we've only succeeded in creating
artificial idiots as far as I'm
concerned I my colleagues I'm sure at
Google in deep mind would would disagree
with that argument in fact they've done
some pretty interesting things though
those of you watch the alphago success
four out of five games of go or
successfully played by the alphago
artificial intelligence system but I
would still argue as complex as that
game is it's a really narrow space it's
not like general-purpose problem solving
which we are not very good at I've
noticed artificial idiot is in fact a
very reasonable label there are some
devices that purport to try to learn
your patterns in order to adapt well to
your needs and I've had a particular
thermostat which learned that we were
never home because we didn't go where
the thermostats were so they never
noticed that we were there and so they
assumed that we were gone and they went
into energy-saving mode and at the end
of the month I get this little email
saying I saved all of this energy aren't
you proud of me and I'm sitting here
saying we froze our butts off last
winter thank you very much so we've
learned that in order to to deal with
this you have to have more information
and more sensors around the house to
provide this little art
official idiot with more information
about whether there's anybody home or
not and I'm sure you can make up other
scenarios and I'm sure everybody's heard
about the chat bot that that learned bad
language and bigotry and a whole bunch
of other things very quickly on the
Internet
thanks to people who are happy to feed
it that information all of these machine
learning things are dependent on the
kinds of training that they get and the
samples that they get so if if you are
imagining that you know populating your
house or office with these devices will
somehow make everything wonderful
because they will learn to make life
beautiful for you you have to keep in
mind what kind of experiences they're
learning from before you conclude that
this is going to work well I also have
this this problem about certain what
I'll call ephemeral or episodic access
think well think about what happens if
you have a house that's got a lot of
devices in it and as a household member
you have control over things and then
you invite a guest over now a question
is how do you give the guest access to
some if not all of the controls to the
house you might not want to give them
the ability to unlock the doors for
example I don't know but but you can
pick your favorite case so the first
question is how hard is it to configure
the house to offer some control to a
guest I mean do you have to sacrifice
the chicken over the CPU and you know
dance up and down on one leg and then
the problem is what happens when they
leave how do you unconfigured that and
how do you make sure that they can be
identified how do we know that they have
this authority that you're trying to
confer on them and you see these
examples and we have them too at Google
where you have these voice control
systems well now you get into this
interesting voice recognition problem by
who is it that just gave you the
requests or issues a demand and how do
you make that work to say nothing of the
problem about saying turn the light on
and there are 16 lights in the room and
have to figure out which light is it
that you meant and you probably don't
want to say turn on light number four
three seven one one a which would be the
easy thing to do except that it's
unacceptable so we have a bunch of hard
problems but this ephemeral access
worries me so long to give you an
example where ephemeral access is fairly
tricky suppose that your house is on
fire
and the fire department is on the way
you might under that circumstance you
might want the fire department to have
access to the webcams in the house have
access to the temperature sensors and
other things to figure out where is the
fire burning are there anybody who's
unconscious in the house where are they
you want them to have that information
under that condition after the emergency
is over you don't want them to continue
to have access to that you can make up a
similar scenario for the police
department they're on their way because
the house you know security system has
said somebody has broken into the house
so we have to find ways of easily and
you know in authoritative ly providing
and removing access to some of these
systems if we want to take advantage in
these emergency kinds of situations
another example would be if you exposure
in a strange city and you have a medical
emergency you've never been in the city
before you're in the emergency room
assuming you're conscious you might very
well be less worried about the privacy
of your medical stuff than you are
making sure the people trying to save
you have every piece of information they
can possibly have in order to respond to
the medical emergency now after the
emergency is over assuming you survive
you probably don't want all those people
to still have access to all of your
medical information so now we get this
problem of being able to grant and
revoke the ability to access and control
or get data from these various systems
so I don't think we've solved these
problems terribly well this is I've
already done the little residents vs.
the guest things what about parents
versus the kids and usually it's the
parent that gets a bad end of the deal
because the kids know how to do this
better than the parents do and so
they've configured the controls to keep
the parents
from getting into the house or getting
into the garage or whatever it is
starting with heart but this is an issue
how do you how do you distinguish and do
you wish to distinguish between parent
and child when it comes to access to
these devices whether it's in a
residential setting or not and of course
then there's in the industrial setting
there shopfloor operations versus the
administrative staff and the visitors if
you're in a plant that's got a whole lot
of robots in it the last thing you want
is some random character who's just
visiting to somehow get control over the
robots and interfere with their
operation
so making making it easy to distinguish
among the authorities and the identities
of these various parties feels like it's
a fundamental infrastructure issue and I
have to say I'm not persuaded yet that
we understand how to do this in any
scaled up way yes you can show up with
your mobile and have an app and somehow
you know you introduce the devices
playing the Bluetooth game or something
along those lines so now your app is
recognized even across the network and
will pretend that there's good you know
strong authentication mechanisms the
problem with that is that the apps
multiply and the last thing you want to
do is be flipping through apps to figure
out how to turn on the bathroom light so
I don't think we've understood in some
visceral way the scaling problems
associated with the vision of having
lots and lots of programmable devices
surrounding us at home and at work so
let me just mention the again this
notion of how long does this stuff
persist and what are the implications of
having things for long periods of time
people seem to march through Mobile's at
a fairly quick pace some people every 3
or 6 months some people every couple of
years but there are other things that I
have anyway picture frames that I bought
10 years ago and I've had them face
in various ways the storage gets
corrupted the power supply doesn't work
anymore and I can't find one that works
you know provides the right kind of
polarity and empower level so this
notion of having devices around for a
long time means that they may or may not
get very much support now a picture
frame is not terribly important but you
know the heating ventilation air
conditioning system or the security
system or some other vital part of a
home or office is a big deal and I think
that if we're serious about doing this
IOT thing on perpetrating IOT on the
rest of the world then we need to think
about what the long-term implications
aren't having these things around there
are implications for software updates
there questions about escrow of source
code there are a whole series of
protective measures that we collectively
probably have not worked through like I
would certainly argue that I haven't
anyway then there are custom systems
some of you may have done what I've done
which is there invest in a custom
entertainment system with projection
systems and the like things built into
the walls every time it doesn't work I
have to call a guy in Ellicott City
Maryland the drive down and reprogram
stuff now you might say you idiot why
don't you reprogram it yourself and the
answer is I'm not sure I trust myself to
reprogram this properly and if I don't
get it right my wife will be very
unhappy with me and so I'm trying to
preserve the peace while still having a
nice you know custom entertainment
system but it is not very supportive if
this guy moves away or decides to go
into another line of business it's not
clear to me how easily you know I would
be able to maintain this stuff and so
you really have to think about the
robustness and resilience of the systems
that we install and I even have some
programmable light switches that go into
the walls for turning the lights off and
on
intervals exterior lights primarily and
I discovered that these only work if I
have a certain kind of battery and now I
started to worry about the battery
business because you could spend a lot
of money for a device only to discover
it's useless because the guys that make
the batteries for it decided it wasn't a
worthy business to stay in and they
don't make them anymore this is very
personal for me I wear two hearing aids
they cost several thousand dollars each
I have to buy these little batteries for
them if the people who make the
batteries decided to hell with the
battery business these four thousand
dollar devices would be worthless and I
keep thinking I've even written about
this but I keep thinking about these
dependencies that we have even in
today's world and I wonder about the
dependencies we may be inventing maybe
without thinking about it as we push
further into this IOT space so I hope
I'm disturbing your peace of mind a
little here because I think some of you
anyway should feel some responsibility
for this so let me this I think this is
my last slide let me start out by
arguing that if these devices are not
reliable people are not going to want to
use them they you you don't want a light
switch that works sixty five percent of
the time and so when I have discussions
with my colleagues about this space of
products my highest priority is make it
reliable make it easy to use and that by
the way mitigates against the 75 apps in
your mobile trying to figure out how to
turn the lights on there is however an
all and equally worrisome issue and
that's safety why on earth would anyone
want to have a product at home or at
work or embedded in their bodies let
alone on their persons that is
categorically unsafe so now there's a
little problem here because it's not
always easy to figure out
whether something is actually safe or
not could the device could
malfunctioning device in fact cause
serious harm and there are some obvious
cases I mean if you're wearing medical
instrumentation or something or a
pacemaker or some other thing like that
has a very or let's say an insulin pump
I mean those things could absolutely
have a very serious potentially fatal
fail failure and so it's obvious that
safety is at the top of the list for
that but I think that you could see that
even other devices that well how about
the security system at the house you
know when the power goes out should the
doors be opened around or locked or not
all and what happens if the security
system fails so you can make a list I
guess of various things that you might
have in use and then ask yourself what
are the consequences if the safety of
the device isn't assured and what are
the side effects when things fail which
drifts into security questions now if I
am relying on the on these devices to
keep the door locked and to not open the
door for anybody that isn't authorized
to get in I should care a lot about that
and so along this checklist of IOT the
responsible behavior in the production
of IOT is security is is in there as
well privacy shows up too and if most of
the time I think I think when I think of
privacy I think of all kinds of personal
information the webcam you know and
things of that sort but it dawned on me
that even very simple devices like
temperature sensors have a potential
safety error or a privacy risk they may
also have a safety risk think about it
in my house I have this little
temperature sensors that are also
forming a store and forward mesh network
and so every five minutes they pick up
the temperature and they send that
information to a server down in the
basement and I got to thinking what
would happen if somebody could look at
the temperature Sentinel readings in all
the rooms in the house over a period of
six months let's say remember there is a
sampling is every five
I wonder if you could figure out how
many people live in the house I wonder
if you could figure out what their
diurnal patterns are I wonder if you
could figure out whether they're home or
not by the patterns that you would have
absorbed and machine learned let's say
over a six-month period so here's a case
where a bunch of temperature readings
potentially turn into a safety and
privacy problem I I think when when I
may be an extreme you know case but it
seems to me that when we start thinking
about designing and building systems
like this we have to be thoughtful about
these edge cases that might turn out to
be serious problems and autonomy is
another digital easy list of desirable
properties I think of these devices
autonomy by this I mean that you don't
want a house that doesn't work when it's
not connected to the Internet or to put
it another way your house operations
should not be dependent on being
connected to the Internet I know it's me
saying that but I admit that you know
it's it's it's actually a serious issue
because there are times when the
internet goes away I mean it may be a
local phenomenon all the power went out
your generator is running but the
internet isn't accessible because the
guys that supply the you know ISP
service are not running even if your
house is and the idea that you have a
collection of devices that don't work
unless the internet is running and is
accessible has to be a really bad idea
and so again I find people not focusing
on things like that they focus on look I
have this app in my mobile and I can
talk to this device remotely isn't this
cool I can check the temperature in the
refrigerator and I can turn the lights
off and on in the master bedroom and I
can see if the front door is open or
closed and you know they get all excited
about this amazing ability to do this
remotely which is cool on the other hand
if the house doesn't work anymore
because the internet isn't there that's
got to be a bad design so I worry that
people don't take that into account when
they're thinking through all the
positive scenarios that they might
undertake
and finally there's this question about
interoperability there are a lot of
different companies including alphabet
and Google that are interested in making
these kinds of products and even working
hard to make them work so within within
a particular brand space in some
interoperable way so that a collection
of devices could all be made to
cooperate with each other but there are
going to be other brands showing up and
you and I are going to buy things from
multiple parties it's not going to be
fun
if each will each brand has its own
control hub and has to be configured in
a different way well this is just
another way of talking about standards I
don't think we're very close to having
agreement at this point on what standard
should apply to Internet of Things and
we may not know until we get some
experience with what they're like what
works and what doesn't work what scales
and what doesn't but I think at some
stage or other consumers like you and me
are going to be serious about wanting
interoperability across the devices that
we buy and that certainly would be true
for somebody who's trying to run an in
an industrial setting you don't want to
have a bazillion different devices that
require completely different control
processes and practices especially if
you're trying to automate some of it
which we were hearing about earlier in
the configuration space and so I think
that even though there is almost
inescapably a period of time when we
will be exploring rather incompatible
protocol spaces for these devices at
some point there will be wisdom in
looking for commonality and an agreement
on standing
standards so I think that's the last
slide and so what I'd like to suggest is
that I put my headset on we can get into
a discussion or if you're bored to tears
we can stop and so I'll test that by
finding out anybody wants to raise an
issue I see we got people at the
microphones hang on a second while I get
myself sorted out I I do want to point
out
some people call this part of the
discussion QA this is a terrible way to
I don't have all the answers so you can
ask all the questions you want but I'm
not going to guarantee I have answers to
them okay
testing testing how's that working yes
question in the middle thank you very
much for this talk Vint amazing stuff I
am curious on that last slide where you
listed considerations you managed to
leave off one that I think is going to
be front and center very very soon which
is the legality aspects going back to
February of this year I noticed the
NHTSA approved Google's AI as a driver
from the legal perspective the Internet
of Things assumes in a big way that
these are simply inanimate image objects
that we have absolute control over we're
already going down the road of granting
status to programs that verge on the
rights that we give humans at what point
do you start to worry that the device in
your home says I'm sorry I'm not going
to allow you to upgrade my software I
consider that an invasion of my
sovereign right as a as a functioning AI
I'm sorry I can't let you do that Dave
okay I have to be over here to be heard
first of all you raise a really good
point
second you also raise the point that I
want to emphasize and then this is not
just about artificial intelligence this
is about letting software make decisions
or take actions in an autonomous way and
so even I mean beyond legality I mean I
think the other things show up here to
safety privacy all these other things so
yes we should be absolutely worried
about that and now there's liability
which is the other side of this equation
at Google of course we have these
self-driving cars and on the whole
they've been fairly safe although we've
had you know an occasional collision
mostly it's somebody who runs into us or
you know one of our cars although I
remember one you probably read about
this was the car that had come to an
obstruction in the road and there was a
bus over here in the next lane and it it
thought that if it could if it could
edge its way around the obstruction the
bus would move out of the way and it
didn't and so we had this massive three
mile an hour collision with the side of
the bus and so then we started running
the self-driving cars to a whole series
of training things to say if it's bigger
than you I don't try to get it to move
out of the way no bad idea like while
I'm on cars I just have to tell you
about this anecdote some of you may have
heard this but you know we we can't
anticipate all the things that the cars
are going to encounter situations and so
sometimes you know if we're trying to
figure out why did this car stop you
know why is it not moving you know we'll
turn on the video cameras and and look
and at one point there was a car
this is told to me so I didn't actually
see this but but a car was stopped at an
intersection and it wasn't moving and we
turned on the camera or they turned on
the cameras and there was a woman in the
middle of the intersection in a
wheelchair chasing a duck with a broom
and and we didn't have anything in the
program that said
John there's a woman in the intersection
and chasing a duck with a broom I don't
think I know it would have known what to
do either somebody's moving in the
intersection
you know rule number one do not run into
anything so anticipating what some of
the problems are is really difficult
thank you very much for the question
it's a very good one let me take it's
over on your left yes Devlin Bloomberg
so by the way a chatbot on your
thermostat might be really entertaining
but one of my concerns is actually I
think the right word similar word would
be weaponization of this technology
towards each other you know we have
heard many stories over the years about
wireless networks and using standards to
attack other wireless networks that D
off in conferences as an exam while
Wireless is a built-in standard people
have worked around the standards to
attack other systems and you know my
concern is that a vendor decides that
their light switch will now send a pulse
down the electable system to knock out
the dishwasher because it's not allowed
to get enough power and we have no
standards we have no laws saying
basically play nice in the sandbox I
can't help but ask about your
anthropomorphize a ssin of the light
switch now so we should be a little
careful about going overboard with
regard to that on the other hand we do
have indications of parties who might be
motivated to interfere with somebody
else's product in order to get the
consumer for example to buy a different
product now that I could understand
could happen my experience suggested we
were less likely to have that happen and
we are to have the other thing which is
that the design simply is crappy and the
system doesn't work very well because
the different manufacturers didn't
coordinate anything and so there's
interference of one form or another but
you're right to raise the question and
the possibility that there that the
standards would get abused I think
that's not specific to the Internet of
Things this is a problem in general
okay I'll take the center I Patrick
Gilmore mark leading group burst thank
you dr. Cerf very interesting although
I've noticed having seen several of your
presentations everything you say is more
interesting because you said it so
that's very nice of you this is all
wrong you should never make such a look
if an old fart like me comes up and says
something you should assume it might not
be right what was it was it was uh come
on who's the guy that figured out the
satellite idea Arthur Clarke Arthur
Arthur C Clarke said if an oh sorry if
an if an old and respected scientist
tells you you can do something he's
probably right if he says you can't do
something he's probably wrong but thank
you for the compliment but please folks
you should think for yourselves I'm not
gonna think for you go ahead
so do very quick things I hope first of
all it's pretty well established that
the large DDoS was cameras if you think
about it half of million cameras which
is not that many pushing a megabit each
is 500 big bits right number two you
berate a point about reliability and
ease of use and I don't I very hesitant
to disagree with you but taking your
advice I remember back in the day
telephone companies when cell phones
came out they said no one would ever use
them as people dropped calls
does anybody here even have a landline
anymore but calls are still dropped to
this day well I do too but most people
don't and just because we all like to
blame Microsoft I mean you know
computers these days if it breaks
everybody just thinks to reboot it
because that's what Microsoft taught us
um the idea of going into your bathroom
your light switch doesn't work you can
say nobody would ever agree to that but
if it becomes you know 10 times easier
and then it doesn't work once every year
people are going to go ahead and agree
to that so I disagree the reliability is
paramount I think it's important but
it's not the only
okay well that's fair I think that
there's probably some incidence rate of
failure at which we would probably cut
the line and for some of us you know
that might be in a different place
failure in one year that's not so bad
that happens lots of things break on the
other hand if this is if if things are
you know only 75% likely to work I think
that we might you might pick a different
number than I do but your points
well-taken that it isn't only
reliability that counts but a really
poorly functioning system is not going
to get a lot of friends great thank you
sir okay
Rob Higgins ale bent thanks for coming
good to see you I have a question on
machine learning okay so as I think
everyone would agree you know
politically this country is quite
divided today and I've read several
articles or perhaps I should say people
tell me but I've read several articles
that say that machine learning would be
somewhat to blame that is to say that
algorithms which tend to feed someone
more you know articles websites blog
posts Twitter posts whatever that like
align with my previous habit then just
reinforce when I'm thinking and and
really prevent a person from in in some
cases you know looking at what is the
other side really all about that was
just curious your thoughts on that yeah
well you can see me not in my head in
agreement there was a time when I'll
give you an example from history in the
early stages of trying to do digital
libraries there was a concern that the
response to a search of the digital
library would be so precise that you
would lose the serendipitous experience
of walking into the stacks and pulling
out a book and discovering the book next
to it was actually more relevant or more
interesting or whatever then the
you were looking for and the big concern
was that the quality of the search
system would be so good that you
wouldn't get that serendipitous effect
and for a long time we laughed at that
saying you know the quality of the
feedback or the searcher response was
not all that good however I would say
that it's getting a lot better and your
point about the echo chamber effect
where the only things that come back are
the things that somehow match the
system's expectation of what you're
interested in does feed that feedback
loop is quite real it almost makes me
think that we should program the
televisions to automatically switch back
and forth between fox news and CNN and
something else if you know forcibly
exposing using more than one point of
view I suppose that would be treated as
an unreliable device and it will be
tossed out of the house I don't know
what to do about that the the optimistic
thing would be to recognize that with
this vast ability to pull information in
from so many sources that we have an
obligation to ourselves to be thoughtful
about and even a little suspicious of
the information that we get and to think
you know critically about where did it
come from what and what are the
antecedents to that information I'm
afraid people are fairly lazy and they
don't do that I will admit to not doing
more of that and so I think we do have a
worry that our information spaces are
becoming segregated and as a result we
don't even recognize that there's
another story over here I don't know
what to do about that it's a social
engineering problem in Hawaii thank you
thank you for raising the question
gender microphone Gary Geeson
centralogic tear points on autonomy and
interoperability it seems most most of
the time these days all the IOT
interoperability is in the cloud and
guarantee pulled by the larger players I
wonder if you might be able to speak to
this kind of concentration of power in
in the hands of larger players and the
ability to shut out upstart players who
are trying to innovate market
I can't imagine why
you would ask somebody from Google that
question I'm shot
so this is a potential issue and you you
frame it quite well let me argue that
the cloud systems ours and Amazon's and
Microsoft's and so on are becoming
increasingly accessible to a larger
number of parties and so in some sense
even though your concern I think is as
it has a reasonable basis that my
impression right now is that the
capacity of the various cloud-based
systems are are in fact opening up to
more parties able to put their software
on board Google Offers a substantial
amount and so does Amazon for example
and I'm not picking on Microsoft here I
just don't know the details David but
those systems are more and more
available now to people who wish to
populate those systems with their
applications so the applications don't
belong to the people who run the clouds
though I'm not trying to run away from
your your point but I would like to
argue there is a countervailing effect
and it's very attractive for cloud based
companies to to reinforce that because
it increases the utility of the cloud
system itself in to the extent that
you're selling access to computation as
a service roughly speaking this is a
good thing
so your point I think and I think
there's some countervailing forces that
will keep that from being the disaster
that you probably are worried it might
be thank you very much okay I'll take I
guess this might be the last question
pulling DeLong Akamai so my concern with
the Internet of Things that's a little
bit more immediate than a lot of these
other more long-term concerns and many
of them actually kind of touch on it and
I will say that the manufacturer of my
smoke detectors my very very expensive
smoke detectors is one of the worst
offenders in this regard is the fact
that I can buy this expensive device and
I
penned on the maintenance of this cloud
service by the manufacturer without them
getting paid anything other than what I
paid for the device in perpetuity as the
only way or the only thing that prevents
my device from becoming instead of a
nice expensive piece of plastic that is
very useful a brick and the lack of a
local API on IOT devices is to me one of
the biggest missing pieces on many of
these IOT things not that I don't want
to use the Google cloud and the Google
Cloud API and all of that to run my nest
thermostats or nest smoke detectors or
what have you actually I don't have a
nest thermostat because it doesn't have
a local API I have a ven start because
it does but the lack of a local API to
me is is a really bad thing and Google
has carefully avoided providing any sort
of local API and forces you into their
cloud and you know Google may be better
than some of the others about running
this cloud in perpetuity but I've
already had five different vendors
terminate the cloud services on me
turning my products into bricks and so
I'm not buying any more products with
the exception of the nest smoke
detectors but that's because they die in
five years anyway
and I expect the cloud will be there for
five years so do you have any more darts
that you want to have pointing in this
direction well I'm not just throwing
it's a more general problem but since
you're representing one of the prime
examples but behaving in this way I it's
fair game
well first of all these points are all
very good and I actually agree with them
the concern that I had about autonomy
for example feeds exactly into your
concern about API is because I won't
have the ability to interact with these
things locally regardless of whether the
cloud is still available or not so I am
concerned about that although I am a
voice not necessarily in the wilderness
I'm in one voice out of many but I think
that it is almost inescapable that we
have to have in the local ability to
manage and configure and control these
devices it's enhanced potentially by
having access to the cloud its resources
its computational ability it's
machine-learning ability and everything
else but if we don't have this local
capability then the autonomy problem
fails the solution that is not a
solution if there's no local API so I am
speaking on your behalf
well with or with I can't say what
success I won't have but you and I are
actually in agreement about the value of
having that kind of interface I'll look
forward to it changing well I won't
guarantee that but at least I will
guarantee to articulate the point I
think we have two more question sorry we
have two more questions in the middle
and then we're only one minute away from
finishing so please go ahead Matt PTAC
who you mentioned in your talk earlier
about the mesh of temperature sensors in
your house as a company that is 97%
funded by advertising how long do you
think it'll be before they decide that
spotting an unusually high thermal
activity in one particular bedroom might
lead to certain advertisements for
material showing up many months later in
the air
god that's a brilliant idea let me write
that down
do you know the story about a guy at
Walmart who's who
Walmart was tracking I think it's
Walmart Target he was actually Target it
was a Target think it was target that
was tracking purchases and this guy's
was his father was seeing mail coming
about you know baby clothes and baby
food and all this other stuff and he's
really angry because it was it was
addressed to his daughter and so he
stormed into Target and complain to the
manager he's all pissed off and then a
few months later he came back and
apologized because guess what she was
pregnant so yeah I don't know that's a
great idea though I'll take that back to
our ad people thank you so so if this
starts happening to you folks it's his
fault okay
all right Chris would people Twitter
wanted to follow on with Owens questions
and comments around the local API issues
and it seems that the your answer was
focused more on the fact that not having
a local API limits the ability to manage
the device and almost requires device
management over the Internet which
depends of course you know network
availability what about survivability of
the service provider what about choice
of clients and those types of questions
that would make would make a lot of
these devices far more useful because it
opens up possibilities people may come
up with ways of managing the devices
that the original vendor never dreamed
of yeah so there there's several threads
in this in this little weave here yeah
no pun intended in case you didn't know
we have a protocol at Google called
weave which we use for the IOT devices
ok sorry about that first of all the
standardization has the value that it
can increase competition for example for
management of devices and I will
actually think that the consumer is
including me it would like it if I had a
choice of different parties whose
control systems could manage multiple
devices from multiple brands I actually
think that would be a good thing I think
competition generally is good thing now
I think that there exists already for a
lot of these devices at least some
interface even if it's not exactly the
full thing that Owen might be interested
in because in order to get the devices
configured you often have to convince it
that you are the person in control of it
sometimes that's a Bluetooth exchange
with your mobile but there's at least
some interface typically that requires
the device to come close to the convert
the party controlling it in order to
make that connection but I like very
much the picture they're painting which
I think requires standardisation that
will allow parties to compete with each
other and also to experiment with
ensembles of devices that nobody thought
to put together to perform a particular
function so I frankly hope that we will
get to that stage as this IOT phenomenon
unfolds because I think that's where a
lot of the creativity will be so let's
hope that you and I realize that what we
all realize the benefits from that idea
and as the future unfolds so thank you
all very much for letting me take up
part of your afternoon
you