good morning so yeah my name is Greg
to be communities joke Schneider
as a co-presenter he is here with us in
spirit although not in person though
large bgp communities are a new
technology to signal routing information
between networks I'll tell you a little
bit about the history how we got here so
the things that we're doing to
evangelize the technology and most
importantly how we're going to get this
out to network operators quickly ok if
we look at a brief history of bgp
communities how people are using them
this RFC 1997 was 20 years old so it was
written in 1996 it was designed
initially to simplify internet routing
policies it gives us this community that
we use today which isn't encoded as a
16-bit ASN with a 16-bit value there's
broad support in implementations it's
widely deployed by network operators and
used for day-to-day internet routing
about 10 years later we had something
called the extending communities
attribute which was also published as an
RFC this adds a value a label a longer
range it was more used for layer 3 VPN
routing fewer implementations available
and also a slower adoption rate and the
thing about the extended communities
attribute is that it's really
complicated in fact there's an RFC that
has the value allocations for this
community so it really wasn't what
operators wanted for internet routing
this is what operators used today a
simple 1997 Style community and I have a
couple examples here there's one from
NDT which is the actual community values
that they provide to their customers and
then there's also the one step
consulting index to the communities so
there's a bunch of operators that are
listed on this webpage and Charles has a
summary of all their routing policies
and the communities that they use so
it's very widely deployed it's also used
in training material operations
procedures policy documentation and then
also I didn't know this but a joke said
that they have contractual obligations
from their customers to provide these
kind of communities and ways to
manipulate the routing system so it's
especially difficult if you have a
32-bit ASN because there's no way to
actually do this so long came a problem
we knew that we'd run out of 16-bit asns
eventually work started a long long
time ago to develop a 32-bit ASN in a
couple different RFC's the IRS started
allocating 32 bits ASNs almost 10 years
ago by request initially and now there's
really no distinction between a 32-bit
ASN and a 16-bit ASN an ASN is an ASN
and it can be one of either it's used
widely for edge and transit ASNs so you
can't really say oh the 32-bit ASNs are
just edged ASNs they're not there are
also transit in essence the fundamental
problem is is that you can't fit a
32-bit value into a 16-bit field so that
means if you have a 32-bit ASN you can't
use your ASN in these 1997 communities
at all so you have to do things for you
you use private ASNs as your communities
or or some other Cluj some other strange
mapping but then there's namespace
collision because you it's not unique
anymore right you're reusing something
between multiple providers so the
solution is something called large BGP
communities this is an effort that
started in the IETF recently it's a
collaboration between network operators
and system vendors so it's it's not a
vendor thing or it's not an operator
thing that people are pushing it's
definitely collaboration and this is I
just want to mention some related work
for a 32-bit ASNs because there has
there have been some efforts in the past
there's the RFC 56 68 which was
basically extending the 4360 style
communities for 32-bit ASNs it's kind of
a micro optimization it doesn't solve
the fundamental problem of signaling
ASNs in a 1997 format there was an
effort called flexible bgp communities
which seems to have lost momentum there
hasn't been a lot of work on that
recently and there's also never called
wide bgp communities there is still a
lot of a lot of amendment behind this
one it's a complementary solution and a
more comprehensive solution it adds a
lot more things like peer grouping scope
and things like that but there's no
consensus or no implementations
available today and I think the solution
needs more more time to develop so
basically what the state that we're in
today is we have no community solution
for over ten years
that supports 32-bit ASNs
so support for large beach communities
has been overwhelming when the when it
was introduced on the IDR list there was
a lot of support from both network
operators a lot of you people here in
the room and also from implementers
there were hundreds of messages on the
adoption thread on the ITF mailing list
so very very wide support and a lot of
enthusiasm and a lot of operators saying
you know yes we need this and please
give it to us now don't talk about it
from the next you know several years and
come out with something you know in the
future we need something now is the
overwhelming message that we got from
network operators so the goal is very
simple like RFC 1997 communities but
larger that's all we're trying to do
design goals as I said simply larger we
didn't want to add any complexity or
extra functionality we're just trying to
extend the communities that people have
been using for 20 years to support
32-bit ASNs there's also another
important thing that's added which is an
action so that now we can signal
information having the the source the
destination and the target of the action
without losing that information we want
to do something that's easy to implement
easy to adopt easy to remember the
canonical representation is very easy to
remember easy to talk on the phone or to
you know tell people that have
international language difficulties and
most of all this is something that Joe
Provo pointed out too is it provides
parity and fairness to people that have
a 32-bit ASN because they can now use
the same signaling that other people can
that have 16-bit asns so we don't have
any namespace collision now between a
SMS because you can use a native 32-bit
ASN you can use a native 16-bit ASN
these are all supported down a couple
things are out of scope these all came
up on the IDR list in in discussion we
didn't want to add some sort of mapping
like an RFC 1997 to large communities
mapping I think that's really out of
scope because everyone's routing policy
differs and you know a mapping that
works for me might not work so well for
you so we just kind of left that up to
the the individual operators we didn't
want to add a TLV or a header
that kind of gets that's back in the
situation as the other community efforts
where you're adding more more
functionality and then you know you get
everyone wants to throw on something and
we have another kitchen sink
implementation so we just purposely
wanted to keep it simple it's designed
to do one thing and and that's all its
gonna do we also didn't feel the need to
define any new well-known communities
because you can still use RFC 1997 and
16-bit communities so those well-known
communities that are defined work just
as well with with large communities so
no need to extend that encoding and
usage is very simple it's a 96 bit
quantity the canonical representation is
three 32-bit AAS and 32-bit numbers so
the representation is me my ASN some
sort of action that we're doing together
and then your ASN we're also working on
a 1998 style usage draft with some
examples and some routing policies and
how this could be used in in different
providers to you know some some policy
definitions that's real simple it's just
encoded on the wire as a 96 bit quantity
and and that's it here are a couple
examples and some of these you can argue
well you can do that today and that
that's true but the fundamental point
here is that there's no namespace
collision or use of reserved numbers in
these communities and all of them allow
us to use a 32-bit ASN in the me or you
values so for example you you couldn't
do this today with with 1997 communities
if the field look of the first example
do not advertise to p ras in north
america this isn't an example from NTT
if you have a 32-bit ASN as i mentioned
you can't actually do that because you
can't fit that value in the field so you
have to have some Cluj to map or use an
internal private ASN to signal that if
we use an amzing example for do not
announce something to a router appear
you also can't do that today with 1997
communities so that possible and then
some of the examples you could actually
do today but they just become more clear
if you add large communities because you
have the the you and the me and the the
action we have several milestones i
don't want to go through all these but
the key point
here is that this was first published in
September early September and we're on a
very fast path to move this through the
ietf and get this out into network
operators as I mentioned at the start
there are a couple key points adoption
as I said September and then we had the
first path code allocation at the end of
September that has caused some issues
I'll get to that in the next slide we
have some beacon prefixes that we
announced those highlighted the issues
and then also just a couple days ago on
October 17th the IDR announced last call
so two week last call on this one so
we're well on a very fast track towards
RFC publication timeline where were you
there's really three parallel efforts
that are independent but we're moving
we're doing all of them at the same time
so the IETF that's kind of the first
step that defines a standard so we have
to get that started and then once we
have the early allocation and enough
consensus in the IETF then implementers
started to work on this depending on
what type of implant or you are it can
take you a couple days or it could take
you a long time system vendors you know
I'll include my company will be a little
more it takes us longer to get stuff out
open source implementations had stuff
literally out within a few days or a
couple weeks and then there's also the
evangelism perspective and the education
perspective so that's what we're doing
today we're going to get people to
understand and learn about the new
community we want people to think about
how they can incorporate this technology
and the network in terms of the training
preparation testing deployment and we
have a lot of conference presentations
planned so I'm it started out with job
giving his presentation at n L nog a
couple months ago or a couple weeks ago
so I'm giving this presentation today
jobs giving it a tripe next week and we
have a conference schedule mapped out so
that we we hit all the major conferences
and so on some of the smaller ones in
order to to make sure that we educate
all the network operators about about
this new technology so there's a lot of
things going on in parallel to get this
into your hands terms of status we
maintain a website called large bgp
commune
so the latest information will always be
there I just
I'll keep pointing you towards that from
an implementation status a number of
vendors have committed or planned
something on their road map so we listed
that here and if you don't see your
vendor on here then and you want to use
this technology then you should be
talking to them now it's important from
an ecosystem perspective to also have
the tools and other system support so
it's not just the BGP implementation
that need to be updated obviously if you
have something and you can't
troubleshoot it or you know you monitor
it then it doesn't really do you any
good so those two things go hand in hand
so all of the tools the major tools have
been updated to support large BG
communities so the tcp dumps Wireshark
PM act was just updated a couple days
ago so again visit the Status page for
the latest on all the implementations
beacon prefixes so this slide I
originally was just going to talk about
the beacon prefixes but this light could
also be an entitled Along Came another
problem so initially the story here is
that job announced his to homeland
prefixes on the internet with a large
beach beach communities so this was all
great he has a v4 prefix and a v6 prefix
implementations saw them on some
implementations without large BGP
community support it showed up as an
unknown transitive attribute so that's
great it was able to display that and
then on implementations with bgp
community support it actually showed the
large community that was signal so
that's great so after job had done this
for a couple days his girlfriend noticed
that she couldn't reach certain websites
that she could reach before so okay that
was interesting so through some
troubleshooting and found IX and talking
to network operators it turns out that
the prefixes that were unreachable were
behind a certain brand of Huawei routers
so that was interesting after some more
investigation and this is what just came
out a couple days on the IDR list is
that Huawei was squatting on path
attribute code xxx
and also 1:29 1:29 isn't so relevant to
our presentation but 30 is the one that
has been allocated by the Ayana so they
would actually just blackhole any route
that came in with this new community
attribute so that left us in a position
well what do we do now so there's two
choices one is you know we can go tell
huawei that they've been bad and asked
them to fix their implementation okay
well you know considering that that
there are a lot of routers out there by
the time this is roll down into a
release and then deployed by network
operators you know we're looking at a
year maybe 18 months so basically you
black hole people that want to use this
community for the next year or two so we
didn't think that was a good solution
the other solution is okay let's just
choose a new attribute code and
deprecated the old ones and you know
change all their implementations and
move forward so the consensus on the IDR
list was that this was the best idea for
the community and the best option to get
this technology out there so the
attribute code 30 will likely change to
something else and then we'll announce
new beacon prefixes and they'll make
sure that no one's black holing those as
well so interesting story there
there was also an issue with a Cisco
ipv6 route but you know that turned out
to be something minor so it's really
interesting to see what happens if you
just announced stuff on the internet
with reserved path attribute codes okay
so here if you're an implementer here
are the takeaways for two different
groups if you're an instrument or
obviously you need to add support for 30
or whatever path attribute codes it
turns out to be some implementers are
providing an optional Co not CLI command
to enable it that's fine you can do that
you'll have to extend your routing
policies the matches and sets obviously
regular expressions now have to change
you need to extend your show commands
and please also make sure to update the
debug commands on the packet dump output
you know again if we have something that
signaled on the internet but we can't
see it or troubleshoot it then it
doesn't really help us because then
we're just gonna be in a position where
we're stuck trying to figure something
out again update all your documentation
your training material your technical
staff you know it goes this is a full
new feature that
to be introduced so needs to go all
through all the the platform and and
feature progress lifecycle things like
that
this is especially the the most
important slide for you network
operators if you would like to use this
new technology large bgp communities
then you need to ask your vendors for
support especially if they weren't on
the slide that I mentioned previously
make sure to go talk to them and tell
them that you want to use this
technology or if you think it's this is
something you don't want to use then
also go tell them what you want this is
you know this is a consensus-based group
here so if you don't want to use it
that's fine it's optional as I mentioned
the whole ecosystem has to support large
bgp communities so this is your tools
software your provisioning software your
routing policies you know please publish
this information as well as many people
have done on their web pages and then
you have to train your technical staff
to you have to train them how to use it
and you know how to educate your
customers on how to use it as well so
there's a big effort that goes into this
and that's it so this was just a joint
presentation that we did as I mentioned
we're doing a lot of evangelism around
this technology so visit large bgp
communities net for latest information
we have a whole bunch of news that we're
putting up there as it develops also the
implementations that I mentioned and
also lastly you would like to reuse this
slide deck in any form for a you know
your internal use or not operator
conference get in touch with us and
we'll be glad to give you the slides and
and let you reuse it that's it any
questions
hi Chris will Twitter hey Chris hi so so
it looks like we're that this is going
to need to require a new path attribute
value yes
31 looks open at the same time has
Huawei indicated any willingness to
deprecated their squatting on value 30 I
don't think anyone from Huawei I'm a
little bit behind on my IDR mail so as I
as far as I know
don't know if anyone has has said what
they're going to do but you know we
would that would be what we would
encourage them to do Matt PTAC Yahoo
extending Chris's question a little more
broadly as a community we've endowed
some of these organizations such as I
Anna with responsibilities and ownership
for protocol parameters assigned numbers
and things like that are we going to put
up with vendors essentially co-opting
that function and saying hey I know
you've appointed a standards body but
what the heck we're gonna do our own
thing in some ways rather than
deprecated attribute 30 I would say as a
community we need to push back to on
vendors that try this and say this is
not cool we've decided from the internet
governance model that we've assigned
that function to this particular
standards body and thou shalt not co-opt
the standards body like that this is not
OK from the community perspective I
agree 100% and this has kind of been
some of the feeling on the IRF mailing
lists about this topic has been exactly
what you said but again you know in
terms of just trying to get this out
there in a usable form you know there's
like there's really two separate issues
is one what do we do now and two you
know from a policy and in the bigger
picture perspective what do we do when
vendors do I agree on the expediency
part for this but as a community I'm
calling out to the community to say this
is a name and shame a moment for us to
say if we believe in Internet governance
from the Community Supported model we
need to push back when people violate
that thank you
absolutely absolutely agree Joe go
Google Hey
just wanted yes to follow on a Matt's
point vote with your wallet people tell
tell your sales reps this is beyond not
good sorry front of my throat the the
only thing I wanted to come up
originally and say say thanks Greg for
presenting this and just put a thank out
onto the stream for the members of the
IDR for working with the operator
community we keep hearing ATF wants
operator input this is a really good
example of while there may have been
some heat a lot of light got shed good
work was done and we're making fast
progress yes absolutely agree video
photo Qi Telecom well okay first of all
I was watering for dedicate whether we
would get something like this and I had
lost hope to see this before I retired
on the issue of the use of code points
and so on I would like to remind the
community that in the past years we have
seen people injecting undefined
attributes and causing trouble couple of
times and we certainly as operators
cannot rely on anybody who is connected
to play according to the rules because
well okay most of us at one point in
time actually will do some some error
and actually don't play ourselves by the
rules the thing that was done something
like five years ago to respond to this
was that well okay
most of vendors actually introduced
attribute filters and I would actually
point out that when you
have a bgp an ebgp session with some
peer what's going on in the attributes
is essentially in the first place a
bilateral met the bilateral thing and
while okay if you if you do not know
exactly what you are doing yourself and
what you the other party is doing you
actually you actually have to accept
that that responsibility and actually in
cases where there is a problem through
filtering not so kind of the expectation
of job with its beacons to expect that
the new attribute would propagate
everywhere to some extent is naive under
this point of view yeah I I think you're
right I think the challenge is okay now
now we have this this allocation code
and someone's squatting on it so what do
we do in that case and also really I
want to thank you because your comments
at ripe were very inspirational to the
people that started this work so
hopefully we will see it in your before
you retire david firm hate Ashley
Minnesota I want to remind everybody
who's saying it's bad that they're
squatting and yes it is but it's our job
there is no internet police remember
that's something we like to talk about
here we have to make it not be okay and
this room writes the checks so remember
that when you're writing your check
yeah and you know just kind of expand on
the onion attributes now there's
discussion on the IDR list about okay
well what other unknown attributes are
out there so there's there's a couple
asns that are actually announcing
deprecated or even reserved at that to
beYOU codes so till we determine what
happens with that because as Dan said
there is no internet police Jeff Houston
if you're soliciting opinions expediency
says move your code because you're
deployed mass just isn't out there yet
and it's faster to do that we're already
circling around a whole bunch of legacy
problems this is another and it's sad to
see and I wish they weren't there etc
etc and I totally agree naming and
shaming is wonderful but the packets
still have to move and you know you've
been crying out for this extended
community attribute since about 1997 you
finally got it change the code and put
it out there would be my view I think
that's the last question so as I said
get in touch with us and I appreciate
your time